<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77ft25b"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interactions between types and levels of dietary fiber and Heligmosomoides polygyrus (Nematoda) infection in mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sun, Yi, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objectives of this study were to determine the effect of different types and levels of dietary fiber on Heligmosomoides polygrus (Nematoda) in laboratory mice. BALB/c mice were randomly assigned to one of seven diets: no fiber, cellulose (5%, 10%, 20%), and pectin (5%, 10%, 20) and infected with H. polygyrus one week later. The length of intestine increased significantly with the concentration of pectin and was associated with longer villi, thicker mucosa and increased villus/crypt ratio. In contrast, changing concentration of cellulose had minimal effects on the gastrointestinal tract. More day 5 larvae were found in mice fed 20% pectin, but neither type nor level of dietary fiber affected worm survival or spatial distribution. An increase from 5% to 10% pectin increased per capita egg production both in vivo and in vitro, but a further increase to 20% pectin decreased per capita egg production in vivo to the low level seen in mice fed no fiber. However when the parasites from mice fed 20% pectin diet were cultured in vitro, they released very high numbers of eggs. Changing concentration of cellulose had no effect on parasite egg production in vivo or in vitro. Our study supports the hypothesis that pectin promotes the establishment and reproduction of Heligmosomoides polygyrus, and that this is closely related to the changes in gut morphology. Therefore we conclude that cellulose, not pectin, should be used to balance reduced content of macronutrients in studies on malnutrition and nematode infection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Scott, M. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z7215.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft25b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Heligmosomatidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Helminthiasis -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fiber in human nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice -- Parasites</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gx934"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Etude des interactions ARN-protéines de la télomérase chez Tetrahymena et chez l'humain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Triki, Ibtissem</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Telomerase is the major mechanism that compensates for telomere loss during conventional DNA replication in eukaryotic cells. This enzyme is a ribonucleoprotein reverse transcriptase, composed of an RNA subunit (TR) containing a template that dictates the telomeric DNA sequence, a catalytic subunit (TERT), and others associated proteins. In order to characterize the telomerase RNA-proteins interactions in two different organisms, Tetrahymena thermophila and human, we developed two electrophoretic RNA mobility shift assays. In Tetrahymena, we identified a specific RNA-protein complex by using whole cell extracts partially purified and in vitro transcribed and radiolabeled Tetrahymena telomerase RNA (159 nt). Certain Tetrahymena telomerase RNA mutants tested in competition with wild type RNA by shift assays and containing deletions of structures and sequences previously predicted to be involved in protein binding were unable to competitively inhibit complex formation, suggesting a role in protein binding for the deleted residues or structures. In human, we identified a specific telomerase RNA-protein complex by using 293 human cell extracts partially purified, and in vitro transcribed and radiolabeled hTR (451 nt). Using different hTR mutants in competition with wild type hTR, we identified nucleotides 1--424 of hTR as a minimal region that is able to reconstitute a stable RNA-protein complex.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Autexier, Chantal</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw37s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gx934</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r9675528"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional studies on the coxsackie and adenovirus receptor (CAR) in skeletal muscle cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tai, Yunlin, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>CAR (for C̲oxsackievirus and A̲denovirus R̲eceptor) is a novel member of the Ig superfamily, which has recently been identified as a high affinity receptor for both Coxsackievirus and certain adenovirus (AV) serotypes. Virus bound by CAR is believed to be passed to integrins which bind an RGD (Arg-Gly-Asp) sequence in the viral penton base protein and act as secondary receptors responsible for virus internalization. Recent studies have shown that, in integrin-expressing cells, CAR-mediated AV uptake does not require the cytoplasmic (CP) domain of CAR, presumably because virus bound to the CAR extracellular (EC) domain can be passed to integrins for subsequent internalization. It has however also been reported that CAR can directly mediate AV uptake in the absence of penton base RGD-alphav integrin interactions. I therefore attempted to determine whether the CP domain of CAR is required for CAR-mediated AV uptake in cells which do not express integrins, or in which integrin function has been blocked by RGD-containing peptide. As CAR is the primary AV receptor and integrins are secondary AV receptors I investigated the possibility that these proteins associate in a functional complex in the cell membrane. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Holland, Paul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s69s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9675528</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Adenovirus diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Viruses -- Receptors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coxsackievirus infections</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p001n"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of food web structure on the growth and bioenergetics of lake trout (Salvelinus namaycush)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pazzia, Ivano</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Most fish species tend to feed on larger prey as their size increases. The lack of suitable prey during critical periods of their life can prevent them from shifting their diet to larger prey and also from reaching larger body sizes. In this study, we compared the energy budget of lake trout ( Salvelinus namaycush) populations with contrasting food webs. Non-piscivorous lake trout (NPLT) populations reached a much smaller size and grew at a much slower rate than picivorous lake trout (PLT) populations. Food consumption rates were on average, 2--3 times higher in NPLT when they were expressed on a wet weight basis. However, only a slight difference in their energy intake was detected (less than 10%) once consumption rates were corrected for differences in prey caloric content. Growth efficiency was about two times lower in NPLT compared to PLT, while their metabolic costs were higher and assimilation efficiency was lower. It is most likely that the increased metabolic costs were associated with higher foraging costs, since more feeding attempts must be made to acquire a given quantity of food when fish are feeding on smaller prey. Furthermore, the portion of indigestible matter is likely to be higher in the diet of NPLT than in PLT (e.g. chitin versus bone). These results are consistent with theoretical models of fish growth that have showed that lake trout must have access to larger prey, even if they are rare, to reach larger body sizes. Our study also illustrates how the restructuring of a prey community by the arrival of an exotic species into a food web could alter the growth rate of a top predator. Furthermore, our study suggests that age at first maturity is influenced by growth efficiency in indigenous populations of fish. Therefore, the dynamic of a population and its vulnerability to exploitation are likely to be influenced by their energy allocation strategy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rasmussen, Joseph B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t343.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p001n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lake trout -- Food -- Ontario -- Algonquin Provincial Park</dc:subject><dc:subject>Food chains (Ecology) -- Ontario -- Algonquin Provincial Park</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lake trout -- Growth</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp95t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of selenium and vitamin E intake on diet-induced oxidative stress and hyperlipidemia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poirier, Johanne, 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To examine the effects of fat composition and supplemental vitamin E (Vit E) and selenium (Se) on in vivo lipid peroxidation, diet-induced hypercholesterolemia, and glutathione (GSH) metabolism, male Syrian hamsters were fed for three weeks butter fat (BF-) or fish oil- (FO-)based diets supplemented with Vit E and/or Se. The effect of supplemental Vit E and Se on tissue lipid peroxidation (LPO), glutathione peroxidase (GSH-Px) activity and GSH concentrations differed between heart and liver and also was affected by dietary fat. The reduced glutathione/oxidized glutathione (GSH/GSSG) ratio was more consistently associated with tissue lipid peroxidation than was tissue Vit E content. Plasma lipids were lowered with supplemental Se and Vit E. Se supplementation, however, exerted a more potent hypolipidemic effect than Vit E. A pro-oxidative action of Se in hearts of FO-fed hamsters was noted, which was inhibited by supplemental Vit E. Hence, the combination of Vit E and Se may offer the most benefit against diet-induced oxidative stress and hyperlipidemia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kubow, Stan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d608w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp95t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vitamin E -- Physiological effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>Membrane lipids -- Peroxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hyperlipidemia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glutathione -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Selenium in human nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Selenium -- Physiological effect</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494b23v"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comprehensive approach to array bounds check elimination for Java</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Qian, Feng, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We present a new approach to eliminate array bounds checks in Java by using static analyses. Our approach is based upon a flow-sensitive intraprocedural analysis called variable constraint analysis (VCA). VCA collects constraints between locals related to array references. The array bounds check problem is formulated as solving a system of difference constraints. The analysis builds a small constraint graph for each important point in a method, and then computes the shortest-path weight of the graph. The shortest-path weights from upper bound to array index and from the index to lower bound indicates the safety of checks. Using VCA as the base analysis, we also show how two further analyses can improve the results of VCA. Array field analysis is applied on each class and provides information about some arrays stored in fields, while rectangular array analysis is an interprocedural analysis to approximate the shape of arrays, and is useful for finding rectangular (non-ragged) arrays. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hendren, Laurie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb41d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494b23v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150k943"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expressiveness in mobile process calculi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Posse, Ernesto</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The development of formal methods and theories for the construction and analysis of concurrent systems has been a subject of increased interest, particularly in the last decade. Amongst the most recognized and studied theories is the pi-calculus and its family of languages. The pi-calculus is a language for describing and reasoning about mobile systems, that is, systems in which the topology of the communications network is dynamic and not fixed a priori. Examples of such systems include mobile phone networks and the TCP/IP protocol that underlies the Internet. Another paradigm for concurrency is known as Concurrent Constraint Programming or CCP for short. This is a particularly attractive model because of its close ties with Logic and its declarative style. In this thesis a survey of the pi-calculus family and the CCP family is presented, emphasizing the relations both within each family and between the two paradigms. In particular we explore the question of whether CCP supports mobility.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Panangaden, Prakash</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602271h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k943</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494b244"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessing the efficiency of In Vivo electroporation as a nonviral gene transfer technique and studying its application in antiangiogenic cancer gene therapy and cancer immunotherapy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maietta, Antonio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Electroporation refers to a technique that makes use of electrical pulses to create transient and reversible pores into cellular membranes which allows the passage of drugs and macromolecules, such as plasmid DNA, into the cell's interior. It is a widely used laboratory procedure for the transfection of cultured mammalian cells, plant cells and bacteria. Only recently has in vivo electroporation been used for the transfer of genetic material into living tissue, such as muscle, hepatocytes, and tumors of experimental animals. Using a luciferase assay, we have shown that electroporation-mediated luciferase gene transfer into solid, subcutaneous tumors in mice resulted in a 103 fold increase in tumor luciferase activity compared to naked DNA injections. Using this technique, we succeeded in inhibiting the growth of LLC tumors in mice by delivering plasmid DNA encoding mouse Endostatin and mouse single-chain IL-12 directly into the tumor site. Lastly, in vivo electroporation was used to enhance DNA vaccination with the tumor associated antigen CEA and IL-12 gene adjuvant, which protected mice from a tumor challenge with LLC/CEA+ tumor cells. Our results suggest that in vivo electroporation is an efficient nonviral, gene transfer vehicle that can be used in the fields of antiangiogenic cancer gene therapy as well as cancer immunotherapy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prud'homme, G. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j675.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494b244</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hb57k"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Protein synthesis in a piglet model of gastrointestinal inflammation and malnutrition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mackenzie, Michelle Lee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A piglet model of gastrointestinal inflammation (INF) and protein energy malnutrition (PEM) was developed to determine the mechanisms responsible for growth retardation and muscle wasting during inflammatory stress. Acute PEM decreased liver and plasma protein fractional synthesis rates (FSR), measured by stable isotope (2H3-leucine) incorporation. Conversely, both rates increased during PEM+INF at the expense of growth and muscle FSR. INF increased plasma protein synthesis by 77% in PEM without increasing its plasma concentration, demonstrating that the measurement of plasma protein concentration alone underestimates the metabolic impact of INF. INF during PEM results in a re-prioritization of amino acids from muscle protein synthesis and growth to hepatic synthesis of plasma proteins to support the acute phase response. This underscores the critical role of adequate protein-energy nutrition during inflammation in preventing muscle wasting and growth failure. This new piglet model can be applied to investigate nutritional and therapeutic interventions in inflammatory bowel disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wykes, Linda</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m8586.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb57k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Malnutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inflammatory bowel diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Proteins -- Synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Piglets</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p002x"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Document processing for adaptive page segmentation using order statistic filters</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ma, Li, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Page segmentation is one of the important and basic research subjects of document analysis. Traditionally, there are two major kinds of page segmentation approaches. One is the top-down approach and the other is the bottom-up approach. Though these two approaches are been used till now, they are not effective for processing documents with high geometrical complexity and the process of splitting document needs iterative operations which is time consuming. The Modified Fractal Signature (MFS) approach which was presented in recent years can overcome the above weaknesses, however it needs to calculate modified fractal signature which makes the theory and the algorithm very complex. In this thesis, we present two new page segmentation approaches (one is the Maximum Order Statistic Filter (MaxOSF) approach, the other is the Median Order Statistic Filter (MexOSF) approach) based on the order statistic filter (OSF) which is more direct and much simpler. We use the MedOSF to remove the salt-pepper noise of the document and use the MaxOSF to do the page segmentation. In practice, they not only can adaptively process the documents with high geometrical complexity, but also save a lot of computing time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Newborn, Monty</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm12x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p002x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5h73px877"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The importance of a radial spoke protein in flagellar motility</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Magder, Ilana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of our investigation was to gain insight on the regulation of flagellar movement, at the axonemal level. In our laboratory a panel of monoclonal antibodies (MoAbs) has been produced against the axoneme of the biflagellated algae, Chlamydomonas reinhardtii, a well-characterized model for the study of flagellar movement. Of these MoAbs, L2H12 has been selected, because it has a potent inhibitory effect on the motility of de membranated-reactivated flagella of Chlamydomonas cells. Using video micrography, we demonstrated that low concentrations of L2H12 cause a progressive decrease in the wave amplitude and beat frequency of the flagella. Results of Western blotting of the axonemal proteins indicates that L2H12 recognizes a 105 kDa protein. Analysis of Chlamydomonas radial spoke mutants deficient in one or more radial spoke proteins (RSPs) suggests that this protein is RSP2. Immunoprecipitation of this protein was performed to further characterize it.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gagnon, Claude</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg364.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px877</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655j45w"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nest parasitism in red-breasted mergansers (Mergus serrator) in New Brunswick</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Janishevski, Lisa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Intraspecific nest parasitism was studied in a group of colonial Red-breasted Mergansers (Mergus serrator) nesting on the Tern Islands of Kouchibouguac National Park in New Brunswick in 1992. Nest parasitism is very common in this colony, and may influence the high rate of nest abandonment observed. Emphasis was placed on determining rates of successful parasitism (i.e. eggs added during the laying period of the hen at that nest), which are evolutionarily significant, and can easily go undetected. Three methods were used to determine if a nest contained egg(s) from another hen: abnormally large clutch size: more than one egg laid per day: and comparisons of DNA fingerprints of the hen versus putative chicks. When eggs were added to a nest during incubation, the nest was also labelled parasitized, but such eggs were not fully incubated (non-term) and thus were not successful. A new method of blood sampling ducklings in pipped eggs was tested and found to have negative effects on survival. As many as 14.8% (13/88) of the ducklings sampled subsequently died. Researchers wishing to use this method should proceed with caution. DNA fingerprinting determined that 50.0% of nests tested (6/12) were successfully parasitized. Two of six parasitized nests would have gone undetected using the other criteria to detect parasitism, thus proving the value of DNA fingerprinting. Of hatched young genetically analyzed, 30.9% (17/55) were parasitic. Nest parasitism appears to be an alternative breeding strategy in this population. Extra-pair copulation, previously unrecorded in this species, was discovered through DNA fingerprinting in two of four nests analyzed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Titman, Rodger</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kuhnlein, Urs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9031813.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j45w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Red-breasted merganser -- New Brunswick -- Reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brood parasitism -- New Brunswick</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544br29k"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Survival of Salmonella typhimurium in simulated intestinal fluids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Igue, Patience</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Salmonella species are among the major foodborne intestinal pathogens that are of public concern with respect to food safety. The ability of intestinal pathogens to resist gastric acidity corresponds to their oral infective dose (ID). The survival and lipopolysaccharide (LPS) profiles of Salmonella typhimurium grown at different pH values and to different phases of growth were examined in simulated gastric fluid (pH 1.5), ileal fluid (pH 7.0), colon fluid (pH 8.0). The survival and growth of S. typhimurium were also examined during sequential passage through all three fluids. Viable cells were rapidly reduced from 106 CFU.ml-1 to &lt;10 CFU.ml-1 within 4 min in gastric fluid. Cells inoculated directly into ilea] and colon fluids survived and multiplied extensively. When low numbers of viable cells of Salmonella in contact with gastric fluid (0.5 min of contact) were transferred sequentially to ileal and colon fluids, only the early and late stationary phase cells were capable of recovery and growth to high numbers. The harsh environment of the gastric fluid did not change the LPS profiles of the inoculated Salmonella cells. Entrapment of S. typhimurium in calcium alginate beads and chocolate increased its survival in gastric fluid. This implies that Salmonella cells are protected from killing when ingested with food. These results may explain why Salmonella species have a very low ID when consumed as part of some contaminated food sources.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Idziak, E. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j68f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br29k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Salmonella typhimurium</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gastric juice</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr429"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of genetic variants on hydrolysis of -casein by chymosin and pepsin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jeyaragavan, Tharmalingam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several studies have demonstrated that certain genetic variants of beta-casein are closely related to milk production, milk composition and technological properties of milk such as coagulation properties during cheese making, calcium precipitation and water binding properties. The objective of current study is to investigate the effect of the genetic variants on hydrolysis of beta-casein by chymosin and pepsin. On the basis of a preliminary analysis, a total of 50 milk samples which provided representatives of different available genetic variants of beta-casein were collected from different herds in Quebec. Casein was prepared from milk samples by the acid precipitation and the genetic variants of beta-casein were identified by both alkaline and acid urea-PAGE. An anion exchange chromatography was employed for the separation of beta-casein from whole casein. An initial hydrolysis of beta-casein of different phenotypes by chymosin and pepsin were achieved under the optimized hydrolytic conditions. Hydrolysates were periodically removed from the reaction mixture and they were analyzed by both RP-HPLC and SDS-PAGE in order to study the hydrolytic pattern of each beta-casein variant with the increasing hydrolytic time. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ng-Kwai-Hang, K. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f536d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr429</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chymosin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic polymorphisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Casein</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pepsin</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848s335"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Circadian adaptation to full-time night shift work with bright light intervention regimen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>James, Francine O.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The primary consequence of night shift work is a misalignment of the endogenous circadian pacemaker with the inverted sleep-wake cycle. This study evaluated the efficacy of a judicious schedule of light exposure on circadian adaptation to night work. Fifteen night shift workers (mean age +/-S.E.M.: 41.8 +/- 1.8 years) were studied for 3 weeks in their work environments under one of two experimental conditions. Treatment group participants underwent an intervention including bright light in the workplace, while control group participants were studied in their habitual light environments. The efficacy of the intervention was evaluated in the laboratory via constant routines. Following the intervention, treatment group subjects displayed a mean phase delay of (+/-S.E.M.) -9.32 +/- 1.06 hours and full entrainment to the night-oriented schedule while control group subjects displayed a phase delay -4.09 +/- 1.94 hours and a partial entrainment (F(1,30) = 11.33, p = 0.002). The results of this study suggest a means of alleviating the difficulties associated with night shift work with control of the overall pattern of light exposure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boivin, Diane B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989362.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s335</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Physiological</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5h73px88h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of the new coactivator SRA (Steroid RNA Activator) on the transcriptional activity of ER and ER</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deblois, Genevieve</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nuclear receptor coactivators are factors that enhance the transcriptional activity of the receptor. Most coactivators characterized to date work in a ligand-dependent manner by interacting with the activation function-2 (AF-2) of the receptor. A newly characterized coactivator termed steroid RNA activator (SRA) was cloned as an AF-1-dependent and ligand-independent coactivator. SRA was shown to enhance the transcriptional activity of the steroid receptors by interacting with their AF-1. Here, we describe the effect of SRA on the transcriptional activity of the estrogen receptor alpha (ERalpha) and beta (ERbeta). SRA coactivates ERalpha and ERbeta in a ligand-dependent manner and the transcriptional activity of ERalpha can be enhanced by SRA in a ligand-independent manner through the AF-1 domain of the receptor. The integrity of the serine residue at position 118 (S118) in ERalpha AF-1 is required for the complete coactivation of ERalpha by SRA. Activation of MAPK induces ligand-independent activation of ERalpha by SRA, a mechanism independent of the AF-2 activity of the receptor. Mutation of S118 to an alanine residue abolishes the MAPK-induced activation of ERalpha, suggesting that phosphorylation of S118 by MAPK may be important for the ligand-independent effect of SRA on ERalpha AF-1. Thus SRA may play an important role in the regulation of ER transcriptional activity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giguere, Vincent</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967554t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px88h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q25m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Susceptibility of apple cultivars to Venturia inaequalis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dewdney, Megan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Apple scab is one of the greatest apple management problems throughout the world Much work has been done on cultivars resistant to Venturia inaequalis (Cke.) Wint., but few have been a commercial success. This frequently leaves fungicides as the only control method used. As Quebec growers select new cultivars for planting, more information is needed on their relative susceptibility for efficient scab control. In this light, 21 cultivars common to central and eastern Canada, were examined for their relative susceptibility using several components of partial resistance; disease severity, incubation period, latent period, lesion size, and conidial production. The cultivars used were Cortland, Early Geneva, Empire, Golden Delicious, Golden Russet, Idared, Jersey Mac, Jonagold, Jonamac, Lobo, Lodi, Summerland McIntosh, Mutsu (Crispin), Northern Spy, Paulared, Red Cortland, Red Delicious, Royal Gala, Spartan, Sunrise, and Vista Bella. A final ranking of the cultivars and selection of partial resistance components was done using the principal components analysis. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paulitz, Tim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n302p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q25m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Venturia inaequalis -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apple scab -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apples -- Disease and pest resistance -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cg23z"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gaze, eye, and head movement dynamics during closed- and open-loop gaze pursuit</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dubrovsky, Alexander Sasha</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Horizontal step-ramp stimuli were used to examine gaze, eye, and head movement dynamics during head-unrestrained pursuit with and without imposed retinal velocity errors (RVE; i.e. open- and closed-loop, respectively) in two rhesus monkeys. In the closed-loop experiment , pursuit was elicited by step-ramp stimuli with a constant velocity of 20--80 deg/s. Each monkey used a combination of eye and head motion to initially fixate and then pursue the target. Additionally, we found that initial eye and head acceleration increased as a function of target velocity. In the open-loop experiment, step-ramp stimuli (40 deg/s) were presented and ~125 ms after pursuit onset, a constant RVE was imposed for a duration of 300 ms. In each monkey, when RVE = 0 deg/s, gaze, eye, and head velocity trajectories were maintained at their current or at a damped velocity. Moreover, the head as well as the eyes mediated the observed increase and decrease in gaze velocity when RVE was +10 and -10 deg/s, respectively. Based on our findings we conclude that the pursuit system uses visual and non-visual signals to drive coordinated eye-head pursuit.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cullen, K. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n052k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg23z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75r961r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between dispositional optimism and quality of life in upper aerodigestive tract cancer patients</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dehestani, Fatemeh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this study was to investigate the hypothesis that pre-therapeutic "dispositional optimism" is associated with post-therapeutic "quality of life (QOL)" in a sample of patients with upper aerodigestive tract (UADT) cancer. A sample of 101 subjects with UADT cancer was enrolled in this cohort study. QOL was evaluated through the EORTC QLQ-H&amp;N35 and the global domain of the EORTC QLQ C-30. Dispositional optimism was measured using the Life Orientation Test (LOT). Subjects completed these self-administered questionnaires prior to treatment and one week to one month after their treatment. Other data were gathered by interview and medical chart review. Prior to treatment, an association between dispositional optimism and QOL was observed for the global, pain, swallowing, senses and feeling ill domains. However, no such associations were observed following treatment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Allison, P. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Feine, J. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq368.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r961r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Physiological</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k9079"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Long-term effects of tillage and residues on selected soil quality parameters</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Callum, Ian R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A two year study was initiated in 1999 at the Macdonald Campus Farm, on a 2.4 ha site consisting mainly of St-Amable sand to shallow loamy sand (Typic Endoaquent; Humic Gleysol). The site was planted to alfalfa ( Medicago sativa) prior to the establishment of the experimental design and has been planted to corn (Zea mays L.) since 1991. The experiment was set up as a randomized complete block design and consisted of three tillage levels (NT, no-till; RT, reduced tillage; and CT, conventional tillage) and two residue levels (-R, no residues; +R, with residues). This study was performed in order to ascertain the effect of these management systems on soil organic carbon (SOC), particulate organic matter carbon (POM-C), microbial biomass carbon (MBC) levels and soil physical properties. Soil physical properties measured included bulk density, saturated hydraulic conductivity (Ksat), dry and wet aggregate stability, total porosity, macroporosity at -1 kPa and -6 kPa of matric potential, and moisture content. Crop yield was also measured. Results indicated that lower rates of mineralization of POM-C under NT+R in the surface 0--10 cm led to significantly higher SOC at the same depth. There were no significant differences between treatments at the 10--20 cm depth. The MBC was not a good indicator of the differences in soil organic matter levels between treatments. No-till treatments had higher bulk densities, reduced total porosity and macroporosity, increased moisture content, and increased constant-head measured Ksat. Differences in Ksat as measured with the Guelph permeameter, were not significant between treatments, most likely due to increased earthworm activity in NT. There were no significant differences in crop yield in 1999, but a significantly wetter year in 2000 caused lower grain yields in NT+R compared to NT-R and CT+R.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madramootoo, C. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b298b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k9079</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Crop residue management -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tillage -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Residues -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conservation tillage -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soils -- Carbon content -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil physics -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rn15n"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thermal injury increases TMR induced angiogenesis in the ischemic myocardium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bousette, Nicolas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. A growing number of patients suffering from ischemic cardiomyopathy are not eligible for conventional revascularization. This has prompted new research in the field of angiogenesis. This study hypothesized that since inflammation is probably the mechanism behind TMR induced angiogenesis; a larger inflammatory response induced by thermal injury may lead to increased angiogenesis. Methods. The model used for this study was coronary artery ligation in the Rat. Four groups of animals were used to compare the novel experimental approach with conventional TMR and with ischemia alone. Neovascularization was determined by immunohistochemical techniques using anti-Factor VIII antibody. Evaluation of VEGF, Ang-1 and Ang-2 expression was also carried out using immunohistochemistry. Results. The experimental "HOT" TMR technique resulted in significantly increased angiogenesis presumably due to the thermal injury induced by the novel technique. Also a significant increase in VEGF expression was observed in all ischemic groups. Ang-1 expression was decreased in the experimental group while it was similar in the other groups. Finally Ang-2 was induced by ischemia as evidenced by increased expression among all ischemic groups. However Ang-2 expression did not significantly vary among ischemic groups. Conclusions. The addition of thermal injury by heating of the needle led to an increased angiogenic response compared to ischemia alone and compared to conventional TMR. This increased angiogenesis was associated with increased VEGF expression at one week, however there was a significant inverse correlation between VEGF expression and angiogenesis among the ischemic groups. Also angiopoietin expression was in agreement with expression characteristics described in the literature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shennib, Hani</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c09m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn15n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227mr73j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The use of a fungal antagonist to reduce the initial inoculum of Gibberella zeae on wheat and corn debris</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bujold, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gibberella zeae (anamorph: Fusarium graminearum) is the causal agent of fusarium head blight (FHB) and maize ear rot, two major diseases of wheat and corn in Eastern Canada. In Quebec, Microsphaeropsis sp., an antagonist of Venturia inaequalis, the causal agent of apple scab, was isolated from the apple leaf litter. This fungus, well adapted to Quebec climate, can reduce the initial inoculum of V. inaequalis. FHB and Gibberella ear rot are similar to apple scab because the major inoculum source comes from melanized structures produced on crop residues. Consequently, we evaluated the potential of Microsphaeropsis sp. (isolate P130A) to inhibit ascospore production of G. zeae when applied to crop residues as post harvest or pre-planting applications. Under in vitro conditions, the antagonist significantly reduced ascospore production on wheat and corn residues, when applied prior to (82% and 92% respectively) or at the same time as the pathogen (36% and 58% respectively). Under field conditions, the antagonist had no effect on the pattern of perithecia maturation but significantly reduced the number of ascospores produced on two sampling dates, May 1998 and July 1999. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paulitz, Timothy C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c238f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr73j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microsphaera</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Diseases and pests -- Biological control -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wheat fusarium culmorum head blight -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gibberella zeae -- Biological control -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw37638854"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kinetics and mechanisms of morphological transitions in block copolymer aggregates and sodium dodecyl sulfate as a morphogenic agent</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burke, Susan Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The kinetic and mechanistic details involved in the morphological transitions occurring in aggregates prepared from the copolymer polystyrene-b-poly(acrylic acid) (PS-b-PAA) in dioxane-water mixtures and the ability of sodium dodecyl sulfate to induce architectural changes in these aggregates are described in this dissertation. The kinetics of the sphere-to-rod, rod-to-sphere, and vesicle-to-rod transitions were determined by following the change in the solution turbidity as a function of time after the transitions were induced by a sudden jump in one of the solvent components of the system. The kinetics of each transition was explored as a function of the initial solvent composition, the magnitude of the solvent content jump, and the initial polymer concentration. In another study, the amphiphile, sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS), was found to induce morphological transitions in the copolymer aggregates at lower water contents than those required in the absence of surfactant. The effect was studied as a function of SDS concentration, solvent composition, and copolymer concentration.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eisenberg, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r68d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37638854</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gj26n"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cross-border strategic alliances in the transition of regulated telecommunications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wei, Chia-Lee, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Competing successfully in globalized markets requires a complex mix of product, price, promotion and distribution. It requires novel approaches to ownership in overseas involvement and the development of new modes of global relationships. In response to these needs, new types of alliances are emerging as corporations endeavor to meet the global challenge. At the forefront of globalization, the telecommunications industry is experiencing a high-rate of cross-border alliance formation. This thesis attempts to straddle both business and legal domains, on national and international levels, to survey the evolution of the telecommunications industry and to envisage the future prospects of multinational telecom carriers with respect to the conduct of transnational alliances for international expansion. Chapter 1 describes the changes occurring in the field of telecommunications, while Chapter 2 and Chapter 3 provide an essential understanding of the motivations and the modalities of cross-border strategic alliances and propose contracting techniques for the purpose of surmounting managerial and operational challenges that may be confronted when engaging in global strategic alliances. With a focus on the telecommunications industry, Chapter 4 explores the motives of and difficulties encountered by multinational telecom carriers in using alliances to expand globally, and examines their business strategies and performing phases. Chapter 5 further questions the necessity of using cross-border strategic alliances in an increasingly international competitive environment by examining the current national and international regimes with respect to the transactions of telecom services. The Conclusion reviews significant factors that may infringe upon the use of strategic alliances as a business strategy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, Richard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000198k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj26n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Telecommunication -- Technological innovations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competition, International</dc:subject><dc:subject>Telecommunication -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strategic alliances (Business)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cs303"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patentability of living organisms : legal and ethical aspects of the question</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vandenabeele, Fabienne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Given the considerable advances in the field of biotechnology in the last decades, new issues of scientific, social, legal and ethical nature have been raised, particularly concerning inventions making use of living material, and their patentability. Notwithstanding some reluctance at the outset, most of patent offices as well as courts and tribunals in the United States, Canada and Europe have finally accepted patentability of living organisms. Oppositions are however numerous and, more than a criticism towards the patent system itself, it is genetic engineering that is put into question. Europe has recently regulated the legal protection of biotechnological inventions. Being a text of compromise, the Directive is already subject of controversies. The United States and Canada have not yet decided to explicitly legislate in this field. Some decisions taken in particular cases allow to determine the state of the question in these two countries. It is however not certain that they can be satisfied with an unregulated technology that raises so many moral questions. The question of the foremost importance concerns the research branch, as well as the use that will be done with inventions emerging from the biotechnology industry. Patent law being unable to prevent technological creations, it is above all the utilisation of it that will allow to retain the most beneficial inventions for humankind and its environment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lametti, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r499g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs303</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bioethics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biotechnology -- Patents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biotechnology -- Moral and ethical aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Patent laws and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>