<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wp521"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Initiation of developmental asymmetry by Drosophila Bic-D, DLis-1 and microtubules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Swan, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>I have investigated the mechanisms by which developmental asymmetry arises, using oocyte determination in Drosophila melanogaster as a model system. The Bicaudal-D (Bic-D) gene is required early in oogenesis for the asymmetric localization of specific mRNAs and proteins and for the differentiation of an oocyte from one of a cluster of 16 interconnected germarial cells. To better understand how Bic-D functions in creating this asymmetry, I took two approaches. First, I examined the role of Bic-D in the asymmetric localization of mRNA and other cellular components during later oogenesis. Second, I molecularly and genetically characterized a gene that interacts with Bic-D in oocyte determination. To determine the role of Bic-D in later oogenesis, I used an inducible source of Bic-D activity to selectively rescue the block at oocyte determination in Bic-D null mutants. Using this system, I find that Bic-D is indeed required in the later stages of oogenesis for the localization of specific mRNAs at both the anterior and posterior of the oocyte. Bic-D is also required for oocyte growth and nuclear positioning, processes which also depend on microtubules. In the second part of this thesis, I describe the characterization of a Bic-D interacting gene which I have identified as the Drosophila homologue of the human Lissencephaly-1 (Lis-1) gene, DLis-1. Human Lis-1 is the causative gene for Miller-Dieker Syndrome and is required for neuronal migration in the developing brain, while fungal homologues have been implicated in dynein dependent nuclear migration. Like Bic-D , DLis-1 is essential for oocyte determination and for intracellular localization throughout oogenesis. DLis-1 is required for correct positioning of the oocyte nucleus, and appears to function upstream of dynein in this process. Immunolocalization studies suggest that DLis-1 functions as part of a cortical anchor that links microtubules and the oocyte nucleus, via dynein and microtubules, to the cell cortex. DLis-1 and Bic-D are also required for nuclear positioning during neural development in Drosophila, supporting a model in which the neuronal migration defects in Miller-Dieker Syndrome are due to a disruption of dynein/Lis-1 dependent nuclear migration.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Suter, Beat</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc15x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp521</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Oogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drosophila -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795940w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A view-based system for eliciting software process models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turgeon, Josée</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We propose an approach, together with specific underlying techniques and a system to support these, for eliciting models of software development processes. Software process elicitation involves: gathering process information from the agents involved in a development process, from documents, and through observation; modeling this information; and verifying that the model built is consistent and complete. The elicited models can be used in process assessment and for identifying improvement opportunities, which could lead to improvement in product quality, delivery and costs. Process models can also be used for other purposes, such as measurement of software products and processes; insertion of software tools in development processes; training new developers on the overall development tasks; project planning; risk assessment; software process guidance and automation; etc. In our approach, process information is gathered from different sources, and the separate descriptions (called views) are merged---after ensuring their consistency and completeness---to form the entire model. Our hypothesis is that models built from information gathered from multiple views are of higher quality than those built without consideration for such views. The techniques underlying our approach include: (1) planning for elicitation; (2) eliciting the different views; (3) checking for intra-view consistency; (4) identifying common components across views; (5) merging the views; (6) checking for the overall model quality; and (7) modifying the model if necessary. The thesis demonstrates these features through usage scenarios of the system, called V-elicit. The underlying techniques, together with the supporting V-elicit system, constitute a novel contribution in the software process field. The validation of our approach is demonstrated through five case studies and a comparison with tools described in the literature. These studies show that V-elicit: (i) helps develop process models of superior quality (in terms of coverage); (ii) is more time consuming for developing models, but this time can be reduced by concurrent view development (involving multiple elicitors); and (iii) supports more elicitation tasks than do competitive tools.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madhavji, Nazim H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96022529.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795940w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp806"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The spectral theory of ordinary derivations of K[X,Y] and weaker forms of the Jacobian conjucture</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tian, WeiDong, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let K be a field of characteristic zero, K[ x, y] be the polynomial ring in two variables. Let Delta f denote the K-derivation of K[ x, y] given by Deltaf(g) = J(f, g) = fxg y -- fygx, the Jacobian determinant of f, g with respect to the coordinate system x, y. The derivation Deltaf is a differential operator on K[x, y]. The main objective of this thesis is to develop the spectral theory of the differential operator Deltaf. More precisely, we not only determine the eigenvalues but also the structure of the eigenfunctions of Deltaf. In developing this spectral theory, we prove two weaker forms of the Jacobian Conjecture and establish some relations between the Jacobian Conjecture and our spectral theory.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Russell, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc868.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp806</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t799q"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Prototype of consumption emotions and implications for service evaluation : the case of anger and anxiety in extended service transactions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Menon, Kalyani</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two studies, based on the prototype approach to emotions, examined individual level (appraisals, expressions/action readiness and coping) and interpersonal components (provider response to consumer emotions) of consumer anger and anxiety during air travel, and the impact of these components on service evaluation. It is proposed that the nature of provider response to the overall emotion experience determines consumer evaluation of the service. A survey of recalled experiences of these emotions (Study 1) found that, consistent with the hypotheses, anger experiences comprised appraisals of provider blame for the negative event, problem focused coping (e.g., confronting the provider), and support withholding provider response (i.e., not assisting the consumer through the negative experience). Anxiety experiences, as hypothesized, had greater appraisals of uncontrollable circumstances, but emotion-focused coping (i.e., attempts to manage the affective reaction) was only marginally more than problem-focused coping, and there was no difference in support providing (i.e., assisting the consumer though the negative event) and support withholding provider responses. The survey could not elicit details of the physical expressions accompanying either emotion. Analysis of structured questions show that while support withholding responses decrease evaluations, support providing responses can increase evaluations despite the negativity of the emotions. Study 2 sequentially manipulated emotions (anger, anxiety) and provider response---emotion support (reassuring consumers), instrumental support (attempting to resolve the problem), mixed support (doing both), and no support. Structured questions that followed the emotion manipulation measured coping and action readiness underlying expressions. Coping patterns replicated the results of Study 1. Expressions of anger conveyed action readiness modes of approach and antagonism while anxiety expressions conveyed approach and helplessness. Measures of consumer evaluation followed the provider response manipulation and confirmed that support providing responses lead to higher evaluations. The social support literature indicates that support strategies closely aligned with the components of consumer emotions will be the most effective. Results confirm, that this occurs at high levels of emotion intensity. Instrumental support that matched the well-defined problem oriented components of anger experiences tended to be more effective than emotion support. Instrumental support was also effective for anxious consumers, but a mixed support strategy that matched the occurrence of both emotion-focused and problem-focused coping in anxiety, tended to be more efficacious. Results are discussed in terms of the context specific nature of the components of emotion experience, and of the need to be cognizant of these components when designing provider response strategies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dube, Laurette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft064.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t799q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Consumers -- Psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Airlines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Consumer satisfaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Service industries -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz40r"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ohmic heating of viscous liquid foods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcotte, Michèle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The technical feasibility of ohmic heating was evaluated for viscous liquids in static ohmic heating cells in three stages. First, electrical conductivities and time/temperature profiles were measured and compared for selected hydrocolloids (carrageenan, gelatin, pectin, starch and xanthan) in water at various concentrations (1--6%). Of the thickening agents examined, carrageenan gave the highest value for electrical conductivity and the shortest time to raise the temperature from 20 to 100°C. It was followed by xanthan. Pectin and gelatin samples were found to exhibit lower, but similar electrical conductivities and heating profiles. Starch samples had the lowest electrical conductivity and the temperature of starch solutions never exceeded 62°C within the specified time limit of 10000 s. In the second stage, the effect of salt and acid concentration was evaluated on electrical conductivities and time/temperature profiles of the above selected hydrocolloids in water solutions at a concentration necessary to achieve a similar apparent viscosity of 0.2 Pa.s at 300 s-1 and 20°C (carrageenan 1.7%, pectin 2.5%, starch 4.3% and xanthan 2%). In the third stage, measurements of electrical conductivities, time/temperature and heating rate profiles were performed applying six voltage gradients (5.26, 7.14, 13.16, 17.86, 21.05 and 25 V/cm), with two electrode cross-sectional surface areas (19.84 and 37.95 cm2) and the electrodes separated at three specific distances (10.05, 14.33 and 20.01 cm) at 150 V. Applied voltage gradients had a major effect on temperature and heating rate profiles but no effect on electrical conductivities. Rheological properties of carrageenan, pectin, starch and xanthan solutions were investigated at various temperatures (20--80°C) and concentrations (carrageenan 1.5, 1.7 and 1.9%; pectin 2.3, 2.5 and 2.7%; starch 3.8, 4 and 4.2%; xanthan 1.6, 1.8 and 2%) in the presence of 1% salt. Both temperature and concentration influenced the rheological properties of solutions. Finally, electrical conductivity measurements and rheological properties of starch at 4% and 1% salt were used as input to evaluate a theoretical model for the electrical, thermal and flow behaviour in a continuous ohmic heating unit. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ramaswamy, Hoshahalli</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g04r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz40r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food -- Effect of heat on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Radiation preservation of food</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electric currents -- Heating effects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gm593"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Connectionist models of the perception of facial expressions of emotion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mignault, Alain, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two connectionist models are developed that predict humans' categorization of facial expressions of emotion and their judgements of similarity between two facial expressions. For each stimulus, the models predict the subjects' judgement, the entropy of the response, and the mean response time (RT). Both models involve a connectionist component which predicts the response probabilities and a response generator which predicts the mean RT. The input to the categorization model is a preprocessed picture of a facial expression, while the hidden unit representations generated by the first model for two facial expressions constitute the input of the similarity model. The data collected on 45 subjects in a single-session experiment involving a categorization and a similarity task provided the target outputs to train both models. Two response generators are tested. The first, called the threshold model , is a linear integrator with threshold inspired from Lacouture and Marley's (1991) model. The second, called the channel model, constitutes a new approach which assumes a linear relationship between entropy of the response and mean RT. It is inspired by Lachman's (1973) interpretation of Shannon's (1948) entropy equation. The categorization model explains 50% of the variance of mean RT for the training set. It yields an almost perfect categorization of the pure emotional stimuli of the training set and is about 70% correct on the generalization set. A two-dimensional representation of emotions in the hidden unit space reproduces most of the properties of emotional spaces found by multidimensional scaling in this study as well as in other studies (e.g., Alvarado, 1996). The similarity model explains 53% of the variance of mean similarity judgements; it provides a good account of subjects' mean RT; and it even predicts an interesting bow effect that was found in subjects' data.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marley, A. A. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt734.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm593</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Facial expression</dc:subject><dc:subject>Connectionism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Face perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Emotions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hh22z"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modulation of oxidative metabolism in human visual cortex studies with positron emission tomography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marrett, Sean, 1960-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation addresses the question of whether increases in neural activity caused by sensory stimulation require a significant acceleration of aerobic metabolism in the brain. A new technique for measuring cerebral oxygen consumption with Positron Emission Tomography (PET) was used to assess focal changes in oxidative metabolism in different conditions of visual stimulation. Specifically, positron emission tomography was used to determine whether statistically significant increases in regional cerebral oxygen metabolism are produced by different lengths and types of visual stimulation. These experiments employed a single-bolus inhalation of [15O]O2 to measure oxygen uptake into cortical tissue. In one experiment, oxygen consumption during a monocular presentation of a stimulus restricted to a single visual hemi-field (after 3 minutes and 8 minutes of stimulation) was compared to oxygen consumption measured during a simple fixation baseline. Oxygen consumption increased by 20.5% after 3 minutes. In a second experiment similar procedure was used to examine the changes in oxygen metabolism produced by two different visual stimuli. Regional oxygen metabolism increased by 23% for both stimulus conditions, a reversing yellow-blue checkerboard and a rapidly blinking white-disk. In conclusion, focal activation of human visual cortex is accompanied by significant increases in oxygen metabolism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Evans, Alan</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gjedde, Albert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d160c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh22z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79407z88d"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development ethics and the Canadian North : a case study analysis of the Churchill-Nelson Rivers Hydro Diversion Project</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Friesen, Wilbert J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis argues that economic development, in both theory and practice, is inevitably based on moral questions. These questions have been explored in recent years by "development ethicists," a multidisciplinary group of scholars and practitioners committed to evaluating the policy implications of economic development. Chapter 1 engages this body of literature, arguing that the capability ethic articulated by Amartya Sen and Martha Nussbaum can provide a valuable ethical framework for evaluating economic development in the Canadian north. Their approach is considered in conjunction with other ethical proposals, and, in particular, how theological insights provide an additional dimension for a more comprehensive development ethic. Chapter 2 investigates the ethical assumptions in the theories and models of economic development proposed for the Canadian north, and how public policy based on these theories and models has infringed on the claims and aspirations of Aboriginal peoples. The chapter then shifts from the larger Canadian context to Manitoba, and explores the story of how two hydro development projects impacted several Aboriginal communities. This story provides the context for understanding why four church denominations became involved in defending the rights and aims of five Aboriginal communities in northern Manitoba. Chapter 3 examines the moral vision of the four Christian churches and their rationale for sponsoring four days of public hearings on the Churchill-Nelson Rivers hydro diversion project. The public hearings provide an opportunity to analyse how development affects the lives of a people group when it is thrust upon them without consideration of their economic, cultural, and social value systems. The final chapter examines the issue of the loss of cultural identity for Aboriginal communities as economic development occurs. A major issue pertaining to the loss of cultural identity is whether a development ethic should be based on a universal ethic, or on local traditions, for example, the traditions of the five Aboriginal communities in northern Manitoba. The efforts of the Interchurch Task Force are investigated as a particular type of response to these issues.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Gregory</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418p90g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407z88d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hydroelectric power plants -- Churchill River Region (Sask. and Man.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economic development -- Moral and ethical aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economic development -- Religious aspects -- Christianity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydroelectric power plants -- Manitoba -- Nelson River Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indigenous peoples -- Canada -- Claims</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q5772"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of an experimental component in the analytic classrooms of minority-language students</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fazio, Lucy, 1947-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study, undertaken in the classrooms of minority-language students in French-language schools in Montreal, aims to test Stern's (1990, 1992) proposal for integrating analytic and experiential teaching strategies in second language pedagogy. A related objective seeks to establish the pedagogical orientation of instructional practices during French language arts as being more analytically---or more experientially---focused and to describe the setting from the perspective of these culturally and linguistically diverse students for whom French is a second language. Research procedures entailed the implementation of an integrated activity---journal writing with differential feedback (form-focused, content-based, and a combination of form-focused and content-based)---in four Grade 5 classrooms (N = 112 in total) for approximately four months of one academic year. Twenty-four classroom observations that included coding with the COLT observation scheme and taking fieldnotes were also carried out, and individual interviews were conducted with students, teachers, and administrators. Throughout the study, the francophone students in the participating classrooms acted as a comparison group. The study demonstrated that minority-language students' home cultures and the potentially positive role of the mother tongue in second language learning were not well understood in this context of submersion. COLT findings and qualitative outcomes triangulated to reveal instructional practices that were more inclined towards an analytic than towards an experiential approach to teaching. For both groups of students, MANOVA results indicated no significant effects for quantity of production, accuracy, and overall effectiveness in the journal writing as a function of differential feedback; behavioural and attitudinal data proved helpful in the interpretation of these statistical outcomes. A qualitative analysis of various aspects of the journals' contents revealed that the activity had b</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stevens, Florence</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lyster, Roy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j059r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q5772</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Experiential learning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interaction analysis in education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rw17s"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Growth and IGF-I response to breast muscle selection by ultrasound and dietary protein programs in Pekin ducks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farhat, Antoine G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Four experiments were conducted to determine the reproductive, metabolic, growth and IGF-I response to ultrasound selection for increased breast muscle thickness (MT) in Pekin ducks. Selection for body weight had a negative ( P &lt; 0.05) effect on the reproductive performance while the selection for greater breast muscle thickness resulted in egg production, fertility and hatchability similar to those of the control line (C). Males from the MT line reached market weight at 6 wk but the breast muscle thickness improved from 6 to 7 wk. Compared to females from the C line, MT females had higher (P &lt; 0.05) carcass yield, plasma glucose, and body protein; lower fat and plasma uric acid; and no difference (P &gt; 0.05) in plasma triglycerides and total cholesterol. Males responded more efficiently to increasing dietary protein than females, and males selected for greater MT can be slaughtered at an earlier age when a high protein feeding program (HP) was followed. Males receiving HP had greater (P &lt; 0.05) pectoralis muscles yield, longer keel bone, and lower breast skin and total skin fat yields. Female dissection data show similar (P &gt; 0.05) effects of high and medium protein programs. Increasing dietary protein reduced (P &lt; 0.05) carcass fat and increased (P &lt; 0.05) crude protein (CP). In vivo breast muscle measurement correlated positively (P &lt; 0.05) with body weight, pectoralis yield, and keel bone length. Birds with higher pectoralis yield tended to have more CP and less fat in their carcasses. A low correlation (r = 0.19) was found for the caliper measurement of breast skin plus fat thickness and carcass fat. We determined the metabolic differences between lean and fat male and female ducks, associated metabolic parameters and body composition, and assessed the difference between two feeding solutions for the determination of metabolic endogenous losses. There was a positive correlation between breast muscle:total breast muscle thickness ratio (MT/TO</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chavez, E. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f539.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw17s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ducks -- Breeding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Food of animal origin -- Fat content</dc:subject><dc:subject>Somatomedin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ducks -- Feeding and feeds</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88cj29q"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The rhetoric of silence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Church Farrell, Mary Joanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores how we may read silence in dramatic works as a rhetorical strategy. Silence is usually equated with absence, oppression, or passivity. Speech is usually equated with presence, expression, and action. While silence can be imposed to prevent articulation, my study suggests that we re-read women's discourse, including their use of silence, as an empowering tool. By examining silence as strategic we allow for individual agency. Part One of the thesis demonstrates how the rhetoric of silence functions as a tool to communicate, persuade, and generate knowledge for women protagonists. The study of silence on the stage explores how choosing to employ a non-verbal form of communication challenges the logocentric tendency that privileges assertation and speech over silence. For this reason, Shakespeare's Cordelia serves as the paradigmatic silent rhetor. Cordelia demonstrates how silence, employed by choice, affirms authenticity. In Part Two, twentieth-century interpretations of female protagonists---Salome, Antigone and Philomele---are examined to show how we may read them as strategic rhetors who employ silence in order to recreate themselves as agents.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lieblein, Leanore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg232.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj29q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silence in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010r86m"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Risk for lung cancer among sugar cane farmers and processing workers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Amre, Devendra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There has been recent interest in the possible carcinogenic potential of vegetable fibers (plant fibers) containing amorphous silica. These fibers referred to as Biogenic Amorphous Silica Fibers (BAS) are the normal constituents of number of plant species such as sugar cane, wheat, barley, oats, rice etc. Exposure to fibers within the respirable range has been documented during sugar cane and rice farming and processing operations. Some studies have suggested that such exposure could increase the risk for lung cancer while others have suggested the contrary. In countries like India, sugar cane farming is the major occupation in a number of provinces. A large workforce is involved in its farming and processing. In order to investigate the risk for lung cancer among one such population in Western Maharashtra, we carried out a hospital-based case-control study in the region. As part of this study we measured the exposures to BAS fibers during the harvesting of the sugar cane and the processing of the cane in the mills. Cases of lung cancer were ascertained from 6 cancer treatment centers and matched to controls who had other types of cancers on age, sex, area of residence and timing of diagnosis. After controlling for potential confounding variables such as smoking, asbestos exposure, family history of lung cancer, income, education and farming of other crops, the risk for lung cancer was elevated in workers involved in the farming of the sugar cane, Odds ratio (OR) 1.92; 95% Confidence Interval (CI) 1.08--3.40. Specifically, the risks were elevated for those involved in the preparation of the farm (OR: 1.81; 95% CI: 0.99--3.27) and in the burning of the farms after harvesting (OR: 1.82; 95% CI: 0.99--3.34). Risks were moderately elevated for those involved in the harvesting of the crop (OR: 1.41; 95% CI: 0.70--2.90) and in the processing of the crop in the sugar mills (OR: 1.70; 95% CI: 0.20--12.60). Smoking modified the relationship between sugar cane farming and lung cancer. Sugar cane farmers who smoked had a 6-fold higher risk compared to those who never farmed and did not smoke. Environmental measures both during harvesting and processing of the crop in the mills showed exposure to vegetable fibers. Some of these fibers contained silica and resembled BAS fibers in morphology. However a majority of the fibers lacked mineral content and were unlikely to be those of BAS. The epidemiological study showed increased risk for lung cancer among sugar cane farmers but the limited exposure data did not show high concentration of BAS fibers. The role of polynuclear aromatic hydrocarbons and crystalline silica in particular needs to explored in future studies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Infante-Rivard, Claire</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v93s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010r86m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture, Agronomy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pp70q"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>All our innocences : Fredric Wertham, mass culture and the rise of the media effects paradigm, 1940-1972</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaty, Bart H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation investigates the development of mass communication research in the United States in the years between 1940 and 1972. Central to that investigation is the career of Dr. Fredric Wertham, a psychiatrist whose interventions into debates about the effects of mass communication in the 1950s have remained largely overlooked in received histories of the discipline. By focussing on Wertham's contribution to the development of communications research a number of submerged tendencies are illuminated. A context for the development of the media effects research paradigm is suggested in the first three chapters, each of which highlights a different element which structured postwar communication research. The importance of elitist critiques of mass culture which dominated aesthetic discussions throughout the first half of the twentieth-century are assessed as a foundational factor in the development of communication research paradigms. Postwar concerns about the role of group-mindedness and collectivization are seen to contribute to a conservative political climate which shaped the development of the discipline. Differences between psychoanalysis and behavioral psychology are examined in order to demonstrate the ways in which communication research was consolidated around quantitative and scientistic methodologies. The remaining chapters present two specific case studies of media effects research. Wertham's 1954 anti-comics book, Seduction of the Innocent, is examined in detail in order to illustrate an approach to the study of the mass media that was not pursued by communications researchers. The development of a conservative and individualistic media effects paradigm stemming from research on the impact of television on children is presented as the culmination of postwar tendencies in communication studies. This dissertation argues that because the study of mass communication has been largely defined in the United States through reference to research into me</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Straw, Will</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v92h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp70q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Popular culture -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Comic books and children -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wertham, Fredric, 1895-1981</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp81g"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Apolipoprotein E in Alzheimer's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beffert, Uwe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is the most important cause of dementia, but the mechanism of pathogenesis remains unknown. The epsilon4 allele of apolipoprotein E (apoE) has been confirmed as the most important genetic risk factor for most cases of AD and is associated with Abeta-containing senile plaques, one of the neuropathological hallmarks of AD. We determined the neuronal binding, internalization and degradation of human apoE isoforms apoE3 and apoE4 in the presence and absence of Abeta peptides using primary hippocampal neurons from rat. The findings demonstrate apoE binding and internalization in neurons without endogenous synthesis. Increased apoE3 degradation was observed relative to the apoE4 isoform. Lipophilic Abeta peptides increased apoE binding to hippocampal neurons; the increase was greater for the apoE4 isoform than for the apoE3 isoform. Abeta uptake by hippocampal neurons was increased in the presence of apoE, more so in the presence of the apoE4 than apoE3 isoform. Further, apoE was shown to reduce the extracellular level of Abeta in hippocampal cultures. We also find that all three major apoE isoforms were equally potent inhibitors of Abeta fibril formation, which is thought to be necessary for in vitro neurotoxicity and possibly the neuronal degeneration observed in AD. Further, when apoE was associated with cholesterol-containing liposomes or very low density lipoproteins, its ability to prevent Abeta fibril formation was diminished. In two brain regions affected by AD neuropathology, the hippocampus and frontal cortex, apoE levels were found to be decreased while Abeta levels were increased. Levels of apoE and Abeta1--40 were found to be apoE genotype dependent, with lowest levels of apoE and highest levels of Abeta occurring in epsilon4 allele carriers, suggesting that a reduction in apoE levels may give rise to increased deposition of amyloid peptides in AD brain. The low density lipoprotein receptor-related protein, an important neuronal ap</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Poirier, Judes</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns62s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp81g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763874m"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Before the fact : how Paul's rhetoric made history</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson, Matthew, 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Given the sheer volume of scholarship which has been devoted to examining Paul and his congregations, it is surprising that so little attention has been paid to what the texts portray as the apostle's main concern: not what his congregations were in any 'objective', historical sense, but what they were 'in Christ'. Building on this observation, my thesis may be stated as follows. Traditional Pauline studies, with their emphases either on the apostle's thought or on his congregations' historical situation, obscure the importance of the 'church in the work', a reality established in the text, structured to engender change, and made real rhetorically for readers. These, then, are some of the questions posed: What influence should an awareness of Paul's hortatory, theological image of his congregations have on our efforts to reconstruct them historically? May the well-known Pauline 'indicative-imperative' be taken as a rhetorical strategy? And: In what way does the text try to make its portrayal the definitive reality lived out by its readers? The focus of this thesis is on Paul's congregations as the letters indicated 'they should be', and on the linkage this vision in the letters provides between theology and history, author and reader.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wisse, Frederik</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h1247.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763874m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10ws02w"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The methaphysical foundations of modern physical science : a window on the life and work of E. A. Burtt, twentieth-century pragmatist and postmodernthinker</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Villemaire, Diane Elizabeth Davis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>E. A. Burtt's The Metaphysical Foundations of Modern Physical Science (1924) has been described by H. Floris Cohen, writing on the historiography of the Scientific Revolution in 1994, as the "individual thought of an individual thinker...beyond philosophical or historical currents or fashion." The book is something of a puzzle within the context of American twentieth-century intellectual history and more specifically, of the philosophy and history of science of North America and Europe. Burtt's inter-disciplinary study---as it would be called today---has proved to be both pioneering and prophetic in its rejection of both scientism and positivism. The thesis examines the author's novel interpretation of Isaac Newton's achievement, as well as that of Newton's predecessors in the Scientific Revolution. Burtt's singular view of the rise of modern science from religious underpinnings was, for the most part, either misunderstood or ignored at the time. In fact, the whole idea of a Scientific Revolution was only introduced into the curriculum at leading American universities following the Second World War, in response to Herbert Butterfield and Alexandre Koyre, both of whom owe unacknowledged debts to Burtt. The Metaphysical Foundations was conceived in the progressive era of the 1920s, the latter part of the "Golden Age" in American philosophy. The thesis examines the role of innovating intellects such as John Dewey, James Harvey Robinson, and Morris R. Cohen in shaping Burtt's view, described against the background of his studies at Columbia university. Under the sway of pragmatic naturalism, Burtt's interpretation of Newton was part of a grand scheme to develop a new philosophy of mind which he intended would overcome the problems of Cartesian dualism. The dissertation concludes with an extended analysis of Burtt's public, academic, and personal life based upon archives, correspondence and interviews with those who remember him. It considers his politics of conscience during the Cold War and concludes that integrity combined with the relentless search for philosophic understanding drove his more exotic philosophical quests and steered his personal life, including its tragic dimension, toward simple virtues.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boss, Valentin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pf63p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws02w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Burtt, Edwin A. (Edwin Arthur), 1892- Methaphysical foundations of modern physical science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Science -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Science -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214q85g"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Simple acid-base hydrolytic chemistry approach to molecular self-assembly</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yam, Chi Ming, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new route to molecular self-assembly using a simple acid-base hydrolytic approach on silica based surfaces, is reported in this thesis. Based on this methodology, a number of compounds containing terminal groups with acidic protons, such as alcohols, thiols, carboxylic acids, and terminal alkynes, can be easily deposited on silica surfaces. The quality of the thin films was monitored by contact angle goniometry, ellipsometry, XPS, FTIR-ATR and UV-Vis absorption spectroscopies. The deposition conditions were optimized to produce ordered and densely packed mono- and multilayers. Using the two-step process, self-assembled monolayers (SAMs) of a variety of long chain alcohols containing terminal alkyl, phenyl and acetylene groups on silica surfaces were successfully prepared. The newly formed monolayers were found to be relatively ordered and densely packed. They showed comparable stabilities to OTS/SiO 2 at ambient and high temperatures, and upon treatment with acids and bases. A layer-by-layer construction methodology, based on acid-base hydrolysis of aminosilanes and dihydroxy terminated molecules containing rigid-rod type and alkyldiacetylene backbones, led to multilayers with higher stability under various conditions compared to monolayers. The thin film assemblies were subjected to topochemical polymerization, and upon UV-Vis exposure, the formation of a blue film was observed. Using the acid-base hydrolytic chemistry approach, silica surfaces functionalized with Sn-NEt2 groups can be easily modified using a number of terminal alkyne molecules with varied backbones. SAMs of a variety of rigid-rod alkynes on silica surfaces were successfully prepared. The pi-pi interactions in the molecules lead to ordered and densely packed thin film structures with a surface coverage of 2--7 molecules/100 A 2. The thin film assembly with diacetylene backbone was also subjected to topochemical polymerization, and upon UV-Vis exposure, the formation of a blue film was observed. Furthermore, a layer-by-layer construction methodology using aminostannanes and dialkyne terminated molecules containing alkyl or aromatic type backbone led to multilayered structures on silica surfaces without increasing disorder in the thin films with the increase in number of layers. The acetylene groups in the thin film assemblies were found to coordinate with cobalt carbonyl, corroborated by the observation of lambdamax at 277 nm.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kakkar, Ashok K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj89m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q85g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mn999"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transformant system and gene expression of yeast Schwanniomyces occidentalis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Tsung-Tsan, 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Schwanniomyces occidentalis (Debaryomyces occidentalis ) is able to grow rapidly with high cell mass on cheap starch as a carbon source, produce strong amylolytic enzymes extracellularly and secrete large proteins without hyper-glycosylation and measurable extracellular proteases. Schw. occidentalis thus has a high potential as, a useful alternative to Saccharomyces cerevisiae in the production of heterologous proteins. However, the molecular study of Schw. occidentalis has been very limited due to the insufficient transformation system and lack of gene expression information. A new transformation system of Schw. occidentalis has been developed. This system was based on vector YEp13 ( LEU2) and a stable leu auxotrophic mutant, Schw. occidentalis DW88, obtained by treating the yeast with 1-methyl-3-nitro-1-nitrosoguanidine. The transformation efficiency of YEp13 by spheroplast-mediating method was 103 transformants/mug DNA. The 2-mum replicon is proposed to be responsible for YEp13 replication in Schw. occidentalis. The YEp13 stability in Schw. occidentalis was low, but it kept its structure in the yeast, suggesting that Schw. occidentalis DW88 does not modify foreign DNA. After analysis of 14 cloned Schw. occidentalis genes and comparison of associated genes from both Schw. occidentalis and S. cerevisiae, 25 codons were arbitrarily chosen as putative preferred codons for Schw. occidentalis. They are similar to those of S. cerevisiae, except for TTA for leucine, and AAA for lysine. Codon Bias Index (CBI), a criterion to evaluate gene expression, is calculated from preferred codons. A computer program (PCBI) which reads a gene containing introns was developed to quickly calculate CBI. Schw. occidentalis DWSS should be a good host to produce and secrete heterologous proteins and the putative preferred codons and program PCBI can facilitate molecular study of Schw. occidentalis. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lee, Byong H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r946n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn999</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant genetic transformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schwanniomyces occidentalis -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b5033"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mental content in a physical world : an alternative to mentalese</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Viger, Christopher David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In an attempt to show how rational explanation of human and animal behaviour has a place in the scientific explanation of our physical world, Fodor advances the language of thought hypothesis. The purpose of this dissertation is to argue that, contrary to the language of thought hypothesis, we need not possess a linguistic internal representational system distinct from any natural language to serve as the medium of thinking. I accept that we have an internal representational system, but by analyzing Fodor's theory of content, I show Fodor's argument that the internal system must be as expressive as any natural language, which he uses in arguing that the internal system is the linguistic medium of thought, is unsound. Distinguishing an informational theory of content from a causal theory of content, which Fodor conflates, I argue that internal representations, whose content is determined by information they carry, cannot be related in a way that corresponds to semantic associations between terms in natural languages, reflecting actual associations of items in the world. Furthermore, provided certain animal cognition, which is homogeneous with human cognition, can be explained without requiring that the internal system possess anything corresponding to the logical connectives, the internal system need not possess anything corresponding to the logical connectives. I give such an explanation of animal cognition by developing an approach to content in the Rylean/Dennettian tradition, based on the notion of embodied cognition, in which animals embody the hypotheses they entertain in virtue of their total dispositional state, rather than explicitly representing them. It follows that there are two features of natural languages, semantic associations of terms and possessing logical connectives, that the internal system need not have. Hence a rational interpretation of linguistic behaviour need not be derived from an intentional interpretation of the transformations on int</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Davies, David</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pietroski, Paul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698919d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b5033</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Thought and thinking</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language and languages -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cognition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892c54w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of airborne flux measurements of heat, moisture and carbon dioxide, and their correlation with land cover types in BOREAS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ogunjemiyo, Segun Ojo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The landscape of the boreal forest in north-central Canada is characterised by mosaics of broad-leaved deciduous trees (aspen, Populus; birch, Betula), evergreen conifers (black spruce, Picea mariana; jack pine, Pinus banksiana; and larch, Larix), fens and lakes. The forest has been cited as the possible location of a global carbon sink, and its likely response in the event of global climate change remains unclear. To improve our current understanding of the links between the boreal forest ecosystem and the lower atmosphere, the Boreal Ecosystem-Atmosphere Study (BOREAS) was executed in a series of field experiments in 1994 and 1996. This thesis documents the efforts made to characterise and map temporal and spatial distributions of the fluxes of heat, water vapour and CO2 over two 16 km x 16 km heterogeneous sites at the BOREAS study sites. Most of the data in this thesis were obtained from the airborne observations by the Canadian Twin Otter Aircraft, operated by the Institute for Aerospace Research of the Canadian National Research Council, at the BOREAS Northern Study Area (NSA), and Southern Study Area (SSA). The research aircraft was flown at a fixed altitude of about 30 m agl. The data acquired in 1994 were primarily used to develop an objective deterending scheme in eddy-correlation flux estimates, that took into consideration the physical nature of turbulent transport during convective daytime conditions, and to map the spatial distribution of sensible heat, latent heat and CO2 fluxes over three intensive field campaigns. Maps of spatial patterns of the surface characteristics, such as the surface temperature excess over air temperature (Ts-T a) and Greenness index (GI), were also constructed. The mapping procedure involved generation of an array of grid points by block averaging the parameter of interests along the flight lines, spaced 2 km apart, over 2 km windows, with 1 km overlap between adjacent windows. The (Ts-Ta) maps showed, not surprisingly, that surface temperatures were relatively cooler over the mature forests than over the disturbed, regenerating and burn areas. However, they also showed a decoupling between sensible heat flux and T s-Ta not seen in less complex terrain. By contrast, close correspondence was observed between maps of CO2 flux and greenness, suggesting that the potential to infer CO2 exchange from remote sensing observations of the surface is higher than that for energy exchange. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r56m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c54w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Eddy flux</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atmospheric carbon dioxide -- Saskatchewan -- Prince Albert Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atmospheric carbon dioxide -- Manitoba -- Thompson Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taigas -- Saskatchewan -- Prince Albert Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taigas -- Manitoba -- Thompson Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water vapor transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atmosphere -- Latent heat release</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zz25v"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interactions between polyomavirus large T antigen and the viral replication origin DNA : how and why</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peng, Yu-Cai, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Polyomavirus large T antigen is the major regulatory protein in the polyomavirus life cycle. It binds to multiple G(A/G)GGC pentanucleotide sequences in sites 1/2, A, B, and C within and adjacent to the origin of viral DNA replication on the polyomavirus genome. The nature of interactions between large T antigen and the viral origin of DNA replication is not fully understood. We set out to produce large T antigen protein in the methylotropic yeast Pichia pastoris by placing the large T antigen gene downstream of the strong alcohol oxidase (AOX1) promoter. Large T antigen was purified by immuno-affinity chromatography by using a monoclonal antibody. While optimizing the conditions for binding of large T antigen to viral origin DNA, we discovered that binding was substantially stronger at pH 6 to 7 than at pH 7.4 to 7.8, a range often used in DNA binding assays. We showed that increased binding at low pH is due to increased stability of protein-DNA complexes, and that large T antigen molecules self-associated at low pH, forming massive complexes. ATP increased binding of large T antigen to origin DNA by about 2-fold at pH 7.8, but had no detectable effect at pH 7 or below. Enhanced, stable DNA binding by large T antigen to viral origin DNA at pH 6 enabled us to develop a novel gel mobility shift assay using unfixed protein-DNA complexes. We demonstrated that this assay is very sensitive and highly specific. This method can be used both for detection of large T antigen in crude cell lysates and for quantitation of binding of purified large T antigen to target DNAs under various conditions. Using a series of point and deletion mutants in the viral origin of DNA replication, we demonstrated that binding of large T antigen to sites 1/2, A, B, and C is cooperative. Binding of large T antigen to one site stimulated binding to other sites 20 to 100 bp distant, and binding to inherently weak sites was strengthened if two or more such sites were present on the same DNA molecule. These findings suggest that large T antigen molecules bound to DNA interact with each other to mutually stabilise their binding. ATP was shown to stabilise large T antigen-DNA complexes against dissociation only if the DNA contained site 1/2. ATP specifically enhanced protection against DNase I digestion in the central 10 to 12 bp of site 1/2, where hexamers are believed to form and begin unwinding DNA. We propose a model in which large T antigen molecules bound to sites 1/2, A, B, and C on origin DNA form a compact protein-DNA complex via mutual interactions; large T antigen molecules bound to sites A, B, and C are mobilised and "handed over" to site 1/2, where ATP stimulates their assembly into hexamers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Acheson, Nicholas H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/736666251.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz25v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752j500"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Numerical studies of Ising models defined on a random lattice as applied to the phase behaviour of lipid bilayer systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nielsen, Morten</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We examine complex fluid systems where both translational and conformational degrees of freedom are present and focus on systems in which the interplay between the two sets of degrees of freedom is manifested in the macroscopic phase behaviour. We develop an efficient random lattice algorithm describing the translational degrees of freedom and analyze a series of microscopic models defined on a two dimensional fluid surface. Different degrees of complexity in the description of the microscopic coupling between the translational and conformational degrees of freedom allow us to study a variety of models related to pure lipid membrane and lipid-sterol membrane systems. The phase equilibrium described by the models is calculated by use of Monte Carlo simulation techniques. The different models are shown to exhibit a rich phase behaviour. Depending on the specific model parameters, the phase transition associated with the conformational degrees of freedom is found to be either coupled to, or uncoupled from, that associated with the conformational degrees of freedom. Specifically, the order-disorder transition of an Ising model defined on a fluid surface is shown to be of first order, when the two sets of degrees of freedom are strongly coupled. In contrast, the transition falls in the universality class of the two-dimensional Ising model when the two sets of degrees of freedom are weakly coupled. We next analyze a model for pure lipid bilayers which is shown to exhibit a phase behaviour with different types of macroscopic coupling between the two sets of degrees of freedom. Depending on the strength of the microscopic interactions the lipid chain melting transition and the lattice melting transition may be either macroscopically coupled or uncoupled. A related model for lipid-sterol mixtures is shown to provide a consistent interpretation of the various phases of lipid-cholesterol and lipid-lanosterol binary mixtures based on the microscopic dual action of the sterol molecule on the lipid-chain degrees of freedom. We discuss the results for the systems in the context of membrane evolution and suggest that evolution has tended to optimize the lipid-sterol interaction so as to stabilize optimally the mechanical properties of the membrane. Furthermore, a specific small-scale structure is identified and characterized in the liquid-ordered phase in lipid-cholesterol mixtures. This structure is found to be absent in lipid-lanosterol mixtures. Finally, a model for membrane lysis gives evidence for the high mechanical stabilizing effect of cholesterol on the membrane. The inclusion of cholesterol is shown to inhibit lysis whereas lanosterol only has little stabilizing effect.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zuckermann, Martin J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558f92d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j500</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn72n"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of fatty acid chain length on energy metabolism in healthy women</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Papamandjaris, Andrea A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of fatty acids on energy metabolism has been shown to be dependent on their acyl structure. In humans, following short term feeding, medium chain triglycerides (MCT) have been shown to increase the thermic effect of food and fat oxidation as compared to long chain triglycerides (LCT). Short term results in animals have been comparable. In longer term, animal studies, MCT vs. LCT have resulted in less weight gain during overfeeding or refeeding after weight loss. However, observations of the longer term effects of MCT in humans beyond 7 days are sparse and inconclusive. Hence, the objective of the thesis was to examine the effects of MCT vs. LCT on total energy expenditure, its components basal metabolic rate and thermic effect of food, and on substrate oxidation, including both exogenous and endogenous fat oxidation for a period of one week, following one week of prefeeding. Twelve healthy college aged women were fed eucaloric 14 days diets enriched with either MCT or LCT in a randomized cross over design, with a two week washout period. Doubly labelled water, respiratory gas exchange analysis, and 1-13C labelled myristic, palmitic, and stearic acids were used to measure total energy expenditure, components of energy expenditure, and endogenous long chain fatty acid oxidation, respectively. The presence of MCT in the diet significantly increased endogenous oxidation of labelled long chain fatty acids following 14 days of feeding, while the presence of LCT did not. Respiratory gas exchange analysis showed significantly increased basal metabolic rate on day 7 of MCT vs. LCT feeding, but this effect of diet was reduced to a trend by day 14. Dietary treatment did not result in significant differences in total energy expenditure during the second week of feeding. These results suggest that, after two weeks of feeding, MCT continue to affect energy metabolism through increased endogenous fat oxidation and a suggestion of heightened basal metabolic rate, but</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jones, Peter J. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt74d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn72n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fatty acids -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fatty acids -- Physiological effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bw24q"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Production and characterization of bioactive peptides from soy fermented foods and their hydrolysates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gibbs, Bernard F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Biologically active peptides are found in the amino acid sequence of bacterial, fungal, plant and animal proteins. They are among the most potent pharmacologically active agents. Examples are venom toxin (mellitin), hormones (oxytoxin), opioids (beta-endorphin) and enzyme inhibitors (hirudin). These bioactive peptides are released from proteins by enzymatic proteolysis by processes such as gastrointestinal digestion or food processing. Soybeans were fermented with Bacillus subtilis ATCC 41332 and Rhizopus oligosporus NRRL 2710 to produce tempeh and natto, respectively. Samples were taken throughout the fermentation and analysed for biochemical changes. Protease activity and ammonia production detected in the early stage of the tempeh preparation suggested that protein was used as a carbon source during that period and contributed to a rise in pH. Bacillus subtilis did not produce ammonia and maintained a constant pH throughout the fermentation. The total peptides produced were at a maximum at the end of the fermentation cycles. Angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitory activity increased throughout both fermentations. A method was developed to monitor the production of biogenic amines throughout the fermentation. The levels of biogenic amines increased dramatically as the fermentation proceeded until maturity was achieved. In the tempeh fermentation, the polyamines levels rose from the initial 19 ppm to final concentration of 862 ppm, with the largest increase in histamine (616 ppm) followed by putrescine (204 ppm). These compounds also contributed to the pH rise from 3.8 to 6.8 in 24 h. In the Bacillus fermentation, the total polyamines at the end of the fermentation was 110 ppm with the largest increase in putrescine, followed by cadaverine. Soy hydrolysate and the soy fermented foods, natto and tempeh, were deglycosylated and treated with proteolytic enzymes (plasma proteases, kidney homogenate, pronase, pepsin, thermolysin, trypsin, chymotrypsin and proteinase K) to produce oligopeptides. Several peptides were isolated, purified and characterized. The peptides had a range of biological activities---angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitory, antithrombotic, surface tension, antibacterial, anti-oxidant and insulin-modulating activities. Three potent ACE inhibitors, three thrombin inhibitors, five peptides with surface-active properties and one peptide with antibacterial activity were identified. They were all derived from glycinin and were found in the plasma protease digest, the kidney homogenate digest and the pronase digest of fermented foods. Another sequence ELLVYLL possessed good surface active properties but its precursor could not be identified. However, it was analogous to a peptide produced by Bacillus subtilis , and was probably synthesized during fermentation. Peptide analogs were synthesized and evaluated. They showed similar activities. Other sequences of known inhibitors, TPKDFEEIPEE, FPRGGG and DFEEIPEEL, were found to be competitive substrates for ACE.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alli, I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p24r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw24q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fermented soyfoods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peptides -- Separation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827d382"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimal discretization-based adaptive finite element analysis for electromagnetics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Giannacopoulos, Dennis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the primary objectives of adaptive finite element analysis research is to determine how to effectively discretize a problem in order to obtain a sufficiently accurate solution efficiently. Consequently, a major research issue in adaptive finite element analysis is the feedback control system used to guide the adaption; essentially, one needs to resolve which error data to feed back after each iteration, and how to use it to initialize the next adaptive step. Currently, there exists substantial evidence suggesting that the optimality of a finite element discretization plays a significant role in the accuracy of computed solutions at given levels of problem refinement. Therefore, in order to exploit the potential benefits in adaptive finite element methods, the characterization of optimal finite element discretizations has been investigated extensively. However, valid criteria for characterizing optimal finite element discretizations for a sufficiently wide range of problem applications have not been reported. A theoretical formulation for the numerical study of optimal finite element solutions to partial differential equations of macroscopic electromagnetics is presented. The formulation is based on variational aspects of optimal discretizations for Helmholtz systems that are closely related to the underlying stationarity principle used in computing finite element solutions to continuum problems. The optimal characteristics of approximate finite element solutions, as predicted by the theory and observed numerically, have been employed to develop new optimal discretization-based feedback refinement criteria for use with advanced strategy adaption models in finite element electromagnetics. Numerical tests indicate that they are effective and economical for efficiently and reliably guiding practical h-, p- and hp-type adaption models towards accurate solutions. In addition, a series of important benchmark adaption problems are introduced to examine the validity of the theoretical concepts and the practical value of the new refinement criteria. Moreover, many of the computational and theoretical difficulties inherent in the currently available characterizations of optimal finite element discretizations are explained and illustrated with numerical results computed for the same benchmark problems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McFee, J. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x42s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d382</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>