<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fm21j"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Matthew : Jewish Christian or gentile Christian?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pettem, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation addresses the problem of whether the Gospel of Matthew reflects a Jewish Christian or gentile Christian stance within the early church. A study of the principal theories of the evolution of the early church provides the background against which the terms "Jewish Christian" and "gentile Christian" may be understood. The dissertation examines the bases on which Matthew has been classified as either Jewish Christian or gentile Christian. This previous work on Matthew is found to be unsatisfactory because of the lack of adequate criteria for classifying Matthew. A study of Acts and the letters of Paul reveals that the practice or rejection of Jewish dietary purity was a cause of division in the early church, and thus constitutes a suitable criterion for distinguishing between Jewish and gentile Christianity. Examination of Mt 15:1-20 shows that Matthew does not accept Jewish dietary purity as a part of God's will. Matthew thus reflects a gentile Christian position.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb55p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm21j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gentiles in the New Testament</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jewish Christians -- Christianity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Christianity and other religions -- Judaism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b416z"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A remote sensing-microclimatic study for estimating regional evapotranspiration fom [i.e. from] tea (Camellia sinensis) at Kericho, Kenya</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kairu, E. N. (Edward Nganga)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study has demonstrated that for tea canopies, thematic mapper data (Landsat 5 short wave and thermal infrared bands) can be used to produce regional estimates of important surface parameters like albedo, surface temperature, net radiation and instantaneous evapotranspiration. The study has also shown that the TERGRA model can be successfully used to convert instantaneous evapotranspiration to daily evapotranspiration for tea canopies. At Kericho, the combination of remotely sensed data and TERGRA model produced point daily evapotranspiration estimates that differed from ground-based estimates (Penman and Bowen ratio energy balance methods) by up to 7%. For field #12, the range of evapotranspiration estimates (0.3 mm/day, by use of the Bowen ratio, Penman and remote sensing methods) was much smaller than the spatial variability of evapotranspiration throughout the study area (2-5 mm/day) as estimated by the remote sensing technique. When a large number of pixel values is used to estimate regional evapotranspiration, the standard error of the estimate approaches zero. Consequently, mean aerial evapotranspiration can be estimated to a better accuracy than would be possible with point based models. The study also showed that regression analysis (whereby evapotranspiration was predicted by use of remotely sensed canopy temperature) could be used to estimate regional evapotranspiration. Finally, for the specific situation at Kericho, advection was found to be virtually non-existent over mature tea canopies.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb577.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b416z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tea -- Kenya -- Kericho</dc:subject><dc:subject>Evapotranspiration -- Kenya -- Kericho</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xf93z"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Flow and heat transfer phenomena in aerated vibrated beds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eccles, Errol R. A. (Errol Ray Antonio)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Flow characteristics including resonance phenomena, bubble phenomena, particle circulation and mixing patterns as well as surface-to-bed heat transfer in aerated vibrated beds were studied experimentally. Beds of various model particles were vibrated in the vertical direction with a frequency varying from 0-25 Hz and half-amplitude from 0-4 mm. Alumina, glass beads and molecular sieve particles of sizes ranging from 6 $ mu$m to 3600 $ mu$m were used as the model particles. Air flow rates through holes in the bottom plates varied from 0 to 4 times the minimum fluidizing velocity with one, five or a multiplicity of holes. The resonance phenomenon was characterized by a sudden bed expansion and intense surface agitation; this phenomenon was generally observed only in beds of small particles (d$ sb{ rm p}$ $&lt;$ 250 $ mu$m). Bubble sizes increased while the bubble rise velocities decreased with increasing vibration frequency. An analytical model was developed to predict the resonant frequency assuming that the aerated vibrated bed behaves as a porous piston undergoing reciprocating motion at the applied frequency. Contact heat transfer between an immersed circular cylinder and the vibrated bed was found to be a function of particle circulation which, in turn, depends on the vibration parameters. Particle circulation is maximal at the point at which the bed displayed resonant behaviour. The cylinder-to-bed heat transfer coefficient is also maximal at resonance. A correlation is proposed for the surface-to-bed heat transfer based on these features.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848r347.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xf93z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r967442t"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A crisis of metanarratives : realism and innovation in the contemporary English novel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gasiorek, Andrew B. P. (Andrew Boguslaw Peter)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Critics of the English novel, arguing that it is underpinned by liberalism, frequently claim that the crisis of realism disclosed in the work of many contemporary writers derives from a concomitant crisis of liberalism. Liberalism's dissolution is thus seen to prefigure the death of the novel. This dissertation contends that realism cannot be equated with liberalism and that the contemporary crisis of representation signals a broader crisis of metanarratives. Focussing on selected novels of five post-war English novelists--B. S. Johnson, Doris Lessing, John Berger, Iris Murdoch, and Angus Wilson--I argue that their different responses to the crisis of representation show that it is not a crisis of liberalism alone. Johnson rejects realism for epistemological reasons; Lessing and Berger question it on political grounds; Murdoch and Wilson combine its strengths with a self-reflexive awareness of its weaknesses. I suggest that Murdoch's and Wilson's novels, which argue that fiction does not reflect reality but endows it with meaning and which are at once representational and metafictional, offer the most fruitful ways of acknowledging the crisis of representation while refusing to be paralyzed by it.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g581k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967442t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Realism in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h5148"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>State-society relations and the design and implementation of public policy : an application of the state-centered paradigm to a case study of the National Energy Program</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gallagher, Stephen J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to analyze the relative influence of state and societal actors on public policy and, specifically, to determine the potential for state autonomy in Canada. To advance this project, two 'paradigms' of state-society relations are developed from an analysis of a range of contending theories of state-society relations. These include Eric Nordlinger's state autonomy theory, elitism, pluralism, and Marxism. The paradigms are then applied to a case study of the design and implementation of the petroleum related elements of the National Energy Program. We conclude that the Canadian state can demonstrate a significant degree of autonomy from societal influence using various strategies and resources which are generally unavailable to societal actors. The specific findings of our case study are that in the development and implementation of the NEP the greatest impediments on the federal government's autonomy arose, not from business interests or public pressure, but from the opposition of other state actors and the impact of market forces and international economic conditions.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333293v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h5148</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political planning -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy policy -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Industrial policy -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wg66p"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Normed double algebras, local and global optimization, and slow H00 adaptation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Le Yi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A normed space of input-output mappings equipped with two products, one global and the other local, called a normed double algebra (NDA), is introduced for the frozen-time analysis of stabilization and optimization of a class of slowly time-varying systems. Local-global relations within a normed double algebra are established, in the time and frequency domains, in systems which vary slowly. The local-global relations, applied to system properties such as stability, coprime factorization and optimization, enable global properties to be deduced from the local ones, especially in the frequency domain, by methods which are computationally tractable, at least in principle. Classical frozen-time stability is reinterpreted in terms of a relation between local and global resolvents in the NDA. Relations between local and global coprime factorizations and their implications to local and global robust stability are obtained. An explicit double algebraic expression for adaptive BIBO sensitivity reduction is established. Notions of adaptive and robust (non-adaptive) sensitivity minimization are applied to an example involving rejection of narrowband disturbances of uncertain bandwidth and center frequency. The double algebra symbolism is employed to show that adaptive minimization can give better sensitivity than $H sp infty$ optimal robust minimization. To implement a design strategy of global sensitivity optimization using local $H sp infty$ interpolation, Lipschitz continuity of optimal $H sp infty$ interpolants on data is investigated. While optimal $H sp infty$ interpolants in general do not depend Lipschitz continuously on data, $ delta$-suboptimal interpolants based on AAK's maximal entropy solutions satisfy an appropriate Lipschitz continuity condition. These, applied to slowly time-varying systems, achieve approximations to the globally optimal interpolants, which become accurate as the rates of variation approach zero.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr63t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wg66p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430548w"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biological factors governing infection by HIV-1 of T cells and EBV- carrying B cells : (infection par le VIH-1 de lymphocytes T et de lymphocytes B transformes par EBV: caracteristiques biologiques)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tremblay, Michel, 1955-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The potential relationship between the Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV) and the Human Immunodeficiency Virus type 1 (HIV-1) in lines of EBV-carrying B cells that had been super-infected by HIV-1 was investigated. We found that such cells can produce high levels of viral particles, over long periods, with a minimal cytopathic effect and were less susceptible to HIV-1 infection than primary cultures of human peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC). We also investigated whether an alternative receptor, other than the well-known CD4 receptor, could permit HIV-1 infection of B cells immortalized by EBV. We detected a mechanism of complement-mediated antibody-dependent enhancement of HIV-1 infection in these cells implicating the CD4 receptor, the complement receptor type 2, and the alternate pathway of complement. The fact that AZT is actually the most widely used drug in treating HIV-1 infections prompted us to investigate the ability of AZT to prevent infection and replication of HIV-1 in EBV-positive B cells. Three concentrations of AZT (1, 5 and 10 $ mu$M) prevented infection by one clinical isolate (334). In contrast, no such inhibitory effect was observed with each of a second clinical isolate (336) or with the HIV-III$ sb{ rm B}$ laboratory strain of HIV-1. Nevertheless, in these two particular cases, AZT significantly delayed and attenuated viral expression. Finally, we determined that exposure of PBMC from HIV-1-infected individuals to preparations of HSV-1, HSV-2, or CMV stimulated the cells to become active producers of HIV-1 and point to a possible role for these viruses as co-factors in the pathogenesis of AIDS.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk30p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430548w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010q811"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Erosion of plasma torch electrodes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Szente, Roberto Nunes</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The erosion of copper electrodes in a concentric cylinder geometry with magnetically driven arcs was studied at steady state for currents up to 250 A in a variety of gases and gas mixtures, magnetic field strengths and gas flow rates. The effects of arc velocity, gas composition, current density and heat transfer to the cathode on erosion rates were examined. The arc velocity varied with the magnetic field strength and arc current accordingly to a newly developed equation, V $ alpha$ B$ sp{0.60}$ I$ sp{0.56}$, when the cathode surface was slightly contaminated with C, Cl, O or N. The composition of the surfaces was found using Auger and ESCA spectroscopy. A surface drag force, a new force opposing to the arc motion was proposed. In the case of clean and heavily contaminated surfaces (contaminant layers thicker than 10 microns), the surface drag becomes the major force opposing the arc movement. Work function measurements showed that surface drag increased as electron emission became more difficult. A novel technique was developed to determine the current distribution of the arc foot on the electrodes. A correlation between the arc foot current density and erosion rate was proposed. The effects of the surface composition, magnetic field and arc velocity on the arc current distribution were also examined. A conceptual model was developed for electrode erosion; the model was supported by experimental results and by the results of simulations using macroscopic and microscopic heat transfer models.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g59c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010q811</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290b20p"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolic derangements following bone marrow transplantation : an integrated analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taveroff, Arlene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bone marrow transplantation (BMT) involves the use of maximal doses of chemotherapy and total body irradiation. As a result, even well-nourished patients exhibit negative nitrogen balance and hypoproteinemia in the post-transplant period, despite a high energy and protein intake from Total Parenteral Nutrition (TPN). The purpose of this research was to investigate the impact of cytotoxic therapy, with a view toward explaining and improving the response to nutritional support. Stool, urine and serum biochemistry were studied prospectively in 10 BMT patients. Analysis of stool revealed increased sodium and decreased potassium. Examination of serum electrolytes indicated hyponatremia and hyperkalemia. A significant decrease in nitrogen balance, serum albumin and net protein utilization immediately followed the disturbances in serum electrolytes; improvement began as serum sodium and potassium returned to normal. Thus, electrolyte imbalance may have reduced the capacity of cells to utilize nitrogen. Lowering the volume of TPN dramatically decreased serum electrolyte aberrations and improved nitrogen utilization.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s20s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b20p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Parenteral feeding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cancer -- Chemotherapy -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bone marrow -- Transplantation -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515p10s"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The local structure of image intensity discontinuities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leclerc, Yvan G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We present two solutions to a critical problem in computer vision: that of describing an image as the sum of an underlying piecewise-smooth image and spatially varying white noise. Both solutions employ the idea that simplicity and stability of description lead to important inferences about the processes that give rise to an image. The first solution uses a set of local operators, each hypothesizing a simplest description of the underlying image within its spatial domain by estimation-theoretical means. Hypotheses from overlapping operators are then combined to produce the simplest overall description. The second, and more powerful, solution uses an objective function based on the information-theoretic complexity of describing an image in a given language. This objective function is highly non-convex, so that standard optimization techniques cannot be used. Instead, a local, parallel, and iterative optimization algorithm is devised for finding near-optimal solutions. This algorithm is adaptive, requiring no change in parameters across a wide range of images, and has the added advantage of finding the most stable features of the simplest description first. Even though the language contains no models of three-dimensional shape, lighting, or texture, the simplest and most stable descriptions in this language are intuitively satisfying.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zr42t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515p10s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881m698"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the global properties of hadronic matter at large densities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lamarche, François, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We present a study of the properties of the nuclear matter under extreme conditions of density and temperature, using collisions of heavy-nuclei measured in the experiment NA34. The emphasis is given to the study of the variation of the properties of average central collisions with the sizes of the colliding nuclei. The projectiles used are 200 GeV protons, 60 and 200 GeV/nucleon $ sp{16}$O nuclei, and 200 GeV/nucleon $ sp{32}$S nuclei. The targets are thin disks of aluminium, copper, silver, tungsten, platinum, lead and uranium nuclei. The energy density achieved in these collisions, of the order of 10 GeV/fm$ sp3$, is a necessary (but not sufficient) condition to create a plasma of quarks and gluons. We investigate whether an hydrodynamic description is appropriate for our data, in which case, from the observation of the work done by the hydrodynamic forces, constraints are obtained on the properties of the hypothetical plasma.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp28c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m698</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405s9981"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Weak separation of sets</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Houle, Michael E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Consider the following fundamental problem: given two sets R and G of objects positioned in d-dimensional Euclidean space, does there exist a surface of some specific type which separates the objects of R from the objects of G? Much attention has been given to this problem, for many classes of objects and separating surfaces. However, very few satisfactory alternatives exist when the objects are not separable by any of the surfaces of the chosen class. In this thesis, a new combinatorial measure of separability is proposed, based on the largest subset of the objects in $R cup G$ that may be separated using surfaces drawn from a certain class. The combinatorial and algorithmic questions arising from this weak separation measure are the main focus of the thesis. The strong relationship between the separable subsets of point sets and faces of hyperplane arrangements is investigated, and a variety of algorithms are presented for finding linear and spherical separators for point sets and sets of hyperspheres.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d495t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s9981</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806049w"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the spectral synthesis property and its application to PDE</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guo, Kanghui</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let M be a k-dimensional manifold in $R sp{n}$. Using a new idea, we extend the known result of Y. Domar on the weak spectral synthesis property of M when k = n $-$ 1 by reducing the smoothness assumption upon M. For the case k $ leq$ n $-$ 2, the property is only proved for the curve in $R sp3$. We discuss the situation when M is a 2-dimensional quadratic manifold in $R sp4$ and the same result as in the ($n-1$)-dimensional case is proved. The interesting point of our method is its application to solving the uniqueness problem for some partial differential equations. Combining the Beurling-Pollard technique with our method, we can slightly improve Hormander's result for a class of elliptic equations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>ury, S. W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53ww52f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806049w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vp29n"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization by size exclusion chromatography of cationic polyelectrolyte degradation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Soponkanaporn, Teerapon</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859g41p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp29n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn009z569"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Insertional mutagenesis by provirus integration in Moloney murine leukemia virus-induced rat thymomas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Villeneuve, Luc</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085k91x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z569</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z6006"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Small scale farming and agricultural risks in the semi-arid areas of Jordan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hassani, Mohammed A.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq84r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z6006</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Farms -- Jordan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Agriculture -- Jordan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qs771"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of a new fracture toughness procedure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bernard, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf488.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs771</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j876x"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"The dayspring from on high hath visited us" : an examination of the missionary endeavours of the Moravians and the Anglican Church Missionary Society among the Inuit in the Arctic regions of Canada and Labrador, (1880s-1920s)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Davis, Davena, 1940-</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k7972.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j876x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Missions -- Arctic regions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Moravian Church -- Missions -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church Missionary Society -- Missions -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612p365"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kadomtsev-Petviashvili type differential systems : their symmetries and an application to solitary wave propagation in nonuniform channels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>David, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s76t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p365</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wave equations, Invariant</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wave-motion, Theory of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Differential equations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b681f"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the metabolism of gonadotropin (follitropin) and analogues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sebok, Karl, 1949-</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jp427.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b681f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n187k"><ual:graduationDate>1985</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vers une semantique representationnelle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Raccah, Pierre-Yves</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dn07b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n187k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pragmatics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semantics -- Methodology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hg185"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression differentielle du produit du gene 'src' dans les tumeurs induites par le virus de sarcome aviaire = Differential expression of the 'src' gene product in tumor cells induced by avian sarcoma virus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poulin, Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0967780.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg185</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bird Diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neoplasm Circulating Cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sarcoma</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tumor Cells, Cultured</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn009z57k"><ual:graduationDate>1986</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Liquid and solid sample introduction into the inductively coupled plasma by direct sample insertion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sing, Robert L. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz04h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z57k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atomic spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasma spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasma (Ionized gases)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sd416"><ual:graduationDate>1986</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of the teratogenicity of acrolein in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Slott, Valerie L.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z855x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sd416</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fs04c"><ual:graduationDate>1986</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Invariant distributions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vu, Tuan T.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds80n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fs04c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Invariants</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>