<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fh720"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Légitimité et autonomie des principes d'UNIDROIT relatifs aux contrats du commerce international</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mercedat, Ralph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyses three issues raised by the application of  the general principles of law to commercial arbitration. First, it is essential to  assess the core and the substance of the general principles of law. Our first  hypothesis purports that the UPICC reduces considerably the uncertainty of the  general principles of law in international trade. Secondly, an analysis of the  nature of the UPICC is needed, in order to determine whether they have the essential  features of a transnational norm and can thus escape the application of national  legal norms. We will thus analyse the existing mechanisms to assure the autonomy, of  PUCCI, from national law. Thirdly, we will analyse the legitimacy of the UPICC. In  doing so, we shall refer to the concept of reflexive legimitacy, a legitimacy  obtained through the consensus of the merchant community. This reflexive legitimacy  over the UPICC is generally admitted. Two rules within the UPICC, however, raise  doubts and concerns over their acceptability in the merchants' community: the  hardship and the gross disparity provisions. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gelinas, Fabien</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526c89s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh720</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International Institute for the Unification of Private Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Contracts (International law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>International trade</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arbitration and award, International</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r622q"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) : the engine of Canada's economy : the legal framework of three sensitive spheres for SMES' growth : financing, taxation and international trade</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Olivieri, Javier Alejandro</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is widely believed that small and medium-sized enterprises  ("SMEs"), acting as a source of innovation and job creation, play a key  role in the economy of Canada. The legal framework which regulates SMEs' activities is vast.  This thesis focuses on the legal framework and most important aspects of three  critical areas: financing, taxation and international trade. After describing and interpreting the legal framework of these  areas and the information obtained from public and private institutions which are  considered key in these issues, this thesis presents conclusions in relation to the  question of how and in what way, if any, the current legislative and regulatory  framework relating to SMEs contributes to the growth and prosperity of SMEs and to  the importance of such a framework to SMEs' success and growth.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Walsh, Catherine</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q698h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r622q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Foreign trade regulation -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taxation -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Small business -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Business enterprises -- Canada -- Finance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Business law -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v367r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Going private with public concern : a comparative study of going private techniques under Canadian and German law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kreymborg, Dorothea</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is the objective of this comparative thesis to analyze how  Canadian and German legislators have addressed the compromise between minority  shareholder protection and flexibility in the regulation of going private  transactions. The structure of this study follows the distinction between indirect  and direct-methods that are available to a controlling shareholder who sets out to  eliminate minority shareholder participations in order to become the exclusive  shareholder of a corporation. In fact, both jurisdictions under consideration  provide for a complex regime of corporate and securities law to govern going private  transactions. The interplay of corporate and securities law produces a typical  regulatory conflict between the goals of shareholders as opposed to investor  protection on the one hand, and the purpose of a flexible corporate law regime and  efficient capital markets regulation on the other hand. This comparative analysis  evidences the respective advantages and disadvantages of the Canadian and German  regimes and provides for regulatory prescriptions that result from the  comparison.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, Lionel D.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x12d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v367r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Minority stockholders -- Germany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corporation law -- Germany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Going private (Securities) -- Germany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corporation law -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Minority stockholders -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Going private (Securities) -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021f812"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic information and the family : a challenge to medical confidentiality</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lacroix, Mireille, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Because of its perceived ability to predict future health and  its relevance for family members, genetic information challenges the traditional  justifications for medical confidentiality. This thesis examines the question  whether a health care professional should have the discretion or a duty to breach  confidentiality in order to inform a patient's relatives of their increased genetic  risk. There is currently no exception to the statutory, common law and ethical  duties of confidentiality for the non-consensual disclosure of genetic information  to relatives. Precedents developed in the context of threats of harm and  communicable diseases are of limited value. The law should not recognise the  existence of a duty to warn in the context of genetics. As a last resort, health  care professionals should be authorized, but not required, to disclose genetic risk  information when there is a serious risk of preventable harm and when the potential  harm of non-disclosure outweighs that of disclosure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Glass, Kathleen Cranley</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm24n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021f812</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Confidential communications -- Physicians</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human chromosome abnormalities -- Diagnosis -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623d19j"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Legal aspects of aviation risk management</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leloudas, Georgios</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis in the first part examines the notion of risk and  describes the process of risk management with emphasis on the identification of  emerging threats to civil aviation and on the adoption of new risk handling  techniques. In the second part, the role of law into the airlines'  management regime is examined especially in the light of two prima facie conflicting  trends: liberalization of market access and increased State involvement in war risk,  safety and security issues. Furthermore, the contractual and tortious/delictual  exposures of airlines are being scrutinized and the ways to handle them are being  analyzed. The main objectives are (i) to demonstrate that risk management  is not restricted to insurance, but involves a number of techniques and procedures  that have the potential not only to minimize risk but also to turn risk into  opportunity and value and (ii) to identify the role of law as a management tool in  the oncoming liberalized aviation environment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225b601.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d19j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Security measures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Risk management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859g23r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le droit et les cartels internationaux</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Le More, Pauline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis aims to underline the paradox surrounding cartels in  general and international cartels in particular. While they are almost unanimously  recognised as the most egregious form of antitrust violations, real political  willingness fails to fight efficiently against cartels. Notwithstanding, this paper  shows why international cooperation is essential but still unsatisfactory in  eliminating international cartels through concrete examples in domestic laws, such  as the Fine Arts Auctions Case and export cartel configurations. Existing national  and international instruments present advantages and disadvantages. International  competition law, including international cartel issues, is still subject to virulent  debates within the international community, particularly with respect to the future  of a WTO Multilateral Agreement. It raises the question as to what can be suggested  in order to solve aspects of these debates in a satisfactory manner and thereby  contribute---modestly---to ameliorate the fight against international  cartels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, Richard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd549.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859g23r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Antitrust law (International law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antitrust law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trusts</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cartels</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n3987"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Premenstrual syndrome as a substantive criminal defence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gore, Sally, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is now over twenty years since the criminal trials of two  women caught the attention of the British media. Sandra Craddock (later Smith) and  Christine English both raised a successful defence of diminished responsibility  based on premenstrual syndrome to a murder charge. In these cases the Court of  Appeal apparently determined that PMS is a factor that can limit criminal  responsibility. Although this thesis concentrates on the situation as it exists in  English law, many of its conclusions are equally relevant to other legal systems,  particularly those in common law jurisdictions. The issues that are likely to arise in a criminal trial in which  a defendant wishes to base a substantive defence on premenstrual syndrome can be  condensed into five central questions: (i) Does premenstrual syndrome exist at all?  (ii) If so, does the defendant suffer from the condition? (iii) Did PMS cause or  contribute to the defendant's actions? (iv) If the answer to (iii) is yes, should  the act be excused? (v) If so, under what category of excuse? This thesis will  discuss the way in which these questions might best be approached. (Abstract  shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sklar, Ronald</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qq14x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n3987</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Premenstrual syndrome -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Defense (Criminal procedure)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719m97j"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of the General Agreement on Trade in Services on Jamaica</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grant, Lisa L. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper examines the impact of the General Agreement on Trade  in Services (GATS), an agreement under the World Trade Organization (WTO) on  Jamaica. In its analysis, it considers both the island's existing and former foreign  trade policy, as well as the progressive trade liberalization being undertaken  within the Caribbean Single Market and Economy under CARICOM and its regionally  devised policy initiatives. Having followed a fairly liberal path in its trade relations  since 1991, the provisions in domestic law which accommodate or hinder  liberalization are referred to. Negotiation strategies for future rounds of the GATS  are another important aspect of the thesis. This closely follows the schedule of  commitments made under the GATS, taking into account recent instances of autonomous  liberalization, including those taken in the telecommunications industry. Finally, a  critical look is taken at the dispute resolution process of the WTO to determine the  extent to which the trading interests of a developing microstate such as Jamaica are  protected by this system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>de Mestral, Armand</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547r99h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m97j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Jamaica -- Commercial policy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515n98q"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nouvelles perspectives pour le droit de l'espace = New prospects for space law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guillotte, Côme</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As it is standing now, space law is mostly a product of the Cold  War and, as such, a compromise between the capitalist and socialist ideologies. As a  result, it forms a separate block of international law obeying to original  principles. Space law is a reality based on several international treaties and some  practice but, no major international success in improving or expending the original  rules have been achieved for a while. This situation had driven certain to stress  that important matters remain underdeveloped and that some specific rules are  missing. In fact, the actual evolution of the world is rising the question of the  viability of the general principles presently governing outer space. In our opinion,  those unattended issues include the important growth of the commercial exploitation  of space in our globalisation context as well as the question---prompted by the  unilateral approach of certain States---of how and by whom Space should be  controlled or policed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jakhu, Ram</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc17c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n98q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mv711"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>fMRI responses to first- and second-order modulations of visual textures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mortin, Catherine Leanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The world around us contains a variety of visual information,  both first-order (luminance-defined) and second-order (defined by characteristics  other than luminance). Previous studies suggest that the human visual cortex employs  distinct mechanisms for segregating regions whose borders are defined by modulations  of first- and second-order properties. This study uses a new approach of human  psychophysics and fMRI experiments to explore the brain responses to both  first-order and second-order (orientation, spatial frequency and contrast) texture  borders. The results reveal differential activation among these modulations both in  known retinotopic areas and in higher occipital/parietal regions. Orientation  modulated textures elicit significantly different responses compared to modulations  of other properties; whereas spatial frequency and contrast modulated textures  produce similar responses. These findings suggest that higher visual cortical areas  are heavily involved in texture processing, with a functional dissociation between  segregating textures with modulations of (a) orientation, (b) spatial frequency or  contrast and (c) luminance.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hs463.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv711</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fh68d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of Ni-based electrocatalysts for hydrogen production in a PEM-type hydrogen generator</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Navarro Flores, Elisa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Results on the development of Ni-based electrocatalysts for  hydrogen evolution in an acidic medium are discussed in the thesis. This topic is of  a great importance for the development of a PEM-type hydrogen generator, as a global  initiative for the development of clean sustainable energy systems. A number of  experimental techniques were used in research: linear dc polarization (Tafel),  electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), potential-decay, inductively coupled  plasma (ICP), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The  first part of the thesis discusses the results on the influence of alloying nickel  by left-hand side transition metals (Fe, Mo, W) on the electrocatalytic activity in  hydrogen evolution, while the second part of the thesis discusses the results on the  development of Ni electrocatalysts using conductive polymers, polypyrrole (PPY) and  polyaniline (PANT) as catalysts pattering matrices. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505103x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh68d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zb641"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimal design of a lightweight robotic manipulator using carbon fibre-reinforced composites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Qi, Gang, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the most attractive applications of composite materials  is in robot industry. The reason lies in the fact that lightweight composite  materials with excellent performance can dramatically overcome the tricky conflict  of simultaneously achieving high end-effector positional accuracy and high link  acceleration. This thesis describes the process of analysis and redesign of an  anthropomorphic parallel robotic manipulator using graphite/epoxy fiber reinforced  composites, which exhibit high stiffness-to-weight ratio and strength-to-weight  ratio as well as good damping properties. From the structural viewpoint, by means of  finite element analysis, the research into the composite robot arms covers the  following aspects: redesign and shape optimization of the robot arms using shell  structures; optimizing stacking sequence and fiber orientations for composite  laminates; incorporating metal inserts into composite structures to improve local  stress concentrations and modal analysis to ensure the high dynamic characteristics  of the newly developed structures. Comparing with the original design using metal  links, the improved composite counterpart significantly increased the stiffness of  the robot arm while decreasing their mass and inertia to achieve a very high  specific stiffness, specific strength and excellent dynamic  performance.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j766.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb641</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2676w145"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the stability of multi-wavelength mode-locked erbium-doped fiber lasers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rotili, Roberto</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Presented in this thesis is a novel systematic approach to  determine the general characteristics and stability of an EDFL, and a thorough  experimental investigation of a mode-locked dual-wavelength EDFL. The novel method to characterize an EDFL consists of performing  an extensive set of measurements, and from these measurements a set of parameters is  calculated. These parameters quantifiably describe the laser in terms of its  temporal and spectral characteristics, signal power and wavelength variations, and  number of occurrences for which the laser ceases its multi-wavelength  operation. An experimental investigation of a free-running mode-locked  dual-wavelength EDFL with different signal wavelength spacing and pulse chirps is  performed with the characterization method proposed in this thesis. The original conclusions that are drawn from the experimental  investigation of an EDFL are that the stability of the EDFL exponentially decreases  as a function of the signal wavelength spacing, and the stability of an EDFL is  improved with linearly chirped FBGs.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cq972.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676w145</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Optics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s5355"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of exfoliation and intercalation in polymer layered silicate nanocomposites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mollet, Vincent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A microstructural and morphological analysis of polymer/layered  silicate nanocomposites (PLSN) is proposed. The analysis employs wide angle x-ray  diffraction (WAXD) and to a larger extent, transmission electron microscopy  (TEM). Polyamide-6 (PA) and polystyrene (PS) nanocomposites were  produced by melt processing the resins with several grades of organically modified  clay in a twin screw extruder (TSE). The TSE was operated in two different  configurations (C and A). The effects of the type of organoclay, TSE configuration,  clay concentrations and addition of a compatibilizing agent in the matrix were  evaluated. Both WAXD and TEM analysis revealed exfoliated or intercalated  structures for PA-based nanocomposites depending on the organoclay, whereas PS-based  nanocomposites mainly exhibited intercalated structure. A quantitative analysis of  the diffraction peaks was carried out in order to identify the ambiguous nature of  the secondary reflection peak. Depending on the case, it is proposed that the  secondary reflection peak could be due to a combination of secondary reflection of  the intercalated structure and a primary reflection of a collapsed structure of the  layered silicate particles.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296wz61j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s5355</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hj62j"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Finite-element modelling of the human middle ear</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mikhael, Chadia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Most models of the middle ear are based on oversimplified geometries and iterative material-property fitting to experimental data which may yield physiologically incorrect estimates. The aim of our work was to build an accurate human middle-ear finite-element model that is based on accurate geometry and a priori material-property estimates. A human temporal-bone specimen was obtained for which the middle-ear response had been measured by means of laser Doppler vibrometry. High-resolution micro-computed tomography data for the specimen were used for accurately defining structure geometry. This model comprises the tympanic membrane, the ossicles, two joints, and four ligaments. We assigned estimated material-property values derived from the literature. We compared the response of our model with those of other human middle-ear models, and with experimental measurements including those from the same ear. Sensitivity of the model to several of its parameters was also investigated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Funnell, W. Robert J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v5962.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj62j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mc56z"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Subcritical heat treatment of cold rolled multi-phase trip steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jeong, Tae Ki, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The high strength of TRIP (TRansformation Induced Plasticity)  steel enables high fuel efficiency by reducing the weight of a car without any loss  of safety. In addition, the good formability shown by TRIP steel extends the  application of this type of steel to complicated component shapes. TRIP steels can  be used in the cold rolled and 'TRIP annealed' condition. After cold rolling, TRIP  steels are subjected to a complicated anneal/heat-treatment encompassing  intercritical annealing followed by bainitic transformation. Because the 'TRIP  annealing' is designed to produce the complex microstructures, comprised of ferrite,  bainite, retained austenite, which achieve the best combination of strength and  formability; the processing of these steels requires careful selection and delicate  control of temperatures and holding times. In this context, this research work has  been carried out to design an alternative process for TRIP steel, using a relatively  simple subcritical heat-treating process. Basically, the concept is to cold roll the  TRIP steel to produce strain induced martensite, as well as work hardened ferrite  and bainite, and then to 'conventionally' anneal the steel to produce tempered  martensite and bainite, as well as recrystallized ferrite. For this purpose,  'subcritical heat treatment' of multiphase cold rolled TRIP steel at 200, 300, 400,  500, 550, 600, 650ºC for a hour were done then the microstructure,  mechanical properties were investigated with x-ray diffraction, OM and SEM, tensile  testing and hardness measuring. The mechanical properties after the subcritical heat  treatment at 600ºC and over are approaching those of traditional TRIP  processed steel hence this process can be a promising alternative and worth further  study.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bv16t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mc56z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343s74h"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Composition and biodegradation potential of polychlorinated alkane mixtures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jensen, Soren Ross</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A Monte Carlo Model was developed to simulate the free-radical  chlorination of n-alkanes by which polychlorinated alkane mixtures are produced. The  model parameters were the relative reactivity of the hydrogen atoms on the alkane  chain to chlorine free-radical substitution. The values of the parameters were  determined by free-radical chlorination experiments; by interpolation of data from  these experiments or from data in the literature. The result of the model is a  complete characterization of the molecular composition of PCA mixtures of any carbon  chain length and degree of chlorination. Properties of modeled PCA mixtures were in  good agreement with properties of real PCA mixtures. This model represents the first  published attempt to characterize polychlorinated alkane mixtures. The substrate specificity of oxygenolytic dehalogenase enzymes  was determined. Biodegradation experiments were performed to determine what specific  arrangements of chlorine atoms on n-alkane carbon chains could be acted upon by the  enzymes. Terminally substituted chlorinated n-alkanes were readily dehalogenated by  Pseudomonas sp.273, which expresses the enzymes. Vicinal chlorine atoms on the  carbon chain could not be removed by oxygenolytic dehalogenases. By combining the  results from the Monte Carlo model and the biodegradation experiments, it was  possible to generate an estimate for the upper limit to aerobic  biodegradation.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zr255.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s74h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wn43v"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dipole localization using simulated intracerebral electroencephalograms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chang, Nathalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Interpreting intracerebral recordings in the search of an  epileptic focus can be difficult because the amplitude of the potentials is  misleading. Small generators located near the electrode site generate large  potentials, which could swamp the signal of a nearby epileptic focus. In order to  address this problem, two inverse problem algorithms, beamforming and RAP-MUSIC,  were used with simulated intracerebral potentials to calculate equivalent dipole  positions. Three dipoles were positioned in a semi-infinite plane medium near three  intracerebral electrodes. Their potentials were simulated and contaminated with both  white and correlated noise. Localization simulations for each type of noise showed  that the two methods detected the sources accurately with RAP-MUSIC reporting lower  orientation errors. A spatial resolution analysis for both methods was also  performed to assess the separation ability of both methods. Beamforming adequately  distinguished the sources separated by 1.2 cm, whereas RAP-MUSIC separated sources  as close as 0.4--0.6 cm.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s301h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wn43v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644s11t"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Testing and performance of steel frame wood panel shear walls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Chang Yi, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Light gauge steel frame/wood panel shear walls are more commonly  being used in the residential and low-rise building markets. However in Canada, no  design guide for these shear walls has been published. Furthermore, although  laboratory investigations that cover the performance of light gauge steel frame/wood  panel shear walls with different sheathing material have been carried out, no  analytical methods have been developed to predict the in-plane stiffness and  strength of light gauge steel/wood panel shear walls based on member and connection  properties. This thesis has two main objectives. One is to investigate the  performance characteristics of various configuration light gauge steel frame/wood  panel shear walls under monotonic and reversed cyclic loading. The second is to  recommend an effective analytical model, which relies on sheathing-to-framing  connection test results and the mechanical properties of structural sheathing and  steel frame members, to predict the resistance and deflection of shear walls  subjected to lateral loads.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rh551.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644s11t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pn480"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gypsum production and hydrochloric acid regeneration by reaction of calcium chloride solution with sulfuric acid</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Othman, Amani Lutfi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One critical issue in chloride hydrometallurgy is the  regeneration of the lixiviant HCl that is commonly achieved by pyrohydrolysis. It is  the scope of this thesis to investigate a low temperature HCl regeneration process,  which regenerates HCl and produces saleable gypsum. Experiments were performed to  determine the optimum conditions of the chemical reaction that involved the reactive  mixing of calcium chloride (CaCl2) solution with sulfuric acid (H2SO4) solution at  low temperature and atmospheric pressure. The results showed that the crystallization chemistry of the  CaCl 2-H2SO4 reaction can be controlled in such away that favors the production of  well grown gypsum crystals with the simultaneous regeneration of practical strength  HCl. High strength HCl (= 4 M) was regenerated by the reaction of (3.5 M) CaCl2  leach solutions with (8 M) sulfuric acid in the temperature range of  20-60°C. Acid addition in stages to simulate the titration procedure,  seeding and recycling, and increasing temperature were found to favor crystal growth  and filterability. Finally, this research showed that there is negligible metal  uptake with the exception of lead, making the production of marketable gypsum  possible.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f77g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn480</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r6159"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of time-varying ankle stiffness</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baker, Mackenzie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The joint stiffness plays a significant role during movement;  however its function is not fully understood, particularly in terms of reflex  contributions. Studies examining the mechanical consequences of reflex activity  during movement are few. The long term objective of this thesis was to develop and  validate a method for identifying joint mechanics during movement. Previously developed ensemble, time-varying algorithms were used  to extend the parallel-cascade model to non-stationary conditions. This algorithm  was tested using simulated data. We obtained parameter estimates of ankle stiffness  from experiments under stationary conditions and used them to create a simulated  system undergoing a ramp displacement. Data was acquired from three subjects as an  electro-hydraulic actuator imposed a ramp displacement with superimposed  perturbations to the ankle. The algorithm performed well with simulated data.  Experimental system estimates were good at certain times and not at others, because  the ensemble input was not rich enough to permit a good  identification.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xf794.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r6159</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95051046"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quality of life in liver transplant patients : responsiveness of the SF-36, EQ-5D AND GHQ-30</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wong, Philip, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Health is defined as a state of complete physical, mental and  social well-being, and not merely the absence of disease. Quality of life refers to  a person's perception of well-being and life satisfaction. Chronic liver failure can  have significant negative impact on a patient's cognitive abilities and can cause  physical debilitation. Thus, it is not surprising that cirrhotic patients often have  severe impairment in their quality of life (QOL). From the perspective of the health  care system, patient's health-related quality of life (HRQL) is the more relevant  construct. Success of liver transplantation (OLT) is often measured by length of  survival, as opposed to patient perceptions of personal health. The primary objective of this study is to identify which of the  Short-Form Health Survey (SF-36), EuroQuol (EQ-5D) VAS, and General Health  Questionnaire-30 (GHQ-30) is the most responsive for detecting HRQL change for  patients pre- and post-liver transplantation. The secondary objective is to compare  the relative efficiency of the HRQL measures to traditional liver biochemistry  parameters.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t9120.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95051046</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870w44c"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Text operators in a relational programming language</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xie, Jiantao, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>JRelix is an implementation of a relational database system  which provides a significantly powerful database programming language and which is  especially adept with complex data. This thesis documents an enhancement of JRelix  which provides intuitive descriptions and efficient manipulations for textual  information in the database. Coupled with the relational and domain algebra in JRelix, the  new database system supports rapid textual information retrieval, flexible text  mining, structured text schema discovery, relational operations on text,  transformation between text and relation, and powerful pattern matching in  structured or unstructured data. These endow JRelix with the capacity of handling  complicated textual information from heterogeneous data sources (e.g., data from the  web), and also enrich its searching power on vast bodies of electronic data as a  text/relational database management system.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp141.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870w44c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fr86n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Divergent natural selection and the parallel evolution of mating preferences : a model and empirical test for the origins of reproductive isolation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schwartz, Amy K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ecological speciation involves the evolution of reproductive  isolation (RI) as a by-product of adaptation to different selective environments.  Parallel patterns of non-random mating by environment type provide strong evidence  that ecological speciation has occurred. The processes involved in the origins of RI  are more difficult to detect however. One mechanism involves the correlated  evolution of mating preferences and sexually selected traits. I developed a  conceptual model for detecting RI under various scenarios of mate preference  evolution. The model predicts that RI will not evolve if preferences are  evolutionarily constrained relative to the preferred traits, but is detectable as  long as preferences evolve in parallel. I then applied this framework to an  empirical system with populations of guppies (Poecilia reticulata) adapted to low-  and high-predation environments. I measured female mate preferences for male colour  and size; traits which are divergent between the two environment types. Preference  functions for colour also diverged in the predicted direction. The parallel pattern  of preference divergence suggests that divergent natural selection from predators  may be contributing to RI between guppy populations.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw63f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fr86n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Natural selection -- Trinidad and Tobago</dc:subject><dc:subject>Guppies -- Adaptation -- Trinidad and Tobago</dc:subject><dc:subject>Guppies -- Trinidad and Tobago -- Geographical distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sexual selection in animals -- Trinidad and Tobago</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kb31b"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A page based storage manager for a native XML database</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Suchak, Raj Narendra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With the advent of XML as a standardized data representation  model, the need has emerged to store, retrieve and update XML data. A new breed of  databases called native XML databases have been designed from the ground up to  perform such actions. McXML is an example of a native XML database. McXML was  developed at McGill University and it specializes in updating XML. We have designed  and developed a page based storage manager for McXML, which replaces the existing  plain text manager. The new storage manager allows efficient persistence, retrieval  and update of XML data using complex data structures. The new storage manager is  more efficient than the original storage manager and sets the foundation for  advanced features like concurrency control and buffer management in McXML. In  particular, the new storage manager is effective in persisting updated data changes  to disk. We prove the above assertions in performance benchmarks performed for this  thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h496j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb31b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>