<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kc511"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hydrologic modelling on the Saint Esprit watershed</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Romero, David R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study was undertaken to evaluate the suitability of the SLURP hydrological model for simulating the hydrology of the Saint Esprit watershed (26 km 2) in Quebec. Climatic data and other input were made available through a monitoring program set up in the watershed from 1994 to 1998. GIS was used to store, analyze and export the watershed information into the model. The continuous semi-distributed model SLURP was calibrated using three years of data (1994--1996). Parameter calibration, except that of snowpack melt-rate, was done through an automatic optimization technique. The model was validated using graphical outputs, the Nash/Sutcliffe (R2) coefficient of performance for daily runoff, and the percent difference of predicted versus computed runoff on a monthly, seasonal and annual basis. Additionally, the evapotranspiration (ET) component of the model was compared with an ET estimated using the Baier &amp; Robertson model (BR) calibrated for the region. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madramootoo, Chandra A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q6026.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc511</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Saint-Esprit River Watershed (Québec)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrology -- Québec (Province) -- Saint Esprit River Watershed</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrologic models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geographic information systems -- Québec (Province) -- Saint Esprit River Watershed</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vq38t"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of P-glycoprotein intracellular domains by cysteine scanning mutagenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rousseau, Marc-Etienne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Interactions between the various intracellular loops and nucleotide binding domains (NBDs) of P-glycoprotein (P-gp), and the extent to which they contribute to protein structure and transport mechanism are widely unknown. Analogy to bacterial members of the ABC transporter family suggests that the nucleotide binding domains interact with a specific site on an intracellular loop and with each other, as a cooperative dimer, in order to energize the transport functions. To investigate this hypothesis, we have used a cysteine scanning mutagenesis strategy on four potentially interacting regions of P-gp. We have analyzed the biological activity of the different mouse P-gp cysteine mutants in a yeast heterologous system. We established that the biological activity of the human MDR1 and MDR1-cysteine-less proteins can also be monitored by the yeast system. We also engineered and tested a MDR1 cysteine-less protein containing a factor Xa protease recognition site located in the third extracellular loop as a tool for future studies. Finally, analysis of the biological activity of the substitution mutants reveals key residues in regions that may be involved in drug binding and/or intramolecular domain interactions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gros, Philippe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk04h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq38t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816p32c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dimethylsulfate (DMS) protection footprinting of the interaction of cruciform DNA with a human cruciform binding protein (CBP)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robinson, Fiona</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cruciforms are an alternative secondary structure which may be adopted by DNA containing inverted repeats, under conditions of adequate torsional strain. Inverted repeats are distributed, in a non-random fashion, throughout the genomes of prokaryotes and eucaryotes. Mounting evidence suggests that they are involved in the initiation of DNA replication. A structure-specific cruciform DNA binding protein (CBP) has previously been enriched from HeLa cells, and demonstrated to be a member of the 14-3-3 family of proteins. This thesis reports the dimethylsulfate (DMS) protection footprinting of this protein on a stable cruciform, with the goal of testing a model proposed for this interaction. The footprint obtained was not clear or reproducible enough to allow this verification, however, it does support previously identified regions of binding on the cruciform DNA. Possible explanations for the nature of the footprint obtained, and suggestions which may allow the achievement of verification of the model, are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zannis-Hadjopoulos, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gx95p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p32c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans0647669"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nitrogen retention in freshwater ecosystems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saunders, Darla L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Given the prominent role of nitrogen in the eutrophication of aquatic systems, recent increases in nitrogen loading to freshwaters are of concern. A comparison of nitrogen retention in freshwaters in North America and Europe shows that wetlands retain the greatest proportion of their nitrogen load, followed by lakes and then rivers. A comparison of the relative importance of nitrogen retention mechanisms found denitrification to be responsible for the greatest proportion followed by nitrogen sedimentation and then uptake by aquatic plants. A more in-depth examination of denitrification in the littoral sediments of Lake Memphremagog in Quebec, using the N2 flux technique, found an average denitrification rate of 111 mumol N m-2 h-1. Denitrification rates were positively related to the % organic matter of the sediment, temperature and macrophyte biomass density and negatively related to depth. These results, in combination with a review of the literature indicate that denitrification rates are higher in littoral than profundal sediments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kalff, Jacob</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh458.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647669</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nutrient cycles -- Memphremagog, Lake (Québec and Vt.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Denitrification -- Memphremagog, Lake (Québec and Vt.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lake ecology -- Memphremagog, Lake (Québec and Vt.)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x5789"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mutational analysis of the human oxytocin receptor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oh, Karen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Oxytocin (OT) is a neurohypophyseal hormone that has an important role in mediating uterine contractions during parturition. As preterm labor is a major cause of perinatal mortality, the importance of elucidating the mechanisms involved in parturition become evident. Recently, our lab has discovered a novel mechanism of a non-genomic steroid-induced inhibition of OT receptor (OTR) function (1). It was shown that the steroid hormone progesterone specifically inhibits the rat OTR functions, not the human, via direct binding. Conversely, the human OTR is inhibited by a progesterone metabolite, 5beta-dihydroprogesterone. As there are only a limited number of amino acids that differ between the rat and human OTRs, site directed mutagenesis was used to determine those residues involved in mediating the specific steroid effects, by exchanging selected human-specific residues for the corresponding rat-specific residues. Whereas mutations L51F and A159G of the human OTR did not have any significant effects, the T218A mutant interacted with progesterone and not 5beta-dihydroprogesterone. The corresponding mutation in the rat OTR (A218T) induced an equivalent opposite change of its phenotype. Other mutations such as A84R, 1201V, V313A and A84-T218A were unable to bind OT, suggesting that these residues may be involved directly or indirectly in ligand binding. The data indicate that the 218th residue is critically involved in mediating the steroid specificity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zingg, Hans H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg26s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x5789</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km561"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of leptin during neonatal rat development : impact on the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis and energy balance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oates, Maxwell</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work examined the consequences of elevated leptin levels in neonatal rat pups and the possible relationship between leptin and dietary fat levels during development with respect to neuroendocrine and energetic parameters. While acute leptin injection elevated circulating leptin levels, it failed to have an effect on the HPA axis. In contrast, chronic injection of leptin produced a decrease in stress responsiveness as well as a decrease in body weight gain and fat deposition in 10 day old rat pups. Tonic exogenous administration of leptin also resulted in a decrease in stimulated CRF expression, a decrease in NPY expression and downregulation of the leptin receptor in these pups. Also, dams nursing leptin injected litters spent more time in ano-genital grooming of their pups. We also conducted experiments feeding dams a high-fat diet throughout gestation and lactation and found that a high fat diet produced increased plasma leptin in the offspring and is associated with decreased stress responsiveness, increased fat deposition and decreased NPY expression, but not with any changes in maternal behaviour.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Walker, C.-Dominique</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx678.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km561</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n204100h"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Preparation of gelatin from fish skin by an enzyme aided process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ofori, Rosemary Anima</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gelatin was extracted from shark and salmon skins by an enzyme aided process. A three factor, two level central composite rotatable design was used to optimize the process. The factors were namely, enzyme: dry fish skin weight ratio, incubation time, and temperature. The data were analyzed by response surface methodology to determine the optimum conditions for the deproteinization, demineralization and extraction process variables. Optimum conditions for deproteinization of shark skin by trypsin was about 25°C for 3h, and an E/S ratio of 0.08% (w/w). That for salmon was optimum at 25°C for 1 h with an E/S ratio of 1:1000. The ash content of the shark skins was reduced to over 80% at optimum demineralization conditions of 0.7M citric acid at 25°C for 3h. Demineralised salmon skins treated with pepsin at an E/S ratio of 0.02% (w/w) for 1h at 25°C resulted in maximum gelatin yield ranging from 7--8%. For shark, the maximum yield was between 18--20% at an E/S ratio of 0.02% (w/w) for 3h at 25°C. The chemical and enzyme treatments had an effect on the viscosity, bloom value and molecular weight for both salmon and shark gelatins.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Simpson, B. K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj61m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204100h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gelatin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trypsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pepsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fisheries -- By-products</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4j03d182d"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Changes of lipopolysaccharide of Salmonella enterica grown under different conditions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farah, Abdullah O.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The incidence of foodborne disease caused by Salmonella enterica is increasing yearly, despite the growing body of information regarding these most common pathogens. We examined the growth of, and lipopolysaccharide (LPS) expression of three Salmonella species (S. typhimurium, S. enteritidis , and S. blockley) grown at different pH values and temperatures and to different stages of the growth cycle. Growth conditions were found to affect the compositions of the LPS molecules produced by the organisms. The Tricine-SDS-PAGE and immunoblot profiles of LPS from the three Salmonella species were in accordance with the chemical data. Altered LPS profiles at different growth conditions were noted. Such differences among the profiles include variations within core oligosaccharides and the presence of O-side chains. The results also show that S. enteritidis and S. blockley grown to their exponential and stationary phases of the growth cycle produced longer O antigens and greater amounts of O antigens than did S. typhimurium grown at different growth stages. Tricine-SDS-PAGE allowed excellent resolution of low molecular weight LPS and the core region of LPS.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Idziak, Es</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z0276.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d182d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Endotoxins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salmonella -- Growth</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rn18g"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Novel implications of the cell adhesion molecule N-cadherin in B lymphocyte development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mak, Anton</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cadherins are a family of cell adhesion molecules (CAMs) that mediate calcium dependent cell-cell interactions. Amongst the many functions of cadherins are several well-established roles in the immune system, such as thymocyte development, and the heterotypic interaction between T cells and dendritic cells. To date, it is not known whether cadherins are expressed on B lymphocytes. CAMs play important roles in B cell maturation, by mediating cell adhesion with stromal cells of the microenvironment and initiating signalling cascades that promote cell survival. In the present study, N-cadherin expression was examined during B lymphopoiesis. We have demonstrated that a subset of CD19+ B cells in human marrow, but not in peripheral blood lymphocytes (PBLs) express N-cadherin, suggesting loss or down-regulation of N-cadherin as B lymphocytes mature and enter the circulation. In contrast, PBLs derived from B cell chronic lymphocytic leukemic (B-CLL) patients continue to express N-cadherin. To test whether N-cadherin may be re-expressed on B cells with a more mature phenotype, we characterized its expression on Daudi, Raji, and Ramos B cells. N-cadherin mRNA and protein was found in Daudi cells but not in Raji or Ramos cells. Finally, the inhibition of N-cadherin mediated adhesion results in an increase in programmed cell death. Maturation of B lymphocytes to antibody-secreting cells involves stringent selection as 95% of developing B lymphocytes are deleted by apoptosis. We surmise that N-cadherin may contribute to protection from cell death during the course of B cell maturation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jensen, Gitte S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd67s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn18g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773x58p"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>P53 polymorphism at codon 72 and risk of HPV-induced cervical cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Makni, Héla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An association between p53 polymorphism at codon 72 and risk of Human papillomavirus-related (HPV) cervical cancer has been reported (Storey et al., 1998) but followed by substantial controversy. In this study, we assessed the impact of inclusion of HPV-negative controls and of inter-laboratory variation in p53 genotyping on the validity of this association. Codon-72 genotype was blindly analyzed by three different laboratories in preserved DNA specimens from 54 HPV-positive cancer cases, 52 HPV-negative and 39 HPV-positive controls, selected from a previous case-control study. Age- and race-adjusted odds ratios (OR) of cervical cancer and their respective 95% confidence intervals (CI) were calculated using logistic regression. The proportions of p53 genotypes varied among laboratories with Kappa coefficients between 0.49 and 0.63. The OR for the homozygous arginine genotype, as compared to the combined heterozygous and the homozygous proline p53 forms, varied from 1.5 (95% CI: 0.5--3.9) to 8.0 (95%CI: 2.3--28.5), after exclusion of discordant genotypes between tabs. Restricting the comparison to HPV-positive controls increased the latter ORs to 2.9 (95%CI: 0.7--11.9) and 21.5 (95%CI: 3.4--137.8), respectively. The results indicate that the ability to detect the association between p53 polymorphism and HPV-induced cervical cancer risk could be affected by the inclusion of HPV-negative controls and by misclassification of p53 status.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Franco, Eduardo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3657098.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x58p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956h767"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Toward an Algebraic proof of Toda's theorem</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Majlis, Flavia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is devoted to an approach of computational complexity based on computations within finite semigroups. The theory of finite semigroups and its algebraic aspects are deeply connected with the theory of automata and regular languages [Eil76a] [Pin86]. The link between finite monoids and regular languages, for instance, is well known. We want to explore the existence of further links between a language that lies beyond the set of regular languages and the properties of the algebraic structure of the monoid recognizing it. The technique that will allow us to overcome the limitation of finite systems to recognize languages only within the set of regular languages is to approach a complexity class from the point of view of its leaf language [DPR92]. In this framework we expand the set of languages being contemplated by the model from the set of regular languages to the set PSPACE, the class of languages recognized by nondeterministic Turing machines in polynomial space. We then classify a complexity class by analyzing the algebraic structure of the monoid recognizing its leaf language. In this context, we will interpret a result by Toda [Tod91] in terms of the algebraic properties of the structure of the monoids recognizing the leaf languages of the classes involved.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Therien, D.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lemieux, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv49r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h767</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418q03b"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gas-solid reaction analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malus, Shem</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A gas-solid reaction analyzer was built in order to study the kinetics of various interesting gas-solid reactions, including the interstitial modification kinetics of carbonitride magnets. The system performs an analysis of the pressure and temperature of the carbonitride during the interstitial modification, as well as performing atomic mass analysis of the gases present throughout the gas-solid reaction. All the hardware, software, and electronics that make up the system were constructed as part of the requirements for the M.Sc. thesis, with the exception of the Quadrupole Mass Spectrometer (QMS) and the Transpector electronics unit which shipped with the mass spectrometer.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ryan, D. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q603g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q03b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f5400"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of dietary flaxseed and ℓ-topopherol supplementation on broiler's performance, fatty acid composition in muslce [sic] tissues and meat storage stability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kalinowski, Antonio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Experiments were conducted to investigate the effects of dietary fat, vitamin E(Vit. E) and selenium(Se) supplementation on the performance, fatty acid(FA) composition, lipid oxidation on blood and the oxidative stability of muscle tissues (breast and thigh) during refrigerated storage of broiler chickens fed high levels of flaxseed(FXS). Four hundred and eighty d-old broiler chicks were fed experimental diets for a 3 wk period, which consisted of the combination of two dietary fat sources: fullfat soybean(FFSB) and FXS; 3 Vit. E levels: 10, 40 and 80 IU/kg and two Se levels: 0.15 and 0.30ppm (Exp. I). Four hundred and forty d-old chicks were fed on FFSB diets supplemented with 10, 80, and 160 IU of Vit. E/kg, FXS diets supplemented with 10, 40, 80, 120, 160 and 200 IU of Vit. E/kg, corn-soybean based diet (control), and on a commercial diet for 21 days (Exp. II). For Exp. III, 1680 (840 of each sex) d-old broiler chicks were raised up to 41d. Three basal diets containing 10% FXS and 3 levels of Vit. E: 60-, 90- and 160 IU/kg were formulated for 3 age periods: starter (0--3wk), grower (3--5 wk) and finisher (5--6wk). Three groups of birds were fed these basal diets, while 3 other groups were fed the diet containing 160 IU of Vit. E either during the starter, grower or finisher phase (diets supplemented with 60 IU/kg were given in the two remaining phases). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chavez, Eduardo R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt032.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f5400</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fatty acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flaxseed</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vitamin E in animal nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Broilers (Poultry) -- Feeding and feeds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poultry -- Preservation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vd33q"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Crystallographic studies of the formimino transferase domain from the bifunctional enzyme formiminotransferase-cyclodeaminase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kohls, Darcy John Reinard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The structure of the formiminotransferase (FT) domain of formiminotransferase-cyclodeaminase (EC 2.1.2.5) - (EC 4.3.1.4) has been solved in complex with the product analogue, folinic acid, and in complex with the substrate analogue, C5,C10-dideazatetrahydrofolate. The protein is arranged as a homodimer, with each subunit comprising two a/(3 subdomains which adopt a novel protein fold. Within each subunit, an electrostatic tunnel which traverses the width of the molecule is observed and comprises the ligand binding sites. The distribution of charged residues in the tunnel enables us to propose the mode of binding for the natural substrate, tetrahydropteroylpolyglutamate. Modeling studies indicate that a gamma-linked triglutamate form of the tetrahydrofolate substrate can be accommodated through the length of the tunnel. The electron density also indicates that a single molecule of glycerol is bound to each protomer at the base of a second tunnel contacting the main electrostatic tunnel. This second tunnel is the expected entrance for formiminoglutamate to the active site of the enzyme. The structure has enabled us to propose that the residue His82 may be important in the catalytic mechanism of the transferase reaction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vrielink, Alice</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p0079.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd33q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10ws167"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Application of artificial neural network modeling in thermal process calculations of canned foods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khodaverdi Afaghi, Mahtab</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The feasibility of using Artificial Neural Network (ANN) models for application in thermal process calculations was studied. For a better understanding of the effect of process parameters on the evaluation of thermal process, the accuracy of several formula methods (Steele &amp; Board, Ball, Stumbo and Pham) were studied over a wide range of commercial conditions. A computer simulation based on finite difference method of numerical solutions of heat transfer to packaged foods in cylindrical containers was applied to obtain the time-temperature data for designed conditions (retort and initial temperatures, thermal diffusivity, package sizes and processing time). Moreover, the process time and process lethality from this simulation were used as the reference values for the purpose of comparison. The accuracy of methods was evaluated based on the variation of each parameter over the range of conditions employed in the study. As the final goal of the study, a multi-layer ANN model was developed as an alternative to thermal process calculations. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ramaswamy, H. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm15r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws167</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canned foods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neural networks (Computer science) -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canning and preserving</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g2033"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Caching behaviour in captive American kestrels (Falco sparverius)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kerr, Leslie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The storing of food is a common behaviour in the American kestrel ( Falco sparverius), a small, cavity-nesting falcon whose prey is comprised mainly of insects and small mammals. It may be a mechanism by which breeding birds ensure a sufficient food supply crucial to reproductive success. In 1996, caching behaviour of 10 single females, 10 single males and 20 paired captive American kestrels was recorded over the breeding season at the Avian Science and Conservation Centre of McGill University. Cache site preference and seasonal influence on caching frequencies were studied in 8 hand-raised, male kestrels in summer, fall and winter from 1996--1997. Caching frequency during the three seasons was significantly different with most occurring in fall, fewer in winter, and still fewer in summer. Memory for locations of cached prey was tested in 7 hand-raised males, three days after a caching event, from July to September 1997. The birds located their own caches significantly better than those caches placed by the experimenter. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f5397.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g2033</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>American kestrel -- Food -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>American kestrel -- Behavior -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741t61g"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Population genetics and sperm physiology associated with genome resource banking in the eld's deer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harnal, Veera Kumari</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Genome resource banking (collection, storage and use of germ plasm) has emerged as a potentially powerful tool to assist in managing and conserving endangered species. The development of genome resource banks is multi-faceted. This thesis focused on aspects of population genetics and the phenomenon of sperm capacitation, a fundamental biological process crucial to the use of germ plasm for assisted breeding (i.e., artificial insemination, in vitro fertilization). Computerized simulation modeling, using two endangered species models, the Eld's deer (Cervus eldi thamin ) and Pr-zewalski's horse (Equus przewalskii) clearly demonstrated the value of certain sperm storage and use strategies for maintaining genetic diversity in captive populations. Laboratory studies with Eld's deer sperm examining a host of conventional strategies (developed in livestock) demonstrated clear challenges in provoking capacitation and the acrosome reaction in the Eld's deer. This finding reaffirmed the importance of species-specific studies in wildlife research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z2768.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t61g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Przewalski's horse -- Germplasm resources</dc:subject><dc:subject>Population genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eld's deer -- Germplasm resources</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sperm banks</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074x13x"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Memory modulation produced by post-training exposure to an aversive conditioned stimulus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Holahan, Matthew R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Separate groups of rats were trained to enter one arm of a Y-Maze for food. They were then exposed to footshock, cues previously paired with footshock (CS), or neutral cues. When tested on the Y-Maze 24 hours later, rats that received post-training shock exhibited improved performance compared to rats that received no shock. Immediate post-training CS exposure improved performance compared to rats that were previously shocked but exposed to neutral cues as the post-training treatment. Delayed (2 hours) post-training presentation of the CS did not improve Y-Maze performance compared to immediate post-training presentation of the CS. Post-training exposure to the individual CSs (context or tone) improved Y-Maze performance relative to the neutral cues but not to the combination of cues. Conditioned freezing and place avoidance in the presence of the CS were two other conditioned responses measured. No correlation was found between any of the responses measured. These findings suggest that conditioned "fear" (an internal affective state) may function independently from observable behavioral measures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>White, Norman M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d51m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x13x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Conditioned response</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Maze tests</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fear</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806174f"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic and molecular investigation of the spinocerebellar ataxias</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hayes, Sean I. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The spinocerebellar ataxias (SCAs) are a clinically and genetically heterogeneous group of neurodegenerative disorders. To date, ten SCA loci have been described (SCA1-SCA8, SCA10 and SCA11), with six genes having been cloned (SCA1, SCA2, SCA3/MJD, SCA6, SCA7 and SCA8) and shown to contain CAG/CTG repeats. This study investigated various aspects of the SCA2, SCA6, and SCA7 subtypes. Haplotype analysis in our panel of SCA2 families identified multiple ancestral mutation events to be responsible for disease in this group. Screening for the newly identified SCA6 and SCA7 mutations in our large collection of SCA families and patients revealed that these mutations are rare in our panel, each accounting for less than 1% of our ataxia samples. Finally, the CAG repeat-containing locus hGT1 was found to be associated with residual age at onset variability in our SCA2 families. Together, these results add to our growing understanding of the SCAs, and bring us a few steps closer to effective diagnoses of, and treatments for, these devastating diseases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rouleau, Guy A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt04b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806174f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Friedreich's ataxia -- Molecular aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Friedreich's ataxia -- Genetic aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r034d"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of sub-grid scale clouds on sulphate production</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hasell, Natalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Clouds and aerosols impact on climate, both independently and through their interaction with one another. Thus, in climate models, it is important to make cloud schemes and in-cloud chemistry as realistic as possible. To this end, the UQAM sub-grid scale cloud scheme was added to LCM11, a one-dimensional version of the Northern Aerosol Regional Climate Model (NARCM). The goal of this project is to assess whether it is necessary to complete parameterization of sub-grid scale processes in LCM11 by implementing sub-grid scale parcel chemistry. Parallel runs of LCM 11 with and without parcel chemistry were performed under various chemical scenarios. The production of sulphate, the main anthropogenic constituent of tropospheric aerosols, was compared within parallel runs. Sulphate production was not significantly changed by the implementation of parcel chemistry. Thus, for the scenarios assayed in this project, the addition of sub-grid scale parcel chemistry to LCM11 is deemed unnecessary.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leighton, Henry G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg272.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r034d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386m24v"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>North American ecological zone classification for the UN Food and Agriculture Organization's Forest Resource Assessment 2000 Project : map compilation and validation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Douville, Michelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Classification and mapping of ecological zones on a global scale has been a topic of research for many years. This research looks at the development of a global spatial database of ecological zones for the FRA 2000 Report of the United Nations FAO. Besides evaluating the most appropriate type of classification scheme for this purpose, it explores and demonstrates how existing data, for the United States and Canada, can be reclassified to match the FAO classification scheme. Accuracy of mapping is a synergistic function of error, uncertainty, and quality. An assessment of the draft FAO Level D Ecological Zone map was performed which classifies 10-year average, bi-monthly, smoothed AVHRR-NDVI composites of the conterminous United States by applying linear discriminant and decision tree analyses. The results of the linear discriminant analysis were more significantly correlated to the FAO classes, although both approaches suggest that the classification scheme does maximize between-class variance of the NDVI temporal series.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lewis, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x094g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m24v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biotic communities -- North America -- Maps</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ecology -- North America -- Maps</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vegetation and climate -- North America -- Maps</dc:subject><dc:subject>Forest Resources Assessment Programme (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biotic communities -- North America -- Classification</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237ht62p"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biocatalysis of immobilized lipoxygenase in organic solvent media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dioum, Ndeye</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The biocatalysis of purified soybean lipoxygenase (LOX) (EC 1.13.11.12) using linoleic acid as a substrate model was investigated in selected organic solvent media, including chloroform, dichloromethane, hexane, iso-octane, octane and toluene. The results indicated that there was a 2.6 fold increase in LOX activity in the monophasic iso-octane medium compared to that obtained in the aqueous medium. In addition, the optimum concentration of octane and iso-octane in the biphasic medium containing the organic solvent and Tris-HCl buffer solution, was determined to be 3.5 and 4%, respectively, for LOX activity which resulted in a further increase in LOX activity. The immobilized LOX showed better substrate specificity towards linoleic acid, followed by arachidonic acid. The enzymatically-catalyzed end-products were investigated, and the results indicated that different proportions of the 9- and 13-HPOD isomers were produced by LOX biocatalysis depending on the reaction medium used and the free or immobilized state of the enzyme. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kermasha, Selim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs32n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht62p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lipoxygenases -- Separation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organic solvents</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074x146"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Signaling and cell cycle regulation in B lymphocytes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doyle, Iris S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>T-dependent activation of B cell proliferation is crucial to humoral immune responses. Regulation of this activation is required to limit responses. The cyclin dependent kinase (CDK) inhibitor (CKI) p21cip-1/waf-1 is implicated in inhibition of cell cycle progression. This thesis describes experiments that investigated the role of p21cip-1/waf-1 in regulating B cell proliferation. C57Bl/6 splenic B cells were stimulated to enter cell cycle by crosslinking CD40. p21cip-1/waf-1 expression was upregulated by CD40 stimulation of B cells, and superinduced by co-crosslinking intercellular adhesion molecule 1 (ICAM-1)/CD54, major histocompatibility complex (MHC) I or MHC II with CD40. Treatments that superinduced p21 cip-1/waf-1 inhibited CD40-stimulated proliferation and induced apoptosis. Apoptosis was abrogated in p21cip-1/waf-1-/- B cells, which otherwise responded equivalently to controls. By contrast, B cells from p27cip-1/waf-1-/- mice showed the same induction of cell death as wild type mice. These results show that MHC and ICAM-1, specifically modulate CD40-mediated signals and this process involves p21cip-1/waf-1.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Owens, Trevor</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064768v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x146</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx28n"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Construction and dosimetric evaluation of compensators for intensity modulated beams</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dimitriadis, Doris M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We investigated the feasibility of constructing compensators for intensity modulated beams. The average uncertainty in the constructed compensator thickness was +/-0.3 mm. It was found that the beam hardening effect was significant, and can lead to an error of 6.2% in the transmission, for 6 cm of lead alloy in the beam. The maximum scatter contribution to the measured fluence was 19.8% for a 20 x 20 cm2 field size, and 6 cm of lead alloy in the beam. The compensators were constructed using a simple attenuation model. For a simple wedge-step compensator there was a maximum deviation of 6% between the measured and our predicted fluence profile. For simple compensators this deviation can be attributed to scatter according to the scatter analysis introduced. The maximum deviation between the measured and predicted fluence, for fluence files derived from a commercial inverse treatment planning system was slightly higher at 7%. This is because other factors such as penumbra and scatter from neighboring modulations must be considered for each compensator individually.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fallone, B. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps29b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx28n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892c72t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The regulation and function of interleukin-6 after peripheral nerve transection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Borthwick, Lindsay</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Previous work has demonstrated that interleukin-6 (IL-6) is synthesized in approximately one-third of lumbar dorsal root ganglion neurons during the first week after sciatic nerve transection. The present study was undertaken to determine the signals influencing IL-6 synthesis in the peripheral nerve and the functional consequences of IL-6 production in response to nerve injury. The first sets of experiments demonstrate that IL-6 is induced by an injury factor arising from the nerve stump rather than by interruption of normal retrograde trophic support from the target tissues or distal nerve stump. Furthermore, the use of agents that stimulate or inhibit degranulation of mast cells suggest that they release a factor(s) that can induce IL-6 mRNA in the sciatic nerve after injury. Additional studies propose that endogenous IL-6 performs at least two important functions in sensory neurons after nerve injury. First, IL-6 supports neuronal survival in cooperation with brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF). Specifically, IL-6 is required for de novo synthesis of BDNF mRNA in injured sensory neurons, and BDNF mediates the survival of DRG neurons in response to IL-6. Second, endogenous IL-6 mediates the development of behavioural changes associated with neuropathic pain. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richardson, Peter M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t88t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c72t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>