<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247dw409"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation of the role of gamma-tubulin phosphorylation in regulation of spindle assembly</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nazarova, Elena</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>    La formation d’un fuseau mitotique  complet, avec des microtubules attachés aux kinétochores ou associé à un microtubule antiparallèle, est essentielle au processus de ségrégation des chromosomes. La première étape de ce processus est la nucléation des microtubules depuis la duplication des pôles des fuseaux. Dans la levure, Saccharomyces cerevisiae, les fuseaux des microtubules sont initiés et construits à partir d’anneaux de gamma-tubulines composés de gamma-tubulines et de protéines interagissant avec les gamma-tubulines (GRIP) localisés dans le centre d’organisation du microtubule (MTOC) fongique, appelé le corps polaire du fuseau.     Nous avons utilisé des techniques de microscopie électronique tridimensionnelle et procédé à un suivi automatique des fuseaux dans des levures vivantes afin d’étudier la processus d’assemblage des fuseaux depuis leur séparation initiale jusqu’à la métaphase. La gamma-tubuline est impliquée dans la nucléation des microtubules. De plus l’état phosphorylé d’un site évolutivement conservé de Cdk1, la Sérine 360 (S360), dans les gamma-tubuline est corrélé avec le nombre et l’organisation de l’appariement des microtubules antiparallèles. En utilisant des mutants imitant les état phosphorylé et non phosphorylé de la gamma-tubuline au résidu S360 (respectivement, gamma-tubS360D and gamma-tubS360A), nous avons dévoilé une nouvelle fonction de la gamma-tubuline dans la levure. Nous montrons que la phosphorylation de la gamma-tubuline au résidu S360 régule l’architecture et la stabilité du fuseau durant la phase d’assemblage des fuseaux, mais aussi durant la formation bipolaire des fuseaux. Nous montrons également que la Kinésine 5, qui permet la réticulation des fuseaux antiparallèles,  est le produit probable d’une cascade de réaction initiée par la gamma-tubuline, et caractérise sont activité au cours de la séparation initiale. Cette étude suggère aussi que la Kinésine 5 contribue à la compression et la relaxation des microtubules, et que ce mécanisme est essentiel à la séparation initiale des pôles.    En résumé, ce travail identifie de nouvelles fonctions de la gamma-tubuline de la levure dans les mécanismes de régulation des fuseaux au cours de leur assemblage. Nous proposons que la phosphorylation du résidu S360 de la gamma-tubuline contribue à un mécanisme général  de construction stéréotypé des fuseaux, en accord avec les données de régulation, qui assure une bonne division cellulaire.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>    Formation of a fully assembled spindle, with microtubules attached to kinetochores or paired with antiparallel microtubules, is essential for accurate chromosome segregation. The first step in this process is the nucleation of microtubules from duplicated spindle poles. In the budding yeast, Saccharomyces cerevisiae, spindle microtubules are nucleated and projected from gamma-tubulin ring complexes composed of gamma-tubulin and associated gamma-tubulin–interacting proteins (GRIPs) located at fungal microtubule organizing centers (MTOC), called spindle pole bodies.     We used a combination of three-dimensional electron microscopy and automated feature tracking of spindles in living yeast cells to investigate the process of spindle assembly from initial pole separation to metaphase. Canonically, gamma-tubulin is known to be involved in microtubule nucleation, however the phosphorylation state of an evolutionarily conserved Cdk1 site, Serine 360 (S360), in gamma-tubulin is correlated with the number and the orga¬nization of paired antiparallel microtubules. We used phospho-mimicking and phospho-inhibiting mutants of gamma-tubulin at S360 (gamma-tubS360D and gamma-tubS360A, respectively) to characterize the role of S360 and we revealed a novel function of gamma-tubulin in budding yeast. We showed that phosphorylation of gamma-tubulin at S360 regulates the architecture and the stability of the spindle during the spindle assembly and the bi-polar spindle formation. We present evidences that kinesin-5, which cross-links antiparallel microtubules, is one of the likely downstream effectors of gamma-tubulin. Our analysis of bi-polar spindle formation suggests that kinesin-5 also contributes to the compression and relaxation of spindle microtubule, which is essential for initial pole separation.    Collectively, this work identifies a novel contribution of yeast gamma-tubulin in the regulation of spindle organization during spindle assembly. We propose that the phosphorylation of gamma-tubulin at S360 is a part of a general mechanism for building a stereotyped spindle, in accordance with regulatory inputs, that ensure accurate cell division.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacalyn Vogel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483n31q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw409</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999977v"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Have you heard that...? Developmental trajectories and psychological variables associated with relational aggression and gossip</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gomez-Garibello, Carlos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Traditional definitions of aggressive behaviours have emphasized acts of physical and verbal aggression.  By labelling behaviours such as gossip, manipulation or social isolation as aggressive acts, the traditional definition of aggression has been challenged and expanded.  Consequently, relational aggression has emerged as a prolific field of study.  In this context, researchers have examined the characteristics and associations of these behaviours with psychological constructs.  Particular attention has been placed on the role of psychological variables in the prediction of relational aggression.  In addition, researchers have analyzed the influence of chronological age and sex on the manifestation of relational aggressive acts.  This dissertation is comprised of two manuscripts that collectively contribute to the literature by documenting characteristics and predictors of relational aggression and gossip in children between the ages of 6 to 9 years old, as well as the role of chronological age and sex in such associations.The first manuscript in this research program examined whether age moderates the relationship between cognitive factors (theory of mind and attribution of intentions) and relational aggression.  Participants (N = 426; 216 boys) between 6 and 9 years of age (M = 97.43 months, SD = 10.98) were asked to complete theory of mind tasks and answer an attribution of intentions questionnaire. Teachers of the students evaluated their students’ social behaviours, including relationally aggressive acts.  Results suggest that theory of mind did affect relational aggression, while this association was moderated by chronological age.  Specifically, it was found that the association between theory of mind and relational aggression was only significant for younger participants. Taken together, findings from this manuscript partially support the assertion that sophisticated cognitive skills are a prerequisite for indirect acts of aggression. The second manuscript in the current research program examined the role of sex on the relationship between cognitive (theory of mind and attribution of intentions), emotional (empathy) and social (perceived popularity) factors, and gossip.  Participants (N = 422; 216 boys) aged between 6 to 9 years old were asked to nominate their best friends, resulting in 211 dyads.  Interactions within each dyad were recorded and codified. Differences in predictors of gossip were found across sexes, such that gossip was associated positively with theory of mind and perceived popularity only for boys.  None of the examined factors predicted gossip in girls.  Results suggest that sharing information was the most common function of gossip; positive gossip was more common than negative gossip; and peers were the most frequent target of this behaviour.  All in all, results from the second manuscript suggest that boys and girls engaged in gossip, yet different predictors explain this phenomenon across sexes.Taken together, the findings from the current research program provide empirical support for theoretical discussion about the impact of cognitive, emotional and social factors in the manifestation of relational aggression and gossip.  In addition, the results delineate the effects of chronological age and sex on the association between psychological attributes and relational aggression and gossip.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les définitions traditionnelles des comportements agressifs se concentraient en général sur les actes d’agression physique et verbale.  Le fait d’inclure des comportements comme les commérages, la manipulation ou la mise à l’écart d’un groupe social représente une remise en cause et un élargissement de la définition de l’agressivité.  Il en est résulté un développement prolifique du thème de l’agressivité relationnelle comme nouveau champs de recherche.  Dans ce contexte, les chercheurs ont examiné les caractéristiques et relations de ces comportements avec  les concepts psychologiques, en portant une attention particulière sur le rôle des variables psychologiques dans la prédiction des agressions de type relationnel.  En plus, les chercheurs ont analysé l’influence de l’âge et du sexe sur les expressions d’actes d’agression relationnelle.  Cette thèse comprend deux manuscrits qui, ensemble, contribuent à la littérature en documentant les caractéristiques et les prédicteurs de l’agression relationnelle et des commérages chez les enfants âgés de 6 à 9 ans, ainsi que le rôle de l’âge et du sexe dans ces relations.Le premier document dans notre travail de recherche a examiné si l’âge joue un rôle dans la relation entre les facteurs cognitifs (théorie de l’esprit et attribution des intentions) et l’agression relationnelle.  Un groupe de 426 participants (dont 216 garçons) âgés entre 6 et 9 ans (M = 97,43 mois, DS = 10,98) ont complété des tâches et répondu à un questionnaire d’intentions.  Les enseignants de ces jeunes participants ont évalué leur comportement social, y compris les actes d’agression relationnelle.  Les résultats indiquent que la théorie de l’esprit affecte l’agression relationnelle, et que le rapport entre les deux est influencé par l’âge.  Spécifiquement, la corrélation entre la théorie de l’esprit et l’agression relationnelle n’est significative que pour les plus jeunes participants.  En fin de compte, les résultats du présent travail ne confirment que partiellement que les compétences cognitives sophistiquées sont indispensables pour se livrer à des actes d’agression indirects.  Le second manuscrit du programme de recherche présenté ici examine le rôle du sexe dans la relation entre les facteurs cognitifs (théorie de l’esprit et attribution des intentions), émotionnels (empathie) et sociaux (popularité perçue), d’une part, et les commérages d’autre part.  Les participants à l’enquête (N = 422; 216 garçons), âgés entre 6 et 9 ans,  indiquèrent le nom de leurs meilleurs amis, ce qui donna 211 groupes d’amis.  Les interactions au sein de chaque groupe d’amis furent enregistrées et codifiées. L’étude trouva des différences significatives entre prédicteurs de commérages entre garçons et filles, notamment que les commérages sont positivement liés à la théorie de l’esprit et la popularité perçue uniquement chez les garçons. Aucun des facteurs de prédiction n’ont été relevé chez les filles.  Les résultats suggèrent que le partage d’information était la fonction la plus commune des commérages; les commérages positifs étaient plus fréquents que les commérages négatifs; et les autres camarades étaient les sujets les plus fréquents de ces commérages.  En conclusion, les résultats du second manuscrit indiquent que les garçons et les filles participent également aux commérages, mais que des prédicteurs différents expliquent ce phénomène pour chaque genre.  Considérés ensemble, les résultats de ce programme de recherche font un apport empirique à la discussion théorique sur l’impact des facteurs cognitifs, émotionnels et sociaux sur les manifestations d’agression relationnelle et les commérages. De plus, les résultats permettent de cerner les effets de l’âge et du sexe dans la relation entre les attributs psychologiques et l’agression relationnelle, et les commérages en particulier.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Victoria Talwar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n648n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999977v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qm97k"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Oxepinobenzofurans controlled-copper catalyzed aerobic synthesis and reactivity as oxidants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Petitjean, Laurène</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Copper catalyzed phenolic oxidations have historically shown a lack of selectivity due to the ease of autoxidation of phenols. The resulting phenoxyl radicals provide complex mixtures of oxygenation and oxidation products, such as quinones, biphenols, oxepinobenzofurans and polymeric materials. Despite this lack of selectivity, phenolic aerobic oxidations show promise as environmentally benign, efficient and versatile means to access a wide variety of structurally different products from a single starting compound. In Chapter One, an overview of previous efforts towards the selective oxygenation of phenols via copper-catalyzed aerobic oxidation is provided, along with a detailed summary of previous syntheses of oxepinobenzofurans and a review of their reactivity.Chapter Two describes the successful development and optimization of a copper-catalyzed aerobic synthesis of both oxepinobenzofurans and biphenols. Subtle changes to the catalytic system enabled the identification of factors that govern selectivity between each product class. The scope of each of these reactions was demonstrated, and showed that subtle steric and electronic factors influence efficacy and selectivity. Chapter Three relates efforts towards the development of a catalytic aerobic dehydrogenation through the use of oxepinobenzofurans as hydrogen transfer agents. The dehydrogenation of dihydroanthracene by several oxepinobenzofurans is demonstrated, furnishing anthracene and biphenols. Proof of a potential catalytic aerobic dehydrogenation method is given by the fruitful development and optimization of copper-catalyzed aerobic oxidation of biphenols to oxepinobenzofurans. Electron spin resonance measurements of oxepinobenzofurans demonstrate an equilibrium with radical species, observed at high temperatures. Initial results thus indicate a biphenoxyl species as the reactive intermediate mediating dehydrogenation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Historiquement, les oxydations phénoliques aérobiques catalysées par le cuivre ont démontrées un manque de sélectivité, due à la facilité d’auto-oxydation des phénols, donnant des mélanges complexes de produits d’oxydation et d’oxygénation, comme les quinones, les biphénols, les oxepinobenzofuranes ainsi que certains polymères. Néanmoins, les oxydations aérobiques de phénols possèdent un énorme potentiel en tant que méthodes versatiles et efficaces permettant l’accès à de nombreux produits structurellement différents à partir d’un seul phénol. Le Chapitre Un propose un aperçu des efforts préalables en ce qui trait au développement d’oxygénations sélectives de phénols via des oxydations aérobiques catalysées par le cuivre. Un sommaire détaillé des synthèses et de la réactivité établie des oxepinobenzofuranes est aussi donné.Le Chapitre Deux décrit le développement et l’optimisation réussis des synthèses d’oxepinobenzofuranes et de biphénols par oxydations catalytiques et sélectives de phénols. Des changements subtiles au système catalytique ont permis l’identification des besoins du complexe de cuivre afin d’être sélectif. L’essai des deux réactions avec plusieurs phénols ont démontrés les facteurs électroniques et stériques subtiles qui influencent l’efficacité et la sélectivité du système.Le Chapitre Trois relate les efforts vers le développement de déshydrogénations aérobiques et catalytiques en cuivre, possible grâce à l’habilitée des oxepinobenzofuranes à agir comme agents de transfert d’atomes d’hydrogène. La déshydrogénation de dihydroanthracene par plusieurs oxepines est décrite, donnant le produit oxydé anthracène et des biphénols comme produits réduits des oxepines. Le potentiel d’une méthode catalytique aérobique de déshydrogénation est prouvé grâce au développement et à l’optimisation avec succès de l’oxydation des biphénols donnant des oxepinobenzofuranes sous l’action de l’oxygène et du cuivre. Des mesures d’oxepines par résonance paramagnétique électronique ont démontrées l’existence d’un équilibre entre les oxepines et des espèces radicalaires observées à hautes températures. Les résultats préliminaires indiquent qu’un biphénoxyl serait l’intermédiaire réactif dans les déshydrogénations par les oxepines.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean-Philip Lumb</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q463t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qm97k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r626c"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bioremediation of petroleum hydrocarbons: multi-scale investigation of effects of pore size and role of diurnal temperature changes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Akbari, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Indigenous, cold-adapted, hydrocarbon-degrading bacteria have been frequently detected in soils from cold region sites suggesting bioremediation, as a cost-effective remediation technology is potentially viable for cleanup of contaminated sites in cold regions. Previous studies on bioremediation of petroleum hydrocarbons in cold regions have been conducted with coarse textured soils. However, fine-grained or clayey soils are commonly found in several cold regions. The overall objective of this research was to investigate the factors controlling biodegradation of aged, clayey petroleum hydrocarbon contaminated soils from a sub-arctic site, under relevant temperature regimes. The biodegradation rates and extents of petroleum hydrocarbons were investigated for a clayey site contaminated soil in four pilot scale biopiles maintained at 15˚C. Non-volatile petroleum hydrocarbons (C16-C32) were biodegraded 24 to 38% under continuous aeration and with amendments of 17.5% or 23.5% moisture and also 17.5% moisture with 95 mg-N/ kg soil. In contrast, statistically significant biodegradation of the non-volatile hydrocarbon fraction was not observed in a biopile tank containing soils amended with 23.5% moisture content and 1340 mg-N/ kg soil. While a significant shift occurred in soil microbial community over 60 days in the biopile tank amended with 23.5% moisture only, there was no change in the microbial community of soil samples amended with a similar level of moisture and 1340 mg-N/ kg soil, indicating that high amounts of nitrogen amendment inhibited bioremediation.This study investigates the effect of diurnal temperature variations on the biodegradation of petroleum hydrocarbon contaminated soil typical for the site from northern Canada from which contaminated soils were obtained. The extents of biodegradation of petroleum hydrocarbons after 70 days, in systems incubated at temperatures varying between 5 ˚C to 15 ˚C daily (representative of daily high and low temperatures) were similar to systems incubated at constant temperature of 15 ˚C, and were significantly higher than systems incubated at 5 ˚C. The soil microbial community of systems with daily changes in temperatures between 5 ˚C to 15 ˚C was similar to those incubated at 15 ˚C, but significantly different than those incubated at 5 ˚C, based on both 16S rRNA and alkB gene analyses. The results suggest that the highest temperature (15 ˚C) to which the soil was frequently exposed to, determined the microbial community profile in the site soil, and periods of low temperatures did not reduce the overall biodegradation efficiency or the microbial community compared to that maintained solely at 15 ˚C.Experiments were conducted to investigate if hexadecane, a biodegradable but effectively insoluble hydrocarbon phase, was accessible to, and degraded by hydrocarbon degrading bacteria when the hexadecane-water interface was separated from the microbial culture by membranes with specific pore sizes. In these systems, bacteria were unable to degrade hexadecane when the membrane pore size was 0.4 µm or 3 µm, but was able to degrade hexadecane when separated by pore sizes of 12 µm. To investigate the implications of these results to aggregates from clayey and sandy soils, the in-situ aggregate micro-structure of representative soil aggregates from petroleum contaminated clayey soil and petroleum contaminated sandy soil were compared by micro-scale computed tomography (micro CT) imaging. The “bioaccessible porosity” defined as fraction of aggregate volume corresponding to pores larger than 4 µm was comparable in case of clayey (26-27%) and sandy (24%) aggregates.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Des bactéries indigènes, adaptées au froid, dégradant les hydrocarbures ont été fréquemment détectées dans les sites de région froide. Par conséquent, la bioremédiation, une technologie avec un bon rapport coût-efficacité, est potentiellement viable pour la réhabilitation des sites contaminés en régions froides. Des études antérieures sur la bioremédiation des hydrocarbures pétroliers en région froide ont été complétées avec des sols à grain grossier. L’objectif principal de cette recherche était d’étudier les facteurs contrôlant la biodégradation de la contamination par hydrocarbures pétroliers vieillis de sols argileux provenant d’un site subarctique sous des régimes de températures pertinents.Les taux et l’étendue de la biodégradation des hydrocarbures pétroliers ont été examinés dans quatre biopiles à l’échelle pilote contenant des sols argileux et contaminés, maintenues à une température de 15 ˚C, la température moyenne du site durant l’été. Les hydrocarbures non-volatiles (C16-C32) ont été biodégradé jusqu’à 24 à 38% sous aération continue et avec un amendement en humidité de 17,5% ou 23,5 % et 17,5% d’humidité avec 95 mg-N/ kg de sol (HPT:N = 100:5). À l’inverse, la biodégradation de la fraction d’hydrocarbure non-volatile n’a pas été statistiquement significative dans la biopile contenant des sols amendés avec une humidité de 23,5% et 1340 mg-N/ kg de sol. Les coefficients de vitesse de la biodégradation au premier ordre de la fraction d'hydrocarbure de pétrole non-volatile étaient de 0,11 + 0,04 jours-1 (r2 = 0,9) dans les systèmes de suspension de sol amendés avec 95 mg-N / kg de sol, et étaient significativement plus élevée à 0,009 + 0,003 jours-1 (r2 = 0,69) obtenues à partir des systèmes de biopiles avec la même modification en azote. Toutefois, l’étendue de la biodégradation de 46% dans les systèmes de boue incluant sol/eau a demeurée inchangée entre 30 et 60 jours, et était comparable à une étendue de 50% qui a été observée dans les systèmes de biopiles pour une période de 385 jours. Après une période de 70 jours, l’étendue de biodégradation des hydrocarbures pétroliers semi-volatiles (C10-C16) et non-volatiles (C16- C32) dans les systèmes incubés à des températures variant entre 5 ˚C et 15 ˚C quotidiennement (représentant les hautes et basses températures quotidiennes) était comparable à ceux incubé à une température constante de 15 ˚C, mais significativement meilleure que ceux incubés à 5 ˚C. De même que les communautés microbiennes des sols avec des changements de température entre 5 ˚C et 15 ˚C quotidiens étaient similaires à ceux incubés à 15 ˚C, mais différaient significativement de ceux à 5 ˚C d’après les analyses d’ARN ribosomaux 16S et le gène alkB. Les résultats suggèrent que c’est la plus haute température (15 ˚C) qui détermine le profil de la communauté de microorganismes dans les sols et que les périodes de basses températures n’ont pas réduit l’efficacité de la biodégradation en gros ou de la communauté microbienne lorsqu’ils sont comparés aux systèmes maintenus à une température constante de 15 ˚C.Des expériences ont été effectuées pour étudier si l’hexadécane, une substance biodégradable mais effectivement insoluble, était accèssible à et dégradé par des bactéries capables de dégrader les hydrocarbures dans des situations où l’interface hexadécane-eau était séparé de la culture microbienne par des membranes de pores à grandeur spécifique. Dans ces systèmes, les bactéries n’étaient pas capable de dégrader hexadécane en présence de pores de 0.4 µm et 3 µm, mais étaient capables de le dégrader lorsque le pore avait un grandeur de 12 µm. Afin d’investiguer les implications de ces résultats sur les agrégats de sol argileux et sableux, la microstructure de l’agrégat in-situ d’un agrégat de sol représentatif d’un sol argileux et d’un sol sableux contaminé en hydrocarbures a été comparée par imagerie de tomographie à micro-échelle (micro CT) par ordinateur.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Subhasis Ghoshal</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd4730564.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r626c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920g094f"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some algorithmic problems in group theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mohajeri Moghaddam, Atefeh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, nous nous intéressons à deux types différents de problèmes algorithmiques sur les groupes. Dans la première partie, nous considérons le problème des géodésique dans les groupes métabeliens libres de type fini ainsi que dans les produits en couronne de type fini. En particulier, nous prouvons qu’il y a un algorithme de 2-approximation pour le problème des géodésique dans les groupes métabeliens libres de type fini. Nous montrons aussi que le problème des géodésique dans le produit en couronne restreint d’un groupe de type fini et non-trivial A avec un groupe abélien de type fini B contenant le groupe abélien libre de rang 2 est NP-difficile. En outre, nous prouvons que si le problème des géodésique est décidable dans A en temps polynomial, alors il existe un “Polynomial Time Approximation Scheme” pour le problème des géodésique dans le produit en couronne restreint de A et B.Dans la deuxième partie (Chapitre 3 and Chapitre 4), nous considérons des équations dans des groupes. Nous montrons que les solutions minimales des systèmes d’équations dans les groupes libres de type fini avec des contraintes alphabétiques sont polynomialement compressibles en la taille des données. Nous donnons aussi une majoration polynomiale sur la taille des solutions minimales des équations quadratiques dans les groupes hyperboliques sans torsion et dans les groupes relativement hyperboliques toriques. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this thesis we consider two different types of algorithmic problems over groups. In the first part, we consider the geodesic problem in finitely generated free metabelian groups as well as finitely generated wreath products. In particular, we show that there exists a 2-approximation algorithm for the geodesic problem in finitely generated free metabelian groups. We also show that the geodesic problem in the restricted wreath product of a finitely generated non-trivial group A with a finitely generated abelian group B containing the free abelian group of rank 2,  is NP-hard. Moreover, we prove that if the geodesic problem is polynomially decidable in A, then there exists a Polynomial Time Approximation Scheme for the geodesic problem in the restricted wreath product of A and B.In the second part of the thesis (Chapter 3 and Chapter 4), we consider equations over groups. We show that minimal solutions to systems of equations over finitely generated free groups with alphabetic constraints are polynomially compressible in the size of the input. We also give a polynomial bound on the lengths of minimal solutions of quadratic equations over torsion-free hyperbolic groups as well as toral relatively hyperbolic groups. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Olga Kharlampovitch</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Frederick Shepherd</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r419t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g094f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sk437"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Emotion regulation, executive functioning, and academic competence: testing moderator effects and predictive relationships</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Glaser, Sarah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Researchers have become interested in examining the relationships between emotion regulation (ER), executive functioning (EF), and academic competence (AC). ER involves monitoring and controlling emotions; EF consists of cognitive skills such as planning and organization; and AC regards academic skills and grades, as well as academic enablers (i.e., school behaviours necessary for success such as engagement and motivation). Despite adolescence being a turbulent time period for many students because of increased social, psychological, academic, and other stressors, ER, EF, and AC are poorly understood in this population. Several theories within the ER and EF literature propose that (a) disruptions in ER lead to disruptions in EF and adaptive functioning such as AC, (b) EF and ER are dependent on each other, (c) ER acts as a gateway to efficient EF, and (d) EF is composed of cool (metacognitive) and hot (ER) components, which interact to initiate effective problem solving and performance (Barkley, 1997a, 2012; Blair &amp; Dennis, 2010; Blair &amp; Ursache, 2011; Zelazo &amp; Cunningham, 2007). These models all suggest that ER is a moderator between metacognitive EF and adaptive behaviour. In the present study, the interactions between ER, EF, and AC were explored among a sample of adolescents between the ages of 13 and 18 years (N = 205; 130 females, 75 males). The first objective of the study was to use multiple regression to examine how various components of ER and EF each predict AC. Specifically, it was hypothesized that students who reported well-developed ER and metacognitive EF would have significantly higher AC, whereas students with poorly developed ER and metacognitive EF would have significantly lower AC. The second objective of the present study was to examine the moderating effect of ER between metacognitive EF and AC. This objective was reached by using multiple regression analyses with bootstrapping in order to examine the interaction effects. Results revealed that many aspectsof ER and EF were significant predictors of AC. In particular, with regards to ER, situational responsiveness, self-awareness, positive refocusing, positive reappraisal, rumination, and catastrophizing were robust predictors of AC. Findings also revealed that with regards to EF, planning and task completion predicted AC. Analyses confirmed the moderating effect of many ER skills including self-awareness, situational responsiveness, rumination, positive reappraisal, and the ability to put negative events into perspective. Adaptive ER abilities in particular acted as a moderator for well-developed AC, especially among students with the weakest EF. Taken together, these findings support the theoretical implication of poor ER as a risk factor with negative effects on both cognitive and academic functioning. Implications for school-based intervention are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le lien entre la régulation des émotions (RE), le fonctionnement exécutif (FE) et la compétence académique (CA) fait l’objet récent d’enquête, en particulier chez les très jeunes et dans un cadre d'auto-préparation au niveau de la maternelle. La RE désigne la surveillance et le contrôle des émotions ; le FE comprend les aptitudes cognitives telles que la planification et l'organisation ; et la CA concerne les compétences académiques et les résultats scolaires ainsi que les facilitateurs académiques (c.-à-d., les comportements nécessaires pour réussir à l’école, par exemple l'engagement et la motivation). Bien que l'adolescence soit une période turbulente en raison de l'augmentation du stress social, psychologique et scolaire, la RE, le FE et la CA sont mal compris chez ces jeunes. Plusieurs modèles de la RE et le FE suggèrent que (a) des perturbations dans la RE provoquent des perturbations dans le FE et le fonctionnement adaptatif, y compris la CA, (b) le FE et la RE sont interdépendants, (c) la RE agit comme un point d’accès au FE efficace et (d) le FE est composé d’éléments métacognitifs et des éléments de la RE qui interagissent pour initier la performance et la résolution efficace des problèmes (Barkley, 1997a, 2012 ; Blair &amp; Dennis, 2010 ; Blair &amp; Ursache, 2011 ; Zelazo et Cunningham, 2007). Tous ces modèles suggèrent que la RE soit une modératrice ou un tampon entre le FE métacognitif et le comportement adaptatif. Dans la présente étude, les interactions entre la RE, le FE et la CA ont été explorées chez un échantillon d'adolescents âgés entre 13 et 18 ans (n = 205 ; 130 femmes, 75 hommes). Le premier objectif de la présente étude fut d’examiner, à l’aide d’une régression multiple, comment les différents composants de la RE et le FE prédisent la CA. Plus précisément, l'hypothèse prédit que les élèves ayant une RE et un FE métacognitif bien développés aient une CA nettement meilleure. Le deuxième objectif de la présente étude fut d'examiner l'effet modérateur de la RE entre le FE métacognitif et la CA. Cet objectif fut atteint à l'aide d'analyses de régression multiple avec « bootstrap » afin d'examiner les effets d’interaction. Les résultats ont révélé que de nombreux aspects de la RE et du FE sont des variables explicatives importantes de la CA. En particulier, la réactivité à la situation, la conscience de soi, le recentrage positif, la réévaluation positive, la rumination et le catastrophisme (tous des compétences de la RE) furent des prédicteurs robustes des facilitateurs et compétences académiques ainsi que des résultats scolaires. Les résultats ont également révélé que la planification et l’organisation prédisent les compétences académiques. Les analyses ont confirmé l'effet modérateur de nombreuses compétences de la RE : la conscience de soi, la réactivité à la situation, la rumination, la réévaluation positive et la mise en perspective. Les capacités adaptatives de la RE agissent comme des tampons pour une CA bien développée, en particulier chez les élèves ayant un très faible FE. L’ensemble de ces résultats confirme l'implication théorique de la RE médiocre comme facteur de risque indépendant, ayant des effets négatifs sur le fonctionnement cognitif et académique. Les conséquences pour les interventions en milieu scolaire sont discutées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steven Shaw</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376085b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sk437</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r179z"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Pencil-regions": the pencil and paper of Robert Walser's micrography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schwebel, Shoshana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master’s thesis examines the writing materials of Robert Walser’s micrography, his pencil and papers, with respect to both their physical qualities and their figurative significance within the scope of Walser’s prose. As the first full-length study of Walser’s pencil and paper, my thesis aims to show that an understanding of Walser’s relationship to his writing materials is crucial in order to approach his middle to late writings. Crucial, because Walser’s switch to writing microscopically hinged on his change in writing materials, from the pen to the pencil, and gradually, from blank sheets of paper to tiny, pre-used scraps. I argue that these changes in Walser’s materials were first, a manifestation of his changing attitudes towards the ‘public’ (the industry of publishing as well as his readership); and second, a reflection of his long-term affinity with that which is small, peripheral, and overlooked. The thesis proceeds in three chapters. The first chapter exposes the material and metaphoric significance of Walser’s pencil and paper, while the second and third chapters search for the fictional presence of paper and pencil in Walser’s middle to late prose.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine la matière des « microgrammes » de Robert Walser, à savoir ses crayons et papiers, en se concentrant particulièrement sur leur caractère matériel,  ainsi que sur leur signification métaphorique dans la prose de Walser. En tant que première étude complète des crayons et des papiers, ma thèse cherche à démontrer que la compréhension du rapport qu’entretient Walser avec son matériel d’écriture est indispensable à l’étude de ses textes de milieu et de fin de carrière. Indispensable, puisque le mouvement de Walser vers l’écriture microscopique découle directement de la transformation de son matériel d’écriture, c’est-à-dire du stylo au crayon de plomb, et plus graduellement, des feuilles de papier vierge à de petits bouts de papier déjà utilisés. Mon projet soutient ainsi que cette transformation se révèle d’abord comme la manifestation d’un certain changement d’attitude envers le « public » (tant le milieu de l’édition que son lectorat), et ensuite, comme le reflet d’un attachement de longue date à ce qui est petit, périphérique et négligé.Cette thèse contient trois chapitres. Le premier s’attache à étudier les réseaux de significations matérielles et métaphoriques des crayons et papiers de Walser, tandis que les deuxième et troisième chapitres cherchent à repérer les marques de la présence fictive du papier et du crayon dans le contexte de sa prose tardive.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andrew Piper</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wt618.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r179z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Germanic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h7566"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of continous theta burst stimulation of human brain areas MT + and V1/V2 on color and motion perception</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaderali, Shaleeza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bien que les propriétés de l'information visuelle telles que la couleur, le mouvement, la forme et la profondeur soient intégrées perceptiblement, la plupart sont traitées séparément par différentes aires du cerveau. Cette étude porte sur les différents effets de la SMT (cTBS) des aires hMT+ et V1/V2 sur le mouvement global afin de comparativement révéler leurs rôles dans le traitement du mouvement chromatique et achromatique. De plus, cette étude compare les effets de la stimulation sur les seuils de détection et de discrimination afin de déterminer si ceux-ci présentent des origines physiologiques différentes, sachant qu'une dissociation entre ces deux types de seuils a été établie en psychophysique. Le report de phosphènes en mouvement ou statiques a été utilisé pour localiser les aires corticales hMT+ et V1/V2 respectivement. La position de la bobine qui générait le phosphène le plus intense était ciblée pour la perturbation par cTBS selon un protocole de stimulation magnétique transcrânienne répétitive. La région vertex a été utilisée comme contrôle pour les effets non-spécifiques de la cTBS. Les stimuli consistaient en des kinématogrammes à points aléatoires (RDKs) achromatiques ou isoluminescents-chromatiques. Les participants effectuaient une tâche de discrimination de mouvement lors de laquelle la direction de formes gaussiennes (gauche ou droite) était identifiée, et d'une simple tâche de détection, lors de laquelle la présence d'un stimulus à bas contraste devait être détectée sans tenir compte de son mouvement. Les seuils étaient mesurés avant, et quatre fois après la cTBS, durant une heure, afin d'étudier les effets de la cTBS sur la performance au cours du temps, étant donné que cela n'a pas encore été établi en vision. Les performances lors des tâches de discrimination de mouvement étaient significativement réduites par la cTBS de l'aire hMT+ à la fois pour les stimuli achromatiques et isoluminescents-chromatiques. En comparaison, aucun effet de la cTBS sur la performance n'a été observé lors de la stimulation des aires V1/V2 et vertex. Les effets maximaux ont été observés 10-11 minutes après la stimulation. Une heure après la stimulation, la performance revenait à son niveau de base. Aucun effet spécifique de la cTBS entre les trois aires corticales n'a été observé pour la tâche de détection. Cette étude a premièrement validé l'utilisation de la cTBS en tant qu'outil pour altérer le fonctionnement de l'aire hMT+. Ainsi, elle apporte des preuves supplémentaires que l'aire hMT+ est impliquée dans l'analyse du mouvement global à la fois chromatique et achromatique. L'aire hMT+ contribue au mouvement chromatique isoluminant. Les résultats indiquent un lien causal entre l'activité neuronale dans l'aire hMT+ et la perception du mouvement chromatique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Although aspects of the visual image such as color, motion, form, and depth appear perceptually integrated, many are processed separately in different, specialized areas of the brain. This study investigates the differential effects of repetitive TMS (cTBS) in areas hMT+ and V1/V2 on global motion in order to reveal their roles in isoluminant chromatic compared to achromatic motion processing. Additionally, this study compares the differential effect of stimulation on motion direction versus simple detection thresholds to determine whether they have different physiological origins, since a dissociation between these two types of threshold has been established psychophysically. The report of moving or stationary phosphenes was used to localize brain areas hMT+ and V1/V2, respectively. The coil-position within each area that elicited the strongest phosphene responses was targeted for disruption by cTBS, a repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation protocol. The vertex was used as a control for non-specific cTBS effects. Stimuli consisted of either isoluminant chromatic or achromatic random dot kinematograms (RDKs). Participants performed a motion discrimination task in which the direction of Gaussian blobs (left or right) was identified, and a simple detection task, in which the presence of a low contrast stimulus was detected regardless of motion. Thresholds were measured before and four times after cTBS stimulation within one hour to investigate the effects of cTBS on performance over time, as this has not yet been established for vision. Performances on the motion discrimination task for both achromatic and isoluminant chromatic stimuli were significantly impaired following cTBS of area hMT+. In comparison, no effect of cTBS on performance was seen for areas V1/V2 and vertex. Maximal effects occurred at 10-11 minutes after stimulation. One hour after stimulation, performance returned to baseline levels. No differential effects of cTBS between the three brain areas were observed for the detection task. This study firstly validated the use of cTBS as a tool to impair the function of area hMT+. In doing so, it provides additional evidence that area hMT+ is involved in the analysis of both achromatically as well as chromatically defined global motion. In conclusion, area hMT+ is contributing to chromatic motion seen at isoluminance. The results indicate a causal link between neural activity in area hMT+ and the perception of chromatic motion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kathleen T. Mullen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb41t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h7566</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752k99n"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional characterization of a novel ENU-induced mutation in Unc93b1 and its role in single-stranded RNA virus infection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lafferty, Erin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les PRRs constituent la première ligne de défense du système immunitaire inné contre les agents pathogènes envahissants. Ces protéines reconnaissent des PAMPs parfaitement conservés et déclenchent la signalisation en cascade à l’origine de l’activation de la réponse immunitaire. Les premiers PRR mis en évidence étaient des TLRs qui peuvent identifier un large éventail de motifs microbiens. Alors que certains d’entre eux se trouvent à la surface des membranes cellulaires, la reconnaissance des acides nucléiques d’origine étrangère à l’hôte s’effectue fréquemment à la surface des endosomes (TLR3, TLR7, et TLR9). Bien que ces TLRs endosomaux reconnaissent des PAMPs hautement conservés, leur contribution dans la défense immunitaire de l’hôte et le résultat en termes d’infection varient selon l’agent pathogène étudié.Pour étudier la contribution des protéines associées aux TLR dans l’activation du système immunitaire, nous avons mené une étude en mutagénèse chimique aléatoire. Cette étude a permis d’identifier une souris hyporéactive aux PAMPs associés aux récepteurs TLR3, TLR7, et TLR9. La cause de cette absence de réponse est une mutation dans le gène Unc93b1, le chaperon moléculaire qui accompagne les TLRs endosomaux du réticulum endoplasmique vers l’endosome. Cette mutation appelée Letr (loss of endosomal TLR response), cause une défaillance dans l’épissage du gène Unc93b1 qui se traduit par la perte de deux domaines transmembranaires de la protéine UNC93B1. Auparavant, le rôle protecteur d’UNC93B1 lors d’infections par des parasites ou des virus à ADN a été bien défini. En revanche, son rôle lors d’infections par des virus à ARN simple brin (ARNsb) est beaucoup moins caractérisé. Par conséquent, nous avons étudié la contribution de l’activation immunitaire contrôlée par UNC93B1 lors de deux modèles infectieux par deux virus à ARNsb différents, à savoir le virus de l’influenza A/PR/8/34 (H1N1) et le virus Coxsackie B3 (CVB3). Comme ces deux virus peuvent activer les récepteurs TLR3 et TLR7, nous avons utilisé pour chaque infection notre lignée de souris Unc93b1Letr/Letr pour définir un rôle spécifique à l’activation immunitaire contrôlée par les TLR endosomaux.Suivant une infection par le virus de l’influenza, les souris Unc93b1Letr/Letr présentaient une activation immunitaire innée réduite au site de l’infection, caractérisée par une diminution du recrutement des macrophages exsudats activés, de l’activation des cellules T et de la production des médiateurs inflammatoires. La défaillance Letr a entraîné un retard de la clairance virale pulmonaire et une augmentation de l’inflammation des voies respiratoires, mais n’a pas modifié la survie après infection de manière représentative. Ces résultats suggèrent que la signalisation contrôlée par UNC93B1 dans l’infection par le virus de l’influenza joue un rôle dans l’activation immunitaire précoce, mais qu’elle n’est pas requise pour déterminer un dénouement positif en cas d’infection.Par opposition, les souris Unc93b1Letr/Letr étaient plus sensibles aux myocardites virales aiguës induites par le CVB3, accompagnées d’une augmentation de la charge virale multi-organe et de lésions cardiaques avec présence d’une fibrose importante. L’analyse du transcriptome cardiaque suivant une infection au CVB3 a mis en évidence un dérèglement de l’expression des gènes de la réponse inflammatoire, ainsi que des gènes d’apprêtement et de présentation des antigènes exogènes au niveau du CMH de classe II chez les souris Unc93b1Letr/Letr. En particulier, l’expression des gènes Ifn-b, Lcn2, et Serpina3n avaient augmenté dans les tissus cardiaques des souris Unc93b1Letr/Letr au jour 2 suivant l’infection. En conclusion, ces études ont caractérisées une mutation unique dans Unc93b1 qui cause une perte de fonction. Nous avons aussi illustré une contribution variable des voies de signalisation activées par les TLR endosomaux à l’immunité de l’hôte après l’infection par deux virus à ARNsb différents. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) of the innate immune system are on the front line of host defense against an invading pathogen. These proteins recognize highly conserved pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMPs) and initiate signaling cascades that lead to immune activation. The first PRRs discovered were toll-like receptors (TLRs) that can recognize a broad range of microbial structures. While some TLRs localize to the cell membrane, recognition of foreign nucleic acid frequently occurs at the endosome through TLR3, TLR7, and TLR9. Though endosomal TLRs recognize conserved PAMPs, their contribution to host defense and infection outcome varies according to the pathogen under consideration.To investigate the contribution of TLR-associated proteins to immune activation we conducted random chemical mutagenesis using N-ethyl-N-nitrosourea (ENU) and found a deviant mouse that was hyporesponsive to TLR3-, TLR7-, and TLR9-specific PAMP stimulation in vitro and in vivo. This was caused by a mutation in Unc93b1, a chaperone that trafficks nucleic acid-sensing TLRs from the endoplasmic reticulum to the endosome for immune activation. The ENU-induced mutation in Unc93b1, which we termed Letr for ‘loss of endosomal TLR response’, causes a splicing defect that removes two transmembrane domains of the UNC93B1 protein. A protective role for UNC93B1 has been previously defined following infection with parasites or DNA viruses but its role in ssRNA viral infection has been less well characterized. Therefore, we studied the contribution of UNC93B1-mediated immune activation following infection with two ssRNA viruses; influenza A/PR/8/34 (H1N1) – an important global respiratory pathogen, and coxsackievirus group B type 3 (CVB3) – the most common etiological agent of viral myocarditis. As both pathogens are capable of activating TLR3 and TLR7, we used Unc93b1Letr/Letr mice to define a specific role for endosomal TLR-mediated immune activation in each infection.Following influenza infection, Unc93b1Letr/Letr mice had diminished innate immune activation at the site of infection that was characterized by decreased activated exudate macrophage recruitment, T cell activation, and inflammatory mediator production. The Letr defect led to delayed lung viral clearance and increased tissue inflammation but did not significantly alter infection survival. This suggests that Unc93b1-mediated signaling in influenza infection plays a role in early immune activation but is not required to define a positive infection outcome, a scenario that is most likely explained by the activation of additional host immune mechanisms.In contrast to influenza, Unc93b1Letr/Letr mice were significantly more susceptible to acute CVB3-induced viral myocarditis, accompanied by increased multi-organ viral load and cardiac injury with substantial fibrosis. Cardiac transcriptome analysis revealed dysregulated expression of inflammatory response genes as well as genes for antigen processing and presentation of exogenous peptide antigen via MHC class II in Unc93b1Letr/Letr mice. In particular, Unc93b1Letr/Letr hearts had increased expression of Ifn-b, Lcn2, and Serpina3n at day 2 post-infection. The latter two genes have been previously linked to tissue injury and fibrosis and may be contributing to the severe cardiac pathology observed during CVB3 infection. In conclusion, these studies have characterized a unique loss-of-function mutation in Unc93b1, and illustrated the varying contributions of the endosomal TLR pathway to immunity following infection with two different ssRNA viruses. Further detailed analysis of this mutant mouse could provide additional insights on the role of endosomal TLRs in immune activation and better define the process of host-pathogen interaction during virus infection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Salman Qureshi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v84r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752k99n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988p06g"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Half- and full-duplex amplify-and-forward single-relay systems: Achievable rates, power allocations and code designs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jiménez Rodríguez, Leonardo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Relaying techniques, in which a source node communicates to a destination node with the help of a relay, have been proposed as a cost-effective solution to address the ever increasing demand for high data rates and reliable services over the air. As such, it is crucial to design relay systems that are able to not only provide high spectral efficiency, but also fully exploit the diversity of the relay channel. With this objective in mind, this thesis investigates achievable rates, power allocation schemes, and code designs for half-duplex (HD) and full-duplex (FD) amplify-and-forward (AF) single-relay systems.The first part of the thesis is concerned with systems in which the relay operates in HD mode. First, we study the capacity and respective power allocation strategy for a non-orthogonal AF relay system over static channel gains. By assuming full channel state information (CSI) at all nodes, we derive the optimal input covariance matrix at the source and power allocation scheme at the relay that maximize the achievable rate under both per-node and sum power constraints. Second, we investigate the ergodic capacity for a wide range of AF protocols over Rayleigh fading channels. Assuming full CSI only at the destination node, a general method is proposed to obtain tight and simple approximations to the achievable rates in high and low transmission power regimes. The proposed approach is applicable to several one-way (OW) and two-way (TW) schemes using the conventional channel inversion or fixed-gain amplification coefficients. The derived approximations are then used not only to compare the protocols of interest, but also to characterize the asymptotically optimal allocations that maximize the achievable rate and sum rate for OW and TW schemes, respectively. Third, optimal amplification coefficients at the relay are developed based on the rate and sum rate criteria for OW and TW relaying. Specifically, optimal power adaptation schemes are established under a long-term average power constraint and assuming full CSI at the relay. Insights into proposed schemes are then discussed and numerical results are presented to quantify the gain of the adaptation techniques over the conventional approaches. Finally, turning our attention to the performance with finite constellations, we propose the idea of precoding over multiple cooperative frames for a non-orthogonal AF system over Rayleigh fading channels. In particular, by adopting the framework of bit-interleaved coded modulation (BICM), we show that multi-frame precoding is able to improve the diversity and approach the capacity of such an AF channel. The second part of this thesis deals with the FD mode of operation, where the residual self-interference due to FD transmission is explicitly taken into account. In particular, we assume that the self-interference variance is proportional to the lambda-th power of the transmitted power. First, we investigate the optimal power allocation scheme and corresponding capacity of a static dual-hop AF system with full CSI at all nodes. By analyzing such system in different high power regions, the role of lambda on the capacity is examined and comparisons to its HD counterpart are carried. Then, we focus on the error performance of several FD protocols over Rayleigh fading channels. Specifically, considering the same interference model, we analyze the error and diversity behavior of uncoded and coded systems, where we again adopt the framework of BICM. Similar to the capacity analysis, insights into the effect of lambda and comparisons to HD schemes are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La technique du relais, dans laquelle le nœud transmetteur communique avec le nœud destinataire à l’aide de relais, a été proposée comme une solution à coût réduit pour satisfaire l’augmentation de la demande du très haut débit et garantir les services par la communication sans fil. C’est pour cela qu’il est crucial de concevoir des systèmes de relais qui sont capables non seulement d’offrir une grande efficacité spectrale, mais aussi d’exploiter la diversité du canal relais. En considérant ces objectifs, cette thèse traite les débits atteignables, des schémas d’allocation de puissance, et la conception de codes pour le système à relai avec amplification-et-retransmission (amplify-and-forward ou AF) sous les modes half-duplex (HD) et full-duplex (FD).La première partie de la thèse est consacrée aux systèmes où les relais opèrent en mode HD. En premier lieu, nous étudions la capacité et les stratégies d’allocation de puissance pour un système AF non-orthogonal dans un canal à gains statiques. En assumant une connaissance parfaite du canal dans tous les nœuds, nous dérivons la matrice de covariance optimale à la source et un schéma d’allocation de puissance au relai qui maximisent le débit. En second lieu, nous examinons la capacité ergodique pour une multitude de protocoles AF dans un canal à évanouissement Rayleigh. En supposant une connaissance complète du canal à la destination, une méthode générale est proposée pour obtenir une approximation simple et étroite du débit dans les régions de large et basse puissance de transmission. L’approche proposée est applicable à plusieurs schémas unidirectionnels (one-way ou OW) et bidirectionnels  (two-way ou TW) utilisant les coefficients d’amplification du canal inversé ou à gain fixe. Les approximations dérivées sont utilisées non seulement pour comparer les protocoles en question, mais aussi pour caractériser les allocations asymptotiquement optimales qui maximisent le débit et la somme de débits pour les schémas OW et TW. En troisième lieu, les coefficients d’amplifications optimales au relai sont développés en se basant sur les critères de débit et de la somme de débit pour les relais OW et TW. Particulièrement, des schémas d’adaptations optimaux de puissance sont établis sous la contrainte de puissance à long terme et en assumant une connaissance complète du canal au relai. Finalement, en tournant notre attention à la performance avec des constellations finies, nous proposons l’idée de précodage pour un système AF non-orthogonal sur les canaux à évanouissement Rayleigh. En particulier, en adoptant le schéma de modulation codée avec entrelacement par bit (bit-interleaved coded modulation ou BICM), nous démontrons que le précodage est capable d’améliorer la diversité et d’approcher la capacité de ce canal AF. La seconde partie de cette thèse traite le mode de transmission opérant en FD, où l'autobrouillage résiduel causé par la transmission en FD est explicitement pris en considération. En particulier, nous assumons que la variance de l'autobrouillage est proportionnelle à la puissance de transmission portée à la puissance lambda. Premièrement, nous étudions un schéma d’allocation de puissance optimal et sa capacité pour un système AF statique avec connaissance totale du canal. En analysant ce système dans des régions à puissance élevée différentes, le rôle de lambda sur la capacité est examiné et comparé à son contrepartie HD. Ensuite, nous nous focalisons sur la performance en termes d’erreur de plusieurs protocoles FD dans les canaux à évanouissement Rayleigh. Particulièrement, en considérant le même modèle d’autobrouillage, nous analysons le taux d’erreur et la diversité pour les systèmes codés et non codés, où nous adaptons aussi le codage BICM. Tout comme l’analyse de la capacité, l’effet de lambda et une comparaison avec le schéma HD sont discutés.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tho Le-Ngoc</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z12k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p06g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311s56p"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A novel postsynaptic role for DDC in synaptic plasticity in the adult mammalian hippocampus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thompson-Steckel, Greta</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>S'il est bien connu que la nétrine-1 et son récepteur deleted in colorectal cancer (DCC) sont essentiels pour le développement normal du système nerveux, on ne sait pas pourquoi leur expression persiste dans le système nerveux adulte. Nous avons récemment démontré que DCC est exprimé au niveau des synapses dans le cerveau de mammifères mature et qu'il régule la fonction des synapses et leur plasticité. Les fonctions pré- et post-synaptiques précises de DCC au niveau des synapses établies chez l'adulte ne sont pas encore comprises. Pour étudier le rôle spécifique de DCC post-synaptique, nous avons généré des souris R4ag11 :: Cre / DCC floxé chez lesquelles l'expression de DCC est éliminée de manière sélective dans les neurones pyramidaux du CA1 de l'hippocampe une fois le début du développement achevé, tandis que l'expression de DCC dans les neurones pré-synaptiques de la région CA3 adjacente est restée intacte. Cette perte conditionnelle de DCC dans les neurones post-synaptiques du CA3-CA1 entrainent une morphologie dendritique anormale de la colonne vertébrale dans les neurones CA1 de souris âgées malgré le maintien global de l'organisation topographique et de la densitée dendritique de la colonne vertébrale. Le manque de DCC post-synaptique dans ces animaux transgéniques a également entraîné des déficits dans les tâches de reconnaissance de la mémoire spatiale et de nouveau lieu mais n'a pas réussi à perturber la mémoire de reconnaissance de nouveaux objets, ce qui suggère que la suppression sélective de DCC dans les neurones de CA1 entraîne des perturbations dans les circuits neuronaux sous-jacents de la mémoire spatiale contextuelle. Ensemble, ces résultats fournissent la preuve d'un rôle post-synaptique critique pour DCC dans des souris adultes et que DCC contribue à la consolidation de la mémoire lors de la navigation spatiale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>While it is well known that netrin-1 and its receptor Deleted in Colorectal Cancer (DCC) are essential for normal neural development, it remains unclear why their expression persists in the adult nervous system. We have recently demonstrated that DCC is expressed at synapses in the mature mammalian brain and that it regulates synapse function and plasticity. The precise pre- and post-synaptic functions of DCC at established synapses in the adult is not yet understood. To study the specific post-synaptic role of DCC, we generated R4ag11::Cre/DCC floxed mice in which DCC expression is selectively eliminated from CA1 hippocampal pyramidal neurons once early development has been completed, while DCC expression in the pre-synaptic neurons of the adjacent CA3 region remained intact. This conditional loss of DCC from the CA3-CA1 post-synaptic neuron resulted in abnormal dendritic spine morphology in CA1 neurons in aging mice despite maintaining overall organization and spine density. Post-synaptic DCC deficiency in these transgenic animals also resulted in deficits in spatial memory and novel place recognition tasks but failed to disrupt novel object recognition memory, suggesting that selective deletion of DCC in CA1 neurons results in disturbances in the neural circuits underlying contextual spatial memory. Together, these findings provide evidence for a critical post-synaptic role for DCC in adult mice and that DCC contributes to memory consolidation during spatial navigation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Timothy E. Kennedy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn45h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s56p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fv78k"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Emotional experiences and their relationship to epistemic change: a multiple case study of Chinese graduate students in a Canadian university</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Xihui</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le but de cette étude de cas multiples est de détailler et comprendre les expériences émotionnelles des élèves chinois du troisième cycle, et d'évaluer les relations possibles entre leurs expériences émotionnelles et leurs changements épistémiques au cours de leur premier semestre dans une université de recherche intensive canadienne. En particulier, les enquêtes ont été faites en demandant quatorze étudiants représentatifs chinois 1) de répondre à quatre questions sur leur croyance épistémique, à deux reprises, au début et à la fin de leur premier semestre; et 2) de témoigner leurs expériences émotionnelles par le biais de notes bimensuelles dans un journal intime (six notes tout au long du premier semestre).Plus spécifiquement, l'analyse de contenu a été menée afin d'examiner la portée et la nature des expériences émotionnelles de l'ensemble des élèves, ainsi que celles de leurs expériences émotionnelles les plus saillantes (les émotions les plus souvent rencontrées, et les émotions les plus fortes). Les résultats montrent que ces étudiants internationaux chinois ont connu une vie affective riche et intense dans la phase initiale de leurs études supérieures ainsi que dans leurs vies sociales. Parmi toutes les émotions rapportées, les plus soulignées sont le stress, la joie et l'anxiété. Les fluctuations des émotions discrètes indiquent une relation entre la nature des émotions et la charge de travail et le niveau de stress rencontrés dans leur parcours académique. Une procédure de codage ouvert a été appliquée aux notes (de journaux intimes) portant sur les incidents ayant déclenchés des expériences émotionnelles importantes. Les résultats identifient trois sources principales d'émotions: la source académique, la source de soi-même, et la source sociale; ces étudiants ont été plus affectés par les émotions de source académique et auto-née plutôt que social. Les résultats suggèrent aussi qu'il n'y aurait pas de relation définitive entre les expériences émotionnelles des élèves et leurs changements épistémique. Cependant, des sources liées à soi  (ex: les méta-émotions) se sont révélées être des facteurs importants qui influencent à la fois la nature des émotions des élèves aient ainsi que leur volonté à faire un changement épistémique.Les résultats de cette étude soutiennent non seulement les théories actuelles sur les croyances épistémiques, mais aussi font progresser les travaux empiriques dans ce domaine en identifiant l'importance du soi comme lien potentiel entre les émotions et les expériences épistémiques. Les émotions de source soi peuvent jouer un rôle important dans le processus de changement épistémique. De plus, ces résultats donnent lieu à des applications bénéfiques aidant les enseignants à harmoniser le bien-être des étudiants provisoires internationaux et d'optimiser leur apprentissage.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The purpose of this multiple case study was to describe and understand Chinese graduate students’ emotional experiences, and to explore the possible relationships between their emotional experiences and their epistemic change in their first semester in a Canadian research-intensive university.  In particular, investigations were made by asking fourteen purposively sampled Chinese international students to 1) respond to four questions about epistemic beliefs twice, at the beginning and the end of their first semester respectively; and 2) to record their emotional experiences in six biweekly journals throughout the first semester.Specifically, content analysis was conducted to examine the range and nature of students’ overall emotional experiences, as well as those of their significant emotional experiences (i.e., the most often experienced emotions, and the strongest emotions). Results demonstrate that these Chinese international students experienced a rich and intense emotional life in academic as well as social settings in their initial stage of graduate studies. Among all the emotions reported, the most highlighted ones are stress, joy and anxiety. Fluctuations of discrete emotions indicate a correspondence between the nature of emotions and the workload and stress level of their academic life.  An open coding procedure was applied to participants’ accounts of the triggering incidents of the significant emotional experiences. Results identified three sources of emotions: academic-related, self-related, and social-related sources; these students were more affected by academic- and self-originated emotions rather than social-originated ones.  Results suggest no definitive relation between students’ emotional experiences and epistemic change.  However, self-related sources (e.g., meta-emotion) were found to be important factors that influence both the nature of emotions that students have as well as their readiness for epistemic change.  Findings of this study not only support current theories about epistemic beliefs, but also advance empirical work in this area by identifying self as a possible key link between students’ emotions and epistemic experiences. Self-related emotions may play an important role in the change process. Furthermore, these results have implications for educators to promote international sojourners’ well-being and optimize their learning.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alenoush Saroyan</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mark Wesley Aulls</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f668w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv78k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301455z"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular determinants influencing CEACAM1-L-mediated inhibition of MC38 murine colon cancer metasasis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Forrest, Laura</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The two major isoforms of CEACAM1 (CC1) have different effects on colorectal cancer (CRC) growth and metastasis.  Izzi et al. have shown that CC1-L Tyrosine phosphorylation inhibits CRC growth and metastasis in vivo in xenograft assays, which opposes the minimal effect of CC1-S.  It has also been shown in mouse colon carcinoma CT51 cells that the Ser503A residue is essential for Tyr488 phosphorylation, and that mutants of the three lysines (3K-3A) at the C-terminus of the protein display similar results.  However, the impact on CRC metastasis of these last mutants is unknown.  We introduced the Ser503 and 3K-3A mutants into the MC38 murine CRC cell line and selected and sorted cell populations for these mutants.  Proliferation of these mutant cell lines was assessed in vitro.  Then, the mutant CRC mouse cell lines (MC38) intrasplenically injected into mice (C57Bl/6) to investigate their metastatic ability in vivo.  The metastatic burden was measured in the liver of these animals, and it was found that mutation of the Ser503, Ser516, and 3 terminal Lys abrogated the tumor inhibitory phenotype of CC1-L.  Future studies include identifying the kinase responsible for Ser503 phosphorylation and identifying the pathways involved.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les deux isoformes principales de CEACAM1 (CC1) ont des effets différents sur la croissance et la métastase du cancer colorectal (CRC).  Izzi et al. ont démontré par des analyses xénogreffes que la phosphorylation des tyrosines de CC1-L inhibe la croissance et la métastase du CRC in vivo, ce qui oppose l’effet minimal du CC1-S.  Dans les cellules murines colorectales CT51, il a été démontré que le résidu Ser503 est essentiel pour la phosphorylation du Tyr488, et que les mutants des trois lysines (3K-3A) produisent des résultats similaires.  Cependant, l’effet de ces mutants sur la métastase du CRC est inconnu.  Nous avons donc généré des lignées mutantes dans la lignée colorectale métastatique MC38 par infections rétrovirales de ces mutants.  Nous avons sélectionné des populations de cellules et isolé des populations uniformes par triage cellulaire.  La prolifération de ces lignées cellulaires mutantes a été évaluée in vitro.  Ensuite, les lignées cellulaires murines et mutantes du CRC (MC38) ont été injectées dans la rate des souris C57Bl/6 afin d’évaluer leur capacité métastatique in vivo.  La charge métastatique du foie a été mesurée, et nous avons trouvé que la mutation des Ser503, Ser516, et des 3 Lys terminales diminue le phénotype de la lignée exprimant CC1-L, qui agit comme un inhibiteur des tumeurs.  Les études ultérieures porteront sur l’identification de la kinase qui phosphoryle le Ser503 et des voies de signalisation qui  sont impliquées. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giuseppina Ursini-Siegel</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Nicole Beauchemin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nx76f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301455z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c575z"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Receptor tyrosine kinases in granulosa cells of ovulating follicles in mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schuermann, Yasmin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Expulsion d'un ovocyte fécondable à partir des follicules nécessite l'action des signaux extracellulaires et intracellulaires, y compris ceux médiés par les récepteurs de tyrosine kinase (RTK). L'activation du récepteur épidermique de facteur de croissance (Egfr) a été bien établi suivant le pic préovulatoire de l'hormone lutéinisante (LH). Cependant, les rôles potentiels pour les autres RTK et de leurs facteurs de croissance respectifs n'ont pas été profondement étudiées au moment du pic LH. Par conséquent, l'objectif de ce projet était d'analyser la signalisation des facteurs de croissance induite par LH dans les cellules de la granulosa de souris. Des échantillons de cellules de la granulosa ont été recueillies à partir des souris, superstimulé avec la gonadotrophine chorionique équine (eCG) et la gonadotrophine chorionique humaine (hCG) à 48 h d'intervalle. Nous avons utilisé le Mouse Phospho-RTK Array Kit afin de determiner les RTK qui sont activés par une signalisation de LH. Il y avait une augmentation de la phosphorylation du récepteur de fibroblastes de facteur de croissance 2 (Fgfr2) et le récepteur éphrine B1 (Ephb1) dans les cellules de la granulosa à 4h hCG par rapport à 0h hCG. Nous avons mesuré l'expression des gènes codant pour des isoformes Fgfr et Ephb1 avec leurs ligands respectifs. L'abondance de l'ARNm relative des récepteurs n'a pas changé sur le traitement de l'hCG. Cependant, les niveaux de leurs facteurs de croissance respectifs, Fgf2 et Efnb1, ont augmenté de manière significative à hCG4h. Nous avons également constaté que l’abondance de protéine de Fgf2 a augmenté à hCG4h. De plus, l'augmentation de l'expression du Fgf2 a été associée à une diminution de la quantité d'ARNm Spry3, un membre de la famille Sprouty de protéines connues pour inhiber la signalisation de Fgf. Enfin, le traitement par voie intrapéritonéale avec deux inhibiteurs de Fgfr (AZD4547 ou BGJ398) n'a pas modifié le taux d'ovulation. Dans l'ensemble, la présente étude a identifié deux nouvelles voies RTK dans les cellules de la granulosa des follicules pré-ovulatoires chez la souris. Le stimulus ovulatoire de hCG induit l'expression du Fgf2 et Efnb1 en liaison avec une phosphorylation accrue de leurs récepteurs respectifs, Fgfr2 IIIC et EphB1 dans les cellules de la granulosa. Cependant, les voies de signalization de Fgfs et éphrines ne semblent pas être obligatoire pour l'ovulation. Leur association temporelle avec la lutéinisation suggère qu'ils peuvent participer à la formation de la CL.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Successful expulsion of a fertilizable oocyte from follicles, ovulation, requires the actions of extracellular and intracellular signals including those mediated by receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) and growth factors. The activation of the epidermal growth factor receptor (Egfr) has been well established during ovulation induced by the preovulatory surge of luteinizing hormone (LH). However, potential roles for other RTKs and their respective growth factors have not been thoroughly studied during ovulation. Therefore, the aim of this project was to analyze growth factor signaling induced by LH in mouse granulosa cells of ovulating follicles. Granulosa cell samples were collected from immature mice, superstimulated with equine chorionic gonadotropin (eCG) and human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) at 48h apart. We used the Mouse Phospho-RTK Array Kit to systematically catalogue the RTKs that are activated by LH signaling. There was an increase in phosphorylation of fibroblast growth factor receptor 2 (Fgfr2) and ephrin receptor B1 (EphB1) in granulosa cells at 4h post-hCG when compared to 0h hCG. We measured the expression of the genes encoding Fgfr isoforms and EphB1 along with their respective ligands. The relative mRNA abundance of the receptors did not change upon hCG treatment. However, transcript levels of their respective ligands, fibroblast growth factor 2 (Fgf2) and ephrin-B1 (Efnb1), increased significantly at 4h post-hCG. We also found that protein abundance of Fgf2 increased at hCG4h. Further qPCR analyses revealed that increased Fgf2 expression was associated with decreased mRNA abundance of Spry3, a member of the Sprouty family of proteins known to inhibit FGF signaling. Finally, intraperitoneal treatment with two Fgfr inhibitors (AZD4547 or BGJ398) did not alter ovulation rate when compared to vehicle treatment. Taken together, the present study investigated two RTK pathways in granulosa cells of preovulatory ovulating follicles in mice. The ovulatory stimulus with hCG induces the expression of the ligands Fgf2 and Efnb1 in association with increased phosphorylation of their respective receptors, Fgfr2 IIIC and Ephb1 in granulosa cells. However, FGF and ephrin pathways do not appear to be obligatory for ovulation. Their temporal association with luteinization suggests that they may participate in the formation of the CL, which require further investigation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raj Duggavathi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k121k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c575z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g570b"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Statistical accuracy of image correlation spectroscopy: applications to ligand-receptor binding, flow and molecular diffusion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brandão, Hugo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un outil important dans la biologie moléculaire est la microscopie par fluorescence, qui permet de sonder des interactions biomoléculaires dans les cellules vivantes. La microscopie par fluorescence enregistre des vidéos contenant la dynamique et la cinétique des molécules marqueés pendant qu'elles s'interagissent dans une cellule. k-Space image correlation spectroscopy (kICS) est une technique qui utilise les fluctuations d'intensité de pixels de ces films afin de fournir une description quantitative des mouvements moléculaires. Cependant, la puissance quantitative de cette technique est limitée par des facteurs expérimentaux tels que l'étendue spatiale de l'image, et le temps d'acquisition d'image; ces facteurs vont systématiquement biaiser l'estimation des paramètres dans les modèles stochastiques s'ils ne sont pas considerés. Dans cette thèse, des modèles quantitatifs biophysiques sont conçus qui incorporent les contraintes spatiales et temporelles finies d'expériences de transport et de signalisation des protéines.L'applicabilité de kICS est étendue au-delà de la simple mesure de transport des protéines, en dérivant des modèles biophysiques pour les interactions de liaison ligand-récepteur. Deux types de modèles expérimentaux sont pris en compte: (A) des ligands libres en solution marqués par fluorescence interagissent avec des récepteurs non marqués qui diffusent dans le plan focal du microscope, et (B) récepteurs qui diffusent dans le plan focal se lient et délient, s'interconvertissant entre deux différents états de diffusion. % Avec la démonstration de deux applications expérimentales de ces modèles , la voie est pavée à l'aide CIEk comme une méthode efficace et fiable pour élucider taux liaison cinétique pour des études dans les membranes biologiques .Le biais dans l'estimation des paramètres des modèles dérivés est exploré théoriquement en employant la théorie de l'échantillonnage. Une théorie est conçue pour améliorer considérablement la portée et la précision des analyses avec kICS normalisées de données finies par une expansion par perturbation au première ordre. Un cadre est général est aussi développé pour tenir compte de l'étendue spatiale finie de l'image. Les théories analytiques sont ensuite comparées aux données de simulation pour vérifier les corrections de biais.Finalement, il est montré que les déformations de la fonction d'étalement du point par suite des effets combinés du mouvement des particules, de la photophysique de fluorescence, et du temps d'acquisition du signal biaisent systématiquement l'estimation des paramètres. Une nouvelle extension de kICS est développée en utilisant le calcul intégral stochastique pour corriger cette source d'erreur. En conclusion, cette thèse améliore l'applicabilité des outils de corrélation d'images pour fournir des descriptions quantitatives des rouages de la cellule. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>An important tool in molecular biology is fluorescence video microscopy, which helps to probe biomolecular interactions in living cells. As fluorescently tagged molecules interact within a cell, fluorescence microscopy acquires movies of their dynamics and kinetics. k-Space image correlation spectroscopy (kICS) is a spatio-temporal image correlation technique which uses pixel intensity fluctuations from such movies to provide a quantitative description of the molecular movements. However, the quantitative power of this technique is limited by experimental factors such as finite image size and finite image acquisition times; not accounting for such factors can systematically bias parameter estimation in the conventional image correlation models. In this thesis, quantitative biophysical models are developed to reflect the finite space and time constrains of experiments involving protein transport and signaling. By deriving biophysical models for ligand-receptor binding interactions, the applicability of kICS is extended beyond simple measurement of protein transport. Two kinds of experiments are considered: (A) fluorescently labeled, free ligands in solution interact with unlabeled, diffusing receptors in an imaging plane and (B) diffusing receptors in the imaging plane are allowed to bind/unbind and inter-convert between two different diffusing states. Next, the bias in parameter estimation of the derived models is explored theoretically using methods from sampling theory. A first-order temporal perturbation theory is developed to significantly improve the range and accuracy of normalized, finite kICS measurements. A general framework is also incorporated to account for the finite spatial extent of images. The analytical theories are compared to simulation data to verify the accuracy of the bias corrections.  Finally, it is shown that deformations of the optical point-spread-function due to the combined effects of particle motion, fluorescence photophysics, and the finite signal acquisition time (pixel dwell time) of the imaging device can systematically bias parameter estimation. A novel extension of kICS, time-integrated kICS, is developed using stochastic integral calculus to correct for this source of error. Overall, this thesis extends the range and applicability of image correlation tools to provide quantitative descriptions of the inner workings of the cell. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Wiseman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c371p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g570b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042x25t"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessing bimanual performance in brain tumor resection using a novel virtual reality simulator NeuroTouch</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alotaibi, Fahad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: La plate-forme NeuroTouch est un simulateur de réalité virtuelle avec retour de force haptique, qui peuvent être utilisées pour évaluer les performances neurochirurgie dans un environnement expérimental. La validité de ce simulateur est critique à la réalisation de l'objectif de l'utilisation de ce simulateur neurochirurgical dans la formation, l'évaluation et l'élaboration de programmes d'enseignement.Méthodes:  Cette étude a été menée pour évaluer les performances bimanuelles de résidents et groupes de consultants resecting une variété de simulé tumeurs cérébrales avec purge et complexité différente. Treize des métriques ont été évalués, notamment: distance totale parcourue par la pointe de l'aspirateur à ultrasons et d'aspiration (TTPL), La force maximale appliquée (AMF) et la somme des forces utilisées (SFU) par instruments simulées, une perte de sang (BL), indice de l'efficacité, l'aspirateur à ultrasons longueur de chemin index (PLI), l'aspirateur à ultrasons bimanuelles rapport de forces (BFR), la coordination des index et simulé total normal du cerveau volume retiré (BVR), et la tumeur pourcentage spécimen tumoral prélevé (corrélé (TPR). Trois hypothèses ont été évalués: 1)La complexité de la tumeur simulé influences caractéristiques performances neurochirurgicales. 2)Neurochirurgie Consultants performances est moins influencé par les tumeurs la complexité.3) Nouvelles mesures de performances neurochirurgie différencier les performances parmi les résidents et consultant groupes Résultats: Notre analyse a montré des différences dans les performances en fonction de la tumeur la raideur, la couleur et la distinction de tumeur frontière. Les résidents réduire sensiblement moins tumeur pourcentage d'exploitation sur le disque dur, noir, et frontière indistincte tumeurs par rapport aux consultants. Groupes de résidents avaient sensiblement plus élevés sang perte d'exploitation sur le disque dur et noir tumeurs, plus d'aspirateur à ultrasons TTPL sur disque dur ou soft la tumeur et d'aspiration plus élevé l'MFA, SFU, TTPL de consultant group Entre les groupes analyse a montré une importante différence entre les consultants, senior et junior résidents sur indice d'efficacité, à ultrasons aspirateur PLI indépendamment des caractéristiques de la tumeur. Coordination index a montré une importante différence entre résidents junior et des consultants. Aspirateur à ultrasons BFR a montré une importante différence entre résidents senior junior et résidents.Conclusion: La plate-forme NeuroTouch utilisant les scénarios simulés employées différencie entre les trois groupes étudiés en fonction du niveau de formation. Notre étude est la première à démontrer les différences significatives en neurochirurgie bimanuelles performances basé sur la tumeur simulé la complexité. La tumeur croissante complexité en augmentant la rigidité et la diminution de la distinction de la frontière influences résident bimanuelles groupes significativement les performances plus de consultants.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: The NeuroTouch platform is a virtual reality simulator with haptic feedback utilized to assess neurosurgical performance in experimental risk-free environments. Validation of NeuroTouch is critical to the goal of using this simulator in neurosurgical training, evaluation and curriculum development.Methods:  This study was conducted to assess bimanual performance of resident and consultant groups resecting a number of simulated brain tumours with bleeding and increasing complexity. Thirteen novel NeuroTouch derived metrics were assessed including: blood loss (BL), tumour percentage resected (TPR), total simulated normal brain volume removed (BVR), total tip path length (TTPL), the maximum force applied (MFA) and sum of forces utilized (SFU) of the simulated ultrasonic aspirator and suction, efficiency index, ultrasonic aspirator path length index (PLI), ultrasonic aspirator bimanual forces ratio (BFR), and coordination index.The three hypotheses assessed were:1) Complexity of simulated tumour characteristics influences neurosurgical performance.2) Consultants neurosurgical performance is less influenced by tumours complexity.3) Novel performance metrics differentiate neurosurgical performance among resident and consultant groups.Results: Our analysis demonstrated significant differences in performance based on tumour stiffness, colour, and distinctness of tumour border. Residents resect significantly less tumour percentage operating on hard, black, and indistinct border tumours compared to neurosurgeons. Resident groups had significantly higher blood loss operating on hard and black tumours, longer ultrasonic aspirator TTPL on hard vs. soft tumour, and higher suction MFA, SFU, and TTPL than consultant group.Between groups analysis outlined significant difference between the consultants, senior, and junior residents on efficiency index, ultrasonic aspirator PLI regardless of tumour characteristics. Coordination index showed significant difference between junior residents and neurosurgeons. Ultrasonic aspirator BFR showed significant difference between senior and junior residents.Conclusion: The NeuroTouch platform utilizing the simulated scenarios and novel metrics employed differentiates among the three groups studied based on level of training. Modulating tumour complexity by increasing tumour stiffness and decreasing distinctness of tumour borders significantly impairs resident groups bimanual performance more than neurosurgeons. Our study is the first to demonstrate significant differences in neurosurgical bimanual performance based on simulated tumour complexity and provides validation for the NeuroTouch simulator.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rolando Fausto Del Maestro</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j854g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x25t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn9999784"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Topics in early universe cosmology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McDonough, Evan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse concerne deux questions de la cosmologie de l’univers primordial,telles qu’adressées dans les articles arXiv:1305.5259 et arXiv:1402.5112.Dans la première partie de cette thèse, nous examinons l’évolution des pertur-bations cosmologiques dans un univers rebondissant sans singularité à deux champs.Les champs que contiennent ce modèle consistent en un champ scalaire massif (champde matière) et un champ de type “galileon” (champ de rebondissement). Le champde matière mène à un univers en contraction dominé par de la matière froide et sanspression, tandis que le champ de rebondissement mène à une violation de la condi-tion d’énergie de genre lumière et à un rebondissement sans singularité à une énergiesous l’échelle de Planck. Nous étudions l’évolution des fluctuations de courbure etd’entropie à travers le rebondissement, et nous montrons qu’elles ont tous les deuxun spectre indépendant de l’échelle. Par contre, nous trouvons que les fluctuationsd’entropie ont une amplitude qui est beaucoup plus petite que les perturbations decourbure lors du rebondissement.Dans la deuxième partie de cette thèse, nous étudions la limite de la supergravitéde la théorie des cordes de type IIB couplée à des flux, des champs scalaires, des D-branes, des anti D-branes, et des plans orientifold. Nous montrons que cette théorien’admet pas de solutions avec un espace de Sitter à quatre dimensions. Nous éten-dons l’analyse pour inclure des corrections de courbure d’ordres supérieurs, et noustrouvons qu’une solution de Sitter dans la théorie de type IIB peut Ãłtre obtenue siles corrections de courbure d’ordres supérieurs sont soigneusement contrôlées.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis concerns two questions in Early Universe Cosmology, as addressedin the papers arXiv:1305.5259 and arXiv:1402.5112.In the first part of this thesis, we examine the evolution of cosmological per-turbations in a two-field non-singular bouncing cosmology. The field content ofthis model consists of a canonical massive (“matter") scalar field and a galileon-like(“bounce") field. The matter field leads to an effective cold, pressureless, matterdominated contracting universe at early times, while the bounce field leads to a vi-olation of the Null Energy Condition and a non-singular bounce at a sub-Planckianenergy scale. We study the evolution of both curvature and entropy fluctuationsthrough the bounce, and show that both have a scale-invariant spectrum. However,we find that the entropy fluctuations have an amplitude that is much smaller thanthat of the curvature perturbations, due to gravitational amplification of curvatureperturbations during the bounce phase.In the second part of this thesis, we study the supergravity limit of Type IIBstring theory coupled to fluxes, scalar fields, D-branes, anti D-branes and Orientifold-planes. We show that this theory does not admit solutions with a four-dimensionalde Sitter space. We extend the analysis to include higher-order curvature correc-tions, and find that a de Sitter solution in type IIB theory may be achieved if thehigher-order curvature corrections are carefully controlled.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert Brandenberger</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268838p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9999784</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Theory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247dw41k"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inapproximability of combinatorial problems in subexponential-time</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laekhanukit, Bundit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many natural combinatorial optimization problems turn out to be NP-hard. A standard way to cope with these problems is to design an algorithm that outputs an approximate solution and still runs in polynomial-time. Although a decent solution can sometime be found, many of the natural problems that we encounter, e.g., the maximum independent set and graph coloring problems, resist almost every approximation algorithm. In fact, assuming P &lt;&gt; NP, there exists a barrier that prevents us to get arbitrarily close to an optimal solution. Thus, understanding the limit in which one can find an approximate solution is an important subject in theoretical computer science.This thesis studies the inapproximability of combinatorial optimization problems in the fashion of time-approximability trade-off. In particular, assuming the exponential-time hypothesis, we show that even allowing an algorithm to run in subexponential-time, some problems cannot be approximated to within some factors.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Beaucoup de problèmes d'optimisation combinatoire naturelle s'avèrent être des problèmes NP. Une méthode standard pour faire face à ces problèmes consiste à concevoir un algorithme qui fournit une solution approchée et qui fonctionne toujours en temps polynomial. Même si une solution décente peut parfois être trouvée, de nombreux problèmes physiques que nous rencontrons, par exemple, un ensemble indépendant maximal et des problèmes de coloration des graphes, résistent à presque chaque algorithme d'approximation. En fait, en supposant que P &lt;&gt; NP, il existe une barrière qui nous empêche d'obtenir arbitrairement proche de la solution optimale. Ainsi, en comprenant la limite dans laquelle on peut une solution approchée est un sujet important dans l'informatique théorique.Cette thèse étudie l'inapproximabilité des problèmes d'optimisation combinatoire sous la forme d'un un compromis au niveau de l'approximabilité du temps. En particulier, en nous basant sur l'hypothèse exponentielle-temps, nous montrons que même en permettant à un algorithme d'être exécuté en temps sous-exponentiel, certains problèmes ne peuvent pas être estimés dans certains facteurs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Adrian Roshan Vetta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs99n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw41k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f6695"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the scalability and security of distributed multiplayer online games</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yahyavi Firouz Abadi, Seyed Amir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Multiplayer Online Games (MOGs) are an extremely popular online technology, one that produces billions of dollars in revenues. Yet, providing scalable, fast, and cheat-resistant games is challenging. In this thesis we propose solutions to some of these challenges.The underlying architecture plays a crucial role in enabling the games to meet the scalability, response time, and low cost requirements that are of utmost importance in designing a successful massively multiplayer online game. Peer-to-peer architectures where the game runs exclusively on client machines, and hybrid approaches, where some tasks run on the clients while a central server controls other aspects, have, due to their distributed and collaborative nature, low infrastructure costs, and can achieve high scalability. They can also achieve fast response times by creating direct connections between players. However, they introduce their own challenges such as cheating. As one contribution of this thesis, we provide a comprehensive overview of current peer-to-peer and hybrid solutions for massively multiplayer games using a uniform terminology.Most of the solutions we studied fail to meet one of the following main requirements: (1) fast response time, (2) scalability, (3) cheat-resistance. This thesis makes several proposals that address these requirements: Watchmen, mobile security, AntReckoning, and AntAI.Watchmen is the first distributed scalable protocol designed with cheat detection and prevention in mind that supports fast paced games. It is based on a randomized dynamic proxy scheme for both the dissemination and verification of actions. We show that Watchmen, while scaling to hundreds of players and meeting the tight latency requirements of first person shooter games, is able to significantly reduce opportunities to cheat, even in the presence of collusion. In the context of cheating we also look at the fast rising genre of mobile games. We discuss existing and potential new avenues of cheating that can occur in such mobile environment, and suggest several solutions to improve security based on existing and novel services that are or can be offered by carriers, ecosystems, and developers.AntReckoning is a dead-reckoning algorithm, inspired from ant colonies, which models players' interests to predict their movements. It helps our architecture by allowing us to send updates at lower frequencies and with more accurate predictions which in turn improves the scalability and the quality of experience of the players. AntReckoning incorporates a player's interest in specific locations, objects, and avatars in the equations of motion in the form of attraction forces. In practice, these points of interest generate pheromones, which spread and fade in the game world, and are a source of attraction. AntReckoning greatly improves the accuracy of traditional dead reckoning techniques and can decrease the upload bandwidth by up to a third of overall traffic.Interest modeling can also be used to improve the performance of non-player characters in games. In our AntAI project, we detail how movements, interactions, use of items, and relying on static decision-making schemes result in markedly different behaviors from humans in a popular fist-person shooter game. From there, we propose a framework relying on our pheromone maps, which can lead to a more adaptive human-like behavior.Altogether, this thesis presents components that we believe are key elements for a scalable, cheat-resistant, and fast multiplayer online game architecture.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les jeux multijoueurs en ligne constituent à l’heure actuelle une technologie en ligne très populaire qui génère des milliards de dollars en revenus. En dépit de cela, offrir des jeux qui sont à la fois extensibles, rapides et résistants à la tricherie est toujours un défi. Dans cette thèse, nous proposons des solutions à certains de ces défis.L’architecture sous-jacente joue un rôle crucial lorsque l’on souhaite développer des jeux qui rencontrent des contraintes d’extensibilité, de faible temps de réponse et de faible coût. Ces contraintes sont d’une importance capitale si l’on souhaite que le jeu massivement multijoueurs en ligne ainsi développé devienne un succès. Les architectures pair-à-pair, où le jeu s’exécute uniquement sur les machines des clients (joueurs), ainsi que les approches hybrides, où certaines tâches du jeu s’exécutent sur les machines des clients tandis qu’un serveur central gère d’autres aspects du jeu, permettent, de par leur nature distribuée et collaborative, d’atteindre une haute extensibilité tout en minimisant les coûts d’infrastructure. Ces architectures permettent également d’atteindre des temps de réponse élevés en établissant des connexions directes entre les joueurs. Cependant, elles introduisent également certains défis à résoudre tels que la possibilité de tricher. En tant que contribution à cette thèse, nous exposons une vue d’ensemble exhaustive des solutions pair-à-pair et hybrides courantes pour les jeux massivement multijoueurs en ligne utilisant une technologie uniforme.La plupart des solutions que nous avons étudié ne respectent pas l’une des exigences principales suivantes: (1) temps de réponse rapide, (2) extensibilité, (3) résistance à la tricherie. Cette thèse décrit les différents projets sur lesquels nous avons travaillé qui visent à mettre en oeuvre ces exigences: Watchmen, sécurité mobile (mobile security), AntReckoning et AntAI.Watchmen est le premier protocole extensible et distribué conçu spécifiquement pour la détection et la prévention de la tricherie qui prend en charge les jeux à rythme rapide (fast-paced). Ce protocole est basé sur un schéma d’assignation dynamique aléatoire de noeuds-relais (proxie) pour effectuer tant la dissémination que la vérification des actions. Nous démontrons que Watchmen est en mesure de réduire de manière significative les possibilités de tricherie, même en présence de collusion et ce, tout en prenant en charge des centaines de joueurs et en rencontrant les exigences strictes de latence imposées par les jeux de tirs à la première personne. Dans le contexte de la tricherie, nous nous attardons également aux jeux mobiles. Nous discutons des possibilités existantes et des nouvelles avenues potentielles de tricherie qui peuvent survenir dans des environnements mobiles et nous suggérons différentes solutions pour améliorer la sécurité. Ces solutions sont basées sur des services existants ou nouveaux qui sont ou qui pourrait être offerts par les opérateurs, écosystèmes et développeurs.AntReckonning est un algorithme de navigation à l’estime (dead-reckoning) inspiré des colonies de fourmis qui modèle les intérêts des joueurs pour prédire leurs mouvements. Ce modèle est bénéfique pour notre architecture puisqu’il nous permet de transmettre les mises à jour à des fréquences inférieures et avec des prédictions plus précises, ce qui permet d’améliorer l’extensibilité et la qualité de l’expérience des joueurs. AntReckoning incorpore l’intérêt des joueurs pour des emplacements, objets et avatars spécifiques au sein d’équations de mouvement en tant que forces d’attraction. En pratique, ces points d’intérêt génèrent des phéromones qui se diffusent et s’estompent dans le monde virtuel du jeu et qui sont des sources d’attraction. AntReckoning améliore de manière significative la précision des techniques de navigation à l’estime traditionnelles et peut réduire la bande passante de téléversement (upload) jusqu’à concurrence de un tiers du trafic total.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bettina Kemme</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t949x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f6695</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr1721279"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>MGMT as a regulator of MET expression and activity and its implications for targeted therapy glioblastoma multiforme</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lingard, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les traitements ciblés n'ont pas donné de bons résultats efficaces pour le glioblastome multiforme; à l'inverse, il y a eu des preuves que les médicaments qui ciblent l'axe de signalisation VEGF-VEGFR2 induisent effectivement une forme de réponse pro-invasive dans un sous-groupe de patients. (Degroot, 2010) Cette réponse pro-invasive à la thérapie anti-angiogénique est médiée par le récepteur de HGF, MET. (Lu, 2012) Cependant, l'expression de MET seule n'est pas prédictive d'une réponse pro-invasive et donc les biomarqueurs de ce phénomène sont désespérément nécessaires pour optimiser le traitement de cette maladie agressive et mortelle. O(6)-méthylguanine ADN-méthyltransférase (MGMT), une protéine de réparation, est le biomarqueur le plus couramment utiliser pour prédire la réponse temozolomide. (Hegi et al., 2005) De travaux de notre groupe ont démontré que MGMT est un régulateur négatif d'un phénotype invasif et angiogénique, en outre, l'expression de MGMT serait prédictive d'une réponse positive à l’agent anti-angiogénique sunitinib.  Avec la nouvelle découverte du rôle de MET dans la réponse pro-invasive et un profil d'expression de gènes précédemment rapporté impliquant MET expression dans les modèles cellulaires qui surexpriment MGMT, nous avons analysé l’expression et la signalisation de MET entre les lignées cellulaires isogéniques pour MGMT. Nous avons constaté que l'expression MET a été inversement corrélée avec l'expression de MGMT et MGMT également a découplé l’activation du MET de son programme pro-migratoire. La migration des lignées cellulaires isogéniques MGMT-bas a été réduite de manière significativement plus élevés que celle leurs homologues de MGMT haute avec le traitement par crizotinib.  De plus, les lignées cellulaires isogéniques MGMT-bas ont affiché une réponse pro-migratoire au sunitinib, qui pourrait être supprimée avec l'ajout de crizotinib. Les capacités antiprolifératives de crizotinib ont été étudiées avec le test MTT et ont révélé une réponse différentielle à l'agent sur la base de l'expression de MGMT. Au total, nos résultats révèlent une relation importante entre le statut de MGMT et  l'activité de MET, en soutenant son utilisation à la fois comme un biomarqueur de réponse aux thérapies ciblées de MET et de réponse pro-invasive aux agents anti-angiogéniques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Targeted therapy has not delivered effective therapeutic outcomes for glioblastoma multiforme as once hoped; conversely there is growing evidence that drugs that target the VEGF-VEGFR2 signaling axis actually induce an invasive growth pattern in a subset of patients.(Degroot, 2010) This pro-invasive response to antiangiogenic therapy has been shown to be mediated through the HGF receptor, MET. (Lu, 2012) However, expression of MET alone is not predictive of a proinvasive response and thus biomarkers for this phenomenon are desperately needed to optimize therapy for this aggressive and deadly disease.O(6)-methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase (MGMT) is a repair protein that is the most commonly utilized predictive biomarker of response to the alkylating agent temozolomide.(Hegi et al., 2005) Past work by our group has demonstrated MGMT to be a negative regulator of an invasive and angiogenic phenotype, furthermore, MGMT expression was shown to be a predictive of a positive response to the antiangiogenic agent sunitinib. In light of the discovery of MET’s role in the proinvasive response and a previously reported gene expression profile implicating MET expression in MGMT induced changes we analyzed MET signaling between cell lines isogenic for MGMT. We found that MET expression was inversely correlated with MGMT expression and MGMT also decoupled MET activation from a pro-migratory program.  Migration of MGMT-low isogenic cell lines was reduced significantly more than that of their MGMT-high counterparts with treatment by the MET/ALK inhibition crizotinib. Importantly, MGMT-low isogenic cell lines displayed a promigratory response to sunitinib, which could be abrogated with the addition of crizotinib. Crizotinib’s antiproliferative capabilities were investigated with the MTT assay and revealed differential response to the agent based on MGMT expression.Taken together, our results reveal an important relationship between MGMT status and MET downstream activity, supporting its use as both a biomarker of response to MET-targeted therapies and of a proinvasive response to antiangiogenic agents.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bassam Abdulkarim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c147h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1721279</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z903302v"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Early attachment, negative life events and adolescent adaptation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McConnell, Megan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude examine l'attachement précoce, les évènements négatifs de la vie et l'adaptation des adolescents. Il existe une recherche considérable sur l’attachement précoce et les évènements de vie négatifs en isolation, mais très peu de recherche sur l’influence cumulative de ces deux facteurs sur l’adaptation des adolescents. De plus, il existe très peu de recherche sur l'attachement pendant la période préscolaire et son lien avec l'adaptation à l'adolescence. Les participants de la présente étude furent 72 adolescents francophones (41 filles, 31 garçons) agés de 16 à 18 ans, ainsi que leurs mères. L'attachement fut évalué quand les enfants avaient entre 5 à 6 ans selon le système de classification de séparation-réunion de Main et Cassidy (1988). Les adolescents remplirent un questionnaire d’expériences de vie adapté du « Life Experiences Survey » (LEQ; Sarason, 1988). Pour mesurer leur adaptation, les adolescents remplirent l’auto-évaluation « Youth Self Report » (YSR, Achenbach, 1991), alors que leurs mères remplirent le « Child Behavior Checklist » (CBCL, Achenbach, 2001). Les résultats indiquèrent que, selon leurs mères, les adolescents ayant eu un style d’attachement évitant avaient plus de problèmes d’intériorisation ; ceux ayant eu un style d’attachement ambivalent avaient des scores de compétence plus faibles ; et ceux ayant eu un style d’attachement désorganisé avaient plus de problèmes à l’ensemble, plus de problèmes d’extériorisation, et des scores de compétence plus faibles. Il n’y eut pas de différence significative entre ces groupes par rapport aux échelles YSR. Les évènements négatifs de la vie prédirent de manière significative les problèmes d’intériorisation et d’extériorisation ainsi que l’ensemble de problèmes selon les adolescents et leurs mères. L’attachement et les évènements de vie négatifs prédirent de façon cumulative les problèmes d’intériorisation et d’extériorisation et l’ensemble des problèmes selon les mères, et les problèmes d’extériorisation et l’ensemble des problèmes selon les adolescents. Les conséquences pour les psychologues scolaires sont discutées. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study examines early attachment, negative life events and adolescent adaptation. Previous research has looked at both early attachment and negative life events in isolation but there are few studies that investigated how both of these factors cumulatively predict adolescent adaptation. Additionally, very little research has been conducted on attachment during the preschool period and adaptation in adolescence. Participants included 72 French-speaking adolescents (41 girls, 31 boys) ranging between 16-18 years of age, and their mothers. Attachment was assessed at the age of 5-6 years, using the Main and Cassidy (1988) separation-reunion classification system. Adolescents participating in the study filled out a life events questionnaire adapted from the Life Experiences Survey (LEQ; Sarason, 1988). To measure adaptation, the adolescent completed the Youth Self Report (YSR; Achenbach, 1991) and mothers completed The Child Behavior Checklist (CBCL; Achenbach, 2001). Results indicated that adolescents classified as avoidant in early childhood had higher mother-reported internalizing problems, adolescents classified as ambivalent in early childhood had lower mother-reported competence scores and adolescents classified as disorganized in early childhood had a higher level of mother-reported total problems, externalizing problems and lower competence. The YSR scales did not yield significant group-wise differences. Negative Life events significantly predicted adolescent and mother-reported internalizing, externalizing and total problems scores. Attachment and negative life events cumulatively predicted mother-reported internalizing, externalizing, and total problems scores as well as adolescent-reported externalizing and total problems scores. Implications for school psychologists are discussed. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Victoria Talwar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9033034.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903302v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02871018j"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Postural control during multi-directional perturbations to the arm in standing humans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Forghani Esfahani, Ali Reza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Quand les humains interagissent avec le monde en utilisant leurs mains des interactions impliquent des forces sur le bras qui non seulement perturbent la tâche à effectuer mais peuvent également déstabiliser l’équilibre. L’étude présentée ici fournit une investigation complète sur la réponse posturale aux perturbations sur le bras dans un spectre de conditions réalistes. Les participants étaient debout et tenaient la poignée d’un robot, lequel était programmé pour appliquer des perturbations de force multidirectionnelles sur la main droite. Les signaux électromyographiques, cinématiques et cinétiques ont été enregistrés.En réponse aux perturbations imprévisibles, les muscles posturaux se sont activés à des latences courtes de 50 à 110 ms, ce qui suggére une réponse automatique. L’amplitude des réponses posturales automatiques (APRs) était fortement corrélée à la direction de la perturbation et augmentait systématiquement avec l’intensité de la perturbation. L’activation des muscles des membres inférieurs ne résultait pas de réflexes médullaires proprioceptifs locaux et apparaissait même avant que la posture verticale soit significativement modifiée. Les afférents cutanés de la paume de la main perturbé sont proposés comme les principaux capteurs impliqués dans le codage de la perturbation et la génération de la réponse initiale dans les muscles plus éloignés.La réduction de la stabilité latérale par diminution de l’écart entre les pieds a augmenté significativement l’amplitude de déplacement du centre de masse (COM) ainsi que l’amplitude d’activation des muscles plus éloignés. Cependant, la cinématique de la main et l’activation des muscles des bras étaient invariantes. Par conséquent, les processus impliqués dans le contrôle de la position de la main et dans la stabilisation de l’équilibre en réponse à une perturbation transitoire pourraient être indépendants.L’augmentation de la rigidité de bras, obtenue par extension du coude, a augmenté significativement la stabilité de la main et la propagation des perturbations au corps mais n’a pas influencé de manière significative la cinématique du COM. Ceci est probablement dû au fait que la variation de la dynamique du bras était négligeable en comparaison avec la dynamique du corps. De plus, ni l’activité des muscles des chevilles ni le déplacement associé du centre de pression n’ont été influencés par l’angle du coude, ce qui suggère que l’activité des muscles des chevilles avait pour principale fonction de stabiliser l’équilibre plutôt que de repositionner la main.Quand les perturbations étaient prévisibles, des ajustements posturaux anticipatifs (APAs) ont commencé 50 à 150 ms avant le début de la perturbation. Les APAs étaient corrélés à la direction ainsi qu’à l’amplitude de la perturbation prédite. Les APAs ont servis généralement à accélérer le COM dans la direction opposée à la perturbation prédite. L’amplitude des APRs était également plus grands quand les perturbations étaient prévisibles, ce qui suggère une régulation par anticipation du gain de la réponse. La modulation des APRs avec prévisibilité peut s’expliquer en partie par une plus grande activation de base des muscles due aux APAs quand la perturbation était prévisible. Le déplacement produit par la perturbation posturale était significativement réduit dans toutes les directions quand les perturbations étaient prévisibles. En particulier, le déplacement du COM était étroitement maintenu dans la direction antéropostérieure, de telle manière que son amplitude était relativement petite et n’augmentait pas avec l’amplitude de la perturbation.Il se peut qu’il existe des chemins similaires à ceux des réflexes inter-membres transmis par voie propriospinale dans la moelle épinière du chat, lesquels proviennent dans les récepteurs cutanés de la paume de la main perturbé et seraient à l’origine de la réponse dans les muscles des membres inférieurs quand un membre supérieur est perturbé.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Humans constantly interact physically with the world around them using their hands to manipulate objects and loads while standing. These interactions involve forces to the arm that not only disturb the focal task but can also destabilize balance. The present study provided a comprehensive investigation of the postural response to arm perturbations under a range of realistic conditions. Standing subjects held the handle of a joystick-type robot which was programmed to apply multi-directional force perturbations unilaterally to the right hand within the horizontal plane. Electromyographic, kinematic, and kinetic signals were recorded. In response to unpredictable perturbations, postural muscles were activated at latencies as short as 50-110 ms that suggest the response must be automatic. The amplitude of the feedback automatic postural responses (APRs) was highly tuned to the perturbation direction and systematically increased with the intensity of the perturbation, i.e. it was a function the peripheral sensory input. The activation of the lower limb muscles was not the result of local stretch reflexes and occurred even before the upright posture was significantly displaced. The cutaneous afferents of the palm of the perturbed hand are proposed as the primary sensors involved in encoding the perturbation and the genesis of the initial response in the caudal muscles. Lowering lateral stability by decreasing the stance width significantly increased displacement amplitude of the center-of-mass (COM) and the activity of the caudal muscles, but the hand kinematics and the activity of the arm muscles were invariant. Therefore, the processes involved in controlling the hand position and stabilizing balance in response to a transient perturbation may be independent.   Increasing the stiffness of the arm, achieved by extending the elbow joint, significantly increased hand stability and propagation of the perturbations to the body, but it did not significantly influence the COM kinematics, likely because the variation of the arm mechanics was negligible compared to the overall dynamics of the body. Moreover, neither the activity of ankle muscles nor the associated center-of-pressure displacement was influenced by the elbow angle, suggesting that the ankle muscle activity primarily functioned to stabilize balance rather than to reposition the hand.When perturbations were predictable, anticipatory postural adjustments (APAs) were initiated 50-150 ms prior to the perturbation onset. APAs were tuned to both direction and amplitude of the predicted perturbation such that APAs generally functioned to accelerate the COM in the direction opposite to the forthcoming disturbance. The amplitude of APRs was also larger when perturbations were predictable, suggesting feedforward regulation of the response gain. The modulation of APRs with predictability could be partially explained by greater baseline activation of muscles due to APAs when the perturbation was predictable. The displacement produced by the postural disturbance significantly decreased in all directions when perturbations were predictable. In particular, the COM displacement was tightly regulated in the anteroposterior direction such that its displacement amplitude was relatively small and did not increase with the magnitude of the perturbation. Pathways similar to those of propriospinally mediated inter-limb reflexes demonstrated in the cat spinal cord which could originate from the cutaneous receptors of the palm of the perturbed arm might be responsible for genesis of the response in the lower limb muscles when the upper limb is perturbed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Theodore Milner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m999n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871018j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763b02s"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploration of «Ac/Ds» transposons in wild barley, «Hordeum vulgare» L. subsp. «spontaneum» (C. Koch) Thell</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cardinal, Marie-Josée</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La domestication et la sélection intense par croisement de nos espèces cultivées a causé l’érosion de la diversité génétique de plusieurs des gènes/allèles uniques pour la résistance ou la tolérance contre les stresses biotiques et abiotiques.  Les sélectionneurs commencent à favoriser l’utilisation d’espèces sauvages apparentés aux espèces cultivées comme source de matériel génétique pour l’amélioration génétique des céréales, telle l’orge, l’une des plus céréales  socialement et économiquement importantes dans le monde.  Dans le but d’utiliser le système de la  mutagenèse insertionnelle par transposons Ac/Ds du maïs afin de réaliser des études  de génomique fonctionnelle dans l’orge cultivé, les objectifs de ce projet de recherche sont de 1) établir un système de culture in vitro de tissus végétaux pour des génotypes d’orge sauvage (Hordeum vulgare ssp. spontaneum), et 2) de développer un système de transgénèse végétale afin d’insérer les transposons Ac/Ds.  Nous avons poursuivi notre recherche sur 10 accessions d’orge sauvage pour investiguer la fréquence d’induction de cal et la qualité de cal,  l’induction de cal verte régénérative, et la régénération de plantes fertiles.   Nous avons effectué des transformations transitoires sur des embryons immatures et sur du cal d’orge sauvage pour évaluer l’activité exogène des transposons Ac/Ds.  La sélection des transformants a été accomplie en utilisant l’antibiotique Hygromycin B comme agent de sélection et par l’expression de la protéine fluorescente verte (GFP).  Quarante-six expériences de transformations génétiques utilisant la technique de biolistique ont été effectuées sur 3952 morceaux de cal (3-5 mm chacun) dans 10 génotypes d’orge sauvage.  Sur la base de la sélection des transformants (Hygromycin B et GFP), la fréquence de transformants était de 0-25,7% dépendant de l’accession d’orge sauvage.  Nous avons généré 505 lignes de cals transgénèses putatives, et avons régénéré 54 plantes de ces 505 lignes indépendantes.  L’analyse moléculaire préliminaire pour l’insertion des transposons Ac/Ds sur un sous-ensemble des plantes régénérés à confirmer des transformants.  Ceci est le premier rapport de la transgénèse végétale dans l’orge sauvage.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Domestication and intensive selective breeding of cultivated plants has triggered erosion of genetic diversity of important stress related alleles. Researchers highlight the potential of using wild accessions as a gene source for improvement of cereals such as barley, which has major economic and social importance worldwide.  Based on the introduction of the maize Ac/Ds transposon system for gene identification in cultivated barley, the objective of this research is to investigate the response of Hordeum spontaneum accessions in tissue culture to standardize parameters for introduction of Ac/Ds transposons into the wild barley genome through genetic transformation. We investigated the response of 10 wild barley genotypes for callus induction, regenerative green callus induction and regeneration of fertile plants.  The activity of exogenous Ac/Ds elements was observed through a transient assay on immature wild barley embryos/callus.  Transformed calli were identified using Hygromycin B as a selectable agent in the media and by the expression of GFP.  Forty six bombardment experiments were performed on 3952 pieces of callus (3-5 mm each) in 10 genotypes of wild barley.  The transformation frequency of putative transgenic callus lines based on Hygromycin B selection and the GFP reporter system ranged from 0-25.7% in wild barley genotypes.  Five hundred and five putative independent transgenic callus lines were generated in this study, from which 54 plants were regenerated.  Initial molecular screening analysis for Ac/Ds transposon insertions on a subset of regenerated plants confirmed the transgenic status of wild barley lines.  This is the first report of a transformation system in H. spontaneum. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jaswinder Singh</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn00x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763b02s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Plant Culture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dg76j"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating the biological and mechanical performance of cranberry-modified silicone materials for use in implantable medical devices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Briggs, Louis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Catheter associated urinary tract infections (CAUTIs) are the second most common type of hospital acquired infection in North America with over a million cases reported each year. This high incidence rate, together with the dissemination of antibiotic resistant uropathogens has resulted in much interest in the development of preventative measures within the research community. The consumption of Vaccinium macrocarpon, the North American cranberry, has been linked with the prevention of bacterial infections in the urinary tract for over 100 years. The McGill Biocolloids and Surfaces Laboratory has shown that cranberry derived materials (CDMs) can inhibit bacterial adherence to surfaces, impair bacterial motility, and influence various bacterial virulence functions. It is therefore hypothesized that cranberries and CDMs could prevent the development of CAUTIs via the disruption of various stages of pathogenesis. Herein, we report on the bioperformance of cranberry impregnated biomedical grade silicone against the biofilms formed by Proteus mirabilis, a clinically relevant uropathogen. In addition, the mechanical performance of this cranberry-silicone hybrid material is studied. First, the release of bioactive cranberry materials into an aqueous environment is demonstrated in lysogeny broth using a spectrophotometric method. Second, the ultimate tensile strength, elongation at break, storage modulus, and contact angle of CDM impregnated silicone are reported. Finally, the ability of P. mirabilis to form biofilms on the cranberry-modified silicone surface is qualitatively studied over the course of 96 hours via confocal laser scanning microscopy and quantitatively studied using COMSTAT 2 image analysis and multiple analytical techniques. CDM-modified silicone demonstrated sustained release of approximately 30% of its cranberry content into a lysogeny broth environment over the course of 96 hours. A positive correlation between cranberry concentration and storage modulus was observed, whereas ultimate tensile strength and elongation at break decreased with increasing concentrations of cranberry. Moreover, no change in the surface hydrophobicity of the CDM-modified silicone was detected via contact angle goniometry. The presence of cranberry in the silicon substrate was found to result in flattening of P. mirabilis biofilms, leading to significant increases in surface coverage and surface exposed to nutrients. Biovolume as determined by COMSTAT 2 and number of attached bacteria as determined by hemocytometry presented no difference between cranberry-modified silicone and control, whereas P. mirabilis viability was found to be higher on cranberry-modified silicone. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les infections urinaires attribuées à l’utilisation des cathéters sont le deuxième type le plus courant des infections nosocomiales en Amérique du Nord avec plus d’un million de cas à chaque année.  Ce taux d’incidence élevé, en combinaison avec la dissémination d’uropathogènes résistants aux antibiotiques, a entrainé beaucoup d’intérêt dans le développement de mesures préventives au sein de la communauté de recherche. La consommation de Vaccinium macrocarpon, la canneberge de l’Amérique du Nord, est reliée à la prévention des infections bactériennes dans les voies urinaires depuis plus de 100 ans. Le Laboratoire de Biocolloïdes et Surfaces de l’Université McGill a démontré que les matériaux dérivés de canneberges (MDC) peuvent inhiber l’adhésion bactérienne aux surfaces, compromettre la motilité bactérienne, et influencer divers facteurs de virulence. Il est donc supposé que la canneberge et les matériaux dérivés de canneberges pourraient empêcher le développement des infections urinaires attribuées  à l’utilisation des cathéters en perturbant les diverses étapes de la pathogénie de ce type d’infection. Dans ce document, nous faisons rapport sur la bioperformance d’une silicone biomédicale imprégnée de matériaux dérivés de canneberges contre la formation de biofilms d’un uropathogène cliniquement pertinent, Proteus mirabilis. En outre, la performance mécanique de ce matériau hybride est étudiée. Premièrement, la libération de matériaux dérivés de canneberges par la silicone est étudiée dans un milieu de culture LB pendant 96 heures utilisant une méthode spectrophotométrique. Deuxièmement, la résistance ultime à la traction, l’allongement à la rupture, le module de conservation, et l’angle de contact de ce matériau hybride sont décrits. Enfin, la capacité de P.mirabilis de former des biofilms sur le matériau hybride pendant 96 heures est qualitativement étudiée via microscopie confocal à balayage laser (MCBL) et quantitativement étudiée  utilisant le programme d’analyse d’image COMSTAT 2 ainsi que par multiples techniques analytiques. La libération d’environ 25% des MDCs par le matériau hybride dans un milieu de culture LB a été observée au cours de 96 heures. Une corrélation positive entre la concentration de MDC et le Module de Young a été observée, tandis que la résistance ultime à la fraction ainsi que l’allongement à la rupture ont diminué avec l’augmentation des concentrations de MDC. De plus, aucun changement de l’hydrophobicité de la surface du matériau hybride n’a été détecté. Une structure  de biofilm plus plate a été observée sur la surface du matériau hybride en combinaison avec une plus grande couverture de surface  et une plus grande surface de biofilm exposée au milieu de culture LB. Le biovolume calculé par COMSTAT 2 ainsi que le nombre de bactéries attachées sur la surface du silicone déduit par hémocytométrie  ne présentaient aucune différence entre le matériau hybride et le matériau standard, tandis que la viabilité de P.mirabilis était supérieure sur le matériau hybride.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nathalie Tufenkji</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b186m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dg76j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149s77v"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Individuation et vision du monde: enquête sur l’héritage ontologique de la phénoménologie</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boublil, Elodie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, je démontre que la tradition phénoménologique développe une redéfinition ontologique de l’individuation du sujet fondée sur la notion d’intentionnalité opérante. J’explique comment cette redéfinition offre une nouvelle approche de la vision du monde et des relations intersubjectives qui ne serait ni réflexive ni représentative. Néanmoins, cette configuration montre le développement parallèle de l’individuation du sujet et de ses expressions, grâce à une ontologie relationnelle, aux implications épistémologiques et éthiques.  Analysant la phénoménologie de Husserl, je mets au jour le rapport entre individuation et intentionnalité en montrant que cette relation permet de repenser les problèmes de  l’ipséité et de la différence (1).  A la lumière de l’analyse heideggérienne du Dasein et de la description merleau-pontienne du corps propre,  je montre alors que l’individuation doit être conçue comme un processus permanent de différenciation qui ne repose plus sur le schéma hylémorphique ou sur la représentation cartésienne du sujet (2). Je décris le type de « mouvement » ontologique qui caractérise l’individuation, en m’appuyant sur Patočka et Simondon, afin de montrer la corrélation de la manifestation du monde et de l’individuation du sujet (3). Celle-ci suppose la nécessité paradoxale de la contingence afin de pouvoir penser l’individuation comme ouverture radicale, modelée par une certaine forme d’altérité. En m’appuyant sur l’ontologie tardive de Merleau-Ponty, la psychanalyse et l’herméneutique, je cherche ensuite à dévoiler la structure analogique – mais non représentationaliste – du sensible  et à repenser la corrélation à la lumière du processus d’individuation éprouvé par le sujet (4). Rendant compte de la généralité et de la générativité du mouvement charnel, je démontre pour finir que cette structure analogique permet d’élaborer des conceptions de l’individuation et de la réflexivité requérant moins  la « mort du sujet », comme dans l’optique poststructuraliste, que sa métamorphose et son advenue. Cette thèse conclut en ouvrant des perspectives utiles à la compréhension de la vie, dans les recherches épistémologiques contemporaines (5), et à l’examen éthique de nos visions du monde et de la responsabilité qui incombe au sujet, dans l’épreuve contingente de ses désirs (6). </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this dissertation, I argue that the phenomenological tradition develops an ontological redefinition of the subject’s individuation based on operative intentionality. I explain how this redefinition offers a new approach to world’s perception (vision du monde) and intersubjective relations that is paradoxically neither reflective nor representational. This new approach rests on a perceptive imaginary relying on prereflective and embodied processes. Yet, this configuration exhibits the parallel development of the individuation of the subject and its expressions, thanks to a relational ontology that bears epistemological and ethical outcomes. Analyzing Husserl’s phenomenology, I recast the relation between individuation and intentionality by showing how this relation thinks anew the issues of ipseity and difference (1). Thanks to Heidegger’s analysis of Dasein and Merleau-Ponty’s description of the corps propre, I then show that individuation has to be conceived as an ongoing differentiation process that no longer relies on the hylemorphic principle or the Cartesian picture of the subject (2). I describe the kind of ontological “movement” that characterizes individuation, referring to Patočka and Simondon in order to show that the subject’s individuation is tied to the world’s manifestation and that the phenomenological perspective poses the paradoxical necessity of contingency in order to consider individuation as radical openness shaped by otherness (3). Taking my lead from Merleau-Ponty’s late ontology, psychoanalysis, and hermeneutics, I uncover the analogical — yet nonrepresentational — feature of the sensible in order to reframe the phenomenological correlation according to the individuation process that the subject undergoes (4). Accounting for the generality and the generative movement of the flesh, I ultimately argue that this analogical structure provides us with conceptions of individuation and reflexivity that require not the “death of the subject,” as in poststructuralist thought, but its metamorphosis and advent. New paths are therefore opened, both for contemporary epistemological endeavors to understand life (5) and for ethical concerns about contemporary worldviews and the self-responsibility to be lived through the contingency of our intersubjective desires (6).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Emily J. Carson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms98m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s77v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy, Religion And Theology - Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>