<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qf08g"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structural and contextual factors of school violence in Guerrero, Mexico: policy analysis from critical and anti-colonial lenses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Camargo Balcazar, Ariadna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>School violence in Mexico is a topic that has received significant attention in recent years. Likewise, it has been linked to the overall context of social violence that the country lives and as thus, different state initiatives have been implemented to address the problematic. However, not much have been said regarding the adequacy of these initiatives to fully address the roots of the problem. With this research, I reveal that the policy-approaches to prevent violence are not fully consistent with the structural and contextual factors underlying school violence in one of the Mexican federations: Guerrero. Utilizing case study methodology, as well as policy and textual analysis of institutional documents, I found that current policies are based on three main perspectives: a liberal approach to differences and diversity, a focus on social and emotional learning, and a zero tolerance approach to school discipline. Drawing on anti-colonial discourse framework, I argue that these perspectives are not addressing the different forms of oppression to which students from Guerrero have been historically subjected and that create the necessary conditions for violence to emerge.  I show that Guerrero is a region in Mexico characterized by social inequalities, state-sanctioned violence predicated on processes of racialization and othering of Indigenous populations, as well as various manifestations of resistance. Within the current approaches to prevent violence in Guerrero, these social forces are not acknowledged and thus the initiatives created are directed toward the symptoms rather than the roots of the problem. The study seeks to provide different lenses through which to analyze school violence and invites to create more supportive and inspiring school environments</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La violence à l'école au Mexique est un sujet qui a reçu une grande importance au cours des dernières années. De même, elle a aussi été liée au contexte général de violence sociale dans lequel vit le pays et, par conséquent, à son environnement, diverses initiatives étatiques ont été mises en œuvre pour faire face à ce problème. Toutefois, on n'a pas beaucoup parlé de la pertinence de ces initiatives pour s'attaquer pleinement aux racines du problème.Grâce à cette recherche, je constate que les approches politiques de prévention de la violence ne sont pas pleinement cohérentes avec les facteurs structurels et contextuels sur la violence à l'école dans l'une des fédérations mexicaines : Guerrero. En utilisant la méthodologie des études de cas, ainsi que l'analyse politique et textuelle des documents institutionnels, j'ai constaté que les politiques actuelles sont fondées sur trois grandes perspectives: une approche libérale des différences et de la diversité, l'accent sur l'apprentissage social et émotionnel, et une approche de tolérance zéro à l'égard de la discipline scolaire. S'inspirant du cadre du débat anticolonial, Je soutiens que ces perspectives n'abordent pas les différentes formes d'oppression auxquelles les étudiants du Guerrero ont été historiquement soumis et qui créent les conditions nécessaires à l'émergence de la violence.  Je montre que le Guerrero est une région du Mexique qui se caractérise par des disparités sociales, la violence sanctionnée par l'État et fondée sur des processus de racialisation et d'autres formes de discrimination à l'égard des populations autochtones, ainsi que diverses manifestations de résistance. Dans le contexte des approches actuelles de prévention de la violence au Guerrero, ces forces sociales ne sont pas reconnues et, par conséquent, les initiatives créées sont axées sur les symptômes plutôt que sur les racines du problème. L'étude vise à fournir différents angles d'analyse de la violence à l'école et incite à créer des environnements scolaires plus encourageants et inspirants</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Naomi Nichols</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h865c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qf08g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zg37z"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A reusable concern for continuous integration specifications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sidhu, Puneet Kaur</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'intégration continue (IC) est une pratique largement adoptée dans laquelle les modifications au code sont automatiquement construites et testées pour vérifier la régression telles qu'elles apparaissent dans un système de contrôle de versions (VCS). Les services IC permettent aux ingénieurs de mise en production de personnaliser des phases qui définissent les étapes séquentielles des tâches de construction déclenchées par des modifications apportées au projet. Bien que des travaux antérieurs fassent d'importantes observations sur l'adoption et l'utilisation de l'IC, on en sait encore peu sur les modèles de réutilisation dans les spécifications IC. Si la réutilisation est commune aux spécifications IC, nous envisageons d'étendre le cadre CORE (Concern-Oriented Reuse) pour aider les développeurs à réutiliser les spécifications textuelles IC basées sur des séquences fréquentes de phases et de commandes. Pour évaluer la faisabilité de proposer des suggestions de réutilisation dans CORE, nous effectuons une analyse empirique de l'utilisation de différentes phases et commandes à l'aide d'un échantillon de 913 spécifications de projets basées sur Java qui utilisent Travis CI, l'un des fournisseurs publics de services IC les plus populaires. Premièrement, nous observons que cinq phases parmi neuf sont utilisées dans 18% à 75% des projets. Deuxièmement, pour les cinq phases les plus populaires, nous effectuons un forage de règles d'associations afin de découvrir des motifs d'usages fréquents de phases, de commandes et de catégories de commandes. Nous observons que les règles d'association manquent d'évidence, de confiance ou de valeurs de montée suffisantes pour être considérées comme statistiquement significatives. Nos résultats suggèrent que l'utilisation de phases et de commandes dans les spécifications Travis CI est diversifiée. Par conséquent, nous ne pouvons pas fournir de suggestions pour les projets basés sur Java comme nous l'avions envisagé. Cependant, nous fournissons une implémentation démontrant la faisabilité de la réutilisation des spécifications IC (sans suggestions) en étendant le modèle de caractéristiques dans CORE et son mécanisme de composition avec la capacité de gérer des spécifications IC textuelles</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Continuous Integration (CI) is a broadly adopted practice where code changes are automatically built and tested to check for regression as they appear in the Version Control System (VCS). CI services allow release engineers to customize phases, which define the sequential steps of build jobs that are triggered by changes to the project. While the past work has made important observations about the adoption and usage of CI, little is known about patterns of reuse in CI specifications. Should reuse be common in CI specifications, we envision extending the framework for Concern-Oriented Reuse (CORE) to help developers reuse textual CI specifications based on popular sequences of phases and commands. To assess the feasibility of providing reuse suggestions in CORE, we perform an empirical analysis of the use of different phases and commands in a curated sample of 913 CI specifications for Java-based projects that use Travis CI---one of the most popular public CI service providers. First, we observe that five of nine phases are used in 18%-75% of the projects. Second, for the five most popular phases, we apply association rule mining to discover frequent phase, command, and command category usage patterns. We observe that the association rules lack sufficient support, confidence, or lift values to be considered statistically significantly interesting. Our findings suggest that the usage of phases and commands in Travis CI specifications is broad and diverse. Hence, we cannot provide suggestions for Java-based projects as we had envisioned. However, we provide a proof-of-concept implementation for the reuse of CI specifications (without suggestions) by extending the feature model in CORE as well as the composition mechanism with the ability to handle textual CI specifications</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gunter Mussbacher</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Shane McIntosh</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483p59m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zg37z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hf24n"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bubble wall velocity and electroweak baryogenesis with a Z2 singlet scalar field</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Friedlander, Avi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite electroweak baryogenesis being a promising and testable explanation of the matter-antimatter asymmetry, it relies on difficult computations of bubble wall velocities during the electroweak phase transition. In this thesis, I determine the wall velocity during a two-step electroweak phase transition that is first-order due to a massive scalar singlet field. I first review the theory of electroweak baryogenesis and what conditions must be met for a model to be a viable explanation. Then I present the scalar singlet model and derive its one-loop effective potential. I introduce a vector-like top partner which allows for new CP violations. I then review the methodology used for determining the dynamics of bubbles during a first-order phase transition. I find that this model has a region of parameter space that produces the slow bubble walls necessary for baryogenesis. I also find that including loop contributions to the effective potential is important and wall velocity calculations cannot be performed independently of new CP violating interactions introduced</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Malgré le fait que la baryogénèse électrofaible explique de façon prometteuse et testable l’asymétrie matière-antimatière, elle se fie à des calculs difficiles de vélocité de mur de bulle pendant la transition de phase électrofaible. Dans cette thèse, je détermine la vélocité des murs pendant une phase de transition électrofaible à deux étapes qui est de premier ordre dû à un champ singulet scalaire avec masse. Dans un premier temps, je passe en revue la théorie de baryogénèse électrofaible et des conditions qui doivent être remplies pour faire du modèle une explication viable. Ensuite, je présente le modèle scalaire singulet et je calcule son potentiel effectif à une boucle. J’introduis un quasi-vecteur partenaire au quark t, ce qui permet de nouvelles façons de briser la symétrie CP. Ensuite, je passe en revue la méthodologie utilisée pour déterminer les dynamiques de bulles pendant une transition de phase de premier ordre. Je trouve que ce modèle a une région d’espace de paramètre qui produit les murs de bulles lentes nécessaires à la baryogénèse. Aussi, je trouve qu’il est important d’inclure les contributions de boucles dans le potentiel effectif, et que les calculs de vélocité ne peuvent être faits indépendamment du modèle qui fournit les nouvelles façons de briser la symétrie CP</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James M. Cline</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wc84t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hf24n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bt65v"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A laboratory study on a biochar-amended biosand filtering system for «Escherichia coli» removal from lake water</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guan, Peining</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La contamination des eaux de surface est une préoccupation mondiale depuis des années, surtout dans les pays en développement dépourvus de systèmes de traitement de l'eau centralisés de haute qualité. Le filtre de biosable (BSF) est un traitement alternatif de l’eau domestique adoptée globalement. Cependant, son efficacité d’élimination des bactéries indicatrices fécales (Escherichia coli) a tendance à être faible. Il a été démontré que l’amendement du biochar dans certains systèmes de filtrage améliore l’élimination de E. coli. Le rôle du biochar lorsqu'il est ajouté à un BSF reste inconnu. Cette recherche a visé les performances d’un système de filtrage au biosable enrichi en biochar à l’échelle du laboratoire pour éliminer E. coli d’une eau lacustre.Deux expériences avec des BSF ont été menées ou l’eau lacustre fut fourni par le bas des colonnes. Dans une première expérience, l’effet sur l’élimination de E. coli d’un ajout de biochar (diamètre &lt; 1 mm) de bois franc et sa position [couche indépendante au milieu (filtre biochar); bien mélangé avec le sable (filtre mélangé)]. Une préfiltration d’eau lacustre de trois semaines sans inoculation d'E. coli, a été réalisée pour favoriser le processus de maturation du filtre. Les filtres ont ensuite reçu quotidiennement, sur une étendue de deux semaines, un volume de pores d’eau lacustre inoculée avec E. coli. Tout au long de l'expérience, aucune différence significative ne parut dans l'élimination de E. coli entre le filtre biochar et l’étalon sans biochar. Le filtre biochar présenta généralement une meilleure performance que le filtre mélangé, avec une élimination de E. coli significativement supérieure observée sur deux jours différents. L’amendement du biochar réduisa considérablement la conductivité hydraulique du sol dans les deux types de filtres biochars (le filtre biochar et le filtre mélangé).Dans la seconde expérience, l’effet du type du biochar sur l’élimination de E. coli a fut étudié. Des biochars fabriqués à partir de bois de saule et de paille de blé, dotés de propriétés physicochimiques distinctes, ont été utilisés. Ils ont été criblés à une taille de 1 à 4 mm et ajoutés en temps que couche indépendante dans les filtres. Un filtre sans biochar a servi comme étalon. Dans cette seconde expérience, le mode de fonctionnement du filtre et la concentration de E. coli furent maintenus comme dans la première expérience, mais aucune préfiltration n’eut lieu. Par rapport à l’étalon, l'élimination des E. coli fut réduite dans les deux filtres contentant du biochar. Le filtre recevant le biochar de paille de blé présenta une élimination moyenne d'E. coli plus élevée (0,88 log10) par rapport au filtre recevant un biochar de bois de saule (0,73 log10). Les deux biochars augmentèrent le pH, la conductivité électrique et la teneur en phosphore de l'effluent.La présence de biofilm (schumuzekecke) à la surface d'un sable grossier près de l'entrée d’eau, tel qu’observée pour tout les filtres à l'aide d'un microscope électronique à balayage. Les filtres de la première expérience ont permis d’obtenir une élimination plus élevée d’E. coli par rapport aux filtres de la deuxième expérience, ce qui relève du rôle de la maturation du filtre dans l’amélioration des performances du filtre. Malheureusement, la formation de biofilm à la surface du biochar ne fut pas confirmée. L'effet du biofilm associé à un biochar sur l'élimination de E. coli est également incertain.Comme, lors des deux expériences, aucune amélioration de l'élimination d'E. coli fut noté pour les filtres augmentés au biochar, nous suggérons que le biochar ne serait pas un matériel idéal à ajouter dans un BSF. Des études sur l'élimination de E. coli par d'autres types de biochar, sur l'effet de la maturation du filtre sur l'élimination de E. coli par biochar et sur l'influence de l'amendement de la teneur en biochar sur l'élimination d'autres contaminants sont recommandés pour l’avenir</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Surface water contamination has been a global concern for years, especially in the developing world where high-quality centralized water treatment systems are often lacking. An alternative point-of-use household water treatment technology widely adopted in many developing countries, the biosand filter (BSF) generally shows poor removal efficiency for fæcal indicator bacteria (Escherichia coli). However, amendment of some filtering systems with biochar has been shown to enhance the E. coli removal. As the role of biochar as an amendment in a BSF remains unknown, the present research sought to investigate the performance of a laboratory-scale biochar-amended biosand filtering system for the removal of E. coli from lake water.In the first of two laboratory experiments, the effect of hardwood biochar (&lt; 1 mm diameter) and its placement in the filtering column [independent layer in the middle (biochar filter); thoroughly mixed with sand (mixture filter)] on E. coli removal from lake water was investigated. A 3-week pre-filtration of lake water, without E. coli inoculation, was conducted to promote filter maturation. Filters were then daily dosed with one pore volume of E. coli-inoculated lake water over a period of two weeks. Throughout the experiment, no significant difference in E. coli removal was found between the biochar filter and control filter with no biochar. With significantly greater E. coli removal observed on two different days, the biochar filter showed a generally better performance than the mixture filter. For both types of biochar-amended filters (the biochar filter and the mixture filter), the soil hydraulic conductivity was dramatically reduced compared to the non-amended filters.In the second experiment, the effect on E. coli removal on type of biochar was investigated. Biochars, produced from feedstocks of willow wood and wheat straw, were sieved to a size of 1-4 mm and added as an independent layer in the filters - filters without biochar served as a control. The pattern of filter operation and concentrations of E. coli were maintained as in the first experiment, but no pre-filtration step was carried out. Compared to the control, both biochar-amended filters showed reduced E. coli removal, the filter amended with wheat straw biochar achieving a greater mean E. coli removal (0.88 log10) than the willow wood biochar-amended filter (0.73 log10). Both biochars increased the pH, electrical conductivity and phosphorus content of the effluent.In the first experiment, Scanning Electron Microscope observations indicated the presence of biofilm (schumuzekecke) on the surface of the coarse sand near the columns’ water inlets. These filters achieved a higher E. coli removal rate than the filters employed in the second experiment, showing that filter maturation improved filter performance. Formation of biofilm on the biochar’s surface could not be confirmed, so the effect of biochar-associated biofilm on E. coli removal remains unclear.Since biochar-amended filters showed no enhancement of E. coli removal in either experiment, biochar may not be an ideal medium for amending BSFs. Investigations on the performance of biochar-amended biosand filter on E. coli removal using a downward filtering system, E. coli removal by other types of biochar, the effect of filter maturation on E. coli removal by biochar, and the influence of biochar amendment on removal of other contaminants are recommended for the future research</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Muhammad T. Afzal</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Shiv Prasher</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278z73x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bt65v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bioresource Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z5201"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Monotonicity of value function and optimal policy in cross-layer design of communication systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sayedana, Borna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La théorie de la décision de Markov a été largement utilisée pour modéliser les configurations d’ingénierie sous forme séquentielle problème d’optimisation.L’utilisation de modèles de décision de Markov et de techniques sous-jacentes de cette théorie a permis aux ingénieurs d’améliorer les performances du système.Une programmation dynamique approximative est le principal outil pour trouver des politiques optimales.Cependant le fait de trouver numériquement la politique optimale n’ajoute rien à notre ingénierieIntuition sur le système physique;Afin de mieux comprendre le déséquilibre du processus physique dérivé on pourrait être intéressé à étudier les propriétés qualitatives de la fonction valeur optimale et de la politique optimale.Ces résultats qualitatifs aident non seulement les chercheurs à mieux comprendre le comportement du système physique, mais également à permettre aux concepteurs de simplifier leur mise en oeuvre.Connaître la structure d’une politique optimale peut réduire celle d’une table de consultation à une matrice clairsemée ou à un ensemble de seuils.La théorie de la décision de Markov  a été largement utilisée dans les problèmes de file d’attente liés à des systèmes de communication.Ces problèmes concernent un émetteur en train de transmettre un flux de paquets de données en file d’attente dans une mémoire tampon sur un canal physique.L’émetteur ne devrait pas traiter uniquement avec la stochasticité dans les données à venir mais il devrait aussi gérer la physique des contraintes desouche.Ce type de problème est généralement classé en tant que problème de file d’attente et, dans la littérature technique, la solution est étudiée à l’aide d’outils de la théorie de la file d’attente et de la théorie de la décision de Markov.Dans ma thèse l’accent est mis sur l’investigation de la monotonie.Propriété de la stratégie optimale dans de tels modèles.Nous commençons par une brève introduction à Markov concernant le processus de décision et les techniques et outils communs dans sa théorie pour prouver la monotonicité.Nous étudions ensuite un résultat classique dans ce domaine.Nous présentons des preuves plus simples pour les résultats existants et essayons de généraliser l’idée dans deux directions.Tout d’abord nous essayons d’établir la propriété de monotonicité lorsque l’émetteur a accès à un retour ACK  / NACK canal.Dans la seconde approche nous essayuns de montrer ces propriétés dans un système de récupération d’énergie.Scénario</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Markov decision theory has been widely used to model engineering setups as sequential optimization problems. Using Markov decision models and underling techniques in this theory let the engineers improve the performance of the system. Dynamic programming and approximate dynamic programming are the main tools to find optimal policies; however, just finding the optimal policy numerically does not add anything to our engineering intuition about the physical system. In order to grasp a deeper understanding of the underlying physical process, designer is interested in investigating qualitative properties of the optimal value function and optimal policy. These qualitative results not only help researchers to understand the behavior of the physical system better, but also let designers simplify their implementation. Knowing the structure of optimal policy can reduce the implementation of an optimal policy from a look up table to a sparse matrix or just set of thresholds.Markov decision theory has been widely used in queuing problems related to  communication systems. In these problems a transmitter is dealing with transmitting a stream of data packets queued in a buffer, over a physical channel. Transmitter should not only deal with stochasticity in the arriving data but also it should manage the physical layer constraints.These type of problems usually are categorized as queuing problems, and in the literature, the solution to these problems are investigated with tools in both queuing theory and Markov decision theory. In this thesis, our emphasis is on investigating monotonicity property of the optimal strategy in such models. We start with brief introduction to Markov decision processes and common techniques and tools in Markov decision theory to prove monotonicity. We then investigate a classic result in this area. We present simpler proofs for the existing results and try to generalize the idea in two directions. First, we try to establish monotonicity property when transmitter has access to an ACK/NACK feedback channel. In the second approach, we try to show these properties in an energy harvesting scenario</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mahajan, Aditya</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sg03h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z5201</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r964v"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Brushing the surface: Edgar Degas’s La Coiffure as site of experimentation and corporal dissolution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harnish, Lauren</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines how the repetition of forms and figures in Edgar Degas’s artworks presents the representation of the female body as a foundation for Degas’s experimentation with different media. Through an analysis of Degas’s 1896 painting La Coiffure and three negative photographic plates, unique for their colouristic effects caused by developmental error, I explore Degas’s interest in media-specific effect, particularly his heightened interest in photography between 1895 and 1896. In the first half of this thesis, I link Degas’s chosen subject matter of hair brushing to his artistic production and argue that both are material processes that elicit the tension between touch and sight. I also examine hair as a visual signifier of difference within nineteenth-century French culture. The second section of this thesis outlines the visual similarities between the glass negatives and La Coiffure to argue that Degas references the visual qualities of the plates in paint. From this analysis, Degas’s use of photography as a modern technology that encouraged his longstanding practice of repetition is explored. To conclude, I connect the process of dry-plate development to Degas’s artmaking and nineteenth-century ideals of hair care. I ultimately argue that both the photographic plates and La Coiffure exist as sites for Degas’s artistic experimentation. This connection reveals how the body of the model, exhibited in the negatives, dissolves through Degas’s artistic process. My research aims to provide a critical approach to Degas’s La Coiffure and to contribute to alternative feminist interpretations of his images of women</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire examine comment la répétition des formes et des figures dans les œuvres d’Edgar Degas révèle que la représentation du corps féminin était un élément fondamental dans l’expérimentation de Degas avec différents médias. À travers une analyse de La Coiffure, un tableau de Degas datant de 1896, et de trois planches photographiques négatives uniques pour leurs effets de couleur, causés par des erreurs de développement, j’explore l’intérêt qu’avait Degas pour les effets spécifiques aux médias, plus particulièrement son intérêt accru pour la photographie entre 1895 et 1896. Dans la première moitié de ce mémoire, je fais le lien entre le sujet choisi par Degas, le brossage des cheveux, et sa production artistique. Je propose que ces deux processus représentent des processus matériels qui provoquent une tension entre le toucher et la vision. J’examine également les cheveux comme marqueur de différence dans la culture française du XIXe siècle. La deuxième partie de ce mémoire souligne les similitudes visuelles entre les négatifs sur verre et La Coiffure pour démontrer que Degas fait référence aux qualités visuelles des plaques dans sa peinture. À partir de cette analyse, j’examine comment l’utilisation que fait Degas de la photographie comme technologie moderne l’encourage dans sa pratique de répétition. En guise de conclusion, je fais le lien entre le processus de développement de la plaque sèche, la pratique artistique de Degas et les idéaux de soin des cheveux du XIXe siècle. Je soutiens qu’à la fois les plaques photographiques et La Coiffure sont des sites d’expérimentation artistique pour Degas. Cette connexion révèle comment le corps du modèle, tel qu’il est exposé dans les négatifs, se dissout dans le processus artistique de Degas. Mes recherches ont pour objectif de proposer une approche critique de La Coiffure de Degas et de contribuer à des interprétations féministes alternatives de ses images de femmes</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mary Hunter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042z536.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r964v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art History and Communications Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c496r"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Coming to life: the illustrated novel and Theodor von Holst's creation of the 1831 "Frankenstein" frontispiece</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Benzschawel, Andrea</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>En 1831, Henry Colburn et Richard Bentley ont publié une nouvelle édition révisée de Frankenstein de Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley comprenant une nouvelle introduction de l’auteure et l’image frontispice de Theodor von Holst. L’illustration de Holst constitue la première représentation visuelle publiée de Frankenstein et de sa Créature. Elle évoque de nombreux éléments découlant de l’histoire du roman quant à sa publication, au public et à la science. Cette thèse détermine comment l’illustration de Holst représente une époque particulière par l’examen des publications de Frankenstein, de son auteure, de son public, de ses précédents théâtraux et des notions de mélancolie romantique et d’émerveillement gothique. Elle explore la relation entre les pratiques dans l’art académique, les traditions en anatomie, en portrait médical et le renouveau de l’alchimie qui puisent dans le passé de ce roman et qui reflètent les conditions socio-politiques contemporaines de 1831. En utilisant le livre, objet qui peut être manipulé comme média pour ce roman illustré, l’édition de 1831 de Frankenstein donne vie au « Monstre de Frankenstein » et à sa culture</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Henry Colburn and Richard Bentley published Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley’s Frankenstein in 1831 with the additions of an authorial introduction, revisions, and Theodor von Holst’s frontispiece image.  Holst’s illustration was the first-ever published image of Frankenstein and his Creature and engages with a number of diverse elements from the novel’s publishing, public, and scientific histories.  This thesis acts to place Holst’s image back into a very specific time through the examination of Frankenstein’s publications, author, audiences, theatrical precedents, and notions of Romantic melancholy and Gothic wonder.  Additionally, I examine how practices in academic art, traditions of anatomy, medical portraiture, and an alchemical revival reflect the novel’s past and respond to its present 1831 socio-political conditions.  By utilizing the medium of the book itself as a handled, illustrated novel, Frankenstein’s 1831 edition comes to life as a cultural “Frankenstein’s monster.”</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Matthew Hunter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010v25h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c496r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art History and Communications Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397d68c"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Whole exome sequencing to uncover the genetic etiology of a cohort of patients with suspected mitochondrial leukoencephalopathies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moore, Travis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le nombre de maladies mendéliennes identifiées à ce jour a largement dépassé ce qu’il aurait été possible sans le progrès des technologies de séquençage de l'ADN tel que le séquençage d'exome entier (WES). En médecine, cette avancée est devenue un outil indispensable à l’identification rapide des causes moléculaires des maladies rares, en plus d’être essentielle pour le diagnostic, le traitement et les conseils génétiques associés à ces maladies. Dans le cas des leucodystrophies, un groupe de maladies héréditaires rares affectant la substance blanche, touchant principalement les enfants et présentant un profil spécifique d'imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM), il existe encore de nombreux cas génétiques non résolus.La première partie de ce projet porte sur l'identification de l'étiologie d'une cohorte de patients atteints de leucoencéphalopathies mitochondriales non résolues. Ces dernières sont des leucodystrophies non hypomyélinisantes causées par une perturbation de la fonction mitochondriale. L’analyse WES a été effectuée sur 11 patients à l'aide de panels de gènes prédéfinis et suivant les lignes directrices de l'American College of Medical Genetics (ACMG). De ces analyses, une délétion importante de l'ADN mitochondrial a été identifiée chez un patient et des variants bialléliques dans les gènes MBOAT7, WDR62, PDHA1 et AARS ont été identifiés chez quatre autres patients. Nous avons identifié un gène candidat chez 5 des 11 patients, ce qui équivaut à 45% de la cohorte. Ce taux est similaire à celui publié dans les autres cohortes.La deuxième partie de ce projet porte sur l’étude fonctionnelle de deux nouveaux variants identifiés dans l’aminoacyl-ARNt synthétase de l’alanine (AARS) chez l’un de nos patients. Le patient présente un nouveau phénotype associé à un trouble lié au gène AARS et les variants identifiés (NM_001605.2) c.295G&gt; A; p.E99K &amp; c.778A&gt; G; p.T260A se sont révélés pathogéniques. Il a été confirmé que les variants de AARS du patient étaient en trans, que la mutation c.295G&gt;A a été héritée de la mère et par les techniques d’amplification et de clonage d’ADN complémentaire que la mutation c788A&gt; G est de novo. Les conséquences fonctionnelles de ces variants sur l'ARN messager ainsi que sur la localisation protéique et cellulaire de AARS ont ensuite été évaluées. Une augmentation significative des niveaux d’ARNm a été constatée. Cependant, les taux de protéines AARS ont été réduits de manière significative. De plus, la protéine AARS est distribuée de façon homogène dans le cytoplasme, mais dans les fibroblastes du patient, la distribution de la protéine AARS est perturbée et est sous forme anormale en puncta. L’évaluation de l’activité d’aminoacylation de AARS dans les fibroblastes dérivés du patient, réalisée par des collaborateurs, a révélé une réduction de l’activité de l’AARS de 16% par rapport à celle d’un témoin. Pris ensemble, ces tests fonctionnels montrent que les variants ont provoqué des défauts fonctionnels dans la protéine AARS et que ces défauts causent le nouveau phénotype associé à AARS chez notre patient.En identifiant des gènes candidats chez les patients atteints de leucoencéphalopathies mitochondriales non résolues, le WES s’avère être un outil précieux pour l’identification des causes moléculaires des maladies rares. L’étude des mutations de AARS, spécifiques à certains patients, permet d’apprécier l’expansion phénotypique des maladies reliées à AARS ainsi que les défauts fonctionnels spécifiques qui sont associés avec les cas d’apparition tardive. Puisque la compréhension pathophysiologique des aminoacyl ARNt synthétases est limitée à ce jour, notre travail ainsi que celui d’autres chercheurs est indispensable à une meilleure compréhension de ce groupe de maladies, ouvrant ainsi la porte au développement de thérapies potentielles</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The number of identified Mendelian disorders has far surpassed what would be possible without advancements in DNA sequencing technologies, such as whole exome sequencing (WES). In medicine, this advancement has become an invaluable tool for rapidly identifying the underlying molecular causes of rare diseases and is essential in diagnosis, treatment, and further genetic counselling. In the case of leukodystrophies, a group of rare heritable white matter diseases that primarily present in children with distinct Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) patterns, there are still many unsolved genetic cases. The first section of this project focuses on identifying the etiology of a cohort of patients with unsolved mitochondrial leukoencephalopathies, a non-hypomyelinating leukodystrophy caused by disruption of mitochondrial function. WES analysis was performed on 11 patients using custom gene panels and variant categorization calling using guidelines from the American College of Medical Genetics (ACMG). From this analysis, a large mitochondrial DNA deletion was identified in one patient, while biallelic variants in MBOAT7, WDR62, PDHA1, and AARS were identified in four other patients. We identified a strong gene candidate in 5/11 patients, i.e. 45% of the patients, a rate that is similar to what has been published in other cohorts. The second portion of this project focuses on investigating the functional consequences of two novel variants identified in the aminoacyl-tRNA synthetase for alanine (AARS) in one of our patients. The patient presented a novel phenotype of AARS-related disorder and the patient-specific variants, (NM_001605.2) c.295G&gt;A; p.E99K &amp; c.778A&gt;G; p.T260A, were proven to be pathogenic. The patient’s AARS variants were confirmed to be in trans, with the c.295G&gt;A being inherited from the mother and c.778A&gt;G being identified as a de novo variant by cDNA amplification and cloning techniques. The functional consequences of these variants on messenger RNA was assessed next, in addition to protein and cellular localization of AARS. A significant increase was seen in mRNA levels, however, the AARS proteins levels were significantly reduced. Finally, AARS typically has a homogenous distribution in the cytoplasm, yet patient’s fibroblasts showed an altered distribution with abnormal puncta staining. Assessment of AARS aminoacylation activity in patient-derived fibroblasts, completed by collaborators, revealed a reduction of AARS activity at 16% compared to that of a control. Taken together, these functional tests demonstrate the variants have caused functional defects in AARS protein and that this patient presents with a novel AARS phenotype. By identifying strong candidates in patients with unsolved suspected mitochondrial leukoencephalopathies, WES continues to be demonstrated as an invaluable tool in the identification of the molecular causes for rare diseases. Investigations into patient-specific AARS variants provide evidence for the phenotypic expansion of AARS-related diseases and the specific functional defects that underlie these late-onset cases. As the pathophysiological understanding of aminoacyl t-RNA synthetases is still limited, our work as well as others’ will be invaluable to our foundational understanding of this group of disorders, opening the door to the development of potential therapies</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Genevieve Bernard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z9480.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397d68c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x816x"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nitrogen transformations and loss over winter in manure-amended soils with cover crops</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ejack, Leanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>De nombreux agriculteurs épandent du fumier à l'automne, mais sans une culture en pleine croissance, l’azote (N) dans le fumier est susceptible de subir des pertes pendant l'hiver. Les cycles de gel-dégel peuvent exacerber les pertes de N par la stimulation des microbes du sol, transformant ainsi les substrats réactifs tels que N minéral du sol en oxyde nitreux (N2O). La culture de couverture pourrait absorber N réactif relâché par le fumier épandu pendant l’automne et pouvant réduire les pertes de N en hiver. L’objectif de ma recherche était d’étudier l’effet d’association du fumier épandue à l’automne et des cultures de couvertures sur les réactions de N du sol en hiver, et durant les cycles de gel-dégel, dans le terrain et au laboratoire. J’étudiais également la relation entre la production de N2O et la concentration de substrat réactif présent dans le sol. L’expérience de terrain consistait en une conception factorielle complète en bloc aléatoire complet avec trois traitements de lisier et quatre types de cultures de couverture. L’expérience a eu lieu sur deux sites au Québec, Canada. Le total de N dans le sol en automne (0,15 m de profondeur), N du fumier et N de la culture de couverture ont été comparés au N total du sol au printemps (0,15 m de profondeur) et N des tissus végétaux de la culture de couverture tuée par l'hiver pour chaque combinaison de traitement. Après la fin de la culture de couverture, le blé (Triticum aestivum L.) a été ensemencée et chaque parcelle principale a été séparée en deux sous-parcelles recevant soit a) 100 kg d'engrais à base d'urée, ou b) aucun engrais. Des échantillons de blé ont été prélevés au tallage, à la floraison et à la maturité pour déterminer la teneur en N. Les rendements finaux des récoltes ont également été mesurés. Les cultures de couvertures ne retiennent pas efficacement N du fumier (absorption ≤ 7%) et il n'y avait pas de différence entre les niveaux de N d'automne et du printemps entre les parcelles recevant du fumier et les parcelles sans fumier. Lors de la prochaine saison de culture, le fumier épandu à l'automne ne fournissait pas de N résiduel et les rendements moyens de blé étaient inférieurs de 11 à 14% dans les sous-parcelles sans engrais au printemps, par rapport à celles de 100 kg N ha-1. Au laboratoire, des pots contenant de 280 à 285 g de terre agricole ont reçu quatre traitements d’engrais N (aucun engrais, fumier liquide, fumier solide, urée), avec ou sans culture de couverture de ray-grass. Les pots ont été exposés à 0, 1, 2 ou 3 cycles simulés de gel-dégel entre -4 et + 4°C. La production de N2O a été mesurée par intervalle de 3 h à 0, 3, 6 et 9 h pour chaque cycle de gel-dégel, puis des pots ont été échantillonnés de manière destructive pour déterminer la concentration en N réactif. Il n'y avait pas de différence de production de N2O entre les combinaisons de traitement parmi tous les cycles de gel-dégel, mais les pots contenant de l'urée ou de l'engrais à base de lisier avaient la concentration la plus élevée de N minéral dans le sol. La culture de couverture a eu un effet minimal sur la concentration de N minéral dans le sol. N minéral du sol explique environ 14% de la variation de la production de N2O. La production de N2O des pots sous cycle de gel-dégel a connu une augmentation de 937 à 1000% par rapport aux pots non congelées. Cela suggère qu'une activité microbienne qui produit du N2O a eu lieu dans les sols gelés à -4°C, provoquant une accumulation de N2O sous la glace et a été émis après la décongélation du sol (à 4°C), principalement durant les 3 premières heures. Les résultats de ces études de terrain et de laboratoire suggèrent que les transformations microbiennes de N ne s’arrêtent pas pendant les mois d’hiver, et entraîne des pertes importantes de N dans les sols fertilisés en dehors de la saison de croissance dans les régions tempérées froides et humides</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Many farmers apply manure in the fall (autumn season), but without an actively growing crop in the ground, the nitrogen (N) in the manure is susceptible to over-winter losses. Periods of freeze-thaw cycling can exacerbate N losses by stimulating soil microbes to transform reactive substrates like soil mineral N into nitrous oxide (N2O), a potent greenhouse gas. The uptake of reactive N from fall-applied manure by a fall-sown cover crop may reduce over-winter N losses. The objective of my research was to investigate the effect of combining fall manure application with cover cropping on soil N dynamics over winter and during periods of freeze-thaw cycling under field and laboratory conditions. I also examined the relationship between N2O production and reactive soil substrate concentrations. The field experiment was a full factorial in a randomized complete block design with three manure treatments (none, liquid, solid) and four cover crop types (no cover crop, 100% ryegrass [Lolium multiflorum Lam.], a 75% ryegrass/25% hairy vetch [Vicia villosa Roth] mixture and a 50% ryegrass/50% vetch mixture). The experiment was established at two field sites in Québec, Canada. A partial N mass balance (g N m-2) was calculated in fall (sum of the fall soil N stock to 0.15 m depth, N in fall-applied manure, and N in cover crop biomass) and in spring (sum of the spring soil N stock to 0.15 m depth and N in the winter-killed cover crop) for each treatment combination. After terminating the cover crop, spring wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) was planted, and each main plot was split into two subplots that received either 100 kg N ha-1 urea fertilizer or no fertilizer. Wheat samples were taken at tillering, flowering, and maturity to determine N content. Final yield was also measured. Cover crops were not effective at retaining manure N (≤7% uptake) and there was no difference in the fall and spring N balance among the manure and non-manure plots. Residual N was not supplied from fall-applied manure to the spring wheat in the next growing season, and average wheat yields were 11–14% less in the subplots that received no spring N fertilizer than those that received 100 kg N ha-1. In the laboratory, pots with 280–285 g soil received four N fertilizer treatments (none, liquid manure, solid manure, urea), with or without an annual ryegrass cover crop. The pots were exposed to 0, 1, 2, or 3 simulated freeze-thaw cycles (FTCs) at -4 to +4°C. The N2O production was measured at 0, 3, 6 and 9 h for each FTC, then pots were destructively sampled to determine the soil mineral N concentration. There was no difference in N2O production among the treatment combinations across all FTCs, but the pots that received urea or liquid manure had the highest soil mineral N concentration. The cover crop had minimal effect on the soil mineral N concentration. Soil mineral N explained approximately 14% of the variation in N2O production. Pots that underwent FTCs had a remarkable 937–1000% increase in N2O production compared to unfrozen pots. This suggests that N2O-producing microbial activity occurred in the frozen soils at -4oC, causing N2O to accumulate under ice and be released when the soils thawed at 4oC, mostly within the first 3 h. The results of both the field and laboratory studies suggests that microbial N transformations do not stop during the winter months, leading to substantial losses of N in fertilized soils during the non-growing season in cold humid temperate regions</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joann Karen Whalen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903436w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x816x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Natural Resource Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57nw05s"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>FOXA1: Its role and its interaction with prolactin hormone signaling in triple negative breast cancer tumorigenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ibrahim, Mounira</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le cancer du sein triple négatif (TNBC) est le sous-type de cancer du sein le plus résistant. Le manque d'expression des récepteurs des œstrogènes, de la progestérone et du facteur 2 de croissance épidermique humain dans le TNBC conduit à une utilisation limitée du traitement ciblé. Par conséquent, le traitement par chimiothérapie demeure la principale approche pour le traitement de la TNBC avec de faibles avantages thérapeutiques et un risque accru de résistance. Les thérapies fondées sur la différenciation par inversion des cellules cancéreuses du sein en un phénotype épithélial ont récemment été étudiées comme une approche thérapeutique prometteuse pour le TNBC. En effet, le laboratoire du Dr Ali a montré que le rétablissement de la voie de différenciation de la prolactine a inversé le phénotype mésenchymateux agressif de la TNBC dans la forme épithéliale avec un comportement moins agressif, moins invasif et moins de métastase. De plus, ils ont identifié un sous-groupe de patients TNBC dont l'expression du récepteur de la prolactine (PRLR) est élevée, la survie globale meilleure et le pronostic meilleur. Par l'analyse des groupes de métagènes, le sous-type TNBC-PRLR est caractérisé par la régulation ascendante des gènes de différenciation de type luminal qui sont FOXA1 et AR. Notre objectif est de déterminer l'effet de FOXA1 sur la transition mésenchymateuse épithéliale (EMT) des cellules cancéreuses du sein et comment il peut moduler le rôle antitumorigène de la prolactine et sa voie de signalisation dans le cancer du sein. Pour atteindre nos objectifs, nous avons mesuré l'expression de FOXA1 au niveau de l'ARNm et des protéines après avoir traité les lignées cellulaires TNBC-PRLR avec la prolactine. Nous avons également produit CRISPR knock out de FOXA1 dans ces lignées cellulaires et mesuré le taux de protéines de la E-cadhérine, un marqueur épithélial et de la vimentine comme marqueur mésenchymateux. Comme on s'y attendait, les cellules éliminées ont montré une diminution du taux de E-cadhérine et une augmentation de la vimentine par rapport aux cellules parentales. Enfin, nous concluons que FOXA1 peut être un marqueur pro-différenciation potentiel dans les cellules du cancer du sein. D'autres études sont nécessaires pour étudier ce rôle de FOXA1 et son utilisation comme cible de la médecine personnalisée dans le cancer du sein triple négatif</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Triple Negative Breast Cancer (TNBC) is the most resistant subtype of breast cancer. The lack of expression of estrogen, progesterone, and human epidermal growth factor 2 receptors in TNBC leads to the limited use of targeted therapy. Therefore, treatment with chemotherapy remains the main approach for treating TNBC with low therapeutic benefits and increased risk of resistance. Pro-differentiation based therapies by reversing breast cancer cells into an epithelial phenotype have recently been studied as a promising therapeutic approach for TNBC. Indeed, the laboratory of Dr. Ali showed that restoring prolactin pro-differentiation pathway reversed the mesenchymal aggressive phenotype of TNBC into the epithelial form with less aggressive behavior, less invasiveness, and lower metastasis. In addition, they identified a TNBC subgroup of patients that preserved prolactin receptor (PRLR) expression to show better overall survival and better prognosis. By metagenes cluster analysis, the TNBC-PRLR subtype is characterized by the up regulation of luminal-like differentiation genes which are Forkhead Box A1 (FOXA1) and androgen receptor (AR). Our aim is to determine the effect of FOXA1 on the epithelial mesenchymal transition (EMT) of breast cancer cells and how it may modulate the antitumorigenic role of prolactin and its signaling pathway in breast cancer. To achieve our objectives, we measured the expression of FOXA1 at the mRNA and protein levels after treating TNBC-PRLR cell lines with prolactin. We also produced CRISPR knock out of FOXA1 in these cell lines and measured the protein level of both E-cadherin, an epithelial marker and vimentin as a mesenchymal marker. As expected, the knock-out cells showed a decrease in the level of E-cadherin and an increase in vimentin compared to the parental cells. Finally, we conclude that FOXA1 can be a potential pro-differentiation marker in breast cancer cells. Further studies are needed to investigate this role of FOXA1 and its use as a target for personalized medicine in triple negative breast cancer</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Suhad Ali</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zg387.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nw05s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bq850"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intermediate flortaucipir uptake is associated with beta-amyloid PET, &amp; cerebrospinal fluid tau in cognitively normal older adults</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McSweeney, Melissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hyperphosphorylated tau protein in the form of neurofibrillary tangles is one of the major pathological hallmarks of Alzheimer’s disease (AD). This thesis explores early tau accumulation, as measured with the positron emission tomography (PET) imaging radiotracer [18F]flortaucipir, and its associations with Alzheimer’s disease-related biological and cognitive markers in cognitively intact older adults with a familial history of sporadic Alzheimer’s disease. We show that flortaucipir binding in cognitively normal older adults is associated with three key markers of Alzheimer’s disease: amyloid-beta PET tracer retention, phosphorylated tau in the cerebrospinal fluid, and cognitive performance. Moreover, the associations of flortaucipir with Aβ and cerebrospinal fluid phosphorylated tau are evident at subthreshold levels of flortaucipir binding. These results suggest that intermediate levels of flortaucipir retention can indicate meaningful pathological changes associated with Alzheimer’s disease before the onset of clinical symptoms, while higher levels of flortaucipir retention may be necessary to observe associations with worse cognitive performance on a group level</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les enchevêtrements neurofibrillaires composés de protéines tau hyperphosphorylées sont l’un des principaux signes pathologiques de la maladie d’Alzheimer (MA). Cette thèse explore l’accumulation précoce de tau, mesurée en tomographie par émission de positrons (TEP) à l’aide du radiotraceur [18F]flortaucipir, et ses associations avec les marqueurs biologiques et cognitifs liés à la maladie d’Alzheimer chez des personnes âgées sans trouble cognitif avec antécédents familiaux de la forme sporadique de la MA. Nous montrons que la rétention du traceur flortaucipir chez les personnes âgées cognitivement normales est associée à trois marqueurs clés de la MA: la rétention du traceur bêta-amyloïde (Aβ) TEP, la tau phosphorylée dans le liquide cérébro-spinal et les performances cognitives. De plus, les associations de flortaucipir avec Aβ et la protéine tau phosphorylée dans le liquide cérébro-spinal sont évidentes même à des niveaux faibles de rétention du flortaucipir. Ces résultats suggèrent que même de faibles quantités de rétention du flortaucipir peuvent indiquer des modifications pathologiques significatives associées à la MA avant l’apparition de symptômes cliniques. En revanche, des quantités plus élevées de rétention du flortaucipir sont nécessaires pour observer des associations avec des performances cognitives</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sylvia Villeneuve</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c4971.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bq850</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x357z"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fragmented abundance: disjunction and uncertainty in a solar economy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Auerbach, Joel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This project examines contemporary capitalism’s relationship to abundance and uncertainty, via the political economy of electrical infrastructure. Echoing Bataille’s notion of solar economy, in which the primary problem is not scarcity but managing excess, I orient around a case of relative wealth and literal solar energy abundance: California’s electricity grid, especially from the 1990s to the present. Whereas much recent attention to infrastructure has focused on moments of breakdown, I develop the conceptual terrain surrounding positive investments in infrastructural mediation of the human-earth metabolism. In attempting to smooth over the uncertainty and intermittency introduced by renewable energy, electrical infrastructures work to compose abstract, homogeneous spacetimes insulated from other rhythms (producing stasis out of flux). By maintaining this type of gap, I show how the category of infrastructure occupies a key point of convergence between Marx’s theory of metabolic rift and Deleuze and Guattari’s concept of disjunction in Anti-Oedipus, in a way that opens questions about the meaning of communism today (with ecological issues given prominence). Part I describes the problem of intermittency and its driving role in grid dynamics, showing how capital seizes on this to recapture the potentials of solar energy. Part II examines different figurations of the concept of planning, which is often suggested as a means of reining in capitalist irrationalities of this type. For an articulation of planning sensitive to questions of self-sufficiency, scale, and uncertainty amidst abundance, I turn toward Harney and Moten’s The Undercommons, asking how their framework might bear on questions of energy, ecology, and infrastructure</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce travail examine le rapport du capitalisme contemporain à l’abondance et à l’incertitude, via l’économie politique des infrastructures électriques. Faisant écho à la notion d’économie solaire de Bataille, dans laquelle le principal problème n’est pas celui de la rareté mais celui de la gestion de l’excès, je considère un cas de richesse relative et d’abondance littérale d’énergie solaire : le réseau électrique californien, en particulier depuis les années 1990 à aujourd’hui. Alors que l’attention récente portée aux infrastructures s’est concentrée sur les moments de dysfonctionnement, je développe le terrain conceptuel autour des investissements positifs dans la médiation infrastructurelle du métabolisme humain-terre. En tentant de dissiper l’incertitude et l’intermittence occasionnées par les énergies renouvelables, les infrastructures électriques créent des espaces-temps abstraits et homogènes, isolés des autres rythmes (produisant une stase à partir des flux). En maintenant ce type de séparation, je montre comment la catégorie d’infrastructure occupe un point de convergence entre la théorie de la rupture métabolique de Marx et le concept de disjonction théorisé par Deleuze et Guattari dans L’Anti-Oedipe, d’une manière qui soulève des questions sur la signification du communisme aujourd’hui (les problèmes écologiques étant mis en évidence). La première partie décrit le problème de l’intermittence ainsi que le rôle moteur que joue celle-ci dans la dynamique des réseaux, en montrant comment le capital s’en sert pour récupérer les potentiels de l’énergie solaire. La deuxième partie examine différentes représentations du concept de planification, qui est souvent suggéré comme moyen de mitiger les irrationalités capitalistes de ce type. Pour une articulation de la planification sensible aux questions d’autosuffisance, d’échelle et d’incertitude en milieu d’abondance, je me tourne vers The Undercommons de Harney et Moten, en explorant la pertinence de leur cadre théorique pour les questions d’énergie, d’écologie et d’infrastructure</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Darin Barney</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s457t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x357z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art History and Communications Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mm683"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The metacognitive knowledge of adolescent students during the information search process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bowler, Leanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La connaissance métacognitive est essentielle à la maîtrise de l’information. Dans un monde où les possibilités en matière d’infonnation et de communication ont explosées, la principale difficulté pour les utilisateurs des systèmes et des services d’information ne consiste pas tant à trouver l’ infonnation qu’à la filtrer et à l’intégrer à un tout cohérent. Pour y arriver, ils doivent être en mesure de la comprendre, ce qui présuppose la connaissance de ses propres besoins, objectifs et habiletés en matière d’information. Ce type de connaissance de soi - appelé connaissance métacognitive - est constitué de trois composantes de base: la connaissance de soi, la connaissance de la nature d’une tâche cognitive en relation avec ses propres habilités cognitives et la connaissance du comment et du quand utiliser efficacement les approches cognitives pour effectuer une tâche cognitive. De telles connaissances utilisées pour rechercher de l’information peuvent aider l’utilisateur à résoudre des problèmes d’information complexes. Le groupe d’utilisateurs à qui le développement de la connaissance métacognitive peut profiter le plus est probablement celui des adolescents de 16 à 18 ans. Sur le point de devenir des adultes, ils sont confrontés à nombre des problèmes d’information complexes des adultes, mais en tant que jeunes adultes, la profondeur de leur connaissance dans la plupart des domaines peut être limitée, leur expérience de la vie ne reposant que sur quelques années. La présente étude a employé les méthodes qualitatives de recherche en milieu naturel pour analyser la connaIssance métacognitive des adolescents pendant qu’ils recherchaient, triaient et utilisaient l’ infonnation pour un projet de recherche scolaire dans le cadre du processus de recherche d’information (Information Search Process (ISP)) de Kuhlthau. L’étude s’est poursuivie sur une période de quatre mois dans un des cé</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Metacognitive knowledge is a critical piece of the information literacy puzzle. In a world of exploding information and communications possibilities, the difficulty for users of information systems and services may not lie in finding information but in filtering and integrating it into a cohesive whole. To do this, they must be able to make sense of it, an act that assumes knowledge about one’s own information needs, goals and abilities. This type of self-knowledge - called metacognitive knowledge - has three basic components: knowledge of one’s self, knowledge of the nature of a cognitive task in relation to one’s own cognitive abilities, and knowledge of how and when to effectively use cognitive strategies to complete a cognitive task. Such knowledge, when used in information seeking, may help users to solve complex information problems. There is perhaps no other user group who could benefit more from the development of metacognitive knowledge than adolescents, aged 16 to 18. On the cusp of adulthood, they face many of the complex information problems of adults, but as “novice adults” their depth of knowledge on most topics may be shallow simply because they have only experienced life for a handful of years. This study used naturalistic research methods to investigate the metacognitive knowledge of adolescents as they searched for, selected and used information for a school-based, inquiry project, within the framework of Kuhlthau’s Information Search Process (ISP). It was conducted over a four-month period in a Montreal-area CEGEP (post-secondary educational institutions in Quebec). The participants were students in their first year of CEGEP (equivalent to grade 12). Ten participants, ranging in age from 16 to 18, each kept a written or audio journal in which they recorded their thoughts, feelings, actions, and self-prompting questions, participated in four interviews, three conducted by telephone and one face-to-face, and completed a visualizing ex</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Large, Andrew</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d6966.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm683</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Information behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metacognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Information retrieval</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236241v"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An exploratory study on information work activities of competitive intelligence professionals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jin, Tao, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Malgré l’intérêt grandissant pour la veille concurrentielle, il existe peu d’études empiriques traitant du travail des professionnels oeuvrant dans ce domaine. La présente étude pose trois questions de base: qui sont les professionnels faisant de la veille concurrentielle; quelles sont leurs tâches et activités et comment sont elles réalisées; et finalement, quels facteurs limitent leur performance et capacité de compléter ces tâches et ces activités. À travers le Canada, 28 professionnels de la veille concurrentielle ont été recrutés pour l’étude représentant 24 organisations différentes dans 12 industries générales et 16 de type spécifique. Ces professionnels représentent des analystes, des gestionnaires de l’information, des chercheurs en études de marché, des conseillers stratégiques et des spécialistes de l’information. Leurs objectifs principaux consistent à accroître la conscientisation à l’environnement concurrentiel dans lequel leurs organisations rivalisent et à rehausser la qualité de la prise de décision chez leurs différents clients. Pour atteindre ces objectifs, ils et elles s’impliquent dans dix catégories distinctes d’activités: scruter les nouvelles et gérer une veille informationnelle; gérer des projets; répondre aux demandes d’information ponctuelles; communiquer avec les différentes parties; élaborer des produits de veille concurrentielle; lire et évaluer le matériel diversifié; rédiger et réviser des documents variés; former des employés à la veille concurrentielle; recevoir une formation continue; et s’impliquer dans d’autres activités administratives non-reliées au domaine de la veille. La plupart du temps est consacré à la préparation des produits de veille concurrentielle, aux communications avec les diverses parties, à la gestion de courriel et à la scrutation des nouvelles. La plupart des besoins informationnels des participants ne sont pas individuels mais$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Competitive intelligence (CI) can be loosely defined as the process by which an organization legally and systematically collects, organizes, analyzes, and disseminates the information about its competitive environment. Notwithstanding the growing interest in CI, there are few empirical investigations on the work activities of CI professionals. This research addresses three basic questions: Who are CI professionals, which tasks and activities are they engaged in and how do they go about them, and what factors constrain their performance and completion of these tasks and activities? Twenty-eight CI professionals across Canada participated in the study from 24 different organizations, representing 16 specific industries. These CI professionals include various intelligence managers and analysts, market researchers, strategic advisors, and information specialists, representing two main groups: business professionals and information professionals. Their major goals are to heighten awareness of the competitive environment in which their organizations compete and to enhance decision making by their various clients. To achieve these goals, they engage in 10 general classes of activities: news scanning and monitoring; project management; responding ad hoc requests; communicating with various stakeholders; preparing CI products/deliverables; perusing and evaluating various materials; writing and editing diverse documents; coaching and training other staff for CI; undertaking training themselves; and administrative, non-CI, and sundry other activities. Among them, most of time is allocated to preparing CI products or deliverables, communicating with various stakeholders, and email processing and news scanning. Most of the information needs of the participants are not personal but derive from their organizational needs and clientele. The information seeking behavior of the participants can be situated on four axes: cyclical and noncyclical, reactive and proactive, linear and</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bouthillier, France</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322d695.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236241v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Competition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Business intelligence</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870w255"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors that influence the attitude of academic librarians in Saudi Arabia toward copyright laws</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>AlReyaee, Sulaiman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le but de cette recherche est d’étudier les facteurs qui influencent l’attitude des bibliothécaires académiques masculins menvers les lois sur les droits d’auteur en Arabie saoudite. Le modèle ternaire est utilisé afin d’évaluer l’attitude générale de ces bibliothécaires; ses trois composantes sont les sentiments, les croyances et les comportements. Cinq variables indépendantes qui pourraient affecter les bibliothécaires sont examinées: le niveau de scolarité, le domaine de travail, le poste, l’expérience professionnelle et les connaissances qu’ont les bibliothécaires des lois des droits d’auteur. Cette dernière variable est aussi évaluée par l’entremise d’un questionnaire divisé en six points, l’index des connaissances. Celui-ci est comparé ensuite aux quatre autres variables. Dans le cadre de cette étude, nous avons recruté 201 participants, tous des bibliothécaires académiques masculins provenant des sept (7) universités les plus reconnus. La méthode du sondage est utilisée pour la collecte des données, et une approche quantitative est employée afin d’évaluer la relation entre l’ «attitude» et les variables indépendantes. Les résultats dévoilent que les bibliothécaires académiques en Arabie saoudite ont une attitude positive, mais qu’ils manquent de connaissances à propos des lois des droits d’auteur. Une seule variable indépendante - le niveau de scolarité - s’avère reliée à la composante des «croyances» de cette attitude positive. Même si le niveau de connaissances, basé sur l’index, n’affecte pas l’attitude, il correspond aux niveaux de scolarité, de l’expérience professionnelle et du poste qu’occupe le bibliothécaire. Cette étude démontre clairement qu’il faut améliorer la scolarité et la formation des bibliothécaires en Arabie saoudite concernant les lois des droits d’auteur. Elle dévoile aussi que les bibliothécaires devraient avoir un mot à dire sur l</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The purpose of this research is to study the factors influencing the attitude of male academic librarians towards copyright laws in Saudi Arabia. The Tripartite Model is used to evaluate the overall attitude of academic librarians, defined in terms of three main components: feelings, beliefs, and behaviors. Five independent variables that may affect this attitude are investigated: level of education, domain of practice, position, professional experience, and academic librarians’ knowledge of copyright laws as measured by six pre-selected questions (knowledge Index). The knowledge Index is also later measured against the four other independent variables. Seven major universities were chosen, and 201 male academic librarians participated in this study. A survey method is adopted for collecting data, and a quantitative approach is used to measure the relationship between attitude and the independent variables. The results reveal that academic librarians in Saudi Arabia have a positive attitude, but inadequate knowledge, regarding copyright laws. Only one independent variable—the level of education—is found to be related to the belief component of attitude. While the level of knowledge based on the knowledge Index does not affect attitude, it is correlated with levels of education, experience, and position. This study demonstrates the need for improving librarians’ education and training in Saudi Arabia regarding copyright laws. It also reveals the importance of librarians’ input in copyright laws.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beheshti, Jamshid</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f148p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870w255</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Academic librarians -- Saudi Arabia -- Attitudes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copyright -- Saudi Arabia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603qx86k"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'écriture migrante au Québec: l'interculturalisme dans le discours littéraire et politique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélair, Karine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Si les écrivains venus d'ailleurs ont toujours existé au Québec, ils sont désignés et célébrés, après 1987, sous le vocable d' « écrivains migrants ». L'émergence, la nomination et la valorisation des écritures migrantes font écho au discours politique interculturaliste qui prône l'ouverture à l'altérité et une intégration des immigrants respectueuse de leur spécificité culturelle. Le gouvernement du Québec, dans divers documents officiels, jette les bases de sa politique de gestion de la diversité, misant d'une part sur la contribution des communautés culturelles à la vie québécoise, et d'autre part sur la promotion d'attitudes favorables à l'immigration et à la diversité. L'étude de quelques anthologies de littérature québécoise publiées au niveau collégial entre 1994 et 2008 montre la reprise du discours officiel par ces instruments pédagogiques, et la présentation des écritures migrantes comme littérature d'immigration dont le principal intérêt demeure le témoignage d'une réalité néo-québécoise ou étrangère. La reconnaissance des écritures migrantes s'insère donc dans un projet de transformation de la société québécoise, d'éducation interculturelle et de développement de consensus sociaux face à la nouvelle réalité pluraliste. Ainsi, le discours des institutions littéraire et scolaire en matière d'écritures migrantes ne se comprend bien qu'à la lueur du discours politique québécois en matière d'immigration, dont il épouse  les valeurs et les mots. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Writers of various origins have always written in Quebec. Since 1987, they have been recognized and coined the term “migrant writers.”  The emergence, designation and promotion of migrant writings echo the interculturalist political discourse advocating openness towards others and an integration of immigrants respectful of their cultural identity. In various official documents, the Quebec government has established a diversity management policy based upon contributions from cultural communities in Quebec and the promotion of positive attitudes towards immigration and cultural diversity. After some study of Quebecois literary anthologies published at Cegep level between 1994 and 2008, one recognizes that these pedagogical instruments support this official policy and present migrant writings as literature of immigrants whose primary interest remains the testimony of a “néo-québécoise” or a foreigner's reality. Recognition of the migrant literature highlights the political transformation of Quebec society via intercultural education and the development of social consensus with respect to pluralism. The literary and scholarly perspective on migrant writings can be well understood when it is related to the Quebec political view of immigration from which it borrows its words and values.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Biron</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nh48v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qx86k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278t44n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of vitamin D3 in regulating Islet Neogenesis Associated Protein</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Patapas, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diabetes is characterized by a complete (type 1) or partial (type 2) loss of pancreatic beta cells.  Regeneration of beta-cell mass is an important goal of diabetes research. Development of strategies to induce beta-cell regeneration in situ involves identification of candidate molecules with islet regenerating activity. Islet Neogenesis Associated Protein (INGAP), identified in our laboratory, has been shown to stimulate neo-islet formation. INGAP, an endogenous pancreatic protein, is a member of the Reg3 family of proteins.  We have previously shown that INGAP expression is regulated by inflammatory cytokines, more specifically by interleukin (IL)-6.  It would be of interest to identify other factors, preferably of non-inflammatory nature, that upregulate INGAP expression and subsequently induce islet neogenesis.  Here, using an in vitro hamster cell model and real time qRT-PCR, we show that INGAP gene expression is induced by 1,25(OH)2 D3, the hormonally active form of vitamin D. Our data indicate that 1,25(OH)2 D3 upregulates INGAP mRNA (up to 2.14 (± 0.59))  in a dose- and time-dependent manner. We also show that nicotinamide, the amide derivative of vitamin B3, potentiates the effect of 1,25(OH)2 D3 resulting in a 12-fold increase in INGAP mRNA. A computer analysis of the INGAP promoter region identified five candidate vitamin D responsive elements (VDREs), which may bind the ligand-activated nuclear vitamin D receptor (VDR). The role of this classic mechanism of vitamin D signaling in the upregulation of INGAP expression, as well as a potential involvement of rapid, membrane-linked signal transduction or calcium signaling pathways are also investigated here. This is the first study to provide evidence for regulation of INGAP, and possibly, of other Reg proteins by vitamin D3. Interestingly, vitamin D3 can be partially activated in beta cells and is implicated in cell growth and differentiation. Given the presence of VDRs in endocrine and exocrine pancreatic tissue, the potential role of vitamin D3 in islet neogenesis should be further investigated. Taken together, these data suggest an important role for vitamin D3 in beta-cell regeneration, which may prove to be a cost-effect, natural and safe treatment for type-1 and type-2 diabetes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le diabète est caractérisé par la perte totale (type 1) ou partielle (type 2) des cellules beta. La régénération d'une masse fonctionnelle de cellules beta est un objectif important de la recherche sur le diabète. Le développement de stratégies pour induire la régénération des cellules beta in situ implique l'identification de molécules candidates ayant une activité néogénique sur les îlots de Langerhans. La protéine Islet Neogenesis Associated Protein (INGAP), identifiée dans notre laboratoire, stimule la néogenèse des îlots de Langerhans. INGAP, protéine pancréatique endogène, est membre de la famille de protéines Reg3. Nous avons montré précédemment que l'expression d'INGAP est régulée par les cytokines inflammatoires, plus particulièrement par l'interleukine (IL) -6. Il serait intéressant d'interfier d'autres facteurs, préférablement de nature non-inflammatoire, ayant la capacité d'agumenter l'expression d'INGAP et par conséquent la néogenèse des îlots de Langerhans. Ici, en utilisant un modèle in vitro de cellules de hamster et la technique de RT-PCR quantitative (real-time), nous montrons que l'expression d'INGAP est induite par 1,25(OH)2D3, la forme hormonalment active de la vitamine D.  Nos données indiquent que 1,25(OH)2D3 induit l'expression de INGAP (ARNm) d'un facteur 2.14 (± 0.59)  de façon dose-dépendante et en suivant une cinétique bien precise. Nous montrons également que la nicotinamide, un dérivé amidique de la vitamine B3, potentialise l'effect de la 1,25(OH)2D3, ce qui a pour résultat une augmentation de 12 fois de l'expression de INGAP (ARNm). En utilisant une analyse informatique de la séquence du promoteur d'INGAP, nous avons identifié 5 éléments de réponse a la vitamine D (VDREs) qui pourraient lier le récepteur a la vitamin D (VDR) activé par la fixation de son ligand. Le rôle de ce mécanisme classique de la signalisation de la vitamine D dans l'induction de l'expression d'INGAP, ainsi que la participation potentielle d'une transduction rapide via liaison à la membrane ou encore l'implication de la voie de signalisation du calcium sont également étudiées ici. Cette étude est la première à démontrer la regulation de l'expression de INGAP, et probablement d'autre proteins Reg, par la vitamine D3. De façon intéressante, la vitamine D3 peut être partiellement activée dans les cellules beta et est impliquée dans la croissance cellulaire et la différenciation. Compte-tenu de la présence de VDR dans le le pancreas endocrine et exocrine, le rôle potentiel de vitamine D3 dans la néogenèse d'îlot devrait être étudié plus avant. L'ensemble de ces données suggère un rôle important pour la vitamine D3 dans la régénération des cellules beta, qui pourrait donc constituer un traitement naturel, sécurataire, et peu coûteux pour le diabète type-1 et type 2.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maria Petropavlovskaya</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lawrence Rosenberg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p28d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t44n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sg71s"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Statistical analysis of a high-content screening assay of microtubule polymerization status</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lo, Ernest</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present work describes the analysis of the first high-content, double-immunofluorescence assay of microtubule polymerization status.  Two novel features of the work are the extraction of a new class of cell metrics that target fiber-based cell phenotypes (using the Fiberscore algorithm) in a high-content assay, and the development of a non-uniformity correction algorithm that allows the unbiased analysis of dim cells. Findings relevant to HCS data analysis in general include: (1) Spatial plate biases are significant in HCS data and manifest differently for different cell-level metrics; (2) Individual plates are separate statistical entities; thus cellular data in HCS cannot in general be pooled before proper normalization procedures are applied; (3) Inter-plate variance is significant in HCS data such that inter-plate replicates are a necessity.  However HCS data also appears to be amenable for empirical Bayes methods for improving sensitivity to 'hit' compounds; (4) Cell populations are observed to respond heterogeneously to treatment compounds.  Initial tests of an alternative cell population summary statistic (the AUC) thought to be suited for the detection of cell subpopulations, did not indicate significant improvements in sensitivity over conventional measures (such as the population median) however. The correlation texture metric was identified as showing greatly increased sensitivity, when used on the Tyr-tubulin-specific channel.  The identification of this cell-level metric provides a preliminary demonstration that high-content assays have the potential to provide superior performance over conventional whole-well HTS assays.  An image-processing related issue termed the 'area-intensity confound', was also identified as a possible major source of variability that limited the performance of the alternative cell-level metrics that were developed.  A resolution to this issue is proposed. Many open questions and avenues of further investigation remain, and the current study represents only a preliminary step in the ongoing analysis of the HCS microtubule polymerization status assay, and the development of pertinent statistical inference methods.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La présente étude décrit l'analyse du premier criblage à haut-contenu (HCS) d'un test multi-paramétrique utilisant trois marqueurs fluorescents; ce test  permet d'explorer l'état de polymérisation des microtubules. Ce travail se distingue par deux caractéristiques novatrices: 1)  L'extraction d'une nouvelle catégorie de mesures cellulaires qui caractérisent des organites cellulaires de type « fibres » (en utilisant l'algorithme Fiberscore) dans un criblage haut-contenu, 2) Le développement d'un algorithme pour la correction du manque d'uniformité des images permettant l'analyse non biaisée des cellules sombres. Les résultats inhérents à l'analyse de données de HCS incluent en général les points suivants: (1) Les biais spatiaux liés aux plaques sont significatifs et se manifestent différemment selon les paramètres mesurés; (2) Chaque plaque est une entité statistique distincte; donc les données de HCS ne peuvent pas être compilées sans utilisation préalable de méthodes de normalisation appropriées; (3) La variance entre les plaques est significative; ainsi la présence de réplicats est cruciale.  Cependant, les données HCS sont conformes à l'application de la méthode de Bayes empirique en vue d'améliorer la sensibilité aux composés bio-actifs; (4) Les cellules répondent de façon hétérogène au traitement par des petites molécules chimiques. Cependant, contrairement à notre attente, les tests réalisés avec l'approche statistique 'AUC' n'ont pas indiqué une amélioration de puissance statistique. La mesure texturale de 'corrélation' a été identifiée comme une mesure qui présente une puissance statistique plus importante sur le canal de 'Tyr-tubulin'. L'identification de cette mesure fournit une démonstration préliminaire que les criblages HCS pourraient être plus performants que les criblages à haut débit conventionnels (HTS). Un problème lié au traitement d'images et plus particulièrement à la segmentation des images, que nous avons appellé 'the area-intensity confound', a été identifié comme une source importante de variabilité : ceci a limité la performance des mesures cellulaires alternatives qui ont été développées. Une solution à ce problème est proposée. Il reste plusieurs questions ouvertes et de nombreuses voies de recherches à explorer. Cette étude n'est qu'une étape préliminaire dans l'analyse du criblage à haut-contenu sur l'état de polymérisation des microtubules, et le développement des méthodes statistiques pertinentes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert Nadon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>James Anthony Hanley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w02c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg71s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t229j"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vitamin D status and recommendations to improve vitamin D status in Canadian youth</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mark, Sean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Little is known regarding the vitamin D status of Canadian youth. Our objectives were: (i) to describe the vitamin D status of Québec youth using a representative sample; (ii) examine the relative contributions of diet, physical activity and fat mass to the variance in plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D{25(OH)D}, the best biomarker of vitamin D status; and (iii) examine the influence of household income and food insecurity on the intakes of dietary vitamin D, calcium and dairy foods. To describe vitamin D status, we used data from a cross-sectional survey representative of Québec youth aged 9, 13 and 16, the Québec Child and Adolescent Health and Social Survey (QCAHS). For the second objective, 159 youth, aged 8-11 whose parents (at least one) were obese or had the metabolic syndrome were used for cross-sectional analysis in the Québec Adipose and Lifestyle InvesTigation in Youth (QUALITY). Fat mass was measured using Dual X-ray Absorptiometry (DXA) and physical activity was assessed by accelerometer. Finally, we analyzed data from the Canadian Community Health Survey (CCHS), a sample of 8960, 9-18-year-olds representative of Canadian youth for whom a single 24 hour dietary recall, measured height and weight, sociodemographic and information on food insecurity were available. Greater than 90% of youth had sub-optimal vitamin D levels {plasma 25(OH)D &lt; 75 nmol} at the end of winter and beginning of spring in both the QUALITY and QCAHS study. In the QCAHS study, older youth had a higher prevalence of vitamin D deficiency {25(OH)D &lt; 27.5 nmol} (&gt; 10%) than younger youth and girls from low income households had lower plasma 25(OH)D concentrations. In the QUALITY study, milk consumption and physical activity had modest associations with plasma 25(OH)D  corresponding to 2.9 nmol/L and 2.1 nmol/L higher  plasma 25(OH)D per standard deviation increase in these exposures, respectively. In the CCHS study, we found evidence that milk intake was being displaced by sweetened beverages amongst low income boys and food insecure girls. Population wide measures to increase dietary vitamin D intake should be examined in Canadian youth.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il y a peu de connaisances concernant le statut vitamin D des jeunes Canadiens. Nos objectifs étaient de: (i) décrire le statut vitamin D des jeunes Québécois en utilisant un échantillon représentatif; (ii) examiner la contribution de la diète, l'activité physique et l'adiposité a expliquer la variance du 25-hydroxyvitamin D, {25(OH)D.}, le meilleur biomarqueur du statut vitamine D; et (iii) examiner l'influence du statut socio-économique et l'insécurité alimentaire sur le consommation des produits laitiers, du calcium et de la vitamine D alimentaire. Pour décrire le statut vitamine D on a utilisé les données transversales d'un échantillon représentatif des jeunes Québecois agés de 9, 13 et 16 ans. Pour le deuxième objectif, 159 jeunes, âgés 8-11 ans avec des parents (au moins un) qui étaient obèses ou avaient le syndrome métabolique etaient utilisés pour une analyse transversale dans l'étude Québec Adipose and Lifestyle InvesTigation in Youth  (QUALITY). Le tissu adipeux a été mesuré avec le dual X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) et l'activité physique était mésurer par accéléromètre. Finalement, on a utilisé des données du Canadian Community Health Survey (CCHS), un échantillon de 8960 jeunes, agés de 9-18 ans qui avaient un rappel alimentaire de 24 heures, le poids et la taille mesuré, l'information sociodémograhique et le statut de sécurité alimentaire. Dans l'étude QUALITY et le QCAHS plus de 90% des jeunes avaient un statut de vitamine D sub-optimal {plasma 25(OH)D &lt; 75 nmol} à la fin de l'hiver et au début du printemps. Dans l'étude QCAHS, les adolescents avaient une prévalence de déficience de vitamine D  élevé {25(OH)D &lt; 27.5 nmol} (&gt; 10%) et les filles venant des foyers défavorisés avait des niveaux de vitamine D plus bas. Dans l'étude QUALITY, un augmentation d'un écart-type de la consommation du lait et l'activité physique était associée avec une augmentation du niveau de vitamin D de 2.9 nmol/L and 2.1 nmol/L respectivement. Dans l'étude CCHS nous avons remarqué que les garçons de milieux défavorisés et les filles avec une  insécurité alimentaire consommaient moins de lait et le lait étaitremplacé par les breuvages sucrés. Des mesures pour augmenter la consommation de vitamine D parmi les jeunes Canadiens devraient être examinées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Katherine Gray-Donald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm448.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t229j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816n015"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Multiple levels of Protein Kinase R inhibition during Human Immunodeficiency Virus replication by double-stranded RNA binding proteins and its relationship to the weak innate cell response to viral infection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Clerzius, Guerline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Following infection by most viruses, an antiviral state is induced in the host cells characterized by the expression of interferon (IFN) and several IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs). IFN treatment is effective to inhibit HIV replication in infected cells, but shows no significant improvement of HIV-infected patients. Currently, the discrepancy between the in vitro and the in vivo findings remains largely unresolved. The IFN-induced RNA-dependent protein kinase PKR is activated via trans-phosphorylation and plays a central role in the IFN-induced antiviral pathway. Our results show that PKR is transiently activated following HIV-1 infection of Jurkat and peripheral blood mononuclear cells. The kinase is then inactivated at the viral peak, when HIV replication is highly active. By immunoprecipitation, we found that PKR forms a ribonucleoprotein complex with cellular double-stranded RNA binding proteins (dsRBPs), the TAR RNA Binding Protein (TRBP), the adenosine deaminase acting on RNA (ADAR)1 and the PKR Activator (PACT) during HIV replication. Over-expression of PKR is sufficient to inhibit HIV production in HEK 293T cells. This inhibition is reversed by expression of the ADAR1, another ISG. By using mutants of ADAR1, we show that this activity is linked to the ability of the protein to bind PKR. In astrocytes that do not replicate HIV efficiently due to an enhanced PKR response, ADAR1 partially restores viral expression. Surprisingly, PACT binds to and inhibits PKR activity. All three dsRBPs, TRBP, ADAR1 and PACT prevent PKR activation and the phosphorylation of its downstream target, eIF2alpha. Together, our results highlight the key function of PKR in innate immunity and its multiple-level of regulation during HIV-1 replication.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'infection d'une cellule par un virus induit un état antiviral, caractérisé par l'expression de l'interféron (IFN) et de plusieurs gènes induits par l'IFN. Le traitement par l'IFN est efficace pour inhiber la réplication du virus de l'immunodéficience humaine (VIH) dans des cellules infectées en culture, mais ne montre aucun effet bénéfique chez les patients infectés par ce même virus. Cette disparité qui existe entre les résultats de recherche in vivo et in vitro n'est toujours pas résolue. PKR, une protéine kinase induite par les IFNs, est activée par phosphorylation et joue un rôle central dans le mécanisme antiviral de l'IFN. Nos résultats démontrent que PKR est activée de manière transitoire suite à l'infection de cellules lymphocytaires Jurkat ou de lymphocytes/monocytes primaires du sang périphérique par le VIH. Par contre, la kinase n'est plus activée durant et après le pic d'infection, lorsque la réplication du virus est intense. Par immunoprécipitation, nous avons démontré que PKR forme un complexe ribonucleoprotéique avec plusieurs protéines cellulaires qui lient l'ARN double-brin, soit la protéine liant l'ARN TAR, TRBP, l'adénosine déaminase ADAR, ainsi que la protéine activatrice de PKR, PACT, pendant la réplication virale. La surexpression de PKR est suffisante pour inhiber la production du VIH dans les cellules HEK 293T. Cette inhibition est supprimée par l'expression d'ADAR1, une des protéines induite par les IFNs. Par différentes mutations dans la séquence protéique d'ADAR1, nous avons démontré que cette activité d'ADAR est liée à sa capacité de lier PKR. Dans les astrocytes, qui ne répliquent pas le VIH efficacement en raison d'une activation accrue de PKR, ADAR1 rétablit partiellement l'expression virale. Étonnamment, PACT se lie à PKR et inhibe son activité dans les cellules infectées par le VIH. Testées en parallèle, TRBP, ADAR1 et PACT empêchent l'activation de PKR ainsi que la phos</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anne Gatignol</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk042.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n015</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Virology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f388r"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theoretical and numerical analysis of high-explosive channel detonation using real-gas models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leung, Ho Wing</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'onde de choc des précurseurs apparaissant à la détonation d'explosifs de grande puissance peut être empêché par la haute pression de remplissage initial et a été démontrée par des expériences précédement. Toutefois, les résultats théoriques et numériques des travaux précédents ont seulement atteint un accord qualitatif. Il a été suggéré d'introduire des équations réelles du gaz dans le modèle analytique et le simulation numérique pour confronter le problème. Dans cette thèse, deux études paramétriques sont eﬀectuées sur le modèle analytique de gaz parfait développé dans les travauxs précédentes, dont les paramètres examinés sont le taux de chaleur spéciﬁque (γ) et la pression de stagnation de l'air et les produits de détonation. Les résultats montrent que (1) les eﬀets réels du gaz sont importantes où le rapport de surface air/explosif est plus petit, et (2) le modèle analytique doit être modiﬁée pour tenir compte des réﬂexions de choc aﬁn d'obtenir de meilleures prévisions. Suite aux suggestions des travaux précédents, les équations réelles du gaz sont introduites dans le modèle analytique. Les équations retenues sont l'équation d'état de Jones-Wilkins-Lee (EOS JWL) pour les produits de détonation, et les polynômes avec les coeﬃcients de NASA Glenn pour l'air. Un algorithme est dévéloppé pour déterminer le rapport de surface critique à une pression initiale donnée, et les résultats sont similaires à celles du modèle des gaz parfaits. Toutefois, les simulations numériques eﬀectuées par un solveur Euler intégrant les EOS JWL pour les produits de détonation démontrent une amélioration dans les résultats et conﬁrment que les eﬀets réels du gaz sont importantes dans les canaux avec un petit rapport de surface.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The precursor shock wave appearing in high-explosive channel detonation can be prevented at high initial ﬁll pressures as has been previously demonstrated by experiments. However, the theoretical and numerical results from previous works have only achieved qualitative agreement. It was suggested to introduce real-gas equations into the analytical model and numerical simulation to account for the high density, pressure, and temperature nature of the problem. In this thesis, two parametric studies are performed on the ideal gas analytical model developed in previous works, and the parameters being examined are the speciﬁc heat ratio (γ) and the total pressure loss of air and detonation products. The results show that (1) the real-gas eﬀects are important in low air-to-explosive area ratio, and (2) the analytical model has to be modiﬁed to include the shock reﬂections for better predictions. Following the suggestions from previous works, real-gas equations are introduced into the analytical model. The selected equations are the Jones-Wilkins-Lee equation of state (JWL EOS) for detonation products and the polynomials with NASA Glenn coeﬃcients for speciﬁc heats in air. An algorithm is developed to determine the critical area ratio at a given initial pressure, and results are similar to the ones from previous works. However, numerical simulations performed by an Euler solver incorporating the JWL EOS for the detonation products show improvement in results and conﬁrmed the real-gas eﬀects are important for the high-explosive detonation studies in small area ratio channels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Evgeny Timofeev</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d19s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f388r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117p29p"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Perte, déchéance et enfermement. Images de la vieillesse dans le roman québécois</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grech, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Contrairement aux chercheurs américains et français, les chercheurs québécois n'ont montré qu'un intérêt mitigé pour l'étude des représentations littéraires de l'âge. Notre travail propose donc une lecture de la vieillesse mise en discours dans la fiction romanesque québécoise. En raison de l'allongement de l'espérance de vie, la sénescence est désormais compartimentée en différents stades, soit le mitan de la vie, le troisième âge et la grande vieillesse. Ainsi que le mettent en évidence les auteurs interrogés ici, chaque étape possède ses caractéristiques et ses défis. Le milieu de la vie s'envisage chez les personnages comme un passage entre la jeunesse et la vieillesse. Le sujet, confronté à son image vieillissante dans la glace, a l'impression désagréable de vivre en sursis en attendant le cataclysme de la vieillesse dont il connaît l'inéluctable. Puis, arrive ce jour terrible : il a traversé le miroir et est devenu vieux; il ne peut le nier. Si plusieurs finissent par s'y résigner, d'autres n'y parviennent pas. Tous cherchent néanmoins à se consoler de cette nouvelle réalité odieuse à tout point de vue. Enfin, la vieillesse s'aggravant jusqu'à devenir humiliante, le grand vieillard cherche à tout prix à s'en libérer. La mort, longtemps crainte, est non seulement un droit inaliénable, mais la seule libération envisageable.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Unlike researchers in the United States and France, researchers in Quebec have demonstrated little interest in examining the experience of aging as represented in literature. This thesis proposes to explore the concept of aging as depicted in Quebecois literature. With the rise in life expectancy, aging now consists of three stages, i.e., midlife, the third age and the fourth age. As demonstrated in the works of the authors examined, each stage is characterized by specific features and challenges. Midlife is seen as a transition, the passage by which one journeys from youth to age. The subject looks in the mirror and is forced to confront an image that is growing old, the confirmation that time is passing.  As such, he or she has the disturbing experience of living on borrowed time while waiting for the calamity of old age to happen, followed by the inevitable.  Then, one day terror strikes. The subject looks in the mirror, and the image reflected is noneother than that of an old man or woman. Denial is no longer possible. Though some eventually resign themselves to having grown old, others cannot accept this fate, but all look for consolation. The reality is grim, from every point of view. Over time, age takes a greater toll – it becomes a humiliating defeat. At the end, the subject must find a way out, an escape at all costs. Death, for so long feared, becomes not only a fundamental right, but the only hope for freedom.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jane Everett</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j606d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p29p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dq10t"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Birch and Swinnerton-Dyer conjecture for the Mazur-Kitagawa p-adic L-function in the presence of an exceptional zero</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gauthier-Shalom, Gabriel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Starting with the work of Mazur, Tate and Teitelbaum, various p-adic analogues of the Birch and Swinnerton-Dyer conjecture have been formulated. The case of an elliptic curve with split multiplicative reduction at the prime p is of special interest. In this so called ``exceptional zero'' case, the order of vanishing of the Mazur-Swinnerton-Dyer p-adic L-function at the central point seems to be one higher than it is in the classical case. Greenberg and Stevens proved results about this conjecture, using properties of the two variable Mazur-Kitagawa p-adic L-function L_p(E, k, s). Their proof relies on the fact that the Mazur-Kitagawa p-adic L-function L_p(E, k, s) vanishes along the central critical line s=k/2, and the fact that the restriction to k=2 is equal to the Mazur-Swinnerton-Dyer p-adic L-function attached to E. In the case where L_p(E, k, k/2) is not identically zero, a formula of Bertolini and Darmon  gives a formula for its second derivative at k=2. Their formula is also valid for twists of the L-function by quadratic characters, and their method of proof relies essentially on the fact that the twisting character is quadratic. This thesis looks into possible generalizations of the result of Bertolini and Darmon in the case of twists by Dirichlet characters of higher order.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Depuis les travaux de Mazur, Tate et Teitelbaum, diverses conjectures ont été proposées qui sont analogues à celle de Birch et Swinnerton-Dyer, dans le cas p-adique. Cette thèse traite principalement le cas d'une courbe elliptique à réduction multiplicative déployée en p; ce cas est dit ``exceptionnel''. Dans ce cas, la multiplicité de zéro de la fonction L de Mazur et Swinnerton-Dyer au point central semble être une de plus que ce qui est prédit dans le cas classique. Greenberg et Stevens ont prouvé des résultats concernant cette conjecture en utilisant la fonction L de Mazur et Kitagawa, qui est une fonction L_p(E, k, s) de deux variables. Leur preuve se base sur le fait que la fonction L de Mazur et Kitagawa s'annule sur la ligne centrale critique s=k/2 et qu'elle est égal à la fonction L de Mazur et Swinnerton-Dyer quand k=2. Quand L_p(E, k, k/2) ne s'annule pas, Bertolini et Darmon ont trouvé une formule pour la dérivée seconde de L_p(E, k, k/2) en k=2. Leur formule tient encore quand on tord par un charactère quadratique. Cette thèse considère des généralizations conjecturales des travaux de Bertolini et Darmon lorsque le caractère est d'ordre supérieur à deux.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henri Darmon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67314313.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dq10t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j8512"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Photoelectrochemical degradation of ciprofloxacin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Viger, Marie-Élise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les produits pharmaceutiques sont seulement partiellement dégradés dans les centres de traitement des eaux usées. Des antibiotiques se retrouvent donc dans les ruisseaux et rivières. Leur présence cause une résistance grandissante des bactéries aux traitements antibiotiques. Un réacteur photoélectrochimique avec une électrode RuO2-TiO2 fut construit pour déterminer s'il pouvait être utilisé pour le traitement des eaux usées contenant des antibiotiques. La ciprofloxacine fut choisie comme modèle antibiotique. Les procédés photochimique, électrochimique et photoélectrochimique peuvent tous dégrader la ciprofloxacine. Le meilleur résultat est obtenu avec la dégradation photoélectrochimique grâce à un phénomène synergétique. Par exemple pour la dégradation d'une solution de 1mM de ciprofloxacine avec un courant de 0.4A, le procédé photoélectrochimique dégrade 56% tandis que les procédés électrochimique et photochimique dégradent respectivement 41% et 3%. La dégradation photoélectrochimique s'avère donc prometteuse pour le traitement des eaux usées contenant des antibiotiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Conventional wastewater treatment plants have been found to only partially degrade pharmaceuticals. As a result, antibiotics have been detected in the aquatic environment, causing an increase in bacteria resistance. In this research a photoelectrochemical reactor with a TiO2-RuO2 working electrode was built to study its possible application for the treatment of antibiotic-containing wastewaters. Ciprofloxacin was chosen as a model antibiotic. Degradation of ciprofloxacin was carried out photocatalitically, electrochemically and photoelectrochemically. All three methods were successful in degrading the antibiotic. However, photoelectrochemical degradation was found to be significantly more efficient than the other two techniques due to a synergetic factor. For instance after one hour at a current of 0.4A for 1mM of ciprofloxacin, photoelectrochemical process degrades 56% while electrochemical and photocatalytic process only degrades 41% and 3% respectively. Overall, it was demonstrated that photoelectrochemical degradation represents possibly a viable method for the treatment of antibiotic-containing industrial wastewaters.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sasha Omanovic</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Dimitrios Berk</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn49h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j8512</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vr376"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Visioning local futures: agent-based modeling as a tourism planning support system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Johnson, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Souvent entrepris dans un environnement complexe et mal compris, le processus de planification touristique peut s'avérer difficile et exigeant. Pour solutionner les problèmes de planification, des outils technologiques sont souvent utilisés avec plus ou moins de succès. Une méthode de simulation informatique utilisée dans l'étude des systèmes sociaux humains complexes, la modélisation ABM (agent-based modeling), est de plus en plus souvent appliquée à l'exploration des problèmes de planification. Malgré cette approche prometteuse, la modélisation ABM utilisée pour représenter la dynamique du domaine touristique, ou comme aide à la planification, a été peu étudiée et rarement évaluée par les planificateurs eux-mêmes. La présente recherche vise à remédier à cette lacune en trois étapes : 1) en élaborant le concept de tourisme comme phénomène fondamentalement individuel ; 2) en formalisant ce cadre conceptuel par une modélisation ABM représentant la dynamique du tourisme en Nouvelle-Écosse, une province canadienne dont l'économie est centrée sur l'activité touristique ; 3) en fournissant, pour évaluation, cette modélisation ABM aux spécialistes de la planification touristique afin de savoir si elle pourrait permettre d'identifier les tâches de planification auxquelles elle apporterait une valeur ajoutée, de même que les contraintes individuelles, techniques et organisationnelles qui nuiraient à son adoption. Les résultats de la présente recherche indiquent que l'utilisation d'un système de soutien à la planification (SSP) fondé sur l'approche de modélisation ABM est un outil de développement de scénarios plus puissant, qui fournit un environnement permettant de poser des questions du type « que faire si », d'analyser les données et de communiquer les résultats aux membres des collectivités et aux décideurs. Malgré ces avantages, la capacité limitée des modélisateurs de développer des modèles très détaillés et validés confirme que l'approche de modélisation ABM est encore au stade de technologie émergente.  Les utilisateurs ont également fait état du manque de transparence du modèle résultant. Cette lacune est attribuable à des choix de modélisation initiaux visant à rendre le modèle  résultant plus convivial, en masquant toutefois le fonctionnement de base de la modélisation ABM aux utilisateurs. L'application de la modélisation ABM au domaine de la planification est encore récente, ce qui nuit à la confiance des planificateurs dans l'utilisation de l'approche. Ce manque de confiance permet d'illustrer l'écart qui existe entre les besoins des planificateurs et la capacité de la modélisation ABM à les satisfaire. La réduction de cet écart est une tâche qui pourrait faire l'objet d'une nouvelle collaboration entre planificateurs et modélisateurs ABM afin de miser sur les forces de la modélisation ABM identifiées dans le domaine de la planification.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Often operating within a complicated, poorly understood environment, the process of tourism planning can be a difficult and challenging task. Technological aides have often been applied to the problems of planning, with varying levels of success. One computer simulation method used to study complex human social systems, agent-based modeling (ABM), is an approach that is increasingly used as a way to explore planning-relevant problems. Despite this promise, little work has explored the use of ABM to represent tourism dynamics, or as a support for planning, as evaluated by planners themselves. This research addresses these gaps in three steps: 1) by developing the concept of tourism as a phenomenon that is fundamentally individual-based. 2) Formalizing this conceptual framework into an ABM of tourism dynamics set in the tourism-centric Canadian province of Nova Scotia. 3) Providing this ABM for evaluation by tourism planning professionals as a step to identify the specific planning tasks to which this model adds greatest value and individual, technical, and organizational constraints to adoption. The results of this research indicate that the use of an ABM-based planning support system (PSS) is strongest as a scenario development tool, providing an environment for formulating 'what if' style questions, data analysis, and a way to communicate results to community members and decision-makers. Despite these benefits, limitations to the ability of modelers to develop highly detailed and validated models emphasize the position of ABM as an emerging technology. Users also reported a lack of transparency in the model. This was attributed to design choices that were intended to make the ABM user-friendly, but also hid the functioning of the model from users. The application of ABM in planning is still a novelty, and this inhibits the confidence planners may have in using an ABM. This serves to illuminate a disconnect between the needs of the planner and what can be delivered with an ABM approach. Reducing this gap is a task that can be completed through further joint development efforts between planners and ABM modelers to more actively build on identified strengths of the ABM approach within planning.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Renee Sieber</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526c809.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vr376</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>