<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gj54t"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lost horizons : the British government and civil aviation between the wars, 1919-1939</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fitzgerald, Patrick, 1944-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the inter-war period Great Britain lost its pre-eminence in aviation. The new industries centered on civil aviation were not appropriately nurtured. The roots of this decline were in policies struck for military considerations in the pre 1914 period. The emergent institution of the war, the Air Ministry, continued the military priority. Civil Aviation was controlled by an essentially military institution. In the immediate post-war period airline development was inadequately subsidized. The government's chosen instrument, Imperial Airways, failed to nurture civil aviation development. Emergent national aspirations within the Empire and hostile and indifferent governments without frustrated airline route growth. Equally hampered by poor government stewardship was the manufacturing aspect of aviation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h410.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj54t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Great Britain -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Great Britain. Air Ministry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wm36h"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behavioural and physiological effects of two aniracetam analogues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fisher, Kim Noël</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The behavioural and electrophysiological consequences of two newly developed aniracetam analogues were investigated in male Long-Evans rats. Results indicate that an intraperitoneal (i.p.) injection of LD38.2 significantly improved retention in a two odour olfactory discrimination task. However, three different dosages of LN1 did not facilitate memory in the task. In rats with chronically implanted electrodes, both compounds rapidly crossed the blood brain barrier (BBB) after an i.p. injection and influenced several parameters of the field excitatory postsynaptic potential (EPSP) in the CA1 and dentate gyrus regions of the hippocampus. The enhancement of the field EPSP following LD38.2 administration may be related to the drug's ability to facilitate memory in the olfactory discrimination task. Compounds, like LD38.2, that enhance both hippocampal transmission and performance in learning/memory tasks in laboratory rodents may have implications for the treatment of clinical memory disorders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shapiro, Matthew</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Melzack, Ronald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q360s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm36h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Memory -- Effect of drugs on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Smell -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hippocampus (Brain)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nootropic agents -- Physiological effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sensory discrimination -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225d132"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rural weavers in Southern Bolivia : a development project case study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eversole, Robyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While most people would agree that economic development is an important goal, and understanding of exactly what "economic development" implies, and how to achieve it, are considerably more elusive. Specifically, this paper addresses the concern about whether very small-scale "grassroots-style" development projects for producers--especially petty artisans--really have the potential to make a positive impact on an ailing economy. A case study of a textile weavers' project in rural northern Chuquisaca, Bolivia, among the Jalq's (Quechua-speaking) ethnic group, is presented in detail. The local-level organizations, known as "workshops", which administer this project are analysed along with economic data from households, in order to determine both the advantages of such a project for rural women weavers, and the project's limitations. The implications of a form of organization in which local-level organizations share administrative duties with a larger support organization--in this case, the Sucre-based Antropologos del Surandino (ASUR)--are also discussed. The gains and potential gains made by weavers and their households as a result of this project are not overwhelming, yet they are valuable steps toward increased empowerment and an expansion of economic and social options for the Jalq'a.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Attwood, Donald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd94p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d132</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Quechua Indians -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bolivia -- Rural conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in rural development -- Bolivia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weavers -- Bolivia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000217k"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Islam and identity in Motinggo Busye's fiction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dussault, Edmond-Louis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis is a study of one of Motinggo Busye's numerous popular novels, Anna Soen Nio (1984). The key analytical concepts selected here are social discourse, interdiscursivity, and intertextuality. The main argument running throughout the thesis is that Anna Soen Nio is a narrative reworking of contemporaneous debates, pervasive in Indonesian society, on Indonesian identities: Muslimhood, Indonesian-ness (especially Minangkabau-ness), and Chineseness. The introduction contains an overview of the sociocritical approach as well as a preliminary discussion on Indonesian social discourse. Chapter 1 discusses the contemporary position of the Sino-Indonesians as a minority group with a complex status. Chapter 2 presents an overview of Motinggo Busye's life and works as well as an analysis of paratextual elements related to Anna Soen Nio. Chapter 3 is a narratological analysis of M. Busye's novel. Chapters 4 and 5 are closely related: they both focus on the novel's ideological discourse on Indonesian identities. In chapter 4, this is done at the level of the novel's personal onomastics (characters' names). Chapter 5 uses another sociocritical tool, the sociogram, in order to decipher the "image of the Chinese" in Anna Soen Nio and stress its interdiscursive and intertextual character. In the conclusion, Lotman's concept of the hero is used to show that the novel's hero is not its eponymous character. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, Uner A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz64j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000217k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islam in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Busye, Motinggo, 1936-</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537314r"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors which influence employee participation in training and development : a study of clerical staff at McGill University</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dressler, Jacqueline Faith</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the participation of clerical staff in training and development. It also considers the potential benefits of participation and the influence of forces in the work environment on participation. A survey of the population of 937 clerical staff at McGill University yielded a response of 460. Three-quarters of staff indicated awareness of training and development opportunities, with approximately half of these having participated in 1993/1994. Staff consider performance enhancement as by far the most likely benefit of participation. They are also inclined to agree that their supervisors are supportive of training and development, while they tend to be unsure whether they have their co-workers' support. Further, staff tend to be unsure or to disagree that situational constraints influence participation. Significant interactions between several of the variables were found. This study discusses the implications of these findings for McGill and makes recommendations for further research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anderson, Gary</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h32j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537314r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Clerks -- Training of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Employees -- Training of -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b097x"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hildegard of Bingen as an educator : the body as conduit to knowledge</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doran, Geraldine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates how Hildegard of Bingen (1098-1179), a medieval abbess used visions received during the prodromal stages of migraines to reconstruct herself symbolically. In her visions she believed that God, the "Living Light" instructed her "to write and say the Secrete Dei". By obeying, she obtained extensive influence and power, appropriating functions reserved for the medieval male elite only. Hildegard is contextualized within the politico-socio-intellectual parameters of the twelfth century in general and within convent life in particular. Events are chronicled to examine how she reconstructed her weaknesses--gender and infirmity--using them to construct knowledge, and to demonstrate how she used that knowledge to educate by writing, teaching and preaching. The source of Hildegard's knowledge is analysed in an attempt to determine whether it is divinely inspired, neurologically based, or derived from secondary religious and secular writings. Whatever the source, Hildegard herself refused to grant the name of "Knowledge" to any insight unless it came to her in the heavenly voice via the "Living Light." The study culminates with a brief discussion on the questions asked in the introduction regarding research in the history of education.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gillett, Margaret</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2364176.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b097x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hildegard, Saint, 1098-1179</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jb043"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sentencing sexual assault : a study of mitigation and aggravation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dinovitzer, Ronit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In an effort to establish a clearer understanding of the sentencing of sexual assault offenders, this study analyzes data generated from a content analysis of sexual assault cases, using feminist theory as a backdrop for the analysis. The sample consists of ninety-seven sexual assault cases from across Canada for the period of August 15, 1992 through August 15, 1993. Using a statistical analysis, the data were analyzed for evidence of whether certain factors aggravated or mitigated sentence length. The findings indicate that factors not affecting sentence length include breach of trust, sex of the judge, sex of the complainant, plea and show of remorse. Factors that work to mitigate sentence length include the youth or old age of an offender. Finally, variables that, when present, aggravate an offender's sentence length are prior offences, force, sexual intercourse and psychiatric considerations. These findings indicate that while there has been some response to feminist concerns regarding criminal justice processing of sexual assault, some of the myths that have been traditionally associated with its victims and offenders are still influencing the judiciary.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Benaquisto, Lucia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk292.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb043</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Indecent assault -- Law and legislation -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rape -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex crimes -- Law and legislation -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sentences (Criminal procedure) -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gz23n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of private education legislation in the province of Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dikranian, Harry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the unique aspects of education in Quebec is a strong private sector. It is well rooted in the province's history and tradition. This study offers a preliminary examination into the historical development of policies in the area of private education in Quebec. The first two pieces of legislation governing private schools provided subsidies of 100% at par with the public sector. These early laws were repealed and replaced by the Act respecting Private Education. In August 1991, the government proposed a new and comprehensive piece of legislation. Following the first reading of this Bill a parliamentary commission was established to study the proposed law. Over 15 groups expressed their reactions in briefs to this commission. The Bill was harshly criticized by those opposed to public funding of private schools. It was also criticized by those in favor of the private sector. Given the negative reactions from groups opposed and groups in favor, government ministers decided that the Bill must be changed. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Isherwood, Geoff</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p44x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz23n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Private schools -- Law and legislation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw9505250h"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Classics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The contract of mandatum and the notion of amicitia in the Roman Republic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deere, Andrew G. (Andrew Graham)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The contract of mandatum in Roman law, unlike its namesake in modern civil law legal systems, was not a contract of representation or agency. It was a contract of gratuitous performance of services for others. According to Corpus luris Civilis it was a contract which drew its origin from the duties of friendship. This paper examines certain rules of mandatum and compares them with a similar legal institution known as procuratio and concludes that friendship must indeed have been the origin of the contract. The paper then examines various aspects of friendship in Roman society, and concludes that social custom cannot have been the sole basis for the creation of the contract. The philosophical and ethical views of Cicero and Seneca are then considered. From the works of these two authors two lines of thought regarding friendship are deduced: friendships are to be entered into for their own sake, or friendships are to be entered into for the benefits that will ensue. The former is the 'noble' view of friendship, the latter the 'utilitarian'. The author concludes after a reexamination of the rules of mandatum that the 'noble' view provides a better answer to the question of why mandatum was created by the Roman jurists.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Silverthorne, Michael J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z028.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505250h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Contracts -- Rome</dc:subject><dc:subject>Friendship -- Rome</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rome -- Social life and customs</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623f70q"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A Canadian study of admissible monetary asset groupings using nonparametric demand analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cunningham, James K. (James Kenneth)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Structural change and innovation in the market for financial services in recent years have drawn attention to the fact that traditional definitions of money as included in demand for money models and monetary aggregation measures may be misspecified. It is unclear whether or to what extent broader measures of money should be used as targets in monetary policy or as indicators of changes in the real economy. This thesis is a nonparametric empirical test of monetary asset, leisure and consumption good data which seeks to examine whether the underlying structure of preferences implied by monetary aggregation can be said to be justified. Using recent software routines, we test Canadian data for the years 1968-I to 1989-IV in order to determine whether it meets the criteria for utility maximization and for a structure of preferences represented by weak separability. We find that only a narrow grouping of monetary assets meets these requirements. Further, we conclude that many other studies in the literature which have merely assumed weak separability have been misspecified.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Handa, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n3250.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f70q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Assets (Accounting) -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bh18q"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the relationship between Paul Cézanne and Paul Gauguin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cobill, Brenda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis provides a critical analysis of the literature concerning the relationship, both artistic and personal, between Paul Cezanne and Paul Gauguin. It proceeds from the popular belief that Cezanne harbored an excessive amount of ill will towards Gauguin. Examination of the sources upon which this belief is based prove them to be controversial and conflicting, yet the myth of Cezanne's animosity towards Gauguin is still widely accepted, effectively obscuring the more positive, creative aspect of their interaction. In the assessment of this relationship, Camille Pissarro emerges as a pivotal figure because of his close ties to both artists. It will be shown that Gauguin found in Cezanne's art concepts which were germane to his own artistic practices and theoretical directions. The later Symbolist interpretation of Cezanne reflects the dissemination of Gauguin's teachings about the artist and reveals that, in some measure, Gauguin was responsible for the critical acclaim Cezanne was to receive in his final years.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kiefer, Carol Solomon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd79g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh18q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gauguin, Paul, 1848-1903 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cézanne, Paul, 1839-1906 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75df65t"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Author--Ulysses--readers : seduction in the gaps</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Clissold, Bradley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate how the prose style of James Joyce's Ulysses provides seductive gaps which by design prompt readers to become co-producers of the text. Joyce strategically creates opportunities for readers to engage actively with the text through response-inviting gaps in the prose. The various types of gaps in the text place demands on readers and, inevitably, upon the author. The more reader-friendly gaps are overdetermined gaps which, by definition, are obvious and point to their own completion. These gaps when filled are, more often than not, confirmed by related references throughout the text. Ulysses, however, also abounds with gaps of indeterminacy. The ambiguous nature of these gaps generates anxiety for readers by undermining the expectations established by overdetermined gaps. Joyce's prose arrangements continually call on readers to play roles and adapt these roles to the linguistic movements of the text. This project endeavours to analyse how different gaps function and the degree to which they work in conjunction to seduce readers and the author into the dual roles of co-production and co-consumption of Ulysses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wees, W. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t564.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df65t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Joyce, James, 1882-1941. Ulysses</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sc355"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children's causal attributions for performance in creative dance and folk dance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cholod, Kirsten L. (Kirsten Lynn)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated children's attributions for their performance in creative dance and folk dance. Eighty-six grade 5 and 6 children from a suburban elementary school participated in five creative dance and five folk dance lessons as part of their regular physical education program. After participation in each dance type, children completed a questionnaire which assessed their perceived success and attributions for their performance. After rating their perceived success in creative/folk dance, children gave an open-ended attributional statement for their performance, and then scored their statement along the four causal dimensions (personal control, locus of causality, stability, external control) (Weiss, McAuley, Ebbeck, &amp; Wiese, 1990). Thirteen dance lessons were videotaped and the teacher's behavior was analysed. Results showed that children in both creative and folk dance tended to: (a) perceive their performance as successful, and (b) make functional attributions by attributing their performance to factors which they perceived as being personally controllable, internal, and not under the control of other people. Results indicated no significant effects of dance type or gender for perceived success and the four causal dimensions. However, two significant effects were found for grade, as the grade 5's perceived their performance to be more successful than the grade 6's, and also attributed their performance to factors that were less under the control of other people. Results from children's open-ended attributional statements and the observational recordings of the teacher's behavior supported the notion that creative dance and folk dance are two distinct forms of dance. The overall results appear to have positive implications with respect to the influence of creative dance and folk dance on the motivation of children. The findings therefore support the inclusion of dance in elementary physical education programs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Downey, Peggy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569646j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc355</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Folk dancing -- Study and teaching (Elementary)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Movement education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dance -- Study and teaching (Elementary)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526f38q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vérité, véracité, sincérité : "fait divers" et nouvelle chez Vigneulles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chisogne, Sophie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The inherent contradiction that lies in the systematic use of the claim to veracity in narratives built on traditional, widely used motifs and themes is the starting point of this thesis. Through a comparison of Philippe de Vigneulles' (1471-1525) Chronique and his collection of short stories the Cent Nouvelles nouvelles, this study analyses the link between the nouvelles and their historical background. Analysis of those texts whose basic structure is founded on the commission of an infraction, indicates on the one hand that the author's didactic intention, apparently of minor importance and subordinate to the comic of the tales, is in fact essential, functioning as the moral and organisational principle of these tales, and reflecting the writer's values. It shows on the other hand, that the relation between the "fait divers" and the nouvelle is not one of filiation: they are rather "twin" narrative forms or, to use the terminology of Andre Jolles in Einfachen Formen, the second is a "Relative Form" of the first.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stefano, Giuseppe Di</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236418g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526f38q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vigneulles, Philippe de, 1471-1528. Cent nouvelles nouvelles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vigneulles, Philippe de, 1471-1528. Chronique</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vq571"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fragments ; suivi de Brèves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chicoine, Dominique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis on literary writing consists of a critic and of a fiction. The critic entitled Fragments, attempts to bring out the characteristics of fragmentary writing. The theoretic analysis concerns the generic problematic of such writing and its effects on lecture. The last part of the text is devoted to the social context in which the fragmentary writing takes place. The creation Breves contents fourteen short stories. Representing different generations, the characters of Breves are seized in a particular moment of thier lives. Most of the characters are part of a couple; nevertheless, they cannot get away from loneliness.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn564.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq571</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Short stories</dc:subject><dc:subject>Unfinished books</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322g41w"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La formation de la main-d'oeuvre dans le système d'éducation québécois</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chevrier, Chantal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The economy of Quebec suffered for many years of persistent unemployment and skilled labour shortages that the market could not eliminate, neither government intervention as the number of youths enrolled in vocational programs at high school and college dropped of 50% in one decade. Could we adjust vocational training so that it responds efficiently and usefully to the needs for skilled labour? This can hardly be achieved as the role of the educational system in that respect is not well defined, programming is inadequate, training for youths is not a priority, and its resources are as scarce as the information available to evaluate its profitability or to choose the most efficient set of programs. To attain this conclusion, we reviewed surveys on training in firms to estimate if it takes advantage of all available social benefits. Their results did not allow such finding but revealed that Quebec firms train less than elsewhere in Canada, that training is the prerogative of firms experiencing hiring problems and targets mainly a skilled, educated and well paid labour force. Therefore, the intervention of the government lies within a distribution of responsibilities where vocational training supplies skilled labour to which those firms with more specific needs will add complementary skills. Years ago, the vocational training system was well fulfilling this task as training institutions were one source of skilled labour favoured by Quebec firms. This has since changed. Our original analysis of the efficiency of vocational programs confirmed their inadequacy to the needs, especially at high school level, as most skills taught target occupations affected by chronic labour surpluses. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Soderstrom, Lee</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b518.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g41w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Occupational training -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qp14z"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>heb</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Jewish Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Medieval and modern halakhic attitudes on the applicability of Biblical rabbinic law concerning the Seven Nations and the ancient pagans to contemporary non-Jews : a study in Halakhah, exegesis and history</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Charlap, Yaakov</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on two issues among the many comprising the broad subject of the relationship between Jews and non-Jews according to Jewish law. The issues are: (1) the prohibition against selling real estate in the land of Israel to non-Jews; and (2) the prohibition against intermarriage. The prohibition against selling real estate in the land of Israel to non-Jews is based upon a Rabbinic interpretation of the phrase "lo Tehanem" from Deut. 7:2. In the period of the "Rishonim" (from Maimonides till Radbaz) the general view was that this prohibition was still in force and applied to contemporary non-Jews. From the beginning of the modern era, however, this prohibition, as a result of the new reality facing the struggling Jewish settlement in the land of Israel, became problematic. The prohibition against intermarriage underwent a reverse development. During the Talmudic period most of the Rabbis, guided by the context of the Biblical text, argued that the Biblical prohibition only concerned the "Seven Nations" who used to live in Canaan at the time of the conquest and the settlement. But at the beginning of the modern era a rabbinic consensus gradually emerged that this Biblical prohibition related not only to the "Seven Nations" or "Ancient Pagans", but to all non-Jews at all times. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kaplan, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p6844.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp14z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Real property (Jewish law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jewish law -- Interpretation and construction -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Judaism -- Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Palestine in Judaism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interfaith marriage (Jewish law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526f390"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L' exil romanesque ; suivi de La Sainte-Victoire</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carreira, Joaquim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This master's thesis in creative writing is composed of two parts: a critical study and a journal. The critical study, L'Exil romanesque, attempts to define and illustrate the nature of exile. More precisely, it analyses exile as a theme and structure of the novel, as studied in essays and greatly developed by works of fiction. The creative work, entitled La Sainte-Victoire, delineates the sojourn in Aix-en-Provence of a portuguese student born in Angola. This experience, marked by loneliness and failure, gradually reveals to him what drives him apart from himself.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, M. Yvon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q59f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526f390</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Exiles in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k931c"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ordinateur et applications créatives en musique : étude de deux approches basées sur le logiciel Tuneblocks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bureau, Louis, 1961-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to explore the compositional processes of nine-year-old children using a microprocessor computer. Ten children were divided in two groups and were asked to compose a melody by arranging musical blocks. Children in the first group were given pre-composed blocks of Mozart's piano sonatas. Children in the second group were asked to compose their own blocks. Bamberger's computer program, Tuneblocks, was adapted for a use on a Macintosh microcomputer with French-speaking children. Results revealed that type of task does not affect the process-product orientation adopted by children. Pedagogical implications explore the findings in terms of practical applications of both approaches.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stubley, Eleanor</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pennycook, Bruce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp85k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k931c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer composition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1831cn014"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The danger of Nietzsche : a look at Nietzsche's view of Kant in Twilight of the idols</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bryan, Bradley W. (Bradley William)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The author argues that Nietzsche's discussion of Kant in Twilight of the Idols illuminates a very troubling tension at the heart of political philosophy. By looking at two sections, the author shows the way in which Nietzsche understands Kantian philosophy as an outcome of a historical movement he refers to as the "devaluation of values". Nietzsche's claim is that Kantian critique, rather than establish grounds, ultimately exposes the lack of ground truth and value have in objective reality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Booth, William J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z9864.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cn014</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kant, Immanuel, 1724-1804</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1844-1900</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pq17d"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sens et non-sens dans le théâtre de Réjean Ducharme</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boudreault, Lolita</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis attempts a study of the published plays of Rejean Ducharme. Apart from the fact that they have both been published, Ines Peree Inat Tendu et HA!ha!... form a coherent whole because of their shared place in the history of contemporary Quebec theatre. Associated from the beginning with the claims made by the "New Quebec Theatre", Ducharme's plays are now part of the repertory. The first chapter examines the textual forces that allow one to trace the narrative structure in Ducharme's dramatic writing. It also describes the different actantial models as well as the mechanisms that regulate their function. In the second chapter, an analysis of the characters adds a layer of significance to the analysis of the actants and reveals to us the "small world" of Ducharme's plays. The actants take shape, becoming characters who establish ties among themselves. The third chapter describes the universe in which these "unusual" characters evolve. Space and time throw referential precariousness into relief which in turn, gives a sense of meaning and non-meaning to different objects as well as to the logic of events. Finally, the fourth chapter deals with the discursive process and, more particularly, with the initiations that stem from the dialogues. With the advent of theatrical communication, the spectator or the narratee is also initiated into Ducharme's theatre where he or she re-assumes his or her place. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Terrasse, Jean</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm54p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq17d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ducharme, Réjean -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jw70t"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"Mitteilungen für die Truppe' : ideology in publication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Borys, Bill</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A vast amount of literature has been published about Germany's campaign in Russia during the Second World War. New attention has been focused on the role played by indoctrination in the conduct of the ideological war. This thesis examines the thematic content of the German Armed Forces circular Mitteilungen fur die Truppe for a period that coincides with the climactic confrontation on the Eastern Front. It illustrates the presence of a coherent propaganda policy designed to boost troop resilience. The data have been derived from copies of the primary source, namely part of the captured German records microfilmed at Alexandria, Virginia. The evidence is augmented through other primary and secondary sources.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoffman, P. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq689.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw70t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Propaganda</dc:subject><dc:subject>Propaganda, German</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b0986"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An analysis of communications between opponents to Hitler in Germany and the British Government during the "Phoney War" (September 1939-May 1940)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Booth, Donald, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is the objective of this thesis to examine contacts between the British government and German opponents to Hitler during the "Phoney War" (September 1939-May 1940). Throughout this nine month period opponents to Nazism within Germany sought both material and moral support from the British government for an overthrow of the National Socialist regime. This work analyzes the channels through which communication between the German opposition and the British government were established and the nature of the discussions which took place. The work also examines the British reaction to the German overtures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoffman, P. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765373151.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b0986</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anti-Nazi movement -- Germany</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Diplomatic history</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mp413"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>See who created these : a study of the description of Yahweh's creative activity in Isaiah 40-55</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Black, Fiona</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to examine the descriptions of Yahweh's creative activity in Deutero-Isaiah (Isaiah 40-55). In the last century, biblical scholarship on creation has been concerned primarily with its relationship to redemption. This thesis will study the descriptions independently of redemption. The references to creation incorporate a broad spectrum of material which is presented randomly throughout Deutero-Isaiah. Because of their diversity, the references will be organized into three groups: Yahweh's initial creation (cosmogony), his creation of the people, and his new creation (his present or upcoming creative activity). Discussion will begin with the cosmogonic material, since it is the most obvious of the groups in terms of its language and similarities to other biblical material. The other aspects of Yahweh's creative activity will then be studied in accordance with their lexical relationship to the cosmogonic texts. This thesis will investigate what is said specifically about creation, how the creation language functions (i.e., how the message/meaning is effected), and what purpose it serves (i.e., why creation is mentioned). Special attention will be paid to the lexical material in the descriptions, notably the verbs. References will be examined in their immediate context (poem, etc.) and in their Deutero-Isaian context. Where relevant, other texts in Isaiah (Isa 1-66) or the rest of the Hebrew Bible will be used in the expectation that they will provide added insight into the meaning of the references.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Culley, R. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m22j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp413</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Creation -- Biblical teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10ws44d"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A vision of imagery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bell, S. Caroline (Sarah Caroline)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following work provides a psychoanalytic exploration of the contribution of images to the psychological development of children, and their consequent impact on adult communication with both the self and the other. To begin, Jean Piaget's stage theory regarding the cognitive and perceptual development of infants is studied. Its consideration and critique allow me to establish the tenets which I wish to guide my work. For instance, while Piaget proposed the importance of sight in the development of children, he did not effectively distinguish vision, and its product visual imagery, from the conceptual framework of the written and spoken word. Thus, much like classical sociologists more generally, he was unable to assess imagery as a distinct form of communication and as a result subjected its character, role, and importance to misinterpretation. Its strong connection to the unconscious was at once underestimated and used as a means to undermine the intellectual complexity and significance of imagery. To further highlight the importance of visual imagery in the life of both child and adult in chapter 3 I examine the dominant manners in which imagery, primarily through the unconscious, influences and stabilizes our psyche. I have distinguished three forms of psychic activity through visual imagery; (1) simple fantasy, (2) complex fantasy, and (3) dreams. These processes are used at different times and for different reasons as demanded by the need to maintain a healthy balance within the id and the ego, between the two, and with others in one's social sphere. Sigmund Freud, Carl Jung, D. W. Winnicott and Charles Rycroft are among those theorists used to develop these thoughts. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levin, Charles</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq98j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws44d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Imagery (Psychology) in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>