<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n6641"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Respiration rate in transient period, its implication on the effect of hyperbaric pressure treatment; the treatment advantage in shelf life extension of various commodities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liplap, Pansa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les pertes postrécoltes de fruits et légumes frais peuvent être considérables s'ils ne sont pas manipulés convenablement. Le traitement physique hyperbare (TH) a l'avantage, contrairement aux autres traitements, d'être uniforme et indépendant de la taille et de la forme du produit. La réponse des fruits et légumes à ce type de traitement a cependant été peu étudiée. Le taux de respiration (TR) est suggéré comme indicateur de l'efficacité du TH. Par contre, le taux réel de respiration durant la période de transitoire du TH avant d'atteindre l'équilibre est inconnu dû aux effets de dilution et de solubilisation des gaz. Les principaux objectifs de cette étude étaient : 1) étudier le potentiel du TH sur la prolongation de la durée de vie tablette et le maintien de la qualité de différents types de fruits et légumes considérant les aspects physiologique, biochimique et microbiologique; 2) développer une méthode de mesure du TR des divers types de produits horticoles durant la période de transitoire du traitement. Des essaies ont été réalisées en utilisant des pressions entre 100 kPa et 900 kPa sur le maïs sucré, l'avocat, la laitue et la tomate à la température de 20 °C. Les résultats ont montré que le TH réduisait le TR de façons différentes selon le type de produit; soit de manière plus importante pour le maïs sucré et l'avocat, mais peu pour la laitue feuille et la tomate lorsque comparé à l'entreposage à température ambiante et à pression normale (20 °C, 100 kPa). Toutefois, la réduction de la perte de poids a toujours été présente peu importe le produit traité. La couleur, surtout le vert, change moins que le témoin peu importe le produit traité. Le TH à température ambiante a réduit la perte de fermeté de l'avocat, la tomate et la laitue. Le goût des produits traités sous pression a été maintenu. En général, le TH préserve la qualité des produits horticoles durant le traitement, prolongeant leur durée de vie sans effets néfastes sur leur goût et leur apparence. Les effets du TH sur les composés biochimiques (antioxydants) et leur activité antioxydante ont été étudiés avec la tomate. Le TH a influencé considérablement le contenu en lycopène d'abord en limitant, puis en stimulant son accumulation durant le traitement et l'entreposage, respectivement. Les contenus en acide ascorbique, en phénols totaux, en antioxydants lipophiles (LAA) et hydrophiles (HAA) n'étaient pas affectés par le TH. Une expérience sur la croissance de bactéries pathogènes a été réalisée pour déterminer la présence d'effet du TH sur leur développement. Le TH réalisé à température ambiante a réduit considérablement la croissance de bactéries causant la pourriture molle. Ceci pourrait expliquer la réduction de pourriture chez les produits horticoles traités sous pression. Le taux de respiration métabolique réel (RRm) en période transitoire a été évalué en considérant la dilution du gaz durant le période de mise en régime du système et la solubilisation de CO2 dans la chair du produit basée sur un bilan de masse du CO2. Le RRm en période de transition a été estimé en incorporant le RR initial du produit non traité avec le RR à l'équilibre du produit traité. La dynamique du RRm en période de transition a suivi la forme d'une équation exponentielle négative. La valeur de la constante (k) du modèle de RRm a diminué exponentiellement lorsque la pression partielle du CO2 a atteint l'équilibre. La méthode développée devrait être validée sur d'autres produits pour déterminer la valeur du RRm durant la période transitoire située au début d'un traitement hyperbare.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Postharvest losses of fresh fruit and vegetables are considerable if they are not properly handled. Hyperbaric pressure treatment is a physical treatment that has the advantages over other treatments in terms of treatment uniformity on the item and independent of its size and shape. Nevertheless, the response of fruit and vegetables to this technique has been little explored. Respiration rate (RR) has been previously proposed as an indicator to reveal the importance of hyperbaric pressure treatment. However, the real RR measured during the transient period of hyperbaric pressure treatment has been unknown because of the effect of dilution and the gas solubilisation. The main purposes of this study were: 1) to study the potential of hyperbaric pressure treatment (pressure levels ranging from 100 kPa to 900 kPa) to extend shelf life and maintain quality of different types of fruit and vegetables (i.e. sweet corn, avocado, lettuce and tomato) at room temperature (20 °C); and 2) to develop a method for measuring the RR of horticultural produce during the transient period. Hyperbaric pressure treatment generally reduced RR of the tested produce but the magnitudes are dependent on their type. Compared with storage at room conditions (100 kPa, 20 °C), hyperbaric pressure treatment reduced RR greatly in the case of sweet corn and avocado but the reduction was slight for lettuce and tomato. The reduced weight loss was a consistent effect of hyperbaric pressure treatment. The color, especially green, was found to change less for all types of produce. Hyperbaric pressure treatment at room temperature attenuated firmness loss of avocado, tomato and lettuce. The tastes of pressure-treated produce were maintained or not affected by post hyperbaric pressure treatment. Overall, hyperbaric pressure treatment preserved quality attributes of horticultural produce during treatment, resulting in shelf life extension and did not have any adverse effect on taste or appearance during storage or shelf holding periods.The effect of hyperbaric pressure treatment on biochemical compounds (antioxidants) and their antioxidant activities was studied using tomato. Hyperbaric treatment significantly affected lycopene content by inhibiting then enhancing its accumulation during treatment and ripening, respectively. Ascorbic acid and total phenolic contents, lipophilic antioxidant (LAA) and hydrophilic antioxidant (HAA) were not affected by hyperbaric pressure treatment. An experiment on the bacterial growth was conducted to investigate whether hyperbaric pressure treatment had direct impact on the behaviour of decay-causing bacteria or not. Results showed that hyperbaric pressure treatment at room temperature greatly reduced the growth behaviour of bacteria that cause soft rot in fruit and vegetables. This may in part explain the decay reduction of horticultural produce when treated with hyperbaric treatment.The real metabolic RRm in transient period was evaluated by considering gas dilution due to flushing system and solubilisation of CO2 in the flesh of the produce based on mass balance of CO2 in the system. The RRm in transient period was estimated by incorporating the initial RR of untreated fruits with the RR at equilibrium. The kinetics of RRm in transient period followed a negative exponential equation. The constant value (k) of the RRm model in transient period was found to decrease exponentially with the partial pressure of CO2 at equilibrium. It implicates the amount of gas solubilised and the time to reach equilibrium. The developed method should be validated with other produce for the determination of RRm during the transient period at the beginning of a hyperbaric treatment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clement Vigneault</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>G. S. Vijaya Raghavan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m53w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n6641</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Horticulture</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246w30t"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Antimicrobial peptide resistance mechanisms used by Enteropathogenic and Enterohemorrhagic «Escherichia coli»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thomassin, Jenny-Lee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les Escherichia coli entéropathogènes et entérohémorrhagiques (EPEC et EHEC) sont des bactéries à coloration Gram-négative qui causent des diarrhées dans les pays développés et en développement. Pour causer une infection, ces pathogènes doivent surmonter les défenses de l'immunité innée de l'hôte, tel que les peptides antimicrobiens sécrétés (PAMs). Chez l'humain, les PAMs sont divisés en deux groupes, les cathélicidines (ex. LL-37) et les défensines (ex. α-défensine humaine 5). L'expression des PAMs varie selon les tissus. Dans l'intestin grêle, la niche infectieuse des EPEC, les α-défensines humaines 5 et 6 (HD-5 et HD-6) sont abondantes et le niveau de LL-37 est bas. Inversement, HD-5 et HD-6 ne sont pas exprimées dans le côlon, la niche infectieuse des EHEC, et LL-37 est très abondant. Les pathogènes peuvent résister aux PAMs en utilisant différent mécanismes comme l'inactivation protéolytique, la production de structures recouvrant la cellule bactérienne et la modification du lipopolysaccharide (LPS). Notre hypothèse est que les EPEC et EHEC utilisent des mécanismes de résistance aux PAMs pour établir une infection. Précédemment, il a été démontré que la protéase de type omptin, CroP, de Citrobacter rodentium, un pathogène murin utilisé comme modèle pour les infections des EPEC et EHEC, dégrade la cathélicidine murine. Les EPEC et EHEC possèdent un homologue de CroP, OmpT. La contribution de OmpT à la résistance au LL-37 a été examinée chez ces deux pathogènes. Nos tests de clivage de peptide ont démontré que EHEC OmpT clive et inactive LL-37 plus rapidement que EPEC OmpT. La différence observée a été associée à une plus forte expression et production de OmpT chez les EHEC que chez les EPEC. Des tests supplémentaires ont démontré que OmpT ne peut pas cliver les α-défensines repliées. Ces données suggèrent qu'EPEC utilise d'autres mécanismes de résistance pour surmonter l'activité des PAMs présents dans sa niche infectieuse. Pour tester cette possibilité, les structures recouvrant la cellule ont été identifiées. Un haut niveau de transcription de gfcA, un gène requit pour la sécrétion de la capsule du groupe 4 (G4C), a été observé chez EPEC mais pas chez EHEC. Le mutant EPEC non-encapsulé ΔgfcA et la souche sauvage EHEC sont plus susceptible à l'effet du HD-5 que la souche sauvage EPEC. Étant donné que la G4C est composée des mêmes sucres que l'antigène O, la ligase de l'antigène O, waaL, a été délétée pour déterminer le rôle de l'antigène O dans la résistance au HD-5. La souche EPEC ΔwaaL est plus susceptible au HD-5 que la souche sauvage EPEC et le mutant EPEC ΔgfcA. L'addition de polysaccharide exogène augmente la survie du mutant ΔwaaLΔgfcA en présence de HD-5. Ceci indique que HD-5 se lie aux polysaccharides présents à la surface des EPEC. Ces données démontrent que la résistance à HD-5 chez EPEC repose sur la présence de la G4C et de l'antigène O. Toutes ces données indiquent que EHEC et EPEC utilisent des mécanismes de résistance  différents aux PAMs, ce qui démontre une adaptation à leurs niches infectieuses respectives.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Enteropathogenic and enterohemorrhagic Escherichia coli (EPEC and EHEC) are Gram-negative pathogens that cause diarrheal disease in the developed and developing world. To cause infection, these pathogens must overcome innate host defenses, such as secreted cationic antimicrobial peptides (AMPs). There are two groups of human AMPs: cathelicidins (LL-37) and defensins (α-defensin 5). AMPs are expressed in specific locations of the human body. In the small intestine, the infectious niche for EPEC, human α-defensins 5 and 6 (HD-5 and HD-6) are abundant and there are low levels of LL-37. Conversely in the colon, the infectious niche for EHEC, HD-5 and HD-6 are not expressed and LL-37 is abundant. Pathogens can overcome AMP-killing using several mechanisms, including proteolytic inactivation, producing shielding structures and modifying their lipopolysaccharide (LPS). We hypothesized that EPEC and EHEC use AMP-resistance mechanisms to resist killing by secreted AMPs during infection. Previously, CroP the omptin protease in Citrobacter rodentium, a murine pathogen used to model EPEC and EHEC infections, was shown to degrade murine cathelicidin. Both EPEC and EHEC have a CroP-homologue: OmpT. The contribution of OmpT to LL-37 resistance was analyzed in both pathogens. Peptide cleavage assays showed that EHEC OmpT cleaves and inactivates LL-37 more rapidly than EPEC OmpT. Higher ompT-expression and protein levels in EHEC than EPEC are responsible for the differences observed in LL-37 inactivation rates. Additional studies showed that OmpT was unable to cleave folded α-defensins. These data suggest that EPEC uses other mechanisms to resist killing by the AMPs in its infectious niche. To assess this possibility, surface structures that may shield the bacterial membrane from AMPs were identified. High transcript levels of gfcA, a gene required for group 4 capsule (G4C) secretion, were observed in EPEC but not EHEC. The unencapsulated EPEC ΔgfcA and EHEC wild-type strains were more susceptible to HD-5 killing than EPEC wild-type. Since the G4C is composed of the same sugar repeats as the LPS O-antigen, an O-antigen ligase (waaL) deletion mutant was generated to assess the role of the O-antigen in HD-5 resistance. The EPEC ΔwaaL strain was more susceptible to HD-5 than both the wild-type and ΔgfcA strains. Addition of exogenous polysaccharide increased survival of the ΔgfcAΔwaaL strain in the presence of HD-5, suggesting that HD-5 binds the polysaccharides present on the surface of EPEC. These data show that EPEC relies on both the G4C and O-antigen to resist the bactericidal activity of HD-5. Altogether, these data indicate that EHEC and EPEC differentially regulate AMP-specific resistance mechanisms as an adaptation to their specific infectious niches. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Samantha Gruenheid</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Herve Le-Moual</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128f29x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246w30t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s8159"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of prolonged mechanical ventilation on sepsis-induced diaphragm dysfunction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stamiris, Angela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Severe sepsis is a systemic inflammatory response to an infection that often leads to respiratory failure which requires patients to be mechanically ventilated. Mechanical ventilation (MV) also leads to atrophy and weakness what is termed ventilatory induced diaphragm dysfunction (VIDD).  Both these conditions are associated with upregulation of proteolytic pathways such as the ubiquitin proteasome pathway and the autophagy-lysosomal pathway. However, the influence of combining MV on sepsis-induced diaphragm dysfunction remains unknown. In this study, we evaluate the influence of prolonged MV on sepsis-induced diaphragm dysfunction. We studied four groups of rats. Group 1 animals were spontaneously breathing and served as controls. Group 2 (LPS) animals received intraperitoneal injection of E. coli lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and served as the sepsis group. Group 3 animals were mechanically ventilated for 12h. Group 4 animals received LPS injection first and were then mechanically ventilated for 12h.  Diaphragm contractility was measured in-vitro and diaphragm fiber type atrophy was evaluated by measuring fiber cross sectional areas. Activation of the proteasome, calpains, caspase-3 and autophagy proteolytic pathways were evaluated using specific assays. Injection of LPS and MV for 12 resulted in significant attenuation of diaphragm contractility and the development of fiber atrophy.  Combining MV with LPS administration resulted in additional decline in muscle contractile performance but not additional atrophy. Proteasome, calpain, caspase-3 and the autophagy proteolytic pathways were activated in the LPS and MV groups and the combination of prolonged MV with sepsis resulted in the potentiation of autophagy pathway but not proteasome, calpain and capase-3 activation. The AKT and mTORC1 pathways (inhibitors of proteolytic pathways and activators of protein synthesis) were activated in response to LPS administration but not by prolonged MV. Combining sepsis with prolonged MV resulted in attenuation of AKT and mTORC1 activation compared to sepsis alone. Interestingly, the AMPK pathway (activator of autophagy) is inhibited in response to LPS administration and prolonged MV. Combining sepsis with prolonged MV resulted in a milder degree of AMPK inhibition compared to LPS administration alone. Finally, oxidative stress develops in response to LPS administration and prolonged MV. Combining MV and sepsis resulted in worsening of oxidative stress. These results indicate that prolonged MV worsens sepsis-induced diaphragm contractile dysfunction and this worsening of function may be mediated by substantial induction of autophagy and the development of severe oxidative stress. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le sepsis sévère est une réponse inflammatoire systémique consécutive à une infection, pouvant conduire à la détresse respiratoire nécessitant le recours à la ventilation mécanique. La ventilation mécanique (MV) est responsable de l'atrophie et de la faiblesse du  diaphragme connue sous le nom de dysfonction diaphragmatique induite par la ventilation (DDIV). Ces deux mécanismes étiopathogéniques sont associés à l'activation de plusieurs voies protéolytiques comme la voie du protéasome et la voie de l'autophagie médiée par les lysosomes. Cependant, l'effet combiné de la ventilation mécanique associée au sepsis n'est pas encore connu. Dans cette étude nous avons évalué l'influence d'une ventilation mécanique prolongée sur la dysfonction diaphragmatique induite par le sepsis. Nous avons étudié quatre groupes de rats : le groupe 1 représentait le groupe contrôle (animaux en ventilation spontanée) ; le groupe 2 (LPS) représentait le groupe « sepsis » dans lequel les animaux recevaient une injection intrapéritonéale de lipopolyssaccharide (LPS) d'E. Coli ; dans le groupe 3, les animaux étaient ventilés pendant 12h et dans le groupe 4 les animaux recevaient d'abord l'injection de LPS avant d'être ventilés pendant 12h.La contractilité diaphragmatique était mesurée in vitro et l'atrophie musculaire était évaluée en mesurant la surface de section des fibres. L'activation du protéasome et des autres voies protéolytiques (calpaines, caspase 3 et autophagie) ont été étudiées par tests spécifiques. L'injection de LPS et la ventilation mécanique entraînait une diminution significative de la contractilité diaphragmatique et le développement d'une atrophie des fibres musculaires. La combinaison de la VM à l'injection de LPS montrait une altération plus importante de la contractilité diaphragmatique mais pas d'atrophie supplémentaire. Les différentes voies protéolytiques (protéasome, calpain, caspase-3 et autophagie) étaient activées dans les groupes VM et LPS alors que la combinaison des deux résultait en une potentialisation de l'autophagie mais pas de l'activation du protéasome, des calpaines et de caspase 3. Les voies AKT et MTORC1 (inhibitrice de la protéolyse et activatrice de la synthèse protéique) étaient activées en réponse à l'injection de LPS mais pas par la VM prolongée. La combinaison du sepsis et de la VM entraînait une atténuation de l'activation des deux voies AKT et MTORC1 en comparaison au sepsis seul. Par ailleurs, la voie AMPK (activatrice de l'autophagie) était inhibée en réponse à l'injection de LPS et à la VM alors que la combinaison des deux entraînait seulement une inhibition modérée de l'AMPK en comparaison à l'injection de LPS seule.Enfin l'injection de LPS et la VM entraînait un stress oxydatif d'autant plus important quand on combinait les deux facteurs. Ces résultats montrent que la VM prolongée aggrave la dysfonction diaphragmatique induite par le sepsis et que cette aggravation est due en partie à l'activation de l'autophagie et au développement d'un stress oxydatif sévère.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sabah N. A. Hussain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c587r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s8159</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gp28h"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The well-being of Kenyan-Canadian parents and youth living in mixed families in Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Williams, Alexandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse s'intéresse au bien-être de parents et d'enfants canadiens originaires du Kenya et vivant à Montréal dans une famille mixte sur le plan ethnique et racial. L'objectif de la thèse est de déterminer si les immigrants appartenant à une communauté immigrante de petite  taille  et  vivant  dans  un  contexte  de  famille  culturellement  mixte  font  face  à  des défis particuliers. Les retombées permettront de sensibiliser les décideurs politiques et les professionnels de la santé aux besoins particuliers de cette population encore peu étudiée. Les  participants  à  l'étude  ont,  de  façon  générale,   réussi  à  bien  s'adapter  à  leur  vie Montréalaise et ce, malgré un certain stress associé à des expériences de racisme et aux difficultés inhérentes aux politiques linguistiques. Les parents vivant en famille mixte ont quant à eux pu profiter des possibilités offertes par la communauté du conjoint, et ainsi eu accès à une plus grande complétude institutionnelle ce qui a favorisé le bien-être de leurs enfants.  Ce  constat  met  en  lumière  le   rôle  important  qui  peut  être  joué  par  les communautés immigrantes bien établies dans l'accueil et le soutien des immigrants qui ne peuvent compter sur une communauté d'accueil et ce, même si l'affiliation ethnique s'avère inexistante. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the well-being of Kenyan-Canadian parents and youth living in ethnically- and racially-mixed families in Montreal. The objectives of the thesis are to determine whether there are challenges unique to immigrants belonging to small ethnic communities and living in racially- and ethnically-mixed families, and to educate policy makers and health practitioners as to needs that may be specific to this understudied group. The participants generally seem to be adapting well to life in Montreal, although the experience of racism and difficult y with language policies do generate some stress. Notably, the parents have taken advantage of possibilities afforded by other immigrant communities with greater institutional completeness to promote the well-being of their children. This suggests that an important role can be played by established immigrant communities in welcoming and assisting individual migrants without a receiving community, even when ethnic affiliation may be lacking. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cecile Rousseau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Myrna Lashley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bg009.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp28h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gx028"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An assessment of freezing rain processes in the Saint- Lawrence River Valley: synoptic-dynamic analysis and operational model verification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Splawinski, Sophie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La pluie verglaçante (PV) est une forme de précipitation qui pose un danger non seulement pour le secteur publique mais également pour le secteur aérien. Ce phénomène est particulièrement connu dans la vallée du fleuve St. Laurent (VFSL). L'orientation de la vallée ainsi que l'orographie explique ce nombre accru d'évènement. Le but vise est donc de fournir aux météorologues les outils nécessaires pour améliorer les prévisions de durée et de location de PV pour les villes de Montréal (CYUL), Québec (CYQB), et Massena (KMSS). Afin d'y parvenir, deux étapes sont requises :  la première,  introduire un nouveau modèle statistique de prévision et la deuxième, évaluer les conditions synoptiques et meso-échelle des évènements au cours des 27 dernières années. Pendant cette période, 99, 102, et 70 évènements de PV se sont produit à CYQB, CYUL, et KMSS, respectivement. Notre analyse statistique fourni aux météorologues une probabilité d'occurrence de PV (POZR). L'analyse est un moyen d'introduire les prévisions de température à deux différents niveaux et déterminer la probabilité de PV en utilisant un modèle baser sur les données provenant d'une climatologie de précipitations et de vents dans la VFSL. Les analyses synoptiques et dynamiques des évènements passés nous ont montré la nécessité d'incorporer un modèle de prévisions à haute résolution dans la vallée; nécessaire pour résoudre adéquatement l'orographie. Ceci est impératif pour la réussite de prévisions de PV. Ensuite, en utilisant un ensemble de données de vérification, on effectues des analyses de faisabilité et de précision du modèle, ce qui peut être utilise dans un bureau de prévisions. Finalement, une comparaison d'évènements de POZR variées démontre les forces et faiblesses dans les modèles de prévisions actuels. Ces derniers, couplés avec un nouveau modèle de prévision de PV, fourni au météorologues une opportunité de produire des prévisions de PV plus précises dans la VFSL.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Freezing rain (FZRA), a hazardous meteorological phenomenon, poses a significant threat to the general public and can severely damage societal infrastructure. The phenomenon is well known throughout the St-Lawrence River Valley (SLRV), which is known to have one of the highest frequencies of FZRA in the world owing to its orography and spatial orientation. Our focus is to provide meteorologists with the means to better predict both the onset and duration of FZRA at Montreal (CYUL), Quebec City (CYQB), and Massena (KMSS) in a two-stage process: by introducing a new 2-dimensional elliptic regression statistical forecast model and to assess synoptic and mesoscale conditions associated with past events. Analysis of a 27-year period, from 1979 through 2005, was conducted with a total of 99, 102, and 70 FZRA events at CYQB, CYUL, and KMSS, respectively. Our statistical analysis provides meteorologists with the POZR (probability of freezing rain): the ability to input model forecasted temperatures at two pressure levels and determine the probability of the onset of FZRA based on a 30-year climatology of northeasterly related precipitation. Synoptic-dynamic analysis of past events acknowledges the need for a high-resolution forecast model to adequately resolve mesoscale processes crucial to FZRA maintenance. Tests performed using a verification dataset (2006-2011 ZR event data) show the accuracy and feasibility of the model, which could be implemented by forecasting offices. Furthermore, synoptic-dynamic assessment of events within the verification dataset and forecast model comparison provide insight into missed forecasts, great forecasts and false alarms. Utilizing these methods could provide meteorologists with the opportunity to produce more highly accurate forecasts of both the onset and duration of freezing rain events. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Richard Gyakum</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh00b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx028</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010t35j"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hyperspectral remote sensing of individual gravesites - exploring the effects of cadaver decomposition on vegetation and soil spectra</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Snirer, Eva</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La détection des fosses  clandestines (tombes) est un domain d'étude récent (un nouvel outil) dans la télédétection hyperspectrale. Bien que des études antérieures ont démontrés qu'il est possible d'utiliser des techniques de télédétection hyperspectrale pour la localisation des fosses communes, il y a un manque d'études démontrant la faisabilité d'utiliser cette même technologie pour la détection des tombes individuelles. Cette thèse se porte sur la première année d'une étude a long terme, elle constate que des changements sont détectables au niveau de la réponse spectrale de la végétation et de du sol. Ces changements sont causés par les produits chimiques libérées par un corps en décomposition. Dix-huit carcasses de porc (Sus scrofa) ont été enterrées dans un environnement tempéré à Ottawa, ON. Trois scénarios ont été examinés: la décomposition d'un corps déposé en surface, un corps enterré à 30 cm dans le sol, et un corps enterré à 90 cm dans le sol. Un avion Twin Otter avec des capteurs hyperspectrales couvrant les ondes visible à l'infrarouge du spectre électromagnétique ont été utilisés pour recueillir des images aériennes du site. En plus, un spectroradiomètre portable a été utilisé pour recueillir des signatures spectrales des plantes et du sol en laboratoire (les échantillons ont été collectés en même temps que l'imagerie aérienne). Grâce à l'analyse chimique du sol faite avant et après l'établissement du site, ainsi qu'en même temps que l'imagerie aérienne, j'ai déterminer que certains changements chimiques ainsi que des changements dans la réflectance sont causés par la décomposition des cadavres plutôt que par la perturbation du sol. L'analyse statistique des niveaux de chlorophylle et des caroténoïdes démontre une séparabilité de la végétation en trois catégories: 1) le fond, 2) les sols perturbés, les tombes peu profondes et les tombes profondes, et 3) les corps déposé en surface. L'analyse statistique des signatures spectrales de la végétation confirme à l'analyse chimique pour différencier entre le fond, le sol perturbé, les tombes peu profondes et profondes, et les corps décomposant en surface. L'analyse des signatures spectres de sol a aussi permis de séparer entre un sol perturbé, une tombe peu profonde ou profonde, ou un  « enterrement » de surface.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The detection of clandestine graves is an emerging tool in hyperspectral remote sensing. Though previous studies have demonstrated that it is possible to use hyperspectral remote sensing techniques in detection of mass graves, there is a lack of studies demonstrating the feasibility to utilize this same technology for the detection of individual burial sites. This thesis summarizes the first year of a multi-year study to ascertain the detectable changes to vegetation and soil spectra caused by the chemicals released from a single decomposing body. Eighteen pig (Sus scrofa) carcasses were buried in a temperate environment in Ottawa, ON. Three scenarios were examined; surface body deposition, 30 cm, and 90 cm soil cover. A Twin Otter aircraft with hyperspectral sensors covering the visible to shortwave infrared range was used to collect the imagery. In addition to the airborne sensor, a portable spectroradiometer was used to collect plant and soil spectra in the lab (the soil and plant samples were collected coincidentally with the airborne imagery). Through chemical analysis of the soil collected both before site set up and coincidentally with the airborne imagery, I was able to determine the changes in chemistry and spectra caused by decomposing cadavers rather than just soil disturbance. Statistical analysis of the Chlorophyll and Carotenoids extraction demonstrates separability of vegetation into three categories: 1) background, 2) disturbed soil, shallow and deep graves, and 3) surface burials. Statistical analysis of the vegetation spectra corresponded to the chemical analysis in differentiating between background, disturbed soil, shallow and deep graves, and surface burials, as well analysis of the soil spectra allowed for separation into disturbed soil, shallow and deep graves, and surface burials. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Margaret Kalacska</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t971f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t35j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Remote Sensing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207ts35v"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sacred law: the philosophical origin of René Girard's scapegoat mechanism and Giorgio Agamben's «Homo sacer»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ganjedanesh, Farhang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>En dépit de la croissance de la laïcité après Le siècle des Lumières dans les sociétés occidentales et son impact sur la structure juridique de ces sociétés, si le système juridique a été dépouillé de la pensée religieuse est une question qui n'est pas encore résolu. L'idée du sacré comme l'un des éléments de la pensée religieuse est un sujet que de nombreux juristes et sociologues prennent en considération dans leurs études sur la relation entre la religion et la loi. Depuis dix-neuvième siècles, de nombreux penseurs tels que William Robertson Smith, Emile Durkheim et Marcel Mauss ont étudié l'impact du sacré sur la vie sociale et l'a placé au centre de l'ordre social. Pourtant, ces théories contribuent à la complexité de la question mentionnée ci-dessus. Au XXe siècle, deux auteurs, René Girard et Giorgio Agamben a abordé le sujet de la corrélation entre la loi et le sacré. Alors que René Girard, similaire à Émile Durkheim, perçoit le sacré comme une idée religieuse qui constitue l'origine de la vie sociale, Giorgio Agamben s'oppose à toute narration religieuse du sacré et le définit comme un phénomène juridico-politique, qui est exclu de deux lois divines et humaines. Cependant, ces deux penseurs partent des théories d'autres savants tels que Durkheim, car ils croient que le sacré comme l'origine de la loi appartient à une zone originaire dans lequel les relations humaines sont régies par la violence. L'usage de la violence permet à la structure juridique de s'imposer sur la vie des êtres humains. Ainsi, étant donné que Girard, contrairement à la formulation d'Agamben, identifie le sacré avec la religion, la question principale de la présente étude est de savoir s'il est possible de concilier leurs théories du sacré, et de déterminer si l'idée Girardien de la religion a une affinité avec l' nature juridique du sacré qu'Agamben propose. Afin de répondre à ces questions, les premiers écrits de Girard et Agamben qui appartiennent à la critique littéraire et esthétique moderne sont pris en considération parce que ces études littéraires et esthétiques présentent des thèmes tels que la fondation négatif de l'humanité qui qui jouent des rôles fondamentaux dans leurs théories du sacré. En plus de leurs études littéraires et esthétiques ont des racines philosophiques qui créent un lien entre ces théories. Compte tenu de la proximité de leurs premiers écrits, on peut soutenir que, en dépit de leurs différentes méthodes, leurs théories du sacré se réfèrent à la même origine violente de la loi, qui appartient à une zone d'indistinction entre le droit et la religion.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In spite of the growth of secularism after the Enlightenment era in the Western societies and its impact on the legal structure of these societies, whether the legal system has been stripped of the religious thinking is a question that is far from being answered. The idea of the sacred as one of the elements of religious thinking is the subject which many jurists and sociologists take into consideration in their studies on the relationship between the religion and the law. Since the nineteenth and the twentieth centuries many thinkers such as William Robertson Smith, Émile Durkheim, and Marcel Mauss have studied the impact of the sacred on the social life and placed it at the center of the social order. Yet, although these theories have shed light on the role of the sacred in the formation of the legal systems, they have also brought up some new questions which contribute to the complexity of the above-mentioned relationship. In the twentieth century, two authors, René Girard and Giorgio Agamben also addressed the subject of the correlation between the law and the sacred. While René Girard, similar to Émile Durkheim, perceives the sacred as a religious idea which constitutes the origin of social life, Giorgio Agamben opposes any religious narrative of the sacred and defines it as a juridico-political phenomenon, which is excluded from both divine and human laws. However, both thinkers depart from the theories of other scholars such as Durkheim since they believe that the sacred as the origin of the law belongs to an originary zone in which human relations are governed by violence. The use of violence enables the legal structure to establish itself on the life of human beings. Thus, given that Girard, contrary to Agamben's formulation, identifies the sacred with the religion, the main question of the present study is whether it is possible to reconcile Girard's and Agamben's theories of the sacred, and determine if the Girardian idea of religion has affinity with the juridical nature of the sacred which Agamben proposes. To answer these questions, earlier writings of Girard and Agamben which belong to the domains of literary criticism and modern aesthetics are taken into consideration because these literary and aesthetic studies present some themes such as the negative foundation of humanity which later take the center stage in their theories of the sacred. In addition, their literary and aesthetic studies have philosophical roots which create a link between these theories. Proximity of their early writings shows that in spite of Agamben's and Girard's different methods, their theories of the sacred point to the same violent origin of law, which belongs to a zone of indistinction between law and religion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mark Antaki</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2677004q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts35v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pt911"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modeling and analysis of lipid bilayers with applications to vesicles and lipoprotein particles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maleki Karyak, Mohsen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des méthodes de milieux continus pour la modélisation de bicouches lipidiques sont développées et appliquées à des vésicules lipidiques à deux phases et à des particules discoïdes de lipoprotéines de haute densité (HDL). Tout d'abord, en s'appuyant sur un modéle tridimensionnel, la mécanique d'une bicouche lipidique possédant une courbure spontanée est considérée. La Cinématique, la symétrie matérielle, les relations de stress, et la cohérence de bicouches lipidiques sont discutées. En traitant une bicouche lipidique comme une structure mince, la densité d'énergie surfacique d'une bicouche lipidique ayant une courbure spontanée est obtenue à l'aide d'une procédure de réduction de dimension. L'attention est portée sur la source de courbure spontanée de la densité d'énergie bien connue de Canham–Helfrich. En outre, l'effet de l'asymétrie constitutive des sur la densité d'énergie surfacique d'une bicouche lipidique est mis en évidence. Considérant une vésicule à deux phases comme système de domaines sphériques coexistants, son équilibre est étudié à l'aide d'un modèle simple de milieu continu. Des configurations multi-domaines et de l'état fondamental sont considérées. Alors que, dans le premier cas, plusieurs domaines lipidiques bourgeonnés coexistent sur une vésicule, dans le dernier cas, la vésicule est composée de deux grands domaines lipidiques. La variation de l'énergie potentielle nette d'une vésicule multi-domaine en fonction du nombre de domaines lipidiques et de la pression osmotique est étudiée. En se basant sur la comparaison de l'énergie, deux configurations de l'état fondamental correspondant à des niveaux d'énergie minimaux sont identifiés: la configuration étranglée et la sphère complète. Les résultats indiquent que la pression osmotique et le rayon excédentaire initial jouent un rôle clé dans la forme finale des configurations à l'état fondamental. Les valeurs critiques de ces paramètres sont identifiées. Enfin, l'équilibre et la stabilité d'une particule HDL discoïde sont étudiés. Un modèle dans lequel la bicouche lipidique et les composants d'ApoA-I à double bande de la particule de HDL discoïde sont représentées par une surface de matériau et une courbe de matériau parfaitement collée sur le bord de la surface est proposé. L'énergie de courbure et la tension de surface de la bicouche lipidique ainsi que l'énergie de flexion de la chaîne apoA-I sont incluses. En adoptant un schéma variationnel, les équations d'équilibre non-linéaire d'une particule de HDL discoïdale dans une configuration générale sont calculées d'après des formulations directes, basées sur la géométrie, ou paramétrées. Les équations d'équilibre linéarisées d'une particule de HDL circulaire plane sont obtenues et sa stabilité linéaire est étudiée en utilisant la seconde méthode de variation. Une méthode de comparaison de l'énergie est appliquée et se trouve à offrir une approche pratique pour déterminer la stabilité linéaire. Des résultats numériques sont présentés pour l'équilibre et la stabilité des particules de HDL circulaires planes. Un plan de stabilité indiquant différentes régions stables et instables des paramètres d'entrée adimensionnels sous-jacents est fourni. Certaines possibilités de changement de stabilité et les formes modales d'instabilité sont identifiées. Il est démontré que les premiers modes d'instabilité transversale et plane ressemblent aux formes de selle non planes et d'ellipse plane, respectivement.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Continuum approaches for modeling lipid bilayers are developed and applied to two-phase lipid vesicles and discoidal high-density lipoprotein (HDL) particles. First, relying on a three-dimensional model, the mechanics of a lipid bilayer with spontaneous curvature is considered. Kinematics, material symmetry, stress relations, and coherency of lipid bilayer leaflets are discussed. Treating a lipid bilayer as a thin structure, the areal energy density of a lipid bilayer with spontaneous curvature is obtained using a dimension-reduction procedure. Attention is paid on the source of spontaneous curvature in the well known Canham–Helfrich energy density. Also, the effect of constitutive asymmetry of the leaflets on the areal energy density of a lipid bilayer is highlighted.Considering a two-phase vesicle as system of coexisting spherical domains, its equilibrium is studied using a simple continuum model. Multidomain and ground-state configurations are considered. Whereas in the former case multiple budded lipid domains coexist on a vesicle, in the latter case the vesicle is composed of two large lipid domains. Variations of the net potential-energy of a multidomain vesicle with the number of lipid domains and osmotic pressure are studied. Based on an energy comparison argument, two ground-state configurations corresponding to minimum energy levels are identified: pinched-off and complete sphere configurations. The results indicate that osmotic pressure and initial excess radius play key roles in the final shape of attaining ground-state configurations. The critical values of these parameters are identified. Lastly, the equilibrium and stability of a discoidal HDL particle are studied. A model in which the lipid bilayer and double-belt apoA-I components of discoidal HDL particle are represented by a material surface and a material curve perfectly bonded to the edge of the surface is proposed. The curvature energy and surface tension of lipid bilayer and the bending energy of apoA-I chain are included. Adopting a variational scheme, nonlinear equilibrium equations of a discoidal HDL particle in a general configuration are derived using both direct, geometrically-based and parametrized formulations. The linearized equilibrium equations of a flat circular HDL particle are obtained and its linear stability is investigated using the second variation method. An energy comparison method is applied and is found to offer a handy approach for ascertaining linear stability. Numerical results are provided for the equilibrium and stability of flat circular HDL particle. A stability plane indicating different stable and unstable regions of underlying dimensionless input parameters is provided. Possible pathways of stability change and instability mode shapes are identified. It is shown that the first transverse and planar instability modes resemble nonplanar saddle-like and planar elliptic shapes, respectively.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eliot Fried</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c56c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt911</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085p509"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of gaps and overlaps on variable stiffness composites manufactured by automated fiber placement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fayazbakhsh, Kazem</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La conception de composites à rigidité variable (où l'orientation des fibres change avec le plan du stratifié) peut améliorer les performances mécaniques du stratifié, et permettre un meilleur compromis dans les designs. Les stratifiés à rigidité variable peuvent être obtenus à l'aide du procédé de dépose automatique de fibres (AFP). Souvent, lors de la fabrication, certains défauts (espaces ou recouvrements) apparaissent et affectent les performances mécaniques du stratifié. La perte de propriétés mécanique dépend des paramètres de conception et des paramètres du procédé. Ainsi, l'objectif de ce travail de thèse est de prédire l'amélioration effective des propriétés mécaniques d'un composite stratifié à rigidité variable, en tenant compte de ces défauts. D'abord, afin d'exploiter maximum les bénéfices du design à rigidité variable, une optimisation du parcours de dépose permet de maximiser la rigidité dans le plan et la charge maximal admissible en flambage. Un rayon de courbure constant du parcours de dépose est étudié à l'aide d'un algorithme génétique. Les fibres orientées perpendiculairement à la direction de chargement peuvent augmenter la charge de flambage jusqu'à 111%. Toutefois, en considérant le rayon de courbure minimum admissible par la tête de dépose AFP, l'amélioration maximum réalisable en terme de charge de flambage se réduit à 57%. Ensuite, une méthodologie est développée pour localiser les espaces et les recouvrements et calculer leurs pourcentages surfaciques. Il est constaté qu'une augmentation du nombre de mèches par course, en conservant une largeur de mèche constante, réduit significativement le pourcentage d'espaces et recouvrements. Une réduction inférieure est obtenue si la largeur de la mèche est augmentée en conservant le même nombre total de mèches. Enfin, une stratégie, la méthode de la couche défectueuse (Defect Layer Method), est proposée pour construire un modèle d'éléments finis pour les composites à rigidité variable avec espaces et recouvrements. Cette méthode est efficace numériquement et plus précise que les méthodes proposées dans la littérature. Une analyse par éléments finis de deux matériaux composites à rigidité variable spécifique est proposée. Elle montre que les recouvrements améliorent les performances mécaniques tandis que les espaces les réduisent. En considérant le cas d'une dépose avec recouvrements, l'amélioration maximale réalisable en terme de charge de flambage est de 105% (à comparer à 56% lorsque les recouvrements sont ignorés). En considérant le cas d'une dépose avec espace, l'amélioration en charge de flambement est limitée à 40%. Des frontières d'efficacité de Pareto prennent en compte les effets des espaces et des recouvrements sont obtenues. Elles constituent d'importants principes de conception qui ont un intérêt direct pour l'industrie. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Variable stiffness design of composites, where the fiber orientation changes within the plane of laminates, can improve the structural performance of the laminates, and provide a trade-off between design objectives. Laminates with variable stiffness design can be manufactured with Automated Fiber Placement (AFP) technology. During the manufacturing, certain defects, in the form of gaps and/or overlaps, often emerge and hence affect the structural performance of the composite laminates. The amount of change in structural properties depends on the laminates design and manufacturing parameters. Therefore, calculating the actual improvement in the structural properties of variable stiffness composite laminates, when the effect of defects is considered, has been a challenge. In this thesis, first, to fully exploit the benefits of variable stiffness design, simultaneous maximization of in-plane stiffness and buckling load for composite laminates with a constant curvature fiber path is investigated using a surrogate-based genetic algorithm. It is shown that varying the fiber orientation perpendicular to the loading direction can increase buckling load up to 111%. However, considering the minimum turning radius constraint imposed by AFP, the maximum achievable improvement in buckling load reduces to 57%, due to the limited fiber steering. Then, a methodology is developed to locate gaps and overlaps and calculate their area percentages. It is found that by increasing the number of tows inside a course, when the tow width is kept constant, the gap and overlap area percentages are significantly reduced. Smaller reductions in gap and overlap area percentages are obtained when the tow width increases and the number of tows is kept constant. Finally, a strategy, namely the Defect Layer Method, is proposed to build the Finite Element model of variable stiffness laminates with gaps and overlaps. This method is proved to be computationally efficient and more precise compared to the available method in the literature. Finite Element Analysis of two selected variable stiffness laminates is performed and it is found that overlaps increase their structural performance, while gaps deteriorate the mechanical properties. Considering the presence of overlaps, the maximum achievable improvement in buckling load can be increased to 105% compared to 56%, where the overlaps are ignored. Considering the presence of gaps within the laminate, the improvement in buckling load is limited to 40%. Modified Pareto fronts considering the effect of gaps or overlaps are obtained to provide important design guidelines of direct interest to industry.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Damiano Pasini</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Larry Lessard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x12k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085p509</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623g88c"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A software tool for creating and visualizing mappings in digital musical instruments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wilansky, Jonathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans le monde des instruments acoustiques, les propriétés physiques des instruments déterminent les gestes effectués ainsi que les sons produits; ce n'est pas le cas avec les Instruments de Musique Numériques (IMNs) constitués trois parties distinctes: une interface de contrôle, un système de production sonore et le système de correspondance entre les deux ("mapping"). Ceci implique que l'interaction  entre les capteurs et le son fait partie intégrante de l'IMN et influence fortement comment l'instrument sonne et joue. La création de correspondance dans un IMN n'est pas une tâche triviale, et généralement l'exploration de différentes correspondances est nécessaire durant les phases de prototype, composition et production. De plus, les environnement de productions incluant l'utilisation d'IMN peuvent créer des opportunités de rencontre entre les ingénieurs, les compositeurs et les interprètes car la configuration et visualisation des correspondances, qui se doit d'être simple et rapide, requiert un mélange de savoir-faire technique et non-technique. Cette thèse est basée sur deux logiciels développés au sein du laboratoire IDMIL (Input Devices and Music Interaction Laboratory) aidant le processus de correspondance: Libmapper, une logithèque permettant de connecter des signaux numériques et Webmapper, une interface graphique pour Libmapper. Une extension de Webmapper a également été crée afin d'adresser les deux problèmes suivants: pour offrir une interface alternative de configuration de correspondance et pour offrir une visualisation alternative des couches de correspondance. Deux nouvelles interfaces ont également été crées afin d'ajouter deux nouvelles vues: une en forme de ruche et une en quadrillée. Le système a été développé en HTML5, utilisant une architecture inspiré par le patron modèle-vue-contrôleur. Les avantages et les désavantages des trois différentes interfaces de Webmapper ainsi que de sa nouvelle extension seront traités vis à vis de leur capacité d'agir en tant qu'interface et en tant qu'outil de visualisation. Les contributions de ce travail résident dans la démonstration des avantages des méthodes alternatives de configuration et de visualisation des couches de correspondances dans les IMN, ainsi que dans les fondations pour de futures recherches utilisant le logiciel HTML5.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In acoustic instruments, physical properties of the instrument determine both the gestures that can be performed on it and the sound produced by it. This is not the case with digital musical instruments (DMIs) that consist of three distinct parts: the playable interface, the sound generating component, and the mapping between them. The implication is that mapping from sensors to sound is an integral part in the design of a DMI, and a process highly influential on how the instrument is played and sounds. Creating mappings in a DMI is a non-trivial task, and typically a lot of different mappings are explored throughout the stages of prototyping, composition, and production. Furthermore, production environments involving DMIs will typically bring together engineers, composers, and performers in valuable and often short meeting times, requiring configuration and visualization of the mapping layer to be quick and simple, catering to both technical and nontechnical participants. This thesis presents two software components developed at the Input Devices and Music Interaction Laboratory to aid in the mapping process: libmapper, a software library enabling connections to be made between data signals declared on a shared network, and Webmapper, a list-based graphical user interface to libmapper. An extension to Webmapper was created to address the following two concerns: to provide alternate interfaces for configuring mappings, and to provide an alternate visualizations of the mapping layer. Two new interfaces were created to investigate the tasks: a grid inspired view and a hive plot inspired view. The system was developed using HTML5 compliant technologies, and a framework architecture inspired by the model-view-controller paradigm was added to Webmapper for code modularity and maintainability. Advantages and disadvantages of the three different interfaces from Webmapper and its new extension are discussed in regards to their ability to act both as a software user interface and a data visualization tool. The contribution of the work is the demonstration of benefits to alternate methods for configuring and visualizing the mapping layer in DMIs, and the laying of a foundation for future investigations using the created HTML5 compliant software. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marcelo Wanderley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q478f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g88c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42nc220"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Innovations in electrophoretic deposition of nanotitania- based photoanodes for use in dye-sensitized solar cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parsi Benehkohal, Nima</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The scope of this thesis is the investigation and elaboration of novel cost-effective and environmentally friendly electrophoretic deposition (EPD) techniques for the fabrication of robust and adhesive nanotitania film electrodes for high performance dye sensitized solar cells (DSSC). In the first part of this work, EPD in water is investigated, where electrolysis of water is suppressed by adoption of a low DC voltage approach. Growth of adherent and robust films is enabled via the use of isopropanol as co-solvent and Zn(NO3)2 as additive, the latter leading to co-deposition of hydrous zinc oxide that acts as nanoglue. The optimization of the suspension composition, mechanism of zinc co-deposition with TiO2 nanoparticles (P25, Evonic), and the structural and electronic properties of the resultant TiO2-ZnO semiconductor films are described. Subsequent to EPD nanocomposite TiO2–ZnO film growth, the photoanodes after annealing at 450 ºC are assembled into DSSC devices and shown to have better photovoltaic performance compared to that of bare TiO2 film photoanodes. Various photoelectrochemical characterizations indicated that in-situ formation of ZnO causes suppression of charge recombination at the electrode/electrolyte interface thus prolonging photoelectron lifetime. In the next phase, the electrophoretic deposition of mixed nano scale P25 TiO2-metal oxide composite films, namely TiO2-ZnO, TiO2-Al2O3 and TiO2-MgO is investigated in order to probe charge recombination and electron transport properties. The secondary oxides were found to co-deposit uniformly within the TiO2 film (forming island-like nanodeposits) at approximately 1-3 wt% content. Various photoelectrochemical characterization techniques revealed that among the three composite films, the TiO2-Al2O3 electrode exhibits the highest charge recombination resistance at the TiO2/electrolyte interface but its conversion efficiency is the lowest because it suffers from very high electron transport resistance. By comparison, the TiO2-MgO and TiO2-ZnO films exhibit significantly lower electron transport resistance and relatively higher conversion efficiency. In the last part of this thesis, EPD is employed successfully in a suspension of multi-component and different size and morphology (anatase + rutile) TiO2 nanoparticulates to engineer a very robust bi-functional electrode structure. Aqueous-synthesized anatase (5–10 nm) nanocrystallites, sub-micrometer-sized "sea urchin"-like rutile (200–500 nm) aggregates and P25 nanoparticles (30 nm) are formulated in a stable binder-free isopropanol suspension and deposited into adhesive films not only on glass but also metal and plastic substrates without resorting to mechanical compression. As result of the scattering functionality and the excellent film adhesion rendered by rutile, contact resistance between the TiO2 film and the substrate is minimized resulting in higher VOC, fill factor and record-breaking efficiency: 8.59% vs. 8.32% for double-layer benchmark photoanode. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse porte sur l'étude et l'élaboration d'une nouvelle technique d'électrodéposition cationique (EPD) plus rentable et respectueuse de l'environnement. Cette technique est étudiée à des fins de fabrication d'électrodes robustes et adhésives de nano-dioxyde de titane pour des cellules photovoltaïques à pigments colorés (DSSCs) à haute performance. Dans un premier temps, l'EPD a été étudié dans un milieu aqueux. Une basse tension continue a été adoptée pour empêcher l'électrolyse de l'eau. Le dépôt de films solides et adhérents a été rendue possible par l'intermédiaire de l'utilisation d'isopropanol en tant que co-solvant et du Zn(NO3)2 en tant qu'additif. L'emploie du Zn(NO3)2 a également entrainé une déposition d'oxyde de zinc hydraté qui agit comme une nanocolle. L'optimisation de la composition de la suspension, du mécanisme de co-déposition de zinc avec des nanoparticules de TiO2 (P25, Evonic), et les propriétés structurales et électroniques des films semi-conducteurs de TiO2–ZnO obtenus sont décrites. Suite à la fabrication des films enTiO2–ZnO via l'EPD, et après avoir été recuites à 450 °C, les photoanodes sont utilisées pour l'assemblage des DSSCs. Il a été démontré que ces photoanodes ont une meilleure performance photovoltaïque que celles contenant uniquement du TiO2. Diverses caractérisations photoélectrochimiques ont indiqué une élimination de la recombinaison de charges à l'interface électrode/électrolyte lors de la formation in situ du ZnO, prolongeant ainsi la durée de vie des photoélectrons.Dans un deuxième temps, la déposition par électrophorèse de trois films composites P25 TiO2/oxyde de métal est étudiée, à savoir : TiO2-ZnO, TiO2-Al2O3, et TiO2-MgO mélangés à l'échelle nano. Les propriétés de recombinaison des charges et de transport des électrons des films fabriqués ont été examinées. Il a été montré que les oxydes secondaires se co-déposent uniformément dans le film de TiO2 (formant des nanodépôts en forme d'île) à une teneur d'environ 1-3% en poids. Diverses techniques de caractérisation photoélectrochimiques ont révélé que parmi les trois films composites, l'électrode à base deTiO2-Al2O3 présente la plus grande résistance associée à la recombinaison de charges à l'interface TiO2/électrolyte, mais son efficacité de conversion est la plus faible, car elle éprouve d'une très forte résistance au transport des électrons. Au contraire, les films à base de TiO2-MgO etTiO2-ZnO présentent une résistance au transport d'électrons considérablement plus faible et une efficacité de conversion relativement élevée. Dans la dernière partie de cette thèse, l'EPD est utilisé avec succès pour fabriquer une électrode bifonctionnelle très robuste. Une suspension à plusieurs composantes avec des nanoparticules de TiO2 (anatase + rutile) de différentes tailles et morphologies a été utilisée. Des nanocristallites d'anatase synthétisés en milieu aqueux (5-10 nm), des agrégats de rutile de sous-taille micrométrique et en forme « d'oursin » (200-500 nm), et des nanoparticules de P25 (30 nm) sont formulés dans une suspension stable d'isopropanol sans liant, et sont déposés non seulement sur des substrats en verre, mais également sur des substrats métalliques et en plastique, et ce, sans recourir à une compression mécanique. Avec la fonctionnalité de diffusion de la lumière et l'excellente adhérence du film, grâce au rutile, la résistance de contact entre le film de TiO2 et le substrat est réduite entrainant ainsi une augmentation de la tension VOC, et du facteur de remplissage. Une efficacité de conversion record a été mesurée : 8,59 % contre 8,32 % pour la photoanode de référence à double couche.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>George Demopoulos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w305m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nc220</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A028710267"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Simple magnetic nanoparticles as catalysts for hydrogenation, condensation and coupling reactions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hudson, Reuben</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Processes for chemical conversions often either involve one of two divergent catalyst types. Heterogeneous catalysts (bulk material) represent a simple system, which can easily be removed from the reaction mixture after use. Homogeneous catalysts (soluble species) on the other hand, are often much more difficult to separate, but generally provide excellent improved catalytic performance in part because of their equal homogeneous distribution within the reaction media. Moreover, they allow for more tuneability through the use of various ligands. The emerging use of nanoparticle catalysts effectively bridges the gap between homogeneous and heterogeneous catalysis. Often, the smaller the particles become, the more they offer catalytic properties similar to homogeneous catalyst systems. Unfortunately, the reduction in size also makes separation increasingly difficult—again, similar to homogeneous systems. To address the issue of separation, the field of magnetic nanoparticle catalysis emerged. By simple application of an external magnet, magnetic nanoparticle catalysts can be recovered and easily reused. Most examples of magnetic nanoparticle catalysis employ the particle only as a vehicle for magnetic recovery, rather than the catalyst itself. Complex strategies of this kind include coating with a polymer or silica, to which a metal-binding ligand can be anchored. By such a system, one could envision anchoring of nearly any pseudo-homogeneous metal, enabling a broad catalytic scope. The focus of this work is instead on the use of simple magnetic nanoparticles where the particles themselves act not only as the means for magnetic recovery, but also as catalysts. This thesis covers three general types of simple magnetic nanoparticle catalysts. First, this work demonstrated that reduced iron nanoparticles with a shell of iron oxide can efficiently catalyze the hydrogenation of unsaturated hydrocarbons. This scheme can also be adapted to a flow system by growing the nanoparticles in the presence of amphiphillic polymers. Second, in order to address the limited catalytic offering of iron, the scope of reactions can be expanded by decorating these same iron/iron oxide nanoparticles with a more catalytically active metal. Copper- and ruthenium- decorated nanoparticles have been synthesized and used for the azide-alkyne click reaction and transfer hydrogenation, respectively. Third, work presented in this thesis shows that other metals can also be incorporated directly into the magnetic nanoparticle lattice. For example, CuFe2O4 nanoparticles have been used to catalyze the Biginilli condensation and cross-dehydrogenative coupling reactions. By the use of these three general types of bare particles, we have expanded the scope of simple magnetic nanoparticle catalyzed reactions. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les procédés chimiques impliquent souvent des catalyseurs de l'un des deux types suivants. Les catalyseurs hétérogènes (matériaux) constituent un système simple, qui peut généralement être aisément retiré du mélange réactionnel après usage. D'autre part, les catalyseurs homogènes (espèces solubles) sont souvent beaucoup plus difficiles à séparer ; en revanche, ils offrent en general une excellente performance catalytique étant donnée leur répartition homogène dans le milieu réactionnel. De plus, ces derniers peuvent être facilement modifiés par l'usage de divers ligands pour ainsi améliorer leur performance. L'utilisation croissante de nanoparticules en catalyse offre une alternative entre la catalyse homogène et hétérogène. De façon générale, plus leur taille est petite, plus les particules possèdent des propriétés catalytiques similaires à celles des systèmes homogènes. Malheureusement, la réduction de leur taille rend d'autant plus difficile leur séparation, comme dans le cas des systèmes homogènes. Pour résourdre ce problème de séparation, le domaine de la catalyse à base de nanoparticules magnétiques a vu le jour. Grâce à l'utilisation d'un aimant externe, les catalyseurs de nanoparticules magnétiques peuvent être récupérés et réutilisés facilement. Dans la plupart des exemples de catalyse faisant usage de nanoparticules magnétiques, les particules sont uniquement utilisées comme ancre pour la récupération magnétique, et non comme catalyseurs. Les stratégies complexes de ce type comprennent l'enrobage des nanoparticules avec un polymère ou bien avec de la silice, auquel un ligand de coordination peut être ancré. Par un tel système, on peut envisager l'ancrage de presque n'importe quel métal pseudo-homogène, ce qui permet un large éventail catalytique. L'objectif de ce travail est plutôt axé sur l'utilisation de nanoparticules magnétiques simples où les particules agissent non seulement comme moyen de récupération magnétique, mais également en tant que catalyseurs. Cette thèse porte sur trois types généraux de catalyseurs simples de nanoparticules magnétiques. Tout d'abord, il est démontré que des nanoparticules de fer réduit, dotés d'une coquille d'oxyde de fer, peuvent catalyser efficacement l'hydrogénation d'hydrocarbures insaturés. Cette réaction peut également être adaptée à un système "in flow", en préparant les nanoparticules en présence de polymères amphiphiles. Deuxièmement, considérant le potentiel catalytique limité du fer, la portée de ces réactions peut être étendue par la décoration de ces mêmes nanoparticules de fer / oxyde de fer à l'aide d'un second métal possédant un potentiel catalytique plus élevé. Des nanoparticules décorées de cuivre et de ruthénium ont été synthétisées et utilisées pour effectuer des réactions de couplage azoture-alcyne (click) et d'hydrogénation de transfert, respectivement. Troisièmement, il est démontré que d'autres métaux peuvent également directement être incorporés dans un réseau de nanoparticules magnétiques. Par exemple, des nanoparticules de CuFe2O4 peuvent être utilisées pour catalyser des réactions de condensation de Biginilli ainsi que des réactions de couplage inter-déshydrogénation. Par l'utilisation de ces trois types généraux de particules nues, nous avons élargi la portée des réactions catalysées par des nanoparticules magnétiques simples.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Audrey Moores-François</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Chaojun Li</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w5614.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/028710267</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977z29r"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wave propagation methods for the experimental characterization of soft biomaterials and tissues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kazemirad, Siavash</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les propriétés viscoélastiques des biomatériaux et des tissus mous déterminent leur comportement mécanique sous charge dans des conditions biologiques. Par exemple, les propriétés viscoélastiques des hydrogels utilisés dans la culture cellulaire et l'ingénierie tissulaire doivent approximativement correspondre à ceux du tissu qu'ils remplacent. La quantification précise des propriétés dépendant de la fréquence de tissus de cordes vocales et des biomatériaux mous est importante pour la reconstruction de la voix. Les cordes vocales humaines oscillent à une fréquence fondamentale autour de 125, 200, 300 et 500 Hz pour une phonation normale chez les hommes, femmes, enfants et nourrissons, respectivement. Les fréquences de vibration peuvent atteindre jusqu'à plusieurs kHz, spécialement dans le chant. Les oscillations des cordes vocales, essentielles à la production de la voix, sont significativement affectées par les propriétés mécaniques (viscoélastiques) de la muqueuse des cordes vocales. Une méthode de caractérisation nouvelle basée sur la propagation des ondes de Rayleigh a été développée pour la quantification des propriétés viscoélastiques dépendant de la fréquence des biomatériaux moux sur une large gamme de fréquences, soit jusqu'à 4 kHz. Des caoutchouc de silicone synthétique et des échantillons de gélatine ont été fabriqués et testés pour évaluer la méthode proposée. Les modules de cisaillement et élastique et le facteur de perte obtenu à partir de la méthode de propagation des ondes de Rayleigh ont été comparés avec ceux obtenus à l'aide de deux autres méthodes, ainsi qu'a des résultats présentés dans une étude indépendante. La méthode proposée semblé fiable, précise et pratique rentable pour la mesure des propriétés viscoélastiques des biomatériaux mous, comme les biomatériaux de phonosurgical et d'hydrogels, sur une large gamme de fréquences.Une méthode non-invasive a été développée pour mesurer le module de cisaillement des tissus de cordes vocales humaines in vivo au cours de la phonation. Ceci est nécessaire pour le développement de biomatériaux injectables pour l'augmentation des cordes vocales et de réparation, et pour évaluer les procédures de traitement de la voix. La vitesse de propagation de l'onde muqueuse a été mesurée pour quatre sujets humains à des fréquences différentes en utilisant des images endoscopiques à grande vitesse du larynx et des méthodes de traitement d'image. Le module de cisaillement transversal de la muqueuse des cordes vocales a ensuite été calculé à partir d'une équation de dispersion de propagation des ondes de surface en utilisant les vitesses d'ondes mesurées. Les résultats sont en bon accord avec ceux d'autres études obtenus par des mesures in vitro, confirmant ainsi la précision de la méthode de mesure proposée.Les hydrogels acide hyaluronique-gélatine avec des concentrations de cross-linker diverses et d'autres composants ont été fabriqués. Ces biomatériaux sont pour une utilisation comme matrice extracellulaire synthétique dans l'ingénierie tissulaire des cordes vocales. La méthode de propagation des ondes de Rayleigh a été utilisée pour quantifier les propriétés viscoélastiques dépendant de la fréquence de ces hydrogels, y compris les modules de cisaillement et visqueux, sur une large gamme de fréquences, c'est à dire de 40 à 4000 Hz. Les propriétés viscoélastiques des hydrogels conçus sont similaires à celles du tissu pli vocal humain obtenu à partir in vivo et des mesures in vitro. Il est observé que la concentration de réticulation est le paramètre le plus commun pour régler les propriétés viscoélastiques des hydrogels basés sur l'acide hyaluronique conçus. L'acide hyaluronique et le contenu de gélatine de ces hydrogels sont les principaux paramètres à ajuster leurs propriétés biochimiques et biologiques, en tenant compte des changements dans les propriétés viscoélastiques des hydrogels.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A good understanding of the viscoelasticity of soft biomaterials and tissue is needed to predict their mechanical response under loads in biological conditions. For example, the viscoelastic properties of hydrogels used in cell culturing and tissue engineering should approximately match those of the tissue they replace. These properties are strongly dependent on the excitation frequency. This has important implication for voice production. The human vocal folds oscillate at a fundamental frequency around 125, 200, 300 and 500 Hz in normal phonation for male, female, children and infants, respectively. Vibration frequencies can reach up to a few kHz, specially in singing. Vocal fold oscillations, essential to voice production, are significantly affected by the mechanical (viscoelastic) properties of the vocal fold mucosa. A novel characterization method based on Rayleigh wave propagation was developed for the quantification of frequency-dependent viscoelastic properties of soft biomaterials over a broad frequency range; i.e., up to 4 kHz. Synthetic silicone rubber and gelatin samples were fabricated and tested to evaluate the proposed method. The shear and elastic moduli and the loss factor obtained from the Rayleigh wave propagation method were compared with results from two other methods, as well as results from an independent study. The proposed method was found to be accurate and cost effective for the measurement of viscoelastic properties of soft biomaterials, such as phonosurgical biomaterials and hydrogels, over a wide frequency range. A non-invasive method was developed to measure the shear modulus of human vocal fold tissue in vivo during phonation. This is needed for the development of injectable biomaterials for vocal fold augmentation and repair, and to evaluate voice treatment procedures. The mucosal wave propagation speed was measured for four human subjects at different phonation frequencies using high speed endoscopic images of the larynx and image processing methods. The transverse shear modulus of the vocal fold mucosa was then calculated from a surface wave propagation dispersion equation using the measured wave speeds. The results were found to be in good agreement with those from other studies obtained via in vitro measurements, thereby supporting the validity of the proposed measurement method. Hyaluronic acid-gelatin hydrogels with varying concentrations of cross-linker are other constituents were fabricated. These biomaterials are for use as synthetic extracellular matrix in vocal fold tissue engineering. The Rayleigh wave propagation method was used to quantify the frequency-dependent viscoelastic properties of these hydrogels, including shear and viscous moduli, over a broad frequency range; i.e., from 40 to 4000 Hz. The viscoelastic properties of the designed hydrogels were similar to those of human vocal fold tissue obtained from in vivo and in vitro measurements. It was shown that the cross-linker concentration is the most common parameter to tune the viscoelastic properties of designed hyaluronan-based hydrogels. The hyaluronic acid and gelatin contents of these hydrogels are the main parameters to adjust their biochemical and biological properties, considering the changes in the viscoelastic properties of the hydrogels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Luc Mongeau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483n516.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977z29r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79408137h"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A multiscale approach to mechancial modeling of a leaf petiole: integrating cell wall, cellular tissues, and structural morphology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Faisal, Md Tanvir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>    Une plante est une structure hiérarchique naturelle, qui présente des propriétés mécaniques remarquables. Les propriétés mécaniques à grande échelle d'une plante sont le résultat cumulatif des propriétés structurelles du niveau précédent de la hiérarchie structurelle. Pour développer des structures de génie inspirées par une plante et ses organes, une caractérisation détaillée de ses propriétés mécaniques manifestées aux multiples niveaux hiérarchiques est  essentielle pour imiter ces structures pour les applications d'ingénierie.    Cette thèse présente un ensemble de modèles théoriques et numériques à divers niveaux hiérarchiques structuraux afin de capturer les propriétés structurelles aux niveaux globaux d'un pétiole d'une plante. La méthode de modélisation est cadrée au sein d'un système mécanique à niveaux multiples, qui est essentiel pour toute structure composée de plusieurs ordres hiérarchiques d'organisation. Les propriétés structurelles à grande échelle, c.à.d. la raideur  en flexion et en torsion, d'un pétiole d'une plante sont obtenues par la corrélation entre la construction de la paroi cellulaire, la microstructure des tissus, et la morphologie de la forme structurelle. La raideur  de la paroi cellulaire est modélisée en utilisant la théorie des matériaux composites à renfort fibreux. La microarchitecture des constituants des tissus qui gouverne les propriétés du pétiole est modélisée avec un nouveau algorithme – La tessellation de Voronoi de centre à bord fini (FECVT) - qui est capable de fournir une visualisation réaliste du tissu.  La raideur  effective des constituants des tissus est obtenue par la méthode des éléments finis des modèles FECVT accouplée avec les propriétés de la paroi cellulaire. La forme du pétiole en coupe transversale  au niveau structural ensemble avec les propriétés des tissus sont considérées afin de déterminer sa raideur  en flexion et en torsion, qui sont également validés expérimentalement pour le pétiole de la rhubarbe. Ce modèle mécanique à échelles multiples éclaircira le rôle de chaque niveau de la hiérarchie structurelle pour déterminer la souplesse structurelle du pétiole.    Une méthode de modélisation hiérarchique qui capture les propriétés structurelles globales d'un pétiole a été introduite dans cette thèse. Notamment, le modèle établit une relation entre les propriétés du micro et macro niveaux structuraux en utilisant un procédé mécanique adapté, à échelles multiples. Par conséquent, cette recherche peut combler le vide entre la biologie végétale et le génie afin de développer de nouveaux matériaux et des structures bio-inspirées. Cette recherche peut également aider à développer les connaissances fondamentales de la biomécanique cellulaire des plantes et son impact sur la mécanique macroscopique des tiges et des pétioles avec l'objectif final de transférer ces connaissances pour le traitement et la conception des structures et matériaux souples de génie.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>    A plant is a natural hierarchical structure, which exhibits remarkable mechanical properties. The macro (scale) mechanical properties of a plant are the cumulative outcome of the structural properties of its preceding level of structural hierarchy. To develop engineering structures inspired by a plant and its organs, a comprehensive characterization of its mechanical properties exhibited at multiple hierarchical orders is essential to mimic such structures for engineering application.    This thesis presents a set of theoretical and computational models at various orders of the structural hierarchy to capture the overall structural properties of a plant petiole. The modeling method is framed within a multiscale mechanics framework, which is essential for any structure displaying hierarchical orders of organization. The macro structural properties, i.e. flexural and torsional stiffness, of a plant petiole are obtained by correlating cell wall construction, tissue microstructure, and structural shape morphology. The stiffness of the cell wall is modeled using the theory of a fiber reinforced composite material. The microarchitecture of the constituent tissues that govern the properties of the petiole are modeled with a novel algorithm – finite edge centroidal Voronoi tessellation (FECVT) - that is capable to provide a realistic visualization of  the tissue. The effective stiffness properties of the constituent tissues are obtained via finite element analysis of the FECVT models coupled with cell wall properties. With the properties of the tissues, the cross-sectional shape of the petiole at the structural level is considered to determine its flexural and torsional stiffness, which are also validated experimentally for rhubarb petiole. This multiscale mechanical model will elucidate the role of each order of structural hierarchy to determine the structural compliance of the petiole.     A hierarchical modeling approach that captures the overall structural properties of a petiole has been introduced in this thesis. In particular, the model develops a relationship between the micro and macrostructural properties using a tailored multiscale mechanics approach. Therefore, this research can bridge the gap between plant biology and engineering to develop novel bio-inspired material and structures. This research can also help to develop fundamental knowledge of plant cellular bio-mechanics and its impact on the macroscopic mechanics of stems and petioles with the end goal of transferring this knowledge to the processing and design of compliant engineering structures and materials.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alejandro D. Rey</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Damiano Pasini</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq11x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408137h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b199p"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The taphonomy and subsistence strategies from the Middle Stone Age occupation at Sibudu Cave, South Africa</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Collins, Benjamin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examined the faunal assemblage from Sibudu Cave, a final Middle Stone Age site in KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa.  A two-part hierarchical method was employed, with the assemblage's taphonomy being first assessed, followed by a zooarchaeological interpretation of the hunting strategies used by Sibudu's final Middle Stone Age occupants.  These data and the other archaeological information from the final Middle Stone Age occupation were then compared with other sites from similar temporal and geographic contexts to contribute to a broader regional interpretation of the archaeology from this period and the Middle-to-Later Stone Age transition.  The taphonomic study demonstrated that humans were the primary agents in the accumulation of the faunal assemblage, and that the faunal materials were heavily burned and fragmented as a result of human activity.  Based on the geoarchaeology and the similarity of this assemblage to those from previous occupations, the burning and fragmentation are most parsimoniously interpreted as site maintenance and cleaning behaviours.  Site maintenance and cleaning by discarding refuse into fires and hearth features is also posited for earlier occupations at Sibudu, suggesting behavioural continuity through time.  The zooarchaeological analysis identified a bimodal focus on Size 1 and Size 3 ungulates.  A comparison of the ethology for the species identified in the assemblage shows that the Size 1 ungulates are generally solitary and prefer closed, wooded habitats close to the site.  In contrast, the Size 3 ungulates are generally gregarious and prefer more open savanna habitats further away from the site.  This pattern was compared against the ethnographic record, and is posited to demonstrate two different, but complementary hunting strategies.  Small groups of men are suggested to have hunted the larger Size 3 ungulates, while mixed groups of men, women and children are suggested to have hunted the Size 1 ungulates.  To place Sibudu's final Middle Stone Age occupation within its regional and temporal context, it was compared to roughly contemporaneous occupations from Umhlatuzana Rockshelter and Border Cave.  This comparison identifies technological similarities between Umhlatuzana and Sibudu, but differences in both technology and hunting strategies between Sibudu and Border Cave, with the latter being identified as Later Stone Age.  These differences emphasise the complex nature of the Middle-to-Later Stone Age transition within this region, and may demonstrate a potential cultural boundary between the northern and southern parts of KwaZulu-Natal.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette étude prends comme sujet l'assemblage faunique grotte Sibudu Cave, un site du paléolithique moyen-finale au KwaZulu-Natal, en Afrique du Sud. Une méthode en deux parties hiérarchique est utilisé: premièrement l'assemblage de la taphonomie est évaluée, suivie d'une interprétation archéozoologique des stratégies de chasse utilisés pendant le paléolithique moyen-finale  par les occupants de Sibudu. Ces données et les autres informations archéologiques de l'occupation du paléolithique moyen-finale sont ensuite comparé avec d'autres sites de contextes temporels et géographiques semblables afin de contribuer à une interprétation plus régional de l'archéologie de cette période de transition et le paléolithique moyen-finale.L'étude taphonomique démontre que les humains étaient les principaux agents de l'accumulation de l'assemblage faunique, et que les matériaux fauniques ont été fortement brûlé et fragmentée parl'activité humaine. Basé sur la géoarchéologie et sur la ressemblance de cet assemblage à ceux des occupations antérieures, la combustion et la fragmentation sont les plus parcimonieusement interprété comme  les résultats de l'entretien du site et du nettoyage. Cette tendance à nettoyer le site en brûlant les déchets dans des feux et des foyers caractérise aussi les périodes d'occupation antérieures à Sibuduce qui suggère une continuité de comportement dans le temps sur ce site. L'analyse archéozoologique identifie un accent bimodale sur les ongulés des groupes de grandeur 1 et 3. Une comparaison éthologique des espèces identifiées dans l'assemblage montre que les ongulés du groupe 1 on des habitudes généralement solitaires et préfèrent les milieux boisés clos, à proximité du site. En revanche, ongulés du groupe 3 sont généralement plus sociables et préfèrent les environnements de savane plus ouverts qui sont plus loin du site. Ce modèle est comparé à la documentation ethnographique, et il est proposé que ça démontre deux stratégies de chasse qui sont différentes, mais complémentaires. Il est proposé que des pettits groupes exclusivement males ont chassé les ongulés de grand taille du groupe 3, tandis que des groupes mixtes d'hommes, de femmes et d'enfants sont suggérées pour avoir chassé les ongulés plus petits du groupe 1.Pour placer la période d'occupation de la grotte Sibudu pendant le paléolithique moyen-finaledans un contexte régional et temporel, il est comparé à des occupations de site à peu près contemporaine à Umhlatuzana Rockshelter et la grotte Border Cave. Cette comparaison met en évidence les technologies comparables de Umhlatuzana et Sibudu, mais aussi les différences dans la technologie et les stratégies de chasse de Sibudu et Border Cave, ce dernier un occupation de site du période paléolithique finale.. Ces différences soulignent la nature complexe de la transition entre le paléolithique moyen et le paléolithique finale dans cette région, et peuvent peut-être montrer une frontière culturel entre les régions nord et sud du KwaZulu-Natal.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andre Costopoulos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w8038.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b199p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Anthropology Archaeology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741v840"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A system biology approach to uncover the regulatory and effector hubs of Rac-family GTPases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Qi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Rho-family proteins are a major branch of the Ras superfamily of small GTPases. These proteins can be further subdivided into six subfamilies according to primary amino acid sequence identity, structural motifs and biological function: Rho, Cdc42, Rac, RhoBTB, RhoT and Rnd subfamily. Rho-family proteins are "molecular switches" and cycle between GDP-bound "inactive" state and GTP-bound "active" state by regulation of guanine nucleotide exchange factors (GEFs) and GTPases-activating proteins (GAPs). Rho GTPases have a large collection of effectors and are involved in numerous cellular and physiological processes, such as cytoskeletal reorganization, microtubule dynamics, cell polarity, gene expression and cell cycle progression. However, it is poorly understood how Rho GTPases select specific effectors for diverse physiologic functions. We hypothesize that the specificity of effector choice is dictated by the individual GEF or by scaffold proteins binding either the GEF or the Rho proteins. To test this hypothesis, I used a system biology approach which will determine the complete interactome of the Rac GTPases (Rac1, Rac2, Rac3, and RhoG) in their active and inactive conformation. Through this method, we tried to discover new Rac effectors, possible molecular scaffolds and the Rac:GEF and Rac:GAP specificity.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les protéines de la famille Rho forment une branche majeure de la superfamille des petites GTPases Ras. Ces protéines peuvent être subdivisées en six sous-familles selon leur identité de séquence d'acides aminés primaires, leur motifs structuraux et leur fonction biologique, soient les sous-familles: Rho, Cdc42, Rac, RhoBTB, RhoT et Rnd. Les petites GTPases agissent comme des "interrupteurs moléculaires" soit qu'elles vont osciller entre un état "inactif" (GTPase-GDP) et un état "actif" (GTPase-GTP), et ce cycle est régulé par des facteurs d'échange de nucléotides guanine (GEFs) et des protéines activatrices de GTPases (GAPs). Les GTPases Rho ont une multitude d'effecteurs et elles sont impliquées dans de nombreux processus cellulaires et physiologiques, tels que la réorganisation du cytosquelette, la dynamique des microtubules, la polarité cellulaire, l'expression génique et la progression du cycle cellulaire. Cependant, il est encore mal compris comment les GTPases Rho sélectionnent des effecteurs spécifiques pour les différentes fonctions physiologiques. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que le choix de l'effecteur est dictée par la GEF impliquée ou par une protéine d'échafaudage qui est soit liée à la GEF ou à la GTPase. Pour tester cette hypothèse, j'ai utilisé une approche de la biologie des systèmes qui déterminera l'interactome complet des GTPases Rac (Rac1, Rac2, RAC3 et RhoG) dans leur conformation active et inactive. Grâce à cette méthode, nous avons essayé de découvrir des nouveaux effecteurs de Rac, des protéines d'échafaudage, ainsi que des GEFs et des GAPs spécifiques pour Rac.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean-Francois Cote</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z8467.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741v840</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xw29h"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implication of the dopamine D2 receptor in hippocampal dependent memory tasks: spatial, recognition and emotional memory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sagheby, Seyedeh Sara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since all Antipsychotics have the feature to block D2 receptor and it is known that D2 receptor is implicated in mediating a great range of neuronal functions, it is extremely important to understand all the physiological aspects of these antipsychotics, specifically their effects on learning and memory functions. Therefore we planned to study the implication of D2 receptor in Hippocampal dependent memory tasks such as recognition, spatial and emotional memory by using two different methods of D2 receptor manipulation; a genetic model (D2 knock-out mice) and a pharmacological model (using sulpiride as a D2 antagonist), we studied the implication of the D2 receptor in different learning and memory paradigm. The behavioral tests that were used for this purpose included Morris Water-maze (both cued and spatial versions), Barnes maze, fear conditioning and object recognition test. In order to better interpret our results from the learning and memory tests, we also did complementary experiments on anxiety, exploration and locomotor activity in our animal models. We were able to show that both D2 knockout mice and animals injected with sulpiride show significant deficits in learning and recognition, spatial and emotional memory tasks.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Tous les antipsychotiques ont la particularité de bloquer les récepteurs D2 de la dopamine, récepteur qui est impliqué dans une grande variété de fonctions neuronales. Il est donc essentiel de comprendre toutes les conséquences physiologiques liées aux effets des antipsychotiques, en particulier leurs effets sur les fonctions d'apprentissage et de mémoire. Nous avons donc étudié l'implication des récepteurs D2 dans la mémoire dépendante de l'hippocampe, comme la reconnaissance d'objet et la mémoire spatiale et émotionnelle, à l'aide de deux méthodes différentes de manipulation du récepteur D2, un modèle génétique (souris knock-out D2) et un modèle pharmacologique (en utilisant le sulpiride, un antagoniste D2). Les tests comportementaux qui ont été utilisés à cet effet sont le « Morris Water-maze » (dans ses deux versions indicées et spatiales), le labyrinthe de Barnes, le conditionnement par la peur et le test de reconnaissance d'objets. Afin de mieux interpréter les résultats des tests d'apprentissage et de mémoire, nous avons également fait des expériences complémentaires pour évaluer le niveau d'anxiété, d'exploration et de locomotion dans nos modèles animaux. Nous avons montré que les souris D2 knock-out et les animaux injectés avec le sulpiride montrent des déficits significatifs d'apprentissage et de reconnaissance des objecs, de mémoire spatiale et mémoire émotionnelle.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruno Giros</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67317274.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw29h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290d85x"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Employment of Ir/Ti-oxide coatings and electrochemical polishing of a 316L stainless steel surface for the enhancement of biocompatibility of coronary stents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Habibzadeh, Sajjad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Endoprothèses vasculaires métalliques sont des dispositifs médicaux (implantes) qui peuvent fournir des échafaudages endovasculaire afin de soulager une obstruction vasculaire et minimiser le risque d'infarctus du myocarde (crise cardiaque). Cependant, les prothèses actuels sont considérés d'offrir mauvais bio/hémocompatibilité, car leur surface provoque une réaction tissulaire indésirable lors de l'implantation.Dans la plupart des cas, cela se traduit par une resténose intra-prothèses (re-blocage des vaisseaux sanguins au niveau du site d'implantation). Alors, diverses caractéristiques de surface des prothèses jouent un rôle déterminant dans leur biocompatibilité et subséquemment leur fonctionnalité et sécurité. Par conséquent, afin d'augmenter la bio/hémocompatibilité de prothèses s, une méthode de modification de surface appropriée peut être utilisée pour ajuster la texture de la surface du stprothèses et les propriétés physico-chimiques de manière à favoriser les interactions cellulaires/surface souhaitables et rendre la surface des prothèses plus électrochimique stable (résistant à la corrosion).Le but de ce travail était d'étudier la possibilité d'augmenter un bio/hémocompatibilité d'une surface métallique en utilisant deux approches de modification de surface: (i) la formation de revêtements IrxTi1-x-oxyde (x = 0, 0,2, 0,4, 0,6, 0.8 et 1) sur un substrat de Ti et sur une base commerciale acier inoxydable 316L (316L-SS) prothèses coronariens et (ii) le polissage électrochimique d'une surface 316L-SS. La première approche a également été utilisée dans le but d'augmenter la radio-opacité des prothèses (visibilité). Des techniques électrochimiques et surface-caractérisation ont été utilisées pour étudier la topographie/morphologie de la surface, la structure et la composition chimique des revêtements Ir/Ti-oxyde, ainsi que leurs propriétés électrochimiques et des radio-opacité. Ces propriétés ont été trouvés fortement dépendent de la composition de revêtement. Tous les revêtements ont été jugées électrochimiquement stables dans les conditions expérimentales utilisées dans la recherche. 316L-SS prothèses coronaires modifiés par des revêtements Ir/Ti-oxyde ont été trouvés à être plus radio-opaque que celui sans revêtements 316L-SS prothèses. Le revêtement Ir0.4Ti0.6-oxyde a été montré pour être le plus uniforme, résistant à la corrosion et radio-opaque. Spectrométrie photoélectron du rayon-X résultats de spectroscopie de photoélectrons ont révélé que les films d'oxyde du EP ont été caractérisées par une proportion beaucoup plus élevé atomique Cr/Fe et d'épaisseur de film, par rapport au film d'oxyde passif naturellement développée formée sur la surface non traitée 316L-SS. Un particulièrement enrichissement élevé avec des espèces Cr a été enregistré à la couche la plus externe des films d'oxyde EP. En raison de l'augmentation de l'épaisseur du film d'oxyde et enrichissement relatif Cr, les surfaces 316-SS EP-traités offert une amélioration notable de la résistance à la corrosion générale et piqûres. L'influence des méthodes de modification de surface utilisés sur la bio/hémocompatibilité a été étudiée. Ceci a été implémenté en examinant l'interaction des plaquettes, des cellules endothéliales (EC) et les cellules musculaires lisses (SMC) avec les surfaces modifiées. Les expériences sur l'interaction entre la cellule et la surface ont révélé un plus grand ratio de fixation EC/SMC pour Ir0.2Ti0.8-oxyde, Ir0.4Ti0.6-oxyde et les trois surfaces du EP, lorsque en comparant avec la contrôle 316L-SS. Ceci. Ainsi, les surfaces modifiées permettront une endothélialisation plus rapide, ce qui les rend potentiellement supérieure pour les applications de prothèses coronaire.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Metallic cardiovascular stents are medical devices (implants) that can provide endovascular scaffolding in order to relieve a vascular obstruction and minimize the risk of myocardial infarction (heart attack). However, current stents are considered to offer poor bio/hemocompatibility, since their surface provokes undesirable tissue reaction upon implantation. In most cases, this results in in-stent restenosis (re-blocking of the blood vessel at the implantation site). Thus, various surface characteristics of stents play a determinant role in their bio/hemocompatibility, and hence their functionality and safety. Therefore, in order to increase the bio/hemocompatibility of stents, an appropriate surface-modification method can be employed to tune the stent's surface texture and physico-chemical properties in a way to promote desirable cell/platelet-surface interactions and render the stent surface more electrochemically stable (corrosion resistant). The aim of this work was to investigate a possibility of increasing a bio/hemocompatibility of a metal surface by employing two surface-modification approaches: (i) formation of IrxTi1-x-oxide coatings (x=0, 0.2, 0.4, 0.6, 0.8 and 1) on a Ti substrate and on a commercial 316L stainless steel (316L-SS) coronary stent and (ii) electrochemical polishing of a 316L-SS surface. The former approach was also employed with the aim of increasing the stent's radiopacity (visibility). Electrochemical and surface-characterization results showed that the physic-chemical properties were highly depended on the coating composition. All the coatings were found to be electrochemically stable (corrosion resistant) under experimental conditions employed in the research. 316L-SS coronary stents modified by Ir/Ti-oxide coatings were found to be more radiopaque than the bare (naked) 316L-SS stent. The Ir0.4Ti0.6-oxide coating showed to be the most uniform, corrosion resistant and radiopaque. Electrochemical polishing (EP) of a 316L-SS surface in an electrolyte of a new chemical composition was investigated at different cell voltages. The influence of the EP cell voltage on the topographical/morphological and physico-chemical properties of resulting passive oxide films formed on the surface was studied. A particularly high enrichment with Cr species was recorded at the outermost layer of the EP oxide films. As a result of the increase in the oxide film thickness and relative Cr enrichment, the EP-treated 316L-SS surfaces offered a notable improvement in general and pitting corrosion resistance. The influence of the employed surface-modification methods on the resulting bio/hemocompatibility was further investigated. This was implemented by examining the interaction of platelets, endothelial cells (ECs) and smooth muscle cells (SMCs) with the modified surfaces. A significant decrease in platelet adhesion and activation was obtained on Ir0.2Ti0.8-oxide and Ir0.4Ti0.6-oxide coatings (among Ir/Ti-oxide surfaces) and on the surfaces electrochemically polished at the cell voltages of 4 and 10 V (among electropolished surfaces), rendering the surfaces more blood compatible, in comparison to the control (316L-SS). Moreover, ECs and SMCs showed a desirable response to the modified surfaces (the Ir/Ti-oxide coated and the electropolished surfaces). The cell/surface interaction experiments revealed a a higher affinity of ECs towards attachment to the modified surfaces, relative to the attachment of SMCs. Hence, the modified surfaces would enable faster endothelialization, rendering them potentially superior for coronary stenting applications.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dominique Shum-Tim</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Sasha Omanovic</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p362q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290d85x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g588s"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Instance optimality in infinite-dimensional compressed sensing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al Balushi, Ibrahim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis provides a thorough literature review of the newly founded theory of compressed sensing (CS), developed by Cand`es and his collaborators. The majority of the documented developments remain in the treatment of perfectly sparse signals in the finite dimensional setting. This was extended to the treatment of nearly sparse (compressible) signals in infinite-dimensions by Adcock and Hansen. A novel approach in analyzing the performance of CS, in the finite-dimensional setting, was developed by Cohen, Dahmen and DeVore where they study the effectiveness of CS. This is carried by comparing it to the well established theory of best k-term approximation, i.e in terms of how well CS recovers non-sparse vectors which can be well approximated by sparse vectors. The contribution of this thesis extends DeVore and his collaborators instance optimality results for CS to infinite dimensions by following a similar construction carried by Adcock and Hansen. This will be made by appealing to the truncation techniques devised by Adcock and Hansen in their development of the generalized sampling theory, and by appealing to an intermediate result established by Candès and Plan regarding the restricted isometry property (RIP).</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse présente une minutieuse revue de la littérature portant sur l’acquisition comprimée (CS), une théorie récemment développée par Candès et ses collaborateurs. La majorité des travaux qui en découlent se focalise sur les signaux parfaitement parcimonieux en un nombre fini de dimensions. Ces résultats ont été étendus au cas des signaux (compressibles) quasi-parcimonieux dans les espaces de dimension infinie par Adcock et Hansen. Une nouvelle approche permettant d'analyser la performance de la CS en un nombre de dimension finie a été proposée par Cohen, Dahmen et DeVore. Celle-ci étudie l'efficacité de la CS en comparant cette méthode à la très reconnue théorie des approximations par les k meilleurs termes; c'est-à-dire en étudiant la capacité de la CS à recouvrer des vecteurs non-parcimonieux pouvant eux-mêmes être approximés par des vecteurs parcimonieux. La contribution de cette thèse étend les résultats de DeVore et de ses collaborateurs sur l'optimalité exemplaire de la CS au cas des espaces de dimension infinie, en suivant une construction similaire à celle employée par Adcock et Hansen. À cette fin, les techniques de troncation décrites par Adcock et Hansen dans leur développement de la théorie de l'échantillonage général seront utilisées, tout comme un résultat intermédiaire établi par Cand`es et Plan portant sur la Propriété Isométrique Restreinte (RIP).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gantumur Tsogtgerel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924f997.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g588s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn11f"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Polypropylene (PP) nanocomposites incorporating nanocrystalline cellulose (NCC)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khoshkava, Vahid</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main objective of this dissertation is to evaluate the feasibility of preparation of well dispersed polypropylene (PP)/nanocrystalline cellulose (NCC) nanocomposites by melt processing. There has been growing interest in using NCC as reinforcement in polymer systems because of its interesting properties and the abundant and renewable sources of cellulose. Preparation of polymer nanocomposites incorporating NCC has been mainly carried out using solution or water-assisted mixing. Only few attempts have been made to prepare it using melt mixing. Polypropylene (PP) is a commodity polymer with wide application in the automotive, pharmaceutical and packaging industries. In the first phase of this project, physical properties (shape, size and surface energy) of NCC are evaluated. An equation was introduced to estimate the dispersion energy of NCC in polymer matrices based on room and high temperature surface energy data. The influence of NCC surface modification on its interaction with a polar polymer (polylactic acid (PLA)) and non-polar polymer (PP) was evaluated.In the second phase of this project, the relationship between NCC agglomerate structure and its dispersion in polymer matrices is considered. The effect of various drying techniques on NCC agglomerate structure is investigated. It was found that spray drying and freeze drying of NCC aqueous suspensions result in dense and compact NCC aggregates. On the other hand, spray freeze drying of NCC aqueous suspensions could form agglomerates with more open or porous structures. The structure of the agglomerates depends on the initial concentration of the NCC aqueous suspension before spray freeze drying. In the low concentration regime (below ca. 2 wt.%), a web-like structure of inter-connected nano-scale fibers is formed. On the other hand, micron sized spherical-foam structure particles are formed at higher concentration (ca. 2 wt.% and above). The specific surface area of NCC powder produced using spray freeze drying increased by more than 30 times.Polypropylene nanocomposites containing spray dried NCC, freeze dried NCC, and spray freeze dried NCC (NCCSFD) were prepared in an internal batch mixer. Polarized light microscopy (PLM) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) showed better dispersion of NCCSFD particles. The results of dynamic mechanical analysis (DMA) and tensile tests showed a considerable improvement in modulus and tensile strength of samples containing NCCSFD particles. Rheological measurements, including linear and non-linear viscoelastic tests, were performed on PP/NCC samples. Small amplitude oscillatory (SAOS) tests showed a large impact of NCCSFD incorporation on rheological characteristics of PP samples. Steady shear results revealed strong shear thinning and a yield stress for PP samples containing NCCSFD particles. The magnitude of yield stress and the degree of shear thinning increased with NCCSFD concentration. The effects of NCC structure (web-like and spherical-foam structure) on rheological properties were examined.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le principal objectif de cette dissertation consiste à évaluer la faisabilité de la préparation de polypropylène bien dispersé (PP) / la cellulose nanocristalline du (NCC) nanocomposites par traitement par fusion. Il ya un intérêt croissant à utiliser du (NCC) comme renforcement dans les systèmes de polymère à cause de ses propriétés intéressantes et les sources de cellulose abondante et renouvelable. La préparation de nanocomposites polymères incorporant du NCC a été principalement effectuée en utilisant une solution ou un mélange d'eau-assistée. Seulement quelques essais ont été faites à préparer en utilisant un mélange à l'état de fondre. Le polypropylène (PP) est un polymère produit à de larges applications dans l'industrie de l'automobile, produits pharmaceutiques et les industries d'emballage.Dans la première phase de ce projet, les propriétés physiques (forme, taille et d'énergie de surface) du NCC sont évaluées. Une équation a été présentée pour estimer l'énergie de la dispersion du NCC dans les matrices à base de polymère dans une la pièce et les données d'énergie de surface à haute température. L'influence de la modification de surface du NCC et son interaction avec un polymère polaire (acide polylactique (PLA)) et un polymère non polaire (PP) a été évaluée.Dans la deuxième phase de ce projet, la relation entre la structure d'agglomérat du NCC et sa dispersion dans des matrices de polymère est considérée. L'effet des diverses techniques de séchage sur la structure des agglomérats du NCC est examiné. On a constaté que séchage par pulvérisation et par lyophilisation du NCC, les suspensions aqueuses se traduisent dans les agrégats du NCC denses et compactes. D'autre part, la pulvérisation par lyophilisation des suspensions aqueuses du NCC pourrait former des agglomérats ou des structures poreuses plus ouvertes. La structure des agglomérats dépend de la concentration initiale de la suspension aqueuse du NCC avant la pulvérisation par lyophilisation. Dans le régime à faible concentration (en dessous de2%environ en poids), une structure en forme de bande de fibres interconnectée à l'échelle nanométrique est formée. D'autre part, le micron dimensionné des particules de structure sphérique est formé à une concentration plus élevée (ca. 2 wt.% et au-dessus). La surface spécifique de la poudre du NCC produite en utilisant le séchage par atomisation ou lyophilisation a progressé de plus de 30 fois. Les nanocomposites contenant du polypropylène séché par pulvérisation du NCC,  et  lyophilisés à froid du NCC (NCCSFD) ont été préparé dans un malaxeur discontinu interne. La microscopie en lumière polarisée (PLM) et la microscopie électronique à balayage (SEM) ont montré une meilleure dispersion des particules de NCCSFD. Les résultats de l'analyse mécanique dynamique (DMA) des tests de traction ont démontré une amélioration considérable de modules de résistance à la traction des échantillons contenant des particules de NCCSFD. Des mesures rhéologiques, y compris les tests de viscoélasticité linéaire et non linéaire, ont été effectuées sur des prélèvements des PP/NCC. De petits tests oscillatoires d'amplitude (SAOS) ont montré un impact considérable d'incorporation de NCCSFD sur les caractéristiques rhéologiques des échantillons de PP. Des résultats réguliers de cisaille ont révélé une forte fluidification par cisaillement et une limite d'élasticité pour les échantillons de PP contenant des particules de NCCSFD. La magnitude de la limite de stress et le degré de rhéofluidification a augmenté avec la concentration de NCCSFD. Les effets de la structure du NCC (sous forme de bande et la structure en mousse sphérique) sur les propriétés rhéologiques ont été examinés.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dimitrios Berk</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Musa R. Kamal</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773z951.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn11f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cx505"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Property and prosperity: examing contemporary private property ownership in light of increased oil and gas development in the United States</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Phillips, Sara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The concept of private property has played an important role within American history and culture. For many of the country's founding statesmen, private property was heralded as the ultimate path to freedom, financial independence, and prosperity. The role of the private landowner has evolved dramatically over the last two centuries or so, and private property has now become an important component of US states' increased oil and gas development efforts. As demand for the resources continues to rise, the US has experienced an unprecedented boom in oil and gas development, on both public and private lands. In the wake of increased development activity, the demand for greater land conservation measures has also escalated. Private property plays an integral role in US environmental conservation efforts and a growing number of landowners now seek enduring land conservation and protection.This thesis considers the role of private property in light of the arguably equally important state interests of oil and gas resource development and environmental conservation. Utilizing professors Gregory Alexander and Eduardo Peñalver's human flourishing model of the social obligation norm, I argue that private property ownership consists of two primary overarching social obligations: resource development and land conservation. Looking to the state of Colorado as a case study, I examine the various traits inherent in private land ownership within the context of resource development, demonstrating that Colorado has, to its detriment, over-emphasized the obligation of resource development while neglecting other equally important environmental considerations. Throughout the thesis, I reveal how Colorado's substandard regulatory practices have disempowered the state's private landowners, disincentivized land conservation efforts, and effectively undermined the human flourishing model of private property ownership. I therefore argue for a repositioning of the state's interests, to provide greater protection to Colorado's private landowners while also restoring balance and harmony to the social objectives of environmental preservation, and conservation and development of oil and gas resources.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le concept de propriété privée a joué un rôle important dans l'histoire et la culture Américaine. Pour beaucoup des pères fondateurs du pays, la propriété privée était considérée comme la voie ultime menant à la liberté, l'indépendance financière et la prospérité. Le rôle du propriétaire privé a considérablement évolué au cours des deux derniers siècles environ, et la propriété privée est devenue, pour les états américains, une composante importante de leur développement minier et gazier. Du fait de l'augmentation des besoins en ressources, les États-Unis ont connu un essor sans précédent de l'exploitation minière, aussi bien sur les terrains publics que privés. Au fur et à mesure du développement grandissant de l'activité minière, les exigences d'accroissement des mesures protectrices en matière de conservation des sols ont également augmenté. La propriété privée joue un rôle essentiel dans les efforts des États-Unis en matière de protection environnementale et un nombre croissant de propriétaires cherchent dorénavant une conservation et une préservation durables des terres.Cette thèse étudie le rôle de la propriété privée au regard des intérêts étatiques, sans doute aussi importants, en matière de développement des ressources gazières et pétrolières et de préservation de l'environnement. Utilisant le modèle de l'épanouissement de l'être humain fondé sur la théorie de la contrainte sociale, élaboré par les professeurs Gregory Alexander et Eduardo Peñalver, je soutiens que la propriété privée se compose de deux contraintes sociales principales : le développement des ressources et la préservation des terres. Utilisant l'état du Colorado comme cas d'étude, j'examine les différents attributs inhérents à la propriété privée des terres dans le cadre du développement des ressources, démontrant ainsi que le Colorado a, à son détriment, excessivement privilégié le développement des ressources par rapport aux autres considérations environnementales tout aussi importantes. Tout au long de la thèse, je m'attache à exposer comment les lacunes des normes règlementaires édictées par l'état du Colorado ont conduit à désavantager les propriétaires privés de l'état, décourager les initiatives en matière de préservation des sols et ont finalement desservi le modèle d'épanouissement de l'être humain par la propriété privée. J'ai donc argumenté en faveur d'un repositionnement des intérêts de l'état, afin d'offrir une meilleure protection aux propriétaires privés du Colorado, tout en rétablissant l'équilibre et l'harmonie entre les objectifs sociétaux de préservation et conservation de l'environnement et de développement des ressources pétrolières et gazières.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jaye Dana Ellis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838383q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx505</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f935q"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Uninvited guests: NGOs, «amicus curiae briefs», and the environment in the international investment regime</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mikadze, Kirsten</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Environmental regulation is often at the heart of investment treaty arbitration. As the international investment regime, bolstered by the powerful process of investor-state dispute settlement (ISDS), continues to expand into and gain influence in distant corners of domestic environment governance, the pressure points created where the investment regime comes into conflict with environmental regulation have also multiplied. These collisions between the investment regime and the environment have generated public concern. However, the regime has remained seemingly unreceptive to these concerns and has hesitated to embrace participation by outside actors—such as non-governmental organizations (NGOs)—who would see such concerns accounted for in ISDS. This study explores this complicated nexus between the investment regime, the environment, and NGOs. More specifically, it lays bare the relationship between the investment regime and its environmental "others," focusing on the role of NGOs, through the use of amicus curiae briefs in ISDS, in both shaping (and compelling) these interactions and encouraging greater openness and responsiveness in the regime to environmental issues. Ultimately, a discursive analysis of the NGO amicus curiae briefs submitted in environment-investment disputes and the responses to them from the regime's decision makers reveals that through this practice, NGOs have a crucial role in transforming the regime. However, this potential is currently underdeveloped and hampered by the very closed-off nature of the regime that these actors seek to overcome. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La réglementation environnementale est souvent au cœur de l'arbitrage des traités d'investissement. Comme le régime d'investissement international, soutenu par le puissant processus de l'arbitrage de l'investissment, continue de gagner de l'influence dans la gouvernance de l'environnement domestique, les points de pression créés lorsque le régime d'investissement entre en conflit avec la réglementation environnementale ont également multiplié. Ces collisions entre le régime et l'environnement ont suscité l'inquiétude du public. Toutefois, le régime d'investissement reste peu réceptif à ces préoccupations et hésite à accepter la participation des acteurs extérieurs, tels que les organisations non gouvernementales (ONG), qui auraient de telles préoccupations prises en compte dans l'arbitrage des traités d'investissement.Cette étude explore ce lien complexe entre le régime de l'investissement, l'environnement, et les ONG. Plus précisément, il examine la relation entre le régime d'investissement et ses « autres » environnementaux, mettant l'accent sur le rôle des ONG comme amicus curiae dans ISDS, à la fois dans l'élaboration ces interactions et d'encourager une plus grande ouverture et réactivité dans le régime aux questions environnementales. En fin de compte, une analyse discursive des mémoires amicus curiae soumis par les ONG dans les litiges environnementeux et les réponses des décideurs du régime révéle que les ONG ont un rôle critique dans ce processus de transformation du régime. Cependant, ce potentiel est actuellement sous-développé et entravé par la nature fermé du régime. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jaye Dana Ellis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb62k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f935q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128f30p"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Semi-synthesis of ubiquitinated androgen receptor peptides using an expressed protein ligation system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mokhtar, Shaza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Abrégé:Le gène de 90-kb du récepteur androgène (AR) est localisé au locus Xq11-12 et possède huit exons codant pour une protéine d'environ 919 acides aminés. L'exon 1 code pour le domaine transactivationnel, les exons 2 et 3 codent pour le domaine de liaison à l'ADN, et les exons 4 à 8 codent pour le domaine de liaison au ligand. La protéine du AR, un récepteur nucléaire appartenant à la famille des récepteurs hormonaux stéroïdiens/thyroïdiens, agit primordialement en tant que facteur transcriptionnel se liant à l'ADN pour réguler l'expression génique. Le AR possède également un rôle dans le développement du phénotype masculin: en effet, le AR cytoplasmique est activé en se liant aux hormones testostérone ou dihydrotestostérone avant de se translocaliser au noyau.L'amyotrophie bulbo-spinale (SBMA-Spinal and Bulbar Muscular Atrophy), aussi connue sous le nom de maladie de Kennedy, est une maladie neurodégénérative liée au chromosome X récessif. La cause de la SBMA est une expansion du triplet CAG répété, lequel code pour une glutamine (Gln,Q), dans l'exon 1 du gène AR. Ainsi, la SBMA est considérée comme étant un désordre d'expansion polyglutaminique (poly-Gln). Chez l'homme non-affecté, on retrouve 9-33 répétitions CAG codant pour la Gln, alors que l'homme qui hérite plus de 37 répétitions CAG développera la SBMA. Le gain de fonction toxique du AR caractérisant la SBMA se traduit par: une faiblesse musculaire à progression lente, une atrophie de la langue, des fasciculations des muscles bulbaires, faciaux et limbiques et enfin par des crampes musculaires. Une perte de fonction du AR est liée à l'élargissement de la poitrine et à la fertilité réduite.Le système ubiquitine-protéasome (UPS), responsable dans la dégradation protéique, joue un rôle important dans les cellules neurales chez les patients atteints de la SBMA. Les composantes de l'UPS se trouvent dans les aggrégats protéiques de l'expansion poly-Gln dans ces cellules. C'est la raison pour laquelle des études précédentes ont suggéré que l'UPS est affaibli dans la SBMA. D'autres études antérieures suggèrent que les peptides 0QAR et 20QAR peuvent être dégradés par l'UPS, cependant le peptide 50QAR semble inhiber la dégradation par lUPS de certaines protéines spécifiques. L'hypothèse veut que ces mutants AR responsables de la SBMA peuvent s'accumuler dans la cellule et causer la maladie en s'évadant de la dégradation UPS. Le but premier de ce projet était de développer un système d'ubiquitination du AR en appliquant le système de ligation des protéines exprimées (expressed protein ligation-EPL). Afin de prouver cette hypothèse, quelques buts intermédiaires ont été atteints. Les fragments du AR (0Q, 20Q, et 50Q), amplifiés par PCR, ont été clonés dans le vecteur pTWIN2 et les clones ont été analysés sur gels d'électrophorèse suite aux digestions par enzymes de restriction. De plus, les fragments 0QAR, 20QAR et 50QAR ainsi que les protéines de fusion de l'ubiquitine humaine (HUB) ont été purifiés à l'aide de billes de chitine et clivés par l'acide mercapto-2-éthanesulfonique (MESNA).Les peptides 0QAR, 20QAR et 50QAR ont été unis par ligation au peptide de fusion H2B doté d'un tag HA en se servant du système EPL. Ainsi, nous avons développé avec succès des outils permettant d'explorer l'ubiquitination du AR en utilisant les systèmes EPL in vitro. Des expériences à l'avenir viseront à lier par ligation la protéine HUB à un peptide, en utilisant la méthode EPL et ensuite faire la ligation du peptide ubiquitiné aux trois différents peptides AR. Ces derniers seront ajoutés aux protéasomes actifs pour explorer l'implication de l'UPS dans la pathogénèse de la SBMA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Abstract:The 90-kb androgen receptor (AR) gene is located at locus Xq11-12 and has eight exons that encode a protein of about 919 amino acids. Exon 1 encodes the transactivational domain, exons 2 and 3 encode the DNA-binding domain, and exons 4 through 8 encode the ligand-binding domain. The AR protein, a nuclear receptor that belongs to the steroid/thyroid hormone receptor family, functions primarily as a DNA-binding transcription factor to regulate gene expression. The AR also has a role in the development of the male phenotype: in fact, cytoplasmic AR is activated by binding testosterone or dihydrotestosterone hormone before translocating to the nucleus. Spinal and Bulbar Muscular Atrophy (SBMA), also known as Kennedy's disease, is an X-linked recessive neurodegenerative disease. The cause of SBMA is expansion of the CAG trinucleotide repeat, which codes for glutamine (Gln, Q), in Exon 1 of the AR gene. Therefore SBMA is considered to be a polyglutamine (polyGln) expansion disorder.  In unaffected men, 9-33 CAG repeats coding for Gln are found, while males who inherit more than 37 CAG repeats will develop SBMA. The toxic gain of AR function that is characteristic of SBMA results in a slow progressive muscle weakness, atrophy of the tongue, fasciculations of bulbar, facial and limb muscles, and muscle cramping.  A loss of AR function is related to breast enlargement and reduced fertility.The ubiquitin-proteasome system (UPS), which functions in protein degradation, plays an important role in neural cells from SBMA patients. UPS components are found in polyGln-expanded protein aggregates seen in these cells. Therefore previous studies have suggested that the UPS is impaired in SBMA. Previous work suggests that 0QAR and 20QAR can be degraded via the UPS, however, the 50QAR appeared to inhibit the degradation of specific proteins by the UPS. It is also hypothesized that these SBMA-inducing mutant ARs can accumulate in the cell and cause disease by evading UPS degradation. The primary goal of this research was to develop a system for ubiquitinating AR by using an expressed protein ligation (EPL) system. To prove this hypothesis, several intermediate goals have been achieved. PCR-amplified fragments of AR (0Q, 20Q, and 50Q) were cloned into the pTWIN2 vector and contructs were analyzed using restriction enzyme digests and gel electrophoresis. Furthermore, 0QAR, 20QAR, 50QAR and human ubiquitin (HUB) fusion proteins were purified using chitin beads and cleaved using 2-mercapto-ethanesulfonic acid (MESNA). Finally, the 0QAR, 20QAR, 50QAR peptides were ligated with an HA-tagged H2B peptide using EPL. Thus, we successfully developed tools which can be used to explore ubiquitinatination of the AR using EPL systems in vitro. Future work aims to ligate the HUB protein to a peptide to using the EPL method, and then ligating the ubiquitinated peptide to the three different AR peptides. These will be added to active proteasomes to explore the involvement of the UPS in the pathogenesis of SBMA. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lenore Beitel</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mark Anthony Trifiro</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z1442.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128f30p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zf445"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wireless health monitoring: patient arrival models, resource allocation and decision support systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Di</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La surpopulation dans les urgences est un problème très répandu qui peut incommoder les hôpitaux à promulguer des soins urgents dans des délais raisonnables. Au-delà de la satisfaction du patient, le problème de surpopulation entraine une augmentation du nombre de décès en salle d'attente, référant à la mort de patient durant l'attente d'une prise en charge, laquelle est causée par manque de soins médicaux. Ce problème met en évidence l'importance d'améliorer la qualité des soins médicaux, c'est pourquoi un système de surveillance médicale (SSM) pourrait aider le personnel médical à contrôler l'état des patients, en envoyant automatiquement des messages d'alerte aux appareils des médecins (ex. un téléphone intelligent, un assistant numérique personnel ou un ordinateur portable) dès qu'une condition médicale urgente se déclare. Dans une perspective de conception réseau, un SSM sans fil devrait être capable de supporter le nombre de patients qui utiliseront le système, et le fait de pouvoir évaluer l'aptitude du réseau à traiter un certain nombre de patients (défini comme la capacité en patients du réseau) est un facteur important dans la promotion de tels systèmes. Cette thèse étudie les procédés pour augmenter la capacité en patients du réseau dans un SSM. L'objectif principal est de trouver un compromis entre la capacité en patients du réseau et les exigences de la Qualité de Service (QdS) pour chaque patient, de sorte à avoir une capacité de réseau raisonnable en dépit des contraintes de la QdS dans des scénarios de transmissions réelles. Dans la première partie de cette thèse, nous développons de nouvelles méthodes pour estimer la durée moyenne d'attente d'un patient pour accéder au Département des Urgences (DU) d'un hôpital. Ainsi nous montrons pourquoi le développement d'un SSM et l'allocation de ses ressources sans fil limitées sont importants pour améliorer la qualité des soins médicaux. La suite de cette thèse présente plusieurs plans pour l'allocation de ressources dans un SSM, en considérant plusieurs facteurs qui ont besoin d'être pris en compte dans le cas d'un scénario réel, ce qui comprend les différentes exigences de la QdS, les interférences électromagnétiques (IEM) sur les équipements médicaux, ainsi que l'information imparfaite des états du canal. Nous proposons trois nouvelles techniques pour améliorer la capacité du réseau en patients dans un SSM, ce qui inclut une partie sur le multiplexage statistique, une partie basée sur la prédiction du canal et une partie basée sur la décision médical à l'appui.La dernière partie de cette thèse se concentre autour de l'évaluation des performances pour un système d'aide à la décision, qui est un résultat important pour évaluer la validité et l'acceptabilité de la décision d'aide basée sur le schéma d'allocation des ressources proposé précédemment.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Overcrowding in the emergency department  is a worldwide problem impairing the ability of hospitals to offer emergency care within a reasonable time frame. Not merely a problem of patient satisfaction, the problem of overcrowding is leading to an increased number of waiting room death cases, which refer to the death of patients while staying in a hospital's waiting room due to a lack of sufficient medical care, and this problem underscores the significance of improving healthcare quality. As a potential way of improving healthcare quality, a wireless healthcare monitoring system (HMS) could help healthcare staff monitor the condition of patients by automatically sending alert messages to a doctor device (e.g. a smartphone, a personal digital assistant, or a laptop) once emergent conditions occur.From a network design perspective, a wireless HMS should be capable of supporting the number of patients that will be using the system; being able to assess the network's capability to serve a given number of patients (defined as network patient capacity) is a critical factor in promoting adoption of such systems. This thesis investigates schemes for enhancing the network patient capacity within a HMS. The major objective is to explore the tradeoff between the network patient capacity and the Quality-of-Service (QoS) requirements of each patient, so that a fairly good network capacity is achieved subject to the constraints of QoS requirements within real-world transmission scenarios.In the first part of this thesis, we develop novel methods to estimate the average waiting time of a patient to access the Emergency Department (ED) of a hospital, showing why developing a HMS and allocating its limited wireless resources are important to improve the quality of medical care. The following part of this thesis presents various schemes for resource allocation within a HMS, in view of several factors that need to be taken into account in a real scenario, including different QoS requirements, Electromagnetic Interference (EMI) on medical equipments, as well as imperfect channel state information. We propose three novel techniques for improving the network patient capacity within a HMS,  including a statistical multiplexing scheme, a channel prediction based scheme, and a medical decision support based scheme. The last part of this thesis focuses on the performance evaluation of a decision support system, a result that is important to assess the validity and acceptability of the decision support based resource allocation scheme proposed above.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fabrice Labeau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b9260.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zf445</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Hospital Management</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795c08j"><ual:graduationDate>2014</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A recursive Polya tree mixture model: computationally efficient Bayesian nonparametric modelling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Shujie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse décrit une approche flexible et numériquement efficace de modélisation non paramétrique bayésienne au moyen d'un modèle de mélange fondé sur une arborescence de Pólya récursive. Cette approche est motivée par la nécessité de prendre en compte l'hétérogénéité fréquemment observée en biostatistique, notamment lors de la méta-analyse d'essais cliniques ou de l'analyse de durées de vie et d'événements récurrents. Soient Y_{1},...,Y_{N} des observations mutuellement indépendantes telles que Y_i est de loi $h(.|theta_{i})$. On suppose que les paramètres theta_{1},...,theta_{N}$ proviennent d'une loi F inconnue et que la loi a priori sur F est une arborescence de Pólya. On adopte une approche bayésienne empirique pour le choix de la loi a priori de base. Les paramètres theta_{1},..., theta_{N} êtant latents, on a recours à un algorithme d'augmentation de données pour en simuler des valeurs de façon itérative. La loi empirique de ces pseudo observations permet alors de guider le choix de la loi a priori de base. Les propriétés théoriques de cette procédure sont explorées. Malgré sa simplicité, le modèle proposé est pratique et efficace au plan calcul. En plus de fournir une bonne approximation de modèles bayésiens non paramétriques plus complexes, il facilite le traitement de problèmes réputés difficiles en modélisation bayésienne non paramétrique classique. Dans cette thèse, l'emploi du modèle est illustré au moyen des célèbres données de Brown (2008) et de Liu (1996) souvent considérées comme bancs d'essai pour la modélisation bayésienne non paramétrique. Comme on le fait valoir, l'approche peut aussi servir à estimer une densité (y compris bivariée) et à des fins de méta-analyse en biostatistique. On étudie en outre un modèle bayésien semi-paramétrique à temps de panne accéléré (TPA) fondé sur cette approche et on propose une généralisation du modèle TPA pour l'analyse d'événements récurrents.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis describes a flexible and computationally efficient Bayesian nonparametric modelling approach based on a recursive Polya tree mixture model. This approach is motivated by the need to capture the heterogeneity observed in many areas of biostatistics such as meta analysis of clinical trials, survival analysis and recurrent event data analysis. Let Y_{1},..,Y_{N}  be mutually independent observations such that Y_i has distribution h(.|\theta_{i}). It is assumed that the parameters theta_{1},..., theta_{N} arise from an unknown distribution F and that the prior on F is a Polya tree distribution. An empirical Bayesian approach is adopted for the choice of the prior's base distribution. As the parameters theta_{1},..., theta_{N} are latent, a data augmentation algorithm is used to simulate pseudo values iteratively. The empirical distribution of these pseudo values can then guide the choice of the base distribution of the Polya tree prior. The theoretical properties of this procedure are explored.Despite its simplicity, the proposed model is practical and computationally efficient. In addition to providing a good approximation for more complicated Bayesian nonparametric models, it can be used to handle difficult problems in classical Bayesian nonparametric modelling. In this thesis, the use of the model is illustrated using the famous data of Brown (2008) and Liu (1996), which are often viewed as test cases for Bayesian nonparametric modelling. It is also shown that the proposed approach can be applied to density estimation (including in the bivariate case) and meta analysis in biostatistics. Moreover, a Bayesian semi-parametric accelerated failure time (AFT) model based on the proposed approach is considered, and an extension of the AFT model to recurrent event data analysis is introduced.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Stephens</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>James Anthony Hanley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8383840.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795c08j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>