<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881m22c"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intangible security : choice of law rules for intangible secured financing under the Uniform commercial code</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bartleman, Laurent William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent revisions to Articles 9 and 1 of the Uniform Commercial Code (the "UCC") have proposed new intangible secured financing choice of law rules. These choices of law rules contain rules that represent all three major schools of thought in the field of conflicts of laws: multilateralism, substantivism and unilateralism. This thesis examines the new rules by analysing them in the context of the strengths and weakness of these schools of thought and in light of the requirements of a secured financing system. On the whole the strong mulitlateralist focus of the majority of the rules provides a solid basis for the UCC's choice of law provisions. The elimination of the rule that was based on a unilateralist basis is a logical improvement. However, the inclusion of a rule, &amp;sect;9-307(c), with a substantivist basis introduces an element of uncertainty into the system and should be removed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494877r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m22c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Security (Law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n140p"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Camille Pissarro's Turpitudes sociales : challenging the medical model of social deviance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vouitsis, Elpida</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The French temperance movement during the nineteenth century believed that it had discovered the source of social problems when it linked accidents, conjugal violence and crime to an increase in alcohol consumption by the working classes. In a swift attempt to curb these societal ills, the campaign led by the medical community targeted the working classes in France. This instigated the further alienation of the masses and allowed government officials to promote its own agenda of moral reform. In an effort to expose the elitist intentions of this state run temperance movement, this thesis analyzes four images from Camille Pissarro's unpublished album, Turpitudes Sociales of 1889, which represent similar imagery but with an opposite message. I will analyze these images from Pissarro's unpublished work in order to shed light on his incorporation of class relations and depiction of the bourgeoisie's negative impact on the French working classes.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w2586.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n140p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Temperance -- France -- History -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>France -- Social conditions -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pissarro, Camille, 1830-1903. Turpitudes sociales</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s278x"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Making a community : land policy in the Kawartha Lakes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walker, Glenn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Between the mid-eighteenth and the mid-nineteenth centuries, the Crown coordinated a revolution in land usage in the Kawartha Lakes, as elsewhere in the colony, through 'civilization' and land redistribution. Attempts to change native society and build settler communities did not quite unfold the way the government intended. 'Civilization' helped the Mississauga farm and taught skills that eased interaction with colonial society, but they continued to produce much of their food by traditional means. Speculation isolated settlers and made land acquisition more difficult, though some speculators provided essential services. Most immigrants bought land privately and many were not able to establish themselves as farmers. Preferential grants were particularly poor at distributing land to settlers and Crown or Clergy Reserves sales were much more likely to transfer property directly to users. The transition to agricultural land usage occurred largely through the state's mediation of conflicting claims to access.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nh40n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s278x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kawartha Lakes Region (Ont.) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Land settlement -- Ontario -- Kawartha Lakes Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Land use -- Ontario -- Kawartha Lakes Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Missisauga Indians -- Land tenure</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773v99h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stoning and hand-amputation : the pre-Islamic origins of the ḥadd penalties for zinā and sariqa</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Young, Walter, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Determining whether stoning for adultery and hand-amputation for theft were practiced in pre-Islamic Arabia represents the first phase in exploring the origins and evolution of these penalties in Islamic law. Should both punishments prove to predate Islam, then it would appear the Qur'an broke with stoning and confirmed amputation of the hand. An extensive survey of pre-Islamic, Near Eastern legal materials in search of parallel penalties has thus been attempted in this thesis. Remarkably, not only stoning and hand-amputation, but nearly the entire range of Islamic adultery and theft legislation have pre-Islamic parallels. The nature of these parallels, however, does not conform to the paradigm of 'borrowing' from 'foreign' sources. Rather, Arab customary law---a major contributor to Islamic law in general---appears to have diverged from an ancient Semitic 'common source' once shared with other Near Eastern cultural entities. Most major elements of Islamic criminal law, including stoning and hand-amputation, therefore represent the culmination of an ancient Semitic common law.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t41k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773v99h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islamic law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex crimes (Islamic law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amputation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stoning (Islamic law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603qx77m"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of special services for the academic success of college students with disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tzokova-Vladimirova, Vessela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study explores the role of special services and accommodations for the academic success of college students with disabilities. Two students participated, one with mild attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) and one with a severe language disorder. Unstructured interviews were used to examine participants' perceptions of the effectiveness of special services and accommodations. Other factors contributing to students' progress in school, such as areas of learning strengths, effort and assistance from teachers, peers and family members, as well as lack of appropriate services and funding, were also discussed by the participants. Participants' personality characteristics and life circumstances appear to influence their performance in school as well. The present study may inform practice by promoting a more personalized approach to the selection of special services and accommodations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827b96j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qx77m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>College students with disabilities</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sg59h"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modified output of Japanese EFL learners : variable effects of interlocutor vs. feedback types</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sato, Masatoshi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated the interactional moves of Japanese English as a Foreign Language (EFL) learners and, in particular, how differently they modify their oral output depending on their interlocutor---either a peer or a native speaker (NS). By employing retrospective stimulated recall methodology, this study also explored the participants' feelings and perceptions which arguably determined their interaction patterns during a communicative task. Participants were eight Japanese first-year university students and four NSs of English. Conversations of eight learner-NS dyads and four learner-learner dyads (six hours in total) were audiotaped, transcribed, and then statistically analyzed. Learners were interviewed two days after the task completion. Results revealed that learners interacted in significantly different ways depending on whom they interacted with. Specifically, their interlocutor (peer or NS) proved to be a more influential variable than the type of feedback (i.e., elicitation or reformulation) they received. Qualitative analysis of the interview data provides comprehensive explanations for the findings.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z42f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg59h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Interaction analysis in education</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Japanese speakers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58pd23h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Un empereur dans sa ville : nouveaux points de vue sur la cathédrale Notre-Dame de Strasbourg</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sauvé, Jean-Sébastien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As an imperial city, Strasbourg has edified many monuments to promote its particular status in the Holy Roman Empire. Notre-Dame at Strasbourg is not an exception: historians read the construction of the cathedral and its facade as the materialisation of a "civic pride". Many documents, anyhow, testify to the emperors many visits and underline the city's political role in the Empire. This thesis demonstrates that the imperial presence in the Reichsstadt---events usually avoided by historians---is clearly illustrated in the iconographical and architectural programs of the cathedral. The selection of biblical scenes and protagonists, historical figures, and the borrowing of architectural details from royal and imperial buildings, make it a monument erected to the glory of the emperor. From its portal to its spire, Notre-Dame at Strasbourg is a testimony of the Strasbourgeois' loyalty to the imperial crown, loyalty transferred to the Bourbons who took the city in 1682.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mp980.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd23h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cathédrale de Strasbourg</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strasbourg (France) -- Church history</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church decoration and ornament -- France -- Strasbourg</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dv839"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of client-generated metaphors on in-session therapeutic processes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rowat, Ronda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Psychotherapy research indicates that metaphors are often used to express a client's meaningful experience. This study measured the impact of client-generated metaphors on in-session experiencing. The research question explored whether client-generated metaphor use would be associated with greater in-session experiencing as rated by the Experiencing Scale (EXP; Klein, Mathieu-Coughlan, &amp; Kiesler, 1986). It was also asked whether metaphor use would increase the subsequent experiencing of a client. Forty-seven client-generated metaphor events were randomly selected from 47 psychotherapy transcripts of clients in therapy with counsellors-in-training. For each metaphor event, a pre-metaphor and post-metaphor client utterance was selected. A total of 140 utterances were compared using a repeated-measure analysis of variance. Results indicate that client-generated metaphors are not significantly different from pre-metaphor or post-metaphor client utterances. The role of language and the clinical importance of metaphor use in psychotherapy were discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s509j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dv839</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metaphor -- Therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychotherapy -- Methodology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42n8213"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Face processing in children with fragile X syndrome : an ERP feasibility study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roy, Sylvain</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Faces provide important information necessary for social communication. The current study aimed to evaluate Event-Related Brain Potentials (ERPs) as a method of exploring face processing abilities in fragile X syndrome (FXS), a genetic disorder where social deficits lie at the core of the cognitive phenotype. Neural changes were investigated in three children with FXS across various conditions such as upright vs. inverted faces, intact faces vs. faces with no eyes as well as faces vs. cars. Relative to chronological age matched controls, children with FXS displayed greater N170 amplitudes and shorter latency peaks across conditions. In addition, the FXS group showed right hemispheric specialization for both face and non-face stimuli. Heightened electrophysiological responses in FXS are discussed in the context of reported hyper-sensitivity and arousal.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k519v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n8213</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vision disorders</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fragile X syndrome</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b635b"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Integrating Internet-facilitated international academic partnerships into local university environments : faculty perspectives</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Palvetzian, Talene E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores how to integrate faculty-initiated Internet-facilitated international academic partnerships into their local university environments. Recently some faculty have begun initiating international partnership activities which carryout their university's research, teaching, and service missions. These partnerships (including courses, projects, or entire programs) are considered by their initiators to benefit both faculty and student development. Faculty see the Internet as enabling them to construct interactive and collaborative virtual forums where disperse student and faculty bodies can co-engage in exciting international research, teaching, and learning opportunities. This study aims to encourage the development of Internet-facilitated international academic partnerships so that more faculty in all disciplines are supported by their local institutions to better integrate their partnerships. Presently, partnerships are not well integrated. Impart this is because the Internet as a communication tool is relatively new phenomenon. However, it is also due to the tendency for faculty level partnerships to be overlooked by higher levels of university administration. As a result, the value of Internet partnerships has not yet been explored in relation to their local institutional missions. This study therefore consults faculty with experience partnering online in order to garner faculty insights pertaining to partnership integration. The results help to determine (1) core characteristics of these faculty-level partnerships (2) faculty motivations for initiating them (3) university environments implicated by integration and (4) identify faculty support and development opportunities appropriate to support integration.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cd41g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b635b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Internet in education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education, Higher -- Technological innovations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Distance education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j836z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Autour de trois textes-films de Marguerite Duras : Détruire dit-elle, Nathalie Granger, Agatha</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paquette, Marie-Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work of Marguerite Duras comprises seventeen "texts-films" distributed throughout its filmic period from 1969 to 1985. These texts guides of films constitute a particular form of filmic writing which utilizes three different modes of expression. Located at the three decade old border, the text-films being studied here, Detruire ditelle, (1969), Nathalie Granger (1972), Agatha (1981) differently ask the same question of the literary, theatrical and filmic genre all while escaping from it. The "texte-film" which is primarily plural and plurifunctional is showed here in three states, at three moments of its continuous creation. In a rejection of the traditional structures of transposition of writing to film, they challenge authorities as varied as the dialogical form, the dramatic text, the scenario. Stages of a long renouncement of writing or revivals of a creativity unceasingly searching for new ways to express itself, the "texts-films" studied here are holding essential keys to understanding the very whole work of Marguerite Duras.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds43h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j836z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Duras, Marguerite -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Motion pictures and literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p499b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Writing from the inside : domesticity and transcendence in the works of Bahiņā Bāī (c. 1628-1700)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parasharami, Preeti Ashok</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bahiṇa Bai was a female poet-Saint whose participation in the Maharashtrian devotional movement known as the Varkari Panth transformed the image of female devotionalism in the region. A collection of her poetic writings, the Samta Bahiṇabaica Gatha, demonstrates her struggle to reconcile the demands of domesticity with those of devotionalism. Bahiṇa Bai simultaneously extols the roles of the pativrata, devoted wife, and the bhakta, the devotee, in her lyrical compositions, and resolves the tensions between domesticity and devotion by merging her husband's identity with that of Viṭhoba, a localized force of Viṣṇu. This thesis argues that Bahiṇa Bai's rebellion against a parochial vision of female spirituality integrates elements of Brahmanic orthodoxy, non-dual philosophy and bhakti practice.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rw965.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p499b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bahiṇī, ca. 1628-ca. 1700</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spiritual life -- Hinduism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322d54j"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The representation of Muslim women in American print media : a case study of The New York Times, September 11, 2000-September 11, 2002</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McCafferty, Heather</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an examination of representations of Muslim women in the American print media. I focus on one particular publication, The New York Times within a time frame surrounding the events of September 11, 2001. Articles were selected from this publication that fell within the time period of September 11, 2000 to September 11, 2002, in selecting articles, I chose those based on their inclusion of any discussion that clearly identified those discussed as Muslim women, through the use of the words "Muslim" or "Islamic" in their descriptions. The case study was carried out by reading through each daily edition of The New York Times in order to identify any articles that fell within my criteria. I also used an online database containing abstracts of the publication to verify that no article of relevance was overlooked. I then devised 5 categories within which to analyze the representations of Muslim women that were found within these articles, "Veil", "Biographical", "Women's Issues", "Politics" and "Muslims in the West". The main goal of this thesis is to determine how Muslim women are represented within this particular publication and to analyze whether the events of September 11, 2001 had any effect on how Muslim women were portrayed in The New York Times articles.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mx88c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d54j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Journalism -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muslim women</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muslims -- Public opinion</dc:subject><dc:subject>September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 -- Press coverage</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nh41x"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Chinese immigrant parents' educational expectations and school participation experience</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ma, Li, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent years have witnessed the large number of Chinese immigrants in Canada. With the coming of those immigrants is the large number of school age children. Hence, immigrant families' educational expectations and parental participation in their children's schools become major educational concerns. This study focuses on recent Chinese immigrants' expectations of and concerns about their children's schooling. Drawing from Bourdieu's cultural capital theory and Ogbu's social mobility theory, in this study, I used a qualitative interview methodology to explore the educational expectations and school involvement of five Chinese parents who had recently immigrated to Canada. The educational expectations for their children and school participation of these Chinese immigrants are deeply rooted in Chinese tradition and heritage and are also greatly shaped by their personal experiences in Canada. Their cultural values and beliefs and immigration experiences as visible minorities have had a great impact on their educational expectations. Language barriers and different cultural values between dominant mainstream and Chinese traditions are the two main factors that hinder immigrant parents' participation in school activities and hence in their children's schooling.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cg86x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh41x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Home and school</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children of immigrants -- Education -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chinese Canadians -- Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vk41k"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Constructions of Muslim identity : women and the education reform movement in colonial India</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Madhani, Taslim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines educational reforms initiated by British colonial officials in late nineteenth/early twentieth century India and the responses they ensued from Indian Muslim reformers. Focusing on the "woman question," British colonizers came to the conviction that the best method to "civilize" Indian society was to educate women according to modern Western standards. Muslim reformers sought to resolve the "woman question" for themselves by combining their own ideologies of appropriate female education with Western ones. Muslim reformers were also deeply concerned with the disappearance of Islamic identity owing to colonial educational policies. Reformers placed the responsibility of maintaining Islamic culture on the shoulders of women so as to both resolve the debate over the proper place of women in society and retain a distinct Islamic identity in the changing Indian context. This resolution limited Indian Muslim women's access to education as well as their participation in Indian society at large.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j8377.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk41k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>India -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Education -- India -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in Islam</dc:subject><dc:subject>India -- History -- 19th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t2113"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le violon enchanté dans les contes littéraires québécois du XIXe siècle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McCallum, Amy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master's thesis is centered on the enchanted violin and its role in six literary tales from nineteenth century Quebec. The motif is traced throughout its history and its developments in various Indo-European contexts. The importance of the enchanted violin in the oral traditions of Europe and French-Canada is underlined. The motif's literary transformation in the nineteenth century is also analyzed; authors of the tales studied were chiefly concerned with the creation of a national literature, and this affected their portrayal of the enchanted violin in several ways. Vladimir Propp's structuralist morphology is used in order to define the function of the violin as a magic object in each of the works. Lastly, a mytho-critical reading of the six tales concentrates on the symbolic power of the instrument and speculates as to its ethnographic origins.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds44s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t2113</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Musical instruments in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magic in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian literature -- Québec (Province) -- 19th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c048"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>How does what's bred in the bone come out in the flesh? : Devora Neumark's interventions and the concept of flesh</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kiriloff, Vera</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines seven of Devora Neumark's artistic interventions that activate an embodied transfer or continuity of knowledge. I am inspired by phenomenologist Maurice Merleau-Ponty's notion of "the flesh of the world," that is the element enabling a reversibility between subject and object, specifically with regard to the body. Neumark draws from a repertoire of her everyday activities like crocheting or peeling beets to make a stew. She resituates the activity from one which is traditionally practiced in the private sphere of the home, often undervalued, to one which critically engages passersby in various urban settings. I study the repetitive capacities of these everyday activities, how they are negotiated in the public sphere, and how they remain (re)productively in the flesh through body-to-body transmission. Flesh becomes the operative concept in this thesis and activates a phenomenology in Neumark's interventions that goes beyond Merleau-Ponty's and which engages with both aesthetic and socio-political questions.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d4539.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c048</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Interactive art -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neumark, Devora, 1959- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xr894"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Verovio's keyboard intabulations and domestic music making in the late Renaissance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kranias, Alison</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>At the end of the sixteenth century, Simone Verovio printed a series of canzonetta anthologies in Rome. These collections were unique, in that they contained keyboard and lute intabulations alongside their vocal parts. The keyboard intabulations seem primarily intended as accompanimental parts. As such, they inform us about the use of keyboard instruments in ensembles of mixed voices and instruments. This thesis examines how the printing format of Verovio's keyboard intabulations arose from a larger context. In particular, it asks what were the skills and training of amateur keyboard players (often women), when or when not to transpose pieces with chiavette (or high clefs), and how instrumental embellishments relate to the canzonetta's text as well as musical texture. This examination contributes to a better understanding of Italian sixteenth-century performance practice, especially of the ways in which instruments were used along with voices in domestic music making.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx208.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xr894</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music -- Italy -- 16th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intabulations (Keyboard instrument)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Performance practice (Music) -- History -- 16th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Verovio, Simone, fl. 1575-1608</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp42q"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Beyond the bon sauvage : questioning Canada's postcoloniality in Nancy Huston's Plainsong and Thomas King's Green grass, running water</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Holoch, Adele Johnsen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis approaches the question of Canada's postcoloniality through two novels, Nancy Huston's Plainsong and Thomas King's Green Grass, Running Water. Published in 1993, both novels problematize a postcolonial articulation of marginality in Canada, suggesting that it reduces the complexities of otherness to binary divisions of center and margin, colonizer and colonized. While Plainsong imagines the restrictive consequences such a reading may have on the others with which it engages, Green Grass, Running Water pushes past those boundaries to affirm the complex nature of alterity in contemporary Canada. Through King's novel in particular, we are provided a new model for approaching and understanding the nuances of difference in a changing literary and political landscape.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666479x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp42q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Huston, Nancy, 1953- Cantique des plaines. English</dc:subject><dc:subject>Postcolonialism in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canadian literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>King, Thomas, 1943-. Green grass, running water</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892b10m"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La corruption dans les traités polémiques de Mme Dacier</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Krück, Marie-Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The idea of corruption travels down and supports this thesis. It stands as one of the principal stakes of the Homeric Quarrel. By analysing it, we may deepen our understanding of the value the famous hellenist Anne Dacier placed on the heritage of the Anciens and its reception by the Moderns; we may also better understand in which ways her engagement in polemics belonged to her times. Anne Dacier was less an apologist of Homer than a polemist who attacked the corrupted taste of her contemporaries. She feared for them, but above all, she feared for the Homeric text. She had done her best in her translation to preserve the poem while Houdar de la Motte, her adversary thought that an adaptation would suit the public better. Mme Dacier presented herself as the guardian of tradition and its purity; nonetheless, to achieve her goal, she had to compromise with her opponents and speak their corrupted language.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064633j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b10m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Homer -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dacier, Madame (Anne), d. 1720 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corruption</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dc75n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of Fyb as an interacting protein with CD45 in yeast two-hybrid screening</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Linhua, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>CD45, also known as Leukocyte-common antigen (LCA), is a type-1 receptor-like protein tyrosine phosphatase (PTPase), which contains two PTPase domains, the membrane proximal domain (DI) and the membrane distal domain (D2). It is uniquely expressed on the surface of all leukocytes and their hematopoietic precursors and plays an important role in immunoreceptor signaling. In this study, I identified a novel CD45-interacting protein, Fyb, through screening human leukocyte cDNA library with a modified yeast two-hybrid system. Fyb is an adaptor protein mainly involved in the regulation of T cell receptor-induced integrin clustering and adhesion. It contains several regions with potential to mediate protein-protein interactions and has been shown to bind to the Src family kinase Fyn, the adapter protein SLP-76, Ena/VASP proteins, the adapter protein SKAP55, and SKAP55-HOM in T cell receptor signaling. I also demonstrated that the interaction of Fyb with CD45 was through involves the C-terminal region of Fyb, where several tyrosine residues, such as Tyr 594 and Tyr624, are critical for its interaction with other proteins in signaling. The interaction of Fyb with CD45 is phosphotyrosine-dependent since Src kinase is required for the interaction. Mutation analysis revealed that the tyrosine residue 624 of Fyb is the pivotal tyrosine residue involved in its association with CD45, whereas tyrosin 594 was not found to be required for binding. By mutation of CD45, it was demonstrated that the phosphatase catalytic D1 domain of CD45 was involved in the interaction with Fyb. More significantly, I found that only the substrate-trapping mutant (Asp to Val), but not the wild type CD45 interacted with Fyb, suggesting that Fyb is a potential CD45 substrate. Furthermore, I demonstrated the association of the C-terminal fragment of Fyb with CD45 in mammalian cells. However, I was not able to determine the interaction of the wild type Fyb with CD45 in 293 cells.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n141z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dc75n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r5926"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional data analysis for detecting structural boundaries of cortical area</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Wen, 1978-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is widely accepted that the cortex can be divided into a series of spatially discrete areas based on their specific laminar patterns. It is of great interest to divide the cortex into different areas in terms of both neuronal functions and cellular composition. The division of cortical areas can be reflected by the cell arrangements or cellular composition. Therefore, the cortical structure can be represented by some functional neuronal density data. Techniques on functional data analysis help to develop some measures which indicate structural changes. In order to separate roughness from structural variations and influences of the convolutions and foldings, a method called bivariate smoothing is proposed for the noisy density data. This smoothing method is applied to four sets of cortical density data provided by Prof Petrides [1] and Scott Mackey [2]. The first or second order derivatives of the density function reflect the change and the rate of the change of the density, respectively. Therefore, derivatives of the density function are applied to analyze the structural features as an attempt to detect indicators for boundaries of subareas of the four cortex sections. Finally, the accuracy and limitation of this smoothing method is tested using some simulated examples.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150j54x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r5926</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cerebral cortex</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multivariate analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Functional analysis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cw49m"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Longitudinal data with change-points</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhou, Wei, 1968 Jan. 17-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Longitudinal data often consist of a set of covariates and repeated measurements of an outcome over time. In clinical and health studies, a main concern is often the time that a treatment takes into effect, which is referred to as the change-point in this thesis. Modeling and measuring impact of a change in longitudinal data has not been thoroughly explored in the statistical literature. Viewing longitudinal data from the perspective of change-point analysis, we have a data structure that statisticians sometimes refer to as a multi-path change-point problem. In multipath change-point problems, it is often of interest to assess the impact of covariates on the change-point. We model the effect of covariates through hazard of the change using Cox's proportional odds model. We take a maximum quasi-likelihood (MqL) approach in estimation and statistical inference. To find the MqL estimators of the unknown parameters in our model, we have used a variant of simulated annealing. By the means of simulation we compare our model with a model suggested by Diggle et al. for analyzing a set of longitudinal observations on the body weights of 27 cows.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827b97t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cw49m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn106z40n"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A generalized two-dimensional display editor for relations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhu, Lili, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis discusses the design and implementation of a two-dimensional display editor (display2D) for a relational database programming system jRelix. The purpose of this thesis is to integrate relational data visualization into jRelix. The graphical information for any basic geometric shape, such as points, lines, polylines, triangles and text, can be stored in relations. These relations are visualized by the display2D operation, which analyzes the relations and invokes Xfig, an open source drawing tool, to display them. With the displayed data, the users can interactively perform creation, deletion, relocation and modification, on the various objects. The display2D operation will generate a new relational value from an updated graph. The display2D operation also provides flexibility with additional user defined vocabulary relations, which allow users to provide alternate names for attributes so that they can better describe the graphs they represent.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nt837.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z40n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w758c"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Merging metagenomic and microarray technologies to explore bacterial catabolic potential of Arctic soils</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Whissell, Gavin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A novel approach for screening metagenomic libraries by merging both metagenomic and microarray platforms was developed and optimized. This high-throughput screening strategy termed "metagenomic microarrays" involved the construction of two Arctic soil large-insert libraries and the high density arraying of the clone plasmid DNA (~50 kb) onto glass slides. A standard alkaline lysis technique used for the purification of plasmid DNA was adapted and optimized to function efficiently in a 96-well format, providing an economically viable means of producing sufficient high-quality plasmid DNA for direct printing onto microarrays. The amounts of printed material and probe, required for maximal clone detection, were optimized. To examine catabolic clone detection libraries were first screened by PCR for catabolic genes of interest. Two PCR-positive clones were printed onto microarrays, and detection of these specific clones in the printed libraries was achieved using labeled probes produced from PCR fragments of known sequence. Also, hybridizations were performed using labeled PCR fragments derived from the amplification of a catabolic gene from the total community DNA. The ability of selected probes to specifically target clones of interest was demonstrated. This merger of metagenomics and microarray technologies has shown great promise as a tool for screening the natural microbial community for catabolic potential and could also be used to profile microbial diversity in different environments.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719m72p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w758c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soil microbiology -- Nunavut -- Ellesmere Island</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bioremediation -- Nunavut -- Ellesmere Island</dc:subject><dc:subject>DNA microarrays</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microbial genomes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gene libraries</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>