<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719p66z"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Towards interaction-driven enhancement of augmented reality visualization in image-guided neurosurgery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Drouin, Simon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of Image-Guided Neurosurgery (IGNS) systems is now part of the standard of care for the surgical treatment of several neurological diseases. This class of medical device enables the visualization of preoperative scans of the patient on a computer screen during an operation. More importantly, it provides a way for the surgeon to establish a correspondence between the images and the anatomy of the patient by displaying the location of tracked surgical tools in relation with the scans. In currently existing IGNS systems, the interaction between the surgeon and the machine remains difficult and cognitively demanding. Understanding the relationship between the images and the patient's anatomy requires a constant mental effort and may be error prone. Additionally, the surgeon has very limited means to interact with the system and must often rely on vocal instructions to a technician in order to visualize the exact information that is required at a specific step of the procedure.In the following dissertation, we describe the development of an IGNS technology that aims at improving the visualization and surgeon-computer interaction paradigm of this type of system by enabling augmented reality (AR) visualization and direct surgeon-computer interaction through the use of tracked surgical tools.We start by describing an open source IGNS system called IBIS, that is capable of producing AR images in the oculars of a surgical microscope by automatically merging live video captured from the microscope and preoperative scans rendered from the same point of view. The system is able to maintain an accurate overlay of real and virtual images throughout an operation using frequent correction of preoperative scans based on intraoperative ultrasound images. In a second manuscript, we describe PRISM, a novel open source volumetric rendering framework which was developed as an extension of the IBIS platform to produce a wide variety of rendering effects in order to generate the appropriate visualization for each type of AR view. Next, we consider interaction between the IGNS system and the surgeon and the importance of such interaction for the correct understanding of displayed images. Through an extensive review of the literature, we provide an overview of the interactive rendering techniques previously developed in the field of surgical augmented reality. More importantly, we review the human visual perception literature and highlight evidence showing the role of the motor system in achieving an accurate visual perception. This important visuo-motor interrelationship justifies the necessity to systematically consider interaction in the design of new medical image visualization systems. Based on this idea, we propose three novel interactive rendering methods to improve depth perception of angiographic scans and validate their respective benefit in a psychophysics experiment.  The work presented in this thesis demonstrates the feasibility of producing accurate augmented reality images in the operating room and shows the importance and benefit of developing perceptually motivated interactive rendering techniques. The future integration of these contributions has the potential to yield more natural and less cognitively demanding interfaces to guide an operation based on various imaging technologies, leading to shorter and more minimally invasive procedures and less trauma for the patients.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'utilisation de systèmes de neurochirurgie guidée par l'image (NGI) fait maintenant partie de la pratique courante pour le traitement chirurgical de plusieurs maladies neurologiques. Cette classe d'appareils médicaux permet la visualisation des scans préopératoires du patient sur un écran d'ordinateur au cours d'une opération. Il permet également au chirurgien d'établir une correspondance entre les images et l'anatomie du patient en affichant l'emplacement d'outils chirurgicaux superposés aux scans. Dans les systèmes NGI existants, l'interaction entre le chirurgien et la machine reste exigeante sur le plan cognitif. Comprendre la relation entre les images et l'anatomie du patient nécessite un effort mental constant et peut être source d'erreurs. De plus, le chirurgien a des moyens très limités pour interagir avec le système et doit souvent se fier à des instructions vocales données à un technicien afin de visualiser l'information exacte qui est requise à une étape spécifique de la procédure.Dans la thèse qui suit, nous décrivons le développement d'une technologie NGI qui vise à améliorer le paradigme de visualisation et d'interaction chirurgien-ordinateur de ce type de système en permettant la visualisation en réalité augmentée (RA) et l'interaction directe entre le chirurgien et l'ordinateur basée sur des outils localisés en trois dimensions.Nous commençons par décrire un système de NGI ouvert appelé IBIS, qui est capable de produire des images RA affichées dans les oculaires d'un microscope chirurgical en fusionnant automatiquement des images vidéo capturées à partir du microscope et les scans préopératoires d'un patient rendus du même point de vue. Le système est capable de maintenir une superposition précise d'images réelles et virtuelles tout au long d'une opération en utilisant une correction fréquente des scans préopératoires basée sur des images ultrasonores peropératoires. Dans un second manuscrit, nous décrivons PRISM, librairie ouverte de génération de rendus volumétrique qui a été développé comme extension à la plateforme IBIS et qui permet de produire une grande variété d'effets visuels afin de générer la visualisation appropriée pour chaque type de vue de RA. Ensuite, nous considérons l'interaction entre le système de NGI et le chirurgien et l'importance d'une telle interaction pour permettre une compréhension exacte des images affichées. Grâce à une revue approfondie de la littérature, nous donnons un aperçu des techniques de rendu interactives développées précédemment dans le domaine de la RA appliquée à la chirurgie. De plus, nous passons en revue la littérature sur la perception visuelle humaine et mettons en évidence des preuves montrant le rôle du système moteur dans la réalisation d'une perception visuelle précise. Cette importante relation visuo-motrice justifie la nécessité de considérer systématiquement l'interaction dans la conception de nouveaux systèmes de visualisation d'images médicales. Sur la base de cette idée, nous proposons trois nouvelles méthodes de rendu interactives pour améliorer la perception de profondeur des scans d'angiographie et valider leurs bénéfices respectifs dans une expérience psychophysique. Le travail présenté dans cette thèse démontre la faisabilité de produire des images de réalité augmentée précises dans la salle d'opération et montre l'importance et l'avantage de développer des techniques de rendu interactives motivées par la perception. L'intégration future de ces concepts a le potentiel de produire des interfaces plus naturelles et moins exigeantes sur le plan cognitif pour guider le travail du chirurgien durant une opération, ce qui permettra de réduire la durée des procédures plus courtes et de les rendre moins invasives et ultimement, permettra de réduire les traumatismes pour le patients.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Louis Collins</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913s238.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719p66z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biomedical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440w067"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Delineating functional magnetic resonance imaging connectivity states of the old and young during resting-state and sleep</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dickinson, Philip Geoffrey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>À mesure que la population vieillit, le système de santé et la société du Canada font face à des demandes croissantes du public en termes de personnel et de finances.  Les populations âgées sont connues pour l'hétérogénéité de leurs états de santé. Caractériser cette diversité de trajectoires de vieillissement est fondamental pour comprendre la santé et les neuropathologies liées à l'âge. L'utilisation de l'imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM) est une procédure non-invasive typique pour étudier le vieillissement du cerveau. L'IRM fonctionnelle « au repos » mesure efficacement l'activité cérébrale chez des sujets de tous âges et capacités, car elle n'impose aucune exigence au-delà du fait de rester immobile et éveillé. La méthode standard d'analyse statique en IRM fonctionnelle consiste à identifier des différences de connectivité moyenne entre cohortes, mais cette approche est inefficace pour caractériser l'hétérogénéité présente au sein des cohortes. Nous appliquons ici une méthode guidée par les données, avec laquelle nous identifions des états cérébraux prototypiques dérivés de la connectivité fonctionnelle variable dans le temps, afin de discriminer des sous-populations au sein des cohortes âgées. Nous analysons une population saine de sujets jeunes et âgés pour les différences liées à l'âge, pour l'activité différentielle pendant le sommeil de mouvement oculaire non-rapide (NREM2) et pour l'impact du contenu des pensées spontanées, mesurées pendant la procédure de repos. Finalement, dans une analyse exploratoire préliminaire, nous avons utilisé nos méthodes pour comparer les caractéristiques du sommeil et de l'éveil. Nous démontrons que notre méthode guidée par les données identifie des états cérébraux qui discriminent entre et au sein des cohortes, à la fois pendant l'éveil et le sommeil. Dans les deux cas, nous identifions des sous-cohortes âgées qui expliquent la quasi-totalité de la variance liée à l'âge retrouvée dans l'analyse statique. Nous avons observé un effet d'interaction croisée entre les scores du contenu de la pensée et la cohorte d'âge. Cela peut être expliqué par le gyrus temporal moyen agissant comme une voie de compensation pour les pensées liées au passé chez les sujets plus âgés. Dans notre dernière analyse, nous avons trouvé que les états cérébraux les plus corrélés à travers les bases de données de sommeil et de veille étaient associés à la population plus jeune. Cela était prévu, puisque la facilité à s'endormir diminue avec l'âge. Nous avons également observé moins de corrélation entre les états cérébraux des cohortes jeunes et âgées pendant le sommeil que lorsque les participants étaient éveillés, soulignant que le sommeil était une source intéressante pour la recherche liée à l'âge. En somme, notre méthode fournit un aperçu de l'hétérogénéité du vieillissement du cerveau dans les populations âgées, au-delà de ce qui peut être observé au moyen d'une 'analyse standard. Ces résultats soulignent l'importance de délimiter les états cérébraux sous-jacents dans les études sur le vieillissement. De plus, puisque la méthode est guidée par les données, elle peut être appliquée à des bases de données sans connaissance préalable de la pathologie, et offre donc un outil prometteur pour identifier les biomarqueurs dans les études futures.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>As the population ages, Canada faces a personal, public and financial demand on the health system and society. Heterogeneous health outcomes are notable in older populations. Identifying this diversity is fundamental to understanding age-related health and neuropathology. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is a common non-invasive procedure to study brain aging. Resting-state functional MRI, which places no demands beyond remaining still and awake, effectively measures brain activity in subjects of all ages and capacities. The standard static analysis method identifies functional connectivity differences across cohorts, however, it is ineffective at differentiating within-cohort heterogeneities. We present a data-driven method, with which we identify prototypical brain states derived from time-varying functional connectivity, to discriminate sub-populations within cohorts. We analyze a healthy population of young and old subjects for age-related differences, for differential activity during stage 2 non-rapid eye movement sleep (NREM2) and for the impact of differential thought content measured during the resting-state procedure. Finally, in a preliminary, exploratory analysis we used our methods to compare features of sleep and wakefulness across datasets. We demonstrate that our data-driven method derives brain states that discriminate between and within cohorts, during both wakefulness and sleep. In both cases, we identify older sub-cohorts that explain almost all the variance, between old and young populations, found in the static analysis. We observed a cross-over interaction effect between thought content scores and age cohort. This may be explained by the middle temporal gyrus acting as a compensatory pathway for past thinking in older subjects. In our final analysis, we found brain states most correlated across sleep and wakeful datasets were associated with the younger population. This was expected, since the facility to sleep decreases with age. We also observed less correlation between brain states of old and young cohorts during sleep than when awake, highlighting sleep as an interesting source for age-related research. In sum, our method provides insight into heterogeneities in older populations beyond standard static analysis. This underscores the importance of delineating underlying brain states in aging studies. Further, since the method is data-driven, it can be applied to datasets without previous knowledge of pathology. Considering the method can be applied across datasets, it offers a promising tool to identify biomarkers in future studies. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sylvain Baillet</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z70k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440w067</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vd82n"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Age related variations in gene expression patterns of renal cell carcinoma - Biological and translational implications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Feulner, Lara Michele</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le carcinome à cellules rénales (CCR) est connu pour se manifester à travers un large spectre d'âges traversant les changements organiques liés à l'âge, mais on en connait peu sur la façon dont le processus de vieillissement peut affecter l'évolution du CCR et le répertoire des gènes impliqués. J'ai donc examiné les associations entre l'âge des patients et les profils d'expression génique dans les tumeurs CCR et les tissus rénaux normaux. Les données de The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA, n = 436) et du International Cancer Genome Consortium (ICGC) Cancer Genomics of the Kidney (CAGEKID, n = 89) ont été analysées afin d'identifier les voies et les processus cellulaires affectés par le vieillissement dans le contexte du CCR.Mon analyse a révélé différents spectres d'expression génique dépendant de l'âge dans les tumeurs CCR et les tissus rénaux normaux. Ces résultats étaient significatifs et reproductibles dans les deux ensembles de données examinés (p &lt; 2.2 × 10-16). Dans les cellules normales, les gènes ayant une expression plus élevée chez les patients âgés étaient significativement enrichis (FDR &lt;0.05) pour les voies associées à la réponse immunitaire, à la formation de collagène et à la signalisation de la sémaphorine, tandis que dans les cellules cancéreuses ces gènes étaient enrichis pour les voies de métabolisme et d'oxydation. De manière frappante, les gènes ayant une expression moins élevée chez les patients âgés dans les cellules normales étaient également enrichis pour le métabolisme et l'oxydation, tandis que ceux des tumeurs étaient enrichis pour l'organisation de la matrice extracellulaire. Une analyse in silico des cibles médicamenteuses potentielles utilisant des outils de cartographie de la connectivité a prédit l'efficacité préférentielle des inhibiteurs de la phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K) ou de l'immunothérapie en association avec l'âge.Conclusion: Je rapporte des interrelations jusqu'alors méconnues entre le cycle de vie humain et le CCR, suggérant des effets possibles de l'âge sur la réponse aux traitements médicamenteux.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Renal cell carcinoma (RCC) is known to occur across a wide age spectrum traversing age-related organismal changes, however little is known as to how the aging process may affect the course of RCC and the repertoire of genes involved. I therefore examined associations between patient age and the gene expression profiles in RCC tumors and normal kidney tissues. Datasets from The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA, n=436) and the International Cancer Genome Consortium (ICGC) Cancer Genomics of the Kidney (CAGEKID, n=89) were analyzed for pathways and cellular processes that are affected by aging in RCC. My analysis revealed different age dependent gene expression spectra in RCC tumors and normal kidney tissues. These findings were significant and reproducible in both datasets examined (p &lt; 2.2 × 10-16). Age-upregulated genes, that is genes that show higher expression in older patients, in normal cells were significantly enriched (FDR&lt;0.05) for pathways associated with immune response, collagen formation and semaphorin signaling, whereas age-upregulated genes in tumors were enriched for metabolism and oxidation pathways. Strikingly, age-downregulated genes in normal cells were also enriched for metabolism and oxidation, while those in tumors were enriched for extracellular matrix organization. Further in silico analysis of potential drug targets using connectivity mapping tools predicted preferential efficacy of Phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K) inhibitors or immunotherapy in association with age.Conclusion: I report on hitherto unrecognized interrelations between human life cycle and RCC, suggesting possible effects of age on response to drug treatments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janusz Rak</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Yasser Riaz Alhosseini</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z78j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd82n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw812"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Negotiating risk and autonomy: Teenage girls' involvement with child protection in the aftermath of sexual abuse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carlton, Rosemary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse s'avance sur le terrain encore inexploré de l'intersection des expériences de la participation des services de protection de la jeunesse (DPJ) et l'adolescence féminine d'adolescentes ayant subi des abus sexuels.  Il faut tout d'abord comprendre que les notions de risque et d'autonomie font figure centrale dans ce terrain. Cette thèse explore comment les adolescentes et les professionnels de la DPJ comprennent et naviguent les préoccupations de risque et le souhait d'autonomie de ces dernières à la suite d'abus sexuels.  Selon un cadre interprétatif axé sur les filles et une approche d'étude de cas à la recherche qualitative, cette thèse cherche à mettre les voix des filles, leurs situations et leurs expériences au premier plan et à faire la lumière sur des comptes rendus exhaustifs et nuancés du risque et de l'autonomie tels qu'ils sont compris et gérés dans le contexte de la participation de la DPJ auprès des adolescentes victimes d'abus sexuels.S'appuyant sur des connaissances théoriques élaborées dans les études érudites sur la législation, les politiques et les pratiques de la DPJ et sur le contexte élargi de l'État providence canadien dans lequel la DPJ est intégrée ainsi que sur les études féministes sur la construction discursive de la jeunesse féminine, cette thèse aborde les influences des idéologies dominantes de la pensée sur le risque, néolibérales et postféministes sur l'implication des adolescentes ayant subi des abus sexuels avec la DPJ. L'argument central est que ce point de vue contribue à caractériser les adolescentes qui ont subi des abus sexuels d'une part comme étant à risque, donc ayant besoin de l'intervention professionnelle des services de la DPJ, d'autre part comme se rapprochant de l'autonomie des femmes adultes, et tenues notamment responsables de reconnaître et de gérer les circonstances de risque dans leurs vies. Cette thèse illustre comment ces deux caractéristiques apparemment divergentes servent à transformer des adolescentes abusées sexuellement en sujets néolibéraux et postféministes régulièrement jugés sur leurs capacités et leurs échecs à assurer leur propre sécurité face à une multitude de risques associés non seulement aux abus sexuels qu'elles ont subis, mais aussi à leurs propres comportements à risque et à leur transition vers l'autonomie. De cette façon, les adolescentes ayant connu des abus sexuels sont considérées comme étant capables de reconnaître et de gérer le risque et de participer dans leur autonomie future nonobstant leurs situations. Les filles qui démontrent une réticence ou une incapacité sont perçues comme ayant échoué dans leur autoprotection donc ayant recours à des interventions protectrices de plus en plus intensives de la part la DPJ. Cette dissertation se conclut avec une discussion sur l'impact de ces observations sur les politiques et les pratiques de la DPJ ainsi que sur les recherches examinant l'implication des filles abusées sexuellement avec la DPJ. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This dissertation ventures into the previously uncharted terrain of sexually abused teenage girls' intersecting experiences of the involvement of child protection services (CPS) and female adolescence. Starting with an appreciation of the notions of risk and autonomy as central features of this terrain, this dissertation explores how teenage girls and CPS professionals understand and negotiate concerns for risk and aspirations for girls' autonomy in the aftermath of sexual abuse. Employing a girl-centred interpretive framework and a case-study approach to qualitative research, this dissertation seeks to privilege girls' voices, circumstances and experiences and to unearth in-depth and nuanced accounts of risk and autonomy as they are understood and negotiated within the context of sexually abused teenage girls' involvement with CPS. Drawing from theoretical insights developed in scholarship attending to CPS legislation, policy and practice and the larger context of Canada's welfare state within which CPS is embedded as well as Girls' Studies scholarship on discursive constructions of contemporary girlhood, this dissertation elaborates on the influence of prevailing risk thinking, neoliberal and postfeminist ideologies on sexually abused teenage girls' involvement with CPS. The central argument is that these perspectives intersect in ways that contribute to the identification of sexually abused teenage girls as simultaneously at-risk – and thus subject to the protective efforts of CPS professionals – and verging on autonomous womanhood – and thus deemed responsible for recognising and managing circumstances of risk in their lives. This dissertation illustrates how these seemingly competing identifications serve to transform sexually abused teenage girls into neoliberal/postfeminist subjects who are regularly scrutinised for their capacities and failures to assure their own safety from a host of risks associated not only with sexual abuse, but also with their own risky behaviours as well as their transition to autonomous womanhood. In this way, sexually abused teenage girls are construed as willing and able to recognise and manage risk and to participate in investing in their future autonomy regardless of their circumstances. Those girls demonstrating unwillingness or inability are viewed as having failed in their responsibilities of self-protection and thus subject to increasingly intensive protective interventions on the part of CPS. The dissertation concludes with a discussion of the implications of these findings for CPS policy and practice as well as research dealing with sexually abused teenage girls involved with CPS. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Julia Krane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v7867.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw812</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80hx826"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social and learning context profiles of, barriers faced by and proposed solutions for at-risk emerging adults in Montreal adult education centres</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harb, Rawda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using Arnett's (2000) coined term "emerging adults" to refer to youths between the ages of 17 and 25 years old, this thesis aims to honour the perspectives of emerging adults attending adult education centres in Montreal, document a glimpse of their successes and obstacles, and be witness to their journey. This thesis constructs and discusses a social and learning context profile of emerging adults that is inclusive of their identities, their living and learning contexts and the obstacles they are facing and proposes possible actions to mitigate those issues. To this end, it leverages a literary review, the author's professional experiences as an adult educator, and data from an anonymous survey of 240 students fitting this profile. An additional summary of feedback provided by adult learners who identified as 25+ years old is attached as an appendix – though they fell outside the scope of this research, they nonetheless constitute an important part of the adult education population, and their stories should be heard. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En utilisant le terme « adultes émergents » d'Arnett (2000) pour parler des jeunes âgés de 17 à 25 ans, Cette thèse vise à honorer les points de vue des adultes émergents qui fréquentent des centres d'éducation des adultes à Montréal, à documenter un aperçu de leurs réussites et de leurs obstacles, et à témoigner de leur parcours. En utilisant une revue littéraire, les expériences professionnelles de l'auteur en tant qu'éducateur d'adultes et les résultats d'un sondage anonyme auprès de 240 étudiants correspondant à ce profil, cette thèse construit et discute un profil de contexte social et d'apprentissage des adultes émergents qui inclut leurs identités, leurs contextes de vie et d'apprentissage ainsi que les obstacles auxquels ils sont confrontés, puis propose des actions possibles pour atténuer ces problèmes. Il y a également un résumé des résultats sur les apprenants adultes de plus de 25 ans joints en annexe, car ils constituent une partie importante de la population de l'éducation des adultes, et leurs histoires doivent être entendues.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lisa Trimble</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qp492.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx826</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r3368"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A concept of critical feeling: a proposed basis for research in the teaching and evaluation of creativity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blackburn, Richard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first part of the analysis, Act 1: Divergence, exposes the problem of prioritizing critical thinking in the language arts curriculum.  An emphasis on criticality is discordant with the way in which individuals ascribe—and, indeed, make meaning.  Affect is a necessary precondition to conceptualization.  As such, rather than a focus on critical thinking, the author proposes an emphasis on critical feeling, defined as an affective stance of inquiry as the intuitive consideration of possibility that sparks imagination.  The concept of critical feeling is grounded in the way artists assess the perceptual quality of meaning using affective inquiry, analogous to the way in which scientists assess the conceptual quality of meaning using critical inquiry.  Critical feeling is understood in relation to Susanne Langer's theory of presentational abstraction.  Langer's metaphysics of feeling proposes an artistic inquiry paradigm, which the author uses to explain how documentary's production phases of scripting, shooting and editing externalize sub-processes of artistic creativity as acts of impulsive, actualized and consummated experience that can be taught as critical feeling's dynamic processes of feeling, seeing and saying.  In parallel with an exploration of the concept of critical feeling, the author expounds the suitability of a grounded theory methodology for an exploration of creative processes.  In flipping the scientific method's hypothesis-exposition-demonstration dynamic, grounded theory methodology holds the greatest promise for preserving the integrity of artistic knowledge. The second part, Act 2: Emergence, explicates the concept of critical feeling from an educational neuroscientific perspective.  The power of storytelling is explained by the primacy of affective experience and emotional response in understanding the world around us.  Langer's metaphysical frame provides a bio-psychological grounding for the author's proposition; that storytelling's process of affective inquiry produces meaning from feeling and storymaking's process of emergence produces feeling from experience—much like proto-language allows for non-discursive communication.  The dynamic reality of the creative advance is a cycle of divergence, emergence and convergence that we respond to as possibility, actuality and presentation and recognize as intuition, imagination and affirmation.  What we feel is the emotional situation of our body states, simulative and actual, created from the processes of our dynamic reality of self-production.  The standard creative practices of long form narrative documentary filmmaking are conceptualized as an exosomatic model of the creative processes of storymaking, revealing their great potential for teaching creativity without dilution of the artistic voice.Act 3: Convergence develops the pedagogical implications of the concept of critical feeling.  If creativity is conceptualized metaphorically as a consideration of possibility, then the dynamics of artistic production are reminiscent of the means by which children naturally produce knowledge using creativity's basic social processes of feeling, seeing and saying along an emotion-affect-feeling circuit.  Documentary's storymaking model is particularly effective for teaching creativity in that it emulates the processual flow of the creative advance—flashes are more frequent during scripting; shooting is designed to produce moments; and editing is conducive to responding to the voices that emerge from the material—allowing for a presentational immediacy conducive to artistic expression.  The author concludes by proposing a productionist stance of inquiry, building on Antonio Damasio's feeling of knowing and inversing Mary Helen Immordino-Yan's emotional thought sequence of creative processes to develop an approach to teaching writing as production emphasizing affective participation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le texte qui suit est divisé en trois actes. L'Acte 1: Divergence, expose le problème que crée la prédominance de la pensée critique dans les programmes d'enseignement de la langue anglaise. Mettre l'emphase sur la criticalité compromet le processus naturel selon lequel un individu donne un sens à ses expériences. L'affectivité est une précondition nécessaire à la conceptualisation. Ainsi, plutôt que de miser sur la pensée critique, l'auteur propose de prioriser l'impression critique.  Il définit impression critique comme étant une exploration affective qui stimule l'imagination en permettant la considération intuitive du possible. Ce concept s'ancre dans la façon qu'ont les artistes d'évaluer la qualité perceptive d'un contenu par le biais d'une exploration affective.Le concept d'impression critique est analysé en référence à la théorie de l'abstraction de Susanne Langer.  L'auteur s'inspire de la métaphysique des expériences sensorielles de Langer afin de dresser un paradigme d'exploration artistique, sur lequel il appuie sa démonstration voulant que les phases de production du film documentaire externalisent les processus sous-jacents de la créativité. Tels des actes d'expérience impulsive, actuelle et consommée, ces processus peuvent être enseignés à titre de dynamiques de l'impression critique, soit le sentir, le voir et le dire. Parallèlement à son exploration du concept d'impression critique, l'auteur examine la pertinence d'une méthodologie de la théorie ancrée. Renversant la dynamique de l'hypothèse-exposition-démonstration propre à la méthode expérimentale, la méthodologie de la théorie ancrée s'avère fort prometteuse pour préserver l'intégrité du savoir artistique.La deuxième partie, Acte 2: Émergence, aborde le concept d'impression critique d'un point de vue neuropédagogique. Le pouvoir du récit réside dans la primauté de l'expérience affective pour notre compréhension du monde. La théorie métaphysique de Langer fournit un fondement biopsychologique à la proposition de l'auteur, soit que l'exploration affective d'un récit stimule la signification par le biais de l'émotion, alors que la création d'un récit stimule la signification par le biais de l'expérience. La réalité dynamique de l'avancée créatrice est un cycle de divergence, d'émergence et de convergence auquel nous répondons par la possibilité, l'actualité et la présentation et que nous reconnaissons à titre d'intuition, d'imagination et d'affirmation.  Nous ressentons la situation émotive de notre vécu physique, simulée ou réelle, qui résulte des processus dynamiques de l'autoproduction. Les pratiques créatives propres à la production du film documentaire servent de modèle exosomatique du processus de la création du récit, révélant leur grand potentiel pour l'enseignement de la créativité.L'Acte 3: Convergence énonce les implications pédagogiques du concept d'impression critique.  Si la créativité peut être conçue comme étant la considération du possible, la production artistique se rapproche de la façon qu'ont les enfants de produire leur savoir en usant des processus créatifs sous-jacents que sont le sentir, le voir et le dire, et ce tout au long d'un circuit d'émotion, d'affectivité et d'impression. La création du récit documentaire est particulièrement utile à l'enseignement de la créativité, car elle imite le flux processuel de l'avancée créatrice—les flashs sont fréquents durant la scénarisation; le tournage produit des moments; le montage permet aux voix d'émerger du matériel—le tout permettant une immédiateté susceptible de stimuler l'expression artistique. En conclusion, l'auteur propose un paradigme d'exploration affective, le productionisme, qui s'inspire du concept d'impression du savoir d'Antonio Damasio et inverse la théorie de la séquence mentale du processus créatif de Mary Helen Immordino-Yan, afin de développer une approche d'enseignement de l'écriture misant sur la production et la participation affective.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boyd Eric White</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Christopher Stonebanks</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1618557.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r3368</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613n097x"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aging in the context of immigration and care labour: The experiences of older Filipinos in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ferrer, Ilyan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette dissertation doctorale examine de quelles manières les intersections entre l'immigration, le travail et les soins ont un impact sur la vie tardive des Philippin.e.s âgé.e.s au Canada. Une ethnographie critique fût adoptée pour comprendre la réciprocité des expériences vécues, des identités et des politiques (spécifiquement liées à la retraite, au vieillissement et à l'immigration). Des nombreuses observations et des entrevues approfondies semi-structurées avec 18 personnes âgées, 6 enfants adultes et 13 intervenant.e.s communautaires ont identifié les barrières structurelles qui empiètent sur les expériences quotidiennes de vieillissement au sein de la diaspora Philippin-Canadienne vivant à Montréal. Plusieurs thématiques ont émergé incluant (1) la rupture entre les discours sur l'immigration, la migration, ainsi que les manières dont les personnes racisées âgées sont accueillies dans la société canadienne, (2) les intersections entre l'immigration et les politiques de retraite et leurs impacts sur les femmes Philippines âgées œuvrant dans le travail domestique, et (3) les façons dont les Philippin.e.s adultes plus âgé.e.s fournissent et reçoivent des soins dans des contextes intergénérationnels et transnationaux en réponse à la pénurie et à la rareté de ressources formelles. Les résultats de cette étude offrent un nouveau savoir sur les impacts de l'immigration et des politiques de travail sur les expériences vécues du vieillissement et des pratiques de soins parmi les membres les plus âgé.e.s des communautés immigrantes racisées du Nord global en général, ainsi qu'à l'intérieur des communautés Philippines au Canada spécifiquement. Cette étude se conclut en proposant des recommandations clefs liées aux politiques, pratiques et recherches en travail social dans le domaine du vieillissement et de l'immigration.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This doctoral dissertation examines how the intersections of immigration, labour, and care impact the late life experiences of older Filipinos in Canada. A critical ethnography was adopted to understand the interplay of lived experiences, identities, and policies (specifically related to retirement, aging, and immigration). Extended observations and in-depth semi-structured interviews with 18 older people, 6 adult children, and 13 community stakeholders identified the structural barriers that impinged on everyday experiences of aging within the Filipino Canadian diaspora living in Montreal. Several themes emerged including (1) the disjuncture between discourses on immigration and migration and the ways in which older racialized newcomers are welcomed into Canadian society, (2) the intersections between immigration and retirement policies and their impact on older Filipina women engaged in domestic work, and (3) the ways in which Filipino older adults provide and receive care in intergenerational and transnational settings in response to the paucity and scarcity of formal resources. The findings of this study offer new knowledge about the impact of immigration and labour policies on the lived experiences of aging and care practices among older members of racialized and immigrant communities in the Global North generally, and within Filipino communities in Canada specifically. This study concludes by proposing key recommendations related to social work policy, practice, and research in the field of aging and immigration.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shari Brotman</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Amanda Marie Grenier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wq14t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n097x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nh09r"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expressing writing with adolescents: revealing secrets what's really going on?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farella, Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RésuméCette thèse examine les processus émotionnels, psychologiques et cognitifs complexes d'une intervention d'expression écrite (EC) dont des adolescents font l'expérience dans un cadre scolaire. Plus spécifiquement, son objectif premier est l'évaluation de journaux à la recherche d'éléments d'hypothèses récurrentes avancées dans la littérature pour expliquer le pourquoi et le comment du fonctionnement de l'EC en répondant à deux interrogations clés : Quels sont les processus émotionnels, psychologiques et cognitifs impliqués dans l'EC, et comment est-ce que ces processus se reflètent dans les journaux des étudiants durant l'intervention d'EC ? L'étude sur le terrain s'est étendue sur quatre semaines, et les données ont été générées au moyen d'un échantillonnage aléatoire de journaux d'étudiants. L'analyse des données combine une approche thématique analytique inductive à une approche conceptuelle analytique déductive afin de comprendre les journaux des étudiants et comporte l'exploration de chaque journal au moyen de 8 théories sur les mécanismes sous-jacents du fonctionnement de l'EC dans la mesure où ils ont un impact sur les adolescents. Les résultats de la classification thématique effectuée dans le cadre de cette étude montrent que 3 des 5 hypothèses avancées dans la littérature sur les mécanismes sous-jacents présumés sont apparues dans les journaux des étudiants avec les résultats suivants : la plus robuste a été l'hypothèse de la régulation émotionnelle /autorégulation;  l'hypothèse de l'adaptation occupait le troisième rang; et le traitement cognitif, le quatrième. De plus, deux des hypothèses avancées par l'auteur (non récurrentes dans la littérature) ont été vérifiées avec l'autonomisation au deuxième rang et l'hypothèse du bien-être au cinquième rang.  Aussi, la classification thématique inductive a montré que les trois thèmes se dégageant le plus souvent dans les journaux des étudiants touchaient les capacités des étudiants à : (a) favoriser des perspectives saines/des perceptions positives accrues; (b) appliquer les enseignements des interventions dans d'autres contextes; et (c) réfléchir à la façon dont leur expérience peut influer sur les autres après la conclusion de l'intervention d'EC. Les conclusions de cette étude illustrent que ces observations appuient l'idée que les hypothèses de processus cognitif, de régulation émotionnelle /autorégulation et d'adaptation (que l'on retrouve toutes dans la littérature antérieure) ainsi que l'hypothèse de l'autonomisation et celle du bien-être (proposées par l'auteur de cette étude) peuvent représenter des mécanismes sous-jacents importants pouvant contribuer à expliquer la façon dont l'EC influe sur les états mentaux des adolescents. De plus, les conclusions de cette étude sont à l'effet que même si dans le cadre de cette étude des éléments appuyant des hypothèses de désinhibition des émotions, d'exposition/habituation ou de constructivisme ne sont pas apparus dans l'analyse, l'absence de résultats est probablement la conséquence de la méthodologie expérimentale retenue plutôt qu'un argument à l'effet que ces hypothèses ne sont pas des hypothèses pertinentes. Mots clés: Qualitatif, expression écrite, adolescents, école, santé mentale, communication émotionnelle,  journaux, intervention.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>AbstractThis thesis explores the complexity of the emotional, psychological and cognitive processes of an expressive writing intervention experienced by adolescents in a school-based setting. More specifically, the primary objective is to evaluate the journals written by participating adolescents for evidence of recurring theories proposed in the literature to explain why and how expressive writing works. This study aimed to answer two key questions: What are the emotional, psychological and cognitive processes of expressive writing, and how are these processes reflected in the students' journals during the expressive writing intervention? The expressive writing intervention proceeded for four weeks, and data was generated through randomized collection of student journals. Data analysis combines both methods of thematic inductive and conceptual deductive analysis for understanding the student journals and consisted of exploring each journal for evidence of  8 theories that could explain the underlying mechanisms of how expressive writing may operate to impact adolescents. The results from the conceptual deductive analysis find that 3 of the 5 theories proposed in the literature as suspected underlying mechanisms appeared in the student journals with the following results: emotion regulation/self-regulation theory was the strongest; empowerment theory being the second strongest theory, coping theory the third strongest; and cognitive processing the fourth strongest and well-being theory being the fifth. Also, thematic inductive analysis showed that the three most common themes emerging from the journals were the students' abilities to: 1) have a healthier outlook/more positive perception; 2) apply the intervention teachings in other contexts; and 3) think about how their story can impact others after they had completed the expressive writing intervention. In conclusion these findings support the idea that cognitive processing, emotion/self-regulation and coping theories- all suggested in the literature- as well as empowerment and well-being theories -proposed by the author of this study- may be important underlying mechanisms that help explain how expressive writing impacts adolescents' mental states.  Furthermore, the study concludes that even though evidence for emotional disinhibition, exposure/habituation and constructivism theories did not appear in the analysis, this lack of finding is more likely an artifact of the experimental methodology rather than evidence that these theories are not relevant theories. Keywords: Qualitative, expressive writing, adolescents, school, mental health, emotional disclosure, journals, intervention.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Danielle Groleau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd04v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nh09r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychiatry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k747f"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Songs Without Music : Aesthetic Dimensions of Law and Justice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manderson, Desmond</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Romances sans musique traite des dimensions esthétiques qui sont au cœur du droit et de la justice. L'esthétique définit l'ensemble de nos réactions aux images et aux sensations auxquelles nous sommes exposes en permanence et qui, par leurs associations symboliques, influencent de manière sensible nos valeurs et notre société. L'esthétique du droit implique que le discours juridique, lui aussi, est fondamentalement régi par la rhétorique, la métaphore, la forme, les images, les symboles. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Songs Without Music is about the aesthetic dimensions which lie at the heart of law and justice. Aesthetics is the faculty which reacts to the images and sensory input to which we are constantly exposed, and which, by their symbolic associations, significantly influence our values and our society. 'Legal aesthetics' suggests that legal discourse too is fundamentally governed by rhetoric and metaphor, form, images and symbols. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Somerville, Margaret A.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Macdonald, Roderick A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365753t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k747f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law and aesthetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semantics (Law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Symbolism in law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913s24j"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantification of Iron in Al-Si Foundry Alloys via Thermal Analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mackay, Robert Ian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Iron content in aluminum-silicon casting alloys, which contribute to the formation of Al5FeSi intermetallic, can be very detrimental to the physical properties of the final cast part. Because of the brittle and hard nature of the Al5FeSi intermetallic, machining of casting parts can be difficult and costly to the foundry due to the need to increase operating horse power of the machining apparatus and reduced tool life. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En contribuant à la formation d'intermétalliques Al5FeSi, le fer présent dans les alliages de fonderie d'aluminium-silicium peut être préjudiciable aux propriétés physiques du produit coule final. La nature dure et fragile des intermétalliques Al5FeSi peut rendre l'usinage des produits coules, difficile et couteux pour la fonderie à cause de la nécessite d'augmenter la puissance de l'appareil d'usinage et de la durée de vie réduite de l'outil. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gruzleski, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v63n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s24j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Thermal analysis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qc12n"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Glucocorticoid receptor expression in target cells: ligand regulation, target gene responses and immunocytochemical localization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Cunxian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Trois aspects de l'expression du récepteur pour glucocorticoïde (GR) ont été étudiés. Premièrement, une méthode radioimmunologique a été utilisée pour quantifier le niveau de protéines du récepteur chez le rat. Les résultats démontrent que la régulation de l'expression du récepteur par le glucocorticoïde est spécifique a chaque tissu. Les niveaux de GR ont diminué suite à l'administration de glucocorticoïdes dans les oreillettes des rats adrenalectomises, le foie, les ventricules, l'hypophyse, l'hypothalamus et l'hippocampe, et ont diminué dans les oreillettes des rats intacts et dans la rate. Les niveaux de GR dans le thymus ont répondu de manière diphasique en fonction du temps en réponse aux glucocorticoïdes, en présentant initialement une augmentation suivie d'une baisse des niveaux de GR. Deuxièmement, la signification de la régulation spécifique des GR a été étudiée dans le tissu cardiaque en utilisant le facteur natriurétique des oreillettes (ANF) comme gène cible modèle du GR. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Three aspects of the expression of the glucocorticoid receptor (GR) in rat tissues were examined. First, by using a radioimmunoassay to quantitate GR levels, a tissue-specific regulation of GR expression by glucocorticoids was found. While GR levels were decreased by glucocorticoids in cardiac atria of adrenalectomized rats, liver, cardiac ventricles, pituitary, hypothalamus and hippocampus, they were increased in the cardiac atria of the intact rats and spleen. GR levels in the thymus showed a biphasic time response to glucocorticoids, with an initial increase of GR level followed by a decrease. Second, the relevance of the tissue-specific regulation of GR was investigated in the cardiac tissues, using atrial natriuretic factor (ANF) as a model target gene to GR. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Osmond, Dennis G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773z064.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qc12n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Genes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021h57d"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bottom Up Design for Software Reuse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yao, Jianxiang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La réutilisation de logiciels est reconnue comme une fa con réaliste et efficace pour améliorer la productivité du développement de logiciels, et la qualité des produits de développement. La pratique de la réutilisation se heurte à plusieurs types d'obstacles, tant administratifs, qu'organisationnels, économiques, et techniques. Sur le plan technique, les deux défis majeurs sont de: 1) développer des composantes réutilisables "par construction", et 2) développer un environnement qui supporte le développement AVEC des composantes réutilisables. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>It is widely believed that software reusability is a very important method for the improvement of software development process, and for increasing software development productivity. Generally speaking, the activities of software reuse include two aspects: a) building reusable software components, and b) developing efficient methods and tools to support the reuse of existing reusable software components. SoftClass is one of such tools [13]. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Friedman, N.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mili, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301377s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h57d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Software design</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107133t"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Applications of Brauer Induction to Artin L-Functions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yamaji, Minatsu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis we introduce Brauer's induction theorem and its application to Artin's L-functions. We also see several zeta functions, including Artin's L-functions, and their relations.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse nous introduisons le théorème induction de Brauer et son application aux fonctions L d'Artin. Nous faisons aussi une étude de plusieur fonctions zêta, inclus les fonctions L d'Artin, et leurs relations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murty, Ram</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236447x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107133t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brauer induction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p704d"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A CMOS Foveated Image Sensor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wodnicki, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Future mobile robots are expected to demonstrate a greater awareness of their environment through the use of computer vision algorithms presently under development. With the help of machine vision sensors, mobile robots would be able to detect looming objects well ahead of a collision. Such mobile robots would 'see' far greater distances than is possible with conventional range imaging. They would be able to map out their immediate surroundings passively without the need for expending energy to drive laser or SONAR range finders. With the help of higher-level algorithms, mobile robots would begin to recognize objects in the world around them and use this information to direct their own actions. The potential exists for the application of advanced prototypes of these machines in dangerous circumstances such as space exploration and maintenance of deep sea pipe-lines. […]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t91z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p704d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>CMOS</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w695k"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Measurments of Turbulent Structures Over a Canopy Using Split Film Anemometry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smyth, Carolyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has been shown previously that coherent structures are important in the transport of heat, gases, turbulent kinetic energy and momentum. Consequently, a thorough description and understanding of these structures permits a better understanding of the boundary layer and its interactions with the surface. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il était prouvé que les structures cohérentes sont importantes dans le transport de chaleur, des gaz, de l'énergie turbulente et de la quantité de mouvement. Conséquemment, un approfondissement de la connaissance des structures cohérentes permet d'améliorer la modélisation de la structure de la couche limite et de ses interactions avec la surface. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leclerc, Monique</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c067s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w695k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anemometry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw37639290"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Effects of Sodium Flouride on the Reproductive Performance of the Male American kestrel (Falco sparverius) and the Japanese quail (Cotumix japonica)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shutt, Laird</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to evaluate the effects of exposure to fluoride on avian reproduction, male American kestrels (Falco sparverius) and Japanese quail (Cotumix japonica) were chronically treated with sodium fluoride and paired with untreated females. Forty male American kestrels were randomly assigned to one of the following treatments: 1.65, 3.3, or 6.6 mg NaF or a control solution of 13.2 mg NaHC03 administered by oral gavage daily for 45 days. In the first year of the study all males were paired with untreated females upon completion of dosing. In the second year dosing of the males continued for 15 days after pairing with undosed females. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Afin d'évaluer les effets de !'exposition au fluor sur la reproduction d'oiseaux mâles, des crécerelles d'Amérique (Falco sparverius) et des cailles japonaises (Cotumix japonica) ont été traitées avec du fluor de sodium pendant une période de temps prolonge puis couplées avec des femelles non traitées. Quarante crécerelles d'Amérique males ont été assignées de façon aléatoire a un des traitements suivants: 1,65, 3,3 ou 6,6 mg NaF ou une solution contrôle de 13,2 mg NaHC03 administres par gavage oral quotidiennement pendant 45 jours. Durant la première année tous les males ont été couplés avec des femelles non traitées dès la complétion du dosage. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qm17n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37639290</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Japanese quail -- Reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sodium fluoride</dc:subject><dc:subject>American kestrel -- Reproduction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149r974"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pipe Conveying Fluid : a Paradigm of Nonlinear Dynamics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Semler, Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with the nonlinear dynamics of a flexible pipe conveying fluid. It consists of a series of seven articles, published or submitted for publication, describing the dynamical behaviour of this generally nonconservative system. It is endeavoured to show that the system of a pipe conveying fluid has become a new paradigm of nonlinear dynamics. In particular, the nonlinear behaviour of (i) a pipe with a spring support, (ii) a pipe impacting on physical constraints, (iii) a pipe fitted with a small end-mass at the free end, and (iv) a pipe conveying unsteady sinusoidal flow is examined. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse traite de la dynamique non linéaire d'un tube flexible parcouru par un fluide. Elle consiste en une série de sept articles publies ou soumis pour publication et décrivant le comportement dynamique de ce système généralement nonconservatif. Le but de la thèse est de montrer que le tube parcouru par un fluide est devenu un nouveau paradigme de la dynamique non linéaire. En particulier, plusieurs configurations différentes et le comportement non linéaire sont étudies: (i) un tube supporte par un ressort, {ii) un tube heurtant des contraintes physiques, (iii) un tube auquel une petite masse est ajoutée au bout, et (iv) un tube soumis à un écoulement sinusoïdal non constant. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Païdoussis, M. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b71r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r974</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pipe</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225d442"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Integration of stereoscopic video in image guided neurosurgery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pisani, Laura Jean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes a technique to establish live feedback to the image-guided neurosurgery environment, in the form of stereoscopic video scenes from the operating room. The video scenes are superimposed on images presently available in image-guided neurosurgery. The effect of displaying these superimposed images stereoscopically is that the viewer's natural, binocular vision appears to penetrate the patient's head, and to reveal internal anatomy.  […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse décrit une technique qui fournit au système de neurochirurgie guidée par images électroniques, un feed-back continuel, sous la forme de deux scènes vidéos en stéréo de la chambre d'opération. On superpose les scènes vidéos sur des images qu'on emploie présentement dans le système de neurochirurgies guidée par images électroniques. La superposition de ces deux genres d'images en stéréo donne l'effet que, la vision binoculaire naturelle de l'observateur pénètre la tête du patient et expose la structure anatomique interne. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peters, T. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v279.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d442</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj1394411"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A Mass Driven Semi-Geostrophic Model of the Leeuwin Current</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oxilia, David M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The general features of the Leeuwin Current, located off the west coast of Australia are described. A comparison between the Leeuwin Current and other eastern boundary currents reveals the unique character of this coastal flow. An overview of recent studies pertaining to the dynamics of the Leeuwin Current is also presented. An outcropping reduced gravity steady state semi-geostrophic model of the Leeuwin Current is then developed. The system is described by geostrophy in the alongshore direction and is fully non-linear in the offshore direction. The current is driven by a specified Indonesian throughflow at the northern end of the model domain. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les caractéristiques générales du Courant de Leeuwin qui se trouve le long de la côte ouest de l'Australie sont décrites. Une comparaison entre le Courant de Leeuwin et d'autres courants côtiers démontre que cet écoulement côtier est unique. Une description d'études récentes sur la dynamique du Courant de Leeuwin est aussi présentée. Un modèle semi-géostrophique en régime permanent de gravite réduite du Courant de Leeuwin, dont les lignes isopycnales intersectent la surface, est donc formule. Le système suppose l'équilibre géostrophique clans la direction parallèle a la cote et utilise les équations non-linéaires clans la direction perpendiculaire. Le courant est force par l'écoulement Indonésien clans le nord du domaine. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Straub, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sj080.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1394411</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leeuwin Current</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr92h"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Analysis of Sea Ice Cover with the Use of Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) Imagery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ouellet, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'utilité des images radars de type ROS, ou radar a ouverture synthétique, est démontrée pour l'analyse et l'observation de la glace de mer dans le Golfe du Saint-Laurent. Les données ROS servent à identifier les différents types de glace du couvert, de même qu'à entreprendre une analyse statistique de la taille et la forme des "floes". La plupart des études sur le couvert de glace à partir d'images ROS se font pour les régions polaires comme l'Arctique, et par conséquent, très peu d'ouvrages sont consacrés à l'observation des glaces de type jeune caractéristiques de la région du Golfe. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The role of Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) images for observing and analyzing sea ice cover is demonstrated for the Gulf of St-Lawrence. The SAR data is used to identify the various types of ice composing the ice cover and to derive statistics on the size and shape of ice floes. Most of the previous studies on sea ice using SAR data were performed for Arctic regions. Very few studies to date have specifically addressed issues related to the analysis of SAR imagery in the Gulf of St-Lawrence, which is characterized by the predominance of young ice features that are more difficult to identify. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chouinard, Luc E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k9592.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr92h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k748q"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Luteinizing Hormone and the Hastening of Sexual Maturity in the American Kestrel, Falco Sparverius</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Muir, Meloni Mary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Plasma concentrations of luteinizing hormone (W) and body weights were measured in adult female and male, paired and unpaired, American kestrels (Falco sparverius) during first and subsequent breeding seasons in captivity. The influence of photomanipulation on sexual maturation and the possibility of increasing the number of breeding cycles per year in birds which have experienced hastened sexual maturity were studied by exposing juveniles to different short day photoperiods for single and multiple breeding cycles. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La concentration de !'hormone lutéinisante (lutropine) dans le plasma de crécerelles américaines (Falco sparverius) adultes mâles et femelles, accouples et non-accouples, ainsi que leurs poids, ont été mesures pendant la première et la deuxième pariade en captivité. L'influence de la photomanipulation sur la maturation sexuelle et la possibilité d'augmenter le nombre de cycles reproducteurs par année chez les oiseaux ayant eu une maturité sexuelle hâtive ont été étudiées en exposant des oiseaux juvéniles a de courtes photopériodes pendant un ou plusieurs cycles. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Etches, Rob</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Bird, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m184f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k748q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Luteinizing hormone</dc:subject><dc:subject>American kestrel -- Reproduction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx751"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis and Biological Evaluation of Iridoids and Hydrazine Compounds Against the Spruce Budworm Choristoneura fumiferana</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mohammad-Ali, Anmar Kamil</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'iridoide (-)-spécionine est connu pour son activité contre la larve d'épicéa orientale Choristoneura fumiferana. La (-)-spécionine et certains de ses dérivés ont été synthétisés à partir des iridoides naturels disporubles: aucubine et catalposide. L'éthanolyse, en présence de bromhydrate de triphénylphosphine, de l'aucubine acétylée a fourni le produit d'addition diéthoxy-tétrahydropyranne sans réarrangement du lien double au cycle cydopentène. Cette étape a produit quatre anomères, dont le deuxième plus abondant est celui qui mène à la (-)spécionine. La (-)-spécionine a aussi été préparée l partir de l'iridoide catalposide. L'enlèvement enzymatique de la partie glucide du catalposide suivie d'une éthanolyse en présence d'acide p-toluènesulfonique a produit la (-)- spécionine de façon stéréosélective.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chan, T. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc921.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx751</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Budworm</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623f906"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Performance-based correlates of health related quality of life in community dwelling persons with stroke</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McEwen, Sara Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les personnes ayant subi un accident cérébrovasculaire (ACV) ont une qualité de vie inférieure à celle des gens du même âge et en bonne santé. Cependant, jusqu'à 27% de la population ayant subi un ACV n'a jamais été étudiée parce que leurs handicaps intellectuels et de communications ne leur permettent pas de répondre aux entrevues et aux questionnaires. La mesure de la capacité physique, exécutée par les patients eux-mêmes, a été suggérée comme indicatrice de la qualité de vie pour ces personnes. Toutefois, les associations entre ces variables n'ont pas encore été étudiés. Une étude transversale des 45 personnes ayant subi un ACV un an auparavant et demeurant dans la communauté a été effectuée clans le but de déterminer les associations entre les mesures de la capacité physique et la qualité de vie reliée a la sante, telle que rapportée par les sujets. La qualité de vie a été évaluée par entrevue téléphonique, et leur capacité physique a été évaluée au domicile par une physiothérapeute. Cette étude a démontré une association évidente entre la qualité de vie reliée a la sante physique et psychologique, et certaines mesures de la capacité l’exécution des activités.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Health-related quality of life is diminished in persons with stroke as compared to age-matched, healthy individuals. Up to 27% of the stroke population have not been studied in terms of quality of life because they were unable to complete the necessary questionnaires or interviews. Performance-based measures have been suggested as a proxy to quality of life in those people, but the associations have not been evaluated. In order to determine the relationships between performance-based measures of physical function and health-related quality of life, a two-part cross-sectional study of 45 community-dwelling individuals 12 months post-stroke was conducted. The subjects' quality of life was assessed by telephone interview; as well, their physical function was evaluated at home by a physiotherapist. This study demonstrated a clear association between both mental and physical health-related quality of life and many performance-measured impairments and disabilities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mayo, Nancy</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Wood-Dauphinee, Sharon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s717n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f906</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Quality of life</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz954"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Signal Transduction of Volume Regulation in Villus Epithelial Cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacLeod, R. John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des augmentations plus ou moins importantes du volume des cellules épithéliales du jéjunum, actives dans l'absorption du Na+, entrainent l'activation des canaux K+ et er·, le flux des ions K+ et er· qui en résulte amené une diminution régulatrice de volume (DRV) qui rétablit le volume normal de la cellule. L'objectif de la présente thèse est de montrer à quel point I' importance de I' augmentation de volume est un facteur déterminant de l'activation des canaux K+ responsables de la DRV des cellules des villosités jéjunales chez le cochon d'inde. Nous avons déterminé s'il existait un lien entre les variations du pH intracellulaire (pHi) et la DRV après de faibles augmentations de volume (5 à 7 %), qui reproduisaient le gonflement cellulaire durant l'absorption du Na+ en solution, comparativement à des augmentations plus importantes de volume observées après des dilutions hypotoniques standard (dilutions de la solution isotonique de 0.7 à 0.5 fois). […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Volume increases of any magnitude in Na+ -absorbing jejunal epithelial cells result in the activation of K+ and et· channels; the resultant é and et· efflux causes a Regulatory Volume Decrease (RVD) restoring cell volume to normal. The objective of this thesis was to determine how the extent of volume increase was a determinant of the signaling of the K+ channels responsible for RVD in guinea pig jejunal villus cells. We determined whether changes in intracellular pH (pHi) were related to RVD after modest 5 to 7% volume increases, which duplicated the extent of cell swelling during Na+ -solute absorption, compared with larger volume increases observed after "standard" hypotonic (0. 7 to 0.5 x isotonic) dilutions. Cell volume determinations were made using electronic cell sizing and pHi was measured by fluorescent spectroscopy of villus cells in suspension. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hamilton, Dick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s4836.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz954</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epithelial cells</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t872h"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Role of Human Immunodeficiency Virus Type 1 Nucleocapsid Protein in Viral Replication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Xuguang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La protéine nucléocapside (NCp), la transcriptase inverse (TI), l'ARNtLys.3 et I' ARN viral font parti des macromolécules essentielles à la transcription inverse de I'ARN du virus de l'immunodéficience humaine de type I (VIH-1). Nous avons démontré que NCp7 donne une grande spécificité a la transcription inverse en stabilisant et/ou en permettant la formation du complexe ARNtLys.3/ ARN qui est reconnu par la TI pour I' initiation de la synthèse de l'ADN simple brin(-). Ceci est indiqué par la suppression de l'initiation non spécifique de la synthèse de I'ADN par l'auto-amorçage de I' ARN, ainsi que par la stimulation de l'initiation spécifique par l'ARNtLys.3. De plus, il a été démontré que la partie de l'ARNtLys.3 qui ne s'associe pas directement au site de liaison de I'amorce (Primer Binding Site: PBS) de I' ARN viral, est essentielle pour la transcription inverse efficace.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Essential macromolecules of reverse transcription of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 include nucleocapsid protein (NCp), reverse transcriptase (RT), tRNALys.3, and viral RNA. We found NCp7 conferred exquisite specificity to reverse transcription by stabilizing and/or mediating the formation of the tRNALys.3JRNA complex that is recognized by RT for initiation of (-)ssDNA synthesis, as indicated by suppression of non-specific initiation from self-primed RNAs and the concomitant stimulation of specific initiation of tRNALys.3. Moreover, the remaining portion of tRNALys.3, i.e., sequences not directly base-pairing the primer binding site (PBS) of viral RNA, was found to be essential for efficient reverse transcription to occur. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wainberg, Mark</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn99x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t872h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Immunodeficiency</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>