<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g428c"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rethinking the 'Religion of technology' thesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walker, Richard R., 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following study is an attempt to ascertain the most adequate way to understand the relationship in modernity between religion and technology. This relationship is first analyzed by looking at a common way in which technology has been categorized and discussed as representing the religion of modernity. The first chapter critically evaluates several popular and scholarly works which contain arguments for understanding that the modern world participates in some kind of 'religion of technology.' The inadequacies of these arguments are shown to arise from the problematic ways in which they invoke the meanings of both religion and technology. The suggestive possibility of viewing religion as a kind of technology leads to a consideration of how technology is being understood in the field of the philosophy of technology. The second chapter discusses the influence and responses to the conflation of technology and religion as manifestations of the same phenomenon in Euro-American philosophy. Influenced by German philosopher Martin Heidegger, this stream of thought takes as axiomatic his contention that "technique is the metaphysics of our time." The currency of the 'religion/technology' philosophy in European thought leads to a critical body of work amongst some North American philosophers concerned with a practical approach to technology. In chapters three and four the work of two of these North American philosophers, Don Ihde and Albert Borgmann, is analyzed to evaluate their responses and reactions to the metaphysical and onto-theological interpretation of technology. Their interpretations contain an inherently religious understanding of modern technology which leads to the conclusion that there is neither religion nor technology in modernity, but only religious technology and technological religion. The possibilities raised by this state of affairs are explored in the conclusion. The work of these philosophers of technology reveals how the study of religion in modernity would benefit from understanding the quotidian and material way in which religion is manifested technologically and technology religiously. Avenues of future research can address issues regarding globalization, cross-cultural technology implementation and how to understand the place of religion in global techno-culture from the development of a new praxis -oriented philosophy of technology-religion.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44ps00n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g428c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Technology -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Technology -- Religious aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion and science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jg45w"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spellbound : magic in contemporary fiction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vollick, L. Erin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines five figures associated with magic in contemporary literature: voodoo ghosts, magicians, automata, fortune tellers, and freaks. While glancing at a number of novels, this study chiefly examines five books published between 1972 and 2001: Ishmael Reed's Mumbo Jumbo, Allen Kurzweil's A Case of Curiosities, Michael Chabon's The Amazing Adventures of Kavalier &amp; Clay, Susan Sontag's The Volcano Lover, and Thomas Wharton's Salamander. In these novels, figures of magic display different aspects of the work of representation, coded as magic, as well as the effect of magic on representation. In fiction, magic localizes enchantment as an inherent product of the representational act, as spectators or readers are compelled to think about the relation of perception to deception during magical performances. Magical characters highlight the problems of literary bodies, which in these texts are bizarre, exotic, and glamorous. Ishmael Reed employs voodoo ghosts to liberate the novel from cultural essentialist representational practices; voodoo, the marriage of form to spirit, is plural and polymorphous. As celebrations of trickery, voodoo bodies do not reflect inner character. Similarly, magicians are sleight-of-hand artists or escapologists who confound perception. In Chabon's novel, magicians and super heroes evade the bounds of representation through crafts of illusion. Magicians invent visual illusions; analogous to authors, magicians animate inert forms such as golems or automata. The automaton, a spectacular parody of the human body, questions whether any represented body is alive or not. In Kurzweil's A Case of Curiosities, readers wonder about the veracity of the automaton as extensions of or surrogates for novelistic characters. Fortune tellers, on the other hand, turn bodies into objects of destiny. Tarot readers, such as Efrosina in The Volcano Lover, interpret bodies through visual texts in relation to the past and future. By contrast, in Salamander, the freak poses riddles to readers regarding the authenticity of the body. Not unlike automata or voodoo fetishes, freaks are human puzzles that resemble narrative invention rather than mimetic representations of character. Contemporary novels articulate magical bodies as spirit cabinets, ineffable spaces rendered briefly and spectacularly visible for the delight of readers.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w884g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jg45w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Magic in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322j91h"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The manifestation of transference in the formation of the therapeutic relationship</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tellides, Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Across a number of theoretical orientations, the manifestation and working through of clients' central relationship patterns is considered to be an important aspect of psychotherapy process. The Core Conflictual Relationship Theme (CCRT) method was developed as an operationalization of transference, or the transfer of an individual's core relational schemas across relationships. Studies of therapeutic transference using pathological client samples have shown that there is some overlap between clients' relationship patterns with others and those that emerge with the therapist. The main objectives of the present research was to extend the study of therapeutic transference to therapies with high-functioning clients and to improve the methodology used in transference research by exploring an alternate method of collecting client narratives about their relationship with the therapist. The first study explored the manifestation of transference with high-functioning clients in early sessions. Factor analyses of Wish (W), Response of Other (RO) and Response of Self (RS) components of the CCRT were conducted to examine the relationship between client relational themes with significant others and client relational themes with the therapist. Findings within the Wish (W) and Response of Other (RO) components indicated a complementary pattern of relating in which the therapist was idealized and others were devalued, and findings within the RS component indicated a concordant relational transfer, in which clients had a negative response to both the therapist and others. Additionally, control issues emerged in the W component for significant others and in the RS component for the therapist. The second study addressed methodological limitations found in previous studies by drawing therapist narratives from a Participant Critical Event (PCE) interview rather than from psychotherapy sessions. In the PCE interview, client narratives about the therapist are not constrained by the presence of the therapist, resulting in a greater availability of potentially more candid descriptions of the therapeutic relationship. Factor analyses for the W and RO components indicated a complementary pattern of relating, in which the therapist was devalued and others were idealized, and findings for the RS component indicate a concordant relational transfer, in which clients felt bad with both the therapist and others. Additionally, the factor structure of the W and RO components suggests that as clients experience control issues with significant others, they wish to adopt a submissive stance toward the therapist. Although both studies yielded a similar overall pattern of complementary and concordant transference, there was an inversion in the valence of the complementary transference; in the first study, therapists were idealized and significant others were devalued while in the second study, therapists were devalued and others were idealized. Since the source of therapist narratives was the single greatest methodological difference between the two studies, the inversion in the findings could reasonably be attributed to the source of therapist narratives. Taken together, the results of these two studies suggest that the source of relational narratives is an important consideration in the study of relationship patterns. Clinical and research implications are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mr59z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j91h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Therapist and patient</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transference (Psychology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jq79b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Growing entrepreneurial firms in developing countries : the interplay of the state, the market and the social sector</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tzeng, Cheng-Hua, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study builds an integrative framework to delineate the process of growing entrepreneurial firms in developing countries. Deriving from the existing entrepreneurship literature, this thesis uses two notions to delineate the process of growth of indigenous firms: entrepreneurial intent and entrepreneurial capability. Then, drawing on the literature of economic development, it identifies three key sectors, the state, the market and the social sector, that foster entrepreneurial intent and cultivate entrepreneurial capability. The research setting is the information technology (IT) industries in China and Taiwan, each of which has had impressive performance when compared with their counterparts in other developing countries. This study differentiates the growth of entrepreneurial firms into three stages, getting started, getting there, and staying there, and proceeds to analyze the comparative-historical experiences of six IT firms, three in China and three in Taiwan. The firms in China are the Advanced Technology Service Division (ATSD), Lenovo Computer, and Great Wall Computer. The firms in Taiwan are United Microelectronics Corporation (UMC), Acer, and Vanguard International Semiconductor (VIS). It is found that at the stage of getting started, the government tends to be key among the three sectors, and can broadly influence the firms' entrepreneurial intent by building the national institution context, and more specifically through industrial policies. At the stage of getting there, the domestic social sector becomes more salient, and can transfer technology to entrepreneurial firms either from abroad or from their own research; they can also help defend entrepreneurial firms in intellectual property disputes with multinational firms. At the stage of staying there, due to their advanced technology, multinationals as forces in the market become more prevalent, and can enhance or destroy the capability of entrepreneurial firms. Overall, the state can act as context builder, champion and confronter; the social sector can play the roles of capability builder and capability defender, while the market, via multinational firms, can play the roles of capability destroyer and capability enhancer.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44ps01x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jq79b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>New business enterprises -- Developing countries</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economic development -- Government policy -- Developing countries</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electronic industries -- Taiwan -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electronic industries -- China -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economic development -- Economic aspects -- Developing countries</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117t03c"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immigration, individual autonomy, and social justice : an argument for a redistributive immigration policy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Straehle, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Contemporary liberal democratic societies currently enact immigration policies that are morally indefensible from a liberal autonomy and social justice perspective. In a world characterized by stark inequalities in individual opportunities to lead autonomous lives, and in which many individuals lack the basic conditions for autonomous functioning, I argue that contemporary immigration regimes that distinguish between desirable immigrants---who are typically from similarly wealthy countries---and undesirable one ---who are typically members of the global poor---conflict with liberal commitments to individual autonomy and equality of opportunity. I advocate that such commitments should lead wealthy countries to change their criteria for immigration, so that they admit proportionally many more of the global poor than they currently do. Such redistributive immigration policies are a way for rich countries to fulfill their global distributive justice duties. The thesis examines two major objections to formulating immigration policies on grounds of global distributive justice. First, some theorists posit a moral distinction between compatriots and non-compatriots, and argue that duties of redistribution should be restricted to compatriots. Second, some theorists fear that redistributive immigration schemes will have negative consequences on the conditions of social justice in host communities. This fear derives from the assumptions that social solidarity and social trust will be eroded by the greater ethno-cultural heterogeneity that is likely to result from the implementation of redistributive immigration policies. In response I show, first, that social solidarity is not circumscribed by national boundaries; the empirical evidence does not support claims that solidaristic acts rely on a predefined idea of community. Second, drawing on the Canadian case study, I find that institutional trust rather than interpersonal trust is key to motivating compliance with social welfare policies, and that this kind of trust can be sustained under conditions of ethno-cultural heterogeneity.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634772q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117t03c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social justice</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Emigration and immigration -- Government policy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Emigration and immigration -- Government policy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322j907"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An analysis of the supernatural archetype of the Prophet Muḥammad as found in the Sīra/Ta'rīkh and Tafsīr works of al-Ṭabarī and Ibn Kathīr</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Williams, Rebecca R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Reports relating supernatural events - or miracles - in the life of the Prophet Muhammad (d. 11/632) have been traditionally either ignored by those modern scholars attempting to determine the historicity of the source material or have been studied piecemeal in an attempt to determine their origins by those scholars who see them as secondary additions. The current study will examine both the sira/ta'rikh, the story of Muḥammad's life as told within larger works of universal history, and tafsir, exegetical, works of two medieval Muslim scholars, al-T&amp;dotbelow;abari (d. 310/923) and Ibn Kathir (d. 773/1373), to attempt to determine how the reports of the supernatural fit into the story of Muḥammad's life as a whole. The result is that there is both a supernatural and mundane archetype for the life of Muḥammad, and that they appear to mirror each other almost perfectly. Whereas the story begins with God performing all the miracles for Muḥammad's benefit, by the time of his death in Medina, Muḥammad has completed his mastery over the forces of the supernatural, even to the point where it appears that God performs miracles directly in response to Muḥammad's prayers. Thus, as Muḥammad gained more control over the movement he founded, he gained an equal amount of control over the forces of the supernatural. Both al-T&amp;dotbelow;abari and Ibn Kathir include reports that contain the supernatural archetype, but also include reports that diverge from it in important ways. While there is not one, overall theory to explain why each author made the changes he did to the supernatural archetype of Muḥammad's life, the examples in the following chapters indicate that the role of the supernatural versus the mundane, the politicization of the archetype, and authorial opinion were important to each scholar and help to support the argument that the miracle stories are integral to the life of Muḥammad as a whole, and deserve to be studied as such.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763c04j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j907</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muḥammad, Prophet, d. 632</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ibn Kathīr, Ismāʻīl ibn ʻUmar, ca. 1301-1373</dc:subject><dc:subject>Miracles (Islam)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ṭabarī, 838?-923</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr172232c"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dispersal propensity of adult Colorado potato beetles (Coleoptera:Chrysomelidae) on potato and its implications on the insect resistance management plan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mbungu, Nsitu T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A three-year (1998-2000) field and laboratory study conducted in Fredericton, New Brunswick, Canada analyzed and quantified the dispersal of adult Colorado potato beetles within and between conventional and transgenic potato plots established according to the high-dose/refuge strategy. More specifically, the study addressed the following four predictions: (1) Adult Colorado potato beetle abundance or flight activity in transgenic potato fields is positively correlated to the abundance or flight activity in the immediately adjacent refuge field. (2) Colorado potato beetle intraspecific competition on potato plants will increase the flight take-off frequency of adult CPB; tolerating relatively high numbers of CPB egg masses or larvae or a high level of CPB defoliation on potato plants in the refuge could therefore be considered to increase the movement of beetles from the refuge to the transgenic field. (3) CPB flight take-off frequency will be higher on potato plants at the bloom than at the vegetative stage; planting of the non transgenic potato crop in the refuge earlier than the Bt transgenic potato crop in the main field could therefore be considered to increase movement of the Colorado potato beetles from the refuge to the transgenic field. (4) The aggregated distribution of CPB populations in the potato crop is caused by the presence of mating pairs; strategies changing the distribution of males and females in the refuge field could therefore be considered to increase dispersal from the refuge to the main crop field. Population monitoring using plant counts, flight interception traps, flight landing traps and pitfall traps established that a transient population of adult CPB is present in the transgenic potato fields throughout the crop season and that the abundance of the beetle is higher than that required by the high dose/refuge strategy models. Furthermore results showed that the beetles invading the transgenic field population originate as much from the surrounding fields of conventional cultivars as from the adjacent refuges. It would therefore be possible to relax existing requirements for the refuge to be located immediately adjacent to the transgenic crop. Like most insects, the adult CPB populations are aggregated and can be fitted to a negative binomial distribution over the crop season. This study revealed that the distribution results from the presence of mating pairs for the overwintered population and from the clumped pupation for the non breeding summer population. The activity of the males in search of females is at least partly responsible for the higher dispersal activity observed with the overwintered than with the summer populations. The comparatively low level of dispersal activity with the summer population could affect the efficacy of the high/dose refuge strategy during the later part of the crop season. Results of flight chamber tests demonstrated that plant phenology and intraspecific competition have a positive effect on flight take-off frequency. These findings suggest that summer adult dispersal between the refuges and the transgenic crops could be stimulated by manipulating planting dates and the abundance of the different CPB life stages on the plants. Together, the results of the thesis provide support for some of the premises of the high dose/refuge strategy and offer new information on the CPB dispersal that could be used to further improve its efficacy. Although the transgenic potato (NewLeaf) is not commercially available at this time, the threat of CPB resistance to new products or resistant cultivars under development makes it important to continue the research required by CPB resistance management plans.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r7437.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172232c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Potatoes -- Disease and pest resistance -- New Brunswick -- Fredericton</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colorado potato beetle -- Dispersal -- New Brunswick -- Fredericton</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transgenic plants -- Disease and pest resistance -- New Brunswick -- Fredericton</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colorado potato beetle -- Biological control -- New Brunswick -- Fredericton</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bacillus thuringiensis -- New Brunswick -- Fredericton</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988q019"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An anxious society : the French importation of social phobia and the appearance of a new model of the self</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lloyd, Stephanie, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines the introduction of social phobia into France. My analysis is concerned with how this diagnosis, which is inconsistent with the psychoanalytic model that dominates French psychiatry, is increasingly being accepted by French physicians and patients. I argue that the diagnosis social phobia offers physicians and patients a justification for life difficulties that was not provided by existing diagnoses such as phobic neurosis, obsessional neurosis or 'normal' shyness. In 2003-4 I carried out one year of fieldwork in North America and France. During this time I conducted participant observation and interviews with clinicians and members of a social phobia support group. Throughout this thesis, it is my objective to understand the disorder from three perspectives: historical, ethnographic, and sociocultural. First, I examine French psychiatrists' claims that social phobia has existed in French psychiatric literature since the nineteenth century. I investigate the efforts of these French psychiatrists to prove that the diagnostic category has a legitimate place in French medicine. Second, I look at how a small group of Parisian psychiatrists who practice cognitive and behavioural therapy are fighting for greater awareness and acceptance of social phobia. Promoting social phobia is a means of spreading awareness of their therapeutic model. Their aim is to unseat psychoanalysis from its dominant position in French psychiatry. Many individuals prefer cognitive and behavioural therapists' explanations of social phobia symptoms to those of psychoanalysts because they are less stigmatizing and their predicted outcomes more optimistic. But many French clinicians reject the diagnosis social phobia and prefer psychoanalytic explanations for patients' symptoms. Some see it as a 'fashionable' disorder overly promoted by the pharmaceutical industry. Third, I investigate how social phobia is related to cultural behavioural ideals and societal expectations. I look at how these factors lead more people to become concerned about the symptoms of social phobia than in the past. In the end, I explain that French physicians and patients are choosing social phobia from among other possible labels for this set of symptoms. The way that they describe this diagnosis, however, blends multiple therapeutic models and they create an explanation of the disorder which most thoroughly and positively describes patients' experiences.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k2265.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988q019</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>France -- Social conditions -- 21st century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social phobia -- France</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182q422"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Drawing on experience</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Markus, Pamela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is an autobiographical study that explores how my past experiences related to art and education inform my teaching, and how my teaching informs how I theorize about art. Through the research process, I investigated issues about art and education by "drawing on" personal experience. The study supports the notion that personal experience is the basis of knowledge and assumes that to understand teachers' knowledge it is beneficial to observe it from a teacher's perspective. It touches on issues of teacher knowledge, the role of personal history and attitudes, and identity. The research involved observation of my teaching in a summer camp setting, layered with the autobiographical project of writing stories based on experiences related to art and education. The methods used to collect data consisted of established approaches to researching one's own practice, such as narrative writing, video documentation, and observation, as well as an arts-based approach to memory work that combined collage and narrative. The experiences that I addressed include my observation of two quilting guilds, my memories of making art as a child at summer camp and in elementary school, my graduate school experience in a Master of Fine Arts program, and my reflections on art that I see in galleries and museums. Although the original goal of my study was simply to understand my teaching more fully, the process of research has done more than allow me to understand how my lived experiences inform my teaching. The study points out the complex interrelationship between the notion of "place" and my beliefs about art. Autobiographical research has been a process of challenging my beliefs and finding meaning through my own thinking; it has provided a way for me to develop a critical awareness of my practice, to question the taken-for-granted nature of my understanding of art and to imagine other possibilities for practice.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rz78x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182q422</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Markus, Pamela</dc:subject><dc:subject>Art -- Study and teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz8064297"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Recognizing identity : the creation of new states in former Yugoslavia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mandalenakis, Helene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines the emergence of norms and the process through which these influence state behaviour. State identity conceptualized in ethnic or civic terms, shapes state preferences concerning the recognition of new states. Hence, the ethnic or civic identity of Germany, France, Greece and Italy influenced their policy on recognition of the former Yugoslav republics of Slovenia, Croatia, FYROM (Macedonia) and Bosnia-Herzegovina. Nevertheless, the examination of these policies indicates that these preferences were tempered by security concerns and perceptions of threat. Hence, although this thesis supports the constructivist claim on the power of principles such as identity, it also incorporates the realist claims on the significance of geopolitics in foreign policy. Consequently, it does not claim the supremacy of one theory over another instead it attempts to provide a better framework for understanding the sources of foreign policy.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55zc95h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8064297</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Recognition (International law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Former Yugoslav republics -- Foreign relations -- Europe</dc:subject><dc:subject>Europe -- Foreign relations -- Former Yugoslav republics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62fd35r"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Association between life course socioeconomic position and oral cancer among a sample of Indian subjects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thekke Purakkal, Akhil Soman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: Oral cancer has high incidence and mortality rates in both the developed and developing world. Its main risk factors are tobacco and alcohol consumption and, in India, paan chewing habits. Although socioeconomic position (SEP) has been associated with oral cancer, no studies have assessed this association using life course SEP in an Indian population. Objective: To estimate the extent to which life course SEP is an independent risk factor for oral cancer and how much of this association is explained by behavioural habits and oral health related factors in a sample of Indian subjects. Methods: Data from 200 oral cancer cases and 150 controls were drawn from an ongoing hospital-based case-control study: HeNCe Life (Head and Neck Cancer Life course) study. Detailed information regarding SEP, behavioural and oral health factors over the life course was collected using a questionnaire and a life grid technique. Data analysis involved descriptive and logistic regression analysis. Results: Subjects who were in low SEP throughout their lives were at significant risk for oral cancer (OR=5.81, 95% CI: 2.90-11.64) when compared to those who spent their lives in high SEP. The addition of behavioural and oral health factors into the models attenuated this association (OR= 2.08, 95% CI: 0.89-4.89 for low SEP compared to high SEP). However, low lifetime SEP was still related to an increased risk of oral cancer. Conclusion: Low life course SEP is a significant risk factor for oral cancer in this population.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction: Le cancer oral présente des taux d'incidence et de mortalité élevés, à la fois dans les pays développés et ceux en voie de développement. Ses facteurs de risque principaux sont la consommation de tabac et d'alcool et, en Inde, les habitudes de mâchage. Bien que la position socioéconomique (PSE) ait été associée avec le cancer oral, aucune étude n'a encore évalué cette association en utilisant la PSE tout au long de la vie chez une population indienne. Objectif: Estimer le degré auquel la PSE tout au long de la vie est un facteur de risque indépendant pour le cancer oral et à quel point cette association est expliquée par des habitudes comportementales et des facteurs reliés à la santé buccodentaire dans un échantillon de sujets indiens. Méthode: Des données portant sur 200 cas de cancer oral et 150 témoins ont été tirées d'une étude cas-témoins en cours dans les hôpitaux: l'étude HeNCe Life (Head and Neck Cancer Life course). De l'information détaillée concernant la PSE, des facteurs comportementaux et de santé buccodentaire tout au long de la vie a été recueillie à l'aide d'un questionnaire et de la technique de la grille de vie. L'analyse des données impliquait des analyses descriptives et de régression logistique. Résultats: Les sujets qui étaient dans une PSE faible tout au long de leur vie avaient un risque significativement plus élevé d'être diagnostiqué d'un cancer oral (RC=5.81, IC 95%: 2.90-11.64) comparativement à ceux qui ont vécu leur vie dans une PSE élevée. L'ajout de facteurs comportementaux et de santé buccodentaire aux modèles a atténué cette association (RC= 2.08, IC 95%: 0.89-4.89 pour une SEP faible comparativement à une PSE élevée). Cependant, la PSE au cours de la vie est demeurée reliée à un risque accru de cancer oral. Conclusion: Une PSE faible tout au long de la vie est un facteur de risque significatif de cancer oral dans cette population.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul J. Allison</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Belinda Farias Nicolau</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xn74q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fd35r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rq32q"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Combined static-dynamic deformations with haptic rendering</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sedaghat, Yasaman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nous présentons une méthode de simulation temps réel conforme aux lois de la physique pour animer des déformations élastiques à haute résolution, tout en portant une attention particulière aux interactions haptiques. Pour obtenir un résultat permettant une interaction temps réel sans perte de précision, la matrice réduite de rigidité du matériau est précalculée en excluant les équations correspondant aux noeuds internes du système. De plus, nous avons recours à l'analyse modale linéaire pour pré-calculer les modes de vibration naturelle du système. Nous proposons une technique de couplage des déformations afin d'obtenir le comportement à dynamique réduite recherché tout en préservant les propriétés des déformations locales à haute résolution. Lors de la simulation temps réel, les déformations statiques à haute fréquence spatiale sont couplées à la dynamique spatiale réduite à basse fréquence en projetant les déformations en coordonnées réduites sur une base orthogonale construite à partir des modes de vibration naturelle. Afin d'explorer l'impact du système de couplage, nous décrivons différentes techniques d'intégration pour avancer la solution de dynamique réduite dans le temps tout en évaluant le retour de force haptique. De plus, nous détaillons notre approche pour la gestion de points de contact multiples pour des matériaux non-adhésifs ainsi que notre méthode pour la gestion du glissement. Nous comparons la méthode que nous avançons aux techniques existantes en termes de complexité du temps d'exécution et en termes des propriétés de déformation, et ce en utilisant un maillage 3D intégré à un système à éléments finis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>We present a real-time, physically based simulation method for animating high-resolution elastic deformations with a focus on haptic interaction. To achieve interactive rates without losing accuracy, the reduced material stiffness matrix is precomputed by removing the equations that correspond to the internal nodes of the system. In addition, we employ linear modal analysis to precompute the natural vibration modes of the system. We introduce a deformation-coupling technique in order to achieve the reduced dynamic behaviour while keeping the high-resolution local deformations. During real-time simulation, the high-spatial-frequency static deformations are coupled with the low-spatial-frequency dynamics, by projecting the reduced coordinate deformations onto an orthogonal basis constructed from natural vibration modes. To explore the implications of the coupling system, we describe different integration techniques to time-step the reduced dynamic solution in addition to evaluating the force feedback. Moreover, we show how we handle multiple contact points for non-sticky materials. To improve the contact-handling procedure, we employ our sliding technique to include friction. We compare our proposed method to the previously existing techniques in terms of run-time complexity and deformation properties using 3D meshes embedded in finite elements.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Funnell, W. Robert J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kry, Paul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zj63f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rq32q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85ng24w"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nonlinear control and state estimation of holonomic indoor airship</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Yin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Three full-state optimal controllers are proposed to fulfill the requirements of flying an indoor holonomic airship in real-time, namely, hovering control, set-point control and continuous reference tracking. In the hovering control design, the airship is assumed to be a quasi stationary plant, and an infinite horizon linear quadratic regulator (LQR) operating in again scheduling manner is employed. Meanwhile, a controller based on the state-dependent Riccati equation (SDRE) and ad hoc feedforward compensation is synthesized to tackle the set-point control problem. Lastly, a continuous tracker is dedicated to rejecting alldisturbances along any given reference trajectory. With reasonable computation cost, the proposed controllers show significant advantages over the PD controller in both simulationand real flights. A state estimator designed with the unscented Kalman filter is also implemented in this work. The purpose is to track the airship state for the feedback loop and other navigation tasks by fusing information from the on-board (an inertia measurement unit and a laser range finder) and/or o-board (an infra-red based motion capture system) sensors. A loosely coupled sensor fusion scheme is employed and validated in experiments.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Trois méthodes optimales de commande à retour d'état complet sont proposées ici afin d'accomplir les exigences du vol intérieur d'un ballon dirigeable holonomique, et ceci, en temps réel. Les manoeuvres exigées incluent le maintien d'une position stationnaire, le mouvement vers un point et suivant une trajectoire continue. Pour la régularisation, un modèle quasi-stationnaire du ballon est assumé et un régulateur quadratique-linéaire (LQR) à horizon infini est utilisé dans un mode d'échelonnage des gains. De plus, les mouvements vers un point sont accomplis en se basant sur le retour d'état pour résoudre l'équation de Riccati qui en dépend et pour compenser la dynamique non-linéaire. Finalement, les perturbations autour d'une trajectoire continue sont rejetées par une méthode dédiée afin de suivre cette trajectoire. Preuves expérimentales et simulées à l'appui, ces méthodes de commande démontrent des avantages significatifs par rapport aux méthodes classiques de commande porportionelle-dérivée (PD), et ceci, avec des exigences modérées sur le système informatique. Ce travail de thèse démontre aussi l'utilisation d'un filtre de Kalman non-parfumé (UKF) pour estimer l'état du système. Cette estimation produit le retour d'ètat complet nècessaire aux mèthodes de commande et à d'autres tâches de navigation en combinant les mesures de différents systèmes enbarqués (système inertiel et télédétecteur par laser) et non-embarqués (système de capture du mouvement à l'infra-rouge). Une méthode de fusion sensorielle à séparation partielle est utilisée et validée expérimentalement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Inna Sharf</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j77b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85ng24w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Robotics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53x091x"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compressed sensing-based detectors for impulse radio ultra wideband systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shahrad, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the challenging problems of Impulse Radio Ultra Wide Band (IR-UWB) detectors is the need for high rate sampling. Compressed-Sensing-based (CS-based) detectors have recently gained popularity due to their implementation simplicity as they require sampling rates much lower than the Nyquist rate. However, they are not designed specically for IRUWB signals. Furthermore, they require a large number of correlators to capture the signal energy. In this work, we compare a CS-based detector with the energy detector and show that the CS-based detector with enough correlators can surpass the energy detector. Then, we propose a generalized CS-based detector that requires fewer correlators by increasing the sampling rate up to the point that the available Analogue-to-Digital Converters (ADC) can support. Also, we investigate the relation between the chip rate of pseudo-random correlators and the performance of the CS-based detector; we show how much we lose interms of the probability of detection if the chip-rate goes below the Nyquist rate. Finally, we design sub-optimal structured correlators that are suitable for IR-UWB signals, and we derive performance bounds for the proposed correlators. Simulations show that the CS-based detector with these correlators work better in IR-UWB systems comparing with the conventional correlators.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un des problèmes difficiles pour les détecteurs de radio impulsionnelle à ultra large bande(IR-UWB) est le besoin de fréquence d'échantillonnage élevée. Les détecteurs basés sur l'acquisition comprimée (CS-based) sont devenus plus populaires dû à leur simplicité demise en œuvre avec des taux d'échantillonnage beaucoup plus faible que le taux de Nyquist. Cependant, ils ne sont pas conçus pour les signaux surtout les signaux IR-UWB. En outre, ils nécessitent un grand nombre de corrélateurs pour capturer l'énergie du signal. Dans ce travail, nous comparons un détecteur CS-based avec un détecteur d'énergie et montrons que le détecteur CS-based avec un nombre suffisant de corrélateurs peut fonctionner mieux que le détecteur d'énergie. Ensuite, nous proposons un détecteur CS-based généralisé qui nécessite moins de nombre de corrélateur. Pour cela, nous augmentons le taux d'échantillonnage jusqu'au taux maximum pouvant être supporté par l'ADC (convertisseur analogique numérique). Plus tard, nous étudions la relation entre le débit du code pseudo-aléatoire et les performances du détecteur CS-based. Nous montrons le nombre de perte de performance en termes de probabilité de détection si le débit du code pseudo-aléatoire est au-dessous du taux de Nyquist. Enfin, nous concevons les détecteurs structurés sous-optimaux qui sont convenables aux signaux d'IR-UWB et nous obtenons la bande de performance pour les corrélateurs proposés. Les simulations montrent que le détecteur CS-based avec ces corrélateurs fonctionne mieux dans le système d'IR-UWB qu'avec les corrélateurs conventionnels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ioannis Psaromiligkos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fg96n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x091x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537521k"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimal design of dispersion filter for time-domain implementation of split-step method in optical fiber communication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhu, Yang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'équation de Schrödinger non linéaire peut être résolue par des méthodes split-étape, où à chaque étape, la dispersion linéaire et les effets non linéaires sont traités séparément de manière séquentielle.  Cette thèse étudie la conception optimale d'un filtre finis à réponse impulsionnelle (FIR) en tant que mise en œuvre dans le domaine temporel pour la partie linéaire. L'objectif est de minimiser l'intégrale de l'erreur quadratique entre la réponse fréquentiel du FIR et les caractéristiques de dispersion souhaitées sur la bande d'intérêt. Ce problème de moindres carrés (LS) est résolu en deux approches: l'approche équation normale donne une solution explicite et sa structure de Toeplitz permet le calculer rapide; la décomposition en valeurs singulières (SVD) fournit un point de vue géométrique, physique et numérique basé sur la théorie de la séquence discrète sphéroïdale prolate (DPSS). Une préoccupation majeure est que, comme révélé par la théorie de la DPSS, ce problème pourrait être mal conditionné, et désormais sa solution serait sensible aux petites perturbations. Par ailleurs, la réponse en fréquence peut manifester des comportements singuliers tels que les dépassements. Deux approches sont proposées pour atténuer ces lacunes: l'approche LS contrainte ajoute un terme de régularisation de la fonction objectif, alors que l'approche contrainte impose aussi une contrainte magnitude maximale sur la réponse fréquentielle.  Cette dernière approche est formulée dans une norme quadratique contrainte quadratique de programmation (QCQP) problème qui peut être facilement résolu en utilisant l'état de l'art méthodes de points intérieurs. Comparé à des filtres FIR qui est déjà conçu, ces filtres sont plus faciles à extraire et le filtre à base QCQP économise la longueur du filtre par au moins 1 / 3. Il y a une complexité compromis entre ces deux filtres: la contrainte régularisé LS filtre est beaucoup plus facile à extraire à l'aide de la modification de algorithme de Levinson-Durbin; le filtre basé QCQP est plus court dans la longueur et la complexité des calculs sauve des circonvolutions linéaires. Le choix dépend si le filtre doit être régénéré fréquemment ou pas. En outre, les longueurs requises du filtre pour ces filtres sont des fonctions approximativement linéaires de plusieurs paramètres, ce qui simplifie la tâche du choix de la longueur de l'étape. Nous vérifions la faisabilité des filtres proposés dans deux catégories d'applications suivantes. Premièrement, ils peuvent être utilisés dans la simulation dans le domaine temporel de la propagation des impulsions dans les fibres optiques. Pour un seul canal et des canaux WDM, les filtres proposés génèrent des sorties similaires à celles des méthodes précédentes dans le domaine temporel et le domaine fréquentiel, même après la propagation de milliers de kilomètres. Les conceptions proposées, avec overlap-add et over-save peut réduire la complexité globale du calcul de façon significative. Deuxièmement, les filtres proposés peuvent également être appliqués dans le domaine temporel des algorithmes numériques rétro propagation d'indemnisation dépréciation de la fibre. Les simulations numériques d'une division polarisation en quadrature multiplexés déphasage système de transmission de saisie (PDM-QPSK) montrent que les méthodes de partage des étapes basées sur les filtres proposés sont en mesure d'atténuer efficacement les distorsions du signal causé par la dispersion et les non-linéarités.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The nonlinear Schrödinger equation can be solved by split-step methods, where in each step, linear dispersion and nonlinear effects are treated separately in a sequential manner. This thesis investigates the optimal design of an finite-impulse-response (FIR) filter as the time-domain implementation for the linear part. The objective is to minimize the integral of the squared error between the frequency response of the FIR filters and the desired dispersion characteristics over the band of interest. This least square (LS) problem is solved in two approaches: the normal equation approach gives an explicit solution and its Toeplitz structure enables fast computation; the singular value decomposition (SVD) approach provides geometrical, physical and numerical insights based on the theory of discrete prolate spheroidal sequence (DPSS). A major concern is that as revealed by the theory of DPSS, this problem could be ill-conditioned, and henceforth its solution would be sensitive to small perturbations. Besides, the frequency response might exhibit singular behaviors such as overshoots. Two approaches are proposed to mitigate these shortcomings: the unconstrained LS approach adds a regularization term to the objective function, whereas the constrained approach also imposes a maximum magnitude constraint on the frequency response. The latter approach is formulated into a standard quadratically constrained quadratic programming (QCQP) problem that can be readily solved using state-of-the-art interior-point methods. Compared with previously designed FIR filters, these filters are easier to extract and the QCQP-based filter saves the filter length by at least 1/3. There is a complexity trade-off between these two filters: the unconstrained regularized LS filter is much easier to extract with the help of the modified Levinson-Durbin algorithm; the QCQP-based filter is shorter in length and saves computational complexity of the linear convolutions. The choice depends on whether the filter needs to be regenerated frequently or not. In addition, the required filter lengths for these filters are approximately linear functions of several  parameters, which simplifies the task of choosing step size.We verify the feasibility of the proposed filters in two categories of applications. Firstly, they can be used in the time-domain simulation of pulse propagation in optical fiber. For single channel and WDM channels, the proposed filters generate similar outputs as previous time-domain and frequency-domain methods, even after propagating thousands of kilometers. The proposed designs, together with overlap-add and overlap-save, can reduce the overall computational complexity significantly. Secondly, the proposed filters can also be applied in time-domain digital backpropagation algorithms for fiber impairment compensation. Numerical simulations of a polarization division multiplexed quadrature phase-shift keying (PDM-QPSK) transmission system illustrate that the split-step methods based on the proposed filters are able to effectively mitigate the signal distortions caused by both dispersion and nonlinearities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David V. Plant</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1073159.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537521k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440x77d"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental study and thermodynamic modelling of the calcium oxide - silicon oxide - aluminum oxide - calcium fluoride system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Dong-Geun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'usage des poudres de coulée continue est une préoccupation majeure pour l'industrie sidérurgique. Actuellement, plus de 90% de l'acier est produit par le procédé de coulée continue, nécessitant impérativement l'emploi de poudres de coulée. Traditionnellement, le développement des poudres de coulée a été réalisé par la méthode d'essai et d'erreur depuis son introduction dans l'industrie dans les années 1960. Récemment, l'intérêt porté sur le fluor s'est accru car celui-ci présente d'importantes propriétés et fonctions pour le procédé de coulée continue, telles que son influence sur la cristallisation et la diminution du point de fusion et de la viscosité du laitier. Toutefois, la méthode conventionnelle de développement des poudres de coulée appropriées n'est pas efficace pour faire face aux exigences croissantes du procédé de coulée continue, telles qu'effectuer la coulée de brames minces et atteindre de plus grande vitesse de coulée. Par conséquent, l'étude fondamentale du diagramme de phase des systèmes de poudres de coulée est manifestement nécessaire, et la modélisation thermodynamique est le moyen le plus efficace pour concevoir de nouvelles poudres de coulée en termes d'économie de temps et d'argent. Les principaux composants des poudres de coulée, qui font partie du système CaO-SiO2-Al2O3-CaF2, sont examinés dans cette étude car ces quatre constituants affecteront le plus grand nombre de propriétés des poudres de coulée. Malheureusement, le fluor a une volatilité élevée à haute température et une réactivité élevée avec d'autres matériaux. Par conséquent, les résultats des expériences effectuées précédemment sur les systèmes contenant des fluorures sont caractérisés par des écarts importants en raison du changement de composition et de réactions inattendues lors des expériences. Comme les données disponibles dans la littérature rapportent des résultats contradictoires entre eux, des expériences ont été effectuées dans cette étude pour établir les diagrammes de phase. Ces expériences ont été menées avec la méthode de trempe dans des capsules de platine scellées pour empêcher la perte de fluor pendant les expériences. Les analyses ont été effectuées en utilisant un microscope électronique à balayage (MEB) équipé d'un système d'analyse dispersive en énergie de rayons X (EDS), et une technique nouvellement développée qui produit des résultats plus précis lors de la quantification de la composition des phases à l'équilibre. La courbe du liquidus du CaO du système binaire CaO-CaF2, dont les données dans la littérature diffèrent entre elles jusqu'à environ 50 % atomique, a été confirmée. La solubilité de CaO dans CaF2 à l'état solide a été trouvée pour la première fois et atteint environ 5 % atomique à la température eutectique. Les courbes de liquidus des systèmes CaO-Al2O3-CaF2 et CaO-SiO2-CaF2 ont été soigneusement étudiées et l'étendue de la lacune de miscibilité dans le système CaO-Al2O3-CaF2 a été prouvée être beaucoup plus petite que celle rapportée dans la littérature. En outre, une analyse thermique a été réalisée par calorimétrie différentielle à balayage (DSC) dans un creuset en platine. La température eutectique des systèmes CaO-CaF2 et CaAl2O4-CaF2 a été mesurée avec succès et la transition polymorphique de la forme α-CaF2 vers la forme β-CaF2 a été confirmée. Sur base des nouvelles données expérimentales et des données fiables de la littérature, la modélisation thermodynamique du système CaO-SiO2-Al2O3-CaF2 a également été réalisée. Les résultats de calcul thermodynamique peuvent être très bénéfiques pour la conception de nouvelles poudres de coulée.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mould flux for the continuous casting process is a major concern for the steelmaking industry. Nowadays, more than 90 % of steel is being produced by the continuous casting process, which requires mould flux as an essential additive. The development of mould flux has been achieved by the conventional trial and error approach since it was first introduced in industry in the 1960s. Recently, the interest on the properties of fluorine has increased a lot since it is reported that fluorine has important functions such as playing a critical role on the crystallization behavior, and decreasing the melting point and viscosity of slag. However, the conventional way to find a suitable mould flux is not efficient to face the increasingly stringent requirements of the continuous casting process such as thin slab casting and higher casting speed. Therefore, fundamental phase diagram study on mould flux systems is clearly necessary, and thermodynamic modeling is the most effective way to design new mould flux in terms of time and money saving. The major components of mould flux, the CaO-SiO2-Al2O3-CaF2 system, are investigated in this study as these four constituents will mostly affect the largest numbers of properties. Unfortunately, fluorine has high volatility at high temperature and high reactivity with other materials. Therefore, the results of previous experiments on F-containing systems are characterized by large discrepancies due to composition alteration and unexpected reactions during the experiment. As literature data show inconsistent results between each other, key phase diagram experiments were performed in this study. The phase diagram experiments were conducted with the quenching method in sealed Pt capsules to prevent fluorine loss during the experiment. The analyses were performed using a FE-SEM equipped with an EDS system, and a newly developed technique which produces more precise quantitative results for the equilibrium phase composition. The CaO liquidus of the CaO-CaF2 binary system, which the literature data differ from each other by up to 50 mol %, was confirmed. The CaO solubility in solid CaF2 was found for the first time and reaches about 5 mol % at the eutectic temperature. The liquidus of the CaO-Al2O3-CaF2 and CaO-SiO2-CaF2 systems were carefully studied and the miscibility gap in the CaO-Al2O3-CaF2 system was proved to be much smaller than that reported in literature. Also, thermal analysis was performed using DSC in a Pt crucible. The eutectic temperatures of the CaO-CaF2 and CaAl2O4-CaF2 systems were successfully measured and the α to β-CaF2 polymorphic transition was confirmed. Based on the new experimental data and reliable literature data, thermodynamic modeling of the CaO-SiO2-Al2O3-CaF2 system was also carried out. The results of thermodynamic calculation can be very beneficial for new mould flux design.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>In-Ho Jung</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593v042t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440x77d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q562r"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spectrum sensing and access strategies for Markovian primary users</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Salehi Nobandegani, Ardavan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As a large portion of currently assigned spectrum is under utilized [1], the concept of cognitive radio is put forward as a promising solution to enhance the utilization of the available spectrum resources. Spectrum sensing, as a sole means for the Secondary User (SU) to gain awareness regarding his surrounding radio activities, is a cornerstone of the cognitive radio concept. In this thesis, the problem of spectrum sensing for the case of a single SU in the presence of an un-slotted Primary User (PU) whose channel usage pattern is modelled by a Continuous-Time Markov Chain (CTMC) is being studied and two sensing schemes, namely, Steady-State Occupancy Probability Approach (SS-OPA) and Bayesian Recursive Method (BRM) are discussed. As it takes the SU some time to process the observations he makes for the purpose of spectrum sensing, the issue of Sensing Delay (SD) is also addressed and the required modications have been applied on our proposed sensing scheme, BRM, so as to obtain an SD-aware sensing scheme. As soon as the SU nds the channel free, it gains access to it and start transmitting for a length of time which we refer to as a SU's transmission period. The problem of SU's transmission period optimization is being considered and two schemes are proposed as to strike a balance between maximizing the SU's spectrum utilization and the PU's protection against interference induced by the SU. The two SU's channel access strategies are developed so as to incorporate the effect of sensing error in their operation; henceforth the impractical assumption of perfect sensing has been dropped. Last but not least, the problem of uncertainty regarding the CTMC's parameters is studied and a sensing scheme, namely, Sequential Restricted-Minimax (SRM) scheme has been proposed so as to minimize, at each sensing instant, the worst-case cost incurred by the sensing rule. This study is motivated by the fact that the parameters involved in the PU's CTMC are not known a-priori and have to be replaces by imperfect estimates.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Étant donné qu'une portion importante du spectre assigné est actuellement sous-utilisée [1],le concept de radio cognitive apparait comme une solution prometteuse dans l'enrichissement de l'utilisation du spectre disponible. La détection du spectre, en tant que sole moyen pour l'utilisateur secondaire (SU) de reconnaitre des activités radio environnantes est un des piliers du concept radio cognitive. Cette Thése étudie le probléme de la detéction du spectre dans le cas d'un unique US en présence d'un utilisateur primaire (PU) sans crenéau temporel un-slotted et dont la modélisation de l'utilisation de chaine est acquise par une chaine de temps continu de Markov (CTMC). Ceci est analysé à partir de deux schémas, la methodé de probabilité d'occupation l'état stationnaire (SS-OPA) et la méthode récursive bayésienne (BRM). Puisque le SU requiert d'un certain temps an de traiter les observations qu'il fait pour détecter le spectre, le problème du retardement de la détection (dit probleme SD) fera aussi l'objet de cette étude. De même, les modications requises ont été appliquées dans le schéma BRM proposé afin d'obtenir un schéma de détection sensible au SD. Dés que le SU trouve une chaine de libre il en gagne l'accs et commence à émettre pour une période de temps que l'on appellera période de transmission du SU. Le problème de l'optimisation du période de transmission du SU est aussi considérée et deux schémas sont proposés an d'atteindre un équilibre entre la maximisation de l'utilisation du spectre par le SU et la protection du PU contre l'interfrence induite par le SU. Toutes les deux stratégies d'accs de chaine ont été développées dans le but d'incorporer l'effet de détection d'erreur dans leur opération; dès lors, on abandonne hypothèse ctive, de la détection parfaite. Enfin, le problème d'incertitude en relation aux paramètres du CTMC a été étudié et on a proposé le restreint-minimax squentiel (SRM) comme schéma de minimisation à chaque instant de détection où le cout du pire scenario est engagé par la règle de détection. Cet étude est motivée par le fait que les paramètres impliqués dans le CTMC du PU ne sont pas connus apriori et doivent être remplacés par des estimations imparfaites.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ioannis Psaromiligkos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96024972.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q562r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634756b"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A model study of the dynamics of dark energy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Chao</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Observational facts indicate that the expansion of the universe is accelerating, rather than decelerating, because 73% of the total energy density of the universe is a "dark energy" with strong negative pressure, ω &lt; −1/3. In this thesis, we introduce a dynamical dark energy model with dilatational symmetry, which contains two scalar ﬁelds coupled to gravity. Because of the dilatational symmetry, there is no cosmological constant Λ in the Lagrangian, and, instead, two scalar ﬁelds generate the dark energy, evolving slowly in time. At early times, the system is in the slow roll regime, corresponding to Higgs inﬂation due to the Higgs ﬁeld. At late times, the dynamical dark energy dominates the universe and eventually behaves just like the cosmological constant, and the universe becomes exponentially expanding with the scale factor a(t) ∝ exp{Ht}. The numerical results from solving the dynamic equations of the system agree well with the observational facts, which indicates that our model gives a good description of the universe.  At the end of the thesis, we consider the one-loop corrections to our model, and show that they do not alter the classical results in any signiﬁcant way.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les observations actuelles de l'expansion de l'univers indiquent une accéleration decette expansion due à 'l'énergie sombre', qui compte pour 73% de la densité d'énergie totalle de l'univers et qui se comporte comme un ﬂuide avec une pression négative, ω &lt; −1/3. Cette thèse présente un modèle dynamique d'énergie sombre invariant sous une symétrie de dilatation comprenant deux champs scalaires couplés à la gravitation. La constante cosmologique n'est pas présente dans ce modèle, de par la symétrie de dilatation; les champs scalaires génèrent une énergie sombre évoluant dans le temps.   Dans l'univers primordial, le système se situe dans le régime d'évolution lente correspondant à l'inﬂation cosmolgique due au champ de Higgs.  L'énergie sombre dynamique agit ultérieurement sur l'évolution de l'univers comme une constante cosmologique; le facteur d'échelle de l'univers accroit de manière exponentielle a(t) ∝ eHt. Les simulations numériques concordent très bien avec les observations actuelles. Les perturbations quantiques de premier ordre sont ensuite calculées, et justiﬁent la validité des résultats obtenus de manière classique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James M. Cline</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408215p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634756b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zz23k"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Concentration of Laplace eigenfunctions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tousignant-Barnes, Joel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans ce mémoire, nous résumons les résultats connus concernant la concentration des fonctions propres du laplacien dans la limite de haute énergie. Nous révisons les bornes asymptotiques sur les normes Lp des fonctions propres, et les limites quantiques admissibles, sous une variété d'hypothèses sur la variété. Nous prouvons un résultat nouveau qui stipule que si les fonctions propres convergent faiblement vers une limite quantique sur le n-tore, ils doivent aussi le faire sur le n-tore rééchelonné.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we give a review of known results concerning the concentration of Laplace eigenfunctions in the high-energy limit. We review asymptotic bounds on Lp norms of eigenfunctions, and possible quantum limits, under a variety of hypotheses on the manifold. We prove a new result that states that if eigenfunctions converge weakly to a quantum limit on the n-torus, they must also do so on a "rescaled" n-torus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dmitry Jakobson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xh105.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zz23k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t6151"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spirituality and religion in youth suicide attempters' trajectories of mental health service utilization: the year before a suicide attempt</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bullock, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Youth suicide attempters are at high-risk for completing suicide. Many have untreated mental health problems and are not receiving services. Therefore, there is an urgent need to better understand potential influences associated with service use amongst this population. Spirituality and/or religion are potential cultural influences in all stages of youths' mental health service trajectories. This thesis explored youths' experiences of spirituality/religion as it relates to their help-seeking trajectories in the year prior to their suicide attempt. Fifteen youth (aged 14-18) who had made a suicide attempt(s) in the past 1 to 2 years were consecutively recruited through the Depressive Disorder Program of a psychiatric hospital and interviewed using open ended questions and one questionnaire. A mixed-methods design, including an adapted form of the psychological autopsy method, was used. Three themes emerged in the interviews. Religious community members acted as a bridge, step, or provider in relation to mental health services. Religious and spiritual discourses were encountered within services. Many youths reported different levels of spirituality and/or religious beliefs during the year prior to their suicide attempt. Spirituality and religion can have a role in youth suicide attempters' service trajectories.  How this confers protection or challenges for each youth's trajectory needs to be clarified.  Service providers need to be careful how they address these complex issues.  Already, findings from the study in this thesis can inform policies in mental health services, suicide prevention and alert clinicians to suicidal youths' perspectives about spirituality and religion which may affect service utilization.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les jeunes ayant fait une tentative de suicide sont à  haut risque de s'enlever la vie par suicide. De nombreux jeunes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale ne sont pas traités pour leurs problèmes de santé mentale et ne reçoivent pas de services. Ainsi, il y a un besoin urgent de mieux comprendre les influences potentielles liées à l'utilisation de services parmi cette population. La spiritualité et/ou la religion sont des influences culturelles potentielles à tous les stades de la trajectoire de services en santé mentale des jeunes qui ont fait une tentative de suicide. Cette thèse a exploré les expériences des jeunes au niveau de la spiritualité/religion en lien avec leur trajectoire de recherche d'aide dans l'année précédant leur tentative de suicide. Quinze jeunes (âgés de 14 à 18 ans) ayant fait une tentative de suicide dans la dernière ou les deux dernières années ont été recrutés consécutivement via le Programme des Troubles Dépressifs d'un hôpital psychiatrique et ont été interviewés en utilisant des questions « ouvertes » et un questionnaire. Une approche méthodologique mixte, incluant une version adaptée de l'autopsie psychologique, a été utilisée. Trois thèmes sont ressortis des entrevues.  Les membres des communautés religieuses ont permis soit de faire le pont vers les services en santé mentale, d'être une étape dans l'offre de services ou de donner les soins proprement dits. Les jeunes ont été en contact avec des discours religieux et spirituels à différents moments dans les services de santé usuels. Plusieurs jeunes ont rapporté différents niveaux de spiritualité et/ou de croyances religieuses dans l'année précédant leur tentative de suicide. La spiritualité et la religion peuvent avoir un rôle dans la trajectoire de services de ces jeunes. Comment ceci confère un effet protecteur ou encore constitue un défi reste à être approfondi. Les donneurs de soins doivent adresser ces enjeux complexes avec doigté. Déjà, les résultats générés par cette étude peuvent éclairer les politiques dans les services de santé mentale, la prévention de suicide et sensibiliser les cliniciens aux perspectives des jeunes suicidaires à propos de la spiritualité et la religion, perspectives qui pourraient influencer l'utilisation de services.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lucie Nadeau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Johanne Renaud</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p8820.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t6151</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848v443"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Integer least squares search and reduction strategies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Breen, Stephen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with integer least squares problems, also referred to as closest vector problems. One often used approach to solving these problems is the discrete search method, which typically involves two stages, the reduction and the search. The main purpose of the reduction is to make the search faster. Reduction strategies for box-constrained integer least squares problems involve column reordering of the input matrix. There are currently two algorithms for column reordering that are most effective for the search stage, referred to here as SW and CH. Although both use all available information in the problem, the SW and CH algorithms look different and were derived respectively from geometric and algebraic points of view. In this thesis we modify the SW algorithm to make it more computationally efficient and easier to comprehend. We then prove that the SW and CH algorithms actually give the same column reordering in theory. Finally, we propose a new mathematically equivalent algorithm, which is more computationally efficient and is still easy to understand. This thesis also extends the column permutation idea to ordinary integer least squares problems. A new reduction algorithm which combines the well-known Lenstra–Lenstra–Lovász (LLL) reduction and the new column reordering strategy is proposed. The new reduction can be much more effective than the LLL reduction in some cases. The thesis also reviews some common search algorithms. A new one is proposed, which is based on two previous algorithms, the depth-first search and the best-first search. This hybrid algorithm makes use of the advantages of both originals, is more efficient than either and is easier to implement than other previous hybrid algorithms.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse s'intéresse aux problèmes de moindres carrés entiers (ILS), ou les problèmes du vecteur le plus proche. Une approche souvent utilisée pour résoudre ces problèmes est la méthode de recherche discrète, qui implique deux étapes: la réduction et la recherche. Le but principal de la réduction est de rendre l'étape de recherche plus rapide. Les stratégies de réduction des problèmes ILS sous contrainte de boîte impliquent la réorganisation de colonnes de la matrice de données. Il existe actuellement deux algorithmes pour la réorganisation des colonnes, appelés ici les algorithmes SW et CH,  qui sont les plus efficaces pour la phase de recherche. Bien que les deux utilisent toutes les informations disponibles dans le problème, les algorithmes SW et CH sont différents en apparence, et ont été obtenus respectivement à partir d'une point de vue géométrique et algébrique de vue. Dans cette thèse, nous modifions l'algorithme SW pour rendre son calcul plus efficace et plus facile à comprendre. Nous démontrons ensuite qu'en théorie, les algorithmes SW et CH donne effectivement la même réorganisation de colonnes. Enfin, nous proposons un nouveau algorithme mathématiquement équivalent qui est plus efficace, tout en demeurant facile à comprendre. Cette thèse étend également l'idée de permutation de colonnes aux problèmes ordinaires de moindres carrés entiers. Un nouveau algorithme de réduction qui combine le célèbre agorithme Lenstra-Lenstra-Lovász (LLL) avec la nouvelle stratégie de réorganisation de colonnes est proposé. La nouvelle réduction peut être plus efficace que la réduction LLL dans certains cas.Cette thèse examine également certains algorithmes de recherche d'usage courant. Un nouveau est proposé qui est basé sur deux algorithmes précédents: l'algorithme de parcours en profondeur et celui de la recherche au meilleur d'abord. Notre algorithme hybride détient les avantages des deux originaux, tout en étant plus efficace et plus facile à utiliser que d'autres algorithmes hybrides déjà existants.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Xiao-Wen Chang</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505459d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v443</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311t49g"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learner, text, and context factors on conceptual change in biology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trevors, Gregory</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigated how instructional environments might be optimally designed for all students to restructure prior knowledge and learn counter-intuitive science concepts, referred to as conceptual change. Three independent variables were examined in relation to real-time cognitive processes and subsequent learning outcomes: a learner characteristic (students' beliefs about knowledge and knowing, or epistemic beliefs), a property of instructional texts (refutational text structures), and a variable of instructional contexts (reading goals). Fifty-one university students with misconceptions in biological evolution were classified as espousing either absolutistic or evaluativist epistemic beliefs. Participants were randomly assigned to receive a refutational or expository texts and a global comprehension or elaborative interrogation reading goal in a 2×2 nested design. Data on think aloud responses while reading and open-ended essays post-reading were collected. Results reveal that refutations enriched conceptual evolutionary knowledge but failed to foster restructuring of misconceptions. Epistemic beliefs were related to cognitive processing, with evaluativists adapting their processes according to instructional texts. Reading goals likewise enriched conceptual knowledge and did not revise misconceptions, but no interaction between assigned goals and epistemic beliefs was observed. Theoretical and practical implications are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse porte sur la manière dont les environnements pédagogiques pourraient être conçus de manière optimale pour tous les étudiants afin de restructurer les connaissances antérieures et d'apprendre des concepts scientifiques contre-intuitifs, appelés changement conceptuel. Trois variables indépendantes ont été examinées en relation aux processus cognitifs en temps réel et aux résultats d'apprentissage subséquents : une caractéristique des apprenants (les croyances des élèves sur les connaissances et le savoir, ou les croyances épistémiques), une propriété de textes pédagogiques (structures de texte réfutationnel), et une variable de contextes pédagogiques (objectifs de lecture). Cinquante-et-un étudiants de l'université avec des idées fausses sur l'évolution biologique ont été classés comme épousant soit des croyances absolutistes ou des croyances épistémiques évaluativistes. Les participants ont été assignés au hasard à recevoir un ou des textes réfutationnels ou descriptifs et une compréhension globale ou un objectif de lecture d'interrogation élaboratif dans une conception imbriquée de 2 × 2. Les données sur les pensées à haute voix pendant la lecture et des essais ouverts post-lecture ont été recueillies. Les résultats révèlent que les réfutations ont enrichi les connaissances des concepts évolutifs, mais ont échoué à favoriser la restructuration des idées fausses. Les croyances épistémiques étaient liées au traitement cognitif, avec des évaluativistes adaptant leurs processus en fonction de textes pédagogiques. Les objectifs de lecture, de même, ont enrichi la connaissance conceptuelle et n'ont pas corrigé les idées fausses, mais aucune interaction entre les objectifs assignés et les croyances épistémiques n'a été observée. Les implications théoriques et pratiques sont discutées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Krista Muis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78th23g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311t49g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adf65vc740"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional play in autism: an examination of qualities and characteristics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McGill, Laura</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans notre étude, nous avons examiné la diversité dans les comportements fonctionnels d'un petit groupe d'enfants atteints d'autisme et d'un enfant atteint de trisomie 21, dans un contexte d'activités libres. Les objectifs de cette étude étaient d'analyser les traits comportementaux (caractéristiques comportementales) des enfants dans un contexte d'activités non dirigées. Les comportements fonctionnels reliés au loisir ont étés codés en utilisant un schéma adapté de Williams, Reddy, et Costall (2001). Les données ont étés analysées selon un modèle de méthodes mixtes qui incorporait les données quantitatives et qualitatives recueillies à partir d'entrevues semi-structurées et de questionnaires soumis aux parents. Ensuite, la comparaison entre les comportements fonctionnels des enfants autistes et de l'enfant trisomique nous ont permis de faire ressortir des caractéristiques uniques liées aux types d'activités auxquelles le groupe a été soumis. Les résultats nous ont aussi permis d'analyser et d'interpréter les thèmes émergeants de la théorie moderne du loisir applicables aux enfants autistes. De manière générale, les enfants autistes soumis aux activités en situation spontannée ont démontré un répertoire d'actions limité en situation de jeu, et ne suivaient pas un ordre. Les résultats de cette étude ont des implications sur la compréhension que nous avons des caractéristiques comportementales des enfants autistes et contribuent ainsi au développement des programmes éducatifs et des stratégies d'interventions auprès des enfants atteints d'autisme. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The current study examined the diversity of functional play behaviour in a sample of children with autism (N = 5) and one child with Down syndrome.  The objectives of this study were to evaluate the characteristics of functional play acts in a free play situation. Free play behaviour was coded for functional play acts using a coding scheme adapted from Williams, Reddy, and Costall (2001). The data were analyzed using a mixed methods design that incorporated both quantitative and qualitative data collected through parent questionnaires and semi-structured observation. Anecdotal comparisons drawn between children with autism and a child with Down syndrome highlighted unique characteristics of functional play in this sample and allowed for the evaluation and interpretation of the emerging themes in relation to modern play theory as it applies to children with autism.  Overall, children with autism engaged in limited spontaneous functional play and often demonstrated a limited repertoire of play actions that did not follow an apparent sequence. Findings from this study have implications for the current understanding of the components of functional play in children with autism in relation to educational curriculum and intervention programs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steven Shaw</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591d21z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc740</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655m49d"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A tool for configuring mappings for musical systems using wireless sensor networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rudraraju, Vijay</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les instruments de musique numériques, que l'on définit ici comme des systèmes musicaux interactifs contenant un mecanisme de contrôle ainsi qu'un mécanisme de production sonore, constituent de puissants outils pour l'analyse des méthodes de performance ainsi que pour la transformation et la redéfinition de la la performance musicale. Cependant, la nature éphémère des technologie digitales ainsi que la complexité du maintien de la configuration d'un instrument de musique numérique, comprenant des dizaines voire centaines de composantes discrètes interconnectées, présente un reel problème. Même les systèmes musicaux acoustiques le plus complexes, comme le piano, sont assez robustes pour résister à l'usure quotidienne sans l'intervention d'une main experte ayant une connaissance aiguisée des matériaux et de la mecanique de l'instrument. Par ailleurs, ces instruments sont assez standards pour que tout luthier qualifíe soit en mesure d'intervenir sur l'instrument en cas de besoin. A l'inverse, les instruments de musique numériques présentent souvent des configurations propres a chaque performance (cette configurabilité étant une des vertus des instruments digitaux), incluent divers type de système hardware et software, et ne peuvent souvent être configurés de manière fiable que par leur créateur. Le problème grandit lorsque le nombre de capteurs utilisés pour la partie contrôle d'un instrument augmente et que l'interaction entre les sous-blocs contrôle et production sonore se complexifient. Cette relation entre le mécanisme de contrôle et de production sonore est appelée "mapping" de l'instrument. Le "mapping" d'un instrument se rapporte aux aspects les plus configurables définis par le logiciel (par opposition au éléments hardware), et mais aussi faisant partie les caractéristiques les plus importantes de l'instrument. Dans le cas d'un instrument de musique numérique, la capacite a agir facilement sur la configuration devient alors un enjeux de liberté d'expression artistique, en plus d'une condition de pérennisation. Ce travail de thèse se construit sur la base de deux projets menés au sein du laboratoire IDMIL (Input Devices and Musical Interaction Lab), le "Digital Orchestra" et "Libmapper", et traite du problème de construction d'un système/interface pour la configuration de système musicaux complexes sans connaissances expertes en programmation. L'objectif est de présenter un sondage ciblé sur la recherche en conception d'interface utilisateur et visualisation de données, dans le but d'apporter des éléments nouveaux a la conception d'interfaces destinées aux taches de configuration d'instruments digitaux.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Digital musical instruments, which are defined here as interactive musical systems containing a control mechanism and a sound generation mechanism, are powerful tools for analyzing performance practice and for transforming and reimagining the bounds of musical performance. However, the transitory nature of digital technology and the complexity of maintaining and configuring a digital musical instrument involving tens, if not hundreds, of interconnected, discrete components presents a unique problem. Even the most mechanically complex acoustic musical instruments, like a piano, are robust enough to withstand the daily grind without expert intervention by someone with intimate knowledge of the material and mechanical construction of the instrument. Furthermore, they are standardized enough that repairs can be conducted by any number of trained professionals. By contrast, digital musical instruments are often configured differently for each performance (this configurability being one of the virtues of a digital musical instrument), incorporate any number of non-standard pieces of hardware and software, and often can only be reliably configured by their creator. This problem is exacerbated as the number of sensors that make up the control mechanism in an instrument increases and the interaction of the control mechanism with the sound generation mechanism grows more complex. This relationship between the control mechanism and the sound generation mechanism is referred to here as the "mapping" of the instrument. The mapping for an instrument represents the aspect of an instrument that is usually most configurable because it is defined by software (as opposed to hardware) and also most crucial to the character of the instrument. In the case of a digital musical instrument, being able to easily configure the musical instrument becomes a point of artistic freedom in addition to a point of maintainability. This thesis builds upon work encompassed in two projects at the Input Devices and Musical Interaction Lab, the Digital Orchestra Project and Libmapper, to tackle the problem of building an interface/system for configuring a complex musical system without expert programming skills. The intent is to present a targeted survey of user interface design and data visualization design research through the years to inform the design of a graphical user interface for performing this configuration task.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marcelo Wanderley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m599n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655m49d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sf69d"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Estimation of sediment loadings in a small steep tropical catchment impacted by quarrying activities: a case study of the Acono River catchment, Trinidad, West Indies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baccard, Matthieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Sur l'île de Trinité, une activité anthropique intense, couplée à une utilisation inadéquate de sols propices à l'érosion et à un ruissellement de surface rapide, implique une forte sédimentation dans les cours d'eau. Une conséquence est l'augmentation du risque d'inondation durant les intenses précipitations de la saison humide, en raison d'une réduction de la capacité d'écoulement de ces cours d'eau. Ce projet étudie les problèmes de sédimentation dans la rivière Acono, à la vue des importantes quantités de sédiments à l'exutoire d'un bassin versant de 6.6 km2 où une carrière de calcaire est exploitée. Un réseau de mesure hydrologique et sédimentaire a été développé afin de mesurer l'impact de cette carrière sur la charge sédimentaire dans la rivière Acono au cours de plusieurs événements pluvieux. Les résultats indiquent que la majorité des sédiments transportés provient de la carrière en comparaison du reste du bassin versant. Le modèle MUSLE a fourni une estimation satisfaisante des quantités de sédiments transportés au cours des événements pluvieux analysés. Plusieurs équations ont été utilisées pour déterminer la charge sédimentaire en suspension et par charriage durant ces événements. La différence entre les prédictions et les mesures effectuées sur le terrain illustrent la difficulté de prédire la charge sédimentaire dans des cours d'eau naturels.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>On the island of Trinidad, intense anthropogenic activity and inappropriate land use on terrain vulnerable to erosion and rapid runoff lead to severe sedimentation in the watercourses. A major impact is an increase in flood risk during the strong storm events characteristic of the tropical rainy season due to reduced channel capacity. This study addresses the problem of sedimentation in the Acono River in light of the high sediment loadings observed at the outlet of a 6.6 km2 steep catchment where an operating limestone quarry is located. A hydrologic and sediment measurement network was developed to estimate the impact of the quarry on the sediment loadings in the Acono River for several storm events during a year. Results indicated that the quarry yields tremendously more sediment than the rest of catchment. The MUSLE model was used to estimate sediment yield from soil erosion for individual rainfall events and provided good results. Several sediment transport formulae were used to determine both suspended and bed load sediment discharge during rainfall events. The significant deviation of the computed values from the measured values showed how difficult it is to predict sediment discharge in natural rivers, particularly where washload is a significant component.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Susan J. Gaskin</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Vincent Anthony Cooper</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c656z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sf69d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Hydrology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>