<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w749d"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A kindergarten intervention study comparing rime and phoneme based programs and their effects on early literacy through computer literacy software : ABRACADABRA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Comaskey, Erin M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates the use of a new literacy software ABRACADABRA with pre-reading kindergarten students. The participants ( n=27) from one school were assigned randomly to one intervention group (rime or phoneme) and (n=17) school two served as a control. Ten hours of either a rime or phoneme ABRACADABRA intervention were employed to compare overall effectiveness of the software with regular classroom instruction. All participants were pre-tested at the onset of the study and post-tested following the intervention using eight highly sensitive measures to detect change in word reading strategies and phonemic skills specific to the two delivery methods. Measures were developed from previous studies and included blending and segmenting of matched CV (consonant-vowel), VC (vowel-consonant) words, high and low rime nonsense word reading, rime and coda articulation tasks. The results showed improvement in both interventions over the control on Letter-Sound knowledge and a combined reading task with a large advantage to the phoneme intervention in blending of VC words.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687h695.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w749d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language arts -- Computer-assisted instruction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computers and literacy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qc491"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Corps dressé : la représentation corporelle de l'honnête homme dans les traités de civilité au XVIIe siècle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Comtois, Maud</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ideal of honesty proposed by civility treaties results from the social and political reorganization orchestrated by Louis XIV's desire to assert his authority and impose a court ritual. Court treaties, like Antoine de Courtin's Le Nouveau traite de la civilite qui se pratique en France parmi les honnetes gens (1671), pass on an ideal of social behaviour in which the appearances are meticulously planned. Based on the principle that the physical appearance is a reflection of the inner self, the body is of great importance in honesty. Propriety books codify gestures and indicate the best attitude, outfit, posture and gait to single out an "honnete homme" from the mass. In order to respect the social standards, he moulds himself an exterior image and, in doing so, he establishes a difference between the public character and the private man. The representation of the body necessarily affects the creation of the "honnete homme"'s personality, which presents many traits of a modern identity.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zh12g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qc491</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Courtesy books -- France -- History -- 17th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human body in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mf759"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Power discourse and heresy in al-Andalus : the case of Ibn Masarra</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dane, Kirstin Sabrina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a study of zandaqa, or heresy, in the early medieval period of al-Andalus. The goal of this work is to uncover subtexts between caliphal power and legal authority through an analysis of the historiography of the Andalusian Muhammad ibn `Abd Allah Ibn Masarra al-Jabali (d. 319/931). This is accomplished by applying the Foucauldian theories of limit and transgression on the scholarly reconstructions of his life. The formation of the madhahib in al-Andalus, the construction of Orthodoxy and Heresy in Islam, and the historical-legal development of zandaqa colours how scholars have approached the subject, and leads to questions concerning the relationship that marginal or subversive intellectual developments had with authoritative bodies. The resulting play of divergent and authoritative discourses that emerge from a Post-Modernist analysis of the Masarrian context have the capacity to illustrate intellectual developments within early Andalusian society and provide an alternate explanatory narrative for historical reconstruction.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rd746.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mf759</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Andalusia (Spain) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muslim heretics -- Spain -- Andalusia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ibn Masarrah, Muḥammad ibn ʻAbd Allāh, 882 or 3-931</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247ds39x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children with problematic sexual behaviour in long term foster care : a review of attachment difficulties within care giving relationships and placement instability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Christ, Kaaren R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this theoretical study was to examine factors associated with the development of attachment relationships for children in long term foster care who Overt demonstrating problematic sexual behaviour. Due to the dearth in available research on this topic, it was necessary to draw from studies in three distinct areas (1) Attachment, (2) Childhood Sexuality, and (3) Placement Stability. In total, the present study examines 13 studies drawn from these three areas, and includes 11 quantitative and 2 mixed method studies. These studies were chosen for their attention to the middle age child in foster care who was demonstrating problematic sexual behaviour. Due to the lack of attachment studies on fostered middle age children, two infant studies were included with the rationale that middle age children and foster parents engage in a similar attachment process and infant studies would provide direction and context for future studies with older children. In the area of childhood sexuality, clinical samples were also included as they contained large numbers of children who had experienced sexual abuse or who had contact with child protection agencies even if they did not reside in foster care. Studies were examined along dimensions of sample, methods and findings. The results of this inquiry are then discussed, weaving together the three areas of study to answer two research questions: Is there a relationship between problematic childhood sexual behaviour and the development of a successful attachment relationship with a foster parent? And secondly, is there a particular foster parent attachment profile that promotes attachment security with children who are in care? Studies reviewed support the hypothesis that problematic childhood sexual behaviour presents challenges to foster parents significant enough to seriously impair the development of a secure attachment and that the foster parent's attachment state of mind will be an important factor in success. Results of the analysis of these questions contribute to an emerging hypothesis that the human sexual system may be intricately woven together with the attachment system, making an attachment analysis of problematic sexual behaviour in children particular relevant. A concluding discussion examines clinical issues which may be targets of intervention and the necessity of future research in this area is proposed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cd35b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247ds39x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Foster home care</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foster children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Child molesters</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sexually abused children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foster parents</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v5695"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children with developmental disabilities : finding permanent homes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cox, Judith, 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Finding permanent homes for children with developmental disabilities (DD), whose parents have voluntarily relinquished their care, is a problem for social workers. Ontario adoption social workers at a biennial business meeting in November/04 (N = 49) were asked about possible solutions, using a questionnaire designed for this study; information was also collected on relevant experience and caseloads. Workers believed that: (1) a majority of parents who voluntarily relinquish the care of their child do so because of the burden of care and/or financial reasons; (2) subsidies would be more effective than open adoption in improving chances of adoption. Also, a significant number of these adoption workers did not have an experience with DD on which to base their casework decisions. These findings highlight the need for specialist training on DD for social workers who deal with these children, and also the importance of subsidies for families who must care for them.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jk591.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v5695</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Developmentally disabled children -- Care</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311p61x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acheron, river of woe : for wind symphony</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fromm, Mark Stanley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acheron, River of Woe is a large-scale piece for wind symphony accompanied by an analytical thesis. It is a single-movement programmatic piece lasting twelve minutes scored for a wind symphony consisting of three flutes (one doubling piccolo), two oboes, English horn, two bassoons, contrabassoon, E-flat clarinet, three B-flat clarinets, A clarinet, bass clarinet, contrabass clarinet, four saxophones, four trumpets, four horns, two trombones, bass trombone, euphonium, tuba, string bass, timpani, and three percussionists. This piece represents a journey on the River Acheron, inspired by quotations taken from several Greek poets of antiquity. The entire piece flows as one long, fluid stream of music, with different sonic currents, waves, and eddies moving through it. Modal theory governs its harmonic structure and is the foundation of the piece.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z415.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311p61x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Band music -- Scores</dc:subject><dc:subject>Band music -- Analysis, appreciation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cd36m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Orbital debris : technical and legal issues and solutions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taylor, Michael W., 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the current technological and legal issues concerning orbital debris (space debris). The unique physical characteristics of the space environment are identified and explained. The thesis then explores the causes of orbital debris and examines the risk posed by debris to the most frequently used orbital areas. Significant environmental, legal, political, and economic consequences of orbital debris are described. The current technical and legal controls on the creation of debris are discussed and evaluated. Finally, proposed solutions are considered and critiqued. The thesis concludes with a non-binding treaty-based proposal for a new legal debris control regime that can encourage compliance and enhance accountability.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz04s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cd36m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space debris</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space debris -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816m83f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The characterization of drilling process of woven composites using machinability maps approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rawat, Sanjay</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Woven carbon fiber composites are being extensively used in aerospace, automotive and civil applications, owing to their high specific strength, higher fracture toughness, and drapeability as compared to unidirectional composites. The processing phase of composite manufacturing has a high added value to the processed laminate, so any damage during machining has a significant economical impact. However, the characteristic attributes like non-homogeneous structure, anisotropy and high abrasiveness of fibers coupled with non-optimized cutting parameters and tool wear can result in damage to the laminate. This experimental research involves quantifying the effect of processing parameters i.e. spindle speed, feed, and tool wear on hole quality during the drilling of a quasi-isotropic woven graphite fiber epoxy laminate. Drilling tests were conducted for wide range of spindle speeds (1,500 rpm to 15,000 rpm) and feed rates (20 μm/rev to 800 μm/rev) with a 5 mm diameter standard point tungsten carbide twist drill. This investigation extended the drilling approach to evaluate the benefits of high speed (12,000 rpm and 15,000 rpm) and high feed (600-800 μm/rev) regimes, which were not explored or reported in the open literature. Dependence of damage mechanisms; namely, delamination, fiber pull out, thermal damage, surface roughness deterioration, hole circularity and hole diameter errors, on cutting conditions was established. A strong correlation between different types of damages and cutting forces and temperature was also identified. High speed drilling approach produced contrasting results as spindle speed of 15,000 rpm was found to reduce delamination damage and improve surface roughness but increase the hole circularity and diameter errors. Machinability maps were designed to illustrate the affect of cutting parameters on delamination damage, hole circularity, hole diameter error and hole surface roughness. The application of machinability maps as an aid for process engineers to avoid damage and optimize the process is demonstrated. Finally, it was concluded that the process could be controlled and delamination be eliminated by increasing the spindle speed up to 15,000 rpm and feed rate up to 100 mum/rev. It results a higher productivity if a compromise on hole circularity and diameter tolerances is accepted. Having established the benefits of high speed and low feed drilling, tool wear was evaluated at 12,000 rpm and 15,000 rpm and optimal feed rate of 100 mum/rev. Chipping, abrasion and adhesion of carbon were found to be the main wear mechanisms. Abrasion at the flank face of the drills was identified to be the main wear process that controls the deterioration of the drill at high speeds. The three wear regimes i.e. primary, secondary, and tertiary, were found to strongly influence the thrust force, delamination damage, hole circularity, diameter error and hole surface roughness. Finally, the tool wear analysis revealed that a tool change strategy could be devised by monitoring the thrust force, rather than measuring the progression of flank wear.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w751f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816m83f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483j60j"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploring the effects of salts on gas dispersion and froth properties in flotation systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Quinn, Jarrett</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several mineral flotation plants utilize process water with high soluble salt content. The processing of soluble minerals, the use of recycle streams, sea or well water give rise to this situation. It is unclear as to the overall effect on flotation response though there does seem to be evidence of bubble size reduction, increased froth stability and reduced reagent dosage. The present work aims to quantify the effects of salts commonly present in process water on gas dispersion (bubble size and gas holdup) and froth properties (solid and liquid overflow rates) and to compare to a typical frother, MIBC (methyl isobutyl carbinol). Three sets of experiments were run: 2-phase, 3-phase using talc and 3-phase using ore. All tests were run in a laboratory column. The salts examined in the 2-phase tests were NaCl, CaCl₂, Na₂SO₄, Na₂S₂O₃ and Al₂(SO₄)₃. Tests were conducted to determine the effects of salt type and concentration on gas holdup, bubble size distribution and foaming. The salts containing multivalent ions had a greater impact than did the monovalent ions, in keeping with the literature. A relationship between gas holdup and ionic strength was established. The effects of NaCl and MIBC on frothing and on solid and liquid overflow rates in 3-phase tests using 1%w/w talc were investigated. The results showed increased frothing and overflow rates upon the addition of NaCl, comparable to adding MIBC. Three-phase tests using ore (Falconbridge's Brunswick Mine) explored the effect of NaCl concentration. The results show reduction in bubble size and increased gas holdup in salt solutions comparable to those in the 2-phase tests. For each case, the concentration of MIBC giving equivalent gas holdup and frothing as the salt systems was determined. Proposed mechanisms for coalescence inhibition and froth stability in salt solutions are briefly reviewed in light of the current findings.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06987785.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j60j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246s32r"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the failure mechanism of detonations in homogeneous and heterogeneous explosives</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Petel, Oren E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study measured the critical diameter and critical thickness of a variety of explosives. The explosives tested included two "unstable" homogeneous explosives (nitromethane and a nitromethane/nitroethane blend); a model heterogeneous explosive consisting of a packed bed of glass beads (Φ ~ 80 μm) saturated with the homogeneous nitromethane/nitroethane blend; and a commercial heterogeneous explosive, Apex Elite(TM). The comparison of the critical diameter and thickness of an explosive is used to identify the dominant propagation and failure mechanisms of the various explosives. The ratio of critical diameter to critical thickness for nitromethane, the nitromethane/nitroethane blend, the beaded heterogeneous explosive, and Apex Elite(TM) were found to be 3.2 +/- 0.6, 3.6 +/- 0.4, 2.3 +/- 0.1, and 3.5 +/- 1.2 respectively. According to accepted detonation failure theories, the energy losses associated with detonation front curvature are responsible for detonation failure. The curvature model, which is elaborated upon in the present work, leads to a predicted critical diameter to critical thickness ratio of exactly 2. The present study has shown that the only explosive which follows the behaviour predicted by curvature failure models is the beaded heterogeneous explosive, which exhibits fine scale heterogeneities. This seems to indicate that unstable liquid explosives and heterogeneous explosives with large scale heterogeneities do not fail simply due to the wave front curvature, but rather by a local mechanism of failure and reinitiation which dominates the detonation propagation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903013r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246s32r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Fluid and Plasma</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z708w76r"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The determination of modal parameters from experimental data of linear and nonlinear aeroelastic systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Picot, Natalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The determination of the modal parameters of an airplane wing, such as damping and natural frequency, as well as the determination of the aircraft's flutter speed, is an important part of aircraft design and testing. The effect that a 'defect' can have on the system, such as a loose hinge or worn fastening, is also an important part of aircraft analysis. In this study, a two-dimensional, symmetrical airfoil was mounted as part of a linear system in a wind tunnel, subject to steady, incompressible flow. Experimental data was collected using both free and forced vibrations of the airfoil, at different increments of airspeed. This data was then analyzed using conventional modal analysis techniques, extracting the damping factor and the natural frequency of the system, thus enabling a value for the flutter speed to be calculated. A structural freeplay nonlinearity was then introduced into the system, mimicking the effects a loose hinge or worn fastening can have on the airfoil modal parameters. The same tests were performed, and the modal parameters were evaluated using special nonlinear parameter extraction techniques. The behaviour of the damping and natural frequency of the nonlinear system, obtained from all three methods of data collection, were then compared to those of the linear system.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731411m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708w76r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Aerospace</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vb55b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fugitive rhythms : re-imagining diasporic Caribbean-Canadian communities in Ramabai Espinet's The Swinging Bridge, Tessa McWatt's Out of My Skin, and Dionne Brand's What We All Long For</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waisvisz, Sarah Gabriella</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>How do immigrants to Canada experience exile and diaspora? What happens when a person does not identify with a nostalgic past "there" or a present "here," but rather with "nowhere"? I am interested in the development of a diasporic critical consciousness in three recent novels by Caribbean-Canadian women writers. This paper uses theories of diaspora, cosmopolitanism, hybridity, kala pani discourse, and anti-racist feminist analysis to discuss Ramabai Espinet's The Swinging Bridge (2003), Tessa McWatt's Out of My Skin (1998), and Dionne Brand's What We All Long For (2005). Overall the novels explore the potential of art and artistic strategies to express the complex condition of diaspora, to form alliances between different cultural and ethnic communities, and to enable social and political change. While acknowledging the violent and traumatic historical factors that have contributed to diaspora, the novels look to art and hybridity as sites of resistance and hope.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t334.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb55b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brand, Dionne, 1953-. What We All Long For</dc:subject><dc:subject>Caribbean Canadians</dc:subject><dc:subject>Espinet, Ramabai, 1948-. Swinging Bridge</dc:subject><dc:subject>McWatt, Tessa, 1959-. Out of My Skin</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xm241"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Space, vision and identity : imagining and inventing Shanghai in the courtesan illustrations of Dianshizhai Pictorial (1884-1898)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yu, Miao, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates various representational modes and strategies in the Shanghai courtesan illustrations in Dianshizhai Pictorial. The aim of the study is to examine how Shanghai's early modern identity was imaged, imagined and contested through the courtesan figure. I argue that by establishing a new urban iconography, Dianshizhai Pictorial transformed the Shanghai courtesan from a traditional archetypical meiren to a universal image of the urban beauty. On the one hand, the modern city, previously an alien concept, was made familiar and acceptable through the image of the Shanghai courtesan. On the other hand, the ambivalence of the courtesan's new image mirrored a mixed feeling of fear, anxiety and disdain towards the emerging metropolis. The courtesan illustrations, hence, served as an important domain where different public understandings of the city were negotiated and expressed in pictorial terms.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx25w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm241</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shanghai (China) -- Social life and customs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Illustrated periodicals -- China</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prostitutes -- China -- Shanghai -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>China -- History -- Guangxu, 1875-1908</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430491z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>'Like dew from heaven:' : honeycomb, religious identity, and transformation in Joseph and Aseneth</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warren, Meredith</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the construction of identity in the pseudepigraphic novel Joseph and Aseneth by means of discussions of conversion, food ritual, and genre. Each of these is invaluable for interpreting the meaning and significance of the honeycomb scene in which Aseneth is transformed. The interaction of a ritual of eating, angelic visits, and the medium of genre for expressing transformation presents a window through which to view identity in the ancient world. This project explores how the shared symbolic knowledge of the ancient world informs the literary presentation of Aseneth's transformation that describes the development of her religious identity. I argue that the honeycomb scene speaks most strongly about Joseph and Aseneth's notions of religious identity. Through the ritual eating of the honeycomb, Joseph and Aseneth constructs a hybrid identity for Aseneth, integrating biblical motifs with those found in pagan narratives.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h223x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430491z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food -- Religious aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pq59n"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The fearful touch of death : the philosophy of death and pain in aesthetics and media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warwaruk, Eric D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The central question this thesis is concerned with is the question of death: how do we make sense of it? Through philosophical examination, we discover we cannot make sense of death. Death is nonsensical because it cognitively and physically cannot be controlled via a binary context; death becomes something we fear. This fear we feel is, in turn, immune to true catharsis. To control the fear of death to some extent, we suture the fear we experience from physical punishment with our metaphysical fear of death. Thus, the meaning and experience of death become entangled in the binary of punishment and non-punishment. We tentatively argue that this suture is expressed in media texts, such as film; and further posit hypothetically that media texts such as film have the function of either alleviating, or controlling, the fear of death, both in production and reception.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rw91s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pq59n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Death in motion pictures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Death</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fh40q"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Courting the West : Nicholas I, cultural diplomacy and the State Hermitage Museum in 1852</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Digout, Amy Erica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The State Hermitage Museum in St. Petersburg as a royal collection and cultural treasury reveals the aesthetic preferences of a nation that has always stood on the cultural and geographical periphery of Europe. Initially an imperial collection under Peter I, patrons of the Hermitage focused attention on collecting canonical European paintings and also emulating Western models of display. In this way, the Russian aristocracy superimposed itself on Europe's culture through the construction of a collection to rival its great European contemporaries. The development of a standardized practice of display has widely been studied in relation to Western museums but similar attention has not been extended to the State Hermitage Museum in St. Petersburg. I argue that Nicholas was able to use objects of art and strategies of display to assert a greater role in the European state system of the mid-nineteenth century. While the supposed transparency conveyed by the collection's public opening was meant to make Russia seem less threatening to Western powers, in reality the yolk of autocracy was as tight as ever.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569472r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh40q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nicholas I, Emperor of Russia, 1796-1855</dc:subject><dc:subject>Russia -- Foreign relations -- 1801-1917</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gosudarstvennyĭ Ėrmitazh (Russia)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gd27d"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Worshipping the dark : the manifestations of Carl Gustav Jung's archetype of the shadow in contemporary Wicca</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dion, Nicholas Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Swiss psychoanalyst Carl Gustav Jung describes the encounter with the archetype of the shadow as the initial step to be taken by any individual seeking to initiate the individuation process. Jung observes a close relationship between this process and religion, suggesting that a psychologically beneficial religion can help guide the subject through individuation. Yet Jung finds few existing religious traditions that satisfy his criteria. Wicca, a neopagan religion popular in Europe and North America, presents itself at times as consciously psychological, striving to lead the practitioner to a goal of self-transformation, yielding a product that strangely resembles the individuated person. The objective therefore becomes not to criticize Wiccan religious claims, nor to deconstruct Jungian philosophy, but to identify the points of intersection between Wiccan theology/theology and Jungian psychology of religion, with a particular emphasis on the archetype of the shadow.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g540b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gd27d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1875-1961</dc:subject><dc:subject>Archetype (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shades and shadows</dc:subject><dc:subject>Witchcraft</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246s349"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Female subjectivity and religion according to Julia Kristeva</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bruijn, Bonnie de.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the face of an explosion of feminist discourse and an increasingly global, deeply troubled socio-religious climate, the following study explores the role of religion qua Christianity in researching female subjectivity, according to Julia Kristeva. Kristeva's pervasive influence and controversial reception in academic circles grants her the focus of this investigation. This project familiarizes the reader with Kristeva's theory of subjectivity as a process and situates her among the plethora of feminist theorists. It also examines her view that religion is an illusory therapy for the modern subject in crisis. Finally, these two themes are brought together in a discussion on her theory of a culture of revolt, derived from the psychoanalytic process. Kristeva's vision for the future of feminism is shown to be deeply philosophical, while also socially and politically important. Furthermore, in revolt culture, religion might well leave open the possibility of researching female subjectivity.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jk60s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246s349</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Feminism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subjectivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kristeva, Julia, 1941-</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296wz43m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La reine des fées trop longtemps oubliée : translation et traduction de l'œuvre d'Edmund Spenser</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Spenser, Edmund, 1552?-1599</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of this thesis is to reactivate the project of translation (Berman's concept of the passage from one language-culture to another) of Edmund Spenser's The Faerie Queene into French. Spenser, one of the most famous English writers of the Renaissance, has still not been translated into French. A few attempts were made during the first half of the 20th century, but the projects were left unfinished. This thesis first looks at the attempts of these rare translators, to try to find out why the projects were abandoned. It then considers the question of the translation of poetry, which is central to translating Spenser's work, and suggests a new approach: the quest to seek an "effect" of poetry, a concept similar to Barthe's concept of effet de reel. The thesis concludes with Canto I and II of Book I of The Faerie Queene translated into French.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mx82q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296wz43m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature, English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c3064"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Proteomics characterization of the cardiac sarcolemma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elghawanmeh, Omar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As the plasma membrane of the cardiac muscle cell (sarcolemma) plays a major role in the cardiac physiology and homeostasis, the aim of this study is to identify using mass spectrometry (MS) and data base mining the integral and peripheral proteins that are making its composition and to uncover putative novel proteins and to ultimately reveal the differences in protein composition between the sarcolemma of control rat hearts and hearts submitted to ischemia and ischemia-reperfusion to find disease-specific markers. Toward this goal we have developed a new method to purify cardiac sarcolemma using an approach that avoids denaturing conditions and combines subcellular fractionation and immunoadsorption: An initial cardiac sarcolemma preparation obtained by sucrose gradient centrifugation was enriched 27-fold in 5-nucleotidase activity and 5-12-fold in sarcolemmal specific markers. Subsequently, this enriched preparation was incubated with antibodies directed against intercalated disc proteins, N-cadherin and Connexin43, and then immunoadsorbed to superparamagnetic beads (Dynabeads Pan Mouse IgG). Samples from the enriched sarcolemma and immunoabsorbed fractions were separated by 1-D SDS-PAGE and in-gel digested with trypsin. The tryptic fragments were identified, analyzed and assigned to proteins using tandem MS-MS spectrometry in combination with Mascot search software. Out of the 518 identified proteins, 40% were attributed to the sarcolemma and associated cytoskeleton, of which 65% were peripheral proteins and the remainders were either membrane spanning or lipid anchored proteins. Further functional classification of the sarcolemma proteins indicates that the majority (65%) are involved in signaling, trafficking and cell adhesion. The MS analysis also reveals the presence of 71 novel proteins, which are currently being evaluated as relevant candidates for further study. Comparing the sarcolemma and immunoselected intercalated disc preparations; we noticed that the distribution of protein abundance in all of the localization and functional categories follows almost the same trend. This led us to conclude that in order to have an easy, fast and a reliable technique to compare different heart states in terms of sarcolemma protein composition the sarcolemma preparation would serve just as well as an immunoselected preparation with less time, effort and materials. In order to find out differences in protein composition between normal sarcolemma and sarcolemma submitted to global ischemia/ischemia-reperfusion; sarcolemma fractions (SF) obtained from Langendorff rat heart models were analyzed by mass spectrometry. The results of this study revealed that global ischemia induced an increase in calcium binding proteins (i.e. annexins) concomitantly with a decrease in transport proteins (i.e. Na/K ATPase). After ischemia, the signaling proteins category showed a decrease followed by a return to the control level after reperfusion. The amount of G alpha inhibiting 2 protein, caveolin, flotilin and myosin varied significantly during the ischemia/reperfusion protocol.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p739x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c3064</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k515r"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The CDP/Cux transcription factor interacts with hRev1, a translesion polymerase involved in ultraviolet-induced mutagenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dudley, Rachel Gillian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>CDP/Cux, a transcription factor involved in cell cycle regulation, has been shown to play a significant but currently ill-defined role in cancer development, including breast cancer, leiomyomas and myeloid leukemia. Recently, Tandem Affinity Purification (TAP)/Mass Spectrometry (MS) experiments revealed that CDP/Cux may interact with hRev1, a translesion polymerase known to play an important role in damage-induced mutagenesis. To study this interaction, we generated polyclonal antibodies against hRev1. These antibodies were found to be capable of detecting recombinant and endogenous hRev1 through Western blotting, and endogenous hRev1 through immunofluorescence. We also confirmed the interaction of CDP/Cux with hRev1 in vivo in several cell lines using coimmunoprecipitation, affinity purification and immunofluorescence experiments. From these studies it appears that full-length hRev1 binds to a p110 isoform of CDP/Cux, and this complex was found to be capable of binding to DNA through southwestern blotting. Furthermore, GST pulldown assays have shown that the BRCT domain located at the N-terminus of hRev1 is necessary for binding CDP/Cux in vitro, as deletion of this domain abolished or greatly reduced the protein-protein interaction with CDP/Cux. Furthermore, in cells synchronized into S-phase, both full-length CDP/Cux (p200) and p110 were found to bind to DNA with increased affinity following treatment with low levels of UVC. These proteins were also found to have a generally enhanced affinity for DNA with a 5' base overhang compared to a fully double-stranded DNA probe. These findings are the first to define an interaction between CDP/Cux and hRev1. If CDP/Cux cooperates with hRev1 in translesion synthesis, this would implicate CDP/Cux in enabling mutagenesis in response to DNA damage and perhaps expose the consequence of aberrant CDP/Cux activity in cancer cells.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nt78c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k515r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj67314135"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Osteoclast-specific inactivation of the Integrin-Linked Kinase (ILK) inhibits bone resorption</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dossa, Tanya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bone resorption requires the adhesion of osteoclasts to extracellular matrix (ECM) components, a process mediated by the alphavbeta 3 integrin. Following engagement with the ECM, integrin receptors signal via multiple downstream effectors, including the Integrin-Linked Kinase (ILK). In order to characterize the physiological role of ILK in bone resorption, we generated mice with an osteoclast-specific ILK gene ablation. Mice with one inactivated ILK allele (ILK+/-) were mated with TRAP-Cre transgenic mice. Progeny from this cross (TRAP-Cre;ILK+/-) was bred to mice homozygous for a floxed ILK allele (ILKfl/fl) to yield mutant mice with ILK-deficient osteoclasts (TRAP-Cre;ILK+/fl ). The mutant animals thus had one ILK allele inactivated in all tissues, and both alleles disrupted in osteoclasts. Mutant mice appeared phenotypically normal, but histomorphometric analysis of the proximal tibia revealed an increase in bone volume and trabecular thickness. Osteoclastogenesis, assessed by TRAP staining of bone sections or in vitro cultures, was not affected. Indeed, osteoclast-specific ILK ablation was associated with an increase in osteoclast number both in vitro and in vivo. Primary cultures of osteoclasts were generated on synthetic calcium phosphate discs, as well as dentin, and the mutant cells displayed a decrease in resorption activity. We also measured decreased serum concentrations of the C-terminal telopeptide of collagen, a marker of osteoclastic activity, in mice with ILK-deficient osteoclasts. Our results show that ILK is important for the function, but not the differentiation, of osteoclasts. The characterization of the molecular mechanisms responsible for the observed phenotype will identify novel pathways regulating bone resorption.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/000000239.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67314135</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296wz44w"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluating the espressivity of aspectJ in implementing a reusable framework for the ACID properties of transactional objects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duala-Ekoko, Ekwa J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Aspect-Oriented Programming (AOP) continues to gain increasing popularity in both academia and industry for its effectiveness in localizing and modularizing crosscutting concerns. Two recurring criticisms of AOP tools are their deficiency (or inflexibility) in language features and the potential performance overhead that may be incurred from adopting this technology. Using Aspect) as the target AOP tool, I investigate the language features necessary to support aspect dependencies, aspect interactions, aspect interference and aspect reuse in the context of implementing the ACID properties of transactional objects in a flexible and reusable way. Five encountered limitations are identified, namely; lack of support for inter-aspect configurability, lack of support for runtime disabling and re-enabling of pointcuts on a per-object basis, lack of support for per-instance association of aspects, lack of support for stronger and intuitive aspect-to-class binding of reusable static crosscutting behaviours, and the reflection/super-class method execution dilemma. Finally, I discuss the deficiencies of work-around solutions and suggest potential language improvements for addressing these limitations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xh91j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296wz44w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h225g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of the tetrameric monocytic leukemia zinc finger protein complex</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ullah, Mukta</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In human cells, histones bind DNA and form chromatin, a nucleoprotein complex important for various cellular processes. Abnormal histone modification is known to play causal roles in the development of cancer. Monocytic leukemia zinc finger protein (MOZ) is a MYST-family histone acetyltransferase whose gene is rearranged in chromosomal translocations giving rise to acute myeloid leukemia. This acetyltransferase functions as a potent transcriptional coactivator of Runx1 and Runx2, two homologous transcription factors that are important for definitive haematopoiesis and osteoblast maturation, respectively. Mouse knockouts have demonstrated that MOZ is required for the maintenance of hematopoetic stem cells, and is important for erythroid and myeloid cell differentiation. Chapter I reviews the importance of chromatin regulation, MYST histone acetyltransferases and ties them together to explain how gene regulation is achieved. Chapter II addresses the characterization of the tetrameric MOZ complex, and suggests that its activity can be modulated by the presence of associated subunits such as BRPF1, and ING5. We show by histone acetyltransferase assays that MOZ and MORF activity is indeed enhanced by associated proteins. We have mapped the interaction domains of BRPF1 required for binding by MOZ, ING5, and Eaf6 in an effort to understand the mechanism of activation. Given that MOZ and ING proteins contribute to oncogenesis by chromosomal translocations and loss of function respectively, the characterization of the multisubunit complex provides novel mechanistic insights into its function in normal human cells and under conditions of leukemia or other cancers.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np1939453.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h225g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xh92t"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on storage behaviour of tomatoes coated with chitosan-lysozyme films</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thumula, Padmini</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Simple technologies are required for reducing the post harvest losses of horticultural produce. Edible films are being studied extensively for application on fresh and cut fruits and vegetables. Tomato, being a very nutritious and important food and a highly perishable climacteric fruit, this study was planned to investigate the application of chitosan films. Chitosan is a biodegradable waste product from sea food and is safe for consumption. With a view to broaden its antimicrobial activity it was combined with lysozyme, a lytic enzyme. Since the edible films are sensitive to changes in temperature and humidity, they were studied under ambient and optimal conditions of storage. This study showed that 1% chitosan was more suitable for tomatoes for storage at both conditions of ambient and low temperature. Respiration study showed that 1% chitosan treatments resulted in more favorable levels of CO 2 production and internal O2. This was reflected in the quality of tomatoes held under these conditions. Two per cent chitosan films were unsuitable due to their high CO2 production and low internal O 2 levels. Spoilage was more apparent in this treatment. Lysozyme addition did not show any additional benefit. The research in this study has demonstrated that the selection of edible films for horticultural produce needs to be integrated with the requirement of storage conditions of the produce.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds40p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xh92t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Edible coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tomatoes -- Preservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chitosan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tomatoes -- Postharvest physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>