<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dn550"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Responsibility and liability in general public international law and in the law of outer space</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lowe, Sabine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Just as the actions of individuals often conflict with the legally protected interests of others, States may embark on activities which jeopardize the integrity of other States' rights. The new relationship evolving between the risk-creators and the potential victims is governed by social responsibilities as well as rules of law. In the first part of the thesis, the concept of responsibility for internationally wrongful acts is contrasted with that of liability sine delicto. The examination seeks to define the principles upon which each is based and to determine the respective legal significance, scope and applicability. The analysis of both concepts is guided and influenced by the work of the International Law Commission. The second part focusses on the law of outer space. A scrutiny of the relevant norms reveals which stage of development this fairly new subdivision of international law has reached with regard to responsibility and liability.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc362.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn550</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g862d"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of microwave drying on paper properties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kumar, Pawan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Effects of microwave drying on the mechanical and optical properties of handsheets made from kraft and chemi-thermomechanical pulps were studied experimentally. The quality of paper dried in a microwave field of 2450 MHz is compared with that of paper dried by conventional method under standard conditions. Key physical properties measured include burst index, density, tear index, breaking length, zero-span tensile strength, double fold, STFI compressibility and optical properties include brightness, opacity and scattering coefficient. All properties were found to be either enhanced or at the same level as those obtained under standard conditions. Furthermore, it is suggested that microwave drying could replace the conventional drying method in the standard testing of pulp and paper samples for quality control purposes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Koran, Z.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mujumdar, A. S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw29g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g862d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Microwave drying</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418p35d"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La silence et le contrat : approche comparée</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyer, Olivier Frédéric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The author of this thesis undertakes to compare the role of silence in the Civil and Common law of contracts. This thesis demonstrates that these two legal systems, which had at first ignored silence, have reined it in to an increasingly greater degree by objectifying it. This paper's purpose is thus not only to comparatively assess the role of silence through the various phases of the contract, where this process of objectivization occurs, but also to examine the reasons behind this process. Lastly, it will examine the direction the process takes. The scope of silence being indefinite, it would be unreasonable to imagine its complete objectivization. Nevertheless, the parallel processes in both the Common and the Civil law will have to evolve further in order to allow silence to take on a greater role in Contracts. The succes of such an evolution, in either system, will no doubt result from a comparative approach of this phenomenon.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c389w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p35d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Contracts</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silence (Law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801ph54m"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study in transitions : Wesley's soteriology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Scott, Shawn A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to delineate the theological shifts that occurred in Wesley's post-Aldersgate soteriology. To realize this purpose, three distinct soteriological shifts in his thought will be examined. These shifts involve changes in how he understood the following: the conditions of redemption, the state of humanity and the scope of salvation. Through an examination of these shifts, three distinct phases (early, middle and late) were detected. In the early phase there appears to be a distinct Reformed bias; fallen human beings are totally depraved and can be redeemed only through explicit faith in Christ's atonement. In the two subsequent phases, an increasing emphasis is given to Arminian distinctives. Particular emphasis is given to the Arminian understanding of prevenient grace. In the middle phase, the Reformed and Arminian elements appear to co-exist within the same soteriological framework--reconciled through a tenuous and at times tortuous dialectic. This dialectic seems to crumble in the late phase. The Reformed elements are quietly dismissed; the Arminian elements dominate.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032421f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801ph54m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grace (Theology) -- History of doctrines -- 18th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salvation -- Christianity -- History of doctrines -- 18th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Redemption -- History of doctrines -- 18th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wesley, John, 1703-1791 -- Contributions in doctrine of salvation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w032419d"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of exercise intensity on the stereotypic behaviours of individuals with autism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levinson, Leslie J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of exercise intensity on the stereotypic behaviours of three autistic subjects were examined. Two exercise programs which differed on the basis of intensity as measured by heart rate were implemented. The frequency of stereotypic behaviours were measured prior to exercise, immediately following exercise and 90 minutes following exercise. Significant reductions in stereotypic behaviors occurred as a function of the vigorous exercise condition only. The mean reduction of stereotypic behaviours between pre-jogging and post-jogging was 17.5%. The duration of these reductions was found to be temporary. Increases to pre-exercise levels were noted in stereotypic behaviours one and a half hours following implementation of the exercise conditions. For the purpose of examining any differential effects of exercise intensity, the stereotypic behaviours of all subjects were categorized into three components motor, verbal and other. The motor component of stereotypic behaviour was most prominent. The moderate exercise condition had little effect on the motor component, while the vigorous exercise condition resulted in a mean reduction of 17%.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm73k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032419d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Autism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Exercise therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c89k"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Flutter evaluation and control of an airfoil solved in the Laplace domain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jeffrey, Alfred</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Aeroelasticity is concerned with the interaction of aerodynamic forces and the resulting structural deformations for a structure in an airflow. Flutter, which is one example of an aeroelastic phenomena, may result in the catastrophic failure of an aircraft. The traditional methods of predicting the flutter velocity, namely the $U - g$ and $p - k$, have been used with great success. However, in recent years, new methods have been suggested which approximate the unsteady aerodynamic forces and moments by rational functions. The resulting equations are then solved in the Laplace domain. The goals of this work are twofold. Firstly, to solve the equations of motion for an airfoil, in both incompressible and transonic flow, in the Laplace domain using rational functions to approximate the unsteady aerodynamics. Secondly, to implement active control for the airfoil in incompressible flow with the aim of increasing the critical flutter speed. The solution of the aeroelastic equations of motion in the Laplace domain proved to be a powerful tool in the analysis of flutter.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg19w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c89k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161736t"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of German</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A figure of enormity : Thomas Mann's Der Erwählte as political allegory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>King, Lissette N. (Lissette Nicol)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Thomas Mann's novel Der Erwahlte explores the concepts of sin, contrition, and eventual redemption through the life of the sinful pope Gregorius. The concept of enormity provides the link between the seemingly esoteric subject of his novel and the history of Germany under Nazi rule. He draws a direct, if subtle, parallel between German fascism and Gregorius' sins. The hero's sin, his penance, and his redemption are all overwhelming, thus providing the connection with German national character and history as understood by Mann. By examining the deep structure of the novel's imagery and plot in conjunction with Mann's political speeches, this thesis reveals these underlying similarities, and the essentially positive message which the novel finally conveys. The use of language and the Gregorius legend to express Mann's deep-rooted belief in the fundamental unity of European culture is also examined.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418p36p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161736t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955. Erwählte</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wh16p"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rorty, Freud, and Bloom : the limits of communication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cashion, Tim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis examines the nature of political reform and the role of culture in the liberal utopia envisaged by Richard Rorty in Contingency, Irony, and Solidarity. Rorty's overall project is outlined, and situated within the anti-foundationalist critique that has been the hallmark of his recent career. The perilous position of nonintellectuals within the otherwise-acceptable utopia is detailed. Harold Bloom's conception of the strong poet is then examined and compared to the use Rorty makes of Bloom; I conclude that the faults of the liberal utopia lie primarily in establishing the strong poet as that culture's hero. I turn to Rorty's reading of Sigmund Freud, a reading which consistently inverts Freud's insights in order to make Freud fit into Rorty's plan. Finally, I re-examine Freud and suggest ways in which he can be used to correct the faults of the liberal utopia.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx70g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh16p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bloom, Harold -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Freud, Sigmund, 1856-1939</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rorty, Richard. Contingency, irony and solidarity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418p37z"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Failure of laminated composite pinned connections</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shokrieh, Mahmood M. (Mahmood Mehrdad)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this investigation the behavior of pin-loaded composite plates is studied analytically. A progressive damage model is presented which is capable of predicting the three different mechanisms of failure: bearing, shearout, and net tension. The model consists of three major parts: stress analysis, and material property degradation rules. Based on the model a computer code is developed. The computer code is capable of assessing damage, evaluating residual strength, and predicting ultimate strength of pin-loaded composite plates. Predicted results are compared with available experimental data. Excellent agreement between the predicted and the experimental data was found. The computer code is used to study geometric parameters that influence joint strength. Such studies are useful in designing mechanical fastened joints using advanced composites.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq137.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p37z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j215s"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A technique for combining equalization with differential detection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aleong, Kenneth Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A technique for combining equalization and differentially coherent detection is proposed for use in wireless communication when carrier phase recovery is difficult. A decision-feedback differentially coherent scheme, which generates an improved reference phase, is combined with a linear equalizer and the LMS algorithm is used to adapt the equalizer to an unknown channel. In addition, the proposed receiver is simulated for various two-dimensional signal constellations over multipath channels. It is shown that for high SNR, the degradation of this structure is negligible with respect to combined coherent detection and equalization. Therefore, this equalized differentially coherent detection scheme can be used when carrier phase tracking (i.e. coherent detection) is difficult and intersymbol interference is a major obstacle.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x45s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j215s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720d96w"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cultural sovereignty and broadcasting - Canadian content rules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vormann, Thorsten</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>... current Canadian content regulation can hardly be seen as a success. Therefore, l will examine the existing policy with its basic assumptions and consequences. After illustrating the shortcomings of the present regulatory regime, l will provide a survey of various proposed alternatives. Finally, l will introduce my own proposal and address the different objectives of broadcasting policy in a more comprehensive and cohesive way.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Abstract Not Available.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, R.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sd815.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720d96w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, Public Administration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sk63f"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"The Release" : a creative writing thesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Knez, Dora</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The genre of fantasy contains texts which are unlike, or distance from, the real or empirical world--the world of the reader's experience. Nevertheless, fantasy texts can reveal truths which are relevant to the empirical world, and thus fantasy texts can be said to have cognitive value. The notion of possible worlds, the semiotic theory of metaphor, and a discussion of ambiguity are the three critical approaches used to investigate the cognitive value of fantasy texts. The stories in this collection provide a sampler of fantasy figures--such as mermaids, ghosts and living mummies--and make use of the emotional power of ambiguity.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf91j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk63f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fantasy fiction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816n660"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microencapsulation of lactococcus lactis subsp. cremoris for application in the dairy industry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Larisch, Belinda C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Microcapsules are comprised of particles or droplets surrounded by ultrathin polymeric membranes. The process of microencapsulation is currently used in the immobilization of biocatalysts, including enzymes and biological cells. A study of the possible use of encapsulated lactic acid bacteria in the dairy industry was performed for the purpose of comparing three methods of immobilizing Lactococcus lactis subsp. cremoris. A new immobilization method involving microencapsulation of L. lactis subsp. cremoris within a cross-linked polyethyleneimine membrane was developed. This technique was compared to existing alginate bead and nylon membrane microcapsule immobilization in terms of the microorganism viability and lactic acid production activity. The alginate bead, surrounded by a poly-L-lysine membrane, afforded the greatest viability and activity of the encapsulated cells. The nylon encapsulation procedure did not result in the maintenance of viable cells, and the polyethyleneimine encapsulation procedure did not provide evidence of lactic acid production by the cells. The rate of lactic acid production by Lactococcus lactis subsp. cremoris encapsulated in alginate-PLL is less than that produced by unencapsulated or free cells. The difference diminishes with increasing cell concentrations. At a concentration of approximately 10$ sp9$ cells/ml of milk, the time required to acidify the milk to the point at which it is useful in the dairy industry is identical for both free and encapsulated cells.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666564h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n660</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Agricultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1v53jz28x"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La problématique de la communication dans trois romans d'André Langevin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Garneau, Véronique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Andre Langevin's five novels, the theme of isolation keeps on coming back. The characters however try by different means to establish a communication with other people but their attempts almost always fail, due to some sort of fatality. This thesis sheds light on the different attempts by Langevin's characters to establish a relationship with those who surround them. The corpus is composed of Poussiere sur la ville (1953), Le temps des hommes (1956), L'Elan d'Amerique (1972), the latter belonging to the come back of the novelist after a silence of about twenty years. The dialogues and non verbal communications as they are established among the characters will successively be analyzed. The third novel, L'Elan d'Amerique, brings unique forms of this theme as it introduces a new style of the author, which has been compared to the "nouveau roman's". From one novel to the other, the topic of incommunicability as developed by Langevin, takes new forms as the novelistic scope expands. But this research reveals that, in these three novels, a failure is always witnessed by the characters who never succeed in establishing satisfactory or lasting relationships with others.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v6615.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz28x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Langevin, André, 1927- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4j03d0983"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A "Politic well-wrought veil" : Edmund Burke's politico- aesthetic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Macpherson, Sandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to demonstrate the aesthetic strategy of the political philosophy of Edmund Burke, by considering the relation between the "artificial infinite" of the Enquiry Into our Ideas of the Sublime and Beautiful, and the "immemorial custom" of the Reflections on the Revolution in France. The argument addresses misreadings of Burke found in recent critical theories on the "aestheticism" of "bourgeois ideology." The thesis shows that the demotion of the sublime in favour of the beautiful which is considered by these critics to be characteristic of bourgeois aestheticism, does not happen in Burke's aesthetics. It also shows that the "naturalism" of bourgeois ideology is contradicted by the strategic artificiality of Burke's politico-aesthetic. Insofar as the ideologue seeks to resolve the contingent aspects of language and history, Burke cannot be considered an ideological thinker. Rather, Burke's political philosophy consistently fails to provide the coalescence of subjective and universal which is required for ideology. Finally, the irreconcilable contingency of Burke's view of political experience shows that his conservatism is not, as his critics would have it, static and unchanging.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c17z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d0983</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797 -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aesthetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k624x"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional organization of the chloroplast in the diatom Phaeodactylum tricornutum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pyszniak, Andrew M. (Andrew Michael)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The technique of protein A-gold immunoelectron microscopy was used to determine the distributions of two photosynthetic complexes in the thylakoid membranes of the diatom Phaeodactylum tricornutum. The fucoxanthin-chlorophyll a/c light-harvesting complex, believed to be associated with photosystem II, was found to be equally distributed among appressed and unappressed membranes, whereas photosystem I was slightly more concentrated in the latter. These results suggest that in diatoms, the two photosystems and their associated light-harvesting complexes are essentially equally distributed on the two types of membranes, in marked contrast to the lateral heterogeneity observed in higher plants and green algae. Furthermore, it was expected that in P. tricornutum, the nuclear-coded proteins of the fucoxanthin-chlorophyll a/c light-harvesting complex would be present in the vesicles of the periplastidal reticulum, which were postulated to be involved in protein transport into chloroplasts. Immunolabelling results, however, indicated that these proteins were absent from the periplastidal vesicles.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967484b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k624x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diatoms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chloroplasts</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kr657"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Germanic verb order : the case for INFL-second</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Solin, Doreen (Doreen Frances)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Within the framework of Government-Binding Theory, this thesis argues that the Germanic languages, including German and related languages, should be analyzed as having INFL-second underlying work order. Contrary to traditional generative treatments of the so-called "verb-second" (V2) phenomenon, it is claimed here, in light of certain subtle asymmetries, that the final target site of the moved verb is INFL (I$ sp0)$ in sentences with pre-verbal subjects and COMP (C$ sp0)$ in those with pre-verbal non-subjects. It is further maintained that an analysis, as modified and extended in the thesis, in which verb movement is triggered by the Empty Category Principle (ECP) is superior, on both conceptual and empirical grounds, to other theories advanced by generativists to date. A wide variety of clause types in the modern Germanic languages, including in particular German V2 complements and Icelandic infinitival complements, are examined, the final chapter being devoted to a proposal concerning German "parentheticals".</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v208.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr657</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>German language -- Word order</dc:subject><dc:subject>German language -- Verb</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rj12f"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Un environnement pour l'acquisition des connaissances et le dev́eloppement de systemes experts constructifs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lamontagne, François R. (François René)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a development environment for Design Expert Systems that features a new language where the roles of knowledge and the way it is brought to bear are predefined by the solution method. The language also allows knowledge to be organized into classes of objects whose dynamic creation corresponds to the structure of the components to be configured. This approach, combined with a specialized control strategy for Design problems, helps in narrowing the representation gap between the expert's knowledge and the system's knowledge. The environment assists knowledge acquisition by means of a structured editor and by static and dynamic analyses for validation; it is implemented on a micro-computer and includes an internal Production System to execute the Expert Systems that are generated. Two applications to Engineering Design are used to demonstrate the environment's capabilities.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bv725.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj12f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Artificial Intelligence</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k370n"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between family structure and academic achievement among intellectually gifted students</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robin, Donna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examined whether a relationship exists between family structure (the presence of organization and rules in the household) and academic achievement among intellectually gifted students, and whether this relationship differs with respect to gender. Subjects for the study were 175 grade 8 students attending a school for the gifted and their parents (38 mothers and 33 fathers). The relationship between the responses of the subjects to the Organization and Control subscales of the Family Environment Scale and the students' grades from the previous school year was assessed using multiple regression analyses. To test for gender differences, an interaction term comprised of the variables of family structure and student gender was included in each equation. The analyses conducted did not produce any significant results. Possible explanations for the absence of significance and suggestions for future research are presented.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p154m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k370n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Home and school</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gifted children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Academic achievement</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237ht03h"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>New dynamical Monte Carlo renormalization group method</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lacasse, Martin Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The kinetics of a phase transition has been studied by using a new dynamical Monte Carlo renormalization group method. Using a majority rule block-spin transformation in both space and contiguous times, we numerically renormalized the evolving configurations during the phase separation of a kinetic Ising model with spin-flip dynamics. We find that, in the scaling regime, the average domain size R(t) grows in time consistently with the $R sim t sp{1/2}$ Allen-Cahn antiphase boundary motion theory, although some correcting factors may exist. The same procedure has also been applied to the corresponding equilibrium critical system in order to find the critical exponent z. Our method yields values that are consistent with the ones obtained from a finite-size scaling analysis applied on the same data, thus showing that, in principle, this method can be successfully used to determine z in a more precise and consistent way.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nj24g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht03h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322f38c"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characteristics of a laser desorption ion source</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghalambor Dezfuli, Abdol Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The characteristics of a pulsed laser ion source have been studied. A pulse from a heating laser (Nd: YAG laser) desorbs the neutral atoms from the surface of a metal target and then a second pulse or pulses from excimer or dye lasers selectively ionize the desorbed neutrals using the Resonance Ionization Spectroscopy technique. Time-of-flight and electrostatic energy analyzer measurements have been used to study different characteristics of this ion source such as spatial, velocity, and energy distributions. These measurements reveal that although the energy spread of the basic source is relatively high, (FWHM $ sim$ 37 eV) the use of a pulsed acceleration system can reduce this spread by a factor of 5 (to about 7 eV), making the source suitable for collinear laser spectroscopy.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j921j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322f38c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Optics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655h787"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A critique of the protestant secondary one religion programme for Quebec, based on a study of religious maturing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Destrempes-Stein, Michelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The evolution of the religious phenomenon can be organized into five overlapping historico-religious stages based on an analysis of concrete verifiable achievements. It delineates the religious and educational paradigms of each societal evolutionary stage as it considers that what applies to a society as a whole applies also to its education. Education plays an important role in the evolution of the world, and is directly affected by the changes of the image which human beings have of themselves. Religious maturing does not only take place in society but is also an integral part of any individual process of human development. The analysis of the various stages of personal religious development shows the inclusive nature of the religious development in any human educational enterprise. The study of the societal and individual process of religious maturing with the analysis of the contemporary tapestry of education and religious education stand as the various elements needed to formulate a critique of the current Quebec's secondary one Protestant moral and religious education curriculum. The significant role of teachers as active and necessary agents of pupils' maturing process emerges from the evaluation of the present curriculum.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v4113.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655h787</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Protestantism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Christian education -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion in the public schools -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225c187"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An analysis and evaluation of Ivan Illich's social and educational philosophy in the light of his early development and the major critiques of his theories</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cyr, George</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this thesis is to try to bring some clarity and perspective into the controversy generated by Ivan Illich's theory of the necessity for a deschooled society. Furthermore it attempts to elaborate on how Illich's concepts originated and evolved. In this respect, it strives to present all of the elements which have had an impact upon Illich's intellectual formation and his subsequent religious, social, and educational philosophy. The method of inquiry for my thesis is to investigate the various experiences, including definite influences, which contributed to shaping Illich's attitudes towards society, technology, and formal education. Since all of these factors eventually contributed to his famous theory of deschooling, this paper attempts to describe how Illich developed intellectually from his younger days until he conceptualized his notion of a free education in the Centre International de Documentation. In addition, this study analyzes the reactions of the major critics and commentators who either criticized or supported Illich's theories. The thesis concludes by presenting the reactions of the author to both Ivan Illich's theories and to the views of his major critics and commentators.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fs521.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c187</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Illich, Ivan, 1926- -- Views on education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397943w"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>NMR-based radiation dosimetry using polymer solutions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Audet, Chantal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The spin-spin and spin-lattice relaxation times of protons on polymers, T$ sb{ rm 1p}$ and T$ sb{ rm 2p}$, respectively, have been used to probe the absorbed dose of irradiated polymer solutions in which radiation-induced changes in polymer molecular weight, M$ sb{ rm n}$, occur. The M$ sb{ rm n}$ dependencies of T$ sb{ rm 1p}$ and T$ sb{ rm 2p}$, and of the water proton T$ sb{ rm 1w}$ for solutions of poly(ethylene oxide) (PEO) in D$ sb2$O and H$ sb2$O are presented. T$ sb{ rm 1p}$ and T$ sb{ rm 1w}$ are independent of M$ sb{ rm n},$ and T$ sb{ rm 2p}$ varies with M$ sb{ rm n}$ according to a specific inverse power dependence until low M$ sb{ rm n}$ when T$ sb2$ saturation occurs. The dose dependence of T$ sb{ rm 1p}$ and T$ sb{ rm 2p}$ measured for dilute solutions of PEO in D$ sb2$O reflects the dependence of M$ sb{ rm n}$ on dose. A novel semi-empirical model is proposed for the dose dependence of T$ sb{ rm 2p}$ which incorporates the measured M$ sb{ rm n}$ power dependence of T$ sb{ rm 2p}$ into a theoretical expression of the dose dependence of the M$ sb{ rm n}$. This expression is based on previous bulk polymer work and has been modified to hold for polymers in solution. The model can be fitted well to the T$ sb{ rm 2p}$ data measured for different doses, and the values of the fitting parameters agree with those expected from independent measurements. Practical aspects of the NMR/polymer dosimetry technique are also addressed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r221f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397943w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics, Medical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw6634487q"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The perceived use of competency-based instruction by physical education teachers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bukhala, Peter W. (Peter Wisiuba)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of the present study was to investigate the extent to which physical education teachers perceive that they use competency-based instruction and to assess some of the factors that influence them to use competency-based instructional strategies. It was also the intent of this study to design the Perceived CBI questionnaire specifically for this study. The results indicated that physical educators did not utilize many of the CBI strategies frequently or all the time. Most evident was the lack of involvement of parents and volunteers in the instructional planning of individualized programs. Also evident was the limited use of the initial assessment information gathered from students to plan instructional programs that would meet the individual student's needs. A significant relationship between the perceived use of CBI by teachers and the years teachers have taught students with disabilities was noted. No significant relationship was noted between teachers perceived use of CBI and (1) the number of years they have taught physical education, (2) the number of courses taken in adapted physical education and (3) the number of courses in special education. Significant differences were noted between the perceived use of CBI by teachers and the level of education, and the type of school setting.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db07m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634487q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical education and training</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competency-based education</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>