<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f175k"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Insulin-like growth factor-I, insulin-like growth factor binding protein-3 and the risk of cervical squamous intraepithelial lesions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schaffer, Andrea</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Insulin-like growth factors (IGFs) and their binding proteins  (IGFBPs) have been associated with an increased risk of several cancers. This  case-control study investigated the relationship between IGF-I and IGFBP-3 plasma  levels and the risk of squamous intraepithelial lesions (SILs) of the cervix, as  well as the risk of HPV infection in women. 366 cases and 366 controls were  recruited from five Montreal area hospitals. There was a significantly decreased  risk of LSIL for the highest quartile of IGFBP-3 relative to the lowest quartile  (Odds Ratio (OR)=0.25, 95% confidence interval (CI) 0.08-0.77), adjusted for age,  HPV status and IGF-I. Also, there was a significantly increased risk of being  positive for HPV, specifically high-risk types, for the highest quartiles of IGFBP-3  relative to the lowest quartile in controls (OR=4.53, 95% CI 1.33-15.40), adjusted  for age and IGF-I. IGF-I was not significantly associated with SILs or HPV  infection.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s5401.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f175k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vk63m"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of the isoform gamma 2 ([gamma] 2) of the serinethreonine protein kinase Casein Kinase I (CKI-[gamma] 2)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oliva, Rossella Norma</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Casein Kinase I (CKI) is one of the first serine/threonine  protein kinase activities to be isolated and characterized. In vertebrates, CKI  represent a multigene family with seven isoforms, alpha, beta, delta, ε,  gamma1-3 for which, very little is known with respect to their biological functions.  This study reports that stable overexpression of CKI-gamma2 into fibroblasts impairs  cell morphology and the organization of the actin cytoskeleton in a kinase-dependent  mechanism and cell proliferation through a kinase-independent mechanism. In  addition, by immunofluorescence we determined the subcellular distribution of  CKI-gamma2 to perinuclear vesicles. Furthermore, we established that a putative  prenylation motif present in the C-terminal extension of CKI-gamma2 determines its  proper subcellular localization.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq28h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk63m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117p46b"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>ApTrkl, a Trk-like receptor, mediates serotonin-dependent ERK activation and long-term facilitation in Aplysia sensory neurons</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ormond, John, 1978-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Trk family of receptor tyrosine kinases is involved in  synaptic plasticity and behavioral memory in mammals. Here, we report the discovery  of a Trk-like receptor, termed ApTrkl, in Aplysia. We show that it is expressed in  the sensory neurons, the locus for synaptic facilitation, a cellular model for  memory formation. Serotonin, the facilitatory neurotransmitter, activates ApTrkl.  Activation of ApTrkl leads to activation of ERK. Finally, inhibiting activation of  ApTrkl with the Trk inhibitor K252a blocks serotonin-mediated activation of ERK, and  a form of cell-wide long-term facilitation. Thus, transactivation of the receptor  tyrosine kinase ApTrkl by serotonin is an essential step in the biochemical events  leading to long-term facilitation in Aplysia .</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm57b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p46b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623hz29n"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behavioural and electrophysiological explorations of context maintenance and contextual integration dysfunctions in schizophrenia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kumar, Namita</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A meaningful item, such as a word, object or face, that is  unexpected in a given context, elicits the N400, an event-related potential (ERP)  thought to index the amount of effort applied to integrate the item in its context.  This N400 has repeatedly been found to be abnormal in schizophrenia (Sz) patients.  Meanwhile, these patients are also deficient at maintaining context in mind, which,  like the inability to integrate an item, can cause a comprehension deficit. The  maintenance of context can be assessed by measuring another component of ERPs, the  contingent negative variation (CNV). The CNV is evoked by a context stimulus that is  presented just before a target stimulus. As yet, the N400 and the CNV have not been  studied together in order to assess the respective roles of contextual integration  and context maintenance in semantic performance. To this end, Sz subjects and normal  controls were asked to perform semantic categorizations for word, face, and object  targets in an experiment in which each categorization was specified by a context  instruction stimulus presented just before each target stimulus. The extent to which context maintenance and contextual  integration impairments could be related to the thought-disorders (TD) of Sz  patients was assessed. Therefore, high (n=15) and low (n=15) TD patients were  compared to high (n=15) and low (n=15) TD normal controls. It is proposed that the  excess of information extracted from instructions and targets, as indicated by  larger than normal P600s to both types of stimuli in high TD patients, may actually  be the root cause underlying thought disorder.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537182g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623hz29n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pg801"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nodal statistics of Heine-Stieltjes and Van Vleck polynomials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kritchevski, Evgenij</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We study the polynomial solutions of the Lame differential  equation Azy'' z+2Bz y'z+C zyz=0 where A(z), B( z), C(z) ∈ C [z] are  polynomials of degree N + 1, N and N - 1 respectively. We review classical results  concerning the location of the zeros of y(z) and C(z) and their electrostatic  interpretation. Asymptotic distribution of the zeros as the degree K of y(z)  approaches infinity is then discussed. We also derive numerical methods that allow  us to compute solutions of high degree K and present a variety of new fine  experimental results such as the asymptotic nearest neighbor spacing distribution  and the description of complex configurations.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq29s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pg801</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh43g"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of candidate genes in purified protein derivative (PPD) responsiveness in pediatric tuberculosis patients</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eguale, Tewodros</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Tuberculin skin testing is an important tool for  diagnosis and control of tuberculosis. The role of host genetics in responsiveness  of pediatric tuberculosis patients to purified protein derivatives (PPD) has rarely  been investigated. Objective. To determine the impact of the candidate genes -  Natural Resistance Associated Macrophage Protein 1 (NRAMP1), Vitamin D Receptor  (VDR) and Interleukin 4 Receptor (IL4R) with other covariates on PPD reaction size  in pediatric tuberculosis patients. Methods. A family-based association study was conducted using  eighty-three parent-child trios from a database of tuberculosis patients and their  families from Texas, USA. Results. Marker IL4Rrs1805010_GA was in linkage disequilibrium  with PPD size (R2 = 16%; p = 0.0017). PPD size was a predictor of transmission of  allele 1 ("G") of IL4Rrs1805010_GA with an OR (95% CI) of 1.9 (1.16, 3.14)  per five millimeter average increase in PPD size adjusted for age of  diagnosis. Conclusions. This thesis provides evidence for the role of host  genetics in PPD responsiveness in pediatric tuberculosis patients.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc82t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh43g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x4562"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of Mycobacterium bovis-BCG infection on longevity and autoimmune disease in MRL//pr mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eadie, Kalyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a debilitating autoimmune  disease affecting 1/1000 Canadians, primarily women of childbearing age.  Mycobacterium bovis-BCG, the tuberculosis vaccine, is a potent immunomodulator and  has been used to treat other autoimmune diseases. To study the impact of M.  bovis-BCG on disease progression in the MRL/ lpr mouse model of lupus, groups of  MRL/lpr and background control MRL/+ mice were infected with BCG at 16-18 weeks of  age, and their longevity, kidney function and serologic characteristics examined.  MRL/lpr mice infected with BCG showed a slight improvement in longevity, and were  protected from kidney failure. This was accompanied by a delay in the  class-switching from IgM to pathogenic IgG anti-double-stranded DNA autoantibodies,  and a delay in epitope spreading among autoantibodies to spliceosomal proteins. BCG  infection of lupus mice thus provided transient protection from autoimmune disease,  possibly through effects on cytokine production.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mm84g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x4562</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g567r"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Humus as an indicator of nutrient availability in a carefully logged boreal black spruce-feathermoss forest in northwestern Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bailey, Stephanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Black spruce (Picea mariana (Mill.) B.S.P.)-feathermoss forests  are a common subtype of the northern boreal forests. These forests are associated  with large accumulations of mor humus, which is regarded as an important source of  nutrients, contributor to soil structure, moisture retention and vital to the  long-term sustainability of these forests. Harvesting with protection of advance  regeneration (CPRS) is currently used in northwestern Quebec as the method for  sustainable management, which reduces soil compaction and protects advance  regeneration, and genetic diversity. We examined the effects of CPRS on organic  matter and advance regeneration 6 years after harvesting. During the summer of 2002,  a humus classification based on observable field characteristics was developed and  applied to six CPRS sites in the northern Abitibi claybelt region of Quebec. At each  site 75 humus profiles were surveyed and classified by order and thickness of  horizons present. Humus horizons were easily observed using morphological features,  and master horizon classes were distinguished by their nutritional and biochemical  attributes with differences occurring as a result of the natural process of  decomposition. Individual humus horizon and total profile thickness was the variable  that most affected profile nutrient mass. High forest floor disturbance was  associated with shallow profile depth, resulting in low humus profile nutrient mass  and low density advance regeneration. Lower forest floor disturbance resulted in  deeper profiles associated with higher available nutrients in humus profiles and  higher density of advance regeneration. These results suggest that disturbance  caused by harvesting may reduce overall stand productivity in the short term due to  the effect of low tree density and possibly in the long-term due to loss of  nutrients.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p775s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g567r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Taigas -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Forest soils -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Humus -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n397z"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimization of biocatalysis of chlorophyllase in neat organic solvent media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Arriagada Strodthoff, Paula</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The biocatalysis of a crude chlorophyllase extract, obtained  from the biomass culture of Phaeodactylum tricornutum, in neat organic solvent media  was investigated. The addition of selected excipients, including crown ether  (enzyme:crown ether, 135:1--2.7:1, w/w), dextran (enzyme:dextran, 1:2--1:0.25, w/w),  Span 40 and Span 60 (enzyme:Span, 1:2, w/w) and sodium bis (2-ethylhexyl)  sulfosuccinate (enzyme:AOT, 1:12.6, w/w), to the crude solid enzyme preparation  decreased the chlorophyllase activity. The effects of selected parameters, including  solvent hydrophobicity (Log P, 2.40--4.45), initial water activity (aw, 0.44--0.97),  agitation speed (0--200 rpm), reaction temperature (25--45°C) and enzyme  concentration (1.67--5.3 mg solid enzyme/mL) on chlorophyllase activity, were  investigated using a crude solid enzyme. The experimental findings showed that the  highest chlorophyllase specific activity of 362.4 nmol hydrolyzed chlorophyll/g  solid enzyme/min and bioconversion yield of 90.7% were obtained with the  hexane/octanone mixture (98.7:1.3, v/v), aw of 0.90, agitation speed of 200 rpm,  reaction temperature of 35°C and enzyme concentration of 3.33 mg solid  enzyme/mL.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b4088.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n397z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hydrolases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant enzymes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chlorophyll</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organic solvents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glycoproteins</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322d962"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The implications of the Copenhagen political criteria on the language rights of the Kurds in Turkey</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Soykan, Taskin Tankut</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In recent years, the attention is being increasingly drawn to  the role of the European Union on the development of minority rights in the  candidate countries. The adoption of the Copenhagen political criteria, which also  require "respect for and protection of minorities," as preconditions that  applicants must have met before they could join the Union has inevitably led to some  policy changes to the minorities in Eastern Europe. This policy shift is  particularly directed at minority language rights, because one of the most important  aspects of the protection of minorities is the recognition of their linguistic  identity. The aim of this study is to explore to what extent this development has  influenced the situation of language rights of the Kurds in Turkey. In order to  answer this question, it first examines the relationship between the Copenhagen  criteria and international and European standards protecting minority language  rights. Secondly, considering those standards, it assesses the achievements and  failures of the recent legislative amendments which are directed to bring the  language rights of the Kurds within the line of the Copenhagen criteria. The case of  Turkey reveals the vast potential of the European enlargement process on the  development of minority language rights, but also its limits in situations where  there is a lack of political will to respect and protect diversity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leuprecht, Peter</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x10v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d962</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Linguistic minorities -- Civil rights -- Turkey</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kurds -- Civil rights -- Turkey</dc:subject><dc:subject>Linguistic minorities -- Civil rights -- Europe</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415p995f"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The WTO and the mandatory labeling of generically modified foods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shirai, Tomoko</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The manipulation of nature using modern biotechnology has  resulted in the creation of Genetically Modified (GM) foods. There are states  already enacting laws requiring the mandatory labeling of GM foods so that consumers  can make informed choices as to what food to eat. However, on the flip side, the  mandatory labeling of GM foods can also constitute non-tariff barriers as it can  impose burdens on states that export GM foods. How should these two interests be  balanced? This thesis takes the ambitious challenge of exploring whether the  mandatory labeling of GM foods enacted under the government's protection of the  consumers' right to information regarding what food to consume is consistent with  the World Trade Organization (WTO) framework, particularly the Agreement on  Technical Barriers to Trade (MT Agreement). This thesis holds the view that the WTO,  an international organization established to promote trade liberalization, can  incorporate protection of consumers' interests by including it within to the  interpretation of "legitimate objective" contained in Article 2.2 of the  TBT Agreement. Rather, the heart of problem lies in the threshold setting of  exempting mandatory labeling. In particular, the dispersed threshold should be  adjusted hi order to solve this issue, this thesis contends that both the TBT  Committee and the dispute settlement system should be utilized.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>de Mestral, Armand</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s78m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415p995f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Genetically modified foods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Food -- Labeling -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>World Trade Organization</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k319p"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The concept of intergenerational equity in international law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farchakh, Loubna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The theory of intergenerational equity is closely linked to the  notion of sustainable development. It is indeed considered to be one of its aspect.  Intergenerational equity can be divided in two facets: the intergenerational  component links the present generation to future generations, while the  intragenerational aspect imposes, within the same generation, a duty for  industrialized countries to help developing countries. The legal status of  intergenerational equity appears to be limited because of its qualification as a  concept. Therefore, this concept of intergenerational equity belongs to the realm of  soft law. Nevertheless, legal implications can be drawn out from this theory.  Different means of implementation can be envisioned, some belonging to the domain of  soft law, other employing more classical tools, such as institutional  mechanisms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ellis, Jaye</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Blackett, Adelle</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c104d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k319p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental ethics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environmental law, International</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sustainable development -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conservation of natural resources -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bf55f"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Liability for copyright infringements committed by others</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fang, Cheng-Ru, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on third-party liability in the field of  copyright law in common law countries, that is, liability for the copyright  infringement committed by others. By revisiting basic philosophies for copyright  protection and case studies of three basic doctrines, authorization, vicarious  liability, and contributory infringement, employed by courts to deal with  third-party liability in the common law system, the author tries to extract  applicable legal doctrines to treat third-party cases under a variety of  circumstances. These doctrines could serve as a vigorous base with which to face  future challenges, especially those resulting from ever-changing technological  landscape, involving third-party liability in the field of  copyright.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lametti, David</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st13v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bf55f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Liability (Law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copyright</dc:subject><dc:subject>Third parties (Law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732d954s"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Type synthesis and kinematic analysis of translational parallel manipulators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wei, Wei, 1982-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis treats type synthesis and kinematic analysis of  translational parallel manipulators (TPMs) from a group theoretical point of  view. For the TPM type synthesis, based on displacement group theory  (DGT), TPM leg motion is represented by a series of displacement subgroups. For  symmetrical three-legged TPMs, three categories are classified and a total of 90  architectures are proposed. For asymmetrical three-legged TPMs, 13 cases of possible  leg combinations are presented and some possible constructions of TPMs are shown.  The advantages of DGT in mechanism synthesis are described. For the kinematic analysis of symmetrical TPMs, geometric  elements are employed to denote the workspace of different leg links. Solutions of  the inverse and direct kinematics of a certain example are obtained. Moreover, the  proposed approach is applied to a class of TPMs, and the corresponding geometric  representations are listed. The applicability of the proposed approach is discussed  as well. This thesis provides a theoretical approach to design TPMs and  analyze their kinematics for practical applications.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nh62p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d954s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bf481"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A parameterized, sensitivity-driven EM design environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weicker, Phillip J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with the application of sensitivity analysis  to a variational geometry environment for the optimization of the design of  electromagnetic devices. Through a graphical user interface, an electromagnetic  device is sketched in a free-hand manner. The device topology is stored in a  parameteric fashion. The sketch provides the topology (geometric entities and their  interconnection) and defines the device, where changing the parameters provides all  the possible devices under consideration. The performance of the device is computed  using a commerical finite-element package. The effect of changing the system  parameters on the device performance is investigated and used to modify the device  to change the performance in the desired way. Significant gains in optimization  performance are realized through the use of deterministic optimization  techniques.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290b01g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bf481</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bv148"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Strain-induced precipitation in ferrite during isothermal aging of Nb microalloyed steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wei, Qingfeng, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In niobium (Nb) microalloyed steels one of the strengthening  mechanisms is precipitation of Nb(C, N). Precipitation in austenite has been studied  and applied for many decades, but its precipitation in ferrite has been paid less  attention. Some of the findings are somewhat contradictory. Due to environmental and resource saving consideration in recent  years, more and more scrap has been recycled and re-used. Thus, tramp elements  inevitably exist in steel such as Cu, Sn, Ni and so on. These elements may influence  properties of steels at some extent although they are very little in  content. The X80 steel examined in this thesis contains up to 0.09%wt.  Nb, as well as 0.4% Cu, both of which can potentially precipitate in ferrite.  However, most research has shown that Cu levels below 0.5% in steel do not  precipitate out under normal processing conditions. In the present work, this X80 steel was processed by a variety  of thermomechanical treatments. The as hot deformed mechanical properties were  tested and microstructures were characterized by field emission gun scanning  electron microscopy (FEG-SEM). At low aging temperatures, simulating the coiling  stage in steel hot rolling, many fine Cu precipitates were observed in ferrite  compared to a few relatively large Nb containing precipitates. These results were  rationalized, and the consequences were discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fm03m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bv148</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kq979"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nonlinear viscoelasticity and wall slip of molten polymers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xu, Junke, 1976-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two nearly monodisperse polybutadienes (PBd) having different  molecular weights were used to study nonlinear viscoelastic behavior using a sliding  plate rheometer incorporating shear and normal stress transducers. Comparison of data for the shear stress growth function at the  start-up of steady simple shear with predictions of the Wagner model was used to  estimate the time-dependency of wall slip. Both the time-dependent slip velocity and  the steady-state values were found to depend on molecular weight, thus supporting  the hypothesis that "slip" actually involves a shear-induced  disentanglement between molecules strongly adsorbed at the wall and those in the  bulk. The critical shear stress for the onset of slip was about 230kPa for both  PBds, suggesting that the critical stress is independent of molecular weight and  related to the plateau modulus. Slip behavior on steel and glass substrates was  quite similar. Rubber-like high-molecular-weight polybutadiene exhibited  well-defined, steady, normal stresses at moderate shear rates, while molten  polystyrene exhibited a steady normal stress up to much higher shear  rates. Step strain data were used to determine the time and strain  dependency of the nonlinear relaxation modulus. Time-strain factorability was  observed, and the damping function was determined. For the moderately entangled PBd2  the experimentally determined damping function agreed with the predictions of the  Doi-Edwards constitutive model and thus the Lodge-Meissner relationship. The higher  molecular weight PBd3 exhibited strong wall slip.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb399.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kq979</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p0887"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamically adding redundancy for improved error concealment in packet voice coding</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tosun, Levent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Data is sent in packets of bits over the Internet. However,  packets may not arrive in order or in time for playout. Packet loss is a frequently  encountered problem in Voice-over-IP (VoIP) applications. Modern speech coders use  past information to decode current packets in order to reach very low bit-rates.  Therefore, when a packet is lost, the effect of this packet loss propagates over  several subsequent packets. In this thesis, a new redundancy-based packet-loss-concealment  scheme is presented. Many redundancy-based packet-loss-concealment schemes send a  fixed amount of extra information about the current packet as part of the subsequent  packet, but not every packet is equally important for packet loss concealment. We  have developed an algorithm to determine the importance of packets and we propose  that extra information should only be sent for the important packets. This provides  a lower average bit-rate compared to sending the same amount of extra information  for each and every packet. We use a linear prediction (LP) based speech coder (ITU-T  G.723.1) as a test platform and we propose that only the excitation parameters  should be sent as extra information since LP parameters of a frame can be estimated  using the LP parameters of the previous frame. Furthermore, we propose that  excitation parameters of an important frame that are sent as redundant information  should be used in the reconstruction of the lost waveform---as a consequence, the  states of the subsequent frame will also be updated.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hv86w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p0887</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603qz049"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>3-D automatic mesh adaptation for turbulent flows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Suerich-Gulick, Irmgard Frances</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Computational fluid dynamics is increasingly used as an analysis  and simulation tool in research and industry. Mesh generation remains a major  challenge, in particular for turbulent flow simulations, as it can be very difficult  and time-consuming to produce a good mesh that will produce accurate results. Mesh  adaptation schemes have been developed to help improve the solutions obtained and  facilitate the mesh generation process. This work expands the Y+ correction scheme within an existing  3-D anisotropic mesh adaptation module for turbulent flow simulations developed at  the McGill CFD Lab. First, the Y+ correction scheme is improved for structured  layers of elements when the turbulence model uses wall functions. Second, Y+  correction is expanded to handle unstructured meshes that are more appropriate for  complex geometries. Test cases are performed to evaluate the impact of the new Y+  correction on the accuracy of the flow solutions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547r944.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qz049</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zb63r"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pre-osteoblast response to three-dimensional titanium scaffolds for bone regeneration applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>St-Pierre, Jean-Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Porous metals are often used in orthopaedic load-bearing  applications because they promote and direct bone ingrowth while maintaining their  mechanical integrity for long periods in physiological environments. However, the  influence of microstructural parameters of three-dimensional metallic scaffolds on  osteogenic cell response must be studied to improve their design. This study aims to  study the biocompatibility and osteoconductivity of novel titanium foams with three  pore sizes in vitro and to gain knowledge on the mechanisms by which bone is formed  within three-dimensional structures. This is achieved through studies of the cell  viability of macrophages and adhesion kinetics, proliferation, differentiation, and  mineralization of the extracellular matrix by MCT3-E1 mouse pre-osteoblasts. Results  indicate that porous titanium promotes the generation of mineralized extracellular  matrix by differentiating pre-osteoblasts and stress the importance of controlling  the pore size to allow the impregnation of the structure by tissue.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm89m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb63r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b659x"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Construction of a detailed deterministic user-equilibrium traffic assignment model for the Greater Montreal area using Geographic Information Systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Spurr, Timothy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation describes the process of building a detailed  traffic assignment model for the Greater Montreal region using Geographic  Information Systems (GIS). Although deterministic user-equilibrium traffic models  are widely used in planning practice, most contemporary research into transportation  models attempts to deal with the numerous theoretical shortcomings of the static  modeling framework through dynamic methods while the potential for improvements on  conventional algorithms remains largely unexplored. GIS offer a powerful mechanism  for achieving such improvements. This research demonstrates how GIS can be  profitably applied in the construction of a traffic assignment model with a very  fine spatial resolution. The time savings incurred through the application of GIS  permit the construction of a very detailed metropolitan street network comprising  approximately 245,000 directional links and a corresponding system of 981 traffic  analysis zones.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67314509.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b659x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zx04w"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design of a multi-projector display system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sud, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a new multi-projector front-projection  display system that can be used for an immersive environment. The implementation of  such a system faces new challenges that were avoided by design in CAVE-like systems.  These include removing the perspective warping from misaligned projectors and  adjusting the intensity to create a uniformly lit display in regions where  projectors overlap. Also, when the display is in use, occluding objects between the  projector and the display surface cause shadows on the display that must be removed.  These three issues have been addressed in this work based in part on algorithms from  the field of computational geometry and on techniques from existing projector  systems.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d0274.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx04w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sw42f"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The treatment of Li-ion battery waste in a transferred arc plasma reactor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Silla, Vittorio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the new millennium, over 500 million rechargeable battery  operated and miniaturized pieces of electronic equipment will be in circulation. A  battery market survey showed that the average annual growth rate of Li-ion batteries  will increase by 118%. The millions of spent Li-ion batteries will cause an  environmental waste management problem. The cathode metals, which have a high market  value (54 US$/kg cobalt) will leach into the earth when land filled. A transferred arc process was proposed in which the Li-ion  battery waste would be separated into volatile, slag and metal phases using argon as  the plasma gas. A thermodynamic simulation of the process was performed using the  FACT-Sage software. The process was simulated at 1 atm and between 1000 and  2000ºC in both inert and oxidizing operating conditions, assuming the  formation of ideal metal, metal oxide and gas solutions. It was found that at  1800ºC and with the addition of 1.1 moles of oxygen, 84% of the metal phase  would be Co with only 10% Cu, 4% Fe and 2% Ni. To validate the thermodynamic predictions, experiments on spent  Li-ion batteries were performed in a laboratory scale transferred arc batch reactor.  Operating at the maximum power and with 4 times the oxygen suggested by the  simulation, the consolidated metal phase was composed of 50% Fe, 28% Co, 12% C and  7% Cu and 3% Ni. Over 60 of the Co was lost to either the metal oxide or vapor  phases. To better approximate the actual semi-continuous industrial process,  experiments were also conducted with the addition of a 10 g Co heel. Operating at  the maximum power and at 6 times the suggested oxygen input, the recovery of Co was  improved to 60%. The results obtained for both operating conditions differ  considerably from thermodynamic predictions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085k66k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sw42f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x194d"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of a non-stationary Markov random field in brain tissue partial volume segmentation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Singh, Vivek</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes a novel approach to partial volume  segmentation of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) in sulci of 3D magnetic resonance (MR)  brain images that overcomes a key limitation of other techniques. The method is  based upon previous work in that it uses a Markov random field (MRF) to encourage  adjacent voxels to have the same tissue label in most brain regions, but differs in  that it adaptively reverses its behaviour to preserve tissue boundaries in sulci.  Image curvature and medial surface information, both independent of MR pulse  sequence, are used to identify regions where sulci have a high probability of  occurring, in order to modulate MRF behaviour. The method is evaluated using both  real and simulated data, showing a significant improvement in terms of sensitivity  to voxels containing CSF. It is also shown qualitatively to be useful in improving a  deformable model based cortical surface extraction procedure.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w2810.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x194d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322d90d"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of confinement on the response of ductile shear walls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Xiang Yuan, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An experimental study was conducted to investigate the effect of  confinement on the response of ductile shear walls subjected to reversed cyclic  loading. Two shear walls, with identical dimensions, were designed in accordance  with the Canadian Standard Association A23.3-04, except that a greater amount of  confinement was provided in boundary elements. One specimen used normal-strength  concrete, and the other used high-strength concrete. A number of confinement  analytical models were selected to predict the behaviour of each specimen. The test  data of two moderately confined shear walls (Liu 2004) was used to compare the  responses of ductile shear walls at different levels of confinement. These  predictions and comparisons with the test results are presented and discussed in  terms of load-carrying capacities, ductility, moment-curvature responses and energy  dissipation. The test results indicate that the increased confinement of the  boundary elements significantly enhanced the displacement ductility without  appreciable change in load-carrying capacity. In addition, the beneficial effects of  increased confinement were more pronounced in the normal-strength concrete shear  walls than in the high-strength concrete shear walls.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j77g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d90d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>