<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qc65d"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>First-principles study of charge transport in molecular wires and field effect devices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaun, Chao-Cheng 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this work, we present theoretical analysis of charge  transport at the molecular scale. We use a state-of-the-art theoretical tool to  investigate a number of key issues of molecular electronics, paying particular  attention to quantitative comparison with experimental data which have been  confirmed by different labs. Our analysis allows us not only to understand the data,  but also to make quantitative predictions. We have calculated the length dependence of resistance for  molecular wires, including oligophenylene thiol and alkanethiol molecules. Our  results are in excellent agreement with the corresponding measured data. Our  analysis provides a good understanding of charge conduction mechanism in these  molecular wires. This is the first time in molecular conduction research that a  parameter-free modeling agrees so well with real data. We have also studied the  conformational dependence of current of a biphenyldithiol molecule in terms of the  dihedral angle variations. The charge current can be tuned by this parameter, and  the ratio of tuning can be as large as several hundred fold. A physical picture  emerges from our analysis. We have investigated the momentum filtering effect due to  molecule orbitals. This study allows us to understand why some incoming Bloch states  can conduct through the molecule, while others cannot. By adding different  end-groups to the molecule, we found that conduction channels can be varied. We have  also studied the gate potential control of electric current. The gate voltage shifts  the resonance state of the molecule thereby inducing a current modulation. We found  that the gating efficiency strongly depends on the geometry of the gate electrode.  The current through a biphenyl dimethanethiol molecule is found to be switchable by  applying gate voltages, and the on/off current ratio can be  substantial. Finally, using carbon nanotubes with substitutional nitrogen, we  clearly demonstrate that conventional equilibrium conductance analysis was not  enough to describe the whole transport features in molecular devices. A nitrogen  doped zigzag nanotube showed that even a single atom substitution has increased the  current flow and, for small radii tubes, narrowed the current gap. Periodical  substitution makes zigzag semiconducting tubes metallic, a prediction which has been  confirmed by a subsequent experiment. For an armchair metallic nanotube, doping with  a single impurity reduces current. The physics of these behaviours has been  addressed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guo, Hong</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pg72b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qc65d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zx012"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessing the bioavailability of organic pollutants in surfactant solutions using a novel bioluminescent biosensor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keane, Angela, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bioavailability is often considered to be the rate limiting  process in the bioremediation of sites contaminated with hydrophobic organic  compounds (HOCs). In order to meet the need for a direct measurement technique for  microbial bioavailability, the whole-cell bioluminescent biosensor PpF1G4 was  developed. To create PpF1G4, bioluminescent reporter genes (lux) were placed under  the control of the promoter region of the solvent efflux pump genes (sep) in  Pseudomonas putida F1. In screening experiments, it was determined that biosensor  PpF1G4 produced a bioluminescent response to a wide range of aromatic  compounds. PpF1G4 was used to evaluate how three nonionic surfactants  (Triton X-100, Brij 30 and Brij 35) influence the bioavailability of three different  HOCs (toluene, naphthalene, and phenanthrene). Nonionic surfactants were used  because they are in general less toxic to bacteria. The increased bioluminescent  response of PpF1G4 in micellar solutions of Triton X-100 and Brij 35 indicated  higher intra-cellular concentrations of the test compounds, toluene, naphthalene and  phenanthrene, compared to control systems with no surfactants present. In contrast,  Brij 30 caused a decrease in the bioluminescent response to the test compounds. The  effect of the micellar solutions on the toluene biodegradation rate was consistent  with the bioluminescent response. Thus, the bioluminescent response of PpF1G4 was an  accurate indicator of bioavailability. The results suggest that nonionic surfactants  enhance biodegradation in two ways: (1) by augmenting membrane permeability through  binding of surfactant monomers; and (2) by increasing the mass flux of substrates  present in the micellar pseudophase to the cells. PpF1G4 was also employed to evaluate the bioavailability of HOCs  partitioned from multicomponent NAPLs (gasoline, crude oil, and creosote) into  surfactant solutions. All three surfactants tested increased the bioavailability of  HOCs partitioned from creosote and crude oil. None of the surfactants significantly  enhanced the response to gasoline-equilibrated solutions. The suppression of  bioluminescence in Brij 30 solutions containing single test compounds did not occur  in Brij 30 solutions containing multiple HOCs. This research sheds some light on how  certain nonionic surfactants may increase the bioavailability of HOCs and thus  enhance bioremediation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ghoshal, Subhasis</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773w20j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx012</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Environmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff3655681"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bridging the digital divide : beyond the basic telecommunications agreement towards a global universal service and access regime</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guermazi, Boutheina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A tremendous disparity exists between the few countries with  expansive access to information and communications technologies, and the many others  still lacking the basic infrastructure and unable to participate in the information  age. While the current trade regime under the Basic  Telecommunications Agreement, which forms part of the General Agreement on Trade in  Services, offers many opportunities for developing countries, its potential for  bridging the digital divide through increased flows of FDI is likely to benefit only  those countries with large, lucrative markets. Global market failures would result  in deepening the digital divide facing the poorest of the developing countries.  Unable to come under the new liberalization paradigm, these countries are likely to  be left even further behind. A legal approach to bridging the digital divide requires going  beyond the current trade regime and engaging in a new regime-building exercise.  Drawing upon the domestic universal service concept, this thesis calls for a global  universal service and access (GUSA) regime. Such a regime entails a new form of  international cooperation that harnesses all available resources and includes the  recasting of international accounting rates and a revitalization of official  development assistance. It also involves institutional reform and reconfiguration  through the creation of a new international financial institution, a Global  Universal Service Fund (GUSF) as well as the strengthening of the role of the ITU as  the custodian of the GUSA regime. The GUSF would be an independently managed, politically balanced  and internationally accountable institution. Because of its flexibility and its  mandate to supplement market mechanisms and respond to global market failures, the  fund would go a long way towards subsidizing network build out programs in the  poorest developing countries, and ensuring widespread connectivity. The proposal is  legally defensible under human rights law as well as trade and telecommunications  laws, is economically justified under the global public goods doctrine, and  technologically feasible given current capacity to connect the world and create the  global village.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, Richard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx02b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3655681</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Telecommunication -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Telecommunication -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Digital divide</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795822r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic information and insurance : a contextual analysis of legal and regulatory means of promoting just distributions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lemmens, Trudo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyzes the rationale, appropriateness and value of  the available legal and regulatory means to deal with genetic discrimination in the  context of insurance. Insurance is used as a paradigm case for discussing the legal  means to address the concerns related to the impact of new medical technologies. A  new framework is proposed for evaluating the potential impact of such new  technologies on people's ability to participate fully in social life and to have  access to important social goods without unfair discrimination based on certain  inherited traits. A "thick" contextual method is used, which involves a  detailed description of the medical, social, and legal context of the debate. The  approach is based on Michael Walzer's theory of justice, which posits that in  assessing the fairness of the distribution of a particular good, one must take into  account the nature of the good as determined by the specific socio-historical  context in which it obtains its shared meaning. Walzer's theory is used in the  thesis to critically analyze the regulatory and legislative means introduced in  several countries to curb genetic discrimination. It is further argued that Walzer's  contextual analysis resembles the approach taken by the Canadian Supreme Court in  the context of anti-discrimination law. Canadian human rights law is analyzed in  detail to describe how genetic discrimination could be dealt with under the current  provisions and how human rights law can be used to create conditions of substantive  equality. The thesis concludes with an analysis of various legal and regulatory  options to deal with genetic discrimination and its impact on human rights in the  Canadian context. The establishment of a regulatory body is proposed, with the  mandate to review the appropriateness of the use of new tests in the context of  insurance. I argue that this review process, and the contextual analysis that should  be involved in this process, would constitute a useful step towards creating  conditions for substantive equality, not only for those who are genetically  disabled, but for all those who are affected by real or perceived disabling  conditions and stigmatizing traits.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Knoppers, B. M.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Glenn, H. P.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634421m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795822r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Insurance law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human chromosome abnormalities -- Diagnosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Privacy, Right of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dm847"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language/><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Weight for orchestra</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Godin, Scott, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation consists of two parts. Part One is a written  text which defines compositional processes and provides an analysis of the musical  material incorporated in weight, my composition for orchestra. Part Two of the  dissertation comprises the musical score for weight. weight is a nineteen-minute composition for symphonic orchestra  [2222, 4231, piano, percussion (2 players), timpani, strings (16,14,10,10,8)] which  attempts to exploit the various allusions conjured up by the title. The term  "weight" implies lightness or heaviness which can be applied to various  musical elements (e.g., where a chord is "heavier" than the previous, a  rhythm is becoming "lighter," etc.). weight is an attempt to remove the  subjectivity surrounding the use of this type of terminology by measuring and  developing certain musical elements in a logical and elegant manner. Following an introductory chapter, the written text focuses on  three main components. Chapter Two deals with the harmonic component of weight,  first, describing how the harmonic language for the composition has been  constructed, followed by a detailed explanation of how the harmonies are given  numerical "weights," and subsequently how they are manipulated in the  composition. Chapter Three defines and numerically calculates subsidiary elements  such as rhythm, orchestration, and a formal element identified as temporal splicing.  Chapter Four reveals the overall form of weight , and illustrates through a series  of sectional analyses how each subsidiary element interacts with one another in each  formal region. The fifth chapter concludes the written text, summarizing the paper  and considers future uses of the compositional and analytical methods introduced in  this paper.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rea, John</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j70j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dm847</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Orchestral music -- Scores</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj38607499"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dijets and photon remnant studies in photoproduction with the ZEUS detector at HERA</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhou, Changyi, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>At the HERA particle accelerator, 27.5 GeV electrons collide  with 920 GeV protons. In the photoproduction mode, the quasi-real exchange photon  emitted by the electron interacts with the proton at small momentum transfer. Such  events are selected and investigated with the ZEUS detector in the photon proton  center-of-mass range 130 GeV &lt; Wgamma p &lt; 270 GeV using the 55.1 pb-1  gated luminosity of the year 2000 data. The two typical photoproduction processes  are studied separately: in the direct case photons can interact directly with the  proton, while in the resolved case the photon is resolved into its hadronic  components. An inclusive data sample of two parton jet events with each a minimum  transverse energy of 6 GeV and a third jet with a minimum transverse energy of 2 GeV  are reconstructed and selected using the inclusive kT clustering algorithm. The  third jet travelling in the electron propagation direction can be assumed to be the  photon remnant jet. Jet transverse energy density distributions, which are also  known as 'jet shapes' are calculated on the jet sample. The photon remnant jets are  found to be broader than the parton jets.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv67f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38607499</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct409"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Legal basis for a national space legislation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hermida, Julian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to propose the fundamental  regulatory policy basis for a future domestic legislation governing private space  activities in those States where their industry has or aspires to have a  preponderant role in the pursuit of space activities and which have not yet crafted  their national space regulatory framework. This study is based on the premises that  the international legal framework governing space activities provides the  fundamental basis for national space legislations and that the legislative  experience of the countries which have adopted a domestic space legal scenario  presents a useful model for delineating the principal basis of national legislation  for those countries without specific national regulatory framework. The proposal is  analyzed in light of Law Reform and participatory theory, conceived as a multifold  dynamic process, requiring a national effort based on high level of State and  private sector participation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jakhu, Ram S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bc06b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct409</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sg790"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of bit allocation for Gaussian mixture model quantizers and image coders</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tran, Denis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes different bit allocation schemes and their  performances when applied on coding line spectral frequencies (LSF) using the  GMM-based coder designed by Subramaniam and a simple image transform coder. The new  algorithms are compared to the original bit allocation formula; the Pruning  algorithm used by Subramaniam, Segall's method and the Greedy bit allocation  algorithm using the Log Spectral Distortion and the Mean-Square Error for the LSF  quantizer and the Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio for the image coder. First, a Greedy level allocation algorithm is developed based on  the philosophy of the Greedy algorithin but, it does so level by level, considering  the best benefit and bit cost yielded by an allocation. The Greedy level allocation  algorithm is computationally intensive in general, thus we discuss combining it with  other algorithms to obtain lower costs. Second, another algorithm solving problems of negative bit  allocations and integer level is proposed. The level allocations are to keep a  certain ratio with respect to each other throughout the algorithm in order to remain  closest to the condition for lowest distortion. Moreover, the original formula  assumes a 6dB gain for each added bit, which is not generally true. The algorithm  presents a new parameter k, which controls the benefit of adding one bit, usually  set at 0.5 in the high-rate optimal bit allocation formula for MSE calling the new  algorithm, the Two-Stage Iterative Bit Allocation (TSIBA) algorithm. Simulations  show that modifying the bit allocation formula effectively brings about some gains  over the previous methods. The formula containing the new parameter is generalized into a,  formula introducing a new parameter which weights not only the variances but also  the dimensions, training the new parameter on their distribution function. The TSIBA  was an a-posteriori decision algorithm, where the decision on which value of k to  select for lowest distortion was decided after computing all distortions. The  Generalized TSIBA (GTSIBA), on the other hand, uses a training procedure to estimate  which weighting factor to set for each dimension at a certain bit rate. Simulation  results show yet another improvement when using the Generalized TSIBA over all  previous methods.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483j887.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg790</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80hv84b"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The biodegradation of a synthetic co-polyester by hydrolase-producing microorganisms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trinh Tan, Frederick, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The biological degradation of the synthetic aliphatic/aromatic  co-polyester Ecoflex(TM) (BASF) by 30 strains of hydrolase-producing soil bacteria,  fungi and yeasts was investigated at moderate environmental conditions. Previous  studies had shown that these materials could be degraded. These studies were done  uniquely in compost or by axenic compost isolates, and under thermophilic  conditions, but it is likely that most of this material will be found in sites at  more moderate conditions. Thus, a screening procedure was developed to assess the  biodegradability of the co-polyester at ambient environmental conditions. The  screening also allowed for the investigation of the mechanism of biodegradation in  order to determine the fate of these xenobiotics and their degradation intermediates  in the environment. Results obtained from shake flask experiments showed that the  aliphatic/aromatic co-polyester was readily degraded by most of the 30  microorganisms studied. However, less than 5% of the original Ecoflex(TM) film  weight was lost after 21 days of exposure for all the microorganisms studied. Using  GC-MS techniques, the degradation intermediates were identified to be the monomers  of the co-polyester; namely, adipic acid and terephthalic acid. Finally, gel  permeation chromatography (GPC) results suggest that an exo-enzyme type degradation,  where only the ester bonds at the termini of the polymeric chains are hydrolyzed by  the microbes.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451j06v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hv84b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Environmental Sciences</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rp20d"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Photocatalytic oxidation of glymes in an aqueous suspension of titanium dioxide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buchholz, Tuisko M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lower members of the glyme family CH3-(-O-CH2-CH2-)n O-CH3 are  refractory to the usual biological and physicochemical treatments, do not get  retained on biofilters and are hardly sorbed to activated sludge or carbon. An  alternate form of elimination is hence to be devised. TiO 2 particles have been  utilized in the photocatalytic degradation of organic compounds often found in  contaminated waste streams. When they are exposed to UV light, an electron is  excited from the TiO2 valence band into the conduction band. The photogenerated  electron vacancy ("hole") can initiate the oxidation of the organic, while  the photogenerated electron must be removed from the particle by transfer to a  suitable electron acceptor (scavenger). The photocatalytic oxidation of triglyme in an aqueous  suspension of TiO2 has been studied, proving the concept to be feasible.  Characterization of the light distribution in the reactor has been carried out and  related to the influence of catalyst load. The rate of the reaction was considerably  enhanced by introducing Cu2+ as co-catalyst and by controlling the pH, with the  existence of an optimum co-catalyst concentration ([triglyme]/[Cu 2+] = 2) and an  optimum pH at 3.5. The influence of both parameters is explained and the pathway of  the interfacial charge-transfer reaction is proven to be of the Fenton type  (indirect oxidation through activation of water) and not of the Photo-Kolbe type  (direct attack of the holes).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn106z672.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp20d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tv58q"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Designing a security architecture for distributed systems : an engineering approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Udupa, Kuppar Ranganath</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The dynamic and public nature of a large scale public  distributed system introduces challenging security issues that demand new technical  approaches. Existing literature has discussed a variety of schemes but fall short of  describing an engineering process to design security in such systems. This thesis  presents a process model for security system design in large distributed systems  that are prone to unpredictable joins and departures, the possibility of malicious  behaviors by public nodes and diverse local policies. A case study on designing  security architecture for a Public Computing Utility (PCU) is presented which is in  tune with the proposed process model. The security architecture for the PCU  integrates with a hierarchical trust and incentive management system of the PCU. The  trust management system provides a mechanism to build and evaluate trust amongst  resources based on individual transactions and community references. Additional  features of the security architecture include (a) an authentication mechanism  through non forgeable, self-describing certificates; (b) the authorization and  access control for resource access; (c) identification and resolution of a majority  of threats a PCU is subjected to.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dd012.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv58q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vh316"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Estimation of absorptivity and heat flux at the reheat phase of thermoforming process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kumar, Vijay</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Thermoforming is a process of forming thermoplastic sheets into  three-dimensional shapes by heating it to tender soft and pliable, and then, forcing  the sheet into or over the shape of a mold by applying differential pressure or  vacuum. Sheet reheat is the most important step in thermoforming because its result  can affect all subsequent processing steps. In order to develop an advanced in-cycle  and cycle-to-cycle control strategy, one needs to track the desired sheet  temperature profiles throughout the reheat cycle, and identify and characterize the  process and material parameters that vary from cycle-to-cycle and batch-to-batch.  Absorptivity of the polymer sheet material and the heat flux incident on the sheet  are the two important factors that need to be monitored and estimated properly in  order to integrate into the absorptivity based model for the sheet reheat phase.  Estimation of the heat flux can be used to generate the heat gain matrix relating  the energy given to the heating elements and temperature of the sheet. This thesis  develops methods to estimate absorptivity and heat flux in order to improve model  based control systems.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074v66j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh316</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hg04t"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Smoothing spline based vector partially linear model estimation and its applications in GPS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Lili, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The partially linear model (PLM) is a flexible extension of both  the linear model and nonparametric model of time series. The vector partially linear  model (VPLM) is an extension of PLM when there are a set of observations at one time  point from several sources. Smoothing spline is one of the popular approaches for  PLM estimation. This thesis extends the smoothing spline approach to a few VPLMs and  presents algorithms to compute the estimates. Then, we apply the smoothing spline  based vector partially linear model (SSBVPLM) approach to Global Positioning System  (GPS) applications. In an unfavorable environment, the accuracy of position  estimates, which are usually computed by the least squares (LS) method based on the  linear model, can be impaired due to system errors. In order to account the system  errors, we use the vector partially linear models instead of the linear models. We  apply the SSBVPLM estimation techniques to kinematic and static relative  positioning, based on both code and carrier phase measurements. The simulations show  that the SSBVPLM approach can yield more accurate position estimates than the LS  approach.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z1363.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg04t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354f76p"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rendezvous and formation flying related to the TECSAS mission</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Landry, Mathieu Alfred</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, spacecraft rendezvous and spacecraft formation  flying were examined in context of the TECSAS mission. Three terminal rendezvous  trajectories, one V-bar approach and two R-bar approaches, are compared in terms of  DeltaV fuel usage and time of flight (TOF). Results showed that the lidar-based  V-bar approach trajectory with a 90 m straight-line approach distance is the optimal  scenario for the given TECSAS mission guidelines. Four formation flying scenarios  are examined: two projected circular formations and two in-track formations. The  effects of the J2 and atmospheric drag perturbations on these formations are studied  for several time spans. Results showed that the projected circular formations are  disrupted by the J2 perturbations after a short time span, and that atmospheric drag  perturbations caused significant in-track and radial drifts for formations where the  two spacecraft are not identical. Finally, control force requirements are much  higher for both formations when the two spacecraft are not  identical.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg80r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f76p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Aerospace</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722h9406"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neuropeptide Y (NPY) as a modulator of neuroplasticity and emotional behavior in animal models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carvajal, Cristina Celeste</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Neuropeptide Y (NPY) is considered an important neuromodulator  in the regulation of emotional behavior. NPY consistently modulates anxiety-related  behaviors and there is increasing support for a role for this peptide in mood  disorders such as depression. There is also evidence that NPY promotes  neuroplasticity in the central nervous system. Recent studies suggest that chronic  depression is associated with neuronal loss and abnormalities in neuroplasticity  (such as neurogenesis) in the hippocampus. Consequently, the aim of this study was  to elucidate the role of the NPY Y1 and Y2 receptor subtypes in anxiety- and  depression-like behaviors using NPY knockout and transgenic animals and to  investigate the role of NPY as a neuroproliferative factor in hippocampal  neurogenesis. The ability of NPY to induce changes in neurogenesis was assessed in  NPY Y2 knockout mice and in Sprague-Dawley rats after chronic treatment with  NPY.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gn718.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722h9406</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t2466"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of two techniques for testing of polyethylene film resins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tiang, Jen Shueng, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The processability of a resin in film blowing is strongly  influenced by its flow behavior in extension. In this study, the suitability of the  Sentmanat Extensional Rheometer (SER) and of a novel tester for polyethylene film  resins was evaluated. The SER, which subjects the resin to simple extension, is  simple and fast to use, requires a small quantity of sample and gives reliable data  that can be used to detect differences in molecular weight, molecular weight  distribution and levels of long-chain branching. The data are also related to the  stability of the bubble in film blowing. The tester, on the other hand, is a simple  device that generates biaxial extension by inflating a sheet into a bubble. The  resulting pressure traces from this empirical test were found capable of  differentiating resins on the basis of their flow in biaxial  extension.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935350d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t2466</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860753w"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Recruitment specificity of Gab family docking proteins and implications for MET receptor-mediated epithelial morphogenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lock, Lisa S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Activation of cell-surface receptors by extracellular signals  can generate distinct biological responses. Many of these signals are coordinated  through docking proteins, including those in the Gab family (Gab1, Gab2 and Gab3).  Following activation of receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs), cytokine or antigen  receptors, docking proteins are recruited to the receptor complex and become  phosphorylated on tyrosine residues, providing binding sites for multiple proteins  involved in signal transduction. In this manner, they act to diversify and localize  signals downstream from receptors by virtue of their ability to assemble  multiprotein complexes. The recruitment of docking proteins to RTKs depends on the  ability of the protein to interact directly or indirectly with the receptor. In  chapter II, I established that Gab1 and Gab2 can be recruited to RTKs indirectly,  through constitutive association of Gab1 or Gab2 with the C-terminal SH3 domain of  the adapter protein Grb2. This requires two highly conserved Grb2 binding sites in  Gab proteins. One site corresponds to a canonical SH3 domain binding motif, whereas  the second contains an atypical PXXXRXXKP motif that I also identified in the  unrelated Grb2-binding protein, Slp-76. In contrast to the other Gab proteins, Gab1 can also interact in  a Grb2-independent manner with the Met/Hepatocyte growth factor receptor. In chapter  IV, I established that this interaction requires the structural integrity of the Met  receptor, phosphorylation of tyrosine 1349 in the Met C-terminus, and a 13 amino  acid Met binding motif (MBM) in Gab1. Instead of the expected interaction of a  phosphotyrosine-binding domain in Gab1 with a phosphotyrosine-containing motif in  the Met receptor, I propose that the activated kinase domain of Met and the negative  charge of phosphotyrosine 1349 engage the Gab1 MBM as an extended peptide  ligand. In response to Met receptor stimulation, Gab1 overexpression  promotes an invasive morphogenic program in epithelial cells. In contrast, I have  shown in chapter III that Gab2 overexpression fails to induce this response.  Mutation of the MBM in Gab1 abolishes the ability of Gab1 to promote morphogenesis,  whereas its insertion into Gab2 increases Gab2 association with Met, but does not  confer on Gab2 the ability to promote morphogenesis. This indicates that the  Grb2-independent recruitment of Gab proteins to Met is necessary but not sufficient  to promote epithelial morphogenesis. Overall, these studies have identified both  common and unique mechanisms through which receptor tyrosine kinases can recruit Gab  docking proteins, and have established that Gab1 and Gab2 do not share redundant  biological functions in epithelial cells.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Park, Morag</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk591.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860753w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pn455"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>God, saint, and priest : a comparison of mediatory modes in Roman Catholicism and Śrīvaiṣṇavism with special reference to the council of Trent and the Yatīndramatadīpikā</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>O'Rourke, James Colin Daly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Roman Catholicism and Srivaiṣṇavism  are two religious traditions in which mediation, primarily through the use of  images, plays a central role in soteriology. A comparison of various modes of  mediation between these two traditions will highlight a dialectic of presence and  absence, inherent in mediation, and will examine the various ways of interpreting  and dealing with this dialectic in their respective theologies. Three general  categories of mediation are identified through which this comparison will take  place: God, saint, and priest. Images of the full presence of God, namely the eucharistic host  in Roman Catholicism and the arcavatara in  Srivaiṣṇavism, mediate this full presence either through  the transformation of substance (as in Roman Catholicism) or through the appearance  of materiality and limited form (in Srivaiṣṇavism).  Saints and alvars can also be regarded as images or mediatory modes;  the saint embodies and mediates Christ's presence, becoming "as if"  Christ. This presence is manifested not only in the saint's life but in his or her  relics as well. The alvar is regarded as an aṁsa or partial  incarnation, thus manifesting a part of God, most notably His ornaments, weapons and  companions. A specific comparison of Mary and  Aṇṭaḷ/Sri will further highlight the  dialectic of presence and absence in addition to pointing out their unique status  within their respective traditions. A comparison of priests and acaryas will show  mediation in living images. Priests become "as if" Christ through their  ordination, and are seen to embody him particularly in specific ritual acts. The  acarya functions in much the same way as  Aṇṭaḷ/Sri, mediating between God and the  believer as an aṁsa or partial incarnation. Different theological conceptions of God and incarnation result  in the different understandings of mediation and the different ways that the two  traditions deal with the dialectic of presence and absence. Images in both  traditions also bring to light an "as if" conception in the mind of the  believer; saints and priests function "as if" Christ and the various  images in Srivaiṣṇaavism appear "as if"  material or "as if" human, thus allowing them to mediate the divine  presence to the community.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kirby, Torrance</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Young, Katherine K.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s595.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn455</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mediation between God and man -- Christianity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mediation between God and man -- Hinduism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Catholic Church -- Doctrines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Śrī Vaishṇava (Sect) -- Doctrines</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gk39d"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In sickness and in health : romantic art therapy and the return to nature</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lokash, Jennifer Faith</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores the network of relationships among health  and healing, the natural environment, and poetry during the Romantic period in  Britain, and thus offers a new perspective on the Romantic relation to Nature. The  context for this study is both the long and varied history that links literature to  ideas of health and disease, and the intersection of the late 18th- and early  19th-century discourses of holistic science and healing that emphasize the synergy  between self and world and recognize that our living environments can be either  hostile or congenial to body and spirit. For many Romantic poets, illness was a  painful reality that became vital to their thoughts about poetry and creativity in  general. Through Wordsworth's partnership with Coleridge, a vocabulary of health and  disease emerges in relation to poetic production and reception that has influenced  critics of the period. It constructs the "natural" as a source of health,  and establishes Wordsworth and his poetic celebrations of the therapeutic potential  of nature as the often problematic legacy both for Coleridge and for second  generation poets like Byron and Shelley. While composing Childe Harold's Pilgrimage  Canto III, Byron tests Wordsworth's notion that immersion in the natural world can  be spiritually therapeutic from the point of view of poetic production. The  intensity of Byron's bodily existence, however, prevents him from fully experiencing  the spiritual and metaphysical aspects of Wordsworthian nature. As his attempts to  disengage the spirit from the body by meditating on nature actually have the reverse  effect of bringing him more in touch with his physical identity, he must reject  Wordsworth's methodology as a possible vehicle for healing. In refiguring  Wordsworth's ideas about "taste," Shelley conceives of his poetry as  healthy food for thought. His frequently used metaphors of "literature as  food" have their source in his attitudes towards intake first exp</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kilgour, Maggie</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547r92k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk39d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Healing in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>English poetry -- 19th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nature in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gw74q"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design, synthesis and catalytic properties of chiral counteranions on transition metal catalysts : a new route to asymmetric induction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Llewellyn, David B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The design of enantioselective transition metal catalyzed  reactions is an important area of chemical research. The purpose of this study was  to develop a new method to incorporate chirality into transition metal catalysis via  ion pairing interactions. This has led to the development of the first  enantioselective transition metal catalyzed reaction using a chiral counteranion as  the sole source of asymmetry. In chapter two, the synthesis of a chiral  bis(1,1'-bi-2-naphtholato)borate anion is described. This anion can be incorporated  into cationic copper(I) complexes via anion exchange, which has allowed its effect  on the copper(I) catalyzed aziridination and cyclopropanation reactions to be  examined. In the cyclopropanation reaction, it was found that changing the chirality  of the counteranion in the presence of  (R,R)-2,2'-isopropylidenebis(4-phenyl-2-oxazoline), a chiral ligand, results in a  change in the enantioselectivity of the cyclopropanes formed by over 30%. The  influence of the chiral counteranion in the absence of a chiral ligand was also  explored. Chapter three describes the use of the copper(I) bis((R)-1,1'  -bi-2-naphtholato) borate salt as a chiral NMR shift reagent. The coordination of  the (R) and (S) enantiomers of 2,2'-bis(di-p-tolyl-phosphino)-1,1 '-binaphthyl  (tol-BINAP) to copper(I) bis((R)-1,1' -bi-2-naphtholato) borate in CD2Cl2 results in  well resolved 1H NMR (400 MHz) resonances for the two enantiomers. Examination of  standard solutions of 2,2'-bis(di-p-tolyl-phosphino)-1,1 '-binaphthyl demonstrate  that the copper complex can be used as an effective NMR shift reagent over a wide  range of enantiomeric compositions. In chapters four and five, the synthesis of a new class of  peptide-based chiral counteranions, and their incorporation into copper(I) catalysts  via ion exchange, is described. Studies on the copper(I) catalyzed cyclopropanation  of styrene with ethyl diazoacetate demonstrate that ion-pairing with these anions  can provide a novel method to incorporate a copper cation into a chiral alpha-amino  acid environment for asymmetric catalysis. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Arndtsen, Bruce</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mz08n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gw74q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n1673"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Visualising the history of women at Eaton's, 1869 to 1976</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>O'Donnell, Lorraine Frances</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the place of female customers and employees  at the T. Eaton Company of Canada between 1869 and 1976. The central argument is  that the word "witness" conveys well the nature of their place in this,  one of the most important retail firms in Canadian history. Women were witnesses for  the Eaton's and its development. They attested to and consolidated the company by  collectively supporting it in huge numbers, whether as customers or personnel. Women  were also key eyewitnesses of Eaton's, of its merchandise and marketing, its stores  and catalogues. As the word "witness" suggests, visuality was central to  women's central place. Women bought into the Eaton's buying and selling strategies  that privileged appearances, and the company assumed and fostered this  visually-centered role, helping to construct it and encouraging women to adopt it.  The Introduction to the thesis reviews the substantial literature on the company's  history. The main body of the thesis is divided in two. Part I examines the  company's foreign activities and the role of women therein. Following a description  of the firm's foreign buying system is an examination of three of its main regions:  Japan, Europe and the U.S.A. The closer the region was to Canada, the more familiar  it was to Eaton's, the more female Eatonians were employed there, and the more these  women were able carve out a niche for themselves as expert witnesses like fashion  buyers or fashion reporters. Part II discusses the place of women in the company's  activities within Canada. First, it outlines the history of and tensions between the  company's two main retail sites: stores and catalogues. While run by men, these  sites were "spectacles of women" including salesclerks, mannequins and  customers. Examples considered in depth are Eaton's catalogue covers and store  displays for foreign goods and places. They privileged female imagery, a strategy  meant to add value both to the merchandise and the</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levesque, Andree</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j8580.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n1673</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women's Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Business Administration, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>History, Canadian</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860752m"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Porphyre et le Livre de Daniel : réaction à la tradition exégétique chrétienne du IIIe siècle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Magny, Ariane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Neoplatonist philosopher Porphyry of Tyre (ca.232-305 A.D.)  wrote Against the Christians, a fifteen-volume treatise targeting Christianity.  Porphyry's attack was considered so scandalous that it was twice condemned to flames  by Roman emperors. It is thus only in the works of Christian apologists that Against  the Christians is extant, i.e. in a fragmentary state. The topic of this study is  the twelfth book of Porphyry's treatise, the best known and probably the most  challenging to Christians. Indeed, it deals with the Book of Daniel, which underlies  a great part of Christianity's foundations as it allegedly foretells both Parousiai.  It will first be demonstrated that the writing of the treatise can be dated to the  290s, which indicates it was not an immediate threat to Christians facing the Great  Persecution (303-311). Then recent methodological approaches are presented in order  to get a better insight of the content of Against the Christians. It is established  that Porphyry wrote a detailed exegesis of Daniel with the intention of criticizing  the Christian literal interpretation of the Scriptures by adapting history to  prophecy. Finally it is suggested that Porphyry wrote his treatise in response to a  Christian allegorical exegetical tradition of Daniel.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hg053.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860752m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Porphyry, ca. 234-ca. 305. Against the Christians</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xs15j"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thule and Caribou Inuit subsistence strategies : re-evaluating the origins of the Caribou Inuit</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Henderson, Lyle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of this thesis is to re-evaluate the origins of the  Caribou Inuit. The thesis presents theories that have been proposed by Birket-Smith  (1929), Burch (1978), and Clark (1978). Each theory represents a diverse perspective  regarding Caribou Inuit origins that include, respectively, a proto-Eskimo origin,  an immigration origin, and cultural change resulting from European  contact. The alternative theory being proposed in this thesis is that  change in environmental conditions that resulted from the Little Ice Age caused the  most favoured food resource, the ringed seal, to decline significantly in abundance  because the necessary ice conditions that are required for these seals to inhabit a  particular area no longer existed. The implications that are discussed and tested as  a result of a decline in marine resources are there would have been a shift in focal  resources, a corresponding change in regional territories, and a change in  subsistence-settlement systems.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397880t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs15j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Caribou Eskimos -- Nunavut -- Food</dc:subject><dc:subject>Caribou Eskimos -- Origin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thule culture -- Nunavut -- Food</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343s71p"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The text of Paul in the writings of Didymus of Alexandria</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacDonald, Kevin, MA.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study of patristic quotations of the Greek New Testament has  proven valuable in the field of textual criticism as a means of locating variant  readings both chronologically and geographically, facilitating the reconstruction of  the development of the different textual groups. This thesis will document the  Pauline citations, adaptations and allusions of Didymus of Alexandria, and then  determine their textual affinities, along the lines of earlier studies in this  field. Using the methodology developed by B. Ehrman, including both a statistical  analysis and a method of group profiling, this study concludes that the text of Paul  in Didymus clearly belongs to the Alexandrian group. An appendix giving suggestions  for corrections and additions to the critical apparatuses of both the 27th edition  of the Nestle-Aland text and the 4th edition of the United Bible Societies text of  the Greek New Testament has also been provided.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b40b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s71p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Didymus, the Blind, ca. 313-ca. 398</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vp10x"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High-level audio morphing strategies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hatch, Wesley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents high-level strategies for controlling  existing audio morphing algorithms. Prominent methods for spectrally representing  audio data in the context of audio morphing are surveyed, and techniques involving  manipulating and interpolating additive models are explored. Additionally, a  combination of past audio-morphing approaches (sinusoidal morphing techniques as  well as techniques taken from an MFCC approach) are employed in order to facilitate  any type of sonic input. The system presented herein is meant to accommodate a wide  range of inputs, and will adjust the impact of a high-level feature depending on the  type and quality of the input.* *This dissertation is a compound document (contains both a paper  copy and a CD as part of the dissertation).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Depalle, Philippe</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322d873.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp10x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sound -- Recording and reproducing -- Digital techniques</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer sound processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>