<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zz33j"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional characterization of the influence of human RGS1 (hRGS1) on G protein-coupled receptor signaling in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Somerville, Wendy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Regulators of G protein signaling (RGS) are proteins that negatively regulate G protein-coupled receptor signaling. Although a conserved core domain is necessary and sufficient for their GTPase accelerating protein (GAP) activity, many RGSs possess C- and N-terminal protein-binding motifs that augment GAP activity and participate in other cellular regulatory mechanisms. Human RGS 1 functionally complements a Saccharomyces cerevisiae mutant lacking the RGS homologue Sst2p. We demonstrate that deletion of the N-terminus or RGS domain negatively affects this ability in Sst2p-deficient strains, whereas deletion of the C-terminal 10 residues of RGS 1 does not. Coexpression of the N-terminus and RGS domains restores complementation of Sst2p to that of wild type. The conservative replacement of sequential residues spanning the N-terminus of RGS1 causes little loss of function. These results suggest that the N-terminal and RGS domains of RGS I function in concert to effect signaling and that the C-terminal 10 residues of RGS I are not required for this activity. Further, residues present in the N-terminus are not highly conserved suggesting that overall structure, rather than individual residues or motifs, may be important for function.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Greenwood, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n295g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz33j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk375"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of nitric oxide in maintenance of endothelial cell and vascular viability under oxidant stress</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Speranza, Giovanna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Numerous premature infants subjected to oxidant stress are afflicted with retinopathy of prematurity (ROP). Reactive oxygen species (ROS) and increased products of peroxidation with vasoconstrictor and cytotoxic properties ultimately lead to the degeneration of retinal microvessels. However, synthesis and activity of the vasodilator, nitric oxide (NO), are increased in the newborn. Furthermore, NO has been reported to protect cells, including endothelial cells, against injury associated with excess production of ROS. We thus postulated that NO plays a protective role in the development of oxygen-induced retinopathy by limiting the extent of microvascular obliteration and tested this hypothesis in a rat model of ROP. Rat pups receiving inhibitors with differential selectivity for the NO synthase (NOS) isoforms were exposed to 80% O2 from postnatal days 6 to 12 and retinas were compared for extent of capillary obliteration. Endothelial cells being particularly susceptible to oxidative injury, we tested the effect of NO directly on microvascular endothelial cell cultures under oxidant stress. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chemtob, Sylvain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z019h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk375</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h129m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Probabilistic assessment of study quality in meta-analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sultan, Shagufta Ahmed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The quality of studies in meta-analysis can vary widely. This variation is usually described by assigning quality scores to studies. A natural way to incorporate quality scores into an analysis is to weight each study by its quality score in addition to its size or inverse of the variance of the estimate for that study. This method has been used by several authors but has been criticized due to its subjectivity. To improve on this and other existing approaches, Tritchler (1999) introduced a probability model for assessing the effect of quality on a summary effect measure. He derived a number of summarization methods and compared them for simulated data and also applied them on an actual set of studies utilizing fixed effects models. Tritchler's approach was evaluated in two ways. The probability model was compared to other methods for quality adjustment in a simulation study. In addition, the probability model was compared to several other methods for quality adjustment, using an empirical study of 31 meta-analyses. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Platt, R. W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f303r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h129m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz113"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation on fabrication processes and characteristics of BiSrCaCuO films</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Lixia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Superconducting thin films of BiSrCaCuO with a thickness from 0.4 to 1 $ mu$n have been successfully fabricated on (100) oriented MgO substrates by CO$ sb2$ laser ablation and post annealing. Pb-doped BiSrCaCuO targets were prepared from oxide with different ratios of metals. Oxygen pressure during deposition was found to affect the composition of the as-deposited films. Although the substrate heating improved morphology of the films, it did not have a strong effect on the stoichiometry. Good quality superconducting films were produced after a two-step annealing with a controlled rate of temperature increase, which was determined by the chamber pressures used. The onset critical temperature for the superconducting films was between 86 and 118 K and the zero critical temperature was between 77 and 106 K. These critical temperatures are the highest ones obtained so far for BiSrCaCuO films prepared by the CO$ sb2$ laser ablation technique. The critical current density of the films was in the range of $10 sp2 sim 10 sp3$ A/cm$ sp2$. The films were found to contain 2212 and 2223 superconducting phases, with a dominant 2223 phase. The composition was uniform along the films and the average ratio was close to that for the standard 110 K high-T$ sb{ rm c}$ phase. The noise of the BiSrCaCuO films in normal state was inversely proportional to frequency and was at least 5 orders of magnitude larger than the noise of typical metals. In the superconducting state, the films showed a noise peak in the tail region of the superconducting transition. This noise peak also showed a 1/f variation at intermediate frequencies. The noise peak was maximum at a given current, and decreased with an increase in the external magnetic field. It is believed that this noise peak was caused by the vortex motion. Three peaks were observed in microwave-induced voltage versus temperature curves (microwave frequency = 10.28 GHz) for the BiSrCaCuO superconducting films. One of the peaks occurred at the midpoint of the superconducting transition, which was due to a bolometric effect. The other two peaks occurred at temperatures near the tail region of the transition and these were caused by a non-bolometric effect.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shih, I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p869v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz113</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w0324583"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Finite groupoids and their applications to computational complexity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lemieux, François, 1961-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In our Master thesis the notions of recognition by semigroups and by programs over semigroups were extended to groupoids. As a consequence of this transformation, we obtained context-free languages instead of regular with recognition by groupoids, and we obtained SAC$ sp1$ instead of NC$ sp1$ with recognition by programs over groupoids. In this thesis, we continue the investigation of the computational power of finite groupoids. We consider different restrictions on the original model. We examine the effect of restricting the kind of groupoids used, the way parentheses are placed, and we distinguish between the case where parentheses are explicitly given and the case where they are guessed nondeterministically. We introduce the notions of linear recognition by groupoids and by programs over groupoids. This leads to new characterizations of linear context-free languages and NL. We also prove that the algebraic structure of finite groupoids induces a strict hierarchy on the classes of languages they linearly recognized. We investigate the classes obtained when the groupoids are restricted to be quasigroups (i.e. the multiplication table forms a latin square). We prove that languages recognized by quasigroups are regular and that programs over quasigroups characterize NC$ sp1$. We also consider the problem of evaluating a well-parenthesized expression over a finite loop (a quasigroup with an identity). This problem is in NC$ sp1$ for any finite loop, and we give algebraic conditions for its completeness. In particular, we prove that it is sufficient that the loop be nonsolvable, extending a well-known theorem of Barrington. Finally, we consider programs where the groupoids are allowed to grow with the input length. We study the relationship between these programs and more classical models of computation like Turing machines, pushdown automata, and owner-read owner-write PRAM. As a consequence, we find a restriction on Boolean circuits that has some interesting properties. In particular, circuits that characterize NP and NL are shown to correspond, in presence of our restriction, to P and L respectively.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Therien, Denis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g662k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0324583</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bg665"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Residential exposure to 60 hertz magnetic fields and adult cancers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Chung-Yi, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis comprises three independent but interrelated manuscripts. (1) The results from seven epidemiological studies of adult cancers in relation to residential exposure to power frequency magnetic fields (MF) indicated that the association between leukemia and MF has been inconsistent. It also indicated that the risks of brain tumors and breast cancer, the other cancers frequently suspected of being associated with occupational exposure to MF, were rarely investigated. Based on these epidemiological results, the analysis of the roles of chance and bias, and the criteria for causal inferences, it appears that the evidence is not strong enough to support the putative causal relationship between residential MF and adult cancers. (2) A case-control study, using matching on date of birth, sex, and date of diagnosis, was therefore carried out in northern Taiwan to further evaluate the risks of adult ($ sbsp{=}{&gt;}$ 15 years of age) leukemia, brain tumors, and female breast cancers in relation to residential exposure to 60 Hz MF. Cases were newly diagnosed cancers reported to the cancer registry between 1987 and 1992 and controls were incident cancers from sites other than those previously suspected of being associated with MF during the same period. Assessment of MF in the residences occupied by the study subjects at the time of diagnosis was performed by modeling power information of high-voltage transmission lines. The results were based on the separate analysis of 708 leukemia, 455 brain tumors, and 1,562 female breast cancers. The risk of leukemia for exposure to MF $&gt;$ 0.2 $ mu$T relative to the reference level ($&lt;$0.1 $ mu$T) was significantly elevated (odds ratio = 1.51, 95% confidence interval 1.05-2.19). A dose-response relationship showed a gradient increase in relative risk estimates for leukemia with MF. The relative risk estimates for brain tumors and female breast cancers were slightly elevated, but were statistically compatible to null. (3) To valida</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Theriault, Gilles</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw09b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg665</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff365685w"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fault diagnosis in mobile mining equipment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Knights, Peter Fielden</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The development of decision support systems for equipment diagnosis has been found to be an iterative process whereby functionality and knowledge are continually added to a prototype until satisfactory performance is achieved. In order to reduce both the dependency on compiled knowledge sources and the number of prototype stages necessary to develop diagnostic decision support systems, this thesis examines, adapts and applies a set theoretical approach to mechanism diagnosis first developed in the field of Artificial Intelligence. The approach does not require the development of computational models to simulate equipment behaviour. The set theoretical approach was applied to the development of a diagnostic decision support system for a semi-automated Atlas Copco Wagner ST-8B Load-Haul-Dump vehicle. Hypothesis sets were generated for the vehicle's hydraulic circuit and Deutz FL-413-FW diesel engine. A high level of diagnostic resolution was achieved for the hydraulic circuit, but limited resolution was achieved for the diesel engine. This was postulated to be due to the ratio of observable system outputs to input sub-systems, and the number of least repairable units making up each system. Manual knowledge acquisition was undertaken in an underground mine to refine the diagnostic knowledge developed from the hypothesis sets and to add knowledge to discriminate between competing failure hypotheses. Heuristic failure likelihoods were used to rank hypotheses in order of frequency of occurrence. The knowledge base was implemented as a hypertext decision support system using HyperText Mark-up Language (HTML). The resulting decision support system is platform independent, upgradeable and able to be maintained by site personnel. The system is currently installed at surface level and at 1800 level at INCO Limited's Stobie Mine in Sudbury, Ontario. The thesis makes a number of original contributions, the first two of which are of generic significance. It is the first work to apply set theoretical concepts to structural models of mobile mining equipment in order to diagnose faults. A number of modifications are advanced to the conventional trace-back analysis technique for generating contributor and normality sets, and heuristic guidelines are provided for estimating the costs and benefits of developing, implementing and maintaining diagnostic decision support systems. It is also the first work to formalise a decision support system in HTML and to suggest the application of company-wide internets ("intranets") to disseminate maintenance knowledge within mines.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daneshmend, L. K.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Peck, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f42s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365685w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject><dc:subject>Information Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sr61n"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trace metal contamination in forests of southern Quebec and pathway studies of airborne metal deposits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Zhi-Qing</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Trace metal contamination of the air-soil-tree system was examined in southern Quebec, where acid deposition and tree dieback have been recorded in high elevation forests. Mn pollution was emphasized due to its large emission from gasoline combustion in Canada. Airborne Cu, Mn, V, and Zn showed higher concentrations than those reported for other remote locations. Significant fluctuation in Mn concentrations during the winter-spring season was explored by air mass back trajectory analysis. The study suggested that high Mn concentrations resulted from the atmospheric long-range transport from Canadian industrialized and metropolitan regions. Metal concentrations in podzolic topsoils were generally higher than their world-wide average values. Concentrations of trace metals in balsam fir (Abies balsamea (L.) Mill) needles were below their suggested potential phytotoxic levels, except for Mn, which also increased with elevation. The scanning of needles with micro-PIXE showed no significant correlation between metal accumulation and epistomatal distribution on foliar surfaces. Pathways of trace metals deposited in the soil-tree system were elucidated through application of $ sp{54}$Mn and $ sp{65}$Zn on shoot, bark, and soil surfaces in growth-chamber experiments with balsam fir seedlings. Uptake and accumulation by seedlings 70 days after application on the shoot surface was about 25-30% of the remaining activities for $ sp{54}$Mn and $ sp{65}$Zn. Less than 1% of absorbed isotopes was translocated from the bark surface to other plant organs, whereas more than 50% of the radioisotopes absorbed at the shoot moved to the rest of the seedling. Acidic wetness facilitated the metal absorption through tree surfaces. Downward movement of the radioisotopes in podzolic soils was documented, and accumulation in seedlings by root uptake was 5% of the remaining activity for $ sp{54}$Mn and 3% for $ sp{65}$Zn 70 days after application. No appreciable elemental migration from internal tissues to epicuticular wax layers was found, and the leaching ratio was below 0.5 and 1.0% for $ sp{54}$Mn and $ sp{65}$Zn, respectively. This study helps to understand the links between atmospheric deposition and the elevated levels of Mn in trees, and potential effects of acid deposition on the bioaccumulation of toxic metal pollutants in high elevation forests in southern Quebec.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schuepp, Peter H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg099.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr61n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Trace elements -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metals -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atmospheric deposition -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acz30pv20q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of polystyrene based diblock copolymer micelles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khougaz, Karine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The micellization of polystyrene based block copolymers was investigated in aqueous and in organic media. Micelles formed from polystyrene-b-poly(sodium acrylate) (PS-b-PANa) in sodium chloride solutions were investigated by static light scattering (SLS). The aggregation numbers (N$ rm sb{agg})$ were influenced by low salt concentrations ($&lt;$0.10 M) and they were essentially independent of the soluble block lengths. The core radii ($ rm sb{e}$ agreed well with previous solid state results on similar samples studied by small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS). It was thus concluded that no supermicellar aggregates were present and that the cores were solvent free. A method to evaluate the critical micelle concentrations (cmc's) of block copolymer micelles by SLS was developed to account for the effects of polydispersity on the cmc. It was found that for block copolymers which have a significant dependence of the cmc on the insoluble block length and which are polydisperse only the present approach was able to evaluate the cmc. The micellization of PS-b-PANa and PS-b-poly(acrylic acid) (PS-b-PAA) block copolymers were investigated in organic solvents. The cmc's were found to range from $1 times10 sp{-7} { rm to} 5 times10 sp{-9}$ M for insoluble block lengths ranging from 2.6 to 18 units. The N$ rm sb{agg}$ and R$ rm sb{e}$ values for four PS-b-PANa series in tetrahydrofuran, were found to be a function of the length of both blocks. The effect of the degree of neutralization of the PAA block on micellization was probed by SLS and SAXS; micelle formation was found to commence at 5% neutralization. The distribution of water between toluene and the polar cores of block ionomer and sodium bis(2-ethylhexyl)sulfosuccinate (AOT) reverse micelles was investigated by proton chemical shift measurements as a function of temperature. The amount of water solubilized and the thermodynamic parameters of transfer were found to be a function of the core nature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Eisenberg, Adi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db558.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv20q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plastics Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t3607"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Time-dependent phenomena of excitable cardiac tissue</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kunysz, Arkady M. (Arkady Mussa)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of electrical stimulation protocols on the spontaneous activity of multicellular experimental cardiac preparations are examined. Particular attention is drawn to the contribution of stimulation history to the dynamics observed under different experimental protocols. The experimental study focuses on phase resetting, periodic stimulation and fixed delay stimulation of embryonic chick heart cell aggregates. In addition, similar experiments are carried out on rabbit atrioventricular cell clusters to draw a comparison between the dynamics in rapid and slow inward current cardiac preparations. Three classes of models of the rhythmic behaviour are considered. The Shrier-Clay ionic model of electrical activity in spontaneously beating embryonic chick heart cell aggregates. is used to model the response of this preparation to various stimulation protocols. A modified version of this model, which includes a simplified sodium pump term, is developed to account for the effects of stimulation history on the response of embryonic chick heart cell aggregates to sustained external stimulation. Simple nonlinear models expressed in terms of difference equations are considered to describe phase resetting behaviour, phase locking, and the effects of stimulation history on the dynamics during stimulation. A simplified model of a relaxation oscillator is also proposed that incorporates a time dependent term. These different classes of models offer complementary approaches to the understanding of the contribution of stimulation history to the development of complex dynamics in excitable systems. This work shows the importance of the interaction between time dependent phenomena and the intrinsic properties of excitable cardiac tissue to the rhythms observed in many experimental and clinical contexts. The limitations of the current experimental and theoretical approaches are discussed and their relevance to the modeling of biological systems is examined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Glass, Leon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s502.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t3607</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biophysics, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544br03f"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Au sujet des algorithmes de recherche des systèmes de reconnaissance de la parole à grands vocabulaires</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lacouture, Roxane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Given that a probabilistic approach is now broadly used in automatic speech recognition (ASR), it becomes very rapidly impossible from a memory and execution time point of view to perform an exhaustive search, especially for lexica of more than a thousand words. The use of various heuristics or other approaches to reduce the amount of space and/or time needed is thus inevitable. This thesis describes many such approaches, both for very large lexicon ($&gt;$20000 words) speaker-independent isolated word systems and for large lexicon (between 3000 and 20000 words) speaker-independent continuous speech systems. For isolated words systems, it describes an efficient data structure minimization algorithm. For continuous speech systems, it presents three new types of beams. A multi-pass algorithm was also incorporated in a system used for an official ARPA CSR evaluation. Finally, this system was used as a test bed for the development of a new rejection algorithm and a new speech adaptation integration method.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mori, Renato De</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn29z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br03f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945s51b"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theoretical and experimental investigation of wall-control blasting methods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khoshrou, Seyed Hassan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Overbreak and damage to rock walls is one of the most serious problems encountered in blasting operations. Several techniques have been developed to control the undesirable effects of rock blasting. These techniques are collectively known as wall-control blasting methods. The stress distribution around pressurized holes has been numerically evaluated, in order to analyze the mechanism of wall-control blasting methods. The effect of blast geometry and the role of discontinuity on this stress field has also been studied in detail. The results obtained by numerical modelling have been verified by controlled blasting experiments, and further supported by analysis of existing roadcuts on a large scale. It was found that the mechanism of wall-control blast can be explained by the collision and superposition of the stresses between the holes. A narrow fracture zone between the holes was produced by tensile stresses on the centreline. It is neither necessary nor realistic to assume onset of fractures at the midpoint between holes by reinforcement of the stresses from each hole. The analysis shows that a burden can be defined as being infinite when the ratio of that to the spacing is greater than unity. For pre-split blasting (infinite burden) in an isotropic and homogeneous material the hole separation could range up to 15 borehole diameters. The decoupling ratio between the explosive charge and the borehole diameter should be smaller than 0.5. This ratio would generally be between 0.2 and 0.3 for pre-splitting (infinite burden), and between 0.3 and 0.4 in the presence of a free face. A discontinuity parallel to the free face and located at the back of the holes causes high stress levels between the discontinuity and the boreholes, resulting is a shattered one in this region. The presence of a similar discontinuity at the front of the holes leads to considerable overbreak and development of an undamaged "hump" of rock between holes. The effect of a discontinuity oriented normal to the centreline at the midpoint between holes has minimal effect on the blast results. As the angle of the discontinuity with the free face decreases from 90$ sp circ,$ the damage zone between the holes and the discontinuity increases, and the shape of the final wall changes from a smooth face to a corrugated shape. A closed-discontinuity or an open discontinuity cemented with strong filling materials has little effect on the results of the blast. However, as the width of the discontinuity increases, the size of the damage zone also increases. An open discontinuity, 50 mm wide or more, plays a role similar to a free face. In roadcut blast design, hole deviation is a key parameter in determining the quality of the face. However, consistent hole deviation in the same direction has minimal effect in the result of the blast. This type of deviation is usually associated with bedded rocks, with alternating bands of soft and hard rock on the face. The degree of deviation is dependent, amongst other factors, on orientation, thickness, frequency and the position of these bands.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d303.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s51b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx02h"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Water table management and cropping systems for intensive corn production</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaluli, J. Wambua</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of agricultural chemicals, such as nitrogen fertilizers in corn production, often results in water pollution. This research, comprising three parts, was designed to investigate the effects of nitrogen fertilizer application rates, water table management, and corn cropping systems on drainage water quality. The first part was a field study, to investigate the impact of two cropping systems and water table management on nitrate loss through tile drainage. The considered water table treatments were free drainage, and subirrigation with target water table depths at 0.5 m or 0.75 M below the soil surface. Corn (Zea mays L.) monoculture and corn intercropped with annual ryegrass (Lolium multiflorum Lam.) were investigated. The highest annual tile drainage losses of 21.9 kg N/ha were measured in monocropped, freely draining plots. Subirrigation with a water table depth of 0.5 m reduced tile drainage loss of N by over 70%, and intercropping corn with ryegrass under free drainage reduced leaching losses by 50%. The second part of the research was a simulation study with the water quality model, DRAINMOD-N. The water quality impact of fertilizer application rate under free drainage, subirrigation and controlled drainage was evaluated. Leaching losses, denitrification and N accumulation in the soil profile were investigated. Using data obtained from the field experiment, the performance of DRAINMOD-N was evaluated. DRAINMOD-N assumes that denitrification follows first order kinetics, contrary to field measurements which showed little correlation between denitrification rate and NO$ sb3 sp-$-N concentration. Therefore, DRAINMOD-N was modified by replacing the original denitrification function with the Michaelis-Menten relationship. In so doing, denitrification is expressed as a first order process when NO$ sb3 sp-$-N concentration limits denitrification, and as a zero order process for non-limiting NO$ sb3 sp-$-N concentration. For denitrification to be a decision making criterion of water table management, inexpensive but reliable measurement techniques are required. Thus, the purpose of the final part of this research was to formulate a technique for measuring real-time denitrification rate. Denitrification rate could be expressed as a function of soil redox potential (Eh) and temperature. Laboratory and field studies showed that factors such as soil nitrate and organic carbon had negligible effect on denitrification rate. Therefore, it can be concluded that for most agricultural soil, Eh and soil temperature will satisfactorily describe denitrification variation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madramootoo, Chaudra A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c431p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx02h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Water table -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Groundwater -- Pollution -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Companion planting -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z2440"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Integrated optics spectroscopy of polymer thin films</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kanigan, Tanya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the design and construction of an integrated optics (IO) spectrometer for the purpose of characterizing optically transparent polymer thin films (1-10 $ mu$m). IO spectroscopy exploits the properties of electromagnetic fields that exist in a polymer film when it is used as a planar dielectric waveguide. The spectrometer measures waveguide propagation constants and Raman spectra excited by guided modes. These data are used to characterize the structures of solution cast cellulose acetate (CA) films and glassy cellulose films regenerated from them, and laser induced anisotropy in organically modified silicate (ORMOSIL) sol-gel films. Waveguide Raman spectra indicate partial alignment of CA chains within the plane of the film. Deacetylation of CA films in aqueous ammonia to form glassy regenerated cellulose (RC) waveguides preserves orientational anisotropy of the parent CA film. Refractive index profiles are reconstructed from measured optical propagation constants of CA, RC and partially regenerated CA waveguides using inverse Wentzel-Kramers-Brillouin approximation methods. Partially regenerated CA films possess an asymmetric reflective index gradient attributed to depth inhomogeneity present in CA films prior to regeneration. The effects of deviations from right angle scattering geometry on polarized waveguide Raman spectra are discussed. Polarization mode conversion is attributed to the presence of off-diagonal elements in the film dielectric tensor. In CA films, these off-diagonal elements result from excessive pressure on the coupling prism and partial orientation of polymer chains. Coupled mode theory is used to predict the effects of polarization mode conversion on the polarized Raman spectra as a function of film parameters and coupling angle. Photoinduced birefringence and photoalignment are observed in ORMOSIL sol-gel films after exposure to guided light from an argon ion laser (514.5 nm and 488.0 nm lines). By simultaneously exciting TE and TM modes, non-transient, reversible off-diagonal dielectric tensor elements are introduced in the film. These off-diagonal elements cause coupling between the orthogonal TE and TM modes, which is, in turn, observed in polarized waveguide Raman spectra collected from the film. Photorefractive effects are attributed to photoinduced anisotropy (PIA) and glass photosensitivity phenomenon previously observed (by others) in doped silicate glasses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andrews, Mark P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c490.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z2440</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zj31w"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Action diagrams : a methodology for the specification and verification of real-time systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khordoc, Karim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we address issues in the specification, simulation, and formal verification of systems that are characterzed by real-time constraints and a mix of protocol and data computation aspects. We propose a novel specification language and modeling methodology--HAAD (Hierarchical Annotated Action Diagrams). In HAAD, the interface behavior or a system is captured as a hierarchy of action diagrams. The internal behavior is modeled by an Extended Finite State Machine (EFSM). A leaf action diagram defines a behavior (a template) over a set of ports. Procedures and predicates are attached to actions in order to describe the functional aspects of the interface. We propose algorithms and methods for the automatic generation of simulation models and response verification scripts from HAAD specifications. These models perform "on-the-fly parsing" of actions received at their I/O ports, sequencing through state transitions based on the result of this parsing, detecting incorrect, or ill-formed interface operations (bus cycles), verifying that all timing constraints at the input of the model are met, and driving the model outputs with appropriate delays. We formalize the operational semantics of leaf action diagrams under linear timing constraints, based on the concepts of a block machine and causal block machine. We state the realizability of an action diagram in terms of the existence of a causal block machine derived from the action diagram. We examine the problem of the compatability of concurrent, communicating leaf action diagrams described by linear timing constraints and we show the inaccuracies of known methods that address this problem. We define the action diagram compatibility problem in terms of the compatibility of all the possible combinations of causal block machines derived form these action diagrams. We prove that such enumeration is not needed in answering the compatibility question. This leads to an exact and efficient compatibility verification procedure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rumin, Nicholas</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z12p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj31w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, System Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s174v"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic and molecular studies of genes involved in the regulation and assembly of b1,6-glucan in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jiang, Bo, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Analyses of genes involved in yeast cell wall $ beta$1,6-glucan assembly have identified CWH41, PTC1/CWH47, EXG1, PBS2 and a family of genes related to the human oxysterol binding protein, OSBP. CWH41 encodes a novel membrane N-glycoprotein located in the ER. Disruption of CWH41 leads to a K1 killer toxin resistant phenotype, and a 50% reduction in the $ beta$1,6-glucan level The $cwh{ it 41 /} Delta$ mutant displayed strong synergistic defects with $kre{ it 1 /} Delta$ or $kre{ it 1 /} Delta$ null mutations: the $cwh{ it 41 /} Delta kre{ it 6 /} Delta$ double mutant showed a slow-growth phenotype and a 75% reduction in $ beta$1,6-glucan level, and cells containing $cwh{ it 41 /} Delta kre{ it 6 /} Delta$ double mutations were nonviable. These results indicate that CWH41 is involved in the assembly of $ beta$1,6-glucan. PTC1/CWH47 encodes a serine/threonine phosphatase, PBS2 is the structural gene for a MAPK kinase, and EXG1 codes for an exo-$ beta$-glucanase. Overexpression of EXG1 led to a killer resistant phenotype and a reduction in ($ beta$1,6-glucan level; whereas the $exg{ it 1 /} Delta$ mutant displayed modest increases in killer sensitivity and $ beta$1,6-glucan levels. Disruption of PTC1/CWH47 and overexpression of PBS2 resulted in similar $ beta$-glucan related phenotypes, with elevated EXG1 transcription, increased Exg1p activity, reduced $ beta$1,6-glucan levels, and resistance to killer toxin. The killer resistant phenotype caused by PTC1/CWH47 disruption or PBS2 overproduction were partially suppressed by the $exg{ it 1 /} Delta$ null mutation. These results suggest that Ptc1p/Cwh47p and Pbs2p play opposing regulatory roles in $ beta$-glucan assembly, and this is effected in part by modulating Exg1p activity. Three yeast genes, KES1, HES1 and OSH1, whose products show homology to the human oxysterol binding protein, were also identified. Mutations in these genes resulted in sterol-related phenotypes, which include tryptophan-transport defects and nystatin resistance. In addition, mutant combinations showed small but cumulative reductions in membrane ergosterol levels. The three genes are also functionally related; since overexpression of HES1 or KES1 alleviated the tryptophan-transport defect in $kes{ it 1 /} Delta$ or $osh{ it 1 /} Delta$ mutants, respectively. These observations implicate the KES1-related gene family in ergosterol synthesis and provide comparative evidence of a role for human OSBP in cholesterol synthesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bussey, Howard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn310.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s174v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Glucans</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg13t"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Moenawar Chalil's reformist thought : a study of an Indonesian religious scholar (1908-1961)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hamim, Thoha</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis studies Moenawar Chalil's reformist thought, as it was patterned after that of earlier reformists. Issues which have been long formed the heritage of religious reform appear therein, ranging from a call to return to the original sources of Islam to condemnation of popular religious practices. In his approach to Qur'an-interpretation, Chalil stripped the texts of legendary traits, rejected the principle of naskh, offered a particular approach to the interpretation of the mutashabihat verses and emphasized the i'jaz 'aqli/. His aim was to revitalize the Qur'an's function as a guide for modern life and to stress its compatibility with present modes of thought. Chalil's call for the emulation of the Prophet's sunnah was designed to reestablish the latter's direct link to rulings of a legal nature. He urged greater scrutiny of the authenticity of hadiths in order to restore the simplicity of faith and to halt inappropriate practices falsely attributed to the Prophet's example. This attitude was the logical outcome of his puritan stance, which was also manifested in the scope of his ijtihad which he restricted only to matters related to the purification of 'aqidah and 'ibadah. Similarly, Chalil's total rejection of the practice of taqlid shows his puritan agenda which went beyond even that of the early reformists. This extreme position, however, led him to misunderstand the true meaning of taqlid and its role both in the procedures of the judicial system and in shaping the faith of the 'awamm. Chalil's concept of ittiba' did not assess the intellectual state of the 'awamm, whose inability to detect the reasons behind the proofs meant that they would inevitably have to remain in a state of taqlid. Similarly, his call for the abandonment of the madhhab only helped to foster a new taqlid in response to this position. Also central to Chalil's reformist thought was his revision of the understanding of the basic tenets of Islam and his correction of the tradition</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. Uner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g663v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg13t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Scholars, Muslim -- Indonesia -- Biography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islamic renewal -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Khalil, Moenawar</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870x528"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic mapping of restorer genes for cytoplasmic male sterility in Brassica napus using DNA markers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jean, Martine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>DNA markers tightly-linked to nuclear fertility restorer genes for cytoplasmic male sterility (CMS) are valuable tools for breeders and researchers working with these genes. Two different targeting approaches were used to identify markers linked to the Rfp1 restorer gene for the pol CMS of canola (Brassica napus L.): nearly isogenic line (NIL) comparison and bulked segregant analysis. These methods were equally efficient in identifying markers linked to Rfp1; combining them allowed a targeting efficiency of 100% to be achieved. The efficiency of bulked segregant analysis was found to be limited by the inadvertent occurrence of shared homozygosity at specific chromosomal regions in the bulks, in contrast with the efficiency of NIL comparison which was limited by the occurrence of residual DNA from the donor cultivar at scattered sites around the genome of the NILs. Eleven DNA markers linked to the Rfp1 gene were identified, one of which perfectly co-segregates with Rfp1. The linkage group on which Rfp1 is localized contains 17 DNA markers. Two restorer genes of the pol CMS, Rfp1 and Rfp2, and a Rfn restorer gene of the nap CMS were found to be at least tightly linked to one another and may all reside at the same locus. A fourth restorer gene, the Rfo restorer for the ogu CMS, was, however, found to be unlinked to the other restorer genes. Different restorer genes for the nap CMS were found in the lines 'Westar-Rf and 'Karat'. A linkage map of the B. napus genome containing 146 markers organized into 23 linkage groups covering a total length of 850.2 cM was constructed from a BC$ sb1$ population. This map contains 63 loci previously localized on the B. napus genome through analysis of an F$ sb2$ population. Comparative analysis indicates that the total length of the BC$ sb1$-derived map is smaller than that of the F$ sb2$-derived map, which suggests that a reduction in recombination frequency is occurring in male gametes. The preferential use of two or three probe-</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brown, G. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm57s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x528</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cytoplasmic male sterility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rape (Plant) -- Genome mapping</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rape (Plant) -- Cytogenetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v7069"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Low prejudiced people, their ideals, and outgroup overcompensation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kafka, Pauline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The behavior and subsequent affect of people low in prejudice were examined in four experiments. In Study 1, 52 people evaluated two targets differing primarily in sexual orientation and then completed mood and prejudice measures. Although people high in prejudice discriminated against a homosexual target, people low and moderate in prejudice favored this target. In Study 2, 57 people were given target intellectual ability information designed to either challenge or not challenge any propensity towards the outgroup favoritism observed in Study 1. Specifically, study participants evaluated either a more qualified homosexual and a less qualified heterosexual (not challenging outgroup favoritism) or a less qualified homosexual and a more qualified heterosexual (challenging outgroup favoritism). Although low prejudiced people favored the homosexual target when he was better qualified, they were unwilling to make this same distinction when the heterosexual target was more qualified. Study 3 was designed to understand if such overcompensation results from a need to restore social justice. Study participants (n = 77) were made to believe their peers were either discriminatory, overcompensatory, or neutral towards a minority member. As expected for low prejudiced people, only by making them believe their peers overcompensate a minority group member, thereby eliminating any extant need to restore social justice, was outgroup favoritism eliminated. Finally, Study 4 assessed the extent to which the low prejudiced person's tendency to overcompensate a minority member rests on a well-internalized system of beliefs. Following a (mortality salience) manipulation designed either to engage or not engage the internalized belief system, 35 low prejudiced people completed the same procedure employed in Study 1. Results revealed increased overcompensation of a homosexual for participants whose internalized beliefs were engaged. Further, in all four studies, participants failed to man</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lydon, John E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d5837.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7069</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Heterosexism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reverse discrimination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prejudices</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wp42s"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spectroscopic methods for the characterization of thin films of polymer-derived ceramics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Scarlete, Mihai</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Poly(methylsilane) (PMS) has been used as a precursor to form a variety of ceramic materials within the Si-C-N system. Special emphasis was placed on the synthesis of SiC, $ rm Si sb3N sb4$ and derived tertiary ceramic materials for use in semiconductor applications, mainly as thin films coated onto various substrates. Detailed insight into the chemical transformations occurring during pyrolysis under inert (N$ sb2$, Ar) or reactive (NH$ sb3$) atmospheres was achieved by analysis of the layers coated on silicon single-crystal wafers. The oxidation of PMS and its transformation during pyrolysis into SiC were monitored by IR reflectance and transmission spectroscopy. The degree of the oxidation of PMS is not only a critical factor in determining the electronic properties of the final resulting materials, but is also a key factor in determining the pyrolysis mechanism. An important observation was the low-temperature ($ sim$200$ sp circ$C) Kumada rearrangement of the PMS to poly(cabosilane) (PCS). This reaction was evident at 200$ sp circ$C on silicon substrates, when the oxygen concentration in PMS was below 40 parts per million (ppm). Ultrathin layers of amorphous SiC (a-SiC) with thicknesses of $ sim$100 nm were obtained by deposition of the volatile species resulting from the thermal cracking of the precursor. The cracked-polymer vapor deposition (CP-VD) method allowed the synthesis of smooth (mirror-like) ceramic layers. The layers obtained by both CP-VD and spin-coating procedures exhibited resistivities in the range of $10 sp3-10 sp6 Omega$ cm and good adhesion properties onto the silicon substrates. n-type SiC layers doped with nitrogen having a resistivity range suitable for Si/SiC heterojunctions in solar cells were also synthesized on silicon single-crystal wafers. A homogeneous doping procedure was developed that consists of reacting the Wurtz PMS prepolymer with NH$ sb3$ to form a "doping polymer". Partial pressure of NH$ sb3$ can enhance the rate of deposition of ceramics on cold substrates. In this case, CP-VD appears to combine some advantages of the two currently used procedures for growing thin films--i.e., a high deposition rate characteristic of pyrolysis of spin-coated films of precursors and good texture of the layers, characteristic of the chemical vapor deposition process (CVD). The inclusion of higher concentrations of nitrogen into the ceramic material was studied during the synthesis of $ rm Si sb3N sb4$ by pyrolysis of PMS under pure NH$ sb3$. The analysis of the intermediate products resulting from the reaction of the precursor with NH$ sb3$ revealed that carbon loss occurred at temperatures below 600$ sp circ$C, and involves poly(carbosilazane) species. The stoichiometric 4:3 atomic ratio of N to Si is achieved below 500$ sp circ$C. A reaction path way is proposed in which only heterodehydrocoupling between Si-H and N-H groups occurs. This pathway is sufficient to explain the incorporation of excess nitrogen (compared to $ rm Si sb3N sb4$) usually observed in the intermediate pyrolysis products. Carbon loss is not directly related to nitrogen incorporation, thus the two processes are, at least partially, independent. The effect of the thermal decomposition of NH$ sb3$, as an independent variable, on the carbon/nitrogen exchange process was studied. Deviations from thermodynamic equilibrium were related to dynamic conditions characterizing the flow regime.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Butler, I. S.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Harrod, J. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333389g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp42s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26z002b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Methane metabolism and nitrogen cycling in freshwater sediment of a polluted ecosystem : Hamilton Harbour (Canada)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roy, Réal, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Environmental regulation of nitrogen cycling processes, denitrification and nitrification, was studied in sediment of Hamilton Harbour, with particular emphasis on the role of CH$ sb4$ metabolism (production and consumption). Through extensive sediment sampling and numerical analysis, it was found that particulate carbon was the best predictor of potential for anaerobic production of CH$ sb4$ and CO$ sb2$. The only predictor of denitrification capacity was anaerobic CO$ sb2$ production, indicating that beside NO$ sb3 sp-$ and O$ sb2$, a biotic factor involved in carbon metabolism may be important in the control of this activity. Suppression of aerobic N$ sb2$O production in sediment slurries by C$ rm sb2H sb2$ and correlation with NO$ sb3$-production indicated that it was dependent on chemolithotrophic nitrification. Although CH$ sb4$ (1 to 24 $ mu$M) stimulated production of NO$ sb3 sp-$ and N$ sb2$O, we found that CH$ sb4$ at 84 $ mu$M or greater suppressed nitrification. Following extensive studies of pore water chemistry, potential microbial activities, and counts of nitrifiers and methanotrophs, we found that CH$ sb4$ oxidation (i) is more likely to suppress nitrification by competition for O$ sb2$ and NH$ sb4 sp+$ between methanotrophs and nitrifiers, and (ii) may be more important than nitrification as a sink of hypolimnetic O$ sb2$ in Hamilton Harbour. Amongst a number of inhibitors, allylsulfide was found to be a differential inhibitor with much less effect on CH$ sb4$ oxidation in sediment slurries or in axenic cultures of Methylosinus trichosporium OB3b than on nitrification in sediment slurries.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Knowles, Roger</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t11s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z002b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Harbors -- Ontario -- Hamilton</dc:subject><dc:subject>Methane -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitrogen cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microbial metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lake sediments -- Ontario, Lake (N.Y. and Ont.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lake sediments -- Ontario -- Hamilton Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tb00d"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regional development and fertility in Indonesia, 1980-1990</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sarjono, Jono</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Based on data from the 1990 Indonesian Census and the 1991 Demographic and Health Survey, analyses of fertility, fertility decline, and the use of contraceptive methods in Indonesia are presented. Two levels of analysis are carried out in this thesis: a macro-approach and a micro-approach. The analysis using the macro approach reveals that the family planning program, the status of women's jobs, and infant mortality rates are important determinants of fertility in Indonesia. In addition, the micro analysis shows that there are differences in the average number of children ever-born to couples according to the type of present and childhood residence, educational attainment, religion and occupational status. Controlling for regional population density reversed the direction of the impact of agriculture sector employment on fertility. Overall in Indonesia, individual couples who worked in agriculture sector had higher fertility than those who worked in the non agriculture sector. However, in the densely populated areas of the country such as Java and Bali, those who worked in the agriculture sector had lower fertility than those who worked in the non agriculture sector. The results of this dissertation support the claim that fertility and fertility decline are very complex phenomena. There is no definitive set of variables that strongly and consistently affect them. The most important finding from these analyses is that the fertility rate is influenced both by individual couple's characteristics as well as the place where they live. Further research on fertility and fertility decline should emphasize both of these characteristics.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Masi, Anthony C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd764.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb00d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Birth control -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indonesia -- Population</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fertility, Human -- Indonesia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4j03d143q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Catholic Church's reaction to the secularization of nationalism in Quebec, 1960-1980</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seljak, David, 1958-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The political modernization of Quebec in the 1960s meant that the close identification of French Canadian identity with the Roman Catholic faith was replaced by a new secular nationalism. Using David Martin's A General Theory of Secularization, I examine the reaction of the Catholic Church to its own loss of power and to the rise of this new secular nationalism. Conservative Catholics first condemned the new nationalism; by 1969 some conservative accepted the new society and even supported its state interventionism. Most important Catholic groups, including the hierarchy, the most dynamic organizations, and largest publications came to accept the new society. Inspired by the religious reforms of the Second Vatican Council and new papal social teaching, they affirmed the right of Quebeckers to self-determination and social justice. The Church created a sustained ethical critique of nationalism as a means of redefining its public presence in Quebec society. The consensus around this ethical critique and redefinitions of the Church role is evident in the participation of Catholic groups in the 1980 referendum on sovereignty-association.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Gregory</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f2869.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d143q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Catholic Church -- Political activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Catholic Church -- Québec (Province) -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nationalism -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nationalism -- Religious aspects -- Catholic Church</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv9354614"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computer modeling of intergranular fracture in textured materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lu, Jian, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An integrated computer simulation employing the Embedded-atom method (EAM), Molecular dynamics (MD), and Markov Chain Fracture models has been constructed and applied to study the intergranular fracture of brittle polycrystalline materials at both the atomistic and microscopic levels. At the atomistic level, the computer model is capable of treating bicrystals under the influence of external load and temperature with dynamic periodic boundary conditions along the grain boundary plane and a dynamic boundary condition perpendicular to the grain boundary plane. At the microscopic level, the computer model is capable of treating the sample with microstructure defined by the grain boundary character distribution under the influence of an external load to predict the intergranular fracture propagation under stress. The fracture behavior of many $ Sigma$ grain boundaries has been investigated at the atomistic level for Cu, Ni, and Ni$ sb3$Al, and the fracture resistance of the grain boundary was predicted. It has been found that grain boundary energy and fracture resistance greatly depend on the grain boundary structure. Symmetrical $ Sigma$3 twin boundaries and low angle $ Sigma1$ boundaries are particularly strong in resisting intergranular fracture, while some other low $ Sigma$ boundaries are also strong, but grain boundaries with high energies are not at all fracture resistant. The calculated correlation between fracture resistance and misorientation of grain boundaries is in accordance with the experimental data. The calculated fracture resistances of the grain boundaries for Ni$ sb3$Al alloy are not significantly different from those for pure Ni. This suggests that the tendency to intergranular fracture is not due merely to the poor fracture resistance of grain boundaries. One must also consider the overall grain boundary character distribution. In order to find the role of grain boundary character distribution on the intergranular fracture in brittle polycrystalline materials, the crack path, crack arrest distance, and fracture toughness have been investigated at the microscopic level with the different fraction of low-energy grain boundaries, grain boundary fracture resistance, orientation distribution of grain boundary planes, and grain shape factor. The simulations have indicated that with an increase in the fraction of low energy grain boundaries, the fracture toughness increases while the crack arrest distance decreases. With an increase in the number of low energy grain boundaries which are aligned parallel to the stress axis, one observes an increase in the fracture toughness and a decrease in the crack arrest distance. By increasing the grain shape factor, the fracture toughness decreases while the crack arrest distance increases. If five grain diameter is defined as the critical length, and more than 25% of grain boundaries are of low-energy with the highest fracture resistance, such as $ Sigma$3 twin grain boundaries, the intergranular crack formed initially cannot propagate further due to the presence of fewer random boundaries, and the polycrystalline materials will show high ductility. The improvement in fracture toughness of Ni$ sb3$Al brittle polycrystal is due to the introduction of a high frequency of low energy grain boundaries (up to 70% by experimental treatments). Grain boundary design and control achieved by manipulating the grain boundary character distribution (GBCD) are important to fracture toughness improvement of the brittle polycrystal materials.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns497.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9354614</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870x53j"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Degradation processes and related reliability models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lu, Jin, 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Reliability characteristics of new devices are usually demonstrated by life testing. When lifetime data are sparse, as is often the case with highly reliable devices, expensive devices, and devices for which accelerated life testing is not feasible, reliability models that are based on a combination of degradation and lifetime data represent an important practical approach. This thesis presents reliability models based on the combination of degradation and lifetime data or degradation data alone, with and without the presence of covariates. Statistical inference methods associated with the models are also developed. The degradation process is assumed to follow a Wiener process. Failure is defined as the first passage of this process to a fixed barrier. The degradation data of a surviving item are described by a truncated Wiener process and lifetimes follow an inverse Gaussian distribution. Models are developed for three types of data structures that are often encountered in reliability studies, terminal point data (a combination of degradation and lifetime data) and mixed data (an extended case of terminal point data); conditional degradation data; and covariate data. Maximum likelihood estimators (MLEs) are derived for the parameters of each model. Inferences about the parameters are based on asymptotic properties of the MLEs and on the likelihood ratio method. An analysis of deviance is presented and approximate pivotal quantities are derived for the drift and variance parameters. Predictive density functions for the lifetime and the future degradation level of either a surviving item or a new item are obtained using empirical Bayes methods. Case examples are given to illustrate the applications of the models.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Whitmore, G. Alex</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v707k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x53j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Failure time data analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reliability (Engineering) -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>