<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vm06g"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The use of dextran to reduce to platelet retention in extracorporeal shunts containing semipermeable microcapsules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Watson, William J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dextran is a polymer of glucose known to possess several properties which may be desirable in extracorporeal circuits such as oxygenators and standard hemodialysis machines. However, the feasibility of using dextran to decrease platelet retention in the extracorporeal micro capsule shunt system has not been previously examined, and this is the subject of this thesis. In vitro, experiments demonstrated that dextran 70 was effective in decreasing platelet retention after 100 minutes exposure of blood to collodion microcapsules. In vivo studies, in which dogs were hemoperfused with extracorporeal shunts containing CAC microcapsules, showed that dextran 70, infused 1 - 2 hours prior to shunt connection as well as priming the shunt with dextran 70, caused a significant decrease in platelet retention when compared to similar experiments using saline. A modified platelet retention test further showed that either priming the test apparatus with dextran 70 or a prior infusion of dextran 70 caused decreases in platelet retention. The results support the proposal that dextran 70 can be used in extracorporeal microcapsule shunt systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chang, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc348.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm06g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>