<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g802z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The paradox of the retinoic acid receptor beta 2 in cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pappas, Jane Joanna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction. Recent lines of evidence suggest that retinoids1,2  and RARbeta23 may have both beneficial and harmful effects in cancer. Little is  known regarding the specifics of RARbeta2 promoter silencing in cancer, or about the  role that RARbeta2 plays in RARbeta2-expressing cancer cells. Objectives. To analyze  the patterns and heritability of RARbeta2 promoter methylation in cancer and  determine whether it is subject to allelic bias; and to analyze the effects of  RARbeta2 knockdown on growth and mRNA expression profiles in cancer. Methods.  RARbeta2 promoter methylation was analyzed in 20 parental cancer cell lines and 5  subcloned lines using bisulfate genomic sequencing (&gt;150 sequencings); the  proportion of methylated alleles was estimated using methylation-sensitive  restriction enzyme digestion followed by PCR and single nucleotide polymorphism  identification; 18 antisense oligonucleotides against RARbeta2 were tested in  various cancer cell lines using RT-PCR, cell counting and annexin V staining; and  gene expression profiles were compared following knockdown versus all trans retinoic  acid (ATRA) stimulation using cDNA microarray technology (&gt;14,000 genes), SOURCE  and GOMINER databases. Results. Hypo- and hypermethylated alleles frequently  co-exist in lines in which RARbeta2 is inactivated (5111, 45%); divergent  methylation is heritable in the majority of subclones analyzed (618, 75%); and  methylation is subject to allelic bias at a ratio of ~2:1 (3l3 CpG sites,  100%). Cellular proliferation is correlated with RARbeta2 expression levels  (p=0.0003); the most effective oligo reduces cellular proliferation by up to 80% in  cancer cell lines in which RARbeta2 expression has been retained (313, 100%), but  has no apparent effects in lines in which it has been lost (313, 100%); reduction in  cell growth following oligo treatment is at least partially due to activation of  programmed cell death; and over a dozen pro-carcinogenesis genes are downregulated following RAR132 knockdown, whereas half are upregulated following ATRA stimulation. CONCLUSIONS: This work is the first to report the co-existence and heritability of hypo- and hypermethylated allelic copies of a gene completely inactivated in cancer; that hypermethylation in cancer is subject to allelic bias; that a promoter methylation-independent cis-acting silencing mechanism is involved in RAR132 inactivation; and that RAR132 expression may be necessary for growth and oncogenic phenotype of certain RARl32-expressing cancer cells. These findings help explain the paradoxical effects of retinoids and RAR132 in cancer.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>INTRODUCTION: Des études récentes suggèrent que les rétinoïdes 1,2 et RAR1323 ont des effets à la fois bénéfiques et néfastes dans le cancer. Peu est connu vis-à-vis des mécanismes d'inactivation du promoteur de RAR132 dans le cancer, et vis-à-vis du rôle de RAR132 dans les cellules cancéreuses ayant gardé l'expression de RARI32. OBJECTIFS: Analyser les patrons de méthylation du promoteur de RAR132 et leur transmission mitotique; déterminer si cette méthylation est affectée par un biais allélique; et analyser les effets de la diminution de l'expression de RAR132 sur la croissance et le profil d'expression ARNm dans le cancer. MÉTHODES: Le patron de méthylation du promoteur de RAR132 a été analysé dans 20 lignées cellulaires cancéreuses parentales et 5 lignées sous-clonées utilisant le séquençage génomique aux bisulfites (&gt;150 séquençages); la proportion d'allèles méthylés a été estimée utilisant la digestion par enzymes sensibles à la méthylation suivie par PCR et identification par polymorphisme nucléotidique simple. 18 oligonucléotides antisens contre RAR132 ont été testés utilisant le RT-PCR, le décompte cellulaire et la coloration contre l'annexine V; et les profils d'expression suivant l'inhibition de RAR132 versus la stimulation par l'acide rétinoïque all-trans (ATRA) ont étés comparés par la technologie des biopuces ADNe (&gt;14 000 gènes), et les bases de données SOURCE et GOMINER. RÉSULTATS: Des allèles hypo- et hyperméthylés co-existent fréquemment dans les lignées inactivées (5/11, 45 %) ; cette divergence de méthylation est conservée dans la majorité des sous-clones analysés (6/8, 75 %); et cette divergence reflète une préférence allélique -2:1 (3/3 sites, 100 %). La prolifération est corrélée avec l'expression de RARf32 (p=0.0003); l'oligonucléotide le plus puissant réduit la prolifération cellulaire jusqu'a 80 % dans les lignées cellulaires exprimant RAR132 (3/3, 100 %), mais n'a aucun effet apparent dans les lignées inactivées (3/3, 100 %) ; l'expression d'une douzaine de gènes impliqués positivement dans la carcinogenèse est diminuée suite au traitement par l'oligonucléotide antisens, tandis que l'expression de la moitié de ceux-çi est augmentée suite à la stimulation par A TRA. CONCLUSIONS: Ces études sont les premières à documenter la co-existence et la transmission d'allèles hypo- et hyperméthylés d'un gène complètement inactivé dans le cancer; que l'hyperméthylation dans le cancer est influencée par une préférence allélique ; qu'un nouveau mécanisme d'inactivation indépendant de la méthylation et agissant en cis est impliqué dans la répression de RARf32 ; et que le potentiel d'expression de RAR132 est nécessaire pour la croissance ainsi que le phénotype oncogénique de certains cancers. Ces découvertes offrent quelques explications sur pourquoi les effets des rétinoïdes et de RAR132 dans le cancer sont si paradoxaux. </dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w35d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g802z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z574s"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biological, psychological and gambling variables associated with problem gambling: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aulakh, Harjit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude en IRMf  l'activité cérébrale chez des patients souffrant de jeu pathologique, en simulant pour la première fois par ordinateur  un authentique jeu de pari. Le but de cette étude était  de mesurer  les différences potentielles d'activité cérébrale liées à des facteurs tel que les états d'humeur, les connaissances du jeu, le comportement, les traits de personnalité, entre un groupe d'homme souffrant d'un trouble de jeu pathologique (JP) et un groupe contrôle.  Les 14 JP étaient principalement des joueurs de cartes, satisfaisants  le critère DSM-IV-TR de Jeu Pathologique. Le groupe contrôle évalué et recruté pour cette étude était constitué de 15 participants, ne jouant que rarement  aux cartes. Les caractères de personnalité ont été évalués avec l'Inventaire Arnett de Recherche de Sensations Fortes (AISS),  le Questionnaire de Personnalité Tridimensionnel (TPQ) et la version longue de la Mesure de Troubles D'attention et D'hyperactivité Conners (CAARS). Les auto-évaluations de connaissances ont été recueillies avant, pendant et après la tâche expérimentale. Les joueurs pathologiques ont  présenté une amélioration de leur état d'humeur, une plus grande envie de parier, une plus grande croyance en la chance et en son contrôle, étaient les plus  ardents chercheurs de sensations fortes, étaient plus impulsifs et avaient moins tendance à parier rationnellement et à utiliser l'information disponible concernant le risque. Les résultats de neuro-imagerie ont révélé un pattern complexe d'activités en réponse aux différents aspects de la tâche de pari. Bien que les groupes n'aient présenté aucune différence au niveau du Striatum, des différences générales de groupe ont  émergé au niveau du cortex préfrontal médial et dorsolatéral, du noyau sous-thalamique, de l'insula, du cervelet, du noyau lentiforme et du cortex pariétal postérieur. Ces différences sont localisées dans les régions connues$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract> This study investigates brain activity in male pathological gamblers (card gamblers) while gambling using a unique computerized card gambling paradigm that emulates actual gambling.  The current study endeavored to concurrently explore group differences on factors such as mood states, cognitions, gambling behaviours, personality traits, and neural activity between a subset of pathological gamblers and control participants.   A group of 14 predominately card playing male gamblers who met the DSM-IV-TR criteria for Pathological Gambling disorder and 15 infrequent or non-gambling control participants were screened and recruited.  Personality characteristics were measured using the Arnett Inventory of Sensation Seeking (AISS), Tridimensional Personality Questionnaire (TPQ) and Conners' Adult Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder Rating Scale-Long version (CAARS-L), while self-report mood and cognition questions were completed before, during, and after the gambling task.  Pathological gamblers had significant increases in positive mood, urges to gamble, more irrational beliefs around luck and control, were more novelty-seeking and impulsive and were less likely to bet rationally using the information around risk presented at the time.  The neurological findings revealed a complex interplay of activity in response to different aspects of the gambling task.   Groups did not differ in regions of the striatum; however, overall group differences emerged in the medial and dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, subthalamic nucleus, insula, cerebellum, lentiform nucleus, and the posterior parietal cortex.   Differences occurred in regions of the brain involved in conscious awareness of urges, decision-making in uncertain or risky situations, learning, as well as minimizing losses and ensuring future avoidance of penalties.  The group differences that emerged across these factors suggest an intricate interplay of each of these variables in their contribution to the maintenance of</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jeffrey L. Derevensky</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rina Gupta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tv522.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z574s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Psychobiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62f865n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Artificial intelligence analysis of hyperspectral remote sensing data for management of water, weed, and nitrogen stresses in corn fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waheed, Tahir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated the possibility of using ground-based  remotely sensed hyperspectral observations with a special emphasis on detection of  water, weed and nitrogen stresses contributing towards in-season decision support  for precision crop management (PCM). A three factor split-split-plot experiment, with four randomized  blocks as replicates, was established during the growing seasons of 2003 and 2004.  Corn (Zea mays L.) hybrid DKC42-22 was grown because this hybrid is a good performer  on light soils in Quebec. There were twelve 12 x 12m plots in a block (one  replication per treatment per block) and the total number of plots was 48. Water  stress was the main factor in the experiment. A drip irrigation system was laid out  and each block was split into irrigated and non-irrigated halves. The second main  factor of the experiment was weeds with two levels i.e. full weed control and no  weed control. Weed treatments were assigned randomly by further splitting the  irrigated and non-irrigated sub-blocks into two halves. Each of the weed treatments  was furthermore split into three equal sub-sub-plots for nitrogen treatments (third  factor of the experiment). Nitrogen was applied at three levels i.e. 50, 150 and 250  kg N ha-1 (Quebec norm is between 120-160 kg N ha-1). The hyperspectral data were recorded (spectral resolution = 1  nm) mid-day (between 1000 and 1400 hours) with a FieldSpec FR spectroradiometer over  a spectral range of 400-2500 run at three growth stages namely: early growth,  tasseling and full maturity, in each of the growing season. There are two major original contributions in this thesis: First  is the development of a hyperspectral data analysis procedure for separating visible  (400-700 nm), near-infrared (700-1300 nm) and mid-infrared (1300-2500 nm) regions of  the spectrum for use in discriminant analysis procedure. In addition, of all the  spectral band-widths analyzed, seven waveband-aggregates were identified using  STEPDISC procedure, which were the most effective for classifying combined water,  weed, and nitrogen stress. The second contribution is the successful classification  of hyperspectral observations acquired over an agricultural field, using three  innovative artificial intelligence approaches; support vector machines (SVM),  genetic algorithms (GA) and decision tree (DT) algorithms. These AI approaches were  used to evaluate a combined effect of water, weed and nitrogen stresses in corn and  of all the three AI approaches used, SVM produced the best results (overall accuracy  ranging from 88% to 100%). The general conclusion is that the conventional statistical and  artificial intelligence techniques used in this study are all useful for quickly  mapping combined affects of irrigation, weed and nitrogen stresses (with overall  accuracies ranging from 76% to 100%). These approaches have strong potential and are  of great benefit to those investigating the in-season impact of irrigation, weed and  nitrogen management for corn crop production and other environment related  challenges.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg765.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f865n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Corn -- Effect of stress on -- Québec (Province) -- Remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Artificial intelligence -- Agricultural applications -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multispectral photography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Precision farming -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b171q"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>What we have yet failed to achieve: a study of Charles Taylor's Canadian social criticism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gibson, Andrew John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire examine ce que l'auteur dénomme la composante « critique sociale canadienne » de l'oeuvre du philosophe Charles Taylor. Érudit à la renommée internationale, les travaux de Taylor ont maintes fois été commentés. Cependant, l'attention portée à son oeuvre présente un déséquilibre entre les nombreux commentaires relatifs à ses pensées philosophiques plus abstraites, d'une part, et ceux, rares, concernant les aspects de ses écrits porteurs d'un intérêt pratique plus immédiat, c'est-à-dire ses travaux relevant de la critique sociale. Après avoir introduit un cadre de base à la « critique sociale interprétative », cette thèse s'attache ensuite à situer les différents aspects de la critique de Taylor dans le contexte de certains débats contemporains sur des sujets tels que le déclin démocratique, le consumérisme, l'unité nationale ou les politiques égalitaristes. Tout d'abord, chacun des différents chapitres se penche sur un aspect de la culture public commune canadienne et l'analyse. Cependant, l'objectif central recherché par l'intégration de ces chapitres dans un même programme de recherche est de nous permettre d'identifier la manière selon laquelle notre identité politique et culturelle encore incomplète pourrait le mieux être atteinte. Le présupposé directeur de cette recherche est que cela requerrait d'avoir foi tant dans la tradition sociale démocrate de notre pays que dans son potentiel unique de concilier sa diversité ethnoculturelle, régionale et linguistique. Les travaux de Charles Taylor, tels qu'interprétés dans les chapitres qui suivent, nous aident à démontrer ce que cela signifie dans le contexte de questions et débats spécifiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines what the author calls the Canadian social criticism component of the work of philosopher Charles Taylor. An internationally renowned scholar, Taylor's work has been much commented on. Yet there is an imbalance of attention in the reception of his work between the ample commentary pertaining to his more abstract philosophical thought, on the one hand, and the paucity of commentary concerning those aspects of his writing that carry more immediate practical relevance, i.e. his work in social criticism. After introducing a basic framework for 'interpretive social criticism', the dissertation proceeds to situate different aspects of Taylor's criticism within contemporary debates, including the topic areas of democratic decline, consumerism, national unity and egalitarian politics. At one level, each of the different chapters engages with and elaborates on a facet of Canada's common public culture. Yet the central objective in bringing them together in a single program of research is to contribute to our understanding of how this still incomplete culture and political identity can best be achieved. The guiding assumption behind the research is that this would require being faithful at once to the country's social democratic tradition and to its unique potential in reconciling ethnocultural, regional and linguistic diversity. The work of Charles Taylor, as interpreted in the following chapters, helps to demonstrate what this means in the context of specific issues and debates.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barney, Darin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zd97f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b171q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83kz78q"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On vortical and wave motion in stratified turbulence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Waite, Michael L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The dynamics of the atmospheric mesoscale and oceanic  submesoscale are characterized by strong stratification and weak rotation, and the  resulting energy spectra, though surprisingly universal, are still poorly  understood. The aim of this work is to study the nonlinear dynamics and interactions  of vortical motion (with potential vorticity) and internal inertia-gravity waves in  the idealized context of homogeneous stratified turbulence, and to examine the  extent to which they can account for the observations. We consider separately turbulence generated by vortical motion  and internal waves using a combination of theory and numerical simulations. When  vortical motion dominates the flow, the statistical mechanical equilibrium of the  Boussinesq equations points to the absence of an inverse cascade of vortical energy.  Instead, energy leaks into waves and cascades downscale. Our simulations show that  the kz spectrum of vortical energy is flat out to kz ~ N/U (where N is the  Brunt-Vaisala frequency and U is the root mean square velocity), which is consistent  with the asymptotic limiting equations but not with the observations. Steeper  spectra are obtained when waves are forced, but they are nevertheless shallower than  the observations. At sufficiently strong stratifications, the wave energy spectra  are found to be sensitive to the resolution of wave breaking and the presence of  vortical motion. Bumpy spectra are obtained when no breaking occurs, but  interactions with vortical modes cause the bumps to disappear. Overall, these  results indicate that the observed atmosphere and ocean energy spectra are not  universal properties of stratified turbulence, and theories for the spectra must  take other factors into account. In both the vortical and wave-dominated cases, U/N emerges as a  key vertical length scale. Overturning is generated only when U/N is larger than the  dissipation scale. Furthermore, in the vortical case, it is the scale at which  different layers are coupled together. When rotation is introduced, the coupling  scale evolves from U/N to the quasi-geostrophic scale (f/N)L (where f is the  Coriolis parameter and L is the horizontal scale). This transition occurs at a  relatively large Rossby number of O(1).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x729.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83kz78q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537169x"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aspects of braneworld cosmology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vinet, Jérémie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>What is essential is invisible to the eye. Antoine de  Saint-Exupery Of course, Saint-Exupery didn't have extra dimensions in mind  when he wrote this famous line. Nevertheless, the recent realisation that standard  model degrees of freedom can naturally be restricted to a submanifold embedded in a  higher dimensional Universe means that an ingredient essential to our description of  nature might quite literally be "invisible to the eye". Exploring the consequences of such braneworld scenarios has  occupied a large part of the theoretical physics community over the last seven  years, and this thesis is a collection of contributions to this  endeavour. After reviewing the motivations for and early successes of  braneworld scenarios, we examine rho2 corrections to the Hubble rate in the  stabilized Randall-Sundrum I model, where the hierarchy problem is solved in a  natural way, in order to ascertain whether such corrections might be of help in  addressing some issues with inflation and baryogenesis. The three following chapters  are concerned with six-dimensional models that have been advertised as possibly  leading to a self-tuning solution to the cosmological constant problem. We examine  this claim thoroughly, through the study of thick codimension-two braneworlds. This  allows us to provide a generalization of the relationship between the deficit angle  and the brane matter content. We also present the first derivation of the Friedmann  equations on a codimension-two brane containing matter with an arbitrary equation of  state, first in the context of Einstein-Hilbert gravity and then in six dimensional  supergravity.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f1617.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537169x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Theory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k773g"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Seeing music : integrating vision and hearing in the perception of musical performances</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vines, Bradley W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates cross-modal interactions in auditory  and visual perception, focusing on the perception of expressive musical  performances. A primary aim of the work is to advance knowledge pertaining to how  and when musicians' body movements influence an observer's overall experience. Three  studies, comprising two multi-factor experimental investigations and one theoretical  contribution, explore the multi-modal experience of musical performance. The two  empirical chapters investigate, respectively, (1) the real-time experience of  musical structure and musical emotion, comparing unimodal and multimodal conditions,  and (2) the multidimensional structure of affective responses to musical  performance, as a function of sensory modalities and performance intentions. The  theoretical chapter develops a class of quantitative models for studying real-time  phenomena in music (in particular) and time-series data (in general). An original  contribution of this thesis is to quantify the ways in which the auditory and visual  components of musical performance contribute singly and in interaction with one  another to overall experience. The studies show that seeing a musician performing  can augment, complement and interact with the auditory component to significantly  influence music perception. These results are relevant to, and inform theories on,  multi-sensory integration, emotion, and music cognition, as well as performance  practice and audio-video media.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93gz96w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k773g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music -- Performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gesture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Music -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dg21q"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Blood-brain barrier endothelial cells as regulators of immune-mediated injury and repair in the central nervous system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Biernacki, Katarzyna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The blood-brain barrier (BBB) is a specialized structure that  restricts the passage of blood-borne cells and molecules into the central nervous  system (CNS). BBB dysfunction and extensive perivascular leukocytic infiltration are  critical events for lesion formation in multiple sclerosis (MS). To examine the mechanisms that regulate the migration of immune  cells that participate in CNS injury and/or repair, I have used human adult  brain-derived endothelial cells (HBECs) grown in Boyden chambers. I compared the  migration of Th1 lymphocytes, disease-inducing cells, and Th2 lymphocytes, cells  induced by several immuno-modulatory therapies aimed at reducing neuroinflammation,  across an in vitro model of the BBB. I demonstrate that Th2 cells can efficiently  cross the BBB, and do so at significantly higher rates compared to Th1 lymphocytes.  This selectivity is dependent on HBEC chemokine CCL2, and the selective expression  of the receptor CCR2 on Th2 cells. Adhesion molecules are not implicated in  selective T cell recruitment, although migration of both subsets can be blocked with  anti-ICAM-1 antibody. I also explored the consequences of T cell:HBEC interactions  on HBEC properties. I show that supernatants derived from Th1 polarized cells  significantly up-regulate a range of pro-inflammatory chemokines and adhesion  molecules in HBECs. Conversely, Th2 supernatants had no such effects and did not  suppress the effects induced by Thl lymphocytes. Together, this suggests that Th2  cell-mediated bystander suppression does not occur at the level of the BBB. I also  show that Th1 and Th2 cell migration can enhance subsequent passage of cells and  molecules across HBEC barriers. Furthermore, I demonstrate that lymphocyte contact  induced HBEC production of the neurotrophin NGF but not BDNF, an effect potentiated  by IFNbeta. The secretion of NGF was specific to HBECs; neither astrocytes nor  microglia could be induced to secrete this neurotrophin. I also demonstrate an  inverse correlation between HBEC NGF production induced by MS patient lymphocytes  and measures of clinical disability and brain atrophy suggesting that HBECs may have  a neuroprotective role in MS. Collectively, my data indicate that the BBB is a dynamic structure involved in the regulation of immune responses and promotion of repair mechanisms within the CNS.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La barrière hémato-encéphalique (BHE) est une structure spécialisée qui restreint le passage des cellules sanguines et des molécules vers le parenchyme cérébral. L'accumulation péri vasculaire de leucocytes au sein du système nerveux central (SNC) et le dysfonctionnement de la BHE sont deux phénomènes caractéristiques qui accompagnent la formation des lésions observées chez les patients atteints de sclérose en plaques (SEP). Dans le but d'examiner les mécanismes que régulent la migration des cellules immunitaires dans le SNC, j'ai utilisé un modèle in vitro recréant plusieurs des caractéristiques de la BHE. Il s'agit de chambres de Boyden dans lesquelles des cellules endothéliales cérébrales humaines (CECHs) sont cultivées sur une membrane perméable. J'ai comparé la migration des lymphocytes Thl avec celle des lymphocytes Th2. J'ai démontré que les lymphocytes Th2 migrent en plus grand nombre que les lymphocytes Thl à travers les HBECs. Cette sélectivité dans la migration repose sur la sécrétion de la chimiokine CCL2IMCP-I par les HBECs, et de l'expression des récepteurs CCR2 sur les lymphocytes Th2. J'ai aussi démontré que la migration des lymphocytes Thl et Th2 dépend de la molécule d'adhésion ICAM-I mais que celle-ci ne pouvait expliquer les différences de migration entre les lymphocytes Thl et Th2. J'ai étudié les propriétés de l'endothélium cérébral suite à l'application des médiateurs solubles des cellules T helper pour déterminer l'effet des facteurs pro- et anti-inflammatoires sur la BHE. J'ai observé que les surnageants des cellules Th 1 induisent l'expression et la sécrétion de nombreuses chimiokines et des molécules d'adhésion par les HBECs. Les surnageants des cellules Th2 n'ont pas eu de tels effets, et n'ont pas permis de supprimer l'activation endothéliale induite par les Thl. Mes résultats suggèrent que la BHE n'est pas susceptible à la suppression antiinflammatoire par les cytokines produites par les cellules Th2. J'ai par la suite tenté de déterminer si les cellules endothéliales de la BHE pouvaient être une source de molécules protectrices telle NGF. Mes résultats démontrent que la production de NGF, mais pas de BDNF, par l'endothélium cérébral est induite par l'interaction avec les lymphocytes, un effet qui est augmenté par l'IFN,6. J'ai aussi démontré une corrélation inverse entre la production de NGF par les CECHs induite par des lymphocytes isolés de patients atteints de SEP, et le degré de leur handicap et leur niveau d'atrophie cérébrale suggérant que les cellules endothéliales de la BHE étaient impliquées dans les mécanismes de neuroprotection en SEP. Globalement, mes résultats indiquent que la BHE est une structure impliquée dans l'immunité cérébrale. La BHE participe aussi à promouvoir les mécanismes de neuroprotection en SEP. </dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161664s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dg21q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214p55j"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Jewish Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>With friends like these : turning points in the Jewish exegesis of the biblical book of Job</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kalman, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines Jewish exegesis of the book of Job to  two ends. First, it explores four topics previous generations of scholars left  unstudied or incompletely examined. Second, it uses the results of these studies to  describe the history of the Jewish tradition of Job exegesis from the period of the  Talmud until the present. Chapter 1 provides a review of the scholarly literature treating  various aspects of Job exegesis from antiquity to the post-Holocaust period and  highlights a number of issues in need of further study. Chapter 2 argues that Wertheimer's reconstruction of Midrash  Iyov, although unlikely an accurate presentation of a rabbinic original, preserves a  number of authentic rabbinic sources. In contrast to the known tradition these  preserve a laudatory view of Job that appears to have been  suppressed. Chapter 3 contextualizes the rabbinic exegesis of Job. Earlier  scholars argued that the rabbinic interpretation of Job was shaped by anti-Christian  and anti-Gentile attitudes, and that it responded to Christian exegesis. These  studies were challenged because historical evidence for this Jewish-Christian  discussion was lacking. In response to this challenge, this chapter provides  additional evidence and argues that the discussion did take place. The two  participants were the fourth century Babylonian Jewish sage Rava and his Christian  contemporary Aphrahat. A comparison of their comments on Job establishes a  relationship between the two and substantiates earlier scholarly  claims. Chapter 4 explores the relationship between the Zohar's exegesis  of Job and that of Maimonides and Nahmanides. The research concludes that the  Zohar's interpretation is a weaving of these two scholars' views and presents Job as  one who suffered because he was ignorant of mystical secrets. Chapter 5 examines the interpretation of Job in the  post-Holocaust period. It argues that in contrast to the pre-Holocaust tradition,  which blamed Job for what happened to him, post-Holocaust thinkers have not allowed  the victim to be blamed. These thinkers have preferred to challenge God rather than  Job. Concerned with the second objective of the present study,  chapter 6 provides an outline of the major trends in Jewish Job exegesis. In the  Second Temple period Job was described as a pious figure to be emulated. The  earliest rabbis maintained this view. By the late third or early fourth centuries,  Christian valorization of Job led to Jewish negation of his importance. This led to  the depiction of Job as a blasphemer deserving of divine punishment. The view of Job  as a less than innocent victim was preserved but modified in various ways in the  middle ages (by mystics, philosophers, and peshat exegetes), and was perpetuated  through the mid-twentieth century. Only the Holocaust forced a reevaluation of this  view. Job was able to have his righteousness restored in an age when interpreters  understood, by virtue of their own experiences, that the innocent could truly suffer  unjustly.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b35g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214p55j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dw04v"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Beyond child labour in Pakistan's soccer ball industry : hard times in imperial space</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khan, Farzad Rafi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Developing countries and the poor within them (i.e., the other)  receive scant attention in management and organization studies (MOS). The field,  thus, suffers from both ethnocentric and class biases. This research effort seeks to  reduce these biases, particularly in the conversation on power taking place between  MOS' critical management studies and interorganizational collaboration research  streams. Articulating a case study of the Sialkot soccer ball child  labour project in Pakistan (1995-2003), the thesis explores the communication  constraints that are faced by weak actors in interorganizational domains (a social  problem and a set of organizations having a stake or interest in that problem)  located in the developing world. Relying on both written documents (private and  public) and field interviews, especially with women soccer ball stitchers at the  village level, a typology of communication constraints is developed. These  constraints are examined from the perspectives of those at the bottom of the  international supply chain and the injuries these groups suffer from them are  documented in the thesis. It is found that the ability of weak actors to use  communication to influence a domain is highly contingent on how space and time are  configured in a domain. Domains have temporal rhythms and spatial configurations.  The thesis identifies two types of temporal rhythms (technocratic and subsistence  clocks) and a spatial configuration (imperial space) that severely militate against  weak actors exercising agency in a domain through communication. Strategies (e.g.,  emergent collective struggle) that can prevent weak actors from becoming  subalternalized (voiceless) in a domain are also discussed. The case study permits  an investigation of contemporary transnational activism that often sires  interorganizational collaboration projects in developing countries. The thesis  identifies two types of transnational activism (thick and thin), delineates the  various elements constituting them, and shows how thin activism can lead to  interorganizational projects hurting weak and powerless groups that are intended to  be assisted.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bp694.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw04v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Home labor -- Pakistan -- Sialkot District</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sporting goods industry -- Pakistan -- Sialkot District</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sialkot District (Pakistan) -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social responsibility of business -- Pakistan -- Sialkot District</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soccer -- Equipment and supplies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Child labor -- Pakistan -- Sialkot District</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57nr44n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Drawing inferences : drawing, discourse, and spatio-motor representation in an animation storyboarding activity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blatter, Janet</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A case study of collaborative storyboarding in an animation  studio grounded this investigation of visual discourse---discourse about and with  visual displays. The focus was on a problem occurring during a 40-minute task  between the head storyboard artist and his junior colleague in reviewing a rough,  conceptual storyboard. The research investigated the role of different semiotic  modalities produced by the artists', i.e., speech, gesture, and drawing, in  mediating spatial (frames of reference) and motion (action and path) representations  and inferences from the storyboard. One aim was to determine if particular  modalities were used to represent particular spatial and motion  ideas. Both qualitative discourse and quantitative analyses were  undertaken to associate the individual discourse modality in co-occurring external  representations (speech, gesture, or drawing), with spatial and motion ideas  required to understand the storyboard. The results showed that (a) most modalities  did not consistently or uniquely represent specific types of spatial and motion  ideas, (b) representations frequently demonstrated a mismatching between spoken and  gestured or drawn ideas, (c) spatial representation in particular required the  artists to represent specific goal domains as contexts that determined the frame of  reference and local sense of the representation, and (d) a more complex drawing  style was used at the beginning of the problem than in the latter solution  stages. These findings are discussed in terms of the artists' (a)  flexibility needed to traverse between 2-D and 3-D imagined worlds requiring the  representation of different spatial coordinate systems, (b) handling of the  modalities in visual discourse as supporting this flexibility, and (c) strategic use  of drawing styles to assist inferring 3-D dynamic action from an incomplete, 2-D,  static storyboard. The study demonstrates the importance of considering activity  goals and interacting semiotic modalities as contributing to the knowledge needed to  represent and infer space and motion. These findings are significant to research on  the knowledge and tools used to infer space and motion from static visual displays  in authentic collaborative design activities, and have implication for research on  technologies and environments supporting collaborative visual thinking in design  settings.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612p12k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr44n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Storyboards</dc:subject><dc:subject>Group work in art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Visual communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>Communication in design</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773w18h"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Teaching about complexity in primary and secondary schools : an exploration of new approaches to ecosystem education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Karsten, Jennifer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this research was to investigate ways in which  complexity could be used as the paradigm through which schoolchildren might  understand ecosystems in a new way. To that end, new conceptual and practical  approaches for learning about ecosystems have been presented, and the effects of  these approaches on teachers and other educational stakeholders have been explored.  A variety of learning environments were visited and over two hundred educational  stakeholders were consulted. This resulted in a number of suggestions on and a  discussion of the introduction of complexity, as a lens by which to teach about  ecosystems and as a teachable subject, within that context, to pre-university  schoolchildren. The development of the learning and teaching approaches for this  age group (primary and secondary school) involved exploring the state of ecosystem  studies as they are presently conducted, and seeking the content within the current  curricula that had congruity with the content of interest: ecosystem phenomena  related to complexity. The insights gained from that investigation led to the  creation of two types of approach, an approach to learning about ecosystems through  the lens of complexity, and an approach to teaching about ecosystems through the  lens of complexity. The Complexity Conceptual Approach deals with the various ways  of understanding, or conceptualizing, ecosystem complexity and the Complexity  Practical Approach deals with the content, technology, and methodology used for  instruction on ecosystem complexity. The two approaches can be used together as part  of a "complexity framework" that is flexible enough to be used in a  diverse variety of learning situations. Substantial consideration was given to the foreseeable prospects  for these approaches: how implementation might occur, the issues involved, and the  anticipated outcomes. Accordingly, topics of discussion include the introduction of  the conceptual and practical approaches in terms of their effects on various  educational stakeholders (such as teachers, students, parents, and administrators)  and on different levels of the educational system. This type of investigation (in  which potential impacts are considered) is, itself, reflective of the kind of  systems-thinking that the complexity approaches were established to engender in  schoolchildren.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236252c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w18h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biotic communities -- Study and teaching (Elementary)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biotic communities -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956g29n"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Commissar Order and the Seventeenth German Army : from genesis to implementation, 30 March 1941-31 January 1942</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bernheim, Robert B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An essential and critical component of the orders German  front-line formations received in the ideological war against the Soviet Union was  the Commissar Order of 6 June 1941. This order, issued by the High Command of the  Armed Forces prior to the German invasion of the Soviet Union, required that  front-line military formations, as well as SS and police units attached to the Army,  immediately execute Soviet political commissars among prisoners of war. Soviet  political commissars were attached to the Red Army at virtually every operational  level, and were viewed by both Hitler and the High Command as the foremost leaders  of the resistance against the Nazis because of their commitment to Bolshevik  ideology. According to the Commissar Order, "Commissars will not be treated as  soldiers. The protection afforded by international law to prisoners of war will not  apply in their case. After they have been segregated they will be  liquidated." While there is no paucity of information on the existence and  intent of the Commissar Order, this directive has only been investigated by scholars  as a portion of a much greater ideological portrait, or subsumed in the larger  context of overall Nazi criminal activities during "Operation  Barbarossa." Examining the extent to which front-line divisions carried out  the charge to shoot all grades of political commissars is necessary if we are to  understand the role and depth of involvement by front-line troops of the Wehrmacht  in a murderous program of extermination during the German attack and occupation of  the Soviet Union. Such an examination has simply not taken place to-date. My  dissertation seeks to address this issue. The result is both a narrative on the  genesis of the Commissar Order and its attendant decrees and agreements between the  Army leadership and the SS ( SD) and Security Police, and a quantitative analysis of  how many commissars were reported captured and shot by the front-line forces of the  17th Army over a seven month period.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pn38r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g29n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Atrocities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Germany. Heer -- History -- World War, 1939-1945</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Eastern Front</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mg01q"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three essays on the macroeconomic effects of international capital flows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kahsay, Shibeshi Ghebre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents three essays on the role of international  capital flows in growth, real exchange rate behavior and the conduct of domestic  monetary policy in four Asian economies. The first chapter develops an endogenous  growth model based on an infinitely-lived optimizing representative agent. Data from  the four Asian countries is used to test the implications of the model. Using  applied time series econometric techniques, the results for Malaysia, Philippines  and Thailand lend credence to the endogenous growth process, while it is rejected  for Indonesia. Chapter 2 develops a three-good model for the internal real exchange  rate to identify the fundamental determinants of the internal real exchange rates  for exports and imports. The examination of the time series properties of the  variables suggests that the internal real exchange rates in the ASEAN-4 countries  were indeed driven by the fundamentals derived from the model. Furthermore, the  results indicate that there was no misalignment between the actual and equilibrium  real exchange rates. Movements in the real exchange rates were thus equilibrium  responses to changes in the fundamentals. The third chapter estimates coefficients  of capital flow offset to domestic monetary policy and sterilization and analyzes  the implications for domestic monetary autonomy. The relative performance of the  monetary model and the portfolio balance model is compared using quarterly data for  the four countries. The empirical results show that the capital flow offset was less  than complete and that sterilization turned out to be ineffective in three of the  four countries.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x909f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mg01q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Capital movements -- Asia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foreign exchange rates -- Asia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Monetary policy -- Asia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278t52b"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Extracellular matrix regulates glomerular epithelial cell survival and proliferation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bijian, Krikor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Glomerular epithelial cells (GECs) are intrinsic components of  the kidney glomerulus and are in contact with extracellular matrix (ECM). Under  normal conditions, there is little turnover of GECs, but in glomerular injury,  apoptosis and proliferation of GECs, and expansion of ECM may lead to sclerosis and  impaired glomerular function and/or permselectivity. In order to better understand  how adhesion to ECM modulates GEC survival and proliferation, we monitored the  activation of the intracellular signaling pathways activated by adhesion to ECM  (collagen), along with their coordinate modulation of the growth factor signaling  pathways. Adhesion to collagen resulted in the activation of a focal adhesion kinase  (FAK)/Src/Grb2 complex, thus activating extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK),  possibly within focal adhesions. The ERK pathway was necessary to promote survival  and growth factor-dependent proliferation. ECM-induced ERK activation was also  necessary to achieve and maintain a cortical F-actin structure. There appeared to be  a reciprocal relationship between collagen-induced cortical F-actin assembly and  collagen-dependent survival signaling, including ERK activation. Moreover,  maintenance of the cortical F-actin architecture was associated with increased  turnover of inositol phospholipids. Analogous signals for GEC survival are activated  in experimental focal segmental glomerulosclerosis (FSGS) in vivo. These studies  will provide insights into novel therapeutic approaches to preserving intact  glomerular permselectivity.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c3374.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t52b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bf413"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The administration of justice : an exegesis of Max Weber's 'sociology of law' with a focus on the English law and judge</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sahni, Isher-Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines two interconnected and as yet wholly  neglected aspects of Max Weber's 'Sociology of Law,' namely, its substantive  underpinnings and focal concern with the status of the judge. At the heart of the  'Sociology of Law' is a comparative analysis of the Continental and the English  administrations of justice, which can best be understood when read against his  substantive sociology and which requires an assiduous reading of the 'Sociology of  Law.' Thus the first part of this examination elucidates Weber's overarching concern  with the effects of bureaucratization on the development of personality. The second  part provides a detailed explication of the 'Sociology of Law' which privileges his  treatment of the Common Law and distinguishes the juristic and sociological strands  of his analysis, re-examines his notion of formal and substantive rationality, pays  close attention to his assessment of the Free Law Movement, and accords due place to  his discussion of the anti-formalistic tendencies in modern law. Taken together,  these expose the contradictions and assumptions which frame his tendentious analysis  and bring to light the vital role he ascribes to the judge.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kg84w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bf413</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Judges -- Great Britain</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociological jurisprudence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weber, Max, 1864-1920 -- Contributions in sociological jurisprudence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Common law -- Great Britain</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913q40h"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of NURBS to avoid boundary orientation poses in serial manipulators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cebula, Andrzej Jan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A manipulator end-effector (EE) Cartesian workspace is  understood as the set of all possible poses that the EE may assume. Each pose is  described by position of the EE operation point (EE position) and orientation of the  EE. The set of all possible positions of the EE constitutes reachable workspace of  the manipulator. A dextrous workspace is a subset of the reachable workspace, such  that for any EE position within the subset, corresponding set of the EE available  orientations is unbounded. For any EE position that does not belong to the dextrous  workspace the set of available EE orientations is bounded by boundary orientations.  We call the above portion of the reachable workspace a secondary workspace. An EE  pose composed of a secondary workspace position and a boundary orientation is a  boundary-orientation pose. A sequence of desired manipulator EE poses is achieved along a  smooth Cartesian trajectory using state-of-the-art NURBS motion interpolants.  However the manipulator cannot furnish the prescribed continuous motion where  boundary orientation poses are encountered, as these are physical barriers.  Therefore the initially prescribed EE orientational part of the boundary orientation  pose is modified locally to retaining smooth NURBS interpolant properties throughout  the modified trajectory. For this reason an analytical description of the Cartesian  workspace---embracing both positional and orientational parts---for a general serial  manipulator architecture, redundant or not, has been derived herein for the first  time. For serial manipulators where a point of its kinematic chain stays on a sphere  or torus, quadrics, describing EE workspace in seven-dimensional projective space,  were obtained using Study's kinematic mapping. For a general architecture  manipulator, equations of the EE workspace are expressed as quartics in the same  seven-dimensional projective space. Due to the complex form of the quartic a concept  of an ambiguous workspace has been introduced thus leading to equations describing  the EE Cartesian workspace. Both the quartics and Cartesian workspace equations are  functions of manipulator Denavit-Hartenberg (DH) parameters, EE pose and joint  variables. As the above analysis turns out to be independent of the number  of manipulator links, theorems have been formulated to reveal conditions of  existence of the equations describing the quadrics and quartics. These results have  been applied to boundary orientation pose analysis for the wrist offset TELBOT  architecture. As a result, boundary orientation poses have been revealed. Having  obtained boundary orientation poses, the novel concept of boundary orientation pose  matrix has been introduced. Results were incorporated into a procedure to build a NURBS  interpolant to avoid boundary orientation poses. Again, TELBOT architecture was  used. The procedure, which emerged from B-spline curve theory, enabled a local  change of the NURBS interpolant. The change may be accomplished in an arbitrary  neighbourhood of the chosen boundary orientation pose. Therefore, when tracking the  NURBS interpolant, we may change its value at any instant, leaving its remaining  values untouched. Recommendations for further research pertain to exploiting more  general applications of NURBS to robot kinematics.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zsombor-Murray, Paul J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk341.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q40h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2v23vt88t"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A prototype modular detector design for high resolution positron emission tomography imaging</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Nan, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current challenges facing us in developing dedicated positron  emission tomography (PET) systems for metabolic breast mammography (PEM) and small  animal (ANIPET) are to achieve high spatial resolution (less than 2 mm) and high  efficiency. It is also crucial to extend the sensitive areas of PEM detectors to  their periphery in order to overcome the difficulty in imaging near a patient's  chest wall. This limitation of the periphery dead region was revealed in the  clinical trials of our previously developed PEM-I system. In the new study, we developed prototype detectors by using  position-sensitive photomultiplier tubes (PS-PMTS) and pixelated bismuth germanate  (BGO) crystals with depth encoding scheme to detect and localize gamma rays. We used  the following methods in crystal processing: (1) Crystal cutting---each crystal  block was cut by diamond saw into small elements of 2.1 mm x 2.1 mm (2.2 mm pitch)  on two opposite faces. The elements on one face of the block offset by half the  crystal pitch from those on the opposite face in both X and Y dimensions. The depths  of two layers were 11.5 mm and 6.5 mm, respectively. The middle solid space between  the two layers was 2 mm. (2) Crystal polishing and encapsulating---The very roughly  cut surfaces were chemically polished by acid etching method and the cut slots were  encapsulated with an epoxy-compound mixture. (3) Crystal separating---the pseudo  discrete crystal blocks were cut along the middle solid space into two discrete  segments. (4) Crystal coupling---the two crystal segments were glued together and  optically coupled to the PS-PMTs window. We also developed front-end electronic circuits including  high-voltage dividers, anode resistor chains, position readout circuits, and  last-dynode timing circuits. Methods for combining four PS-PMTs with simple X+, X-,  Y+, Y- outputs have been developed to further simplify the position recording. The  detectors were constructed in the structure of arrays (two in the system)---modules  (four in each array)---units (four in each module). The basic unit of one crystal  and one PS-PMT was formed as field replaceable unit. The acquired list-mode data  were analyzed with MATLAB and C. Different methods to generate distortion  look-up-table were examined and evaluated. Our new prototype detectors have spatial resolutions of 1.8 mm  (vs. 2.8 mm in PEM-I), timing resolution of 10.3 ns (vs. 12 ns in PEM-I), and a  field-of-view of 88 mm x 88 mm (vs. 64 mm x 56 mm in PEM-I). Our analysis shows that  the design improves the spatial resolution, enhances the detector field-of-view, and  significantly reduces the peripheral dead regions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thompson, Christopher J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx44v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vt88t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h2492"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synoptic energetics of planetary-scale collapses of available potential energy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wintels, Werner</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We identify physical processes and localized atmospheric  structures that modulate the global-scale atmospheric available potential energy  (APE). A 1979--95 time series of Northern Hemisphere APE is derived from the  National Centers for Environmental Prediction (NCEP) reanalysis. We discern an  average three-day cycle in the APE depletion rate dA/dt with a time series of  intraseasonal (1.6--180-day) fluctuations. Synoptic-scale APE depletion events are  falls and subsequent rises in dA/dt, and are classified as APE collapses when  exceeding climatologically-derived thresholds of APE fall and dA/dt. Three  associated regional baroclinic waves are observed. West Pacific warm surges (Type A)  accompany cyclogenesis over Japan, anticyclogenesis over the west-central North  Pacific, and shallow East Asian cold surges. Bering warm surges (Type B) comprise  intense southerly flow across the Bering Strait, cyclogenesis near the Kamchatka  Peninsula, and intense anticyclogenesis over Alaska. Atlantic Canada warm surges  (Type C) include onshore warm flow and eastern North American storm  tracks. January/February 1989 brought the largest vacillation- and  synoptic-scale APE collapses of the study period. A pronounced Madden-Julian  Oscillation (MJO) modulated equatorial convection over the Indian Ocean during the  APE build-up. The initial APE collapse coincided with Type A development and  intensifying MJO convection shifting to the West Pacific warm pool, which was  prominent because of the 1988--89 La Nina. Extensive large-scale ascent amplified  the thermally direct Hadley cell circulation, with descent strong over East Asia.  The second collapse was associated with Type B development characterized by a  record-breaking Alaska anticyclone. Factors explaining lacking precision in energy budget  calculations include missing o values above 100 hPa, limited representation of  subgrid processes, and limited temporal resolution of diurnal convection over  tropical landmasses. Correlation analysis shows baroclinic conversion (diabatic  generation) accounting for 80% (20%) of vacillation-scale dA/dt fluctuations.  Baroclinic conversion contributes considerably (69%) to the synoptic variability  only during synoptic-scale APE collapses (23 January to 4 February), illustrating  the prominence of resolvable baroclinic processes during these  periods.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gyakum, John R.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zf05x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h2492</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z134j"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The quality of life of family caregivers of stroke survivors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>White, Carole</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The consequences of stroke extend beyond the individual who has  sustained the stroke to include family members, the main providers of care to  community dwelling stroke survivors. Caregiver research, for the most part, has  focused on burden and distress. Although there is a growing consensus among health  care researchers concerning the relevance of quality of life (QoL) as an outcome,  there is little research examining QoL among family caregivers and even less focused  on conceptualization of the construct. This thesis was designed to address these  gaps in theory and measurement through a series of related studies. The development of a conceptual model of QoL for family  caregivers, that includes the caregiving situation, caregiver characteristics, and  environmental factors, and their proposed relationships with QoL, provided a  framework for the measurement and study of QoL. Relationships between patient  characteristics, caregiver burden, and health-related quality of life (HRQL) were  examined over the first two years of caregiving and the results confirmed the impact  of the caregiving role on the caregiver's emotional health, and additionally,  supported the need for a specific measure of overall QoL to more fully capture the  caregiving experience. A subsequent study was conducted to develop this measure of QoL  for family caregivers of stroke survivors. Data from several different samples of  family caregivers contributed to the specific phases required in measure development  and psychometric testing. Four sub-scales, 'health', 'resources', 'role mastery',  and 'rewards', were constructed. Although the overall psychometric properties of  this measure are promising, they also indicate the need for further development of  selected items and the 'rewards' subscale measuring the positive  dimension. The specific hypotheses concerning the relationships among the  variables in the conceptual framework of QoL of family caregivers were tested using  structural equation modeling and they were partially supported. The results suggest  several approaches for intervening with family caregivers. As restructuring of  health care delivery is placing more responsibility for the care of disabled members  on the family, we require effective interventions to ensure that we preserve this  valuable commodity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood-Dauphinee, Sharon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mayo, Nancy</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f166m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z134j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m460x"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Erythropoietin, erythropoiesis, and malarial anemia : the mechanisms and implications of insufficient erythropoiesis during murine blood-stage malaria</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chang, Kai-Hsin, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Severe anemia is a major life-threatening complication of  malaria. Inappropriately low reticulocytosis in malaria patients with anemia  suggests insufficient erythropoiesis, of which the mechanisms and implications are  not clear. The principle growth factor that promotes erythropoiesis is  erythropoietin (Epo). Studies determining the serum level of Epo in malaria infected  patients have been inconclusive. Furthermore, the role of Epo and the erythropoietic  response to Epo stimulation during malaria have never been examined. The purpose of  the experiments performed in this thesis was, thus, to investigate the role of Epo  and erythropoiesis in relation to anemia during blood-stage malaria using the murine  model of Plasmodium chabaudi AS. A murine Epo specific ELISA, which was determined  to be less biased by the presence of other cytokines in the samples as compared to  the conventional Epo bioassay, was first developed to facilitate the research. The  kinetics of Epo production in the kidney and the levels in the serum were  characterized. It was demonstrated that Epo production during blood-stage malaria is  mainly regulated by the degree of anemia and that renal cytokines may have only a  minor effect on this response. Next, the roles of Epo and erythropoiesis during  blood-stage malaria were investigated by neutralization of endogenous Epo or by  administration of exogenous Epo. Timely onset of Epo-induced reticulocytosis was  shown to be important for the alleviation of malarial anemia and survival. However,  reticulocytosis in response to Epo stimulation is severely suppressed by infection  with malaria. Dissection of the upstream events of erythropoiesis demonstrated that  blood-stage malaria compromises the generation of reticulocytes by suppressing the  proliferation, differentiation, and maturation of erythroid-lineage cells at various  stages of erythroid development. Taken together, our data provide important insights  for understanding the patho</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stevenson, Mary M.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d476m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m460x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plasmodium chabaudi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Erythropoietin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anemia -- Pathogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Malaria -- Complications -- Pathogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Erythropoiesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hq123"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Looking at high school dropout problems from students' perspectives : finding a solution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gordon, Joan M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Should we be concerned about the more than 30 percent national  dropout rate? Can anything be done to intervene successfully? Many students who drop  out of school have the intellectual ability to complete college (Howard and  Anderson, 1978). If this is so, then our educational institutions are failing them  and doing them a tremendous disservice (Committee of Canadian Council for  Exceptional Children, 1992). This research investigates the high school dropout phenomenon in  Quebec through the "eyes" of potential dropouts. The project examines the  high school dropout phenomenon from the perspective of students who are at risk of  leaving school prematurely. The objectives of the research are to investigate how  potential high school dropouts perceive success, and to find out what program  reforms these students believe are necessary to keep them in school. In the data  analysis the students' schooling experiences are critically examined, and factors  such as students' perception of public high schools, social affairs schools,  teachers and their view of success are considered. These considerations are made  within the conceptual framework of a variety of sociological theories in education.  Social Affairs schools are special schools reserved for youths who are wards of the  court, and those who are in the care of Youth Protection because they cannot live at  home. This study provides richly descriptive narrative accounts of the  students' experiences, thoughts and feelings. The study gives voice to high school  students who are at risk of dropping out, and of their views of what their needs are  to be successful in school. Data collected from this study can be used to develop  suitable programs for students. The study concludes by signaling a call to parents,  teachers, governments, policy-makers, and caregivers to listen to children and to  involve them in matters that are important to them---such as their views of how they  can achieve school success.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lin, Jing</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>McDonough, Kevin</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt19t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq123</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>High school dropouts</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j613t"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Retinoic acid receptors and mouse epidermal tumorigenesis and development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Changfeng</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Retinoic acid (RA), the major biologically active form of  vitamin A, plays important roles in regulating a broad range of biological  processes. Progressive loss of RARs is associated with skin carcinogenesis  both in human and animals. Despite such observations, the biological significance of  RAR loss in skin carcinogenesis has not yet been clarified. To this end, we  established keratinocyte cell lines deficient in RARalpha, RARgamma, or both and  employed a well-established tumorigenesis model to investigate whether loss of RARs  is causally related to skin tumorigenesis. We found that RARgamma is the major RAR  subtype mediating the growth and AP-1 inhibitory effects of RA on keratinocytes in  vitro. Consistent with this observation, loss of RARgamma, but not RARalpha,  predisposed keratinocytes to tumor formation, suggesting that RARgamma may act as a  tumor suppressor. Reconstitution of RARs in the RARalphagamma-/- keratinocytes  inhibited their tumorigenic potential, further proving that RARs have tumor  suppressive effects. As expected, expression of dnRARalpha resulted in profound  epidermal defects. Intriguingly, dnRAalphaDBD caused a virtually identical skin  phenotype, suggesting that dnRARalpha acts to affect epidermal development via a  DNA-binding-independent mechanism. The epidermal phenotype of these transgenic mice  is reminiscent of that seen in the p63-/- mice, and p63 expression was indeed  significantly reduced in the epidermis expressing dnRARalpha or dnRARalphaDBD,  suggesting that downregulation of p63 by dnRARalpha may be attributable to the  epidermal phenotypes associated with the transgenic mice. These observations also  suggest that DNA-binding is not required for dnRARalpha to attenuate p63 expression  in the epidermis. Consistent with these observations, I also found that p63 is  indeed not a RAR-target, as no overt changes in p63 expression were observed in the  RARalphagamma-/- epidermis, which appeared normal. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lohnes, David</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp052.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j613t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278t54w"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation into genetically programmed responses to cadmium and mercury in HeLa cells by differential display and two-dimensional gel electrophoresis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Charoensri, Nicha</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cadmium and mercury are among the most toxic metals and can be a  serious threat to human health. A clear understanding how cells respond, especially  in terms of genetically controlled responses to these two metals, is required in  order to develop appropriate prevention and treatment procedures that can protect  humans from toxic exposure to these metals. Therefore, this study is aimed at  elucidating the genetically programmed response to cadmium and mercury exposure in  HeLa cells. Two different approaches were employed for this study. Differential  expression patterns of mRNAs were studied by differential display reverse  transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (DDRT-PCR) and changes in protein  composition of HeLa cells were monitored by two-dimensional (2D) gel  electrophoresis. The results showed that transcripts of particular genes were  altered by cadmium and/or mercury exposure. These gene are aspartyl/asparginyl  beta-hydroxylase (asph), monocyte to macrophage differentiation associated antigen  (MMD), and ribosomal protein S24 (rpS24) genes. In addition, some protein spots from  2D gels were found to be altered in their levels as a result of cadmium and/or  mercury exposure. The possible roles of asph, MMD and rpS24 genes in response to  cadmium and mercury are discussed and further studies are suggested.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Acheson, Nicholas H.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p7673.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t54w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57nr47g"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>State identity, foreign policy, and systemic norm diffusion : towards humanitarian intervention</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Greene, Brian W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation explores the complex relationship between  state identity, foreign policy, and systemic norm diffusion. Based on an empirical  examination of the international military response to the humanitarian crises  associated with the Yugoslav wars of secession (1991--1995), Somali civil war and  famine (1991--1993), Rwandan genocide (1994), and Zairian refugee crisis (1996), I  contend that a state's foreign policy is primarily a product of its international  identity. The country case studies (Canada, France, and the United States) are not  merely isolated narratives. Drawing on the logic of 'system effects' analysis, with  its emphasis on the role of feedback and indirect effects, I then situate each state  within the larger systemic narrative, highlighting the systemic normative  consequences of each state's policy choices. In addition to demonstrating that  states from outside the great power club can exert significant international  normative influence (a heretofore unexplored phenomenon), the study paints a much  clearer picture than presently exists about the possibilities for, and limits to,  ethical normative evolution in world politics.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brawley, Mark R.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv130.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr47g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International relations -- Political aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>International relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Humanitarian intervention</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>