<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278z72n"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Entrainment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mile, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Entrainment is a composition for six percussionists. The piece is in seven movements which explore different aspects of rhythmic and metric perception and cognition. In order to express the different rhythmic techniques used in the Entrainment, I develop a theoretical apparatus that allows the analysis of concurrent temporal streams. The first two movements deal with how the brain reconstrues rhythmic material into different meters based on context. The third and fourth movements explore how the brain understands meter when given very little rhythmic information. The fifth and sixth movements explore how the brain understands meters which are out of phase with one another. The final movement serves as a culmination of the various rhythmic techniques used throughout the piece. In addition to the rhythmic elements, the movements contribute to numerous large-scale trajectories pertaining to tempo, timbre, and dynamics, leading to the final movement</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Entrainment est une oeuvre pour six percussionnistes. L’oeuvre en sept mouvements explore plusieurs éléments de la perception et de la cognition du rythme et du mètre. Afin d’exprimer les différentes techniques rythmiques utilisées dans Entrainment, j’ai développé un modèle théorique qui permet l’analyse des strates temporelles simultanées. Les deux premiers mouvements examinent comment le cerveau réinterprète un matériel rythmique donné dans une nouvelle organisation métrique en s’appuyant sur le contexte. Les troisième et quatrième mouvements étudient la façon dont le cerveau comprend le mètre quand il y a peu d’information rythmique. Les cinquième et sixième mouvements examinent comment le cerveau comprend le décalage métrique entre les différentes strates temporelles. Le dernier mouvement utilise toutes les techniques employées dans les mouvements précédents. En dehors des éléments rythmiques, le timbre, les nuances et le tempo forment des trajectoires à grande échelle qui mènent au dernier mouvement</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brian Cherney</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cv99f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278z72n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gs403"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Subnational politics and regime change in Mexico</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Durazo Herrmann, Julián</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>What happens to subnational states when the parent federation undergoes a regime change process? This is a crucial question in understanding political processes in federal countries. The visible political differentiation amongst subnational states belonging to the same federation underscores the fact that some processes are at work that are being ignored by the literature's current focus on national developments. To fill this lacuna, I develop an analytical model that seeks to explain regional differentiation during federal regime change by focusing directly on subnational politics and institutions in comparative fashion, while accounting for the inescapable influence of broader federal actors and processes. In constructing this model, I draw extensively from the theories of federalism, regime change and political parties. I argue that the decision to initiate a transition in an authoritarian setting belongs to the federation. However, regional political actors mediate federal processes in their territory and give them a profoundly subnational logic. Regionally specific institutions, interests and histories thus become intangible frontiers between subnational politics and external processes. The constant repetition of this mechanism throughout the transition creates distinct subnational polities. To test my hypothesis, I study three cases in central-northern Mexico: Guanajuato, San Luis Potosi and Zacatecas.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns0649912.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gs403</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Local government -- Mexico</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 1988-2000</dc:subject><dc:subject>Federal government -- Mexico</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mexico -- Politics and government -- 2000-</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386p74g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theatre and the materialities of communication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Darroch, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is situated within the field of media studies, with a particular focus on the "materialities of communication." The concept of "materialities" is oriented to the underlying conditions that allow communication to take place: the places, carriers and modes of communication that serve to shape and even alter meaning. My dissertation asks how this "material turn" can usefully be applied to and help develop the study of theatre. The dissertation is divided into four chapters. In Chapter 1, I undertake a critical review of the theoretical literature regarding materialities and its applications to media theory. In Chapter 2, I begin to explore the implications of the material turn for theatre. Scholarly interest in the relation of media and theatre has largely been focused on the use of media and technology within theatrical practice. I argue that theatre cannot be conceived of separately from the prevailing communicational possibilities of a given era, even if we accept the capacity for artistic intervention within these parameters. I integrate theoretical standpoints on the reproducibility, iterability and liveness of theatrical presence into a broad discussion of media and communication and thereby demonstrate a more fundamental relationship between theatricality and mediality. In Chapter 3, I extend my discussion of a "materialities of theatre" to the subject of translatability. Translation has long functioned as a metaphor for media as well as for theatrical representation. Discourses of the translatability between media forms have recently been revived by digital technologies that present translation as a model of universalization: the search for the perfect language into which all forms of knowledge can converge. Theatre works to converge media forms as a point of intersecting bodies, texts, voices and technologies, yet also remains persistently aware of the economy of shifting linguistic exchanges that renders total translation an impossible pursuit. I thus develop a study of the materialities of theatre that can attend to this disjunction in translation theory by addressing theatre as a point of medial convergence as well as a site of linguistic difference. In Chapter 4, I elaborate upon these standpoints by discussing circulation as a theoretical concept that, on the one hand, complements the study of materialities of communication and, on the other hand, seeks to overcome the abovementioned disjunction of translation theory. Concentrating on the case of Montreal as a site of heightened linguistic interaction, I investigate theatre as a medial system that works to absorb, interrupt and rediffuse the linguistic materialities of this city.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c670s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386p74g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communication -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poststructuralism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Theater -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161b43v"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An obsession with meaning : a critical examination of the pictograph sites of the Lake of Woods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Colson, Alicia J. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Most researchers who study rock image sites tend to be interested in the meaning of images, even though they could obtain more empirical information about these images and their physical location. Furthermore, very little of the work done in the past on rock image sites has been systematic. In this thesis I address the dearth of detailed information on the images and their context. This thesis presents a thorough examination of the images of the twenty-seven pictograph sites in the Lake of the Woods, in the Canadian Shield. These pictograph sites were selected because they exhibit traits evident in rock image studies in other parts of the world. This study is based on data collected during three months of fieldwork conducted in 2001. Images were found on cliff faces and inside caves. New images and new sites were found and identified. Here, as elsewhere, the choice of theoretical approach influences the fieldwork, analysis, and search for meaning. Each prescribes the types of questions asked and determines the levels of understanding obtained about whichever form of archaeological evidence is being considered. The different but complementary theoretical approaches should be employed in a definite order. The same data must be examined in sequential order using these different approaches to increase the potential quantity and quality of information gained. Archaeologists should use the following sequence of approaches: culture-historical, contextual, followed by either the homological, or analogical approaches, or a combination of the latter two. Classifying and describing any image is very difficult, since the level of description given to an image affects the way in which it can be analysed, and heavily influences the possible outcome of any discussion of perceived meaning. A rigorous examination of the images of these sites was conducted to (a) identify the possible vocabulary of images, (b) determine whether combinatory, rules exist, (c) reconstitute the life history of each site, and (d) ascertain whether the images can be related to other indigenous images to determine if this can provide information about the meaning(s) of the rock images. In assessing the meaning of the rock images, the images of a few birch bark scrolls were considered, since it was posited that a detailed investigation of the scrolls, the ethnographic record, and their pictographs might provide some answers regarding the meanings of the images found on the rock faces.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dx66n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161b43v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Picture-writing -- Ontario -- Lake of the Woods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lake of the Woods -- Antiquities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rock paintings -- Ontario -- Lake of the Woods</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hw89h"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children's use of personal, social and material resources to solve a music notational task : a social constructivist perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carroll, Debra, 1952-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this inquiry, I examined how young children use their personal, social and material resources to solve a music notational task. I asked 13 children, ages 5-9 to notate a song they learned the previous week, sing it back, explain what they did and then teach the song to a classmate the following week. I used Lightfoot and Davis' concept of portraiture as a qualitative research methodology to collect, code, analyze and interpret my data. Data included the children's invented notations and videotaped transcripts of their actions as they created their notations and taught the song to a classmate. Sociocultural Vygotskian developmental theory, activity theory and Bakhtin's dialogic theory provided the interpretive lens through which I examined how the children used their resources as mediational tools to complete the task. Findings revealed that children who had no previous music training used increasingly sophisticated representational strategies to notate a song, and that they were able to refine their notations when singing the song from their notation, teaching the song or when prompted by an adult or a peer. I concluded that the peer-peer situation was a motivating force for triggering a recursive process of reflections-on-actions and knowing-in-action. Classmates' questions, comments and their singing played a critical role in moving the children to modify their notations and their singing, verbal explanations and gesturing in ways they did not do alone or with me. Analysis of the children's notations, verbal explanations and teaching strategies provided insights not only into what they knew about music, but also their appropriation of the cultural conventions of writing and their aesthetic sensibilities, as gleaned from their choice of symbols, colours and how they presented their symbols on the page. Interviews with parents, teachers and school principal provided contextual background for interpreting the children's notations and how they approached the task. This study shows the value of adopting a social constructivist approach to teaching the language of music. It also demonstrates that researching the products and processes of children's invented notations from a social constructivist perspective enables more detailed portraits of children's musical and meta-cognitive understandings.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nd15s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw89h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>School music -- Instruction and study</dc:subject><dc:subject>Musical notation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Music -- Instruction and study -- Juvenile</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vq14h"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>&amp;quot;... Only if you're really interested&amp;quot; : celebrity, gender, desire and the world of Morrissey</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Greco, Nicholas P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Steven Patrick Morrissey was the lead singer of the 1980s British band The Smiths. Since the band's demise in 1987, Morrissey has had a successful career as a solo performer. Morrissey is a rich case study for the analysis of mediated celebrities. This dissertation examines the ways in which Morrissey's public persona has shifted throughout his career. These changes have to do with the nature of popular cultural mediation, the status of celebrity, and Morrissey's engagement with issues of gender and desire. Morrissey's celebrity persona, or star image, takes shape within the ongoing production of what Roland Barthes refers to as enigma, and its incompleteness is thus one of its consistent features. This star image is constructed from---and within---"streams" of information which are produced and circulate over time. The unending character of this "stream" is such that Morrissey's star image is perpetually produced and continues to evolve. The sense of the celebrity's image as incomplete leads, in turn, to an ongoing impulse, on the part of fans and observers, to find resolution. Throughout his career, Morrissey has maintained mystery around key aspects of his identity, in particular his sexuality, his feelings about England, and his relationship to pop stardom. This dissertation explores the various elements which contribute to Morrissey's enigmatic star image: critical press; music videos; live performance; musical syntax; and interviews. This dissertation explores the interaction of these various elements, and how they have given rise to ongoing speculation within fan and critical discourse, and it explores the particular kinds of mystery and gender roles which arise to accompany these sorts of enigmas. As a celebrity, Morrissey is subject to the gaze of an audience in a way that has historically been construed as objectifying, and theorized within important works as feminizing. Morrissey's principle response to this objectification has been the maintenance of a constant sense of enigma. While other performers might seek clarification of their images as a means of controlling them, Morrissey's response to ongoing objectification is the ongoing production of enigma. His active control of his image is manifest through his constant transformation of that image.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89db669.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vq14h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Celebrities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Morrissey</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd4731463"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Schola Cantorum, early music and French political culture, from 1894 to 1914</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Flint, Catrena M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is based on the study of over 340 performances of early music given by the Parisian Schola Cantorum and its sister association, the Chanteurs de Saint-Gervais, between 1894 and 1914. The first chapter explores performance trends for this repertoire in isolation. Chapter 2 is an attempt to root out personal reasons for the changes in Schola programming, and also provides a sketch of the community that was behind the institution. The next chapter considers how Schola programming may have been affected by changes to the institution's mandate, goals, and relationship to the Conservatoire and other Republican institutions. The circle widens in Chapter 4, with a discussion of the relevance of Bordes's revival to sacred music reform. In the final chapter, the Schola's revival is placed in the broader context of French fin-de-siecle politics and nationalism in particular. This dissertation provides a new assessment of Charles Bordes and Vincent d'Indy's respective biographies and demonstrates that many of the right-wing programming tendencies at the Schola should be attributed to Bordes. The importance of personal networks is emphasized in most of the dissertation. In addition to providing information on an unprecedented number of Schola concert types, this dissertation identifies the importance of looking to revivals of seventeenth-century music after 1898. For this repertoire provided an analogue for Ferdinand Brunetiere's ideas of an ideal, seventeenth-century French. An important shift in concert type and repertoire after 1904 provides a new window on d'Indy biography and underscores the transformation of the French public's musical values around the same time. The Schola's role in the reform of sacred music has been over estimated. The papal motu proprio of 1903 only reiterated instructions on sacred music previously handed down by the Sacred Congregation of Rites in 1894 and it was probably not directed specifically at the Parisian Schola Cantorum. The Schola's concerts of early music became sites for the expression of cultural difference. Much like many concerts exclusively devoted to this repertoire---and unlike many events that combined early and contemporary music---the "Frenchness" expressed at these events was intended to remain beyond the grasp of the average French citizen.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n739w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd4731463</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music -- 15th century -- Performance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xj97p"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Object clitics and null objects in the acquisition of French</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grüter, Therese</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation investigates (direct) object clitics and object omission in the acquisition of French as a first language. It reports on two original empirical studies which were designed to address aspects of object omission in child French that have remained unexplored in previous research. Study 1 investigates the incidence of object omission in the spontaneous speech of French-speaking children aged three and above, an age group for which no analysis, and only little data, have been available so far. Findings show that object omission continues to occur at non-negligible rates in this group. A comparison with age- and language-matched groups of English- and Chinese-speaking children (from Wang, Lillo-Martin; Best &amp; Levitt 1992) suggests that French-speaking children omit objects at higher rates than their English-speaking peers, yet at lower rates than children acquiring a true null object language, such as Chinese. Study 2 was designed to investigate whether French-speaking children would accept null objects on a receptive task, an issue that has not been previously investigated. A series of truth value judgment experiments is developed, adapting an experimental paradigm that has not been used previously in the context of null objects. Results from English- and French-speaking children show that both groups consistently reject null objects on these tasks, a finding that constitutes counterevidence to proposals which attribute object omission in production to a genuine null object representation sanctioned by the child grammar. Overall, the pattern of results turns out not to be consistent with any developmental proposals made in the literature, suggesting that a novel approach is required. Proposing a minimalist adaptation of Sportiche's (1996) analysis of clitic constructions, and taking into consideration the recent emphasis on 'interface' requirements imposed by language-external systems, I put forward a hypothesis for future research, the Decayed Features Hypothesis (DFH), which locates the source of object (clitic) omission in child French in a specific language-external domain, namely the capacity of working memory.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hw887.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj97p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Clitics</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Grammar</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language acquisition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593v060r"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The 1950s B-movie : the economics of cultural production</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Davis, Blair</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The United States Supreme Court placed the major Hollywood studios in violation of antitrust laws in 1948, leading to the end of the classical Hollywood studio system of the 1930s and 1940s. Subsequent changes in the corporate organization and mode of production of the major studios signaled the end of the traditional B-movie as a product of block-booking policies. B-movies became a distinctly different entity in the 1950s, however. From the institutional effects of the antitrust ruling, to changing audience demographics, the emergent patterns in production, distribution and exhibition had a profound effect on the evolution of the B-movie from its origins in the early 1930s to its new role in the cinematic marketplace of the 1950s. Increasingly the result of newly formed independent companies, B-movies innovated such industrial components as new genre cycles and demographic patterns. This dissertation takes a political economy approach to examining the B-movie in the 1950s as an economic product, with a specific emphasis on independent filmmaking. The implication for film studies lies in answering questions about the unique nature of the B-movie filmmaking process: how is the mode of production of a B-movie different from that of mainstream Hollywood filmmaking? How does the low-budget nature of independent cinema determine its mode of production? How is a B-movie limited and/or defined by the low budget nature of its mode of production, and how does this affect the film's aesthetics? How do B-movies function in, and what is their value to, the film marketplace? Changes in film production, distribution and exhibition will be examined, as will patterns in film spectatorship in relation to the changing institutional landscape of the film industry in the 1950s. The B-movie was a volatile entity during the 1950s, with both major and minor studios questioning the economic viability of low-budget production. B-movies existed in opposition to the cinematic mainstream in the 1950s, a legacy that was passed on to independent filmmakers of subsequent decades. Analyzing the mode of production of these B-movies is essential in understanding their aesthetics, as well as their historical role in the film industry.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zg24w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593v060r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Motion picture industry -- United States -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>B films</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v6795"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>How does her garden grow? : the garden topos and trope in Canadian women's writing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyd, Shelley Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study offers additional nuance to the garden topos and trope within nineteenth- and twentieth-century Canadian women's writing and extends the critical discussion of landscape and the garden as archetype in Canadian literature. This dissertation cross-fertilizes literary analysis with garden theory, using the work of such garden historians as John Dixon Hunt, Mark Francis, and Randolph Hester. The argument emphasizes that gardens in literature, like their actual counterparts, are an art of milieu, reflective of their socio-physical contexts. Both real and textual gardens are rhetorical: their content and formal features invite interpretation. A textual garden performs similarly to an actual garden by providing a spatial frame; a means of naturalization; a vivid exemplar of growth, fertility and beauty; a mediation of the artificial and the natural; a space of paradox; and a site of social performance. The specific focus of this study is "domestic gardens": gardens that are intimate, immediate to the home, and part of daily life. Chapter one separates the garden from archetypal models by studying the garden as an actual place (specifically, the backwoods kitchen garden) described in the works of Susanna Moodie and Catharine Parr Traill. Chapter two examines how the garden influences Moodie's and Traill's writing of the "transplanted" female emigrant. Chapter three presents the bower as an important precursor to the domestic garden through Gabrielle Roy's Enchantment and Sorrow (1984) and "Garden in the Wind" (1975). Through the bower, Roy mediates the female artist's ambivalence toward home in her pursuit of independence. Chapter four explores Carol Shields' sanctification of the domestic in her fiction through the concept of paradise as both an ideal setting and a mode of being. Chapter five provides a "garden tour" of the poetry of Lorna Crozier, culminating in the garden as a model for the text itself and for the genre of palimpsest. For these writers, literal and figurative gardens are ways of "planting" their characters and personae, "plotting" their narratives, mediating social conventions, and providing an interpretative lens through which readers may perceive the texts as a whole.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gj13w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v6795</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canadian literature -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women authors, Canadian</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gardens in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pm37k"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Altered states : travel, transcendence and technology in contemporary Vodou</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boutros, Sandra Kathleen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Vodou, the religious tradition of Haiti, has been maligned throughout history. However, a growing interest in Afro-Caribbean religions is carving out new avenues of access to this formerly secret and subjugated religion. Altered States: Travel, Transcendence and Technology in Contemporary Vodou is an ethnographic study of Vodou in North America that documents the shifting boundaries between a religion and its representations as it gains contemporary popularity. Contemporary Vodou communities are filled with practitioners who have consciously sought out new religious experiences and allegiances. This text charts their journey to and from Vodou. Altered States examines how Vodou practitioners navigate popular representations and commodification of the religion; how the cosmology of the religion absorbs and incorporates new technology and media practices; and how media practices and representations alters the constitution and constituents of the Vodou religion. The work contributes to an understanding of the shifts in identification and signification engendered by the intersection of religion, communication technologies, media representation and cultural commodification.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53x113r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pm37k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Voodooism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021k35s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Institutional evaluation in Québec : an interpretation of organizational response to policy approaches in the context of Marianopolis College</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brooks, Stanley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the past two to three decades there has been tremendously increased interest from various sectors of society in the performance, effectiveness and social responsibility of higher education. As a result, an audit culture has evolved within which quality assurance has become an integral part of the politics of governance which assumes external regulation of academic activity to be the natural state of affairs. In Quebec, the Commission d'Evaluation de L'enseignement Collegial (CEEC) serves government instrumentally by institutionalizing accountability mechanisms, evaluation, and other quality assurance practices as technologies that transmit, as well as shape, particular values within the college-level sector. The underlying rationale for this study is to develop a deeper understanding of the institutional evaluation process. In order to attain this study's research objectives, a multidimensional theoretical framework is employed to analyze and interpret the ways by which the college of interest relates and responds to the institutional environment within which it is embedded. This framework draws upon neo-institutionalism theory in sociology and the emerging body of discourse literature within organizational studies. In answering the research question, a constructivist, qualitative interpretive case study of the college's self-evaluative experience is developed to clarify three specific aspects of the dynamics of quality assurance and the institutional evaluation process: how national policy regimes and organizations within their fields envision and approach quality assurance; which particular organizational strategies and procedures are adopted to achieve specific quality objectives in response to the organization's mission, vision and the institutional environment; and, how organizational interests are served in the process of implementing and complying with regulatory quality assurance procedures. Three substantive findings emerge from this study. Firstly, quality assurance policy in Quebec focuses on strengthening and sustaining the quality and integrity of academic programs and institutional management, and on encouraging and enabling colleges to develop a culture of evaluation. Quebec's quality assurance agency has placed improvement, the enhancement of relevance, effectiveness, quality and accountability in the forefront. Secondly, the College's evaluative discourse claims alignment with institutional and social expectations and the attainment of organizational mission and goals, the primary goal being the successful preparation of students for university studies. In fact, the overarching thesis which emerges from the data is that Marianopolis is characterized by superior institutional and student success. The competencies and capabilities of the College may be attributed to its commitment to academic excellence, as well as to specific strategic decisions and organizational processes that manipulate and convert resources and assets into new value-creating services. Thirdly, the College uses discourse to solidify its identity, and to be self-defined and identified in relation to specific standards and practices in conformity to institutional norms, policy, and social expectations, and to claim legitimacy in light of such alignment. The propositions that link the patterns, unifying themes and concepts within the data embody a coherent explanation of the organization's response to the management of the educational process in the context of accountability. These propositions have the potential to serve as a basis for transferability from the case of interest to the wider population of colleges. They also suggest avenues for future process-based research on the management and functioning of the colleges, and should inform models for holistic quality development in this regard.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w885r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021k35s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>College teaching -- Québec (Province) -- Evaluation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marianopolis (College)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Educational evaluation -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cz49m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Linking social and ecological dynamics for bird conservation : protecting the endangered Sierra Madre sparrow in Chichinautzin, Mexico</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cabrera-García, Leonardo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Birds are one of the best studied animal groups in the world but are also amongst the most endangered. The wealth of ecological information has shown habitat protection to be vital to bird biodiversity, but habitat loss and degradation continue to defeat conservationists. Community-based biodiversity conservation efforts have been recently recognized as an important option for safeguarding ecosystems while reducing land use conflicts arising from the material, cultural and spiritual needs of local inhabitants. Community involvement is particularly critical for conservation in anthropogenic habitats. Few studies have linked the ecological impacts of community land use practices with the auto-ecological requirements of dependent bird species. In this study I examine the conservation possibilities for the endangered Sierra Madre sparrow (Xenospiza baileyi) by considering three basic elements: the ecological requirements of the bird, the effects of traditional land use practices in shaping the habitat, and the economic and social conditions that influence current and future land use decisions. I draw on ecological field studies, on traditional ecological knowledge systems, and studies of the political ecological context that influences local practices. The studies were carried out from 2000-2003 and employed a combination of ethnographic, participative and spatial-ecological approaches to address human-land interactions and their impacts on the sparrow habitat. Social data were obtained through nine workshops which included site visits, transect walks, participatory mapping, oral histories and semi-structured interviews. Ecological data were obtained from landscape ecology analysis, vegetation post-disturbance assessments and detailed bird's nest-site selection analysis. Results indicate that local people, principally herders, hold a rich knowledge of fire use to achieve diverse purposes, including pasture renewal, grassland maintenance and grass species selection, and prevention of dangerous fires. In order to accomplish their goals, herders have established rotational fire and grazing regimes that consider timing, frequency, location and extent of these disturbance-based practices. This rotational system was found to benefit the Sierra Madre sparrow by maintaining the grassland at the scales needed by the sparrow for nesting. Multiscale habitat recommendations for the species' conservation were derived from this socio-ecological interaction and dynamics. Unfortunately, external conservation perspectives and interests and internal land tenure conflicts have altered this rotational regime and local perspectives on resource management that threaten the resilience of this social-ecological system. Consequently, traditional ecological knowledge on grassland management can be on risk of disappearing and, with it, important native grasses and grasslands are being made vulnerable. The survival of the Sierra Madre sparrow in particular and of associated biodiversity in general, is in peril if these conflicts are not solved in a relatively short time. A community-based fire co-management program is recommended to promote integrative bird conservation-local development scenarios.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pj12t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cz49m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Birds -- Conservation -- Mexico</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rare birds -- Mexico</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sierra Madre sparrow -- Conservation -- Mexico</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sierra Madre sparrow -- Effect of habitat modification on -- Mexico</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655m59n"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wat Phra Chetuphon : the narratives of form, symbol, and architectural order in the Thai temple</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bell, John Barry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis strives to uncover the central narrative latent in the forms, symbols, and architectural order of Wat Phra Chetuphon, a major royal temple in Bangkok, and to consider its revelatory significance in relation to the broader question of Thai sacred building. Conventionally Wat Pho's architecture is assumed to follow a fully formed Siamese tradition.1 Though conceived within a newly challenging historical context, and with a novel pedagogic programme, the architecture's symbolic value has been, therefore, treated as largely self evident. Yet surprisingly neither the traditions of Thai sacred architecture nor their specific expression at Wat Pho have been clearly articulated. After outlining the conceptual context the thesis undertakes a detailed examination of the temple's different parts and their arrangement. This descriptive strategy proposes Wat Pho's architecture as the primary document available for study, with its specific forms and experience orienting the supporting textual research. Existing scholarship, canonic Theravada Buddhist texts, Brahmanic mythology and the specificities of Siamese history and culture are brought into the discussion as directed by the architecture's particularities. Those forms such as the bai sema and the chofa, which identify the temple's indigenous character and symbolic potential without, however, having universally accepted meanings, are of particular significance to the argument. Equally the complexities of Wat Pho's plan and its experience are considered in relation to their narrative potential. This descriptive foundation establishes the facts of the architecture and its associations in order to ground the identification of a range of possible narratives. These are reviewed in relation to the symbolic assumptions regarding the Thai temple and Wat Pho that exist. From this foundation a new essential narrative structure is proposed. Like most of the sacred architecture throughout the region Wat Pho expresses aspects of a Buddhist cosmology. Yet in contrast to a spatial analogue (or map) of the universe centred on Mount Meru prevalent elsewhere, it is argued here that Wat Pho's architecture, and the Thai temple in general, articulates a cosmological understanding through a form of represented event; a mimetic recreation of the Buddha's descent from Tavatimsa heaven where he had gone to preach to his mother and the assembled gods. In conclusion Wat Pho's cosmological vision is placed within its own artistic and historical contexts, exemplary of Thai sacred architecture at the culminating moment of its traditional expression and impending transformation. 1Wat Phra Chetuphon is popularly known as Wat Pho, referencing its earlier name, Wat Photaram, which predated its transformation under the Chakri (Bangkok) dynasty.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44ps026.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655m59n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture -- Thailand</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wat Phrachētuphon (Bangkok, Thailand)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jc99v"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>True light, true method : science, Newtonianism, and the editing of Shakespeare in eighteenth-century England</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bar-On, Gefen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The promotion of Shakespeare to the centre of the English literary canon was largely facilitated by ten major eighteenth-century editions of his plays: by Nicholas Rowe (1709), Alexander Pope (1723-25), Lewis Theobald (1733), Thomas Hanmer (1744), William Warburton (1747), Samuel Johnson (1765), George Steevens (1766), Edward Capell (1767-68), Johnson and Steevens (1773) and Edmond Malone (1790). The popularity of Newtonian science in eighteenth-century England helps to explain the mentality that impelled this energetic enterprise. In their Prefaces, the editors describe Shakespeare as a Newton-like genius who understood the underlying principles of human nature and expressed them through his characters. Shakespeare, however, unlike Newton, was not a systematic thinker, and the editors are critical of his language and of his tendency to cater to the low tastes of the Elizabethan theatre. They view him as a genius who understood fundamental truths about human nature and, at the same time, metaphorically, as nature itself---a site of heterogeneity and confusion where the editor must find hidden knowledge. They figure themselves as, scientists charged with the task of altering, restoring and annotating Shakespeare's writings. In the editions leading to and including that of Johnson, the editors' focus is on the universality of Shakespeare's discoveries. The early editors promote a transcendental image of Shakespeare as a timeless genius who rose above the relatively barbaric age in which he lived. The two editors following Johnson, however, place an increasing emphasis on Shakespeare's Englishness. While the idea of Shakespeare as a universal genius persists, Steevens and Capell also view him as a specifically English figure whose writings are to a large extent a product of his society. This nationalist emphasis goes hand in hand with an increasingly historical approach to the annotation and textual restoration of Shakespeare. The development of editing as a professional scientific vocation culminates with Malone, who augmented the editorial apparatus with thoroughly researched accounts of Shakespeare's life and theatre. The persistent emphasis on knowledge in the editors' work helps to account for the rise of Shakespeare's canonicity in relation to the Newtonian truth-seeking project of the eighteenth century.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nn286.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jc99v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Criticism, Textual</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drama -- Editing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02871126f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>From budgetary pressures to welfare state retrenchment? : economic and monetary union and the politics of welfare state reform</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bolukbasi, H. Tolga</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the relationship between economic and monetary integration culminating in Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) and welfare state trajectories focusing on the cases of Belgium, Italy, and Greece in the 1990s. The conventional wisdom on this relationship expected that EMU would lead to across-the-board downsizing of the European welfare states through imposing macroeconomic austerity in general and budgetary restraint in particular. The study questions the validity of this prediction which is represented by the austerity hypothesis. Based on an analysis of social expenditure data in the run-up to EMU the study reveals that spending levels remained largely stable and therefore that the welfare states of the EMU-candidates largely escaped radical retrenchment. Avoiding significant and systematic expenditure retreat was possible not only in the face of powerful fiscal pressures but also during a period when policymakers had the opportunity to justify even the most draconian measures in the name of achieving EMU membership. Hence the study addresses the following puzzle: How could Europe's welfare states largely avert across-the-board downsizing during the 1990s despite fiscal pressures they faced on the road to EMU? Through an examination of episodes of welfare reform in three critical cases (Belgium, Italy, and Greece) which needed to go through drastic budgetary cutbacks for EMU membership, the study shows that the Maastricht criteria did compel successive governments in these member states to propose radical welfare reforms, vindicating the conventional wisdom's expectations. In episodes of welfare reform, however, governments discovered that their reform capacities were largely limited due to domestic opposition from an alliance of entrenched interests. The convergence period was marred with recurrent mass mobilization of unions against welfare reforms which forced governments to scale back their original ambitions or scrap them altogether. This shows that the expectations of the conventional wisdom that EMU would actually lead to massive retrenchment of Europe's welfare states, however, are not borne out by the evidence on welfare state trajectories in the 1990s.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rn407.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871126f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economic and Monetary Union</dc:subject><dc:subject>Public welfare -- Europe</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j528g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Beyond perception : the ethics of contemporary earth art</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boetzkes, Amanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation considers the aesthetic strategies and ethical implications of contemporary earth art. Drawing from feminist and ecological critiques of phenomenology, it posits that an ethical preoccupation with the earth is identifiable in works that stage the artist's inability to condense natural phenomena into an intelligible art object thereby evidencing the earth's excess beyond the field of perception. Contemporary earth art has the paradoxical goal of evoking the sensorial plenitude of the earth without representing it as such. The first chapter analyzes Robert Smithson's monumental sculpture, the Spiral Jetty (1970), and suggests that the artist deploys the emblem of the whirlpool to express the artwork's constitutive rupture from the earth, a loss that the artwork subsequently discloses in its textual modes, including an essay and a film that document the construction of the sculpture. Chapter two examines the recurrence of the whirlpool motif and other anagrammatic shapes such as black holes, tornadoes, shells and nests, in earth art from the last three decades. In contemporary practices the whirlpool allegorizes an ethical attentiveness to the earth's alterity; not only does it thematize the artwork's separation from perpetual natural regeneration, it signals the artist's withdrawal from the attempt to construct a totalizing perspective of the site. Chapter three addresses performance and installation works that feature the contact between the artist's body and the earth, and in particular, the body's role in delineating the point of friction between the earth's sensorial plenitude and its resistance to representation. Earth artists thereby assert the body as a surface that separates itself out from the earth and receives sensation of it as other. The conclusion summarizes the main arguments of the previous chapters through a discussion of a three-part installation by Chris Drury entitled Whorls (2005).</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064992b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j528g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nature (Aesthetics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Art, Modern -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63t100x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Probing and controlling defects in self-assembled monolayers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Lawrence Yoon Suk, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is focused on the development of a tool for probing defects in self-assembled monolayers (SAMs). Such a tool is necessary for the detailed understanding of fundamental issues in SAM composition and structure. The electrochemical properties of single component and binary ferrocenylalkylthiol SAMs on polycrystalline gold (FcC12S-Au and FcC12S-/CH 3RS-Au) have been investigated in detail. The complex voltammetry obtained for various mixtures of FcC12S-Au SAMs is shown to be linked to local electrostatics caused by the formation of the ferrocenium ion. A procedure involving a Gaussian-Lorentzian fit is used to deconvolute the two peaks consistently observed in the SAMs when the surface mole fraction of the FcC12S-Au ( csurfFc ) ≥ 0.2. The lower potential (Eº' = 250 mV) and higher potential (Eº' = 350 mV) voltammetric peaks are thus assigned to Fc moieties in "isolated" and "clustered" states, respectively. Use of this method to better understand SAM structure is demonstrated by distinguishing the degree of homogeneity in two binary SAMs of similar composition. This characteristic electrochemical property of FcC12S-Au system allows for the quantification of defects in SAMs. This is important because coverage defects, or voids in alkylthiol SAMs, are a critical component of electron transfer mechanisms of soluble redox probes. Short time exposure of a defective SAM to FcC12SH leads to a quantifiable defect-related Fc coverage (GammaFc), with GammaFc &lt; 1% being readily measurable. Using FcC12SH as a label, a number of alkylthiol SAM preparation conditions have been assessed. FcC12SH is further used to probe the progress of the important alkylthiol-for-alkylthiol exchange reaction in SAMs. It is shown that variation of chain length, reaction temperature, terminal group, applied potential, and the initial defect density determines the extent and the rate of the exchange reaction. Kinetics studies of binary (FcC12S-/CH3RS-Au) SAM formation via co-incubation reveal that although csurfFc is initially close to the solution mole fraction of the FcC12 SH ( csolnFc ), the subsequent exchange reaction leads to a csurfFc which is often quite different from csolnFc . Finally, the FcC12SH probe is used to further study the reductive voltammetric desorption of alkylthiol SAMs. Defects in a C14S-Au SAM created by excursions to desorptive reduction potentials were quantified by use of the FcC12SH label. A reductive desorption potential followed by re-adsorption, applied to a binary (FcC12S-/C14S-Au) SAM, results in mixing of the phase separated components of the binary SAM.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687n444.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t100x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqz20sz050"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A miniature atmospheric pressure glow discharge torch for localized biomedical applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Léveillé, Valérie, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents the design and characterization of a novel pulsed miniature capacitively-coupled Atmospheric Pressure Glow Discharge Torch (APGD- t) aimed at localized biomedical applications. Amplitude modulation of the 13.56 MHz carrier signal allows to continuously vary the power level applied to the APGD-t. Typically, the APGD-t produces a plasma jet with a 150-500 μm diameter and ≈2.5 mm length. Helium (He) is the plasma-forming gas with a flow rate ranging from 0.5 to 1.5 slm. The use of a small capillary electrode enhances the electric field, lowering the breakdown voltage (typically 220 Vpk-to-0) and allows the injection of small amounts (0-50 sccm) of a source of reactive species (O2) downstream of the plasma-forming region, in the plasma afterglow. The O2 is electronically dissociated in the plasma afterglow to create atomic oxygen (O) with no effect on the electrical properties. A ratio of 0.3% v/v, O2/He generates a maximum in O production. Careful electrical probe measurements and circuit analyses reveal the strong effect of commercial passive voltage probes on the total load impedance of the APGD-t circuit. The larger the probe capacitance and cable length, the larger the component of the phase angle between the load voltage and circuit current signals induced by the probe. The calibration of the phase angles induced by the voltage probes allows to estimate that a resistive power of ~0.24-1 W is dissipated in the APGD- t under nominal operating conditions. The gas kinetic and atomic He excitation temperatures, and the electron density near the APGD-t nozzle exit are estimated at ≈323 K, ≈1914 K and ≈1011 cm-3, respectively. This confirms that the APGD-t plasma jet near the nozzle exit is in a non-thermal equilibrium state. The emission spectroscopy study reveals the entrainment of air molecules (N2, O2 and H2O) in the plasma jet, and that their excitation by the plasma creates new reactive species (O and OH). A preliminary survey of the chemical reactions taking place in the plasma afterglow reveals that metastable He as well as OH, O, O2(a1Δg), O2(b1Σg+), N2, N2+ and O3 are plasma species that can reach and react with organic or biological surfaces located a few mm downstream of the APGD-t nozzle exit. This thesis demonstrates that the APGD-t is a promising tool for localized biomedical applications.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53x116k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sz050</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395wc70g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on prolactin and its receptor during late embryogenesis in turkeys and chickens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leclerc, Benoît</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Changes in the levels of expression of the prolactin receptor (PRLR) mRNA in the pituitary gland, hypothalamus, liver, pancreas, kidney and gonad from embryonic day (ED) 15 and ED21 to 1 day post-hatch, respectively, in chickens and turkeys were measured by real-time PCR. In both species, PRLR mRNA increased from low levels during the last week of ED to reach maxima at the peri-hatch period. Similarly, circulating levels of prolactin (PRL) also increased during this interval and were correlated with the observed increases in tissue content of PRLR mRNA. This suggested that PRL was up-regulating its own receptor during late embryogenesis. In support of this, in vitro stimulation of the pituitary gland of turkeys with VIP on ED24 resulted in a 4 fold and 3 fold increase in PRL and PRLR, respectively. Stimulation with VIP of either the hypothalamus or gonad had no effect on either levels of the PRLR transcript. This suggests that VIP acts indirectly through increased PRL to upregulate the number of receptors. In order to investigate the transcription of genes that may be induced/suppressed by PRL, suppressive subtractive hybridization (SSH) libraries from control or VIP stimulated ED24 turkey pituitary glands were constructed. Stimulation with VIP resulted in a 5.7 and 2.8 fold increase in media and pituitary content of PRL, respectively. The changes in PRL were consistent with endogenous levels of PRL observed just prior to hatch. Following sequence analysis of random clones (n=96) from each library, a total of 145 non-redundant putative genes were obtained. About 51% of the putative genes have as yet no assigned function, whereas, 15% were housekeeping genes and 34% had known functions within various pathways. Real-time PCR was used to confirm the differential expression of 21 of these genes in VIP treated and control pituitaries. Since the majority of these genes were expressed at levels consistent with the direction of subtraction, these data suggest that these libraries may be useful to study the direct and indirect effects of increasing levels of PRL on anterior pituitary function at about the time of hatch.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19fb19j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wc70g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chickens -- Embryology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prolactin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Turkeys -- Embryology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xj98z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lithic raw material variability and the reduction of short-term use implements : an example from Northwestern New Mexico</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lerner, Harry Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chipped stone tools are a truly dynamic medium of material culture. From initial reduction to contemporary excavation, lithic artifacts undergo continuous change. The role of the properties of raw materials in determining rates of use-wear accrual is poorly understood and has rarely been assessed quantitatively (e.g. Goodman, 1944; Greiser and Sheets, 1979; McDevitt, 1994). This dissertation offers such quantification regarding four materials exploited for the production of short-term use implements at the Late Archaic FA2-13 site located just outside the city of Farmington, New Mexico. Both experimental and archaeological use-wear evidence was assessed in separate but related ways. Digital image analysis of use-wear invasiveness using ClemexVision PE and GIS analysis of use-wear homogeneity using Idrisi Kilimanjaro yielded distinct but highly complementary results. Direct testing of material properties of non-archaeological samples using a Hysitron Triboindenter served to further clarify these findings in terms of the complex relationship between raw material surface hardness and roughness. The results of the present study show that there are significant differences between rates of wear accrual among the four materials. Analysis of tools from FA2-13 indicates that while scraping activities likely did predominate (Schutt, 1997a), it may also be feasible to generate more detailed assessments regarding the kinds of scraping activities that were undertaken and the respective intensities with which they were performed. This increased insight can then be extrapolated for application to long-term use technologies and their more complex life histories.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172234x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj98z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tools, Prehistoric -- New Mexico</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stone implements -- New Mexico</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d832c"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanisms of innate immunity to blood-stage malaria infection : role of dendritic cells in host-parasite interactions and induction of protective immunity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ing, Rebecca Yat Loo, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A favorable outcome of blood-stage malaria infection requires immune responses that effectively eliminate the infection with minimum pathology to the host. There is strong evidence that the innate immune system is critical for initiating and shaping the subsequent adaptive immune response to blood-stage Plasmodium parasites. As sentinels of infection and potent activators of immunity, dendritic cells (DCs) are pivotally positioned to control the immune response to malaria and thereby influence the outcome of infection. Experiments performed in this thesis work aimed to determine the role of DCs in host-parasite interactions and subsequent induction of protective immunity to blood-stage malaria. Moreover, the studies described herein emphasize the critical contributions of key cytokines to DC responses and interactions with other cells of the innate and adaptive immune system during blood-stage malaria. Based on previous linkage analyses that identified interleukin (IL)-15 as a candidate in genetic regulation of host resistance to blood-stage malaria, we demonstrated that IL-15 is important for timely resolution of a primary infection with Plasmodium chabaudi AS and maximal production of Th1-type cytokines and antibodies. Notably, IL-15 was revealed to be a key early cytokine for optimal DC and natural killer (NK) cell function as well as IL-12-dependent IFN-gamma production following P. chabaudi infection. Next, we demonstrated the ability of DCs to recognize and phagocytose parasitized red blood cells (pRBCs) in a highly selective and actin-dependent manner. Following interaction with pRBCs in vitro or in vivo, DCs from malaria-resistant mouse strains were shown to express upregulated costimulatory molecules and secrete abundant Th1-polarizing cytokines, particularly IL-12 and IFN-gamma. These signals enable DCs to prime other immune cells such as NK cells and CD4+ T cells for maximal IFN-gamma production. Reciprocally, malaria-activated NK cells were shown to induce DC maturation and production of Th1-polarizing cytokines, thus propagating an innate feedback loop leading to induction of Th1 immunity. DCs from malaria-susceptible A/J mice, however, showed impaired Th1 priming in favor of selective induction of IL-10-secreting CD4+ T cells, suggesting DC-mediated activation of tolerance, not immunity, in hosts unable to control and survive blood-stage malaria. These findings provide novel and important insights into the DC-mediated immune mechanisms that initiate and regulate host resistance to blood-stage malaria infection.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kp865.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d832c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d182n"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Netrin and netrin receptor function in glial motility and myelination</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jarjour, Andrew A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Netrin-1 and its receptors play crucial roles during embryogenesis, guiding axon and neuronal cell migration. Here, roles of netrins and their receptors in glial function were investigated. In the embryonic spinal cord, netrin-1 expressed at the ventral midline orients axon extension. Spinal oligodendrocyte precursor (OP) cells are born close to, and migrate away from, the ventral midline. We find that OPs express DCC and UNC5 netrin receptors and, in an in vitro microchemotaxis assay, are repelled by a netrin-1 gradient. In the absence of netrin-1 or DCC function in vivo, fewer OPs migrate from the ventral to the dorsal embryonic spinal cord, consistent with netrin-1 acting as a repellent guidance cue for these cells. In the adult CNS, oligodendrocytes continue to express DCC and UNC5 receptors, and upregulate netrin-1 expression. Our findings indicate that netrin-1 and its receptors are localized to paranodal axo-glial junctions, specialized cell-cell adhesions between non-compact myelin loops and axons. In myelinating cerebellar slice cultures derived from neonatal DCC-/- and netrin-1-/- mice, paranodes develop and mature normally but later become disorganized, resulting in loss of domain segregation at the nodal region. These data suggest that netrin-1 and DCC are essential for the maintenance of paranodal junctions, and may be indicative of a wider role in mediating cell-cell contacts in the adult. Netrin-1, DCC, and UNC5 homologues have also been identified as putative tumor suppressors, and their expression is downregulated in many cancers, including glial tumors. In our studies, netrins were found to act as autocrine factors that restrain human glioblastoma cell migration, slowing cell movement and inhibiting the formation of focal contacts associated with lamellipodial protrusion and membrane extension. DCC and UNC5 homologues have previously been proposed to inhibit tumorigenesis by inducing cell death when unbound by netrin. However, we found no evidence of increased cell death in the absence of netrin function in oligodendrocyte precursors, oligodendrocytes or glioma cells. Instead, we find that netrins act as long-range guidance cues during glial precursor migration during development, while acting at short distances to stabilize cell-cell and cell-matrix interactions of mature glia and glial tumor cells, maintaining tissue organization and preventing inappropriate cell motility.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9034218.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d182n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92gc43t"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Meta-analysis of multiple outcomes : fundamentals and applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ishak, Khajak</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Meta-analyses often consider the effect of a treatment on multiple, possibly related outcomes. Typically, summary estimates are derived from outcome-specific meta-analyses. Alternatively, a joint analysis can be conducted with a multivariate meta-analysis model, which also quantifies the correlation between the outcomes. This dissertation presents findings from analyses examining issues pertaining to the accuracy of the multivariate approach and its application to meta-analyses of longitudinal studies. Correlations measured in multivariate meta-analysis models can provide added insight about the treatment and disease. To be useful, however, the measured correlations must reflect the underlying biological relationships between treatment effects. I demonstrate, however, that correlations measured across studies may often be distorted by associations between the endpoints or random errors affecting outcomes within studies in a similar way. Thus, correlations measured in multivariate meta-analyses can be misleading. To properly weight the contribution of each study, the variance of sampling distributions of each estimate is fixed to its observed value. In the multivariate case, however, the sampling distribution also involves covariances between effect estimates on the different outcomes. These are rarely available and must, therefore, be approximated from external information. I evaluated the impact of errors in these approximations on estimates of the parameters of the model in a simulation study. Summary effects and heterogeneity were estimated accurately, but the correlation parameter was prone to possibly large biases and lacked precision. Longitudinal studies often report treatment effects measured at different times. Multivariate meta-analyses can account for the correlations inherent to this type of data. Alternatively, random-effects can be specified to capture the marginal correlations. I contrasted these and the standard time-specific meta-analysis approaches using data from a review of studies of deep brain stimulation. Multivariate models, and to a slightly lesser extent the random-effects models, provided better fit and more precise estimates in the interval with fewest observations. These models were also less affected by an apparently outlying observation. This suggests a potential borrowing of information from estimates at other times. This work builds on research about the potential advantages and limitations of joint meta-analyses of multiple outcomes.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t61r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gc43t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kf96s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of process parameters on TLP bonding of Inconel 617 superalloy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jalilian, Farzad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Joining of superalloy Inconel 617 using a foil interlayer with transient liquid phase bonding (TLP) was studied. Inconel 617 is a solid solution, Ni-Cr-Co-Mo alloy with an exceptional combination of high temperature strength, oxidation and carburization resistance and thermal stability. Two types of interlayer compositions for the TLP bonding process were selected. Specifically, boron containing (AWS BNi-3) and phosphorus rich (AWS BNi-6) were employed as melting point depressant (MPD) elements. Process parameters such as bonding temperature, holding time, composition and thickness of interlayer were selected for study. Two bonding temperatures, 1065°C and 1150°C, and two interlayer thicknesses with various holding times ranging from 5 minutes to 24 hours were selected. Joints were fabricated using Inconel 617 specimens measuring 25 mm long, 5 mm wide and 1 mm thick. A tube furnace under vacuum (1 x 10-5 mbar) was used to carry out the experiments. The specimens were fixed with stainless steel fixture and held at the bonding temperature for the selected times. Optical microscopy, SEM, FEG-SEM, VP-SEM were used to follow microstructure evolution and identify its constituents. The microstructure of the joint area, formation and dissolution of precipitates and the evolution of the base metal grain size with holding time for the two bonding temperatures and interlayer thickness were also characterized using the above techniques. TEM, EBSD and XRD techniques were employed to identify the phases such as borides, carbides, phosphides and other precipitates in the joint area. Microhardness tests of the joint were performed to investigate relationships between microstructure and mechanical properties of the joint. A critical review of the existing theoretical models for isothermal solidification of the TLP bonding was carried out and their application to the obtained results for Inconel 617 was assessed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x87n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kf96s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>