<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021f59j"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of Lasp in the «Drosophila» male stem cell niche and in muscle development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhou, Lili</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chez la drosophile, Lasp est la seule protéine représentante de la famille des Nébuline. Lasp contient un domaine LIM, deux répétitions de type Nébuline et un domaine SH3, et présente une forte homologie avec la famille Lasp des mammifères. Afin identifier le rôle de Lasp, nous avons généré une mutation nulle, nommée Lasp1. Les mutants Lasp1 sont homozygotes viables, mais les mâles stériles. Lasp se localise dans cellules kyste, dans les cellules germinales, les cellules hub et au niveau des cônes d'actine. Chez les mutants Lasp1, les cellules souches ne sont plus ancré à l'extrémité apicale du testicule, et la migration des cônes d'actine est perturbée, conduisant à une individualisation irrégulière des spermatides. Lasp est colocalisée avec l'intégrine βPS et interagit génétiquement avec l'intégrine βPS, amenant une délocalization des cellules hub, indiquant que Lasp module adhésion intégrine dans ce contexte. Les larves mutantes pour Lasp se déplacent avec difficulté et les adultes ont avec une capacité d'escalade et de vols réduite. Lasp se localise aux lignes Z dans les muscles  des larves du troisième stade. Chez les adultes Lasp1, les muscles des ailes présentent une longueur réduite des filaments minces ainsi que des sarcomères, alors que l'ultrastructure  du sarcomère ne semble pas être significativement affectée. Les muscles larvaires présentent le phenotype. De plus, on observe un dérèglement de la longueur du sarcomère en surexprimant Lasp dans un contexte sauvage. Ce phénotype est très similaire à  celui des souris mutantes  pour la nébuline, indiquant que Lasp joue un rôle dans la régulation de la longueur du filament mince, mais avec seulement deux répétitions nébuline. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Drosophila Lasp is the only member of the nebulin family in Drosophila. Lasp has an amino-terminal LIM domain, two actin-binding nebulin repeats and a carboxyl-terminal SH3 domain and exhibits very high homology to human Lasp. To assess Lasp function in vivo, we generated a null mutant in Drosophila Lasp, named Lasp1. Lasp1 mutants are homozygous viable, but male sterile. Lasp localizes to cyst cells, early germ cells, hub cells and actin cones. In Lasp1 mutants, the stem cell niche is no longer anchored to the apical tip of the testis, and actin cone migration is perturbed resulting in improper spermatid individualization. Lasp colocalizes with βPS integrin and genetically interact with βPS integrin resulting in complete hub cell mislocalization, which indicates that Lasp modulates integrin adhesion in this context.  Lasp1 mutant larvae and flies also have impaired crawling, climbing and flying ability. Lasp localizes to Z lines of third instar larval body wall muscles. In Lasp1 mutant indirect flight muscle, thin filament and sarcomere length is reduced while sarcomere ultrastructure is not significantly affected. The same applies to larval body wall muscles, where we observe a misregulation of sarcomere length in both absence and overexpression of Lasp. This phenotype is very similar to nebulin mutant knock-out mice indicating that Lasp plays a role in regulating thin filament lengths, but with only two nebulin repeats.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frieder Schöck</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q932q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021f59j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k762z"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identifying the phosphorylation sites on 4E-T protein</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taheri Heravi, Navid</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Abstract 4E-T, a novel binding partner of eIF4E protein, transports 4E from the cytoplasm to the nucleus. This protein is also involved in mRNA degradation. 4E-T binds to eIF4E and carries eIF4E-protein along with the mRNA to P-bodies, which is the site of mRNA degradation.  In this study, we show that 4E-T is a phospho-protein and is phosphorylated on multiple sites. We tried to identify some of the phosphorylation sites on this protein. By using overlapping PCR, a triple phospho mutant of this protein was made.  We also investigated if 4E-T is phosphorylated by the S6 kinase (S6K). Our results indicate that even though 4E-T contains the phosphorylation motif of S6 kinase, S6K is not a kinase of this protein.  Moreover, we examined if 4E-T phosphorylation on Ser213, 353 resides changes the interaction between this protein and 4E-HP. We could not find any evidence showing that the binding of these proteins together is dependent of phosphorylation of 4E-T on Ser213, 353 amino acids.   Finally, we show that the interaction between 4E-T and 4E proteins is not regulated by phosphorylation.  The Phospho-triple mutant of 4E-T protein can be used a strong tool to elucidate the function of this protein and how the interaction between this protein and its partners is regulated.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Résumé  4E-T, un nouveau partenaire de liaison à la protéine 4E, transporte 4E du cytoplasme au noyau. Il a aussi été démontré que cette protéine est impliquée dans la dégradation de l'ARNm. 4E-T lie 4E et la transporte, ainsi que l'ARNm, au P-bodies, site de la dégradation des ARNm. Ici, nous démontrons que 4E-T est une phosphoprotéine et qu'elle est phosphorylée en plusieurs endroits. Nous avons tenté d'identifier certains des sites de phosphorylation de cette protéine. En utilisant l'overlapping PCR, un phospho-mutant triple de cette protéine a été créé. Nous avons aussi vérifié si 4E-T est phosphorylée par la kinase S6 (S6K). Nos résultats indiquent que, même si 4E-T contient le motif de phosphorylation de la kinase S6, S6K n'est pas une kinase de cette protéine. De plus, nous avons examiné si la phosphorylation de 4E-T change l'interaction entre cette protéine et 4E-HP. Nous n'avons trouvé aucune preuve que la liaison de ces protéines entre elles serait phospho-dépendante. Finalement, nous démontrons que l'interaction entre 4E-T et 4E n'est pas régulée par la phosphorylation.  Le phospho-mutant triple de 4E-T peut être utilisé comme un puissant outil pour élucider la fonction de cette protéine et comment l'interaction entre cette protéine et ses partenaires est régulée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nahum Sonenberg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd341.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k762z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000034t"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Training in self-compassion: reducing distress and facilitating behaviour change</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kelly, Allison</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les psychologues évolutionnistes soutiennent qu'un système interne apaisant existe dans chaque individu afin de lui permettre de déceler des indices de bienveillance et de chaleur humaine dans son environnement et de tirer la conclusion qu'il est en sécurité. Gilbert (2005) a proposé que parmi les individus aux prises avec un sentiment de honte, un trouble de santé mentale ou une dépendance, ce système apaisant est sous actif mais peut être réactivé par le biais d'exercices  « d'entraînement à l'auto compassion ». Mis à part des études de Neff (2003a) qui a démontré que la tendance naturelle d'un individu à ressentir de la compassion pour soi-même influence son bien-être, aucune autre étude contrôlée et randomisée sur les effets de l'entraînement à l'auto compassion n'a été effectuée. Cette dissertation vient pallier à ce manque en présentant deux études sur l'entraînement à l'auto compassion. Dans la première étude, Kelly, Zuroff et Shapira (2009) ont assigné de façon aléatoire 75 personnes souffrant d'acné à l'une de trois conditions suivantes: auto compassion apaisante, résistance à l'autodénigrement et condition contrôle (liste d'attente). Sur une période de deux semaines, les participants à qui on avait demandé au quotidien d'utiliser l'auto compassion apaisante (à l'aide de l'imagerie mentale et le du discours intérieur) ont rapporté une diminution du sentiment de honte, un meilleur fonctionnement psychosocial et une amélioration de leurs symptômes d'acné comparativement aux sujets de la condition contrôle. Les participants à qui on avait demandé de contrer l'autodénigrement à l'aide d'une imagerie mentale et un discours intérieur misant sur la force et la résilience ont obtenu sensiblement les mêmes résultats; ce groupe a aussi rapporté des niveaux inférieurs de dépression, et cela plus particulièrement s'ils rapportaient un haut niveau d'autocritique en début de traitement. La deuxièm</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Evolutionary psychologists posit that a soothing system evolved to detect cues of warmth and kindness in the environment and signal that the organism is safe. Gilbert (2005) proposed that among individuals suffering from shame, mental illness, and addiction, this system is underactive but can be re-activated by “compassionate mind training” (CMT) exercises. Although dispositional levels of self-compassion have been found to predict well-being (Neff, 2003a), there have been no randomized controlled trials (RCTs) on the effects of training oneself in self-compassion. The current dissertation presents two RCTs of CMT-based interventions. In Study 1, Kelly, Zuroff, and Shapira (2009) randomly assigned 75 distressed acne sufferers to one of three conditions: compassionate self-soothing, resisting of self-attacks, and wait-list control. Over two weeks, participants instructed to engage in daily self-compassionate imagery and self-talk reported less shame, better psychosocial functioning, and improved acne symptoms compared to a control condition. Participants instructed to stand up to their-self-attacks with a strong, resilient image had these same outcomes but additionally reported reduced depression, particularly if they were high in self-criticism. Study 2 sought to investigate whether and for whom self-compassion training might facilitate behaviour change. Kelly, Zuroff, Foa, and Gilbert (in press) randomly assigned 126 smokers to one of four interventions. Individuals instructed to engage in self-compassionate imagery and self-talk at every urge to smoke reduced their cigarette consumption more quickly than those in the control condition, and as quickly as those who engaged in self-energizing and self-controlling imagery and self-talk. Furthermore, self-compassion training was particularly effective for participants who were ambivalent about change or self-critical at baseline, or if they had vivid imagery while performing the intervention exercises. Findings su</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David C. Zuroff</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w61z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000034t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Clinical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jk76p"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Desautels Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Four essays on dynamic dependence in large portfolios</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jin, Xisong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis comprises four essays that explore large portfolio dynamic dependence risk related to defaults, risk management and asset allocation, international financial markets, and herding behavior. The first essay investigates the dependence between companies' defaults. We compare credit correlations implied by the prices of collateralized debt obligations with time-varying correlations estimated from equity returns and credit default swaps. We find that the correlations between default intensities from swap spreads are highly time-varying and persistent; the same finding obtains for equity returns. We also find that the correlation implied by structured products co-moves very strongly with the correlation extracted from credit spreads, but less strongly with the correlations between equity returns. Finally, we find that when risk is high in equity and credit markets and when interest rates are low, correlation measures tend to be high. This impedes diversification benefits and depresses prices for senior credit tranches. The second essay develops a new family of Dynamic Conditional Elliptical Copulas to model dynamic high dimensional multivariate distribution for risk management and asset allocation. I examine Value at Risk (VaR) and Expected Shortfall (ES) by Monte Carlo simulation for passive portfolios and dynamic optimal portfolios through Mean-Variance and ES criteria. I find that these copulas work very well for both VaR and ES, and the optimal portfolio by ES does a good job against the tail risk. The third essay studies dependence risk in international financial markets. We investigate patterns and trends in correlations over time for large sets of developed markets (DMs) and emerging markets (EMs). We find that correlations have been significantly trending upward for both the DMs and EMs. The tail dependence has also increased for both EMs and DMs, but its level is still very low for EMs as compared to DMs. Thus, our correlation analysis suggests tha</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse se compose de quatre essais qui explorent la dynamique du risque de dépendance pour les larges portefeuilles, en relation avec la gestion du risque, l'allocation d'actifs, les marchés financiers internationaux, et les comportements moutonniers des investisseurs. Le premier essai examine la dépendance entre les défauts des entreprises. Nous comparons les corrélations de crédit impliquées par les prix d'obligations adossées à des actifs avec des corrélations variables au cours du temps, estimées à partir des rendements des actions et des swaps sur défaillance de crédit. Nous constatons que les corrélations entre les intensités des défauts implicites dans les primes des swaps sont très variables dans le temps et persistantes; on obtient un résultat similaire pour les rendements des actions. Nous constatons également que les mouvements de la corrélation impliquées par les produits structurés sont fortement corrélés avec la corrélation extraite des primes de crédit, mais moins fortement avec les corrélations entre les rendements des actions. Enfin, nous constatons que lorsque le risque est élevé dans les marchés d'actions et de crédit et lorsque les taux d'intérêt sont bas, les mesures de corrélation ont tendance à être élevées. Ceci entrave la diversification et fait baisser les prix pour les tranches de crédit senior. Le deuxième essai développe une nouvelle famille de Copules Dynamiques Conditionnelles Elliptiques afin de modéliser la dynamique de distributions avec un nombre élevé de dimensions dans la gestion des risques et l'allocation d'actifs. J'examine la méthode de la valeur à risque (VaR or Value at Risk) et de la perte attendue (ES or Expected Shortfall) par simulation Monte-Carlo pour des portefeuilles passifs et des portefeuilles dynamiques optimaux en considérant les critères de moyenne variance (Mean-Variance) et la perte attendue (ES). Je trouve que ces copules fonctionnent très bien pour$</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kris J. J. Jacobs</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Peter Frederik Christoffersen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569488n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jk76p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics - Finance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1616563"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Temporal coordination in music performance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Loehr, Janeen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates temporal coordination in music performance. Previous investigations of temporal coordination have focused on people's coordination of simple movements with experimenter-controlled stimulus sequences or with other people performing similar movements. The research presented here focuses instead on coordination of the rhythmically and sequentially complex sequences required of music performance. The study presented in Chapter 2 shows that musicians adapt the timing of their movements relative to a stimulus sequence in response to sensory information that occurs in the intervals between stimulus events. The amount of adaptation depends on the modality of the sensory information, but adaptation is evident whether the sensory information arises from the performer or from an external source. The experiments presented in Chapter 3 show that musicians are better able to adapt the timing of their movements when coordinating them with a stimulus sequence that decreases rather than increases in rate. This work also shows that musicians' coordination performance better matches the predictions of an oscillator model of temporal coordination than a timekeeper model. The influence of individual differences in musical experience on coordination performance is also demonstrated. Chapter 4 investigates interpersonal coordination between pairs of pianists. This work shows some evidence that each performer in a pair activates mental representations of his or her co-performer's actions during temporal coordination. This study also shows that differences between performers' preferred performance rates influence the accuracy of the temporal coordination between them, and that performing with a partner influences individual performers' subsequent performance rates. Together, this work sheds light on the influence of sensory information and events occurring at multiple temporal levels on coordination performance, elucidates the mechanisms underlying adaptation to</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse explore la coordination temporelle nécessaire à la performance musicale. Les études sur la coordination temporelle se sont jusqu'à maintenant principalement intéressé à la coordination de mouvements simples faits par des individus en réponse à des séquences de stimuli contrôlées par l'expérimentateur ou à des mouvements exécutés par d'autres individus. Les travaux de recherche présentés ici se concentrent plutôt sur la coordination de séquences rythmiquement et séquentiellement complexes requise durant la performance musicale. L'étude présentée dans le Chapitre 2 démontre que les musiciens adaptent le rythme de leurs mouvements à une séquence de stimuli en réponse à l'information sensorielle disponible durant les intervalles séparant les stimuli. La magnitude de l'adaptation dépend de la modalité de l'information sensorielle, mais l'adaptation a lieu que l'information sensorielle provienne de l'interprète ou d'une source externe. Les études  présentées dans le Chapitre 3 démontrent que les musiciens adaptent le rythme de leurs mouvements plus facilement lorsqu'ils les coordonnent à une séquence de stimuli diminuant plutôt qu'augmentant en vitesse. Ces travaux démontrent aussi que la performance de coordination des musiciens est mieux expliquée par un modèle oscillatoire que chronométrique. L'influence des différences individuelles en termes d'expérience musicale sur la coordination est aussi démontrée. Le Chapitre 4 s'intéresse à la coordination interpersonnelle au sein de paires de pianistes. Ces travaux suggèrent que chaque interprète active une représentation mentale des actions de leur co-interprète pendant la coordination temporelle. Cette étude démontre aussi que les différences de préférence individuelles en termes de rapidité de performance au sein d'une paire d'interprètes influencent la précision de leur coordination. Elle démontre que la performance au sein d'une paire influenc</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Caroline Palmer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w23m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1616563</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Cognitive</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000000353"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Self-criticism and personal standards dimensions of perfectionism and daily depressive symptoms in depressed patients: daily stress and avoidant coping as mediating traits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Berg, Jody-Lynn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study of depressed outpatients (N = 52) examined the role of personal standards (PS) and self-criticism (SC) dimensions of perfectionism in daily stress, coping, and depressive symptoms.  Prior to treatment, participants completed interviews and questionnaires in a lab session and then completed daily reports of stress, coping, and depressive symptoms at the end of the day for 7 consecutive days. Trait influences were found in the daily reports of stress, appraisals, coping, and depressive symptoms. In contrast to PS, SC was related to aggregated daily stress, negative social interactions, low perceived control, self-blame, avoidant coping, and guilt controlling for depressive severity. Path analyses demonstrated that the relation between SC and depressive symptoms was mediated by avoidant coping both directly and indirectly through event stress.  Overall, these findings demonstrate the importance of clinicians focusing on the maladaptive aspects associated with self-critical components of perfectionism in the treatment for depression.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Résumé Cette étude a examiné le rôle de deux dimensions du perfectionnisme (les «standards personnels» et  l'autocritique) dans la perception du stress, les stratégies d'adaptation au stress et les symptômes dépressifs chez les personnes diagnostiquées avec une dépression (N = 52). Avant de commencer leur traitement, les participants ont rempli des questionnaires et ont participé à une séance d'entrevue dans notre laboratoire. Ensuite, pendant sept jours consécutifs, et ce, à la fin de la journée, les participants ont complété à domicile des questionnaires portant sur le stress vécu au quotidien, les stratégies d'adaptation au stress, les traits de personnalité et les symptômes dépressifs. Les résultats indiquent que les traits de personnalité influencent le nombre de stress vécu quotidiennement, l'évaluation du stress, les stratégies d'adaptation au stress et les symptômes dépressifs. Lorsque le niveau des symptômes dépressifs est maintenu égal pour tous, contrairement au perfectionnisme «standards personnels», le perfectionnisme autocritique est lié au stress vécu quotidiennement, à des interactions sociales négatives, à la perception de faible contrôle sur la situation stressante, à l'auto-accusation, à la culpabilité et à l'évitement. Une analyse des pistes causales a montré que le lien entre le perfectionnisme autocritique et les symptômes dépressifs passe directement et indirectement par l'évitement et ce, par le biais du stress. En somme, ces résultats démontrent la nécessité pour les cliniciens de se concentrer sur les aspects dysfonctionnels associés à la dimension autocritique du perfectionnisme lors du traitement de la dépression. fr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Michael Dunkley</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gail Myhr</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw22z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000000353</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Clinical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405s9735"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Discourses and gender in doctoral physics: a hard look inside a hard science</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gonsalves, Allison</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Canada today, a gender disparity persists in the enrolment and persistence of doctoral students in physics.  Scholarship on this disparity has, in the past, focused on issues of equity and difference in order to find ways to recruit and retain more women in physics.  This approach offered a limited perspective on gender and relied on essentialist notions of being a man, woman or physicist. This study highlights the importance of a focus on gender as an aspect of identity construction, thus opening up possibilities for exploring how doctoral students navigate ideologies of gender at the same time that they learn how to become physicists.  Doctoral physics students have stories about what kinds of actions, behaviours and ways of doing physics allow individuals to be recognized as physicists. Viewing a physics department as a case study, and individual participants as embedded cases, this study uses a sociocultural approach to examine the ways doctoral students construct these stories about becoming physicists.  Through observations, photo-elicitation, and life history interviews, eleven men and women shared stories about their experiences with physics, and the contexts that have enabled or constrained their trajectories into doctoral physics. The results of this study revealed the salience of recognition in the constitution of physicist identities: individuals who saw themselves, or were seen by others, as physicists were more likely to pursue trajectories into academic physics. Further, various interchangeable forms of competence emerged as assets that can be used to achieve recognition in this physics community: technical, analytical, and academic competence were identified by participants as characteristics necessary to achieve recognition as a physicist. Additionally, achieving recognition as a competent physicist often involved a complex negotiation of gender roles and the practice of physics.  The results demonstrated that a persistent tension exists between participants‘ conventional and gendered descriptions of doing physics and being physicists, and the actual business of doing physics and being physicists. The study offers new perspectives on the interaction between gender and physics, and challenges current thinking about the reason for gender inequality in science and the best methods for rectifying that inequality. The dissertation ends with recommendations for further research and suggestions for the undergraduate and graduate physics curriculum.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Au Canada, aujourd'hui, une disparité entre les sexes persiste concernant les inscriptions et la rétention des étudiants qui poursuivent leurs études doctorales en physique. Dans le passé, les recherches sur cette disparité ont portées sur les questions d'égalité et de la différence afin de trouver des moyens pour recruter et garder davantage de femmes en physique. Cette approche a offert une perspective limitée sur les sexes et s'est appuyé sur les notions d'essentialiste d'être un homme, une femme ou un physicien. Cette étude souligne l'importance de l'égalité des sexes comme un aspect de la construction de l'identité, ouvrant ainsi des possibilités pour explorer comment les étudiants doctorales naviguent les idéologies des sexes en même temps qu'ils apprennent à devenir physiciens.  Les étudiants poursuivant des études doctorales en physique ont des histoires des types d'actions, des comportements et des méthodes de la physique permettent aux individus d'être reconnus comme physiciens. En présentant un département de physique comme une étude de cas et des participants individuels comme des cas intégrés, cette étude utilise une approche socioculturelle pour examiner les manières que les étudiants poursuivant un doctorat construisent des histoires qui racontent comment ils deviennent physiciens. Grâce à des observations, extractions avec photos et entrevues d'histoire de la vie, onze hommes et femmes ont partagés des histoires au sujet de leurs expériences avec la physique et les contextes qui ont favorisé ou ont contraints leurs trajectoires menant au doctorat de physique.  Les résultats de cette étude ont révélés la reconnaissance saillante dans la constitution des identités des physiciens : des individus qui se sont vus ou qui ont été vus par d'autres comme physiciens étaient plus susceptibles de poursuivre leurs trajectoires menant au doctorat en  physique. De plus, diverses formes interchangeables de compétence ont apparus en tant qu'atouts qui peuvent être utilisés pour atteindre la reconnaissance dans la communauté physique: les compétences techniques, analytiques et académiques ont été identifiées par les participants comme des caractéristiques nécessaires pour atteindre la reconnaissance en tant que physiciens.
De plus, gagner la reconnaissance en tant que physiciens compétents impliquait souvent une négociation complexe des rôles entre les sexes et la pratique de la physique. Les résultats ont démontré qu'une tension persistante existe entre les descriptions conventionnels et les descriptions sexospécifiques des participants qui pratiquent la physique et qui sont physiciens, et de la pratique actuel de la physique et d'être physiciens. L'étude offre de nouvelles perspectives sur l'interaction entre les sexes et la physique, et met au défi les pensées actuelles sur la raison de l'inégalité entre les sexes dans les sciences et les meilleures méthodes pour rectifier cette inégalité. La thèse se termine par des recommandations pour des recherches plus approfondie et des suggestions pour le cursus des études du premier cycle ainsi que les études supérieures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lynn McAlpine</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Anthony W. Pare</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333261k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s9735</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rp130"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Volatile organic compounds in the marine troposphere and surface oceans: methods, measurements and biogeochemical implications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hudson, Edward</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Volatile organic compounds (VOCs), among them non-methane hydrocarbons (NMHCs) and low molecular weight carbonyl compounds (aldehydes and ketones), affect the oxidative capacity of the atmosphere and thus pollutant lifetimes and global climate. VOCs in the surface oceans may be transported into, or derived from, the atmosphere.  This thesis describes the development and optimization of chromatographic and preconcentration methods to determine volatile organic compounds (VOCs) in surface seawater and marine air, and their use to explore VOC distribution and fluxes at the sea-air interface.   It includes the first measurements of many carbonyl compounds in temperate and subarctic marine waters and the first estimates of fluxes of several aldehydes from the ocean surface into the marine atmosphere. Sea surface air, size-fractionated marine aerosols, and surface ocean water dissolved organic matter were simultaneously sampled in the Nordic seas.  Nineteen C2-C7 NMHCs were quantified in the air samples. Site-to-site variability in NMHC concentrations was high, suggesting variable, local sources. The aerosols consisted mainly of inorganic marine material, but a culturable bacterium identified as Micrococcus luteus was also isolated from the 9.9 – 18 micrometre fraction, suggesting organic matter may be transferred from the surface oceans to the atmosphere by marine aerosols.   Lastly, a number of VOCs, including acetone, were detected in the seawater samples using solid-phase microextraction (SPME), leading to the subsequent development of  an SPME application for carbonyl compounds in seawater. A mobile, economical and solventless method for the detection and quantification of carbonyl compounds in seawater, a matrix of global importance, was developed.  The compounds were derivatized using O-(2,3,4,5,6-pentafluorobenzyl)-hydroxylamine (PFBHA)and then pre-concentrated by SPME for gas chromatography with mass spectrometric (GC/MS) or flame ionization (GC-FID) detectio</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les  composés organiques volatils (COV),  une classe de composés qui inclut les hydrocarbures non méthaniques (HCNM) et les composés carbonylés (aldéhydes et cétones) de faibles masses moléculaires, affectent la capacité oxydante de l'atmosphère et, par consequent,  le temps de résidence des polluants de même que le climat à l'échelle globale. Les COV présents dans l'eau de surface océanique peuvent être transferés de l'océan vers l'atmosphère ou vice versa.  Cette thèse décrit le développement et l'optimisation de méthodes chromatographiques et de pré-concentration pour la détermination des COV dans l'eau de mer et dans l'air marin, ainsi que leur utilisation dans l'exploration de la distribution des COV et leurs flux à l'interface air-mer.   Les premières déterminations de la concentration de plusieurs composés carbonylés dans l'eau de mer tempérée et subarctique, de même que les premières estimations du flux de plusieurs aldéhydes de l'océan vers  l'atmosphère marin sont aussi incluses. L'air de surface, de l'aérosol marin distribué en taille et de la matière organique dissoute présente dans l'eau de mer de surface ont été échantillonnés simultanément dans les mers nordiques.  Dix-neuf hydrocarbures non méthaniques de C2 à  C7 ont été quantifiés dans les échantillons d'air. Une grande variabilité dans les concentrations de HCNM  mesurées d'un site à l'autre indique la présence de sources locales et variables.  L'aérosol était composé principalement de matière inorganique d'origine marine, mais une bactérie cultivable, Micrococcus luteus, a été isolée à partir de la fraction des particules mesurant de 9,9 à 18 micromètres, ce qui suggère que le matière organique peut être transferée de l'océan à l'atmosphère par l' aérosol marin.  De plus, certains COV, dont l'acétone, ont été détectés dans les échantillons d'eau de mer grâce à la technique de micro-extraction sur phase solide (</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Parisa A. Ariya</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq53r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp130</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Analytical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh248"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mitochondrial dysfunction and reactive oxygen species metabolism in the aging process of «Caenorhabditis elegans»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Wen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nematode roundworm Caenorhabditis elegans has been extensively used to study the genetics of aging. The functions of many genes have been found to be able to affect this animal's lifespan.  A large proportion of these genes are expressed in mitochondria, an organelle that plays important roles in energy metabolism and generates reactive oxygen species (ROS). These two characteristics of mitochondria have both been suggested to be crucial for lifespan determination. One hypothesis, called the oxidative stress theory of aging, proposes that high oxidative damage caused by ROS generated in mitochondria is the cause of aging. We found that the lifespan-increasing effect of electron transport chain (ETC) mutants (i.e. isp-1 and clk-1) as well as of several other long-lived mutants is not due to low oxidative damage, and that increasing oxidative damage fails to shorten their lifespan. I also identified a new long-lived mutant in a previously uncharacterized gene --nuo-6(qm200)--, which encodes the C. elegans orthologue of the B15 subunit of mammalian mitochondrial complex I. I found that this new mutation increases lifespan through the same pathway as isp-1(qm150) the previously characterized mutation in the iron sulphur subunit of complex III. Using RNA interference to knock down the level of expression of many mitochondrial genes has been found to increase the lifespan of C. elegans and of Drosophila by a mechanism that was assumed to be identical to that at work in mutations that altered the function of mitochondrial proteins. However, using the isp-1 and nuo-6 mutations I have shown that the mechanism that allows these mutants to be long-lived is, unexpectedly, completely distinct from the mechanism triggered by RNAi. Finally, I found that the generation of superoxide (a reactive oxygen species) is actually increased in these mutants, and that this elevation is necessary and sufficient for longevity. These studies challenge the traditional view about the role</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le nématode Caenorhabditis elegans est un organisme modèle qui a été extensivement étudié afin de mieux comprendre les bases de la génétique du vieillissement. Ces études ont mené à l'identification de plusieurs gènes jouant des rôles essentiels dans la détermination de la durée de vie de ce ver rond. La majorité de ces gènes sont exprimés au niveau des mitochondries, des organelles reconnues pour jouer un rôle primordial dans la régulation du métabolisme énergétique et pour être les principales sources des dérivés actifs de l'oxygène (reactive oxygen species, ROS). Ces deux caractéristiques propres aux mitochondries sont  reconnues pour être cruciales dans la détermination de la durée de vie. Elles sont d'ailleurs à l'origine d'une hypothèse sur la cause du vieillissement, la théorie du stress oxydatif, qui propose que la génération de ROS par les mitochondries cause le vieillissement en induisant de façon graduelle des dommages oxydatifs aux divers constituants cellulaires. Dans cette étude, nous avons démontré que l'augmentation de la durée de vie observée chez des nématodes mutants pour des gènes mitochondriaux impliqués dans le transport des électrons (i.e. isp-1 and clk-1) ainsi que chez d'autres mutants reconnus pour leur longévité accrue n'est pas reliée à une diminution des dommages oxydatifs. D'autre part, nous avons montré que leur durée de vie n'est pas réduite suite à l'induction d'un stress oxydatif causant divers dommages. Cette étude nous a aussi amené à identifier un nouveau gène, nuo-6 (qm200), codant pour l'orthologue chez le ver de la sous-unité B15 du complexe I de la chaîne de respiration mitochondrial précédemment caractérisée chez les mammifères. La mutation de ce gène résulte en une augmentation de la durée de vie d'une manière similaire à ce qui est observé chez les vers mutants pour le gène isp-1(qm150), qui code pour une sous-unité du complexe III. L'utilisation d</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Siegfried Hekimi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr31j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh248</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w511b"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An embedded energy storage system for attenuation of wind power fluctuations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Wei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les caratéristiques de l'énergie éolienne sont uniques par rapport aux autres formes de génération conventionnelles. Avec la rapide augmentation des installations éoliennes au niveau mondial, les fluctuations incontrôlables d'énergie éolienne posent un problème majeur aux réseaux électriques qui veulent les intégrer. L'intégration d'un système de stockage d'énergie dans un parc éolien peut réduire les fluctuations de l'énergie produite. Cette thèse propose une solution pour atténuer ces fluctuations en utilisant un système de stockage d'énergie intégrée. Elle définit les technologies, topologies, dimensions et systèmes de commande. Un système hybride consistant en une batterie et un condensateur de grande capacité est proposé. Ces deux technologies complémentaires peuvent fournir à la fois de grandes quantités d'énergie et de puissance. Il en résulte un système qui offre au niveau du réseau électrique d‘autres avantages telles qu'une réponse rapide, un rendement élevé et une longue durée de vie. La nouvelle méthode de stockage d'énergie, qui vise à atténuer les fluctuations de puissance éolienne dans une gamme particulière de fréquence est réalisée. La topologie, la configuration, et le dimensionnement sont étudiés dans un réseau type. Les performances du stockage hybride sous diverses conditions d'opération montrent que la solution de stockage intégré peut efficacement atténuer les fluctuations de puissance éolienne dans la région de fréquence ciblée. Les variations locales de tension et les écarts de fréquence du système qui résultent des variations de la puissance éolienne sont atténuées. Les résultats de simulation sont validés en utilisant deux logiciels différents, et la commande du système de stockage est vérifiée sur un simulateur en temps réel. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Wind power has its unique characteristics other than conventional generators. As wind installations have been increasing rapidly over the world, uncontrollable wind power fluctuations are a major challenge for power systems to accommodate wind power. Embedding an energy storage system in a wind energy system can smooth the output of a wind turbine generator. This thesis proposes an embedded energy storage solution, addressing technology, topology, size, and control schemes to mitigate the adverse impacts of wind power fluctuations on power systems. A flow-battery supercapacitor hybrid storage system, which takes advantage of the two complementary technologies to provide both high energy and power capacities, is proposed for the wind applications. Cooperation of the two storage technologies also provides the system with other advantages, including fast response, high efficiency, and longer life-span. A novel control and energy management scheme, which aims to attenuate wind power fluctuations in a particular frequency range to improve the performance to size ratio, is applied to the hybrid system. Topology, configuration, and size are investigated through a benchmark system demonstrating feasibility. The operation under various situations show that the embedded storage solution can effectively attenuate the wind power fluctuations in the targeted frequency region, in terms of the fluctuation harmonic content, an index of fluctuation intensity of wind powers. The power quality, i.e., wind-induced local voltage variations and system frequency deviations, is improved. The simulation results are cross-validated using two different types of software and the prototype storage controller is verified through real time hardware-in-the-loop tests.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Geza Joos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731430t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w511b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w257x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Efficient adaptive loading algorithms for multicarrier modulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cudnoch, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Communication networks rely increasingly upon wireless systems to provide transmission over the "last mile". This is due not only to the low cost of infrastructures, but also, and perhaps to a larger extent, to their flexibility. Increasingly, the current applications put a large burden on the throughput of those wireless systems. Multicarrier modulation has proven a highly effective technique to sustain such throughput and is now used in numerous current and future standards such as IEEE 802.11a. To take full advantage of that scheme, however, the multicarrier system needs to adapt to the transmission channel's time varying parameter. This can be achieved by adaptive loading algorithms, which unfortunately, are usually computationally expensive. This work addresses the issue of computational complexity within an adaptive loading algorithm by concentrating on the optimization of two algorithms crucial for a multicarrier system's performance: equalization and bit loading. Firstly, a variable-length equalizer algorithm is optimized and modified to make fast large-scale simulations possible. The algorithm is bound to significantly outperform fixed-length schemes of comparable complexity in terms of probability of error of the system. Secondly, an adaptive bit loading algorithm is implemented in real-time. The implementation target is a fixed-point DSP. The algorithm is optimized and an alternate, more computationally efficient version is proposed. The implementation is then tested for robustness and speed of convergence. Both versions of the algorithm converge to a solution well within the time constraint, with the proposed version offering a clearly better performance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jk63m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w257x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301170f"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A simplified Gravity-Recoverable-Gold test</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Clarke, Jason, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gravity-Recoverable-Gold (GRG) is defined as gold present in a particle in sufficient quantities as to be selectively recoverable from gangue via gravity methods. The McGill standard GRG test is an ore characterization test using three stages of sequential liberation and recovery with a Knelson KC-MD3 centrifuge to determine the size distribution of GRG. This thesis describes the development and testing of two simplified versions of the GRG test, using two and one stages of recovery respectively. Both tests use a feed mass of 20 kg, as opposed to the 40 to 100 kg normally used for the standard test. Eighteen differing ore samples were processed with the simplified GRG tests. For non-abrasive ores the one-stage simplified test returns a similar GRG content and size distribution, making the two-stage test superfluous. For abrasive ores, the one-stage test returns a GRG content that can be as much as 33% relative lower than that of the standard test, with a much finer size distribution. The two-stage test exhibited similar poor performance, though to a slightly lesser degree due to and additional stage of recovery attempted prior to grinding the abrasive material. The GRG lost typically reports to size fractions coarser than 25 µm, strongly suggesting smearing onto gangue particles. Because of the lower feed mass used, both simple tests are susceptible to the nugget effect; feed representativity also becomes challenging for ore samples of a head grade of 1 g/t or less.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb11m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301170f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483j64n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of new predictor climate variables for statistical downscaling of daily precipitation process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Choux, Mathieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Statistical downscaling (SD) procedures have been frequently used for assessing the potential impacts of climate change and variability on hydrological regime. These procedures are based on the empirical relationships between large-scale atmospheric variables (predictors) and surface environment parameters (e.g., precipitation and temperature). The present research work is hence concerned with the development of new predictor climate variables that could be used for improving the accuracy of downscaling of daily precipitation process at a local site. The new predictors should be able to provide a more accurate simulation of the local variable since they could describe more accurately the physical characteristics of the precipitation process. In particular, a better reproduction of summer rainfall event is expected through an improved inclusion of main thermodynamic forcings from humidity and stability parameters. The first part of this study focuses on the re-computation of the geostrophic circulation predictor variables developed by Wilby and Wigley (2000), reconstructed from mean sea level pressure or geopotential heights. The same circulation variables are re-computed from prognostic winds of the National Centre for Environmental Prediction (NCEP) re-analysis data set (Kalnay et al., 1996). Assessment of the performance of the re-computed predictors is carried out using the Statistical DownScaling Model (SDSM), developed by Wilby et al. (2002), and based on a number of climate indices characterizing the frequency, intensity and extremes of daily precipitation process. Two different predictor sets are considered, the first consisting of circulation-only variables, the second including a raw specific humidity predictor. For each predictor set, results obtained from the two computation techniques are compared. Daily precipitation data available at Montreal-Dorval Airport station for the 1961-1990 period were used in this assessment. Results indicated that the re-computation of geostrophic variables for both sets could yield significant improvements in the reproduction of local precipitation characteristics for the validation 1976-1990 period. The most striking improvement can be achieved for winter, as expected from the greater influence of large-scale circulation forcings on precipitation in this season. In the second part, new advection variables are developed based on a generalized omega equation. It is found that the Laplacian of temperature advection and the differential vorticity advection appear as direct forcings of the vertical velocity, strongly correlated with the precipitation process. Precipitable water and atmospheric instability indices are also included in the predictor range, mainly to reach a better simulation of convective precipitation. Next, a new statistical downscaling scheme is developed, combining a Principal Component Analysis (PCA) of the new predictors and the SDSM model. Analysis of the different computed principal components confirms the major role of the two identified advection terms and the humidity/instability predictors. Assessment of the new PCA+SDSM scheme shows significant improvements of the simulation of precipitation intensity, although results are less conclusive regarding the precipitation occurrence. Finally, the influence of the calibration period length on the new downscaling scheme performance was carried out by comparing the simulation results obtained from two calibration runs of 15 and 30 years of length: for the 1961-1975 period and for the 1961-1990 one. It was found that doubling the calibration period length could lead to significant improvements in the reproduction of the local precipitation characteristics.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k11q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j64n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zt54r"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Local buckling behaviour of pultruded FRP composite sheet piles subjected to uniform pressure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Yi, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The buckling behaviour of fibre reinforced polymer (FRP) sheet pile panels subjected to a uniform lateral pressure was investigated. Based on the previous full scale tests by Shanmugan in year 2003 (Shanmugan, 2004), the critical load at buckling initiation was first determined through experimental data analysis, and the theoretical modeling was then followed in an attempt to predict the buckling initiation and understanding the failure mechanism. The behavior of the panels loaded in upright position and inverted position was studied. The local buckling of the compressive flanges was monitored by the strain measurements, which demonstrated that when tested in upright position, the panel failed immediately after local buckling of compressive flange, and when tested in inverted position, the panels could be able to carry the load into post buckling region. The stresses and corresponding axial forces at buckling were calculated by the classical beam flexure formula but taking into consideration the reduction of flexure rigidity and neutral axis shifting. The axial force calculated from the beam flexure formula was comparable with that from stain gauge measurements. The axial force was not uniformly distributed along the width of the compressive flange at upright position and was about zero at the free edge. When tested in inverted position, the neutral axis distance and the flexure rigidity kept almost as a constant. The sheet pile panels were with a uniform axial force along the width of the compressive flange. An analytical modeling was performed to predict the buckling initiation. The buckling of the panel was simplified as the buckling of the compressive flange with various boundary conditions. The differential equation of the compressive flange was established based on the assumption that the flange was subjected to an in-plane axial force and an out-of-plane lateral pressure simultaneously. It was found that the lateral pressure did not have direct effect on the critical load. It was the compressive axial force that determined the local buckling of the flange. Kollar's explicit expressions were also applied but only valid for long plate loaded by uniform axial force. The buckling load obtained by solving the differential equation for the inverted panel compared well with that from the experimental results. However, for the flange in a pile at an upright position, the theoretical prediction was far less than the experimental value which might be attributed to the non uniform axial force on the flange. Energy method was applied to estimate the range of the buckling load of a plate loaded by a linearly distributed axial force. The upper bound value was obtained from fixed boundary condition and the lower bound from simply supported assumption. The experimental result was found in between the two bounds and was in favour of the lower bound as a conservative estimation of critical load for upright panel.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687h716.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zt54r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79407x52t"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of anchorage details on response of deep beams</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahmad, BouSaleh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As part of a research program at McGill University, involving the testing of eight full-scale deep beams, this research studies the response of four full-scale deep beams that were designed in accordance with the strut-and-tie model provisions of the CSA Standard A23.3 (2004). All of the deep beams had a centre-to-centre spacing of 2000 mm between the two supports, 1000 mm in height, and 350 mm in thickness. They were simply supported with an application of a single point load at midspan. The total length of the four beams varies depending on the type of anchorage being used. The four anchorage details that were considered in this study include a straight development length, a standard 90 degree hook, friction-welded 1.5 in. (38 mm) diameter circular headed bars and friction-welded 2 in. (50 mm) diameter headed bars. The dimensions of the loading pad and the bearing pads were 200 mm (and 300 mm) and 100 mm, respectively. All beams were reinforced with two layers of five 15M bars forming the tension tie reinforcement. El-Jorf (2006) carried out the testing and analysis of the other four full-scale deep beams in this overall research program. This research project demonstrated that providing friction-welded circular headed bars capable of developing the full yield strength at the head results in shorter beams and improved response compared to straight bar embedment details. Providing a lead-in length as well as friction-welded circular headed bars, with reduced head size, provides improved ductility compared to the straight bar embedment and compared to the hooked anchorage. This research also shows that benefits of confinement pressures at the supports can increase the bar stress although the provided development length is below code requirements.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784m12w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x52t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cw46s"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Airfoil flow analysis in the presence of the ground</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Capota, Octavian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a new method of solution for incompressible flow analysis past airfoils in the presence of the ground. The present method uses velocity singularities to derive the pressure distribution and the aerodynamic forces and moments acting on the airfoils subjected to ground effect. The method of velocity singularities has been originally developed by Mateescu for the analysis of the steady flow past airfoils and wings in supersonic regime, making use of special singularities associated to the leading edge and ridges, which are characterized by sudden changes in the boundary conditions. In this approach, the presence of the ground is modeled by considering a mirror-image airfoil, which is analyzed in conjunction with the real airfoil using velocity singularities, leading to a correct mathematical formulation of the physical problem. The solutions obtained are of aeronautical interest in flight evolutions such as take-off and landing, when the airplane wings are subjected to ground effects. The present solutions have been successfully validated by comparison with previous results obtained by the lumped-vortex method, and by other methods based on matched asymptotic expansions or on conformal transformations. Accurate theoretical solutions, in closed form, for the pressure distribution and for the lift and pitching moment coefficients have been derived for various airfoil shapes in ground effect, placed at several distances to the ground and angles of attack.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vh01g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cw46s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj96020934"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hybrid organic on inorganic semiconductor heterojunction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Chih-Hsien, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hybrid organic on inorganic semiconductor heterojunctions with a sandwich structure have been fabricated and studied using conjugated polymers. The inorganic semiconductor was n-type silicon substrate. The conjugated polymers used in this work include poly(2-methoxy-5-(2-ethylhexyloxy)-1,4-phenylenevinylene) containing polyhedral oligomeric silsesquioxanes (MEH-PPV POSS), regioregular poly(3-hexylthiophene) (RR-P3HT) and poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) (PEDOT). Current-voltage (I-V) and capacitance-voltage (C-V) measurements were performed to characterize the devices. All the devices displayed a rectifying characteristic. Among these devices, the first ever reported PEDOT doped with BF3 on n-Si heterojunction devices showed the best performance with a rectification ratio around 5.7x105 at +/- 2 V and an ideality factor of 2.3. It is speculated that performance of the devices is inversely proportional to the potential barrier height at the organic-inorganic interface. Other results from this work also suggested that smaller energy level offset between the HOMO of the conjugated polymer and the work-function of anode metal will improve device performance. Contact resistance between the anode and polymer is large (~MΩ range) and should be further investigated in the future.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg65x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96020934</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719m71d"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Finite element computations of transonic viscous flows with the streamline upwind Petrov-Galerkin (SUPG) formulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bucur, Constantin, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Computations of transonic viscous flows are very challenging. The major difficulty comes from the discontinuity in the solution across a shock wave, causing undesired oscillations in the solution. In this work we focus on minimizing the oscillations by the use of a limiter to control the amount of diffusivity. This limiter provides the right amount of viscosity to capture a sharp shock and an accurate solution in high gradient regions. The limiter employs changes in pressure and entropy and has been implemented into the Streamline Upwind Finite Element Method. A mesh adaptation strategy has been employed to further enhance the accuracy of the solution. Results of simulations over RAE 2822 airfoil and ONERA M6 wing indicate significant improvements to the solution with this implementation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds41z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m71d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Aerospace</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fp263"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Testing and analysis of light gauge steel frame 9 mm OSB wood panel shear walls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blais, Caroline, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of light steel gauge framed walls in the residential and commercial sector is increasing in popularity. However, our knowledge of the performance and the behaviour of structures using such walls when subjected to lateral wind and seismic loads is limited. At present, no design method for light gauge steel shear walls is contained in Canadian codes or standards. For this reason a research project on steel frame/wood panel shear walls was undertaken. A comprehensive database of monotonic and reversed cyclic tests on steel frame/wood panel shear walls is needed to obtain different wall parameters for use in design. For this particular project 1220 x 2440 mm walls (3 wall configurations for a total of 18 specimens) composed of 1.09 mm thick 230 MPa grade steel and 9.0 mm thick OSB were tested; where the screw spacing along the perimeter of the wall was varied (75, 100 &amp; 152 mm). The equivalent energy elastic-plastic (EEEP) analysis approach was employed to derive design values from the test results; such as stiffness, strength and a resistance factor for use with the 2005 NBCC, as well as ductility and overstrength modification factors. The resistance factor, o = 0.7, determined by Branston was confirmed. Ductility related, Rd = 2.5, and overstrength related, R0 = 1.8, seismic force modification factors are recommended for use with shear wall design values that are based on the EEEP analysis approach. Furthermore, the test data were used to create and calibrate hysteretic models, with the Stewart element, which later were used in non-linear time history dynamic analyses. The Ruaumoko software was made use of for the modeling of two representative buildings with ten earthquake records for the Vancouver BC region. The shear wall system of a typical two-storey house and a three-storey commercial building was first designed for lateral loads and then modeled. The resulting shear deformations (rotations) obtained from the analyses were compared with the limiting parameters measured during the physical shear wall tests. It was found that the scaled ground motions caused a shear demand that did not exceed the test based deformation limits.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462574d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fp263</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn106z37b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterizing frothers by their bubble size control properties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Azgomi, Fariba</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Frothers are surface-active agents used in flotation to decrease bubble size and promote froth stability. The common frothers are alcohols and polyglycols. One means to classify frothers is by the extent of bubble size reduction. Bubble size measurement is labour-intensive and this thesis explores the use of gas holdup as a surrogate for bubble size. Nine frothers with different chemical structures were tested in a bubble column equipped with instrumentation to measure bubble size and gas holdup. A correlation between frother structure and gas holdup is observed: for alcohols, gas holdup increases with hydrocarbon chain length and whether branched or straight chain does not seem to matter; and for polyglycols, gas holdup increases with number of propoxy groups. The ranking of the frother on the basis of gas holdup is the same as that given by other methods. The assumed unique relationship between gas holdup and bubble size is examined. For a given frother the relationship appears to hold. Evidence is presented that the continued increase in gas holdup at high frother concentration is correlated with a continued decrease in bubble size. When comparing frothers, however, it is shown that for equal gas holdup bubble size can be quite different. The effect is discussed in terms of bubble velocity in the swarm.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623c97q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z37b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A707958010"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessment of tandem mass spectra quality to improve protein identification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaudrie, Christian Earl Henry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Protein identification via tandem mass spectrometry and database searching has become a powerful tool in high-throughput proteomics. However, many tandem mass spectra are noisy, are formed by poorly fragmented peptides, and do not result in peptide assignment. Furthermore, many 'high-quality' un-assigned spectra are discarded as noise when they contain sufficient information for an assignment. A novel method was developed to assess the quality of tandem mass spectra from a LC-QTOF instrument using multivariate classification techniques. Six mass spectral features were first evaluated for their ability to discriminate between 'low-' and 'high-quality' spectra. Next, features were used in combination with three classification methods to create an optimal discriminator. Individual spectra quality scores were determined for two datasets, allowing for the removal of 'low quality' spectra, and a focused database search on 'high quality' unassigned spectra. Using these methods it was possible to reduce data size by 43.2% with a loss of only 5% of 'high-quality' spectra, while increasing peptide identifications by over 6%.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p21g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707958010</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5712m684d"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>FPGA particle graphics hardware</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beeckler, John Sachs</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Particle graphics simulations are well suited for modeling phenomena such as water, cloth, explosions, fire, smoke, and clouds. They are normally realized in software, as part of an interactive graphics application. Their use in such applications is limited by the computational burden and resource competition they create. This thesis presents the design and implementation of a reconfigurable hardware particle graphics system for accelerating real-time particle graphics effects: The Particle Pipe. We explore the design process, implementation issues, limitations, challenges, and new possibilities of using FPGAs for the acceleration of real-time particle graphics. The Particle Pipe has been synthesized to an operating frequency of 130 MHz and has the potential for an increase in performance of two orders of magnitude over software methods and one order of magnitude over GPU methods.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t6588.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m684d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gd28p"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Groupes et identité dans les romans autobiographiques de R. Queneau</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grenier, Marie-Hélène</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis looks at the textual representations of sociability problems in Raymond Queneau's autobiographical novels, which are also the first six novels of his career. Using an eclectic approach that combines elements of autobiographical analysis and social psychology with the numerous studies on the presence of philosophy in Queneau's work, we use the concept of identity to study social attitudes, first the author's own attitudes toward real groups, then the way the characters identify with groups, some having a tendency to share the groups identity, others choosing to distanciate themselves from the groups. Following this path, we try to demonstrate the assumption that the tendency to identify to groups, as well as the distanciation attitudes, are represented in both a positive and a negative way, thus creating, in the novels, an actual "argumentation" between two poles. This assumption runs counter to the preconception, often conveyed by the critics, that distanciation alone is valued in Queneau's writings. Given the impossibility to develop, within this work, a complete collection of the ways our problematics, i.e. the relation between belonging to groups and the formation of identity, is reflected in Queneau's novels, we choose (after examining the author own's attitudes) to analyse, in a first step, the major lines of thought related to our subject in each novel, and then to highlight some "attitude types" that emerge from the novels as a whole. This approach, we believe, allows us to draw out the key issues arising from this reflection.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b08k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gd28p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social groups in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Queneau, Raymond, 1903-1976 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763704q"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Roles of native and non-native teachers in English education in Japan : teachers' and students' perceptions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fujita, Kyoko</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores issues related to native and non-native English speaking teachers in the context of Japanese English education, specifically in public junior high school settings in relatively rural areas of Japan. The study mainly asks Japanese teachers of English, assistant language teachers employed in the Japan Exchange and Teaching Programme, and students about their perceptions of the roles of native and non-native teachers in their English classrooms. These stakeholders seem to have preconceived assumptions about the roles of native and non-native teachers. These include native teachers as opportunity providers and motivators and non-native teachers as facilitators. These fixed roles in the stakeholders' perceptions of the roles of native and non-native teachers may prevent them from expanding their possibilities and may reinforce the existing distinction between native and non-native speakers. Implications for policy makers and stakeholders include the need to adopt a perspective of English as an international language into the goals of Japanese English education to value collaborative teaching and reconceptualize the roles of Japanese English teachers and assistant language teachers in classrooms.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x8916.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763704q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Japan</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Japanese speakers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881m213"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Muslims, national security and the state in Uzbekistan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fugère, Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The idea of an "Islamic threat" to national security in Uzbekistan is widespread in the media and amongst several academics. The regime of Uzbek President Islam Karimov has repeatedly emphasized the seriousness of this threat and acted to contain it. In this thesis, I examine both the present ability of different Muslim political actors to challenge the Uzbek state's defense position and recent historical elements of the Uzbek security strategy related to Islam. I argue that the relationship between Muslims and national security in Uzbekistan is characterized by the two following observations: (1) it is unlikely that Muslims are able to present a national security risk and (2) there are reasons to suspect that the national security policies of the Uzbek leadership target Islamic fundamentalism at least in part to legitimize the continued repression of most types of opposition.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93gz800.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m213</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muslims -- Uzbekistan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Uzbekistan -- Politics and government -- 1991-</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>