<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999889f"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Oral health-related quality of life in children and adolescents with Osteogenesis Imperfecta</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Najirad, Mohammadamin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les enfants et les adolescents atteints d'ostéogenèse imparfaite (OI) peuvent avoir leur Santé bucco-dentaire Liée à la Qualité de Vie (QVLSD) affectée par les caractéristiques orales de la maladie. Cependant, nous connaissons peu de QVLSD et ses déterminants parmi cette population. L'objectif de cette thèse est d'examiner l'étendue des associations entre les conditions bucco-dentaires liées à la maladie et QVLSD chez les enfants et les adolescents qui souffrent d'OI.Objectif : Estimer l'étendue de l'association entre les traits oraux de l'OI et de l'QVLSD parmi les enfants et les adolescents qui souffre d'OI.Méthodologie : Des enfants et des adolescents âgés de 8 à 14 ans ont été recrutés dans le cadre d'une étude longitudinale multicentrique (Brittle Bone Disease Consortium) qui recrute des personnes atteintes d'IO dans 10 centres en Amérique du Nord. Les données sur les facteurs sociodémographiques et les antécédents médicaux ont été recueillies à l'aide d'un questionnaire. QVLSD a été évalué en utilisant des versions du Questionnaire sur la perception de l'enfant (CPQ) pour les 8 à 10 ans (CPQ8-10) et pour les 11 à 14 ans (CPQ11-14). Une évaluation orale complète a été effectuée dans chaque centre par des dentistes calibrés. La régression logistique ordinale multivariée a été utilisée pour ajuster les variables confondantes potentielles.Résultats : Un total de 138 enfants et adolescents (62 % de filles) ayant reçu un diagnostic de type OI I, III, IV, V et VI (n = 65, 30, 37, 4 et 2, respectivement) ont participé à l'étude. La présence des caries (DFT ajustée) et l'hygiène buccale (OHI-S) n'étaient pas statistiquement significativement différentes entre les types d'OI chez les enfants et les adolescents. Parmi tous les participants, 34 % (n = 47) avaient une dentinogenèse imparfaite (DI), 50 % (n = 69) souffraient d'une malocclusion dentaire de classe III, 36 % (n = 50) enduraient une occlusion croisée postérieure et 28 % (n = 39) avaient une béance latérale. La fréquence des traits susmentionnés est principalement élevée chez les patients atteint de l'OI de type III. Le seul déterminant statistiquement significatif de l'impact négatif sur la qualité de vie liée à la santé bucco-dentaire était l'occlusion croisée postérieure dans le groupe des adolescents qui avait une forte association avec le domaine de la limitation fonctionnelle. Ayant l'occlusion croisée postérieure, augmente les chances d'avoir des grades supérieurs de limitations fonctionnelles par un facteur de 6,1 (95 % CI : 1,7 — 22,6). Par conséquent, le fait d'avoir une occlusion croisée postérieure augmente les chances d'avoir une QVLSD inférieure par un facteur de 5,9 (IC à 95 % : 1,6 à 20,9) chez les adolescents.Aucune association statistiquement significative n'a été observée parmi le groupe des enfants.Conclusion : Indépendamment du type de OI, les adolescents avec une occlusion croisée postérieure ont des QVLSD significativement plus faibles que les autres.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Children and teenagers with Osteogenesis Imperfecta (OI), may have their Oral Health-Related Quality of Life (OHRQoL) affected by the oral traits of the disease.  However, there is little that we know of OHRQoL and its determinants amongst this population. The aim of this thesis is to investigate the extent of associations between disease-related oral conditions and OHRQoL in children and adolescents having OI.Aim: To estimate the extent of association between oral traits of OI and OHRQoL amongst children and adolescents suffering from OI. Methodology: Children and adolescents aged 8-14 years were recruited in the context of a multicenter longitudinal study (Brittle Bone Disease Consortium) that enrolls individuals with OI in 10 centers across North America. Data on socio-demographic factors, and medical history were collected using a questionnaire. OHRQoL was assessed using the Child Perceptions Questionnaire (CPQ) versions for 8 to 10-year-olds (CPQ8-10) and for 11 to 14-year-olds (CPQ11-14). A comprehensive oral evaluation was performed at each center by calibrated dentists. A multivariate ordinal logistic regression was employed to adjust for the potential confounders.Results: A total of 138 children and adolescents (62% girls) diagnosed with OI types I, III, IV, V and VI (n=65, 30, 37, 4 and 2, respectively) participated in the study. Caries experience (adjusted-DFT) and oral hygiene (OHI-S) were not statistically significantly different between OI types both in children and adolescents. Amongst all participants 34%  (n=47) had dentinogenesis imperfecta (DI), 50% (n=69) had class III dental malocclusion, 36% (n=50)  had posterior cross-bite and 28% (n=39) had lateral open-bite. The prevalence of aforementioned traits are predominantly higher amongst patients having OI type III. The only statistically significant determinants of negative impact on oral health-related quality of life was posterior cross-bite in the adolescent group with having the strongest association with functional limitation domain. Having posterior crossbite increases the odds of having higher grades of functional limitations by a factor of 6.1 (95% CI: 1.7- 22.6). Accordingly, having posterior crossbite increases the odds of having lower OHRQoL by 5.9 (95% CI: 1.6- 20.9) times amongst adolescents. No statistically significant association was observed in the children's group. Conclusion: Regardless of OI type, teenagers with posterior cross-bite experience significantly lower OHRQoL than those without. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean-Marc Retrouvey</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Shahrokh Esfandiari</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d95x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999889f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t868x"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Validation of a new strategy to repair jaw bone voids in the presence of anti-resorptive induced osteonecrosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rangel Berridi, Karla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis in the jaw (BRONJ) occurs in patients who have received high doses of bisphosphonates to treat osteoporosis or bone cancer metastases. Currently, no effective treatment for BRONJ exists, leaving patients with a debilitating condition that causes chronic pain and greatly impacts their quality of life. 3D printing of biocompatible materials to generate better bone substitutes to treat this disease is a strategy that has not yet been explored, therefore, the objective of this thesis was to evaluate the bone regeneration capacity of a polycaprolactone (PCL) 3D printed scaffold with or without a chitosan coating in a rat model of BRONJ under the hypothesis that chitosan coated PCL scaffolds would promote more microvascular ingress into the defect, thereby promoting more bone regeneration. Repair of a critical size mandibular defect in rats treated with zoledronic acid plus dexamethasone (ZA+DX) or phosphate buffered saline (PBS) treated controls was characterized using micro-CT imaging and histological analyses at 6-weeks post-operative. The data indicate 1) chitosan coated PCL scaffolds promoted more vascular ingress; 2) the repair tissue in the bone defect was characterized by vascularized fibrous tissue; 3) significantly more bone regeneration in coated PCL scaffolds was identified in  ZA+DX treated animals; 4) no significant differences were found in osteoblast activity, but significantly more osteoclast activity was found on ZA+DX treated rats; 5) the underlying mandibular bone of coated PCL scaffolds showed signs of active remodelling and resorption, characterized by less bone quantity and higher expression of osteoclast activity. Taken together, the data suggest that the chitosan coating promotes the ingress of blood vessels at the expense of activation of osteoclast activity, with a significant increase in bone regeneration of ZA+DX treated animals, therefore suggesting that PCL chitosan coated scaffolds may be a suitable material to promote bone healing in BRONJ.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'ostéonécrose liée aux bisphosphonates dans la mandible (BRONJ) survient chez des patients qui ayant reçu bisphosphonates pour traiter l'ostéoporose ou des métastases osseuses. Actuellement, il n'existe aucun traitement efficace pour BRONJ, laissant les patients avec une condition débilitante qui provoque une douleur chronique et qu'affecte grandement leur qualité de vie. L'impression 3D de matériaux biocompatibles pour générer de meilleurs substituts osseux pour traiter cette maladie est une stratégie qui n'a pas encore été explorée. L'objectif de cette thèse était donc d'évaluer la capacité de régénération osseuse d'un échafaudage de polycaprolactone (PCL) imprimée en 3D avec ou sans un revêtement de chitosane en un modèle de BRONJ chez le rat. Notre hypothèse était que les échafaudages de PCL enrobés de chitosane favoriseraient une pénétration microvasculaire plus importante dans le défaut et favorisant ainsi une régénération osseuse plus importante. La réparation d'un défaut mandibulaire de taille critique chez des rats traités avec de l'acide zolédronique plus dexaméthasone (ZA+DX) ou au sérum physiologique tamponné au phosphate (PBS) a été caractérisée par imagerie micro-CT et analyses histologiques à six semaines postopératoires. Les données indiquent 1) que les échafaudages de PCL revêtus de chitosane favorisent une plus grande pénétration vasculaire; 2) que le défaut osseux a été rempli d'un tissu fibreux vascularisé; 3) plus de régénération osseuse dans les échafaudages revêtus de PCL a été identifié chez les animaux traités avec ZA+DX; 4) aucune différence significative n'a été trouvée dans l'activité des ostéoblastes, mais significativement plus d'activité des ostéoclastes a été trouvée sur les rats traités au ZA + DX; 5) l'os mandibulaire sous-jacent des échafaudages revêtus de PCL présentait des signes de remodelage et de résorption actifs, caractérisés par une moindre quantité d'os et une plus grande expression de l'activité des ostéoclastes. Pris ensemble, les données suggèrent que le revêtement de chitosane favorise l'entrée des vaisseaux sanguins au détriment de l'activation de l'activité ostéoclastique, avec une augmentation significative de la régénération osseuse des animaux traités avec ZA+DX. Ça suggeste que les échafaudages de PCL revêtus de chitosane favorisent la guérison des défauts mandibulaires chez BRONJ.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nicholas Maroun Makhoul</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Janet Henderson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p952w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t868x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r538z"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Understanding the influence of changes to diet on individuals living with temporomandibular disorders (TMDs): an interpretive phenomenological study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Safour, Wafaa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>AbstractThe objective of this research was to better understand the experience of individuals who had to alter the types of food they were able to eat because of having a chronic temporomandibular disorder (TMD). An interpretive phenomenology research approach was chosen to achieve this purpose because of its utility to gain insight into complex human experiences. Interpretive phenomenology is a qualitative research approach that endeavours to understand the ways in which people make sense of their experiences. Phenomenology was used because the topic is exploratory in nature and enables rich, in-depth accounts of the phenomenon of TMDs as they relate to pain and food choice.The two major findings from this study were first, the participants' concern for their diminishing health and second, the loss of trust in their dentist and healthcare. The first finding related to participants' health resulting from diet change due to their TMD conditions; these food choice changes resulted in gastric bloating and constipation, a dissatisfaction with not being able to chew previously enjoyed foods, changes in body weight, fatigue, and social connectedness. The second finding was the participants' diminished trust in the healthcare system, and their experience of poor communication about treatments and negative side-effects from prescribed medications.In conclusion, the findings draw our attention to the general need for more effective treatment of people who live TMDs. Improved education about diagnosis and treatment from healthcare providers would enhance patient outcomes and improve their quality of life. The participants also spoke about the need for improved communication with healthcare providers to develop a therapeutic relationship, share knowledge about diet and nutritional practices, and to address the emotional aspects of living with chronic pain, including intervention strategies and programs designed specifically for people living with chronic TMD pain.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>RésuméL'objectif de cette recherche était de mieux comprendre l'expérience des personnes qui sont contraintes de modifier leur régime alimentaire en raison de troubles chroniques de l'articulation temporomandibulaire (TMDs). Au vu de son utilité pour mieux comprendre les expériences humaines complexes, l'approche de recherche en phénoménologie interprétative a été choisie pour atteindre cet objectif. La phénoménologie interprétative est une approche de recherche qualitative qui s'efforce de comprendre la manière dont les gens donnent un sens à leurs expériences. La phénoménologie a été aussi utilisée parce que le sujet est de nature exploratoire, et elle est riche des comptes-rendus approfondis du phénomène de la douleur et des choix alimentaires liés à la TMDs.Les deux principaux résultats de cette étude sont les préoccupations des participants pour leur santé qui se détériore d'une part et la perte de confiance en services de santé en général et aux dentistes en particulier d'autre part. La santé des participants se détériore en effet à la suite du changement de régime en raison de leur état TMDs. Ce changement résulte en de ballonnements gastriques et de la constipation, et entraîne une insatisfaction de ne pas être en mesure de mâcher des aliments d'habitude appréciés. Il cause aussi des changements dans le poids corporel, la fatigue et l'isolement social. Quant à la perte de confiance dans le système de santé, elle est causée par la mauvaise communication sur les traitements et les effets secondaires néfastes des médicaments prescrits.En conclusion, les résultats de cette étude attirent notre attention sur la nécessité d'un traitement plus efficace des TMDs en général grâce à une meilleure éducation sur le diagnostic et le traitement des prestataires de soins pour améliorer la santé des patients et augmenter la qualité de leur vie. Les participants ont également parlé de la nécessité d'améliorer la communication entre les patients et les professionnels de la santé pour développer une relation thérapeutique, partager les connaissances sur l'alimentation et les pratiques nutritionnelles et aborder les aspects émotionnels de la douleur chronique, notamment les stratégies d'intervention.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard Hovey</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx74h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r538z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qf34t"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of cetyl-pyridinium chloride (CPC) treatment on inactivation of «Listeria monocytogenes» on selected foods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pawar, Kshitija</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Food-borne pathogens such as Listeria monocytogenes are a major concern for the food processing industry. As the consumers' demand for fresh fruits and vegetable supply has increased in past few years, it is essential that the microbiological safety of these supplies be adequately controlled and monitored. Cetyl pyridinium chloride (CPC) has been shown to have some antimicrobial effect against L. monocytogenes and has been used to decontaminate raw poultry. The main objective of this study was to determine the effectiveness of CPC treatment against a cocktail of pathogenic strains of L. monocytogenes on selected foods. In the first study, the inactivation of a L. monocytogenes cocktail suspended in an aqueous medium with varied concentrations of CPC was evaluated at two temperatures (23oC and 1oC) with a constant contact time (15 s). As the concentration of CPC increased in the solution, the inactivation effect of L. monocytogenes also increased. In the second study, the exposure time was varied at each CPC concentration. Experiments were carried out separately at 23oC and 1oC. An increase in exposure time of CPC resulted in enhanced inactivation of L. monocytogenes populations in the cell suspension. Thus, CPC concentration, temperature and treatment times influenced the inactivation level of L. monocytogenes. Up to 6 logarithmic reductions was observed with as low as 10 ppm (or 0.001%) CPC was added to the cell suspension containing L. monocytogenes cocktail (107 CFU/ml). The second phase of the study was to treat selected foods with CPC surface decontamination of L. monocytogenes. Prepared potato strips, red pepper strips, broccoli florets and boneless chicken thighs were inoculated by dipping in to an aqueous suspension containing 107 CFU/ml of L. monocytogenes and treated with three different concentrations (0.2 to 0.7% for potato and red pepper; 0.4 to 1.0% for broccoli and chicken) of CPC for three different treatment times (15, 30 and 60 s). Extent of inactivation levels were enumerated by serial dilution plate count. Results had showed that, CPC was more effective against L. monocytogenes when the pathogen is present in suspension form where CPC contact with the pathogen is most effective. The study revealed that the microbial counts on the products tested could be reduced by CPC treatment at concentration levels higher than 0.4% with a 60 s treatment at room temperature. Weibull model demonstrated a good fit for the destruction kinetics. Overall, results indicated that, many factors such as concentration of CPC, treatment time, temperature during treatment, type of food surface have vital role in destruction of L. monocytogenes and CPC treatment can be utilized for decontamination if concentrations higher than 0.4% are permitted for application.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les pathogènes d'origines alimentaires tels que le Listeria monocytogenes sont aujourd'hui une préoccupation majeure pour l'industrie agro-alimentaire. Étant donné que la demande de fruits et légumes frais a augmenté au cours des dernières années, il est essentiel que l'innocuité de ces produits soit contrôlée et surveillée de manière adéquate. Il a été démontré que le chlorure de cétylpyridinium (CPC) a un certain effet antimicrobien contre le L. monocytogenes et a été utilisé pour décontaminer la de volaille. Par conséquent, l'objectif principal de cette étude était de déterminer l'efficacité du CPC contre un cocktail de souches pathogéniques de L. monocytogenes sur des aliments sélectionnés.Dans la première étude, l'inactivation du cocktail de L. monocytogenes en suspension dans un milieu aqueux avec des concentrations variées de CPC a été évaluée à deux températures (23oC et 1oC) avec un temps de contact constant (15 s). Lorsque la concentration de CPC augmentait dans la solution, l'effet d'inactivation de L. monocytogenes augmentait également. Dans la deuxième étude, le temps d'exposition variait à concentration de CPC constante. Les expériences ont été réalisées séparément à 23oC et 1oC. Une augmentation du temps d'exposition de la CPC a entrainé une inactivation accrue de la population de L. monocytogenes dans la suspension bacterienne. Ainsi, la concentration de CPC, la température et le temps de traitement ont influencé le niveau d'inactivation de L. monocytogenes. Lorsque aussi peu que 10 ppm de CPC a été ajouté à la suspension cellulaire contenant le cocktail de L. monocytogenes, une réduction de 6 logarithmi a été observée. La deuxième phase de l'étude consistait à traiter la surface des aliments sélectionnés avec le CPC pour les décontaminer de L. monocytogenes. Des bandes de pommes de terre préparées, des bandes de poivrons rouges, des fleurons de brocoli et des cuisses de poulet désossées ont été inoculées par trempage dans une suspension aqueuse contenant 107 CFU/ml de L. monocytogenes et traitées à différentes concentrations (jusqu'à 1%) de CPC (15, 30 et 60 s). Le niveau d'inactivation de L. monocytogenes a été dénombré par une technique d'énumération totale sur plaques. Les résultats ont montré que le CPC était plus efficace contre L. monocytogenes lorsque le pathogène est présent sous forme de suspension puisque le contact de la CPC avec le pathogène y est alors plus efficace. L'étude a révélé que la contamination microbienne sur les produits testés pouvait être réduites par un traitement CPC à des concentrations supérieures à 0,4% avec un traitement de 60 s à température ambiante. Le modèle de Weibull a démontré un bon accord pour la cinétique de destruction.Dans l'ensemble, les résultats indiquent que de nombreux facteurs tels que la concentration de CPC, le temps de traitement, la température pendant le traitement, le type de surface alimentaire jouent un rôle essentiel dans la destruction de L. monocytogenes et un traitement CPC peut être utilisé pour la décontamination.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430703z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qf34t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gz51t"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>«Ex vivo» expansion of skeletal muscle stem cells with a novel inhibitor of eIF1α dephosphorylation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lean, Graham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Regeneration of adult skeletal muscle depends on rare skeletal muscle stem cells (MuSCs) that reside in a quiescent state underneath the basal lamina of the myofibre. The study, manipulation and use of MuSCs for cell-based therapies is hindered by their scarcity and the inability to expand them ex vivo under current culture conditions. We have shown that a general repression of translation, mediated by the phosphorylation of translation initiation factor eIF2α at serine 51 (P-eIF2α), is essential for maintenance of MuSC quiescence and self-renewal. MuSCs unable to phosphorylate eIF2α exit quiescence, activate the myogenic program and contribute to muscle differentiation, but do not self-renew or return to their quiescent state underneath the basal lamina of the myofibre. Here we show that pharmacological inhibition of eIF2α dephosphorylation by the novel small compound C10 permitted the expansion of MuSCs retaining capacity to regenerate muscle and self-renew after engraftment into a preclinical mouse model of Duchenne muscular dystrophy. We optimized culture conditions with C10 to facilitate a) passaging of MuSCs retaining regenerative capacity and b) genome editing of MuSCs with CRISPR/Cas9.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La régénération du muscle squelettique adulte dépend d'une population rare de cellules souches musculaires (CSMs) qui résident normalement dans un état de quiescence sous la lame basale des fibres musculaires. L'étude, la manipulation et l'utilisation des CSMs dans le cadre de thérapies cellulaires sont entravées par leur rareté et l'incapacité de les amplifier ex vivo dans des conditions de culture normales. Nous avons montré qu'une répression générale de la traduction, médiée par la phosphorylation sur la sérine 51 du facteur d'initiation de la traduction eIF2α(P-eIF2α), est essentielle au maintien de la quiescence et de l'auto-renouvellement des CSMs. Les CSMs incapables de phosphoryler eIF2α quittent leur état quiescent, activent le programme myogénique et contribuent à la différenciation musculaire ; cependant elles ne s'auto-renouvellent pas ni ne reviennent à leur état quiescent sous la lame basale des fibres musculaires. Ici, nous montrons que l'inhibition pharmacologique de la déphosphorylation de eIF2α par la nouvelle petite molécule C10 permet l'amplification de CSMs qui conservent leur capacité de régénérer le muscle et de s'auto-renouveler une fois greffées dans un modèle murin préclinique de la dystrophie musculaire de Duchenne. Nous optimisons l'utilisation de C10 dans les conditions de culture pour faciliter a) le passage des CSMs tout en conservant leur capacité de régénération et b) l'édition du génome de ces mêmes CSMs par le système CRISPR / Cas9.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Colin Crist</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95052697.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz51t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s714t"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Discriminating between schizophrenia subtypes using clustering and supervised learning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Talpalaru, Alexandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Schizophrenia is a complex neuropsychiatric disorder affecting roughly 1% of the population, making it a significant public health concern [Sawa and Snyder, 2002]. Presentation of schizophrenia includes positive (hallucinations, delusions) and negative (lack of motivation, inability to feel pleasure) symptoms, in addition to cognitive impairments [Owen et al., 2016]. However, both symptom burden and associated brain alterations are highly heterogeneous and intimately linked to prognosis. To characterize the clinical heterogeneities, there is a need to develop methods that can predict symptom burden at the individual level. To serve this purpose, machine learning algorithms were implemented to first derive clinical subgroups from high-dimensional interrelated clinical information, and then subject-level classification was performed based on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) derived neuroanatomical measures. Data from the SchizConnect website (http://schizconnect.org/) was used in this analysis, consisting of 104 patients and 63 normal controls. Unsupervised hierarchical clustering was performed on the symptom severity data of the patients. The 3-cluster solutions was chosen, following a stability analysis, representing patients with (1) high loads of both negative and positive symptoms, (2) predominantly positive symptoms, or (3) mild-symptomatology as compared to the average population. Demographic variables and the average cortical thickness in 78 brain regions defined by the Automated Anatomical Labeling atlas parcellation were used as input features into three machine learning algorithms (logistic regression, support vector machine, and random forest), and the 3-cluster solution was used as the class labels. Random forest performance metrics for predicting the group membership of the high-symptomatology, and mild-symptomatology groups exceeded those of the baseline comparison of the entire schizophrenia population versus normal controls (AUC: 0.81 and 0.78 vs. 0.75). Overall, the benefit of this study is to provide a means of stratifying schizophrenia patients into homogeneous clinical subgroups that can be predicted using quantifiable, neuroanatomical features; for a future goal of developing methods that can identify individuals at high-risk for conversion to a first episode of psychosis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La schizophrénie est un trouble neuropsychiatrique complexe touchant environ 1% de la population, ce qui en fait un problème de santé publique important [Sawa and Snyder, 2002]. La présentation de la schizophrénie comprend des symptômes positifs (hallucinations, délires) et négatifs (manque de motivation, incapacité à ressentir du plaisir), en plus de déficits cognitifs [Owen et al., 2016]. Cependant, l'impact de ces symptômes et des changements neuroanatomiques les accompagnant sont hautement hétérogènes et intimement liés au pronostic. Pour caractériser les hétérogénéités cliniques, il est nécessaire de mettre au point des méthodes permettant de prédire l'impact des symptômes au niveau individuel. Pour atteindre cet objectif, des algorithmes d'apprentissage automatique ont été implémentés pour dériver des sous-groupes cliniques à partir d'informations cliniques interdépendantes de grande dimension, puis une classification par sujet a été réalisée à partir de mesures neuroanatomiques obtenues par imagerie par résonance magnétique. Les données du site Web SchizConnect (http://schizconnect.org/), tirées de 104 patients et 63 témoins normaux, ont été utilisées dans cette analyse. La classification hiérarchique non supervisée a été effectuée sur les données de gravité des symptômes des patients. Après une analyse de stabilité, la solution à trois groupes a été choisie, avec des patients avec (1) des charges élevées de symptômes négatifs et positifs, (2) une symptomatologie légère, ou (3) des symptômes principalement positifs par rapport à la population moyenne. Les variables démographiques et l'épaisseur corticale moyenne dans 78 régions cérébrales définies par l'atlas "Automated Anatomical Labeling" ont été utilisées comme données dans trois algorithmes d'apprentissage machine (régression logistique, machine à vecteurs de support, et forêt d'arbres décisionnels), et la solution à 3 groupes a été utilisée pour la catégorisation. La performance des forêts d'arbres décisionnels pour prédire l'appartenance aux groupes à symptomatologie élevée et à symptomatologie légère était meilleure que pour la comparaison de base de l'ensemble de la population schizophrène par rapport aux témoins normaux (AUC: 0.81 et 0.78 contre 0.75). Dans l'ensemble, le bénéfice de cette étude est de fournir un moyen de stratifier les patients atteints de schizophrénie en sous-groupes cliniques homogènes qui peuvent être prédits en utilisant des caractéristiques neuroanatomiques quantifiables, dans le but de développer des méthodes permettant d'identifier les individus à haut risque de conversion vers un premier épisode de psychose.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Megha Chakravarty</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66346008.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s714t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd472z65q"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Radiative contribution to the formation and development of Arctic continental air masses over northwest Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bliankinshtein, Natalia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les vagues de froid sont des régimes météorologiques hivernaux persistants caractérisés par des températures de l'air extrêmement basses à la surface. Les masses d'air produisant ces événements dans les latitudes moyennes sont habituellement formées dans des latitudes plus hautes en tant que masses d'air continentales polaires. Dans les conditions de la nuit polaire, l'émission d'ondes longues à la surface du sol provoque un refroidissement radiatif de la colonne d'air. Cela se produit en raison de la faible capacité thermique de la surface, de sorte que la surface se refroidit rapidement sans apport d'énergie au système en raison de l'albédo élevé de la neige et de la glace et des grands angles zénithaux solaires. Ainsi, avec les nuages et les précipitations, le terme de rayonnement est considéré comme un facteur important du mécanisme de formation. Les masses d'air ainsi formées peuvent se déplacer vers les latitudes moyennes en suivant un courant-jet sinueux, ce qui conduit à une intrusion extrême d'air froid vers le sud.Dans cette thèse, nous étudions la formation de masses d'air continental polaire dans le nord-ouest du Canada, qui est connu pour être une région source de vagues de froid sur des sites de latitude moyenne en Amérique du Nord. Nous évaluons le budget thermodynamique localement, c'est-à-dire dans un cadre eulérien; et également dans un cadre lagrangien, c'est-à-dire en suivant les trajectoires calculées avec le modèle de traçage lagrangien LAGRANTO. Dans les deux approches, nous utilisons des données de réanalyse et le modèle de transfert radiatif rapide (RRTMG) pour quantifier le bilan thermodynamique des masses d'air et pour tenir compte de la contribution radiative à la formation et à l'évolution de l'air froid. Dans un cadre lagrangien, nous décomposons le changement total de température diabatique des parcelles d'air en appliquant RRTMG pour calculer explicitement les vitesses de chauffage radiatif, différenciant ainsi les processus radiatifs et la libération de chaleur latente.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cold air outbreaks are persistent winter weather regimes characterized by widespread extremely low surface air temperatures that travel to lower latitudes. The air masses producing these events in mid-latitudes are usually being formed in higher latitudes as Arctic continental air masses. Under the conditions of polar night, longwave emission from the land surface causes radiative cooling of the air column. This happens because of low surface heat capacity so that the surface cools rapidly without energy input to the system due to high snow and ice albedo and large solar zenith angles. Thus, along with clouds and precipitation, the radiation term is considered to be an important driver of the formation mechanism. The formed air masses may travel to mid-latitudes as a consequence of the meandering jet stream, which leads to intrusions of cold air to lower latitudes.In this study, we investigate the formation of polar continental air masses in northwest Canada, which is known to be a source region of cold air outbreaks at mid-latitude sites in North America. We assess the thermodynamic budget locally, i.e. in a Eulerian frame, and in a Lagrangian frame, i.e. following the trajectories computed with the Lagrangian analysis tool LAGRANTO. In both approaches, we use reanalysis data and the Rapid Radiative Transfer Model (RRTMG) to quantify the thermodynamic budget of the air masses and to account for the radiative contribution to the cold air formation and evolution. In a Lagrangian frame, we decompose the total diabatic temperature change of the air parcels, by applying RRTMG to explicitly calculate the radiative heating rates, thus differentiating between the radiative processes and latent heat release.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yi Huang</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>John Richard Gyakum</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794080450.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z65q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526f55c"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Caries prevalence and experience in individuals with Osteogenesis Imperfecta</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ma, Mang Shin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Objective: Osteogenesis Imperfecta (OI) is a heritable bone fragility disorder of wide ranging severity, which sometimes also manifests tooth abnormalities known as Dentinogenesis Imperfecta (DI). It is unreported how the OI severity and these tooth abnormalities affects Caries Prevalence and Experience (CPE) in these individuals. The objectives of this study were to quantify the caries experience among different OI types and quantify how these values change due to DI. Methods: The adjusted DFT scores were used to account for frequent hypodontia, impacted teeth and retained teeth in an OI population. Univariate logistic regression followed by stepwise multivariate logistic regression was conducted to determine which clinical characteristics were associated with increased CPE in patients with OI. Results: This study included 319 participants (median age=18.4years, range=2.8-75.8years with OI types I (n=150), III (n=68) and IV (n=101). Overall, no statistically significant difference for CPE was found between sexes, OI type or for bisphosphonate use. Only variables such as age and DI were statistically significant in CPE. Univariate regression of these variables revealed that the presence of DI is positively associated with CPE. These independent variables were entered in stepwise regression analysis to ascertain their association with CPE. The presence of DI (OR 2.43; CI 1.37 to 4.32; p=0.002) while controlling for age emerged as the significant independent predictor of CPE in the final model. Conclusion: Although, there is an association between DI and CPE, we did not find sufficient evidence to reject the hypothesis that the relationship between the increase in the severity of OI is associated with the increase in Caries Experience in a population of individuals with OI.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Objectif: L'ostéogenèse imparfaite (OI) est un trouble héréditaire de fragilité osseuse d'une sévérité très variable, qui se manifeste parfois aussi par des anomalies dentaires connues sous le nom de dentinogenèse imparfaite (DI). Il n'est pas rapporté comment la gravité de l'OI et ces anomalies dentaires affectent la prévalence et l'expérience des caries (PEC) chez ces personnes. Les objectifs de cette étude étaient de quantifier l'expérience de la carie parmi les différents types d'OI et de quantifier comment ces valeurs changent en raison de la DI.   Méthodes: Les scores COD (dents cariées ou obturées) ajustés ont été utilisés pour prendre en compte l'hypodontie, les dents incluses et les dents retenues qui sont fréquentes dans une population atteinte d'OI. Une régression logistique univariée suivie d'une régression logistique multivariée par étapes ont été effectuées pour déterminer les caractéristiques cliniques associées à une augmentation de la PEC  chez les patients atteints d'OI.  Résultats: Cette étude incluait 319 participants (âge médian = 18,4 ans, intervalle = 2,8-75,8 ans) avec des types OI I (n = 150), III (n = 68) et IV (n = 101). Dans l'ensemble, aucune différence statistiquement significative n'a été observée pour la PEC selon le sexe, le type d'OI ou l'utilisation de bisphosphonates. Seules des variables telles que l'âge et la DI étaient statistiquement significatives pour la PEC. La régression univariée de ces variables a révélé que la présence de DI est positivement associée à la PEC. Ces variables indépendantes ont été saisies dans une analyse de régression par étapes pour déterminer leur association avec la PEC. La présence de DI (RC 2,43; IC 1,37 à 4,32; p = 0,002), tout en contrôlant l'âge, est apparue comme le prédicteur indépendant significatif de la PEC dans le modèle final.  Conclusion: Bien qu'il y ait une association entre la DI et la PEC, nous n'avons trouvé aucune preuve pour soutenir l'hypothèse selon laquelle la relation entre l'augmentation de la sévérité de l'OI est associée à une augmentation de l'expérience de la carie dans une population d'individus atteints d'OI.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shahrokh Esfandiari</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx75s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526f55c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053j478"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microwave hydrothermal carbonization of orange peel waste</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lei, Qian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>             A high proportion of oranges grown are used to manufacture juice and marmalade wherein about 50% of oranges are wasted. This orange waste needs to be treated appropriately to avoid the potential environmental issues and economic loss. Traditional treatment methods of orange waste are achieved by landfill, incineration, composting and in animal feed. Although these applications are the most straightforward among others, it is a low value-added method and can cause environmental pollution. Biorefinery treatment methods (e.g. extraction, microbial conversion and physical/chemical modification) have been developed to improve the value of products and reduce the environmental risks. However, there are still limitations of these treatment methods such as generation of solid and liquid residues, which requires supplement treatment methods instead of traditional treatment methods to minimize the negative environmental impacts. Hence, novel thermochemical conversion treatments of orange waste including pyrolysis and hydrothermal carbonization are being explored.             Hydrothermal carbonization (HTC) is a sustainable technology to produce hydrochar and bio-oils, which can minimize the environmental impact caused by orange peel waste. Since this technology does not require drying, it is more suitable for high-moisture biomass compared to another thermochemical conversion technology (i.e. pyrolysis). However, the conventional heating method employed in HTC process is limited by long holding time, superficial and uneven heating, and high costs. Therefore, microwave heating technique can be used in HTC to overcome these limitations.  In this study, we used a microwave-assisted HTC (MHTC) system to provide the heat required to drive the process. A response surface design was employed to optimize the holding temperature (150, 175 and 200ºC) and holding time (60,90 and 120 min) of MHTC for maximum hydrochar yield. The elemental composition, chemical properties, energy content and surface morphological characteristics were also measured to analyze the quality of the resulting hydrochar.   The results showed that the physicochemical properties of the hydrochar produced by MHTC of orange peel were comparable to that of hydrochar produced by conventional HTC process, indicating that MHTC has the potential to provide a simpler and more efficient approach to produce hydrochar from lignocellulosic biomass.            Furthermore, citric acid being a common organic acid is non-toxic, less corrosive, and inexpensive; it was used as a catalyst in the MHTC process of orange peel waste to study the catalytic effect on the resulting hydrochar. A response surface plot was also used to optimize the condition of MHTC to obtain the maximum yield. Moreover, the physicochemical properties and surface morphological characteristics were also analyzed. Compared to the MHTC without the catalyst, the maximum hydrochar yield, carbon content and calorific value of hydrochar were all higher. Lower ash content and smaller microspheres on the surface of hydrocahrs were also observed with the use of citric acid. These results indicate that citric acid can serve as an ideal catalyst in the MHTC process of orange peel waste.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>          De grandes quantités d'orange sont utilisés dans la fabrication de jus et de marmelades et plus de 50% de la matière première est rejetée sous forme de déchet. Ces résidus doivent être traités de manière appropriée pour minimiser l'impact sur l'environnement et les coûts de disposition. Les méthodes traditionnelles de traitement des résidus d'orange sont l'enfouissement, l'incinération, le compostage et ils peuvent être utilisés comme nourriture pour animaux. Quoique ces traitements soient relativement simples, ils ne permettaient pas d'ajouter de la valeur et ils peuvent causer des problèmes environnementaux. Des méthodes de traitement de bioraffinerie (extraction de composés actifs, conversion microbienne ou modifications physiques ou chimiques) ont été développées pour améliorer la valeur des sous-produits et pour réduire leur impact sur l'environnement. Cependant, certaines de ces techniques sont très complexes et génèrent beaucoup de résidus solides/liquides ce qui les rendent très dispendieuses et moins attrayantes. C'est pour ces raisons que cette étude a porté sur l'utilisation de nouveaux procédés de conversion thermochimiques pour valoriser les résidus d'orange. Les travaux effectués ont permis d'évaluer les effets de la carbonisation hydrothermique par micro-ondes sur la valeur énergétique des résidus traités.           La carbonisation hydrothermale est une technologie durable qui permet la valorisation des résidus organiques en les transformant en hydrochar et bio-huiles. Puisque cette technologie ne nécessite pas le séchage de la biomasse avant le traitement, elle est mieux adaptée pour les résidus ayant de fortes teneurs en eau. Les méthodes de chauffage classiques utilisée dans les procédés de carbonisation hydrothermique entrainent de longues durées de traitement et des coûts élevés. Des travaux récents sur la valorisation des sous-produits de la mer ont démontré qu'il était possible de surmonter ces limitations en utilisant le chauffage par micro-ondes.           Dans cette étude, nous avons utilisé un système de carbonisation hydrothermale assisté par micro-ondes pour fournir la chaleur nécessaire à la conduite du procédé. Un modèle de surface de réponse a été utilisé pour optimiser la température (150, 175 et 200ºC) et la durée (60, 90 et 120 min) de traitement pour maximiser le rendement en hydrochar. La composition des éléments, les propriétés chimiques, la teneur énergétique et les caractéristiques morphologiques ont été mesurées pour caractériser la qualité de l'hydrochar obtenu. Les résultats ont montré que les propriétés physicochimiques de l'hydrochar d'orange produit par carbonisation hydrothermale assistée par micro-ondes de peau d'orange étaient comparables à celles de l'hydrochar produit par un processus de carbonisation hydrothermale conventionnel. De plus, les résultats ont indiqué que la carbonisation hydrothermale assistée par micro-ondes était une approche plus simple et plus efficace pour produire de l'hydrochar à partir de la biomasse lignocellulosique.          De plus, l'acide citrique, un acide organique commun est non toxique, moins corrosif et peu coûteux; a été utilisé comme catalyseur dans le procédé. Un modèle de surface de réponse a été utilisé pour caractériser les effets catalytiques et pour optimiser les conditions de carbonisation hydrothermale assistée par micro-ondes. Les résultats ont démontré que lorsque comparé à la carbonisation hydrothermale par micro-ondes sans catalyseur, l'ajout de l'acide citrique a permis d'augmenter le rendement en hydrochar, la teneur en carbone et la valeur calorifique. De plus, l'hydrochar obtenu avait une teneur plus faible en cendres et des microsphères plus petites à la surface. L'acide citrique est donc un excellent catalyseur qui permet d'améliorer le processus de carbonisation hydrothermale par micro-ondes des déchets d'orange.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>G. S. Vijaya Raghavan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn849.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j478</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bioresource Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77ft78c"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computational agent-based modeling of surgical vocal fold injury and repair</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Garg, Aman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les problèmes de la voix affectent environ un adulte sur dix à un moment ou à un autre de leur vie. La cicatrisation des replis vocaux peut résulter de l'excision chirurgicale des lésions d bénignes et malignes. Des cellules (neutrophiles, macrophages, fibroblastes) et molécules (cytokines inflammatoires, molécules associées aux dégâts) immunitaires et réparatrices participent à la réponse inflammatoire et cicatrisante. Ce processus implique la localisation du tissu endommagé, l'élimination de cellules nécrotiques et de débris, et la production de substances de la matrice extracellulaire pour la réparation éventuelle du tissu. Une meilleure compréhension du processus de réparation et de blessure des cordes vocales aidera à identifier les traitements efficaces pour la cicatrisation des plis vocaux iatrogènes suite aux complications chirurgicales.L'objectif principal de cette thèse était de développer des modèles numériques multi-agents (SMA) pour des simulations dynamiques du rôle des principaux composants cellulaires et moléculaires impliqués dans la blessure et la réparation des replis vocaux. Le premier objectif de lu présente était de déterminer les phénotypes des cellules immunitaires en utilisant la cytométrie en flux dans la réparation des cordes vocales de rat. Des cellules vivantes ont été récoltées de cordes vocales et ont été colorées avec des marqueurs de surface cellulaire spécifiques aux neutrophiles, macrophages, cellules endothéliales, et fibroblastes. La cytométrie de flux multi-paramétrique a ensuite été utilisée pour compter le nombre de chaque population de cellule.Le deuxième objectif était de calibrer et valider un modèle informatique basé sur un SMA de la blessure aux replis vocaux et leur réparation utilisant les données de lu cytométrie de flux. Une analyse de sensibilité globale busée sur les méthode « Random Forests » a été utilisé pour identifier les paramètres du modèle les plus influents sur les populations cellulaires. L'algorithme ROPE (Robust Parameter Estimation) de l'outil d'optimisation statistique des paramètres pour Python (SPOTPY) a ensuite été utilisé pour calibrer le VF-ABM pour la période initiale allant du Jour 1 au Jour 5 des données de cytométrie de flux. Par la suite, VF-ABM ont été exécutés 100 fois pour générer des intervalles de confiance à 95% pour l'évaluation du modèle. Les permis ont été évaluées avec des prédiction intervalles de confiance de 95% par comparaisons avec les donnesse expérimentales de prédictions a été évaluée pour les semaines 1, 2, et 4 respectivement par rapport aux données empiriques de cytométrie de flux. Bien que les tendances qualitatives de la population cellulaire prédites sout comparables à celles des données empiriques pour les semaines 2 et 4, les valeurs des données empiriques déposent les intervalles de confiance.Les résultats de l'étude de cytométrie de flux ont fourni des données quantitatives et dépendantes du temps sur les principales populations de cellules impliquées dans la lésion du re pli vocal chirurgical. Les résultats de la vérification du modèle suggèrent des améliorations possibles pour la prochaine génération de VF-ABM. Cette thèse constitue une étape essentielles dans le développement d'un outil de calcul qui permettrait de mieux informer les cliniciens dans la prescription de traitements individualises pour les patients atteints de troubles de la voix.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Voice disorders affect about one in ten adults at some point in their lifetime. Vocal fold scarring can result from surgical excision of benign and malignant vocal fold lesions. The elicited inflammation and healing response is complex and dynamic. It involves immune and repair cells (e.g., neutrophils, macrophages, fibroblasts) and molecules (e.g., inflammatory cytokines, damage-associated molecular pattern molecules) to locate damaged tissue, eliminate the necrotic cells and debris, and produce extracellular matrix substances for eventual tissue repair. A mechanistic understanding of the vocal fold injury and repair process will help in identifying the effective treatments for iatrogenic vocal fold scarring from surgery.The overall goal of this thesis was to develop computational agent-based models (ABM) that could numerically simulate the dynamics of major cellular and molecular components involved in surgical vocal fold injury and repair. The first research goal was to phenotype and enumerate immune and repair cells in surgically injured rat vocal folds up to 4 weeks after surgical injury. Viable cells were isolated from harvested vocal folds and were stained for cell surface markers specific to neutrophils, macrophages, endothelial cells and fibroblasts. Multi-parametric flow cytometry was then conducted to count the number of cells for each cell population in the vocal fold samples. The second research goal was to calibrate and validate existing agent-based models of vocal fold injury and repair (VF-ABM) with the flow cytometry data. Global sensitive analysis using Random Forests were first employed to identify the most influential model parameters on the outputs of cell numbers. The Robust Parameter Estimation (ROPE) algorithm from the package of Statistical Parameter Optimization Tool for Python (SPOTPY) was then used to calibrate VF-ABM for early time points from Day 1 to Day 5 of the flow cytometry data. Subsequently, VF-ABM were run 100 times to generate 95% confidence intervals for model evaluation. VF-ABM predicted outputs were considered accurate if the empirical data points were within the 95% confidence intervals of simulated outputs. Cell population quantities were calculated for Day 7, Week 2 and Week 4 respectively against the empirical flow cytometry data. Predicted cell populations reached 100% accuracy for Day 7. Although VF-ABM generated qualitative trends of cell population comparable to those of Weeks 2 and 4, the corresponding empirical data values fell outside of the 95% confidence intervals. Results from the flow cytometry study provided quantitative and time-dependent data on major cell populations involved in surgical vocal fold injury. Results from the model verification informed the area of improvements for the next generation of VF-ABM. This thesis contributes to the development of a computational tool that would better inform clinicians in prescribing treatments for patients with voice disorders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Luc Mongeau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Nicole Yee Key Li</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x148k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft78c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn9998906"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design and synthesis of inhibitors for the human geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate synthase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vincent, Félix</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Synthesis of potent, selective and drug-like inhibitors of the human geranylgeranyl pyrophosphate synthase (hGGPPS) has been a challenge in the last decades. Many reports highlight the finding of potent or selective inhibitors but all of them are substrate-mimic based inhibitors. Consequently, our efforts have been focused on the synthesis of compounds also featuring drug-like structures. Herein, the synthesis of various potent and selective inhibitors of hGGPPS are reported. Those inhibitors are bisphosphonate-containing compounds harboring well established drug-like heterocyclic cores with various side chain substituents. Potent molecules such as those reported in this thesis could serve as molecular probes for exploring the role of hGGPPS in human diseases such as multiple myeloma (MM), bone diseases and Alzheimer's disease.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La synthèse de molécules puissantes, selective et ayant une structure ressemblant à un médicament qui inhibe la géranylgéranyl pyrophasphate synthase humaine (hGGPPS) a été considéré comme un défi depuis la dernière décennie. Plusieurs articles soulignent la synthèse d'inhibiteurs sélectifs ou puissant, mais aucun de ceux-ci ne présente de structure ressemblant à un médicament. Nos efforts ont été placés sur la synthèse de molécules qui possédait aussi une structure de médicament. Ici, la synthèse de puissantes différentes molécules qui possèdent aussi des structures similaires à des médicaments est présentée. Ces inhibiteurs contiennent un groupement bisphosphonate, des hétérocycles reconnus comme ayant une structure de médicament et des chaînes latérales qui elles contiennent plusieurs groupements fonctionnels. Les puissantes molécules décrient dans cette thèse pourraient servir à sonder différentes maladies tel que le myélome multiple, des maladies osseuses et la maladie de l'Alzheimer. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Youla S. Tsantrizos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3334653.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998906</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rr060"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Potential health impact of pollutants in potatoes, grown with wastewater, in a simulated human gut digestion model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaur, Harmanjot</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Sans doute une importante stratégie pour s'adresser à l'important risque globale de pénurie d'eau, l'irrigation au moyen d'eaux usées représente une source alternative d'eau. Cependant ces eaux, sont riches en polluants, à la fois organiques (hormones et produits pharmaceutiques) et inorganiques (métaux lourds). Ces contaminants peuvent, par l'entremise de leur absorption par les plantes, entrer dans la chaîne alimentaire et s'y bio-amplifier.  Certains métaux lourds, tel le Pb, Cd, Ar, Hg, etc. n'ont aucuns bienfaits pour la santé humaine, mais peuvent avoir des effets nocifs. L'on associe leur présence dans les organismes biologiques supérieurs à des perturbations du système immunitaire, au stress oxydatif, à l'endommagement de l'ADN, aux maladies cardio-vasculaires, à la défaillance d'organes, et à la carcinogenèse. De récentes études ont noté une dysbiose de la microflore intestinale liée à l'exposition aux métaux lourds. En vue des risques de santé associés aux métaux lourds, la présente étude entrepris une culture des pommes de terre avec une irrigation au moyen d'eaux usées. Quatre différents traitements expérimentaux, à savoir trois niveaux de contamination en métaux lourds obtenus par différents niveaux d'amendement du sol de culture, et un sol sans contamination ayant reçu de l'eau fraîche (témoin) servirent à cultiver des pommes de terre. Récoltés, ces pommes de terre furent cuites, puis une portion journalière provenant de chacun des traitements fut fermentée par un microbiote fécal humain dans des réacteurs en lots. Des échantillons furent prélevés à différents moments des 24 heures d'incubation. L'ampleur des processus microbiens fut évaluée en mesurant les teneurs en acides gras à chaîne courte (AGCC), le pouvoir antioxydant, et le contenu phénolique total. Un dénombrement de lactobacilles sur plaque d'agar MRS permit d'évaluer l'effet sur les bactéries bénéfiques. Les teneurs en AGCC indiquèrent une tendance semblable pour tous les traitements. De plus, le pouvoir antioxydant et le contenu phénolique total des pommes de terre digérés demeura semblable à ceux des pommes de terre avant la digestion. La population de lactobacilles augmenta avec le temps dans tous les réacteurs. En conclusion, suite à une exposition unique, les antioxydants phénoliques des pommes de terre ont peut-être neutralisé les effets néfastes des métaux lourds sur le microbiome intestinal.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Wastewater irrigation is undoubtedly an important strategy to cope with the global water scarcity crisis. Despite being an alternate source of water, it is also rich in pollutants, both organic (hormones and pharmaceuticals) and inorganic (heavy metals). These contaminants can make their way into the food chain via plant uptake and leading to biomagnification. Some of the heavy metals such as lead (Pb), cadmium (Cd), arsenic (Ar), mercury (Hg), etc. inside the human body, have no biological health promoting significance but can cause adverse effects. Their presence in biological organisms have been associated with disrupted immune system, oxidative stress, DNA damage, cardiovascular diseases, organ dysfunctionality, and carcinogenesis. Recent studies have found gut microbiota dysbiosis caused by heavy metal exposure. Considering the health risks associated with heavy metals, the present study was conducted on wastewater irrigated potatoes. Four different treatments had varying concentrations of heavy metals by virtue of the soil amendments applied and one treatment was freshwater irrigated to represent sample without contamination. The study consisted of fermentation of one daily serving of cooked potatoes in batch reactors using human fecal microbiota. The samples were taken from the fermenters at 0, 6, 12 and 24 h of incubation. The microbial processes were assessed by measuring short chain fatty acid (SCFA) concentrations, antioxidant capacity, and total phenolics. Lactobacilli plate count using MRS agar was also conducted to evaluate the effect on beneficial bacteria. The SCFA concentration trends were similar in all the treatments. The antioxidant capacities and total phenolics determined during the experiment/fermentation process were comparable to the pre-digestion values for all the treatments. The Lactobacilli population increased with time in all the reactors. It was concluded that the polyphenol antioxidants of potatoes could have neutralized the possible adverse effects of heavy metals on gut microbiota in the single meal exposure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shiv Prasher</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jr12x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rr060</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bioresource Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dh95q"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The trouble with the trees: can community-based forestry succeed in Panama and around the world?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Clare, Stephen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La gestion forestière communautaire (GFC), une stratégie de gestion forestière dans laquelle les communautés prennent un rôle actif dans la gestion de leurs forêts, s'est popularisée mondialement depuis 1990. Puisque les communautés ont des connaissances locales et un intérêt pour la durabilité des forêts à long terme, théoriquement, la GFC devrait produire plus de résultats durables pour les communautés et l'environnement. Cependant, les évaluations de la performance de la GFC produisent des résultats partagés. L'enthousiasme de plusieurs chercheurs s'est transformé en scepticisme, donc il est nécessaire d'approfondir la recherche sur la performance de la GFC dans divers contextes. Cette thèse débute par un examen de la littérature existante sur la théorie et la performance de la GFC et poursuit par la présentation d'une étude de cas sur son application au Panama. En tant que pays tropical en voie de développement qui fait face à un taux élevé de pauvreté rurale et de déforestation, le Panama est un bon candidat pour l'utilisation de la GFC. Toutefois, une analyse utilisant un cadre d'évaluation développé par Gilmour (2016) démontre que le pays n'a pas la capacité économique ou politique pour supporter la mise en œuvre réussie de la GFC. Des études de politiques sur la GFC dans d'autres pays ont publié des résultats similaires. Les gouvernements se montrent réticents à l'idée de décentraliser leur pouvoir et les communautés manquent de capacités techniques pour exécuter leur plan de gestion. Vue la persistance de ces problèmes, la prochaine section de la recherche reflète sur les avenues de la recherche sur la GFC. Les thèmes de recherche prioritaires de la GFC ont été identifiés en utilisant une technique en linguistique informatique sur une base de données de 1 112 abstraits d'articles sur la GFC publiés entre 1990 et 2017. Les tendances de sujets de recherche en proportion avec leur occurrence, incluant l'importance accrue de la séquestration de carbone et la recherche sur les contextes locaux, sont décrites. La dernière section de la thèse discute de l'implication des résultats pour la recherche en GFC et argumente que la théorie sur les systèmes complexes adaptifs devrait informer des avenues innovatrices de recherche en GFC. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Community-based forestry (CBF), a forest management strategy in which communities take a more active role in the management of local forests, has expanded quickly around the world since the 1990s. Since communities are thought to have local knowledge and a stake in the long-term sustainability of the resource base, CBF is theoretically positioned to produce more sustainable outcomes for people and the environment. Evaluations of CBF performance, however, have generally found mixed results. For many researchers, enthusiasm is ceding to skepticism, and more research into how CBF performs in a diversity of contexts around the world is needed. This thesis first reviews the literature on CBF's theory and performance before presenting a case study of CBF's current status in Panama. As a developing country in the tropics facing both high rural poverty rates and ongoing deforestation, Panama is viewed as a good candidate for CBF implementation. However, using an evaluative framework developed by Gilmour (2016) finds that the country is not fully ready on political or economic grounds to support successful CBF. CBF policy studies in other countries have reported similar results. Governments are usually reluctant to devolve power and communities often lack the technical capacity to carry out management activities. Noting the persistence of these problems, the next section reflects on the broad trajectory of CBF research. By applying a computational linguistic technique called topic modeling to a database of 1,112 abstracts of CBF research articles published between 1990 and 2017, prominent topics of CBF research are identified. Trends in the proportional occurrence of research topics, including the growing influence of carbon sequestration and local outcomes research, are described. The final part of the thesis discusses what these results say about the state of CBF research and argues for complex adaptive systems theory as a good candidate to inform innovative approaches that may further advance CBF research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gordon Hickey</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq317.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dh95q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Natural Resource Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cg71m"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of ocean heat transport on rapid sea ice declines in the Community Earth System Model Large Ensemble</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Auclair, Gabriel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many climate models predict future rapid sea ice declines in the Arctic. These events are linked with anomalous northward Ocean Heat Transport (OHT). Using the Community Earth System Model Large Ensemble (CESM-LE), we find that the partitioning of the poleward OHT between the different gates of the Arctic (Barents Sea Opening (BSO), Fram Strait or Bering Strait) is key to this link with the rapid declines. In total, 64 of the 79 rapid declines in CESM-LE are linked with anomalous OHT. The interaction between OHT and sea ice happens mainly over continental shelves. The Bering Strait OHT is linked to more rapid declines than the BSO OHT, presumably because of the broader Eurasian shelf. No clear link is found between rapid declines and the OHT through the Fram Strait, which is a deep gate to the Arctic Ocean, except when the rapid decline is also linked to the BSO or Bering Strait OHTs. When the September Sea Ice Extent (SIE) before the rapid decline is located only over deep basins in the central Arctic, we observe a decrease in basal melt during the decline. We hypothesize that this is due to an enhanced stratification that reduces heat transfer between the ocean and the ice. The ice-atmosphere heat flux anomalies are more strongly correlated with the sea ice concentration anomalies over the deep basins in the 21st century than the ice-ocean heat flux anomalies. Our results suggest that OHTs are causing rapid sea ice declines mostly when the SIE is large enough to cover the continental shelves and that the atmosphere is the main driver when the initial SIE is located only over the deep basins.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Plusieurs modèles climatiques prévoient de futurs déclins rapides de la glace de mer en Arctique. Ceux-ci sont liés à des transports de chaleur océanique anormaux. Dans le Community Earth System Model Large Ensemble (CESM-LE), le chemin emprunté par ces transports de chaleur pour entrer en Arctique (mer de Barents, détroit de Fram ou de Béring) est déterminant dans ce lien. 64 des 79 déclins rapides dans le CESM-LE sont liés à un transport de chaleur océanique anormal. L'interaction entre les transports de chaleur océanique et la glace de mer se produit principalement sur les plateaux continentaux. Le transport du détroit de Béring est lié à plus de déclins rapides que celui de la mer de Barents, possiblement à cause du large plateau continental eurasien. Aucun lien direct n'est découvert entre les déclins rapides et le transport du détroit de Fram, qui est une porte d'entrée profonde en Arctique, à l'exception de déclins qui sont également liés aux transports de la mer de Barents ou du détroit de Béring. Quand l'étendue de glace initiale est située seulement au-dessus des bassins profonds, la fonte basale durant le déclin diminue. Ceci est probablement dû à une plus grande stratification de l'océan qui réduit le transfert de chaleur entre l'océan et la glace. Les flux de chaleur glace-atmosphère sont plus fortement corrélés avec les concentrations de glace au-dessus des bassins profonds que les flux de chaleur glace-océan. Nos résultats suggèrent que les transports de chaleur océanique peuvent causer des déclins rapides de la glace de mer quand l'étendue de glace couvre les plateaux continentaux et que l'atmosphere est le principal moteur des déclins rapides quand l'étendue de glace couvre seulement les bassins profonds.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruno Tremblay</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv489.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg71m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s7153"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The endosomal sorting adaptor HD-PTP is required for ephrin-B: EphB forward signaling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lahaie, Sylvie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>To identify new proteins required for ephrin-B:EphB signaling, we conducted a BioID- based screen for novel EphB2 interactors. Among many hits, we found HD-PTP, a regulator of endosomal sorting complex transport (ESCRT) proteins and a tumour suppressor. Co- immunoprecipitation confirmed increased EphB2 – HD-PTP molecular complex in HEK293 cells stimulated with ephrin-B2. Also, HeLa cells overexpressing EphB2 show increased levels of HD-PTP protein and co-localisation of HD-PTP and EphB2. HeLa cells with decreased levels HD-PTP show a blunted collapse response to ephrin-B2 but are collapsed normally by Sema3A, indicating that HD-PTP is not involved in general chemotropic responses. HD-PTP mRNA is expressed in developing spinal motor neurons, whose axon guidance depends on Eph signaling. Spinal motor neuron growth cones with a CRISPR:Cas9-induced HD-PTP loss of function, showed a diminished collapse in response to ephrin-B2 while responding normally to Sema3F. Furthermore, HD-PTP depleted motor neurons make ephrin-B2 dependent axon targeting mistakes in the limb in vivo.At the molecular level in HeLa cells and growth cones with decreased HD-PTP function, we found a reduction of both, ephrin-B2-induced Y418 phosphorylation of SRC family kinases, phosphorylation of EphB2 and surface EphB2 clustering. Eph receptor cyclic trafficking entails its internalization following ligand binding, recycling, degradation and de novo receptor synthesis. To identify which of these steps are impacted by HD-PTP loss, we blocked protein synthesis in control and HD-PTP loss of function HeLa cells, then measured EphB2 protein level following ephrin-B2 stimulation. In control HeLa cells, ephrin-B2 stimulation led to an apparent increase in EphB2 levels, when compared to mock stimulation. In contrast, HeLa cells with lowered HD-PTP levels exposed to ephrin-B2 showed a trend of decreased EphB2 protein levels when compared to mock stimulation. These and other observations suggest that HD-PTP functions to control the cyclic trafficking of EphB2 upon ephrin-B2 exposure.We propose that HD-PTP is a new effector of EphB2 forward signaling, required for ephrin-B2-induced EphB2 clustering at the cell surface. As an ESCRT protein involved in intracellular trafficking of receptors, HD-PTP may also control the amplitude and duration of EphB2 signaling by promoting EphB2 recycling and/or its degradation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Afin d'identifier de nouvelles protéines requises pour la signalisation ephrin-B:EphB, nous avons effectué un criblage par BioID pour de nouveaux interacteurs d'EphB2. Parmi plusieurs candidats, nous avons trouvé HD-PTP, un régulateur du complexe ESCRT (endosomal sorting complex transport) et suppresseur tumoral. Un essai de co-immunoprécipitation a confirmé l'augmentation du complexe moléculaire EphB2 – HD-PTP dans des cellules HEK293 stimulées avec ephrin-B2. Également, des cellules HeLa sur-exprimant EphB2 démontrent une augmentation de protéine HD-PTP ainsi que de sa co-localisation avec EphB2. Des cellules HeLa avec une diminution de HD-PTP montrent un effondrement émoussé en réponse à une stimulation avec ephrin-B2 mais s'effondrent normalement en présence de Sema3A, indiquant que HD-PTP n'est pas impliqué dans les réponses chimiotrophiques générales. L'ARNm de HD- PTP est exprimé dans les motoneurones de la moelle épinière embryonnaire, dont la guidance axonale dépend de la signalisation Eph. Les cônes de croissance de ces motoneurones avec une perte de fonction de HD-PTP induite par CRISPR:Cas9 affichent un effondrement diminué en réponse à ephrin-B2 mais répondent normalement face à Sema3F. De plus, des motoneurones avec perte de HD-PTP affichent des erreurs de guidance axonales dépendantes d'ephrin-B2 dans les membres in vivo.Au niveau moléculaire, dans des cellules HeLa et des cônes de croissance avec une diminution fonctionnelle de HD-PTP, nous avons trouvé une réduction de phosphorylation Y418 des kinases de la famille SRC dépendante d'ephrin-B2, de phosphorylation d'EphB2 de surface ainsi que de l'agrégation d'EphB2. Le trafficking cyclique du récepteur Eph implique soninternalisation suite à sa liaison au ligand, son recyclage, sa dégradation ainsi que la synthèse de récepteurs de novo. Afin d'identifier quelle étape est touchée par la perte de HD-PP, nous avons bloqué la synthèse protéique dans des cellules HeLa contrôles et avec perte de fonction de HD- PTP, mesurant les niveaux protéiques d'EphB2 suite à une stimulation avec ephrin-B2. Dans les cellules HeLa contrôles, la stimulation avec ephrin-B2 a mené à une augmentation des niveaux d'EphB2 lorsque comparé à une stimulation simulée. En revanche, les cellules HeLa avec une diminution des niveaux de HD-PTP exposées à ephrin-B2 ont présenté une tendance décroissante des niveaux protéiques d'EphB2 lorsque comparé à la stimulation simulée. Ces observations suggèrent que HD-PTP fonctionne en contrôlant le trafficking cyclique d'EphB2 suite à une exposition à ephrin-B2.Nous avançons que HD-PTP est un nouvel effecteur de la signalisation forward d'EphB2 et qu'il est requis pour l'aggrégation induite par ephrin-B2 d'EphB2 à la surface cellulaire. En tant que protéine ESCRT impliquée dans le trafficking intracellulaire des récepteurs, HD-PTP contrôle potentiellement l'amplitude et la durée de la signalisation EphB2 en favorisant le recyclage et/ou la dégradation d'EphB2.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Artur Kania</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t152f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s7153</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z29p"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Family Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of primary healthcare professionals in improving access to care and health outcomes of socially isolated older adults in Jamaica: a mixed methods study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McFarlane, Shamiel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>IntroductionSocial isolation has an overall negative effect on the physical health and well-being of older adults. While a qualitative study on Active Aging within the Caribbean and Latin America was performed in 2010, this study did not explore cohesiveness among the viewpoints of isolated older persons, community health aides and physicians, giving a voice to all parties involved in this healthcare ecosystem.  In further examination of social isolation among older adults it is imperative to view the role of the health team on the aging population, seeing how the idiosyncrasies of the Caribbean filter into health and aging. MethodsThis study utilized a convergent multi-method approach. Quantitative methods(i)Self-administered paper survey of physicians to identify their current practices with patients and collect feedback on their perceived overall vulnerability of different patient populations, including isolated older persons over the age of 65.Qualitative methods: (ii)In-depth interviews with persons aged 65 and older to understand the challenges and social issues they face, (iii) a focus group with community health aides, and (iv) interviews with primary care physicians to identify organizational levers for promoting change in health workers' practices. The results of this study are presented here by integrating the results of the survey, the 5 in-depth interviews, 2 physician interviews and the focus group around main themes from a deductive framework, seeking convergence among the viewpoints of each party. Results In total, 60 primary health care physicians responded to the survey (80% response rate), 5 socially isolated elderly persons completed in-depth patient interviews, one focus group was conducted with allied health workers, and 2 physicians participated in key informant interviews. Only a small percentage of survey respondents [n= 21/60, 35%] regarded older individuals as being among the more marginalized and vulnerable members of society. Socially isolated elderly persons interviewed would like their doctors to not only focus on physical health, but also "ask what's going on in my life." Most respondents agreed that it is the role of health workers to enquire about the underlying social challenges of their patients (n=43/60, 71.7%]. Physicians, however, were divided on whether it is their responsibility to address these social issues, with some believing that a simple referral to social work agencies is adequate while others advocate for broader intervention [Kruskal-Wallis 2= 16.775; df=2, p= 0.05, 2= 5.991]; [obs. diff 22.180233, critical diff 16.09816]. Notably physicians over age 50, those who spend more time with their patients and those who had previously delivered care to isolated patients, were more likely to consider it their responsibility to enquire about and propose solutions to the social issues of patients beyond referring to social work [p &lt;0.001]. Physicians suggested a number of strategies that could be used at the clinical-level, the community level and the national level to better support socially isolated older adults.ConclusionMost health workers (physicians and community health aides) recognized the importance of addressing social isolation among older adults, yet were unaware of any outreach programs or mandates within their job description that would allow them to pursue this. A nationwide outreach program, supported by the medical council, was proposed by physicians who answered the survey as a promising approach to provide better access to services for isolated older patients. This program would also incentivize and train health workers on how to provide socially accountable care by linking this with accreditation processes, continuing professional development and medical license renewal. Better transportation and financial supports for patients were also identified as important structural levers to break social isolation and contribute to healthy aging.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>IntroductionL'isolement social a un effet négatif global sur la santé physique et le bien-être des personnes âgées. Alors qu'une étude qualitative sur le vieillissement actif dans les Caraïbes et en Amérique latine a été réalisée en 2010, cette étude n'a pas exploré la cohésion entre les personnes âgées isolées, les aides de santé communautaires et les médecins. Dans un examen plus approfondi de l'isolement social chez les personnes âgées, il est impératif de voir le rôle de l'équipe de santé dans le vieillissement de la population, de voir comment les particularités des Caraïbes se traduisent par la santé et le vieillissement.MéthodesCette étude a utilisé une approche multi-méthodes convergente.Méthodes Quantitatives(i)Une enquête auprès des médecins pour identifier les pratiques actuelles et recueillir des commentaires sur leur vulnérabilité perçue des différentes populations de patients, y compris les personnes âgées isolées de plus de 65 ansMéthodes Qualitatives(ii) Des entretiens approfondis avec des personnes âgées jugées isolées pour comprendre les défis et les problèmes sociaux auxquels elles sont confrontées et leurs points de vue sur des solutions potentielles, (iii) un groupe de discussion avec des aides sanitaires communautaires pour explorer les obstacles et les défis rencontrés. (iv) des entretiens avec des informateurs clés avec des médecins de soins primaires pour identifier les leviers organisationnels permettant de promouvoir le changement dans les pratiques des agents de santé. Les résultats de cette étude sont présentés ici en intégrant les résultats de l'enquête, les 5 entretiens approfondis, 2 entrevues avec des informateurs clés et les groupes de discussion autour des thèmes principaux d'un cadre déductif, cherchant à faire converger les points de vue de chaque partie.RésultatsAu total, 60 agents de santé ont répondu à l'enquête (taux de réponse: 80%), 5 entretiens approfondis avec des personnes âgées isolées, un groupe de discussion avec 4 auxiliaires de santé communautaires et 2 médecins ont participé à des entretiens avec des informateurs clés. D'après l'enquête auprès des fournisseurs de soins de santé, seul un faible pourcentage des répondants [n = 21/60, 35%] considéraient les personnes âgées de 65 ans et plus comme l'un des membres les moins vulnérables de la société. Alors que la plupart des répondants étaient d'avis qu'il appartenait aux travailleurs de la santé de se renseigner sur les problèmes sociaux sous-jacents de leurs patients (n = 43/60, 71,7%), certains médecins ne croyaient pas que questions, au-delà de se référer au travail social [Kruskal-Wallis 2 = 16,775; df = 2, p = 0,05, 2 = 5,991]; [Obs diff 22,180, critique diff 16,098] .Il y avait des preuves solides pour soutenir que la plupart des médecins qui avaient les soins dispensés antérieurement à des patients isolés croyaient qu'il leur incombait d'aborder les problèmes sociaux des patients au-delà du travail social [p &lt;0,001].DéductionLa plupart des agents de santé, dans ce cadre d'étude, ont reconnu l'importance de s'attaquer à l'isolement social chez les personnes âgées, mais ignoraient tout programme ou mandat de sensibilisation dans leur description de travail qui leur permettrait de poursuivre dans cette voie. La création d'un programme de sensibilisation communautaire accrédité par le Conseil médical de la Jamaïque peut fournir à ces médecins deux résultats: les outils nécessaires pour fournir des services de proximité aux personnes âgées isolées et l'accréditation requise pour renouveler leur licence médicale. Les patients et les aides-soignants communautaires étaient d'accord sur le fait que le transport et les restrictions financières constituaient des obstacles importants à l'accès aux soins de santé. On croyait également fortement que beaucoup de personnes isolées bénéficieraient de médecins voyageant dans des communautés plus rurales pour fournir des soins de santé.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anne Adina Andermann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1071300.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z29p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Family Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811kn05r"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La marginalité, résistance identitaire dans quatre romans français du milieu du XXème siècle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dhumerelle, Valériane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This master thesis explores the marginal identities of the main characters in four French novels from the mid-twentieth century:  Le Feu follet (1931) by Pierre Drieu la Rochelle, Un Beau ténébreux (1945) by Julien Gracq, La Volupté d'être (1954) by Maurice Druon et Le Procès-verbal (1963) by Jean-Marie Gustave Le Clézio. They are solitary characters who maintain themselves in peripheral social spaces with which they nurture a simultaneously centrifugal and centripetal relationship. Linked to the final disappearance of the protagonists, this dual dynamic of attraction and repulsion is approached as a provisory suspension of their fall, which is unavoidable. This reading is supported by a triple analysis: social, through the study of the interindividual relationships developed between the characters and their acquaintances, spatial, through the observation of the distances that establish the marginal scope, and of identity, through the awareness of the marginal's auto-perception and the autarkic strategies they display. The understanding of marginality as proposed by the present work is thereupon the one of a deferment, both suffered and assented by the marginal and generated by him in order to put his own self on hold. Supposedly vulnerable on account of a physical or mental dwindling, the marginal is on the contrary seen in this thesis as an active identity, who alone fights the threats against his uniqueness. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire explore la marginalité identitaire qui marque quatre personnages de romans français du milieu du vingtième siècle :  Le Feu follet (1931) de Pierre Drieu la Rochelle, Un Beau ténébreux (1945) de Julien Gracq, La Volupté d'être (1954) de Maurice Druon et Le Procès-verbal (1963) de Jean-Marie Gustave Le Clézio. Il s'agit de personnages solitaires se maintenant dans la fréquentation périphérique d'espaces sociaux et entretenant avec eux une relation simultanément centripète et centrifuge. Mise en relation avec la disparition finale des protagonistes, cette double dynamique d'attraction et de répulsion est ainsi abordée comme une suspension provisoire de leur chute, pourtant inévitable. Cette lecture est soutenue par une triple analyse : sociale, d'abord, à travers l'étude des rapports interindividuels développés par les personnages avec leur entourage, spatiale, ensuite, par l'observation des distances établissant le champ de la marginalité, identitaire, enfin, par la prise en compte de l'auto-perception des marginaux et des stratégies autarciques qu'ils déploient. La conception de la marginalité que propose ce travail est dès lors celle d'un sursis, mise en attente à la fois subie et consentie du marginal par lui-même. Être a priori vulnérable par un état d'amenuisement physique ou mental, le marginal est au contraire abordé par ce mémoire comme une identité active en situation de lutte autonome contre la mise en danger de son originalité.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Isabelle Daunais</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn93n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn05r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French Language and Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tf339"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Resistance training to improve energy metabolism, body composition, and physical function in rheumatoid arthritis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chiarlitti, Nathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Rheumatoid arthritis (RA) is a chronic autoimmune disease characterized by high levels of inflammation, pain, disability, and pre-mature mortality. RA places a significant burden on individuals and the healthcare system as people with RA are more likely to be disabled. Unfavourable changes in energy metabolism and body composition may contribute substantially to the disability and poor health-related quality of life associated with RA.The purpose of this project was to conduct a pilot trial exploring the feasibility and safety of a 12-week progressive resistance training program (PRT) on physical function in RA. A secondary objective was to explore potential mechanisms associated with changes in physical function including energy metabolism, body composition, and muscle strength. It was hypothesized that the 12-week program would result in improved physical function, body composition, muscle strength, and energy metabolism. Eighteen participants with RA (17 females, mean (SD) age 38 (19) years, weight of 65.1 (8.4) kg, RA duration of 8 (5) years) were included in this study. All were sedentary, under the care of a rheumatologist and had received clearance to exercise. At baseline, participants provided sociodemographic information and completed validated questionnaires assessing perceived physical function/disability (i.e., PROMIS-4a, MDHAQ, RA-FQ Physical Function). They also completed questionnaires that assessed disease activity (RAPID3 and RA-FQ), exercise self-efficacy, physical activity enjoyment, and daily physical activity. Participants also underwent tests assessing resting energy expenditure assessment (REE), body composition (dual energy x-ray absorptiometry), and physical function tests (Short Performance Physical Battery, 400-m walk, muscle strength). Participants were randomized to 12 weeks of either a resistance training + flexibility PRT+FLEX); or flexibility (FLEX). The PRF+FLEX group completed two supervised workouts using resistance training equipment and range of motion (FLEX) exercises, and one home-based workout per week using elastic resistance bands. The FLEX group completed the same range of motion (FLEX) exercises at home. Repeated measures ANOVA revealed statistically significant interaction effects in body fat percentage (p = .010), fat-mass index (p = .017), RA-FQ Physical Function (p = .002), RA-FQ disease activity (p = .002), RAPID3 (p = .002), and physical activity enjoyment (p = .026) that favoured the PRT+FLEX over the FLEX group. Additionally, there was an effect of time for appendicular lean mass (p = .028), lower body lean mass (p = .030), PROMIS-4a (p = .002), MDHAQ (p = .005), 400-m walk (p = .002), knee flexion strength (p = .008) and REE (p = .014) with the PRT+FLEX group improving more than the FLEX group. There was no between group differences for total body mass, bone mass, lean mass, SPPB, visceral fat, number of cachectic participants, knee extension strength, exercise self-efficacy, and daily physical activity. The findings of this study suggest that a 12-week resistance exercise program is feasible, safe, and enjoyable in people with RA and can improve physical function, body composition, and muscle strength. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'arthrite rhumatoïde (AR) est une maladie immunitaire chronique caractérisée par des niveaux élevés d'inflammation, de douleur, d'incapacité et de mortalité prématurée. La maladie de l'AR peut être diagnostiquée à n'importe quel moment dans la vie d'un individu et elle constitue un fardeau important pour la société et le système de santé, dû aux nombreuses comorbidités et l'aide quotidienne qu'ont besoin les personnes atteintes par cette maladie. De plus, l'AR est souvent associée à une diminution de la masse musculaire, de la force, du métabolisme énergétique ce qui joue un rôle important sur les fonctions physiques et la qualité de vie des personnes atteintes par cette maladie. Le but de ce projet était d'examiner les effets d'un programme de musculation de 12 semaines sur les fonctions physiques des personnes atteintes de l'AR. Notre objectif secondaire était d'explorer les changements dans la composition corporelle, la force musculaire et la dépense énergétique au repos à la suite du programme. Dix-huit participants (17 femmes et 1 homme, âge = 38 ± 19 ans, poids = 65,1 ± 8,4 kg, durée de la maladie = 8 ± 5 ans) ont été inclus dans cette étude. Tous les participants avaient un diagnostic médical de l'AR, ils étaient sédentaires depuis au moins trois mois et ils avaient l'autorisation de leur rhumatologue d'exécuter un programme d'entraînement supervisé. Au début, les participants devaient remplir des questionnaires sur leurs propres caractéristiques (éducation, activité de la maladie, médicaments) et sur leur incapacité (p. ex. PROMIS-4A, RA-FQ, MDHAQ), tout en complétant une absorptiométrie à rayons-X à double énergie. Ils devaient également participer aux tests mesurant les fonctions physiques (batterie de courte durée, marche de 400 m), à un test de force musculaire et à une évaluation de la dépense énergétique au repos. Une fois les évaluations de bases complétées, les participants ont été aléatoirement choisis pour participer soit au groupe de résistance + flexibilité (PRT + FLEX), ou au groupe de flexibilité (FLEX). Le programme d'exercices exigeait que les participants effectuent deux entrainements supervisés (y compris des exercices de flexibilité) et un entrainement à la maison par semaine en utilisant des bandes de résistance élastique tandis que le groupe de flexibilité effectuait des exercices d'amplitude non-supervisés. Des améliorations cliniquement significatives aux examens des fonctions physiques (MDHAQ, PROMIS-Fonction physique 4A) ont été observées pour les deux groupes, cependant, le groupe PRT + FLEX avait de meilleurs résultats que le groupe FLEX dans toutes les évaluations des fonctions physiques. Les mesures répétées ANOVA ont révélé des effets d'interaction statistiquement significatifs au niveau du pourcentage de graisse corporelle (p = 0,010), l'indice de masse graisseuse (p = 0,017), la fonction physique (RA-FQ) (p = 0,001), et le plaisir lié à l'activité physique (p =. 026), ce qui a favorisé le PRT + FLEX comparativement au groupe FLEX. Les résultats de cette étude ont des implications cliniques importantes à cause des améliorations des fonction physique et de la composition corporelle révélées par le programme de musculation de 12 semaines. Pour les professionnels de la santé, cette étude renforce la sécurité et l'efficacité de la prescription d'exercices de musculation aux patients atteints de l'AR afin d'améliorer les fonctions physiques et la composition corporelle. Chaque fois que cela est approprié, un entrainement de résistance devrait être recommandé pour les personnes atteintes de cette importante maladie. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ross Andersen</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Susan Bartlett</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676z10g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tf339</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans064814r"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of soft exoskeleton with elastic assistance on ice hockey forward skating acceleration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McPhee, Brian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master's study examined the performance effects of a soft exoskeleton designed to store and return elastic energy about the hip joint during ice hockey skating starts. Three elastic resistance conditions ("Soft", "Medium", "Stiff") were examined. Kinematic, kinetic and perception data were collected on nine male high calibre hockey players during skating start accelerations over nine meters. This study demonstrated the feasibility of introducing soft exoskeletons to store and return elastic energy to an athlete's body while skating on ice. Several participants responded well, on average yielding 1.54% shorter times during skating start performance (p=0.052). Gross skating kinetic and kinematic patterns were unaltered, though reduced stride length and double support times were counter balanced by higher cadence. Based on individual time performance and preference measures, specific elastic resistances need to be tailored to each athlete in order to optimize their performance. Further study is warranted with larger sample sizes, both male and female athletes, longer familiarization periods, and on different skating tasks.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette maîtrise à examinée les effets de performance d'un exosquelette avec le but de retenir et redonner de l'énergie élastique au joint de l'hanche durant un accélération de départ-arrêté de hockey sur glace. Trois conditions de résistance élastique (souple, moyen et rigide) ont étés examiner. Des datas kinématique, kinétique et de perception ont étés collectionné sur neuf joueur de hockey de haut calibre pendant des accélérations de départ-arrêté sur neuf mètres. Ce projet démontre la faisabilité d'introduire des exosquelettes souple avec le but de retenir et redonner de l'énergie élastique au joint de l'hanche au corps de l'athlète durant le patinage sur la glace. Plusieurs participants ont bien réagi; en moyenne ils ont eu un rendement de vitesse de patinage de 1.54% plus vite (p=0.052). Les mouvements kinématique et kinétique n'ont pas changés, par contre la réduction de distance de pas et le temps de support double ont étés contre-balancés par une plus grande cadence. Basé sur les performances de temps et les mesures de préférences de chaque individuel, la résistance élastique a besoin d'être adapté différemment pour chaque athlète pour pouvoir optimiser leurs performance. D'autres études sont requis avec ces changements: des plus grandes échantillons, avec mâle et femelle, avec des périodes de familiarisation plus long et avec différentes type de mouvements de patinage.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David J. Pearsall</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Shawn Robbins</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w024.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064814r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mx773"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identifying approaches to incorporating indigenous ways of knowing in PHETE: Informed by Mohawk narratives</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wasyliw, Derek</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude est une enquête narrative sur les expériences de deux détenteurs de grandes connaissances dans la communauté Kanien'keha:ka (Mohawk) qui constituent 7200 habitants et qui est situé à 15 kilomètres au sud-ouest de Montréal au Canada. Le but de cette thèse était de développer une meilleure connaissance sur les manières d'enseignements autochtones pour savoir s'il serait possible d'inclure ceux-ci à l'intérieur d'un programme d'enseignement de l'éducation physique pour professeur. Ce programme a pour objectif d'appeler pour un curriculum et plus d'enseignement sensible à la culture. Les narratives personnelles de mes participants, de même que les enquêtes à l'intérieurs de ces narratives, ont révélé plusieurs sujets important : (a) les histoires riches perturbent l'incorporation de notions simples sur les manières d'apprentissages autochtones en illustrant que les manières de savoir Haudenosaunee sont profondément contextuels, culturels, familials, politiques, géographiques et donc complexes. Alors, il est important de représenter se savoir d'une manière non-générale; (b) leurs histoires rejettent une vérité de colonisation et plaident pour un faillibilisme qui heurte les compréhensions eurocentriques; Cette étude fourni des évidences sur la complexité des manières de savoirs des populations autochtones et sur l'incorporation des programmes PHETE. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study is a narrative inquiry into the experiences of two knowledge holders in Kahnawà:ke, a Kanien'keha:ka (Mohawk) community of approximately 7,200 people located 15 kilometers south west of Montreal, Canada. The purpose of this thesis is to gain a better understanding of how Indigenous ways of knowing may be both practically and theoretically included within PHETE programs with the intent of attending to calls for more culturally relevant teaching and curriculum. The personal narratives of the participants, along with the inquiry into those narratives, reveal a number of key threads: (a) the rich stories disrupt the simplistic notion of incorporating Indigenous ways of knowing by illustrating that Haudenosaunee ways of knowing are complex with deeply contextual, cultural, familial, political, geographical components and in turn complex, thus it is important to represent this knowledge in a non-generalizable fashion; (b) their stories reject a settled truth and advocate for a fallibalism that bumps with Eurocentric understandings of knowledge. This study provides insights into the complexities of Indigenous ways of knowing and its incorporation into PHETE programming. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lee Schaefer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w4715.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx773</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m413v"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tenuous power, anxious peace: postrevolutionary war stagings of identity in the transatlantic theatre, 1783-1832</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>King, Jonathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La résolution de la Révolution américaine de 1783 mettrait fin à un lien entre deux peuples quiavaient paru auparavant interminables. Bien que les deux projettent réflexivement une assurance de soi à l'autre, la révolution initierait une renégociation de la politique identitaire qui régissait depuis longtemps les deux nations. Dans le théâtre britannique et américain au tournant du dix-huitième siècle, cette crise d'identité était encore palpable. À travers une double analyse de l'histoire de performance de Dunlap's André d'un côté de l'Atlantique et de la popularité sensationnelle de Pizarro de Richard Brinsley Sheridan, cette thèse tente de montrer que les notions de liberté au coeur de la Révolution américaine viendraient pour stimuler la contestation interne dans les deux politiques, pour susciter plus de questions que de réponses. À la suite de cette historiographie théâtrale, cette thèse analysera la capacité du théâtre à opérer comme theatrum mundi politique à cette période en raison de son inclusivité. À un moment historique où l'identité était aussi peu fiable que la loyauté et les forces internes et externes entravaient l'autodéfinition nationale, le théâtre fournissait une base à la communauté qui était par ailleurs manifestement absente.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The resolution of the American Revolution in 1783 would terminate a tether between two peoples that had previously seemed interminable. Though both would reflexively project a selfassuredness to the other, the Revolution would initiate a renegotiation of the identity politics that had long governed both nations. In both the British and American theatre at the turn of the eighteenth century, this crisis of identity was still palpable. Through a dual analysis of the embattled performance history of William Dunlap's André on one side of the Atlantic and the sensational popularity of Richard Brinsley Sheridan's Pizarro on the other, this thesis endeavours to show that the notions of liberty at the heart of the American Revolution would come to stimulate internal contestation in both polities, to elicit more questions than it did answers.F ollowing this theatre historiography, this thesis will analyze the theatre's capacity to operate as political theatrum mundi in this period as a result of its inclusivity. At a historical moment where identity was as unreliable as loyalty and forces both internal and external stood in the way ofnational self-definition, the theatre provided a basis for community that was otherwise manifestly absent.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fiona Ritchie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs85t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m413v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386m72h"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of a DVH registry for plan evaluation, dose accumulation, and cohort analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Patrick, Haley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite considerable research and widespread adherence to recommended dosimetric constraints, side effects from radiation toxicities continue to decrease quality-of-life in a large percentage of radiotherapy patients on the order of 50% for some cancers. These issues are likely tied to interobserver variation in radiotherapy contour definitions and the use of planned dose distributions to assess toxicity responses, rather than those that were delivered. The aim of this project was to develop a tool, known as the DVH Registry, incorporating  delivered dose calculations and contouring quality assurance features for the analysis of large radiotherapy datasets. The DVH (dose-volume histogram) Registry is an interactive web application constructed using a Django framework with a Bootstrap and Javascript front end. Patient DVHs and treatment data are imported  into the Registry's database from the radiotherapy treatment planning system using automated scripts, and data analysis is performed using various Python statistics modules. A retrospective study of 560 patients receiving hypofractionated radiotherapy of the prostate (60 Gy in 20 fractions) was performed with the Registry to determine the effect of physician contouring practices on organ dose. Interobserver variation in pelvic lymph node contouring was observed to systematically impact the dose to bladder and rectum. A second pilot study calculated the dose delivered to the rectums of twelve prostate cancer patients and found that delivered doses differed from planned doses in eight individuals. The DVH Registry developed, tested and used in this research project is now available as a tool to facilitate further clinical research studies in radiotherapy.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les effets secondaires des traitements de radiothérapie dus à la toxicité continuent de diminuer la qualité de vie d'une grande partie des patients, et ce, malgré des recherches considérables et le respect des contraintes dosimétriques recommandées. Ces problèmes sont probablement liés à la variation inter-observateurs au niveau de la définition des contours des structures d'intérêt de même qu'à l'utilisation de la distribution de la dose planifiée --- et non délivrée --- pour évaluer la toxicité. Le but de ce projet était donc de développer un outil, nommé le DVH Registry (registre des histogrammes dose-volume), avec des fonctionnalités de calcul de la distribution de la dose délivrée et de contrôle de la qualité des contours pour l'analyse de grands ensembles de données de radiothérapie. Le DVH Registry est une application web interactive construite à partir d'une structure Django avec une interface Bootstrap et Javascript. Les DVHs des patients de même que les données du traitement sont entrés automatiquement dans la base de données du logiciel DVH Registry à partir du système de planification de traitement de radiothérapie. L'analyse des données est facilitée grâce à divers modules statistiques Python. Une étude rétrospective comprenant 560 patients recevant un traitement de radiothérapie hypofractionnée pour la prostate a été réalisée avec le système DVH Registry pour évaluer l'impact de la variation des contours produits par les médecins sur la dose reçue à l'organe d'intérêt. Les résultats de l'étude ont montré que la variation inter-observateurs au niveau du contour du nœud lymphatique pelvien a un impact systématique sur la dose reçue à la vessie et au rectum. Une seconde étude comprenant douze patients recevant un traitement pour la prostate a été réalisée dans le but d'évaluer la dose délivrée au rectum. Les résultats de cette étude ont montré que la dose délivrée diffère de la dose planifiée dans huit cas sur douze. Le DVH Registry développé, testé et utilisé dans ce projet de recherche est maintenant disponible comme un outil pour faciliter d'autres études de recherche clinique en radiothérapie.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Kildea</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g490m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m72h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xn94x"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Monitoring the closest supermassive black hole: X-ray and infrared variability of Sgr A*</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyce, Hope</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Emission from Sgr A* is highly variable at both X-ray and infrared (IR) wavelengths. Observations over the last ~20 years have detected X-ray flares that rise above a quiescent thermal background about once per day, while faint X-ray flares from Sgr A* are undetectable below the constant thermal emission. In contrast, the IR emission of Sgr A* can be seen to be continuously variable. Recently, simultaneous observations have observed a rise in IR activity around the same time as every distinct X-ray flare, while the opposite is not always true (peaks in the IR emission are not always coincident with an X-ray flare). Characterizing the behaviour of these simultaneous X-ray/IR events and measuring any time lag between them can constrain models of the accretion flow and the emission mechanism. Using 100+ hours of overlapping data from a coordinated campaign between the Spitzer Space Telescope and the Chandra X-ray Observatory, we present results of the longest simultaneous IR and X-ray observations of Sgr A* taken to date. The cross-correlation between the IR and X-ray light curves in this unprecedented dataset, which include four modest X-ray/IR flares, show evidence that flaring in the X-ray may lead the IR by 10-20 minutes with 68% confidence, but remain consistent with simultaneity at 99.7% confidence. Simultaneous multi-wavelength observations of more bright flares will improve our ability to constrain the flare timing characteristics and emission mechanisms, and must be a priority for Galactic Center observing campaigns.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'émission du trou noir supermassif Sagittarius A* (Sgr A*) est variable à la fois aux longueurs d'onde des rayons X et infrarouges (IR). Les observations faites au cours des ~20 dernières années ont détecté des éruptions de rayons X comme des événements distincts au-dessus d'un arrière-plan calme, se produisant en moyenne une fois par jour. En revanche, l'émission IR semble varier continuellement. Récemment, des observations simultanées ont observé que les éruptions de rayons X s'accompagnent toujours d'une augmentation de l'activité IR, alors que l'inverse n'est pas toujours vrai (les pics de l'IR ne sont pas tous accompagnés de pics dans les rayons X). Caractériser le comportement de ces événements simultanés et mesurer tout décalage entre eux peut contraindre les modèles du flux d'accrétion et du mécanisme d'émission. Utilisant plus de 100 heures de données de chevauchement provenant d'une campagne coordonnée entre le Spitzer Space Telescope et le Chandra X-ray Observatory, nous présentons les résultats des plus longues observations IR et X simultanées de Sgr A * à ce jour. La corrélation croisée entre les courbes IR et rayons X montre que les pics des rayons X peuvent devancer ceux de l'IR de 10 - 20 minutes avec une confiance de 68%, mais rester cohérente avec la simultanéité à un niveau de confiance de 99,7%.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daryl Haggard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g245m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn94x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214r478"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>De Juan de Flores à Jeanne Flore via Maurice Scève: trajectoire intertextuelle et héritage boccacien</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Raulier, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The introductory poem placed in the beginning of the Comptes amoureux de Jeanne Flore seems to refer to a second poem. Which one is situated in the margins of another text written in Lyon a few years earlier : La Deplourable fin de Flamete, a traduction by Maurice Scève of the work of Juan de Flores, Grimalte y Gradissa. This echo goes past the simple repetition and inverts the amorous conception taking place in Scève's text. Thereby, it reveals the parodic dimension inherent to Jeanne Flore's tale collection.This thesis aims to examine the parodic perspective in the Comptes amoureux, regarding the different intertextual devices implemented through an itinerary following the development of the genre of the sentimental fiction in Italy, Spain, and France. This route leads us from Boccaccio's Elegia di Madonna Fiammetta to the Deplourable fin de Flamete and the Comptes amoureux, passing by Grimalte y Gradissa. With the present case study, we are able to consider the development of the genre of the amorous fiction in France, and particularly in Lyon, as gathering various influences, among which the Boccaccian heritage stands in the foreground, at a confluence of literary practices during the Renaissance.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le huitain liminaire qui prend place au début des Comptes amoureux de Jeanne Flore fait référence à un second huitain, un peu antérieur et situé en marge d'un autre texte lyonnais. Ce dernier, La Deplourable fin de Flamete, consiste en une traduction effectuée par Maurice Scève d'une œuvre espagnole de Juan de Flores, Grimalte y Gradissa. Cet écho dépasse la simple répétition et inverse la conception amoureuse mise en place par Scève, levant par le fait même le voile sur la dimension parodique inhérente au recueil de Jeanne Flore.Ce mémoire vise l'approfondissement de cette visée parodique des Comptes amoureux, en regard des pratiques intertextuelles mises en œuvre dans un itinéraire qui suit le développement du genre de la fiction sentimentale en Italie, en Espagne et en France : depuis l'Elegia di Madonna Fiammetta de Boccace jusqu'à la La Deplourable fin de Flamete et les Comptes amoureux, en passant par Grimalte y Gradissa. Cette étude de cas mène à considérer le genre de la fiction sentimentale qui se développe en France, et principalement à Lyon, comme réunissant diverses influences parmi lesquelles l'héritage boccacien se retrouve au premier plan, au confluent des pratiques littéraires de la Renaissance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Diane Desrosiers</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f56n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r478</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French Language and Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p9535"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Locating the viewer of digital art: A case study of Ian Cheng's 'Emissaries' (2015-2017)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dare, Zoya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le numérique est omniprésent dans les sociétés occidentales contemporaines. Les spectateurs sont aussi des utilisateurs de technologies, alors que se passe-t-il lorsque l'art qu'ils voient embrasse le médium numérique, mais nie la relation habituelle de l'utilisateur. Cette thèse vise à mieux comprendre le spectateur de l'art numérique contemporain. Pour ce faire, elle examine la série de trois simulations numériques de l'artiste américain Ian Cheng intitulée Emissaries (2015- 2017). Les œuvres sont numériques mais non participatives. L'artiste les qualifie de « jeux vidéo qui se jouent eux-mêmes », mais à travers leur structure et leur contexte, elles abordent notre relation à la technologie. En supprimant l'engagement direct, les Emissaries nous permettent de considérer les propriétés de la médialité numérique et notre relation avec elle.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The digital is ubiquitous in contemporary Western societies. Art viewers are also users of technology, so what happens when the art they see embraces the digital medium but denies the habitual user relationship? This thesis seeks to understand the viewer of contemporary digital art. To do so, it examine American artist Ian Cheng's series of three digital simulations titled Emissaries (2015-2017). The works are digital but not participatory. The artist refers to them as "video games that play themselves," but through their structure and context, they address our relationship with technology. By removing direct engagement, the Emissaries allow us to consider the nature of digital mediality and our relationship with it.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ross, Christine</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r670.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p9535</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art History and Communication Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>