<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45q984g"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Decompaction of a degraded clay soil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chambers, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An experiment was set up at Alfred College, in Eastern Ontario, to investigate methods of correcting the negative effects of deep compaction of fine textured soils. The site was divided into two fields of four treatments with three replicates of each. Treatment 1 was control, treatment 2 subsoiled, treatment 3 compacted and treatment 4 compacted then subsoiled. In year 1 barley was sown in both fields, underseeded with alfalfa in Field 1. The following year alfalfa was grown in Field 1 and corn using minimum tillage in field 2. Measurements included cone penetration resistance, dry bulk density, and crop yields. It was found that compaction had a significant effect on lowering yields. However, due to the experiment methodology in the measuring of cone penetration resistance and dry bulk density plus a blocking effect in the corn field, the results were inconclusive statistically as to whether the subsoiling in combination with minimum tillage and alfalfa had an effect of decompacting the soil profile.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McKyes, Edward</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p806k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45q984g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tillage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil stabilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Clay soils</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33rx554"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Classics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Erinyes in Sophocles' Oedipus at Colonus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pearcey, Linda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chapter One of this thesis explores the identity of the Eumenides, the resident deities in Sophocles' Oedipus at Colonus. By examining the language and contents of two important ritual acts in the play, it is proven that their title is euphemistic; these goddesses are the transformed Erinyes of Aeschylus. Oedipus and his sinfulness is the focus of Chapter Two. Although he has committed the heinous crimes of incest and parricide, Oedipus seems to be exempt from the Erinyes' hounding. By reviewing the charges laid against him, it is revealed that Oedipus is a morally innocent man. The final chapter deals with Oedipus' apotheosis and the role played by the Eumenides. By examining the play's dramatic action, it is demonstrated that Oedipus, a man of innate heroic nature, is deserving of heroization. But to reach his exalted end, the championship of the Eumenides is required.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Snider, G. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr136.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rx554</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Erinyes (Greek mythology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sophocles. Oedipus at Colonus</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cx257"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Application of logistic regression in biostatistics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Yin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The primary objective of this paper is a focused introduction to the logistic regression model and its use in methods for modeling the relationship between a dichotomous outcome variable and a set of covariates. The approach we will take is to develop the model from a regression analysis point of view. Also in this paper, an estimator of the common odds ratio in one-to-one matched case-control studies is proposed. The connection between this estimator and the James-Stein estimating procedure is highlighted through the argument of estimating functions. Comparisons are made between this estimator, the conditional maximum likelihood estimator, and the estimator ignoring the matching.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gu, Minggao</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w320g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cx257</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tc97f"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Understanding the community-level impacts of tourism development : the case of Pond Inlet, NWT</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grekin, Jacqueline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis aims to provide a better understanding of the economic and socio-cultural impacts associated with small scale tourism development in the Inuit community of Pond Inlet, Baffin Island. A brief history and economic profile of the community illuminate the reasons underlying its adoption of tourism as a source of income and employment. I then proceed to review past attempts to understand the relationship between tourism and community development. Despite the merits of these studies, they are shown to have largely failed to supply a theoretical framework capable of explaining the underlying factors that influence the scale and nature of the resulting impacts. I then propose that recent theoretical developments, based on the 'flexible specialization' approach, may better assist our attempts to understand the dynamic relationship between tourism and the communities that host it. The empirical section of the thesis is based on surveys of several key actors: residents, tourists, and the tourist industry. When combined with a simplified multiplier analysis, the findings indicate that the community's current tourism strategy is largely consistent with local economic objectives and that as a result residents support tourism development. Nevertheless, the results suggest certain weaknesses in the current approach to tourism development. They include: the potential for conflicts to develop between local hunters and wildlife watchers; a failure to link tourism to other sectors of the local economy; and difficulties reaching consumers in the context of a restructured travel industry increasingly dominated by computer technology. I then proceed to provide some policy and planning recommendations. This is followed by a brief evaluation of the theoretical approach adopted. I conclude by outlining some areas for future research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milne, Simon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj61s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc97f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tourism -- Nunavut -- Pond Inlet</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An870zr63k"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children's game and toy preferences : a contemporary analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bathiche, Marie E., 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Society's changing norms and cultural values are often reflected in children's play activities and their choice of toys and games. Empirical findings have revealed that children's game preferences are influenced by several factors including the child's sex and age. The main aim of this study was to examine the game/toy preferences of children living in two distinct societies. The game/toy preferences of 336 (162 females, 174 males) children living in a non-western society, United Arab Emirates (U.A.E.), were examined and compared with the preferences of 366 children living in Canada. Developmental trends and sex differences were noted. This study also examined children's current game/toy preferences in relation to past reports (Sutton-Smith &amp; Rosenberg, 1961). Results suggest that children living in the U.A.E. and in Canada share similar game/toy preferences however, differences were found between the game/toy preferences of contemporary children and those 30 years ago. The data are analyzed and discussed in the light of societal's changing norms and values, changes in parenting styles and the advances in technology. The psychological and educational implications of the present findings are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denevensky, Jeffrey L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw91m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr63k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Toys -- United Arab Emirates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Toys -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h041p"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Participation and motives in sport relative to perceived competence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson-Howe, Heather J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Children's participation and motives in sport relative to their perceived athletic competence were investigated. One hundred and sixty-three grade 5 and 6 children from a suburban elementary school completed questionnaires designed to assess perceived athletic competence (PAC), sport participation, and participant motives. The sample, when divided into groups by level of sport involvement, revealed that participants at the higher levels had greater PAC than those at the lowest level. Boys and girls did not differ significantly in PAC. The children rated fun and skill/fitness as the most important motives for their participation in sport. When divided on the basis of PAC scores, the top one third of the sample scored significantly higher on all seven motives for participation in sport than the lower one third. Discriminant function analyses revealed that motives of challenge/team atmosphere and skill/fitness best differentiated the high from the low PAC groups. Girls participated to relax and have fun while boys may have been motivated to participate for the challenge and the team atmosphere. The results are interpreted in terms of school and community sport program development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Neil, Graham</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dq555.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h041p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sports for children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sports -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arf55z8744"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ita</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le belle infedeli : l'Iliade in versi e in prosa dell'abate Melchiorre Cesarotti</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barreca, Francesca</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following work consists of a careful analysis of the translation of the Iliad by Homer prepared by Melchiorre Cesarotti. Caught amidst the dilemma of loyalty to the original and the beauty of translation, Cesarotti decided to compose two versions: one in blank verses and the other in prose. This work is therefore none other than a comparison between Cesarotti's version in poetry and the version in prose. The first part deals briefly with a few details on the criticism that Cesarotti's work raised. The second part consists of the comparison work, which is subdivided in "Canti" (as Cesarotti's version in poetry) because the work proposes to compare the version in poetry to the version in prose and not vice-versa. The last part examines the artistic value of Cesarotti's translations and the place they occupy in Europe in the eighteenth century.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gilardino, Sergio</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg35j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z8744</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Greek language -- Translating into Italian -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Homer -- Translations into Italian -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cesarotti, Melchiorre, 1730-1808 -- Criticism, Textual</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cesarotti, Melchiorre, 1730-1808 -- Knowledge -- Language and languages</dc:subject><dc:subject>Homer. Iliad -- Adaptations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Translating and interpreting -- Italy -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j896d"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nathalie Sarraute : raconter l'"Enfance"</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grondal, Ewa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master's thesis is based on Nathalie Sarraute's book Enfance, published in 1983. One would be tempted to classify this work among other autobiographies ... if the author were not opposed to this idea. Nevertheless, we will attempt to discover what category this book belongs to in our study. In the introduction we give conventional and classical definitions of both the autobiography and the novel. In the first chapter we analyse Enfance as an autobiography, according to the criteria of certain theoreticians such as Jean Starobinski, Elisabeth Bruss and Philippe Lejeune. We shall also compare it with similar genres, such as memoirs, the fictional autobiography and the selfportrait. In the second chapter we will read this work as a novel, comparing it to other novels by Sarraute as well as to an autobiographical novel. After having examined the different readings of this work, we conclude that Enfance does not belong to any of the proposed categories in its entirety. The author, therefore, has given us a new genre which finds itself somewhere between an autobiography and a novel.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Everett, Jane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr016.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j896d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sarraute, Nathalie. Enfance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fm454"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soil erosion : the incentives for and effectiv[e]ness of control efforts on cropland in the United States</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Halls, Carol</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Soil erosion from American cropland poses a problem to society in many ways. Ground and surface water is polluted by chemicals carried on the eroded soil, silt builds up in rivers and other water bodies, soil particles carried by wind pollute the air, and finally there is a decline in the productivity of the remaining cropland soil. The rate that soil is eroded from cropland is directly affected by the type of crops planted, tillage systems used and government agricultural programs. This thesis presents the economic costs of soil erosion from cropland and the private and social benefits that can be obtained by reducing erosion rates. Many conservation programs have been less than effective in controlling erosion levels and some commodity and income programs have actually increased erosion rates. A survey of government policies and their various effects on soil erosion rates is included in this thesis. Alternative government policy options are presented.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Green, Chris</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf152.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm454</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soil erosion -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil conservation -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430570d"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>How scientists reason : the use of unexpected findings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baker, Lisa M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While there is much data in the experimental cognitive psychology literature reporting that subjects working on science-like tasks ignore findings inconsistent with their hypotheses, much cognitive science research has found that reasoners focus on unexpected findings. To study how real-world scientists deal with unexpected findings, data was collected from a prominent immunology laboratory. Four lab meetings were analyzed using a standardized coding procedure. The amount of reasoning, interactions, and new hypotheses about unexpected versus expected findings was analyzed. Presenters at the meetings reasoned more about unexpected than expected findings, and group members reasoned and interacted extensively about unexpected findings. Both presenter and group members formed more new hypotheses about unexpected than about expected findings. These results are consistent with the finding in cognitive science research that reasoners focus on unexpected data. It is proposed that several heuristics influence which unexpected findings scientists pay attention to.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dunbar, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c141j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430570d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Reasoning (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Science -- Methodology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62f918g"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Women, AIDS, and invisibility in the United States : using feminist theory to understand sources and consequences of definitions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haddad, Khristina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The practical project of this thesis is to create a critical account of the experiences of women in the AIDS crisis in the United States. The theoretical project is to refine a concept of invisibility of various kinds of problems and obstacles women have been confronted with. The question that both parts of this project seek to answer is roughly the following: "What is it that we can learn about improving the lives of women by looking at the AIDS crisis as a lens into American social conditions at the end of the Twentieth Century?" Feminist theories provide a basis for this inquiry as well as the theoretical work on a concept of invisibility.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tully, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hq58q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f918g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIDS (Disease) -- United States -- Social aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g841n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>El fracaso de Mariano José de Larra como escritor politico</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ohlmann, Georg</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this study of Mariano Jose de Larra's Articulos, it will be shown why Larra was not able to achieve his goal of improving the general lack of culture in Spain, which was, according to him, the biggest obstacle to progress. Larra, a liberal writer, wanted to help Spain become a liberal country, if necessary by revolution, which was to be brought about by his writings. He chose to write newspaper articles, a then still very new medium. Although celebrated for his biting satire, Larra's advice was not heeded. The reasons for this are to be found in the special circumstances of the liberalization of Spain as well as personal circumstances of Larra, which will be addressed in the paper.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r8790.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g841n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Larra, Mariano José de, 1809-1837 -- Political and social views</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spain -- Intellectual life -- 19th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah702q7213"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimized fingertip mapping and hand modeling for telemanipulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rohling, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A difficult research problem in the teleoperation of robot hands by hands masters is the development of an accurate method to transform the measured human hand poses to the robot hand. This thesis describes a novel optimized fingertip mapping (OFM) algorithm developed to perform the pose transformations and an accurate modeling method for the human hand. The OFM algorithm has been implemented to teleoperate the Utah/MIT Dextrous Hand (UMDH) by a new hand master: the Utah Dextrous Hand Master (UDHM). The keystone of the algorithm is the mapping of both the human fingertip positions and orientations to the robot finger. Robot hand poses are generated by minimizing the errors between desired human fingertip positions and orientations and possible robot fingertip positions and orientations. Differences in the fingertip workspaces which arise from kinematic dissimilarities between the human and robot hands are accounted for by the use of a priority based mapping strategy. The OFM gives first priority to the human fingertip position goals and the second to orientation. Open-loop kinematic calibration is used as a method of human hand modeling. The parameters of a kinematic model of the index finger are determined as an example for human hand modeling. Singular value decomposition is used as a tool for analyzing the kinematic model and the identification process. Accurate and reliable results are obtained only when the numerical condition is minimized through parameter scaling, model reduction and pose set selection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hollerbach, John M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds97t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q7213</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42n888g"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An adaptive model of information processing in the primate retina</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shah, Samir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>At the retinal level, the strategies utilized by biological visual systems allow then to outperform machine vision systems, serving to motivate the design of electronic or "smart" sensors based on similar principles. Design of such sensors in silicon first requires a model of retinal information processing which captures the essential features exhibited by biological retinas. In this thesis, a simple retinal model is presented, which qualitatively accounts for the achromatic information processing in the primate cone system. The computer retina model exhibits many of the properties found in biological retinas such as data reduction through non-uniform sampling, adaptation to a large dynamic range of illumination levels, variation of visual acuity with illumination level, and enhancement of spatiotemporal contrast information. The model is validated by replicating experiments commonly performed by electrophysiologists on biological retinas and comparing the response of the computer retina to data from experiments in fish and monkeys. In addition, the response of the model to synthetic and real images is shown. The experiments demonstrate that the model behaves in a manner qualitatively similar to biological retinas and thus may serve as a basis for the development of an "artificial retina".</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levine, Martin D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t84c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n888g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hs773"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>DNA immobilization for the biomonitoring of carcinogens in the gastrointestinal tract</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Quong, Douglas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>DNA immobilization was demonstrated using the emulsification/internal gelation technique for calcium alginate bead production. The microspheres formed were recoverable magnetically, resistant to acidic environments, and strong enough to withstand gastrointestinal transit. Purification of DNA from alginate was accomplished sing a Sepharose CL-2B gel column, resulting in decreased alginate interference when quantifying DNA by absorbance. DNA microspheres were studied in vitro for the ability to trap ($ sp{14}$C) methyl iodide and in vivo with ($ sp{14}$C) benzo(a)pyrene. Assay of recovered DNA microspheres involved DNA purification by gel chromatography and liquid scintillation for the detection of bound radiolabel. Methylation resulted in a 2 fold increase in trapping of label within DNA microspheres compared to that of its control containing no DNA. The in vivo study showed a 5 fold increase in trapping with benzo(a)pyrene metabolites. Approximately 50% of the microspheres introduced by gavage to rats were recoverable magnetically, with a diameter reduction of 57.8% due to dewatering in the lower GI tract.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Neufeld, R. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b4312.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hs773</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418p14n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thermolysis of polystyrene</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simard, Yan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Styrene was recovered from polystyrene (molecular weight of 138 000) by thermolysis in a nitrogen atmosphere at temperatures between 368$ sp circ$C and 407$ sp circ$C. The results were independent of the initial weight of polystyrene which was varied between 30 and 480 grams. Up to 70% of the polystyrene was converted to styrene. The styrene yield increased with temperature. At higher temperatures, the residue left in the reactor consisted mainly of styrene monomer, dimer and trimer (MW of 190). The maximum rate constant of volatile production was found to fit a first order model. The activation energy obtained was 166.5 kJ/mol, which is in accordance with literature values.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kamal, M. R.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Cooper, D. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b15j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p14n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plastics Technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k589j"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cell culture of bush bean (Phaseolus vulgaris I. var. Contender)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liau, Deng-Fong</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t284m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k589j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant regulators</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant cells and tissues</dc:subject><dc:subject>Growth (Plants)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kidney bean</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603qz33r"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Observations on the biology and seasonal distribution of some Ephemeroptera in a stream system at Rigaud, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gibbs, K. Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd62q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qz33r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mayflies -- Seasonal distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mayflies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128b76p"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the arrested development of Haemonchus contortus (Rudolphi, 1803), Nematoda, in sheep</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blitz, Nicolas Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537206v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128b76p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nematodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Haemonchus contortus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sheep -- Parasites</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fm46d"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agronomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparative study of different procedures for heritability estimation in timothy Phleum pratense L.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Faris, Mohamed A.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161713h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm46d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Timothy-grass</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant breeding</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sw725"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Atonement ideas in the Qumran Scrolls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Garnet, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365594n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sw725</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atonement</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj38607880"><ual:graduationDate>1969</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sedimentary cycles and facies in the correlation and interpretation of Lower Cambrian rocks, east-central British Columbia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Young, Frederick Griffin, 1940-</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569543h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38607880</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology, Stratigraphic -- Cambrian</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sediments (Geology) -- British Columbia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cb780"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of endogenous and exogenous estrogen upon carbohydrate metabolism, lipogenesis and protein synthesis in the liver of the domestic fowl</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duncan, Howard James</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb313.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb780</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Estrogen -- Physiological effect</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qq45x"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The microclimate in relation to the development and behavior of a population of Melanoplus femurrubrum (DeGeer) (Orthoptera: Acrididae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dyck, Victor Arnold</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795861f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq45x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Animal ecology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Locusts</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cb77q"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of foreign competition on the Canadian primary steel industry : 1950-1966</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>DeMelto, Dennis</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hq590.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb77q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Steel industry and trade -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competition, International</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>