<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv935481m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In the eye of the beholder : evidence for development of change blindness</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miller, Danny, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The change blindness phenomenon, which is described as changes in the environment that are missed under natural viewing conditions because they occur simultaneously with another visual disruption, was studied from a developmental perspective. Participants included a total of 65 children in 3 age groups, 6, 8, and 10 years, and 20 adults, who were administered a version of the flicker paradigm, a technique in which blank screen is inserted between presentations (Rensink, O'Regan, &amp; Clark, 1997). Participants responded to multiple presentations of 2 objects, positioned side by side, displayed on a computer screen. In each presentation, a distracter object remained unchanged, whereas the target object changed in 1 of 3 ways, color switch, missing part, and rotation. Stimuli consisted of inanimate objects, photographs and drawings, and were displays in either 50 milliseconds or 250 milliseconds. Results revealed that 6 years old participants displayed the highest degrees of change blindness.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burack, Jacob A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f538z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935481m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Visual perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gj31h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of transnationalized markets on U.S. merger review</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mehler, Ulrich</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the impact of transnationalization on U.S. American merger review. It commences by outlining the principles of U.S. merger control, the notion of competition, and effects to be prevented. The study then proceeds with an analysis of transnationalization and gives an evaluation of its influence on firms, markets, and economic systems. The adjacent part holds a description of significant merger decisions made by the U.S. authorities during the recent years thereby covering important markets. An analysis focussing on a possible inequality of the treatment between mergers involving U.S. and foreign firms in order to meet exigencies generated by transnationalization that are not congruent with the objective of maintaining competition follows. The thesis concludes with an examination of extraterritorial application of U.S. antitrust law, the problems generated thereby and the various suggestions produced for a solution of the discrepancy between world-wide markets and enterprises and nationally confined legal systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, Richard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v48j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj31h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Competition, International</dc:subject><dc:subject>Consolidation and merger of corporations -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Globalization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antitrust law -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt48j"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigations of phosphate-mediated adhesion to dentin surfaces</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yavari, Mansoureh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of phosphate functionality and dentin surface state on adhesion to dentin was investigated in a series of experiments. In all cases, variable effects were evaluated by measuring the strength of adhesion promoted by either of two priming agents, (PENTA, or DIPENTA), or their combination, to different surface conditions of dentin. The main difference between primers is the presence of a phosphate functionality in PENTA. These experiments demonstrated that the phosphate-containing primer promotes significantly greater adhesion compared to the non-phosphate containing primer for all surface states studied. They further showed that on demineralized dentin, strong adhesion for PENTA may be due to phosphate interaction with collagen and the mineral aptatite of unaltered dentin. Finally, phosphate bonds to either intact or demineralized dentin were relatively stable in the presence of water. We conclude that for the adhesion promoter studied, the interaction of a phosphate functionality with organic and inorganic components of dentin promotes a strong and durable adhesive joint.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stangel, Ivan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w667d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt48j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw37638897"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A secure, anonymous and scalable digital cash system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xue, Feng, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Blind signatures make anonymity a reality in digital cash systems. However, when deployed in digital cash systems such as eCash, blind signatures raise such drawbacks as bad scalability and unfair anonymity. In this thesis, efforts have been done to combine digital signatures and a mechanism called "money-exchange" found in NetCash to build a new digital cash system. In the new system, two forms of digital cash are introduced: digital notes and digital coins. "Money-exchange" is extended to permit cash exchange from one form to the other. At the side of the digital cash issuer, at least two databases are maintained to detect double-spending. The new digital cash system is secure due to its deployment of both symmetric and asymmetric encryption algorithms. The combination of blind signatures and the extended money-exchange mechanism offers unconditional and fair anonymity, and it makes the system more scalable with the regards to the number of clients served.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crepeau, Claude</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Dini, Petre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g19c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37638897</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics, Commerce-Business</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1g05fd66h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors influencing a personal software process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhong, Xiaoming, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Following the development of Personal Software Process (PSP) by Humphrey, a number of efforts have been made to study the impact of PSP on the improvement of software quality and productivity. However, most of such studies have focused on the results of the execution of PSP. Little attention has been paid to the underlying factors that influence the output of the execution of PSP. By investigating which factors influence the output, and how, we would have an improved understanding of PSP, which, in turn, could lead to improvement of the design of PSP and hence of personal software process. In this thesis, we describe an experiment involving 53 subjects carrying out PSP. In particular, we examine the factors underlying a personal software process and analyzed the impact of these factors on the output of PSP execution, namely, the improvement in software quality and productivity. Our study complements previous work on PSP by providing a "white-box" view of PSP in assessing the effectiveness of PSP.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madhavji, Nazim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m123q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd66h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x3244"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Numerical studies of diffusion in lipid-sterol bilayer membranes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhu, Hong, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We examine tracer diffusion in lipid bilayer membranes containing either cholesterol or lanosterol, using a random lattice Ising model. Specifically the model is a two-state off lattice tethered network of hard disks which is dynamically triangulated and the interactions between the hard disks are only effective along the tethers linking the disks. The model was already applied to lipid-sterol systems and was successful in reproducing the phase diagrams and related physical properties. In this thesis we apply this model in conjunction with Monte Carlo simulation methods as follows. We calculate the diffusion constant for lipid-cholesterol and lipid-lanosterol bilayer membranes both as function of temperature and sterol concentration in all accessible regions of the relevant phase diagrams. Comparison with experiment and comments on sterol related evolution are included.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zuckermann, Martin J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b794.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3244</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wm14g"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Determination of the luminescence decay rate and of the flavin binding affinity by the luxA carboxyl terminal regions in chimeric bacterial luciferases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Valkova, Nelly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bacterial luciferase is a heterodimeric enzyme catalyzing the emission of green-blue light from the double oxidation of flavin mononucleotide (FMNH 2) and fatty aldehyde. The catalytic and functional properties of luciferase are believed to be largely controlled by the a subunit. The functional properties of the carboxyl terminus region of the a subunit of bacterial luciferase were investigated through the construction of chimeric luciferases. The parental luciferases were selected from the species Photobacterium phosphoreum and Xenorhabdus luminescens due to the marked differences in their kinetic and physical properties. Three functional chimeric luciferases were generated by separating the carboxyl terminus of the a subunit into three regions of equal length and interchanging each of these three segments from P. phosphoreum luciferase into the luciferase of X. luminescens . One of the chimeras investigated, LuxA1B, contained a modified region closest to the inner part of the a subunit, and this portion was found to affect the decay rate of luminescence with aldehydes of different chain lengths, as well as the response to high aldehyde concentrations and the overall thermal stability. The other two chimeras, LuxA2B and LuxA3B, underwent changes in the two portions closest to the carboxyl terminus, and these regions were found to affect the ability to bind flavin and to interact with flavin analogues. On the basis of the kinetic properties of these three chimeric luciferases, an equation was developed and validated which related the decay rate of luminescence to the aldehyde concentration and dissociation constant.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meighen, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md67p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm14g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hr54t"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mediated biochemical oxygen demand biosensors for pulp mill wastewaters</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trosok, Steve Peter Matyas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mediated microbial sensors utilizing two different yeast isolates (SPT1 and SPT2) were developed for the estimation of biochemical oxygen demand (BOD). Measurements of glucose/glutamic acid (GGA) standard solution with potassium ferricyanide mediation resulted in linear ranges extending from the detection limits (i.e. 2 and 5 ppm BOD) to 100 and 200 ppm BOD for the SPT1- and SPT2-based sensors, respectively. The standard error of the mean (SEW for 10 ppm. BOD measurements was 10.1% (SPT1) and 3.9% (SPT2). Response reproducibility had 10.6% error between three identically prepared SPT1 sensors. Response times for concentrations of 20 ppm BOD were within 10 minutes. For pulp mill effluent, the detection limits were 2 (SPT1) and 1 (SPT2) ppm BOD, with SEMs of 3.6% and 14.3% for the SPT1 and SPT2 sensors, respectively. Based on the results obtained in this study, it is concluded that SPT2 is the more suitable biocatalyst for pulp mill wastewater analysis. While 18S rRNA gene sequence analyses, including BLAST homology searches, have suggested that isolate SPT1 is a close relative of Candida sojae (99.8% homology), no close matches have been found for isolate SPT2. The closest match for SPT2 was to Candida krusei (76.0% homology). Evidence from biochemical tests, fatty acid analysis, and 18S rRNA gene sequence analyses, indicates that isolate SPT2 is a novel yeast species.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Luong, John</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>iscoll, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km54g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr54t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wood-pulp industry -- Waste disposal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biosensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biochemical oxygen demand</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vm84k"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Opportunism and the neostriatalhyperstriatum complex in birds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Timmermans, Sarah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research seeks to pinpoint the telencephalic structures most closely correlated with feeding flexibility, which is operationalised as feeding innovation rate per taxon. By calculating a weighted average per taxon of 1030 feeding innovations collated from five zones of the world (western Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand and India), the study shows that relative size of the hyperstriatum ventrale and, to a lesser extent, the neostriatum , best predicts weighted innovation rate; these two structures are thought to be functionally equivalent to the mammalian neocortex. The worst telencephalic predictors of innovation rate are two structures respectively thought to be involved in primary visual projection and the control of stereotyped, species-specific behaviour, the wulst area and the paleostriatum. A second presumed correlate of behavioural flexibility, taxonomic variation in the use of urbanised and other anthropogenically-modified habitats, shows a consistent pattern in four geographical zones (Great Britain, North America, Australia and New Guinea), as well as a qualitative association with the relative size of the forebrain. There is no linear correlation, however, between urbanisation rate per taxon and either forebrain size or innovation rate, suggesting that other variables like diet, tameness and neophilia may have to be quantified at finer taxonomic levels in future studies of opportunism in habitat use.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lefebvre, Louis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838239z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm84k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Urban ecology (Biology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neostriatum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Birds -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Birds -- Food</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569630n"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La tomographie par émission de positons à l'étude de la réponse hémodynamique temporelle induite par activation cérébrale : (TEP-RHETIAC)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tremblay, Hugo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The brain can be explored while a subject executes different tasks. Such techniques are commonly referred as activation studies. The regions of the brain involved in a particular task can be located by comparing regional differences in tracer concentration to a control state. Group of neurons in the brain form complex logical circuits and their activities increase while they interpret a stimulation. These neuronal activities require glucose and oxygen and these substances travel in the blood following hemodynamic rules. Many factors influence the hemodynamic response induced by brain activation (FRIBA), but certain aspects of its temporal behavior are still unclear. A special technique was implemented with an ECAT EXACT HR+ (CTI/Siemens) to fulfil this lack in PET activation studies. The new HR+ has this 3D option, which can help to evaluate the FRIBA with a tracer (11C-CO) that remains in the blood vessels to measure the cerebral blood volume (CBV) differences. Only CBV studies can appreciate the temporal course of the FRIBA in PET. The resulting images are, however, very noisy and many pitfalls are present during their analysis. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thompson, Christopher J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j7352.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569630n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics, Medical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw324"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of vacuum rate on the vacuum cooling of lettuce</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rennie, Timothy J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The deterioration of freshly harvested horticultural crops can be minimised by precooling prior to storage. This technique of quickly cooling the produce does not only increases the shelf life, but it also reduces the size of the refrigeration system needed for storage facility. Vacuum cooling is an effective method of precooling leafy vegetables, but has a major drawback of requiring substantial initial capital investment. Thus, vacuum coolers are generally limited to large-scale or co-op operations where the initial investment can be spread across a large quantity of produce. The conventional philosophy behind precooling design is to establish systems to cool produce as quickly as possible; this concept is more so with vacuum coolers. By changing certain design criteria of a vacuum cooler, it may be possible to reduce the capital cost of vacuum coolers by reducing the rate of vacuum. Though the time to cool the produce may be increased, the reduction in the size of the vacuum pump and the refrigeration system, and hence the capital cost of the cooler, may be beneficial to small-scale producers who can not justify the large expenses incurred when purchasing a conventional system. Experiments were performed on a modified vacuum cooler in which the rate of vacuum could be controlled. The cooling characteristics, including the temperature distribution and mass loss, and the lettuce quality were determined for different rates of vacuum. A relationship between the speed of the vacuum and the peak product refrigeration load was developed and tested with experimental data. The results suggest that slower vacuum coolers can be successfully designed and built for small-scale operations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raghavan, G. S. V.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Vigneault, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537291n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw324</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lettuce -- Cooling</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cs31c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Iron acquisition from porcine proteins by Actinobacillus pleuropneumoniae biotype 1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ricard, Michelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Each of two affinity isolation methods, the first based on biotinylated porcine transferrin plus streptavidin-agarose, and the second on Sepharose-coupled porcine transferrin, followed by sodium dodecylsulfate-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (SDS-PAGE), allowed the isolation and identification of two potential porcine-transferrin-binding polypeptides (~64 kDa and 99 kDa) from total membranes of Actinobacillus pleuropneumoniae grown under iron-restricted conditions. Both polypeptides were iron-repressible and were identified as potential receptor candidates as they were not isolated when biotinylated human transferrin was used instead of biotinylated porcine transferrin. The 64 kDa polypeptide was the more easily removed from Sepharose-coupled porcine transferrin and only the 99 kDa polypeptide appeared to be an outer membrane protein. These results suggest that the 99 kDa polypeptide represents the porcine transferrin receptor of A. pleuropneumoniae, and that the 64 kDa polypeptide represents an associated protein serving an accessory role. Fe+3 uptake studies using plate assays and attempted isolation of a putative lactoferrin receptor using biotinylated porcine lactoferrin plus streptavidin-agarose, followed by SDS-PAGE, showed that A. pleuropneumoniae lacks a mechanism for the use of porcine lactoferrin as an iron source.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Niven, Donald F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b793f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs31c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Transferrin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iron -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Swine -- Diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Actinobacillus -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pleuropneumonia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773x57d"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of a capillary electrophoretic method for the separation and detection of resin acids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rigby, Tracey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A method for the separation and detection of standard resin acids (RAs), commonly found in pulp mill effluent and known to bioaccumulate in fish bile, was optimized using cyclodextrin modified electrokinetic capillary electrophoresis (CD-EKC) with ultra violet (UV) and laser induced fluorescence (LIF) detection. Optimal separation conditions were found with RA standards using UV detection at 214 nm, with a 72 mM sodium borate buffer pH 9.25, containing 35 mM beta-cyclodextrin sulfobutyl ether (SPCD), 15 mM of methyl-beta-cyclodextrin (MECD) and a 37 cm capillary with an internal diameter of 50pm. This resulted in a 12-min separation and the identification of 9 peaks, with a LOD of 10 ppm. To enable increased sensitivity, RAs were derivatized using the fluorescent label 4-BrMMc. A method for extracting resin acids from spiked fish bile and pulp mill effluent was developed, the extracted samples were derivatized, separated and identified using CD-EKC with LIF detection. The method of extraction and derivatization using CD-EKC was applied to biological samples of contaminated effluent and fish bile. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kermasha, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s378.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x57d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Capillary electrophoresis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oleoresins -- Environmental aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diterpenes -- Separation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wood-pulp industry -- Waste disposal -- Environmental aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977w88h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Food group contribution to the energy and nutrient intake of the adult Canadian population</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ritter, Heidi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Food group contributions to energy, carbohydrate, protein, total fat, saturated fat, cholesterol, fiber, calcium, iron, folate, zinc, vitamins A and C were evaluated for Canadian adults aged 18--65 years. Twenty four hour recall data from the 1997--98 Food Habits of Canadians survey were used. Mean nutrient intakes exceeded the RNI for all age-gender groups except, calcium for older women. Mean iron (women 18--49 years) and zinc (men and women 50--65 years) intakes were borderline. The differences in food group contribution to nutrient intake among smokers and non-smokers indicated that smokers generally obtained nutrients from foods higher in energy and fat and lower in other nutrients. Important food sources for individuals meeting the RNI for calcium were fluid milk and cheese. Important sources of folate were citrus fruit juices, breads, and lettuce/cabbages/greens as were cereals and beef/veal for iron. Zinc sources were primarily other beef cuts or ground beef.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gray-Donald, Katherine</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns853.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w88h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nutrition -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Food consumption -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canadians -- Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429c11n"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Zinc cluster proteins Leu3p and Uga3p recognize highly related but distinct DNA targets</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Noël, Josée</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The zinc cluster family of fungal regulatory proteins shares a DNA binding motif that contains six highly conserved cysteines residues. Many of the zinc cluster proteins have been shown to bind as homodimers to target DNA sequences containing a pair of CGG triplets, with each monomer recognizing a triplet. Orientation and spacing between the CGG triplets specify the recognition sequences for a given zinc cluster. For example, Gal4p, involved in galactose metabolism, recognizes CGG triplets, oriented as a palindrome, or inverted repeat, spaced by 11 base pairs (bp) (CGG N11 CCG). The spacing is specific enough so that a change to 10 or 12 by does not enable high affinity binding by Ga14p. Another motif is the direct repeat, as exemplified by Hap1p (CGG N6 CGG). More recently, Leu3p, involved in leucine biosynthesis, was shown to bind to a everted motif spaced by 4 by (CCG N4 CGG). Here we show that another zinc cluster protein, Uga3p, also recognizes an everted motif spaced by 4 bp. However, these two proteins have distinct DNA targets. We show that additional specificity is due to the nucleotides in between the CGG triplets. Altering the 4 nucleotides located between the CGG switches the specificity from a Uga3p site to a Leu3p site in both in vitro and in vivo assays. Therefore, our results identify a new mechanism that expands the repertoire of DNA targets of the zinc cluster family of proteins.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turcotte, Bernard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p33n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c11n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t103h"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Two-year predictors of smoking initiation among elementary schoolchildren in multiethnic, low-income, inner-city neighborhoods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Numata, Yuka</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this study was to determine the two-year predictors of current smoking (smoked one or more times in the past year) and of ever smoking (lifetime use of cigarettes) among grade 4 students in multiethnic, low-income, inner-city neighborhoods in Montreal. Baseline and two-year follow-up data were collected from 501 children (54.3% girls) who, at baseline, were never-smokers. At the two-year follow-up, 22.0% reported ever smoking, including 7.6% who were current smokers. Gender-specific multivariate logistic regression analyses identified friends smoking (odds ratio (OR) = 3.0 95% confidence interval (1.2--7.1)) and sibling smoking (OR = 6.6 (1.7--22.2)) as independent predictors of ever smoking among boys. Friends' smoking (OR = 4.7 (2.0--10.7)) and school were predictors of ever smoking among girls. Parental smoking also predicted ever smoking (OR = 4.3 (1.6--11.9)) among girls born in Canada only. The only predictor of current smoking among boys was friends' smoking. Predictors of current smoking among girls included Canadian family origin.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>O'Loughlin, Jennifer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v50k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t103h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qt90s"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Induction and production of specific extracellular lipases from selected microorganisms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ngom, Marie Odile</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Induction of extracellular lipases from Pseudomonas fragi CRDA 037 and Geotrichum candidum was used to increase lipase production in a shorter period of time. Induction was performed using edibles oils such as olive oil, canola oil, fish oil and butter fat. Fermentation trials of the microorganisms in the selected media were done in order to optimize the production of lipases. Optimal lipase activity was obtained in the presence of butter fat (1%, v/v) for P. fragi which was cultivated at 15°C during 48 h, and fish oil (0.75%, v/v) for G. candidum incubated at 27°C for 56 h. The induced lipase extracts of P. fragi and G. candidum obtained after these fermentation trials were purified by 3.7 and 5.9-fold respectively using ultrafiltration, while the non-induced fractions were purified by 2.3 and 5.1-fold, respectively. Activities were evaluated using p-nitrophenyl esters such as p-nitrophenyl laurate and p-nitrophenyl palmitate. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kermasha, Selim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f785.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt90s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lipase -- Separation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pseudomonas fragi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geotrichum candidum</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk421"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulatory effect of phosphorylation of protein kinase C Apl I in the nervous system of Aplysia californica</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nakhost, Arash</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Phosphorylation of calcium-activated protein kinase Cs (PKCs) at threonine 634 (T634) and/or threonine 641 increases during long-term potentiation or associative learning in rodents. We have raised an antibody to a peptide from PKC Apl I phosphorylated at T613 and T620 (sites homologous to T634 and T641). This antibody recognizes PKC Apl I only when it is phosphorylated at T613. Both phorbol esters and serotonin increase the percentage of kinase phosphorylated at T613 in Aplysia neurons. Furthermore, the pool of PKC that is phosphorylated at T613 in neurons is resistant to both membrane translocation and downregulation. Replacement of T613 with alanine increases the affinity of PKC Apl I for calcium, suggesting that phosphorylation of this site may reduce the ability of PKC Apl I to translocate to membranes in the presence of calcium. We propose that phosphorylation of this site is important for removal of PKC from the membrane and may be a mechanism for negative feedback of PKC activation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sossin, Wayne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c12x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk421</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w931c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enhancement of fibrinolytic and thrombolytic properties of endothelial cells seeded on PTFE to increase the patency of small diameter artificial vascular grafts using surface modification by ammonia plasma and retroviral-mediated transduction of endothelial cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lu, Albert, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The current generation of small caliber artificial vascular grafts occlude within a short period of time due to various problems involving blood-biomaterial interactions. One way of circumventing this is to introduce a monolayer of endothelial cells (EC) onto the graft before implantation to mimic a natural human vascular state. In this way, a hemostatic-thrombotic equilibrium can be maintained. Current methods used to transplant cells onto grafts include the pre-coating of grafts with extracellular matrix proteins like fibronectin and fibrin, as well as other methods like ammonia plasma surface modification of grafts. But little is known about the effects of surface modifications on ECs' ability to secrete prostacyclin (PGI2, anti-platelet thrombomodulators), tissue plasminogen activator (t-PA), and plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 (PAM, both fibrinolytic proteins). Our studies show that uncoated and fibronectin (fn) coated ammonia plasma modified poly(tetrafluoroethylene)(PTFE) are capable of secreting high amounts of PGI2. Furthermore, these surfaces secrete highly active t-PA proteins but relatively low amounts of PAI-1. Thus, uncoated and Fn coated modified PTFE support optimal conditions that provide for a non-thrombogenic surface, and may be suitable to further develop protocols and other strategies for arterial and venous reconstruction. Another strategy that we implemented was to further enhance the secretion of t-PA by EC. In this approach, we established a retroviral-mediated transfection protocol wherein human t-PA sequences encoded in a plasmid (PB2NSt) were stably integrated into the EC genome.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sipehia, Rajender</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t868.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w931c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wp63j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of excessive liquid hog manure applications on phosphorus concentrations in soil and surface runoff from corn and forage crops</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacDonald, Tim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study was initiated in 1989 to examine the effects of applying excess liquid hog manure with mineral fertilizers to corn and forage crops. Manure was applied yearly at twice the recommended level either in the spring, fall or a combination of both spring and fall applications. Mineral fertilizers were applied at recommended levels to plots receiving only mineral fertilizers and to manure treatment plots. Two control plots received no fertilizers. During the summer of 1999, soil samples were taken at a depth of 0--2 cm and analysed using different phosphorus extractants. Six runoff events were sampled and analysed for different phosphorus fractions. Strong correlations were found in corn plots between average dissolved reactive phosphorus concentrations in runoff and soil test phosphorus concentrations. Timing of manure application had a significant impact on both soil and runoff phosphorus concentrations. Runoff from forage plots had significantly higher concentrations of dissolved phosphorus, but phosphorus loads were greater from corn plots due to higher runoff volumes. Corn plots released significantly higher particulate phosphorus concentrations than forage plots because of higher sediment loads in runoff from corn plots.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Simard, R. R.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hamel, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1240.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp63j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils -- Phosphorus content -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Soils -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Farm manure, Liquid -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Swine -- Manure -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k6965"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Osteopontin and cathepsin A are expressed in a cell and region specific manner in the testis and epididymis and are differentially regulated by testicular factors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Luedtke, Chad C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The production of fully functional spermatozoa requires, upon the successful completion of spermatogenesis, a minimal migration through the highly regulated and specialized lumenal microenvironment created by the epithelial cells lining the efferent ducts and epididymis. The cells of each region contain the subcellular machinery necessary for protein synthesis and secretion, as well as that necessary for reciprocating the latter by way of endocytosis. The present study details the expression of two proteins, osteopontin and cathepsin A, in the testis, efferent ducts and epididymis of the rat. In accordance with known epididymal and testicular dependence on androgens, the effects of testicular factors on each protein's expression were observed. Osteopontin and cathepsin A each exhibited cell- and region-specific distribution in all the tissues but only osteopontin expression was dependent on testicular factors. The results suggest osteopontin and cathepsin A are used by the epithelial cells of the testis, efferent ducts and epididymis to assist in the production of an environment suitable for sperm maturation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mckee, Marc</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hermo, Louis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s660q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k6965</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fn64j"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Developing novel lipases from Bacillus thermocatenulatus to improve enantioselectivity by directed evolution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Andrew Man Fai, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to make use of enzymes in unnatural applications more efficiently, novel enzymes have to be developed and they may arise from an existing enzyme with similar performance. The fast way to improve the performance of the enzyme is by directed evolution. It alters a naturally existing protein, without in depth knowledge of the starting enzyme and produces mutants containing the required activities. The lipase from Bacillus thermocatenulatus is an alko-thermophilic enzyme. Optimization of the lipase production is carried out for use with the new screening method using a pH indicator to evaluate hydrolytic activities. This newly cloned lipase is next characterized with two substrate libraries made up of commercially available general and enantiomerically pure esters. An important chiral synthon solketal is identified as the directed evolution target molecule for this lipase. By modifying with error-prone PCR, the enantioselectivity of the lipase towards solketal n-octanoate is improved.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kazlauskas, Romas J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537292x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn64j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx27c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Detection of latent heritable genetic damage in populations of aquatic snails, Lymnaea stagnalis, exposed in situ to genotoxic pollution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hum, Stanley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We hypothesized that populations exposed to chronic levels of genotoxins for many generations in situ will accumulate latent heritable genetic damage leading to increases in mutational load and decreased population fitness. Common pulmonate snails (Lymnaea stagnalis) were collected from three sites that differed in pollution level [Manitoulin Island (reference), Beauharnois (moderate pollution), and Varennes (highly polluted)]. These organisms have a rapid generation time and are capable of self-fertilization. Fitness indicators were clutch size, survival (hatching to day 30) and growth (length from hatching to day 90). Recessive deleterious mutations that have accumulated through time are masked as snails preferentially outcrossed, but are expressed when snails self-fertilize. Results obtained by comparing fitness components of snails derived from selfing and outcrossing experiments showed that in sites with higher levels of pollution inbreeding depression increased for clutch size and survival. Results for growth rate were similar to those for clutch size and survival in the two least polluted sites, but not for the most polluted site, due possibly to biased mortality of smaller snails at this site. After correction for size biased mortality, the growth estimates showed patterns similar for the two polluted sites when compared to the reference site. This study suggests that long-term in situ exposure to genotoxic pollution may effect population fitness due to the accumulation of latent heritable genetic damage.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schoen, Daniel</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rasmussen, J. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j736b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx27c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lymnaea stagnalis -- Québec (Province) -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lymnaea stagnalis -- Effect of water pollution on -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic toxicology -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cv84k"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Generating configuration confirming sequence with ObjectGeode simulator</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hu, Zi Jun, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Test cases are very useful in industry. They can be generated for various purposes. In this thesis the test case is generated for configuration conformance in the Extended Finite State Machine (EFSM) model. This kind of test case is called Configuration Confirming Sequence (CCS). Test case generation has been studied for years and fruitful results have been produced [1]. A number of approaches for automatic test case generation have been studied, one of them is based on the reachability analysis in the form of formal specification of the Extended Finite State Machine of the system under test. This thesis adopts such an approach for CCS generation, but with some extensions---after producing all separating sequences for the configuration by reachability analysis, a selecting program is executed to choose out proper separating sequences as CCSs. Today formal description techniques (FDT), including Specification and Description Language (SDL) are widely used in specification and analysis of the EFSM model. A FDT system is a formal, unambiguous, hierarchical description of a set of EFSM models. Various FDT toolsets are now commercially available. Proper use of them can make test case generation simpler. In this thesis, ObjectGeode SDL is selected as a tool for system design and reachability analysis. In this study, the method of CCS generation from an SDL specification is presented first. Then, to demonstrate the correctness of this method, a CCS generator for the Responder process in INRES protocol is designed and implemented, and results of the experiments are presented. A theoretical proof of correctness is also presented. We conclude by pointing out possible future work.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Petrenko, Alexandre</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Newborn, Monroe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n20c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv84k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hr553"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of glucose on the memory and attention of newborn human infants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Horne, Pamela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial was to determine whether glucose enhanced memory for a repeated auditory stimulus in human newborns. Infants consumed water or glucose (2-g/kg) solution. Memory test phases were: Orientation (turning towards the stimulus); Habituation (not turning towards), indicating familiarity; Delay (100 seconds); Spontaneous Recovery (stimulus representation: not turning towards indicates remembering, while turning towards indicates forgetting), and Novelty (turning towards a different word confirms wakefulness). Decreased head-turning towards during Spontaneous Recovery indicates enhanced memory. Blood glucose levels were measured after testing. "Glucose" infants had higher blood glucose levels than "water" infants (p &lt; 0.001). "Glucose" infants had significantly decreased turns towards during Spontaneous Recovery compared to "water" infants (p = 0.008), indicating memory enhancement. Therefore, glucose specifically enhances memory for a repeated auditory stimulus in newborn humans. Elevating blood glucose levels by approximately 2 mmol/L appears to be sufficient for memory enhancement in healthy newborns.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Young, Simon N.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Barr, Ronald G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z247.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr553</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Blood sugar</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attention in newborn infants</dc:subject><dc:subject>Newborn infants -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Newborn infants -- Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>