<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c655p"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dictionary-based analysis/synthesis and structured representations of musical audio</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyes, Graham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the representation of musical audio, it is common to favour either a signal or symbol interpretation, where mid-level representation is an emerging topic. In this thesis we investigate the perspective of structured, intermediate representations through an integration of theoretical aspects related to separable sound objects, dictionary-based methods of signal analysis, and object-oriented programming. In contrast to examples in the literature that approach an intermediate representation from the signal level, we orient our formulation towards the symbolic level. This methodology is applied to both the specification of analytical techniques and the design of a software framework. Experimental results demonstrate that our method is able to achieve a lower Itakura-Saito distance, a perceptually-motivated measure of spectral dissimilarity, when compared to a generic model and that our structured representation can be applied to visualization as well as agglomerative post-processing.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans la représentation du signal audio musical, il est commun de favoriser une interprétation de type signal ou bien de type symbole, alors que la représentation de type mi-niveau, ou intermédiaire, devient un sujet d'actualité. Dans cette thèse nous investiguons la perspective de ces représentations intermédiaires et structurées. Notre recherche intègre tant les aspects théoriques liés à des objets sonores séparables, que les méthodes d'analyse des signaux fondées sur des dictionnaires, et ce jusqu'à la conception de logiciels conus dans le cadre de la programmation orienté objet. Contrairement aux exemples disponibles dans la littérature notre approche des représentations intermédiaires part du niveau symbolique pour aller vers le signal, plutôt que le contraire. Cette méthodologie est appliquée non seulement à la spécification de techniques analytiques mais aussi à la conception d'un système logiciel afférent. Les résultats expérimentaux montrent que notre méthode est capable de réduire la distance d'Itakura-Saito, distance fondé sur la perception, ceci en comparaison à une méthode de décomposition générique. Nous montrons également que notre représentation structurée peut être utilisée dans des applications pratiques telles que la visualisation, l'agrégation post-traitement ainsi qu'en composition musicale.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Philippe Depalle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dk80h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c655p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53x093g"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The treatment of adults with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD): The impact on marital relationships and family functioning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Errington, Tara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude pilote utilise une méthode mixte pour examiner si le traitement d'un partenaire ayant le trouble de déficit de l'attention avec ou sans hyperactivité (TDAH) avait un effet sur les relations conjugales et fonctionnement de la famille. Huit patients qui ont reçu le traitement du programme de recherche du TDAH et leurs conjoints ont terminé deux questionnaires, qui mesurent l'état de leur relation conjugale et le fonctionnement de la famille, avant et après 12 semaines du traitement. Des entretiens semi-structurés ont été complétés avec cinq couples. Le résultat quantitatif suggère que les adultes avec le TDAH montrent des améliorations à leurs relations conjugales. Mais, leurs conjoints n'avaient pas observé cette amélioration. Ni les adultes avec le TDAH et ni leurs conjoints ont observé un changement dans le fonctionnement de la famille. Les entretiens qualitatifs suggèrent que les adultes avec le TDAH étaient plus susceptibles de décrire que leurs relations améliorent, mais les conjoints étaient plus prudents avec leurs interprétations de leurs relations après le traitement. Ni les adultes avec le TDAH et ni leurs conjoints ont observé un changement dans le fonctionnement de la famille après le traitement. En général, les adultes avec le TDAH et leurs conjoints soutenues utilisé un traitement multimodale pour le traitement du TDAH.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This mixed method pilot study examined whether the treatment of adults with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) would have an impact on marital relationships and family functioning. Eight patients receiving treatment from an adult ADHD Research Program and their spouses completed two questionnaires measuring marital adjustment and family functioning prior to and following 12 weeks of treatment. Follow-up semi-structured qualitative interviews were conducted with five of the couples. Quantitative results indicated that adults with ADHD observed an improvement in marital relationships following treatment. However, spouses did not observe a significant change. Neither adults with ADHD, nor their spouses reported family functioning changing as a result of treatment. The qualitative interviews suggested that adults with ADHD were more likely to describe their relationships as improving, whereas spouses were more cautious in their interpretation of their relationships following treatment. Neither adults with ADHD, nor their spouses reported changes in family functioning following treatment. In general, both adults with ADHD and their spouses supported the use of multimodal treatment for the treatment of ADHD. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lily T. Hechtman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g901g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x093g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f773z"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parents' positive and negative cognitive appraisals in raising a child with an autism spectrum disorder</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Quirke, Sara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Parents caring for a child with a disability experience significantly more stress in comparison to parents with children without a disability. Caring for a child with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD) has been reported to be more stressful than caring for a child with other types of disabilities. The concept of cognitive appraisal was used as a method to examine and understand how parents adapt to having a child with a disability. A cognitive appraisal can be positive or negative, depending on parents' interpretation of the consequences of an event. The negative and positive cognitive appraisals that parents make while raising their child with autism, as well as potential factors contributing to their appraisals were investigated, including family quality of life, authoritative parenting, and the child's adaptive and aberrant behaviour. Fifty-four families with a child between 6 and 9 years old participated. In order to confirm the child's diagnosis of autism, gold-standard diagnostic measures for ASD were administered which entailed an interview for the parent and a direct observation of the child's behaviour. Questionnaires and interviews were completed by one parent per family regarding cognitive appraisal of disability, family quality of life, parenting style, adaptive behaviour and aberrant behaviour. The child's cognitive functioning was assessed.  Two multiple linear regression analyses were performed, one for each outcome: positive cognitive appraisal and negative cognitive appraisal. Family quality of life predicted 36.6% of the variance in negative cognitive appraisal, and the relationship between the two variables was inverse, such that parents reporting higher satisfaction with their family quality of life reported that lower negative cognitive appraisals. This study contributes to research literature concerning the negative consequences of caring for a child with autism, and emphasizes the importance of implementing and developing interventions in which positive and negative cognitive appraisal are considered. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le stress éprouvé par les parents qui prennent soin de leurs enfants atteints d'autisme est nettement plus élevé comparativement au stress éprouvé par les familles avec un enfant qui se développe normalement, ou aux niveaux de stress rapportés par les parents qui prennent soin d'un enfant avec un autre type de handicap. Le concept de l'évaluation cognitive peut être utilisé comme une méthode pour examiner et comprendre comment les parents s'adaptent à leur enfant handicapé. Un parent effectue une évaluation cognitive positive lorsqu'il interprète un événement de manière adaptative, par exemple, en visualisant les conséquences d'avoir un enfant handicapé en termes d'éléments positifs dont l'enfant apporte à sa vie (ex. l'aider à devenir plus spirituel). Un parent fait une évaluation cognitive négative lorsque, à son avis, les conséquences de prendre soin de son enfant handicapé engendrent une « perturbation indésirable des routines familiales 'normales' » Les évaluations cognitives positives exercent une influence sur l'adaptation. Les mères d'enfants et adolescents atteints de divers types de handicaps (ex. trouble développemental, déficience physique, trouble de santé mentale), qui affichent une plus grande proportion d'évaluations positives pendant leurs activités quotidiennes, avaient des familles avec des niveaux plus élevés d'adaptation saine, lorsque comparées à des familles qui n'ont pas maintenu des évaluations positives. Les évaluations cognitives négatives et positives effectuées par les familles qui élèvent un enfant atteint d'autisme ont été investiguées. Les facteurs potentiels contribuant à leur évaluation ont été étudiés, notamment la qualité de vie familiale, le style parental et le comportement adaptatif ou aberrant de l'enfant. Au total, cinquante-quatre familles ayant un enfant entre 6 et 9 ans, ont participé à cette étude. Un parent par famille a complété des questionnaires et a participé à des entrevues qui portaient sur l'évaluation cognitive du handicap, la qualité de vie familiale, le style parental, les comportements adaptatifs et les comportements aberrants. L'intelligence cognitive de l'enfant a été évaluée et le diagnostic d'autisme a été confirmé à l'aide d'outils d'évaluation standardisés utilisés pour l'évaluation des troubles envahissants du développement. Deux régressions linéaires multiples ont été réalisées, une pour chaque résultat : évaluation cognitive positive et évaluation cognitive négative. Aucun des prédicteurs hypothétiques n'avait prédit une évaluation cognitive positive. La qualité de vie familiale a permis de prédire 36.6% de la variance de l'évaluation cognitive négative, et la relation entre les deux variables était inverse, de manière que les parents rapportant une plus grande satisfaction avec leur qualité de vie familiale, indiquèrent qu'ils faisaient moins d'évaluations cognitives négatives. Les implications de cette étude comprennent la contribution de la recherche à la littérature portant sur les conséquences négatives de prendre soin d'un enfant autiste, et l'importance de la mise en œuvre et le développement d'interventions dans lesquelles les évaluations cognitives positives et négatives sont abordées. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ingrid Sladeczek</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bk04s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f773z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128g10d"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantifying biodiversity in aquatic ecosystems: evaluating the causes for congruent patterns across trophic levels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Velghe, Katherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Understanding the drivers and patterns of biological diversity has been a central tenet for ecologists over the past century. Aquatic ecosystems appear to be particularly sensitive to biodiversity declines and thus comprehending the causes of these biodiversity losses has become a pressing issue. The objectives of this thesis are twofold. First, I wanted to investigate the effect of phosphorus, a surrogate for productivity in aquatic ecosystems, on the diversity of two taxonomic groups across broad spatial and temporal scales. Secondly, I wanted to quantitatively assess the use of biodiversity indicators in aquatic ecosystems, with particular emphasis on the role of body size. In the first chapter of this thesis, I took a palaeolimnological approach to investigate how the species richness of subfossil diatoms and cladocera varies in response to phosphorus. From both our spatial and temporal analyses, a significant decline in species richness of diatoms and cladocera was observed as phosphorus increased. When subdivided according to habitat preference, only the littoral species richness showed a decline in species richness. We attribute this decline in species richness in the littoral taxa to the interplay of nutrients on littoral habitat heterogeneity. At low levels of phosphorus, the littoral zone is thought to be more productive and harbor a greater abundance of submerged macrophytes and is thus able to maintain a more diverse community. The second chapter of this thesis investigated the efficiency of cross-taxon congruence as a method for estimating biodiversity in aquatic ecosystems. I approached this subject by performing a spatial field study coupled to a meta-analysis of the published literature. The field survey and meta-analysis show that organisms of similar size tended to exhibit more congruent diversity patterns. I argue that this pattern arises because organisms of similar body size have similar life history traits and thus similar biodiversity responses to environmental gradients. I demonstrate that cross-taxon biodiversity indicators are most effective when estimating the diversity of communities of most similar body size. Overall, this research has expanded our understanding of patterns, drivers and similarities of biodiversity across trophic levels in aquatic ecosystems. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Au cours du siècle dernier, plusieurs écologistes ont tenté de comprendre les caractéristiques ainsi que les facteurs qui contrôlent la diversité biologique. Les écosystèmes aquatiques semblent être particulièrement sensibles au déclin de la biodiversité et donc en découvrir les causes devient alors une question pertinente. Cette thèse possède deux objectifs. Tout d'abord, je souhaite étudier l'effet du phosphore, un substitut de productivité dans les écosystèmes aquatiques, sur la diversité de deux groupes taxonomiques à travers de grandes échelles spatiales et temporelles. Deuxièmement, je désire évaluer, de façon quantitative, les indicateurs de biodiversité dans les écosystèmes aquatiques, et ce, en mettant l'emphase sur le rôle de la dimension des organismes. Dans le premier chapitre de cette thèse, j'ai utilisé une approche paléolimnologique pour étudier comment la richesse spécifique des diatomées et des cladocères fossilisés varie en fonction du taux de phosphore. Grâce à mes analyses temporelles et spatiales, j'ai noté une baisse significative de la richesse spécifique des diatomées et des cladocères avec une augmentation du phosphore. De plus, lorsque les communautés étaient divisées par leurs préférences d'habitat, seules les richesses spécifiques littorales ont démontré un déclin en fonction du phosphore. J'attribue ce déclin de la richesse spécifique dans les groupes littoraux à l'effet des nutriments sur l'hétérogénéité des habitats littoraux. À de bas niveaux de phosphore, la zone littorale est plus productive et peut accueillir de grandes abondances de macrophytes qui fournissent plus de niches écologiques pour les espèces, donc une plus grande diversité.Le deuxième chapitre de cette thèse porte sur l'utilisation de la richesse spécifique d'une communauté d'organismes pour estimer la richesse spécifique d'une autre. Cette méthode de substitution est utilisée pour estimer la biodiversité dans les écosystèmes aquatiques. J'ai abordé ce sujet en effectuant une étude spatiale jumelée à une méta-analyse des écrits. Mon analyse spatiale et ma méta-analyse illustrent que les groupes taxonomiques ayant des dimensions similaires ont tendance à présenter des patrons de diversité plus conformes. Je suppose que les organismes de tailles similaires démontrent plus de similarité en ce qui concerne leurs traits de vie et à leurs patrons de diversité lors de gradients environnementaux. Je démontre que les indicateurs utilisés pour prédire la biodiversité sont plus efficaces lorsque leurs tailles sont plus similaires. Conséquemment, cette recherche a permis d'agrandir nos connaissances des patrons, des processus et des similitudes de la richesse spécifique dans les écosystèmes aquatiques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Irene Gregory-Eaves</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kf83q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128g10d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A765375234"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of matrix metalloproteinase-13 expression by CD109 in skin cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lighter, Melani</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Our group has identified CD109 as a novel TGF-β co-receptor that inhibits TGF-β signaling in skin cells. To study the role of CD109 in skin in vivo, our group has developed transgenic (TG) mice that overexpress CD109 in the epidermis. Previous results have shown that these mice display enhanced wound healing and improved scarring as compared to wild-type (WT) littermates. The aim of this study was to determine the effect of CD109 on the regulation of gene expression in the skin by using a genome microarray. Total RNA isolated from TG and WT mouse keratinocytes was subjected to microarray analysis using Illumina Bead Chip technology. The raw data from the microarray was analyzed using the FlexArray program and 300 genes were found to have differential gene expression in the TG compared to WT keratinocytes; 168 of these genes were up-regulated in the TG keratinocytes and 132 genes down-regulated in the TG keratinocytes. These 300 genes were then analyzed using the Ingenuity program, which implicated them in dermatological diseases and cell interaction. Matrix metalloproteinase-13 (MMP-13) gene expression was found to be up-regulated by 8.4-fold in the TG mouse keratinocytes compared to the WT. MMP-13 is of particular interest due to its ability to breakdown extracellular matrix (ECM) and its important role in wound healing and fibrotic processes. As TIMPs are MMP inhibitors, TIMP-2 was also investigated and found to be up-regulated by 3.03-fold. CXCL1 and αSMA were also studied as they were found to be highly down-regulated in TG compared to the WT mouse keratinocytes.  The results obtained from the microarray were confirmed by qRT-PCR and showed an increase at the gene expression level of MMP-13 and TIMP-2 in the TG keratinocytes and a decrease in the gene expression levels of CXCL1 and αSMA. In order to study MMP-13 further a western blot analysis was performed to look at its protein level. Results showed an increase at the protein level of MMP-13 in the TG keratinocytes although the results were not statistically significant. To investigate MMP-13 in vivo, immunohistochemisty was performed and MMP-13 expression was found to be increased in the TG compared to the WT mouse tissue. This study demonstrates increased expression of MMP-13 in TG keratinocytes suggesting that CD109 may modulate wound healing by increasing MMP-13 expression in keratinocytes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Notre groupe a identifié un nouveau co-recepteur du TGF-β, CD109, qui inhibe la cascade de signalisation du TGF-β. Pour étudier le rôle de CD109 in vivo, nous avons développé des souris transgéniques (TG) qui surexpriment CD109 dans l'épiderme. Les précédents résultats du laboratoire indiquent que les souris TG CD109 cicatrisent mieux que les souris sauvages (WT) de la même portée. Pour déterminer les effets de CD109 au niveau moléculaire, j'ai effectué une étude du génome par puce à ADN. Les ARNs totaux extraits de kératinocytes de souris TG et WT ont été préparés et soumis à une analyse par puce à ADN (Illumina). Les résultats ont été analysés à l'aide des programmes FlexArray et Ingenuity et 300 gènes ont une expression différentielle; 168 de ces gènes ont montré une régulation à la hausse dans les kératinocytes TG et 132 gènes ont montré une régulation à la baisse dans les kératinocytes TG. L'analyse par puce à ADN révèle une forte hausse de MMP-13 (métalloprotéinase matricielle-13) dans les kératinocytes TG, comparée aux keratinocytes WT. Les résultats de cette analyse montrent que, parmi les nombreux gènes surexprimés dans les kératinocytes TG, comparés aux kératinocytes WT, MMP-13 est augmentée de 8,4 fois. MMP-13 est d'un intérêt particulier puisque sa capacité à dégrader la matrice extracellulaire joue un rôle majeur dans les processus de cicatrisation et de fibrose. Comme TIMPs sont des inhibiteurs de MMPs, TIMP-2 a également été étudié et a montré une régulation à la hausse de 3,03 fois. CXCL1 et αSMA ont également été étudiés car ils ont montrés une régulation à la baisse des TG par rapport aux kératinocytes de souris WT. Ces résultats ont été confirmés par qRT-PCR, indiquant que l'expression de l'ARNm de MMP-13 et TIMP-2 est augmentée dans les kératinocytes TG et une baisse dans les niveaux d'expression des gènes et de CXCL1 αSMA. De plus, afin d'étudier MMP-13, une analyse Western blot a été réalisée pour examiner sa teneur en protéines. Les résultats ont montré une augmentation au niveau des protéines de MMP-13 dans les kératinocytes TG bien que les résultats n'étaient pas statistiquement significatifs. Pour étudier MMP-13 in vivo, l'immunohistochimie a été réalisée pour examiner l'expression de MMP-13 et on a trouvé une augmentation dans les TG par rapport au tissu de souris WT. MMP-13 est un important facteur impliqué dans la guérison des plaies cutanées, grâce à sa capacité de dégrader les protéines de la matrice extracellulaire. Cette étude démontre que l'expression de MMP-13 est augmentée dans les keratinocytes TG, suggérant que CD109 pourrait moduler les processus de cicatrisation en induisant une surexpression de MMP-13 dans les kératinocytes. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anie Philip</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t507.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765375234</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021k159"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of genetic variability within the Beijing lineage of «Mycobacterium tuberculosis»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Donato, Samuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des recherches antérieures ont démontré que le système de signalisation DosR/DosS est surexprimé dans les souches de Beijing moderne, une sous-catégorie du Mycobacterium tuberculosis (M tb). Une hypothèse explique que la surexpression du système règlementaire est la raison des propriétés plus pathogénique de la souche Beijing moderne. Dans cette thèse, nous avons fait une tentative pour trouver la cause de la surexpression. Pour débuter, les stimuli de signalisation DosR connu a été comparé entre différentes souches de M. tb, en regardant spécifiquement les données concernant l'oxydenitrique (NO) et l'équilibre d'oxydo-réduction (redox). Nous avons démontré que la production NO endogène est semblable aux autres souches. Par contre, nous avons prouvé que les souches Beijing moderne expriment une plus grande proportion de NADH/NAD, ce qui lui donne une propriété plus réduisant que les autres souches. Pour trouver l'unique facteur responsable, nous avons transformé quatre souches de M. tb possédant un reporteur DosR-dépendant et développé une analyse innovatrice : un criblage de colonie. Ceci a pu évaluer l'activité du DosR. Ensuite, nous avons exécuté une mutagénèse utilisant un transposon pour déterminer les gênes capables de modifier l'expression et/ou l'activité du DosR. Après l'analyse d'environ 80,000 colonies, nous avons identifié 49 gênes qui semblaient avoir influencé l'activité du reporteur. À notre surprise, vérifiant l'analyse du qRT-PCR sur nos bactéries, nous étions incapable de démontrer une modulation dans l'expression du dosR. Ceci suggérait donc que l'expression du reporteur était en fait modifiée de manière indépendante du DosR. De plus profondes analyses ont révélé que plusieurs gênes bactériennes, dont nous avons antérieurement identifié, jouent directement un rôle sur l'activité du reporteur en contrôlant les niveaux de H2O2 de la bactérie. Cette découverte a mené à la conclusion que les souches Beijing moderne ont un niveau plus élevé de catalase comparé aux autres. En outre, cette thèse s'interroge plus profondément sur les propriétés uniques de la souche Beijing moderne et identifie un nouveau phénotype qui pourrait être associé au pathogène.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Previous research has demonstrated that the DosR/DosS two-component signaling system is constitutively overexpressed in modern Beijing strains of Mycobacterium tuberculosis (M. tb). It is hypothesized that constitutive overexpression of this regulatory system is related to the unique pathogenic properties reported for this important strain lineage. Within this thesis we attempted to determine the cause of this overexpression phenotype. We first compared known DosR signaling stimuli between different strains of M. tb, looking specifically at NO (nitric oxide) and redox (reduction-oxidation) balance. We demonstrated that there was no difference in endogenous NO production between strains, but we showed that there was a significantly more reductive NADH/NAD pool in modern Beijing strains. To determine the specific factor responsible, we transformed four independent strains of M. tb with a DosR-dependent XylE reporter and developed a novel colony-screening assay to determine DosR activity. We then performed whole-genome transposon mutagenesis to screen for genes that are potentially able to modify DosR expression and/or activity. After screening ~80,000 transductants, we identified 49 genes that appear to influence reporter activity. Surprisingly, when analyzed by qRT-PCR, we were not able to demonstrate a modulation in dosR expression for any of these putative candidates, which suggested that expression of our reporter was being modified in a DosR-independent manner. Further analysis has revealed that many candidate genes directly affect the activity of the reporter protein by modulating H2O2 levels within the bacteria. Intriguingly, this lead us to the observation that modern Beijing strains have elevated catalase activity compared to other strains of M. tb. This work further characterizes the unique properties of the Beijing lineage of M. tb and identifies a novel phenotype that may be associated with its pathogenesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Reed</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d570161f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021k159</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827h00r"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Neuroinflammation in early, pre-clinical stages of Alzheimer's disease: evidence from a new transgenic model of Alzheimer's disease-like amyloid pathology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ferretti, Maria Teresa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Il n'existe aucun remède pour  la maladie de Alzheimer (MA), une condition neurodégénérative dévastatrice, qui attaque plus de 35 millions de personnes dans le monde entier. Lorsque cette maladie est diagnostiquée, le cerveau des patients est déjà gravement endommagé et montre l'accumulation d'enchevêtrements neurofibrillaires intracellulaires et des plaques amyloïdes extracellulaires. Les plaques amyloïdes sont composées d'agrégats insolubles de la protéine beta amyloïde (Abeta) qui est neurotoxique. Il est actuellement admis que, pour obtenir un résultat thérapeutique, il faudrait commencer le traitement pharmacologique dans les premiers stades de la maladie, lors de la période pré-clinique, avant que les dommages neuronaux deviennent irrécupérables. Une meilleure compréhension des événements survenant dans ces premiers stades de la maladie est donc une priorité. Malheureusement, l'étude de ces stades pré-cliniques est compliquée par l'absence de biomarqueurs indiquant la conversion du stade sans troubles cognitifs à MA. Ainsi, les modèles transgéniques (Tg) de la pathologie amyloïde similaires à MA représentent des modèles très appropriés pour étudier l'évolution de la maladie.Afin d'étudier les premiers événements pathologiques survenant avant l'accumulation des plaques, nous avons profité d'un modèle Tg nouvellement généré dans notre laboratoire et nommé McGill-Thy1-APP. Nous avons d'abord examiné l'état cognitif des souris Tg et nous avons démontré que les troubles cognitifs précèdent l'accumulation des plaques. Nous avons aussi démontré qu'une augmentation paradoxale de boutons cholinergiques accompagnait les troubles cognitifs chez ces animaux. Avant l'apparition des plaques, nous avons décrit la survenance de matériel intraneuronal immunoréactif pour l'Abeta.  Par ailleurs, en utilisant des anticorps spécifiques pour les formes oligomériques, nous avons constaté que le matériel intraneuronal est en grande partie composé d'oligomères de l'Abeta.Pour élucider si les mécanismes impliqués dans la dysfonction neuronale précèdent l'accumulation de plaques, nous avons caractérisé l'apparition de l'inflammation chez les jeunes souris Tg, avant qu'elles montrent des plaques. Nous avons d'abord confirmé l'apparition de l'activation microgliale associée avec les plaques amyloïdes chez les vieilles souris Tg de 13-14 mois. Chez les jeunes souris pré-plaques, nous avons observé une augmentation modérée mais significative des enzymes (iNOS et COX-2) et des récepteurs de membranaires  (CD40 et CMH-II) inflammatoires. Par ailleurs, nous avons observé que les cellules microglies à cet âge affichent une morphologie activée et sont spécifiquement associées à des neurones contenant des oligomères de l'Abeta.Enfin, la minocycline (un médicament anti-inflammatoire) a été administrée à des souris âgées de deux mois pour un mois (jusqu'à l'âge de 3 mois) donc en l'absence de tout dépôt de plaques amyloïde. Ce protocole nous a permis d'étudier le rôle de l'inflammation dans les premiers stades de la maladie, avant le dépôt de plaques. Nous avons constaté que, outre la correction de la neuroinflammation, la minocycline réduit considérablement les niveaux de la protéine précurseur de l'amyloïde (APP) et les fragments connexes avec l'APP, y compris les fragments du carboxy terminaux. Par ailleurs, nous avons observé que la minocycline réduit les niveaux et l'activité de BACE.Ensemble, nos résultats montrent que l'accumulation intracellulaire des oligomères de l'Abeta en soi, avant le dépôt de plaques, est suffisante pour déclencher des modifications du SNC. Parmi ces derniers, l'activation microgliale semble avoir, du moins dans sa première manifestation, un rôle fondamental dans le métabolism de l'APP. Nous suggérons que la neuroinflammation dans les stades pré-cliniques de la MA pourrait représenter une cible appropriée pour la découverte de nouveaux agents préventifs et/ou de marqueurs diagnostiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Despite much advancement in our understanding of its pathobiology, there is no cure for Alzheimer's disease (AD), a devastating neurodegenerative disorder affecting more than 35 million people world-wide. At diagnosis, the brains of AD patients are already severely damaged and display massive accumulation of intraneuronal neurofibrillary tangles and extracellular amyloid plaques. Amyloid plaques are composed of aggregated, insoluble amyloid beta peptide (Abeta), which is known to be highly neurotoxic. At this stage, AD drugs can only delay, but not arrest, the progression of the disease, likely because the neuronal damage is already beyond rescue.It is currently accepted that, for any pharmacological agent to achieve efficacy, the treatment should be initiated prior to extensive central nervous system (CNS) damage, possibly in pre-clinical stages. A better understanding of the earliest events occurring in the pre-clinical phase of the disease is therefore a priority. Unfortunately, the study of pre-clinical stages in AD is complicated by the lack of biomarkers signalling the conversion from non cognitive impairment to AD. On the other hand, transgenic (Tg) models of the AD-like amyloid pathology represent a very suitable model to investigate the progression of the disease.In these studies, we took advantage of our newly generated Tg model of AD-like amyloid pathology, coded McGill-Thy1-APP mice to identify early pathological events preceding plaque deposition. We first examined the cognitive status of the animals and demonstrated that cognitive impairments occur prior to plaque deposition. Such deficits were associated with a paradoxical up-regulation of cholinergic pre-synaptic boutons. Prior to plaque deposition we also described the occurrence of intraneuronal Abeta-immunoreactive material. Furthermore, using oligomeric specific antibodies, we found that the intraneuronal Abeta material was in large part composed of Abeta-oligomers. To further elucidate the mechanisms involved in the early neuronal dysfunction, we characterized the occurrence of inflammation in young, pre-plaque mice. We started by confirming the occurrence of the well known, plaque-associated microglial activation in old, 13-14 months old Tg mice. In young, pre-plaque mice we observed a moderate, but significant up-regulation of inflammatory enzymes (iNOS, inducible nitric oxide synthase) and membrane bound receptors (CD40 and MHC-II); the neuronal marker COX-2 was also found to be up-regulated. Furthermore, we observed that microglial cells at this age display an activated morphology and are specifically associated with Abeta-oligomers burdened neurons. Finally, the anti-inflammatory drug minocycline was administered to 2-month old mice for one month, till the age of 3 months, thus in the absence of any amyloid plaque deposition. This protocol allowed us to investigate the role of inflammation in the early, pre-plaque stage of the disease. We found that, besides correcting neuroinflammation, minocycline significantly reduced the levels of amyloid precursor protein and APP-immunoreactive fragments, including C-terminus fragments (CTF). Furthermore, we observed that minocycline reduced the levels and activity of BACE, which were up-regulated in Tg animals compared to Non Tg.Taken together, our results showed that intracellular accumulation of Abeta-oligomers per se, prior to plaque deposition, is sufficient to trigger a number of CNS alterations. Amongst these, microglial activation appears to be, at least in its earliest manifestation, a key player in APP processing. We suggest that neuroinflammation in pre-clinical stages of AD might represent a suitable target for the discovery of novel preventive agents and/or early diagnostic markers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Claudio Cuello</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq967.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827h00r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h5716"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Revising Catholic sexual ethics: nuptial mysticism and John Paul II's theology of the body</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sabouri, Mona</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Jean Paul II (1920-2005), un homme aux pensées Catholique et avec un grand intérêt pour l'éthique sexuelle, a de nombreuses écritures concernant la valeur de la vie, la dignité humaine ainsi que l'union matrimoniale de l'homme et la femme. Les pensées de cet homme ont augmentées la valeur du corps humain dans la pensée Catholique. Malgré le fait que Jean Paul II a des pensées conservatrices concernant la sexualité, ces écritures marquent un changement important dans la tradition du mariage mystique. La pensée Catholique a toujours enseignée la valeur supérieure du mariage mystique en comparaison à la valeur du mariage entre une femme and un homme. Cette hiérarchie ne continue pas avec la pensée de Jean Paul II. Ce dernier juge la valeur du corps humain à être aussi importante dans la relation intime entre un homme et une femme qu'entre Dieu et l'être humain. Ceci est encore plus évident quand on compare la pensée de ce dernier aux écritures Jean de la Croix, un mystique Espagnol du seizième siècle. La pensée de Jean Paul II est basée sur l'égalité de l'homme et la femme, surtout dans une relation intime qui est à l'image de Dieu et de l'esprit humain, qui sont aussi de valeur égale. Après avoir analysé deux des travaux importants de Jean Paul (Théologie du Corps et Amour et Responsabilité), nous pouvons conclure que ce dernier valorise le corps humain et la sexualité en défendant l'incarnation du mariage mystique sous la forme de la matrimoine humaine. Ainsi, Jean Paul II adopte une nouvelle philosophie, c'est-à-dire, une pensée positive concernant la sexualité humaine. Finalement, sa pensée sur le corps féminin renforce le fait qu'il a une pensée positive concernant la valeur du corps humain, l'égalité de l'homme et de la femme ainsi que la valeur de a sexualité humaine. Ses pensées offrent un trajet philosophique pour la pensée féministe encore plus intéressante et tangible que les contributions de Dame Julian of Norwich (1342-1416), mystique et contemplative, ou Pierre Teilhard de Chardin (1881-1955), théologien et homme de science.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The thought and writings of Catholic ethicist John Paul II (1920-2005) concerning sexual ethics, the value and dignity of life, and the bond of a man and woman in marriage highlights the theological value of the body in Catholic thought. While John Paul II belongs to a religious tradition that holds conservative and counter-cultural ideas concerning sexuality, his work marks a fundamental shift in the tradition of Catholic nuptial mysticism. Catholic teaching has always prioritized the critical significance of mystical or spiritual marriage of the soul/Church and God over the importance of marriage between a man and woman. This hierarchical ordering of the spiritual nuptial union over the human does not continue with the work of John Paul II. The latter argues for the value of the body in the immanent world as a good in itself as well as offering a deeper theological valorization of the experience of nuptial sexuality than his predecessor and mystic, John of the Cross (1542-1592). John Paul's understanding of conjugal union is based on the latter's egalitarian rendering of the spousal relation between God and humanity: when man and woman unite intimately, they are two equals. Human dignity and equality is fully realized in the intimate act of love. Through an analysis of two of John Paul II's major studies, Theology of the Body and Love and Responsibility, one comes to the conclusion that the latter valorizes the human body and sexuality by arguing for the incarnation of mystical nuptiality in conjugal union.  In so doing, John Paul II adopts a new and positive theological affirmation of the meaning of the human body and conjugal union. Finally, John Paul's view of the female body in particular sheds even greater light on his innovative approach to the (female) body:  John Paul II's theology of the body is focused on male/female embodiment, equality, identity and dignity. His nuptial mysticism offers an interesting trajectory for Catholic feminist theory, that is more tangible than the contributions of classic female mystics and visionaries such as Julian of Norwich ( 1342-1416) or modern Catholic mystics such as Teilhard de Chardin ( 1881-1955).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daniel M. Cere</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zj668.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h5716</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion - Philosophy of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z922v"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inhibiting translation as a novel strategy to target multiple Myeloma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roman, William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Multiple Myeloma (MM) cell survival has been shown to depend on precise control of protein production and degradation. Disruption of protein catabolism through proteosomal or aggresomal blockade results in MM cell death. We hypothesized that inhibiting protein production would have a similarly toxic effect in MM. We explored the consequences of inhibiting mRNA translation in MM using silvestrol, a powerful inhibitor of ribosomal recruitment, which preferentially disrupts the production of certain cell regulatory and survival proteins. A panel of silvestrol-treated MM cell lines showed profound inhibition of growth and a rapid induction of apoptosis, as seen by MTT viability and AnnexinV flow cytometric assays respectively. The average IC50 in MM cells was determined to be 20nM while it was considerably higher in primary cultures of senescent fibroblasts. We show that silvestrol inhibits protein translation by inhibiting ribosome binding, decreasing polysome content and increasing 80S ribosomes. Western blot analyses show that silvestrol rapidly decreases the expression of c-Myc and non-canonical NF-KB signaling. Expression of anti-apoptotic proteins such as Mcl-1 and Bcl-2 decreased while pro-apoptotic proteins, such as BAX, increased with silvestrol treatment. In a novel transgenic mouse model of MM (vk*myc), which has been shown to behave clinically like human MM, silvestrol does not appear to be toxic and is therapeutically effective. Our results warrant clinical evaluation of silvestrol.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il a été démontré que la survie des cellules cancéreuses chez les patients atteints du Myélome Multiple (MM), dépend de la régulation de la production et de la dégradation des protéines. Une perturbation du système de catabolisme des protéines, à travers un blocage proteosomale, engendre la mort de ces dernières. Nous avons donc formulé l'hypothèse que l'inhibition de la production de protéines aurait des effets toxiques similaires. Grâce à un puissant inhibiteur, le silvestrol, nous avons déterminé les conséquences liées à l'inhibition de la translation de l'ARN messager. Le silvestrol est un inhibiteur de recrutement ribosomale qui affecte de manière préférentielle certaines protéines impliquées dans la division et la survie cellulaire. Une panoplie de lignées cellulaire spécifiques au Myélome ont été susceptibles au silvestrol, ce qui s'est exprimé par une inhibition de la croissance cellulaire et une amorce rapide de l'apoptose. Cela a été observé grâce au test de viabilité MTT et par l'analyse de cytométrie en flux avec les marqueurs Annexin V et 7-AAD. La moyenne du ci50 des cellules du myélome testées a été établie à 20 nM, tandis qu'une concentration considérablement plus élevé est nécessaire pour obtenir les mêmes résultats chez les cultures primaires de fibroblaste sénescents. Nous démontrons que le silvestrol inhibe la translation des protéines en bloquant le ribosome 80S au départ du codon d'initiation de la translation. Ceci engendre une accumulation des ribosomes 80S et une décroissance du nombre de polysome par ARN messager. Nos analyses de western blot montrent que le silvestrol provoque une décroissance de l'expression de l'oncogène c-Myc et de NF-KB. De plus, l'expression de protéine anti-apoptotiques tel que Mcl-1, Bcl-Xl et Bcl-2 décroit avec un traitement de silvestrol, alors que l'expression de la protéine pro-apoptotique Bax augmente. Nos résultats montrent que le silvestrol est efficace et non toxique dans le nouveau model transgénique du MM (la souris Vk*Myc) qui est réputé pour sa similarité de caractéristiques avec le MM humain. Nous prônons une évaluation clinique du silvestrol.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael Sebag</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sm30c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z922v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386p63z"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Discovery of emission above 100 GeV from the crab pulsar with VERITAS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McCann, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les pulsars sont des étoiles à neutrons fortement magnétisées tournant sur ellesmmes, qui émettent réguliérement des impulsions de rayonnement périodiques à travers le spectre électromagnétique. Initialement observée seulement dans le spectre des ondes radio, les pulsars ont maintenant été détectés dans la gamme des rayonsX et gamma. Bien qu'ils aient été découverts il y a plus de quarante ans et que le nombre de pulsars connus dépassent 2000, les processus générant les émissions observées provenant des pulsars sont encore mal compris. Ce travail décrit la détection d'émission du Pulsar du Crabe au-delà de 100 gigaélectron-volt (GeV), ce qui est la radiation la plus énergétique jamais détectée provenant d'un pulsar. Une telle observation n'était pas attendue et présente un défi aux modéles d'émission de pulsar acceptés. Cette observation a été faite en utilisant un réseau de 4 télescopes atmosphriques Cherenkov de 12 métres de diamétre situé dans le sud de l'Arizona, appelé VERITAS (Very Energetic Radiation Imaging Telescope Array System). L'excédent de l'impulsion détecté a une signification statistique de plus de 7 écart-types et donne un flux calculé de moins de 1% du flux de la Nébuleuse du Crabe entre 140 et 880 GeV.Cette mesure est utilisée pour exclure une coupure en forme dexponentielle dans l'émission du Pulsar du Crabe au-dessus de 6 GeV, qui était auparavant la meilleure forme expliquant le spectre. De plus, cette mesure est utilisée pour fixer une limite sur l'altitude minimale du site d'émission des rayons gamma de 10 fois le rayon de l'étoile à neutron, représentant la limite la plus contraignante jamais établie. Finalement, ce travail montre aussi que l'émission observée par VERITAS questionne le rôle du rayonnement de courbure des modéles courants d'émissions de pulsar.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pulsars are highly magnetised rotating neutron stars that emit regular,periodic pulses of radiation across a wide range of the electromagnetic spectrum. Originally only observed in radio waves, pulsars are now regularly seen to emit x-ray and gamma-ray radiation. Although they were discovered over forty years ago and the number of known pulsars now exceeds 2000, the processes that generate the observed emission from pulsars are still poorly understood.This work describes the detection of emission from the Crab Pulsar above 100 gigaelectronvolts (GeV), which is the highest radiation energy ever detected from a pulsar. Such an observation was not expected and presents a challenge to the most favoured pulsar emission models. This observation was made using the Very Energetic Radiation Imaging Telescope Array System (VERITAS), an array of four 12-meter-diameter atmospheric Cherenkov telescopes located in southern Arizona.The detected pulsed excess has a statistical significance above 7 standard deviations and yields a derived pulsar flux that is less than 1% of the Crab Nebula flux between 140 and 880 GeV. This measurement is used to rule out an exponentially-shaped cut-off in the emission of the Crab Pulsar above ~6 GeV, which was previously the preferred spectral shape. Furthermore, this measurement is used to set a limit on the minimum altitude of the gamma-ray emission site to greater than 10 times the neutron star radius, representing the most constraining limit ever set. Finally, it is shown that the emission seen by VERITAS challenges the role played by curvature radiation in current models of pulsar emission.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David Hanna</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945w05v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386p63z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Astronomy and Astrophysics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jz529"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Advanced morphometry of mesiotemporal structures in temporal lobe epilepsy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Hosung</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Temporal lobe epilepsy (TLE) is the most common drug-resistant epilepsy. While TLE is associated with mesiotemporal atrophy on MRI, hippocampal volumes are normal in 30% of patients. There is also growing evidence that developmental anomalies altering mesitotemporal lobe morphology participate in the pathogenesis of this condition. Indeed, about 40% of TLE patients show atypical shape of the hippocampus and collateral sulcus, commonly referred to as malrotation. To date, morphometric analysis of such pathology in TLE has been limited to MR volumetry. Objective. The overall goal was to develop advanced morphometric methods to statistically model aspects of pathology that are not evident in measurement of total volume. We first developed surface-based techniques that independently quantify focal atrophy, positioning and sulcal variants, and investigated their clinical significance. We then evaluated the impact of these morphological features on the performance of state-of-the-art hippocampal segmentation algorithms. Lastly, we developed a novel automatic hippocampal segmentation method based on a multi-template approach that relies on statistical parametric surface models and locoregional texture features. Methods and Results. In simulation, Our surface-based Jacobian determinant analyses could disentangle local volume from positional changes by quantifying independently both characteristics. Our analysis showed that in TLE patients atrophy and positional changes co-occurred at the level of the posterior hippocampus. Compared to volumetry, our technique showed increased sensitivity by unveiling subtle mesiotemporal atrophy/hypertrophy in TLE, in particular ipsilateral hippocampal atrophy in patients with normal hippocampal volume (TLE-NV). A combined analysis of all three mesiotemporal surfaces correctly lateralized the seizure focus in 94% of patients with TLE-NV. Analysis of basal temporal sulcal morphology using 3D sulcal models revealed that significantly more TLE patients exhibit an unbroken long collateral sulcus relative to healthy subjects. Our correlation analysis revealed that developmental anomalies and atrophy negatively impacted on the automated segmentation performance in general. Finally, we developed a novel segmentation algorithm (SurfMulti) to statistically estimate vertex-wise locoregional texture and shape. To account for inter-subject variability, we used a multi-template library derived from a large database of controls and patients. Our proposed hippocampal segmentation technique achieved a level of accuracy in TLE patients virtually identical to healthy controls, with a Dice index of 86.1%. Such performance has not yet been paralleled in epilepsy. Furthermore, we achieved the same sensitivity as manual volumetry in detecting atrophy ipsilateral to the seizure focus. Significance. The analytical framework we developed is intended to substantially improve MRI analysis so that it can fulfill its role for surgical target localization and post-surgical outcome prediction, the two main challenges of contemporary epilepsy surgery. Our results show that a better understanding of mesiotemporal lobe pathology lies in the evaluation of various brain morphological characteristics. By statistically assessing aspects of mesiotemporal pathological variations across the spectrum of drug-resistant TLE, we showed the ability of advanced post-processing of anatomical MRI to unveil anomalies that are not identified using volumetric analysis. The developed techniques can be extended to assess structural changes in neurological and neuropsychiatric disorders in which the temporal lobe is involved. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte. L'épilepsie du lobe temporal (ELT) est l'épilepsie pharmaco-résistante la plus commune chez l'adulte. Généralement associée à une atrophie temporo-mésiale visible par IRM, les volumes hippocampiques sont pourtant normaux dans 30% des cas d'ELT. De plus, il y a de plus en plus d'indices montrant que des anomalies du développement, qui altèrent la morphologie hippocampique et les motifs sulco-gyraux temporo-mésiaux, participent à la pathogénèse de cette épilepsie. En effet, 40% des ELT exhibent une forme et un positionnement atypiques de l'hippocampe et du sillon collatéral, effet communément appelé "malrotation". Jusqu'à présent, l'analyse morphométrique de la pathologie ELT du lobe mésiotemporal s'est limitée à de la volumétrie sur IRM. Objectifs. Le but général de cette thèse a été le développement de méthodes de morphométrie avancées qui permettront de modéliser statistiquement des aspects de la pathologie qui n'ont pas été évalués antérieurement par IRM, et qui n'apparaissent pas de manière évidente par des mesures de volume total. Nous avons tout d'abord développé des techniques surfaciques qui quantifient, indépendemment, des atrophies focales de petite étendue, des écarts de position ainsi que des variantes de formes de sillons, et nous avons étudié leur significativité clinique. Nous avons ensuite évalué quantitativement l'impact de ces caractéristiques morphologiques (l'atrophie et les anomalies développementales de forme et de position) sur la performance des algorithmes de segmentation de l'hippocampe les plus avancés du moment. Enfin, nous avons développé une nouvelle méthode de segmentation de l'hippocampe basée sur une approche de type "multi-templates" (modèles multiples), qui s'appuie sur des modèles statistiques paramétriques surfaciques et des caractéristiques locorégionales de textures. Méthodes. Nous avons réalisé les expériences suivantes: 1) Après avoir extrait les harmoniques sphériques combinées à des modèles de distribution de points (SPHARM-PDM) à partir de segmentations hippocampiques manuelles, nous avons calculé des vecteurs de déplacement entre les surfaces individuelles et le modèle. Nous avons alors calculé des déterminants jacobiens surfaciques (SJD, Surface-based Jacobian Determinants) à partir de ces vecteurs afin de localiser des changements de volume. Pour analyser les différences de position, nous avons construit un axe méridien médian (MEMAX), qui reprend les correspondances de points, contraintes par la forme, de SPHARM, et sur lequel les courbures locales et les vecteurs de positions sont calculés. Notre méthode a été validée sur des formes synthétiques. 2) A l'aide des métriques développées en (1), nous avons étudié les motifs de pathologie mésiotemporale chez les patients ELT, en effectuant des comparaisons de groupes, point à point, entre des patients atteints d'une atrophie hippocampique (TLE-HA), ceux dont le volume hippocampique est normal (TLE-NV), et des contrôles sains. De plus, nous avons évalué la capacité de notre modélisation de formes surfacique 3D à latéraliser le foyer épileptogène et à prédire l'issue de la chirurgie. 3) Les sillons corticaux ont été automatiquement extraits et identifiés à partir d'images IRM grâce à un modèle utilisant une assemblée de réseaux neuronaux artificels. Nous avons inspecté visuellement en 3D les arrangements sulcaux de la face inférieure du lobe temporal, et les avons décrits en quatre classes de motifs. 4) Nous avons segmenté l'hippocampe des sujets contrôle et des patients ELT en utilisant SACHA, un algorithme de croissance de région contraint par des a priori anatomiques, et FreeSurfer, un logiciel libre se basant sur un atlas. Pour quantifier les malrotations, des modèles 3D ont été créés à partir des segmentations manuelles d'hippocampes et des sillons collatéraux extraits automatiquement. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alan C. Evans</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Andrea Bernasconi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30px778.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jz529</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b2873"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enabling precise interpretations of software change data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kawrykow, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Numerous techniques mine change data captured in software archives to assist software engineering efforts. These change-based approaches typically analyze change sets -- groups of co-committed changes -- under the assumption that the development work represented by change sets is both meaningful and related to a single change task. However, we have found that change sets often violate this assumption by containing changes that we consider to be non-essential, or less likely to be representative of the kind of meaningful software development effort that is most interesting to typical change-based approaches. Furthermore, we have found many change sets addressing multiple subtasks -- groups of isolated changes that are related to each other, but not to other changes within a change set. Information mined from such change sets has the potential for interfering with the analyses of various change-based approaches.  We propose a catalog of non-essential changes and describe an automated technique for detecting such changes within version histories. We used our technique to conduct an empirical investigation of over 30000 change sets capturing over 25 years of cumulative development activity in ten open-source Java systems. Our investigation found that between 3% and 26% of all modified code lines and between 2% and 16% of all method updates consisted entirely of non-essential modifications. We further found that eliminating such modifications reduces the amount of false positive recommendations that would be made by an existing association rule miner. These findings are supported by a manual evaluation of our detection technique, in which we found that our technique falsely identifies non-essential method updates in only 0.2% of all cases. These observations should be kept in mind when interpreting insights derived from version repositories. We also propose a formal definition of "subtasks" and present an automated technique for detecting subtasks within change sets. We describe a new benchmark containing over 1800 manually classified change sets drawn from seven open-source Java systems. We evaluated our technique on the benchmark and found that the technique classifies single- and multi-task change sets with a precision of 80% and a recall of 24%. In contrast, the current "default strategy" of assuming all change sets are single-task classifies single- and multi-task change sets with a precision of 95% and a recall of 0%. We further characterized the performance of our technique by manually assessing its false classifications. We found that in most cases (78%), false classifications made by our technique can be further refined to produce useful recommendations for change-based approaches. Our observations should aid future change-based seeking to derive more precise representations of the changes they analyze.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>De nombreuses techniques de génie logiciel exploitent l'information stockée dans des systèmes de gestion de versions. Ces techniques analysent généralement des groupes de changements (ou change sets) sous l'hypothèse que le travail de développement contenus dans ces change sets est à la fois pertinent et relié à une seule tâche. Nous avons constaté que les change sets violent souvent cette hypothèse lorsqu'ils contiennent des changements que nous considérons comme non-essentiels, c'est-à-dire, non-représentatif des changements normalement associés au développement de logiciel. Par ailleurs, nous avons trouvé de nombreux change sets qui contiennent plusieurs sous-tâches -- des groupes de changements isolés qui sont reliés les uns aux autres, mais pas à d'autres changements du même change set. L'information extraite de change sets contenants des changements non-essentiels ou des changements reliés à plusieurs sous-tâches peut interférer avec les diverses techniques qui exploitent des systèmes de gestion de versions. Nous proposons un catalogue de modifications non-essentielles et une technique automatisée pour détecter de tels changements dans les systèmes de gestion de versions. Nous avons utilisé notre technique pour mener une étude empirique de plus de 30,000 change sets dans dix logiciels libres en Java. Notre étude a révélé que entre 3% et 26% de toutes les lignes de code modifiés et entre 2% et 16% de toutes les méthodes modifiées sont modifiés seulement par des modifications non-essentielles. Nous avons également constaté que l'élimination de telles modifications réduit la quantité de fausses recommandations qui seraient faites par un analyse de type "associtation rule mining." Ces conclusions sont appuyées par une évaluation manuelle de notre technique de détection, par laquelle nous avons constaté que notre technique identifie faussement des méthodes non-essentielles dans seulement 0,2% des cas. Ces observations devraient être tenues en compte dans l'interprétation des résultats d'analyse de données contenues das des systèmes de gestion de versions. Nous proposons aussi une définition formelle de "sous-tâches" et présentons une technique automatisée pour détecter les sous-tâches dans les change sets. Nous décrivons un benchmark contenant plus de 1800 change sets tirées de sept systèmes Java. Nous avons évalué notre technique sur cette référence et avons trouvé que la technique classifie des change sets mono-tâche et multi-tâche avec une précision de 80% et un rappel de 24%. En revanche, la "stratégie par défaut" qui assume que tous les change sets sont mono-tâches classifie les change sets avec une précision de 95% et un rappel de 0%. Nous avons également caractérisé la performance de notre technique en évaluant manuellement ses classifications erronées. Nous avons constaté que dans la plupart des cas (78%), les classifications fausses faites par notre technique peuvent être améliorées pour produire des recommandations utiles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Martin Robillard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d8178.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b2873</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752m91n"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A novel «in vitro» mucosal gut bacterial adhesion model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Coussa-Charley, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The gut bacterial system is truly a dynamic, complex organ. Although there is a constant flux of activity, the microflora can be considered as a bioreactor at a quasi-steady state throughout a person's life. In fact, the relative composition of different bacterial genera can lead directly to health or disease. By understanding how the gut is colonized and what can be administered to alter overall composition, one would be able to use the gut as a legitimate target for drug delivery. In vitro gut adhesion models have been developed exactly for this purpose however have several limitations. In this thesis, an attempt has been made to develop a new gut adhesion model that included several key components associated with bacterial adhesion to the gut mucosal lining. For this, mucus-coated beads were used to simulate the mucosal lining. As well, beads were incubated with intestinal bacteria from a fresh human fecal sample. In this way, one would be study to observe the interactions between different bacteria within the gut, and the interaction between these commensal bacteria and any potential therapeutic design. This new model is a continuous model, allowing for real-time analysis of the mucosal-associated flora. This will allow its use to understand the effect of different external factors over an indefinite experimental period on gut bacterial adhesion. Results demonstrated that this model was highly effective in providing a stable microbial ecosystem for a single bacterial strain or for a large number of aerobic or anaerobic bacteria. The model was also shown to perform very well over long-term studies. This model has numerous applications and includes the investigation of probiotics, prebiotics, and antibiotics on altering a mucosal-associated microflora. In this thesis, an attempt has been made to develop a model that included several key components associated with bacterial adhesion to the gut mucosal lining. For this, mucus-coated beads were used in order to simulate the mucosal lining. As well, beads were incubated with intestinal bacteria from a fresh human fecal sample. In this way, one would be study to observe the interactions between different bacteria within the gut, and the interaction between these commensal bacteria and any potential therapeutic design. Finally, the model is continuous, allowing for real-time analysis of the mucosal-associated flora while at the same time, allow the researcher to understand the effect of different external factors over an indefinite experimental period. Results demonstrated that the platform was highly effective in providing a stable microbial ecosystem for a single bacterial strain or for a large number of aerobic or anaerobic bacteria. The model was also shown to perform very well over long-term studies. This model has numerous applications and includes the investigation of probiotics, prebiotics, and antibiotics on altering a mucosal-associated microflora. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La flore intestinale est un organe dynamique et complexe qui se trouve à l'intérieur du tube digestif. Bien qu'il y ait un flux d'activité constant, la microflore peut être considérée comme un bioréacteur ayant un quasi état d'équilibre durant toute la vie d'une personne. En fait, la composition relative des différents types de bactéries est directement reliée à la santé de l'individu. En comprenant comment l'intestin est colonisé et ce qui peut être administré pour modifier sa composition générale, on serait en mesure de l'utiliser comme une cible légitime pour la livraison de médicaments. Des modèles in-vitro d'adhérence intestinale ont été mis au point exactement à cette fin. Un modèle comprenant plusieurs éléments clés associés à l'adhésion bactérienne sur la muqueuse intestinale a été développé pour cette thèse. Tout d'abord, des capsules d'alginates recouvertes de mucus ont été utilisées afin de simuler la muqueuse intestinale. En outre, ces capsules ont été incubés avec les bactéries intestinales à partir d'un échantillon frais provenant des fécales humaines. De cette façon, on serait en mesure d'observer les interactions entre les différentes bactéries dans l'intestin, et l'interaction que ces bactéries ont avec tout autre traitement. Finalement, ce modèle est continu, permettant une analyse en temps réel de la muqueuse associée à la flore et nous permet de comprendre l'éffet de différents facteurs environnementaux sur de longues périodes de temps. Les résultats ont démontré que la plate-forme a été très efficace dans la fourniture d'un écosystème stable microbien pour une seule souche bactérienne ou pour un grand nombre de bactéries aérobies ou anaérobies. Le modèle a également montré de très bonnes performances au cours des études à long terme en utilisant plusieurs échantillons pendant l'expérience. Les applications de ce modèle sont pratiquement infinies, et permettent notamment d'enquêter sur l'effet que les probiotiques, les prébiotiques, et les antibiotiques ont sur la modification d'une microflore associée à la muqueuse.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Satya Prakash</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq98s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752m91n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612s72n"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reference frames for reaching modify the interaction between modes of postural control</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hilderley, Alicia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>En position debout, l'activité postural programmée en mode proactif est produite dans les membres de soutien avent des mouvements d'atteindre le bras, soit pour assurer la stabilité ou à induire le mouvement du corps entier nécessaire pour atteindre vers une cible. Alternativement, lorsque la posture est perturbée de manière inattendue, par exemple par un mouvement brusque de la surface d'appui, à la fois des réponses posturales à latence courte et à latence longue s'ensuivre. Comment ces deux modes (commandes prédictives et commandes en rétroaction) interagissent au cours de tâches posturales dynamiques reste incertaine. On a investigué cette interaction par examinant si les réactions posturales automatiques (APR) évoqués au cours d'atteindre une cible sur une plate-forme mobile sont modulés différemment si la cible se déplace avec le corps (une cible égocentrique, EGO), plutôt que si la cible se déplace indépendamment du corps (cible EXO).  On a varié le début des perturbations de plate-forme de se produire soit dans la phase d'accélération (RPa) ou décélération de la portée (RPd). Analyse de l'activité EMG a révélé que les APRs de latences courtes ont étés réduits dans les conditions RP fois par rapport à P, et les APRs de latences longues ont étés significativement réduits.  La réduction de la phase longue de latence de l'APR était supérieure dans les conditions de RPd que RPa, suggérant que les perturbations pendent la phase d'accélération de la portée sont plus perturbateur. Plus important cependant, la condition EXO produit des activités de latence longue significativement réduit en amplitude que EGO. Cela suggère que les réponses posturales de latence longue doivent être modulée à une plus grande mesure pour les portées à une cible exocentrique (statique par rapport a la plate-forme mobile), que si la cible se déplace avec le corps pour assurer le succès du mouvement.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>When standing, feedforward (FF) activity is produced in the supporting limbs prior to arm reaching movements and provides the biomechanical conditions required for reaching the target. When balance is unexpectedly perturbed, for example by a sudden support surface movement, short and long feedback-based (FB) postural responses are produced which restore body position to its pre-perturbation state. How these 2 modes (FF and FB) interact however, remains unclear. We investigated this relationship by examining if the FB-based automatic postural reactions (APR) evoked during reaching on a moving platform are modulated differently if the target moves with the body (an egocentric target, EGO), rather than moving independently of the body (EXO target). Furthermore, we varied the perturbation onset to occur either in the acceleration (RPa) or deceleration phase (RPd) of the reach. Analysis of EMG activity revealed that short latency APRs were reduced across both RP conditions with respect to P, and long latency APRs were significantly reduced. The reduction in the long-latency phase of the APRs was greater in RPd conditions than RPa, suggesting that perturbations during the acceleration phase of the reach are highly disruptive. Most importantly however, the EXO-RP condition produced significantly less long latency activity than did EGO-RP. This would suggest that when reaching to an exocentrically-placed target (static with respect to the moving platform), the long latency postural responses must be modulated to a greater extent than when the target moves with the moving body to ensure movement success.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Stapley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kc48z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s72n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343w85n"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Laser transmission welding of themoplastic tubes and plates using laser refraction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ramachandramoorthy, Rajaprakash</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Laser transmission welding is a method of joining plastics, which benefits from the infrared transparency in majority of thermoplastics. During the process, a laser beam passes through the laser transparent part and hits the laser absorbent part, which has been made absorbent using additives such as carbon black. The absorbed laser energy is then converted into heat and in turn welds the interface of the two parts by melting the polymer. In the current work, a new refraction technique of laser transmission welding is used to weld nylon plates to nylon tubes with carbon black. For the laser to refract, an angle was machined into the laser transparent nylon plates adjacent to the weld interface. Effect of different laser properties such as laser speed, number of laser rotations and laser power were studied on the quality of welding in terms of better finish and strength. The strength of these welds was assessed using a new tensile test fixture. Subsequently, the weld seam width was found from the tensile tested samples by analyzing the weld interface using vernier and transmission light microscopy. These tensile test results were then normalized using the weld seam area to obtain the tensile stress. The results showed the samples could withstand more tensile stress with an increase in laser power and rotation, excluding the samples which had decomposition due to excessive laser power. Also, the material property changes at the weld interface due to laser welding were characterized using a nanoindenter, for which small square samples were carved out of the weld interface and cold mounted. The results show that the modulus and hardness of nylon decreases right at the interface of the weld. In order to find the reason why there is a decline in the above mentioned mechanical properties, differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) testing was done to find possible changes in crystallinity, as decreasing modulus in semi-crystalline polymers is usually a result of decreasing crystallinity. The results confirmed that the crystallinity indeed decreased at the weld interface which would explain the decrease in mechanical properties.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le soudage par transmission laser est une méthode pour joindre les plastiques qui prend avantage du fait que la majorité des thermoplastiques sont transparent aux infrarouges. Durant le procédé, un faisceau laser passe à travers une région transparente pour aller en frapper une autre rendue absorbante au moyen d'additifs tel que le noir de carbone. L'énergie laser absorbée est ensuite convertie en chaleur. Ce dégagement de chaleur permet de souder l'interface entre les deux parties en fondant le polymère. Dans le présent travail, une nouvelle technique de soudage par transmission laser basée sur la réfraction a été  utilisée pour souder des plaques de nylon à des tubes de nylon contenant du noir de carbone. Afin de réfracter le laser, une surface en angle a été usinée à même les plaques de nylon transparentes, près de l'interface de soudage. Les effets de différentes propriétés du laser telles que la vitesse, le nombre de rotations et la puissance ont été évalués en se basant sur la qualité du soudage en termes du fini et de la résistance aux contraintes. La résistance des soudures a été déterminée à l'aide d'un nouvel accessoire de test en traction. Ensuite, la largeur de la soudure a été mesurée sur les échantillons testés en traction à l'aide d'un pied à coulisse et de la microscopie par transmission de lumière. Pour obtenir la contrainte en traction, les résultats des tests en traction ont été normalisés en les divisant par la surface réelle de leur soudure. Les résultats démontrent qu'une augmentation de la puissance et de la rotation du laser, jusqu'au seuil de dégradation, permet aux échantillons de soutenir davantage de contraintes en traction. De plus, les changements dans les propriétés du matériel dus à la soudure ont été caractérisés à l'aide d'un nano-indenteur, pour lequel de petits échantillons carrés ont été extraits de l'interface de soudure et montés à froid. Les résultats démontrent que le module et la dureté du nylon diminuent à l'interface de soudure. Puisque la diminution du module dans les polymères semi-cristallins est habituellement associée à une diminution de cristallinité, la calorimétrie différentielle à balayage a été utilisée afin de déceler les possibles changements dans la cristallinité. Les résultats confirment en effet que la cristallinité diminue à l'interface de soudure, et expliquent donc, par le fait même, la diminution des propriétés mécaniques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pascal Hubert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq992.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w85n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h844m"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of the atypical protein kinase C zeta orthologue, PKC Apl III, in synaptic plasticity and long term memory in Aplysia californica</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bougie, Joanna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The search for how memories are formed and maintained over time has become a critical question in the scientific community. An important discovery in this field is the requirement for a persistently active kinase, called PKMz, to maintain long term synaptic plasticity and memory. In vertebrates, the atypical PKCz has a brain-specific transcript that produces this constitutively active kinase. The sensory-motor neuron synapse of Aplysia is a leading invertebrate model to study learning and memory. We have cloned the atypical PKC from Aplysia, which we call PKC Apl III. We do not find a transcript in Aplysia that forms a PKMz, and evolutionary analysis of atypical PKCs suggests formation of this transcript is restricted to vertebrates, despite the fact that inhibitors of PKMz erase memory in Aplysia in a fashion similar to rodents. However, overexpression of PKC Apl III in Aplysia sensory neurons leads to production of a PKM fragment of PKC Apl III, PKM Apl III, formed by calpain cleavage. We suggest that PKM forms of atypical PKCs play a conserved role in memory formation, but the mechanism of formation of these kinases has changed over evolution. We further show that kinase activity is required for both nuclear export and efficient cleavage of PKC Apl III into PKM Apl III following overexpression. We used a FRET reporter to measure cleavage of PKC Apl III into PKM Apl III in live Aplysia motor neurons. Our results show that 5-HT application induces cleavage of PKC Apl III in isolated motor neuron processes in a calpain- and protein synthesis-dependent manner. In summary, we provide evidence that PKC Apl III is cleaved into PKM Apl III during memory formation, and the requirements for cleavage are the same as the requirements for the plasticity. Our data supports the hypothesis that the PKM required for formation of the memory trace is formed by calpain-dependent cleavage in Aplysia.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La quête des mécanismes moléculaires sous-jacents à la formation de nos souvenirs et à la persistance de ceux-ci dans notre mémoire continue de préoccuper la communité scientifique. Parmi les découvertes importantes dans ce domaine, on compte celle d'une kinase active de façon constitutive, appelée la PKM zeta. Celle-ci est nécessaire pour le maintien de la plasticité synaptique à long terme et en conséquent de la mémoire. Chez les vertébrés, la PKM zeta est produite à partir d'un ARNm de la PKC atypique, qui est spécifique au cerveau, soit la PKC zeta. Chez les invertébrés, la synapse sensori-motrice de l'Aplysie constitue le modèle par excellence pour étudier l'apprentissage et la mémoire. Nous avons cloné la PKC atypique de l'Aplysie que nous avons surnommée la PKC Apl III. Nous n'avons pas trouvé d'ARNm chez l'Aplysie qui pourrait former une PKM zeta. Par ailleurs, l'analyse de l'évolution des PKC atypiques suggère que la formation de cet ARNm est restreinte aux vertébrés malgré le fait que les inhibiteurs de la PKM zeta peuvent effacer la mémoire chez l'Aplysie de façon similaire à leur effet chez les rongeurs. Cependant, la surexpression de la PKC Apl III dans les neurones sensoriels de l'Aplysie conduit à la formation d'un fragment PKM de la PKC Apl III, soit la PKM Apl III par un clivage dépendant de la calpaïne. Nous suggérons que le rôle des formes PKM des PKC atypiques dans la formation de la mémoire est conservé mais que le mécanisme de formation de ces kinases a changé durant l'évolution. Nous rapportons aussi que l'activité de la kinase est nécessaire pour son export nucléaire ainsi que pour un clivage efficace de la PKC Apl III en PKM Apl III suite à la surexpression de la protéine. Nous avons utilisé un reporter FRET pour mesurer le clivage de la PKC Apl III en PKM Apl III dans des neurones moteurs vivants. Nos résultats démontrent que la 5-HT induit le clivage de la PKC Apl III dans les prolongements du neurone moteur et que ce clivage dépend des calpaïnes et de la synthèse de protéines. En résumé, nous démontrons que la PKC Apl III est clivée en PKM Apl III pendant la formation de la mémoire et que les conditions requises pour le clivage sont les mêmes que celles qui sont requises pour la plasticité. Nos résultats appuient l'hypothèse que chez l'Aplysie , la PKM requise pour la formation d'une trace mnésique est formée par clivage dépendant de la calpaïne.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wayne Steven Sossin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hw780.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h844m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741w82n"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modulation of olfactory processing by visual cortex stimulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jadauji, Jahan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to view the world in a unified manner, information from the different senses must combine at some point in the sensory stream. This is known as perceptual binding and has led to the study of how various senses interact, termed multisensory integration. An intriguing example of a crossmodal interaction is the finding from various imaging studies that primary visual cortex is activated while subjects performed purely olfactory tasks. This is in line with the literature documenting a connection between vision and olfaction, but whether visual cortical activity and olfactory perception are connected causally is unknown. In this thesis I will investigate the connection between vision and olfaction using Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS). TMS is a non-invasive method of stimulating cortex via magnetic induction. The present research involved the application of TMS to early visual cortex, including V1, bilaterally in the context of experiments that test both visual and olfactory perception. In particular subjects were tested on a visual task (contrast detection) and two olfactory tasks that probe the ability to discriminate odor intensity and quality. Behavioral experiments were carried out before and after the application of either no TMS, real TMS to V1, sham TMS to V1 (replicates experimental conditions of real TMS but no current is produced in the cortex) and real TMS to primary auditory cortex. The results have revealed a significant improvement in performance on the visual task, replicating previous data. Interestingly, improvements in the ability of subjects to discriminate among odor qualities following TMS of V1 were also found, with a tendency for female subjects to show more improvement than their male counterparts. Similar improvements were not found in the ability to discriminate among odor intensities or on either olfactory task in any of the control conditions (no TMS or sham TMS or auditory cortex TMS). Implications and limitations of the present results are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Afin de voir le monde d'une manière unifiée, les informations provenant des sens différents doivent combiner à un certain point dans le flux sensoriel. Ceci est connu comme la combinaison perceptuelle et a conduit à l'étude de la façon dont interagissent les différents sens, appelé intégration multisensorielle. Un exemple fascinant d'une interaction intermodale est la conclusion à partir des différents études d'imagerie que le cortex visuel primaire est activé alors que les sujets ont exécuté des tâches purement olfactif. Ceci est en accord avec la littérature documentant une connexion entre la vision et l'olfaction, mais si l'activité corticale visuelle et la perception olfactive sont connectés causalement est inconnue. Dans cette thèse, je vais étudier le lien entre la vision et l'olfaction en utilisant la stimulation magnétique transcrânienne (TMS). TMS est une méthode non invasive de stimulation du cortex via l'induction magnétique. La présente recherche concernait l'application de TMS au cortex visuel, y compris V1, bilatéralement dans le contexte des expériences qui testent à la fois la perception visuelle et olfactive. En particulier les sujets ont été testés sur une tâche visuelle (détection de contraste) et deux tâches olfactives qui sondent la capacité à discriminer l'intensité d'odeur et de qualité. Les expériences comportementales ont été réalisées avant et après l'application soit pas TMS, le TMS réelles à V1, faux TMS à V1 (réplique les conditions expérimentales de TMS réel, mais pas de courant est produit dans le cortex) et TMS réelles à  cortex auditif primaire. Les résultats ont révélé une amélioration significant des performances sur la tâche visuelle, qui réplique des données précédentes. L'amélioration de la capacité des sujets à discriminer parmi les qualités d'odeurs suivantes TMS de V1 ont également été trouvés, avec une tendance pour les sujets féminins à montrer une amélioration plus que leurs homologues masculins. Des améliorations similaires n'ont pas été trouvées dans la capacité à discriminer entre les intensités d'odeur ou de chaque tâche olfactive dans l'une des conditions de contrôle (pas de TMS ou faux TMS ou le TMS du cortex auditif). Les implications et les limites des résultats actuels sont discutés.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christopher Pack</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473138d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741w82n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687n312"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The arc of character: medieval stock types in Shakespeare's English history plays</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oberer, Karen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation focuses on practices of stock characterisation as they are represented in literature and drama of the fourteenth to sixteenth centuries in England, with particular emphasis on the transformations of social types from medieval literature to early modern drama, specifically Shakespeare's English history plays. Its wider focus is on the social context in which medieval authors created their characters, and on the conventional construction of medieval characters from what Elizabeth Fowler defines as "social persons." I argue that stock characters allow for permeability between past history and present performance. Attendant on their deployment in literature and drama is their recollection of past literary and cultural traditions. This is why Shakespeare employs them to such great effect in his English history plays: stock characters have an overt purchase on the past that makes history more socially immediate to early modern audiences. Shakespeare's stock characters recall medieval privileging of family and community, and thus are particularly suitable to the English histories' narratives of a country subsumed by family tragedy. The dissertation focuses on four social persons which Shakespeare uses to construct stock characters: the Garcio, the Alewife, the Corrupt Clergyman and the Romance Heroine. He employs these social persons in four characters: the Bastard Faulconbridge in King John, Mistress Quickly in the second "tetralogy," Cardinal Beaufort in the first "tetralogy" and Queen Isabel in Richard II. This dissertation is intended to provoke reconsideration of the stock characters as "flat" stereotypes, and to elaborate upon their complex roles in literary and dramatic history.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine la représentation des personnages types dans la littérature et le drame en Angleterre du quatorzième au seizième siècle en mettant particulièrement l'accent sur les transformations des types sociaux entre la littérature médiévale et le drame de la Renaissance, surtout dans les pièces historiques britanniques de Shakespeare. Au plus large, la thèse porte sur le contexte social dans lequel les auteurs médiévaux ont façonné leurs personnages et sur la fabrication conventionnelle des personnages médiévaux à partir des « personnes sociales » telles que définies par Elizabeth Fowler. Les personnages types, je soutiens, créent un espace de perméabilité entre l'histoire du passé et la performance au moment présent. L'emploi de ces personnages dans la littérature et dans le drame est associé à leurs souvenirs des traditions littéraires et culturelles du passé. C'est pourquoi Shakespeare s'en sert si bien dans ses pièces historiques : les personnages types ont une prise sur le passé qui rend l'histoire plus immédiate sur le plan social pour les spectateurs de la Renaissance. Les personnages types de Shakespeare rapellent l'emphase sur la famille et la communauté pendant l'époque médiévale, ce qui les rend particulièrement appropriés aux récits des pièces historiques d'un pays subsumé par la tragédie familiale.Cette thèse porte sur quatre personnes sociales à partir desquelles Shakespeare fabrique des personnages types, soit le « garcio », la femme du tavernier, le curé corrompu, et l'héroïne des histoires romanesques. Il a recours à ces personnes sociales dans quatre personnages, soit le bâtard Faulconbridge dans La vie et la mort du roi Jean, Madame Quickly dans la deuxième tétralogie, Cardinal Beaufort dans la première tétralogie, et la Reine Isabel dans Richard II. Le but de cette thèse est de provoquer une reconsidération des personnages types comme des stéréotypes « plats » et d'élaborer sur leurs rôles complexes dans l'histoire littéraire et dramatique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Theodore W. Folkerth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s1566.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687n312</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vn03v"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Understanding the effects of process parameters on the properties of cold gas dynamic sprayed pure titanium coatings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wong, Wilson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des revêtements de titane pur produits par projection à froid ont été étudiés. La relation entre les paramètres de projection à froid et la qualité des revêtements a été étudiée afin d'acquérir une compréhension approfondie du processus de fabrication. Pour atteindre cet objectif, trois études ont été effectuées.La première étude portait sur l'effet du gaz de propulsion (hélium et azote) lors de la projection à froid sur les propriétés des revêtements de titane pur. Pour chaque gaz, les conditions de pression et de température ont été variées afin de déterminer leur effet sur les vitesses moyennes des particules déterminées par une technique de diagnostic optique par temps de vol. Trois conditions de vitesse des particules identique pour les deux gaz ont étés choisis. Les résultats ont clairement démontré que pour la même vitesse des particules, les propriétés des revêtements diffèrent selon la nature du gaz employé. Cette étude a permis de conclure que la température du substrat, la température des particules ainsi que la pression exercée par le flux de gaz supersonique sur le substrat influences notablement les propriétés des revêtements de titane déposés par projection à froid.La deuxième étude portait sur l'effet de la morphologie des particules de titane pur (sphérique, éponge, et irrégulière) et la distribution de taille (taille moyenne: 20, 29 et 36 µm) sur les propriétés mécaniques des revêtements projetés à froid. Pour chaque poudre, plusieurs conditions de projection ont été testées et les vitesses de particules résultantes de même que l'efficacité de déposition ont été mesurées et les températures des particules ont été calculées. Des courbes semi-empiriques de contrainte-déformation ont été générées en utilisant le modèle de plasticité de Johnson-Cook. Ces courbes peuvent être utilisées comme une indication de la facilité de déposition. Pour toutes les poudres, les résultats ont montré que plus la taille des particules est grande, plus la température générée lors de l'impact est élevée. Pour les poudres sphériques, plus la température est élevée lors de l'impact, plus la contrainte requise pour la déformation des particules est basse. En outre, les observations ont montré que plus l'énergie cinétique de la particule sphérique augmente, plus la contrainte maximale est basse et plus la déformation maximale est élevée. Par ailleurs, plus la déformation maximale de la particule sphérique est élevée, plus la différence en microdureté entre le revêtement et la poudre avant la projection est élevée (ΔHV10). Des relations similaires sont attendues pour les poudres éponge et irrégulière. Basé sur la porosité des revêtements, la poudre sphérique avec la taille moyenne de 29 µm s'avère avoir la meilleure facilité de déposition lors de la projection à froid. La dernière étude porte sur l'effet de la rugosité de la surface du substrat et l'épaisseur du revêtement sur la force d'adhérence des revêtements de titane pur projetés à froid sur acier 1020, Al 6061, et Ti. Les contraintes résiduelles en fonction de l'épaisseur des revêtements et des différents substrats ont été mesurées en utilisant la méthode MLRM (Modified Layer Removal Method). Les résultats ont montré que la force d'adhérence augmente avec la rugosité de la surface du substrat initial et diminue avec l'épaisseur du revêtement. De plus, il a été suggéré que les forces d'adhérence élevées sont associées à des contraintes moyennes élevées en compression et à une probabilité plus élevée d'obtenir une instabilité de cisaillement adiabatique de se produire en raison d'une vitesse plus élevée des particules lors de l'impact. En général, les résultats ont montré que pour une condition de projection à froid et pour une préparation de surface quelconque, la force d'adhérence a été plus élevée pour les revêtements de titane pur déposés sur Al 6061, suivie par Ti, puis en acier 1020.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The cold gas dynamic spraying of commercially pure titanium coatings was investigated. Specifically, the relationship between several key cold spray parameters on the quality of the resulting coatings was studied in order to gain a more thorough understanding of the cold spray process. To achieve this goal, three distinct investigations were performed.The first part of the investigation focussed on the effect of propelling gas, particularly helium and nitrogen, during the cold spraying of titanium coatings. Coatings were characterised by SEM and were evaluated for their deposition efficiency (DE), microhardness, and porosity. In selected conditions, three particle velocities were investigated such that for each condition, the propelling gasses temperature and pressure were attuned to attain similar particle velocities for each gas. In addition, a thick and fully dense cold sprayed titanium coating was achieved with optimised spray parameters and nozzle using helium. The corresponding average particle velocity was 1173 m/s. The second part of the investigation studied the effect of particle morphology (spherical, sponge, and irregular) and size distributions (mean particle sizes of 20, 29, and 36 µm) of commercially pure titanium on the mechanical properties of the resulting cold sprayed coatings. Numerous powder and coating characterisations were performed. From these data, semi-empirical flow (stress-strain) curves were generated based on the Johnson-Cook plasticity model which could be used as a measure of cold sprayability. Cold sprayability can be defined as the ease with which a powder can be cold sprayed. It was found that the sponge and irregular commercially pure titanium powders had higher oxygen content, poorer powder flowability, higher compression ratio, lower powder packing factor, and higher average particle impact velocities compared to the spherical powders. XRD results showed no new phases present when comparing the various feedstock powders to their corresponding coatings. For all feedstock powder morphologies, it was observed that the larger the particle size, the higher the temperature generated on impact. For the spherical powders, the higher the temperature generated on impact, the lower the stress needed to deform the particle. In addition, as the kinetic energy of the impacting particle increased, the flow peak stress decreased while the final strain increased. Furthermore, higher final flow strains were associated with higher coating ΔHV10 (between the coatings and the feedstock powders). Similar relationships are expected to exist for the sponge and irregular feedstock powders. Based on porosity, the spherical medium powder was found to have the best cold sprayability.The final part of the investigation focussed on the effect of substrate surface roughness and coating thickness on the adhesion strength of commercially pure titanium cold sprayed coatings onto Steel 1020, Al 6061, and Ti substrates. Adhesion strength was measured by tensile/pull tests according to ASTM C-633-01 standard. Through-thickness residual stresses of selected coatings were measured using the modified layer removal method (MLRM). In addition, mean coating residual stresses were calculated from MLRM results. It was found that adhesion strength increases with increasing substrate surface roughness and decreases with increasing coating thickness. Furthermore, mean coating residual stresses were correlated with adhesion strength and it was suggested that higher adhesion strengths are associated with higher mean compressive stresses and a higher probability for adiabatic shear instability to occur due to the higher particle impact velocities. In general, it was found that under similar cold spray conditions and substrate surface preparation method, adhesion strength was strongest for commercially pure titanium coatings deposited onto Al 6061, followed by Ti, then Steel 1020.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stephen Yue</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784q53r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vn03v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xq729"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Policy, power, and the paradigm shift in the Vietnamese discourses of disability and inclusion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nguyen, Thi Xuan Thuy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the inclusion of people with disabilities into Vietnamese social and educational systems. Using a Foucauldian perspective on discourse, power, and the governing of individuals in the modern context, I trace the shift in the global and local policies on disability and inclusion through three levels of analysis: global, national, and educational. At the global and national levels, I argue that this shift in social and educational policy has reconstructed a vision about disability and citizenship through the forces exercised by global and local institutions. This is indicated by the formulation of a rights discourse about disability, as well as by the institutionalization of social and educational programs that support people with disabilities. However, situated within the development context, the politics of inclusion is demonstrated by the influences of neo-liberal ideologies, as well as by the shift in disability policies that has been in place since the 1990s in Viet Nam. Using historiography, policy studies, visual studies, and site visits as the major methodological approaches to observe the ideological implications and the effects of inclusion on student participation, I argue that the political agenda of inclusion in Viet Nam in the current context is associated with neo-liberal ideologies of governmentality and modern development. This is demonstrated by the re-formulation of policies and laws which foster individual rights, in line with economic development, and the institutional process of normalizing people with disabilities through social and political programs. The fusion of global and local ideologies of citizenship entitlement, normalization, and development has the effect of re-constructing inclusion and exclusion in the Vietnamese context of social change. Within the process of institutional change, the educational system plays an essential role in fostering inclusion. Inclusive education forms an integral part of this social process. The contemporary discourse of inclusive education in Vietnamese education is filled with echoes of the special education discourse of the past and the rights and development discourses in the present. This discourse institutionalizes the politics of inclusion through the provision of educational programs for children with disabilities in public education. However, the inclusion of students with disabilities into public education, driven by neo-liberal ideologies, has continued to perpetuate exclusion in education. Thus, I argue that inclusion is challenged by the exclusionary policies and practices, as well as by the reconstruction of policies which entitle new forms of exclusion in education. Finally, by mapping out the re-conceptualization of disability discourse in the modern context, I argue that our knowledge about individual difference is not objective, natural, or free of bias. It is, rather, a process socially, historically, and politically constructed by our values, beliefs, and social action. Thus, although inclusion has an important impact on the participation of people with disabilities in the mainstream educational system, the bio-political agenda of inclusion and management needs to be interrogated as a new way of governing disability issues in social and educational arenas. Therefore, the study constructs an historical account that opens up new ways of thinking about inclusion and exclusion in the global and local context of development, wherein education plays a part in formulating institutional policies and practices.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette étude examine l'intégration des personnes ayant un handicap dans le système social et éducatif du Viet Nam. Partant d'une perspective foucauldienne sur les discours, la puissance et la gouvernance des individus dans le contexte moderne, je trace l'évolution des politiques globales et locales sur le handicap et l'inclusion à travers trois niveaux d'analyse, soit au plan mondial, au plan national et au plan éducatif. Plus spécifiquement, aux niveaux mondial et national, je postule que l'écart entre la politique sociale et les systèmes éducatifs a réédifié la vision envers le handicap et la citoyenneté à travers les pressions exercées par les institutions mondiales et locales. La formulation du discours des droits des personnes ayant un handicap ainsi que l'institutionnalisation des programmes sociaux et éducatifs qui les supportent montrent cet écart.Située dans le contexte du développement, la politique d'inclusion du Viet Nam semble toutefois être influencée par des idéologies néo-libérales et par les changements survenus envers les politiques du handicap qui ont été mis en place dans ce pays depuis 1990. En utilisant l'historiographie, les études politiques, les études visuelles, et les visites sur le terrain comme principales approches méthodologiques pour observer les implications idéologiques et les effets de l'inclusion sur la participation des élèves, je montre que le programme politique de l'inclusion du Viet Nam, dans le contexte actuel, est associé aux idéologies néo-libérales sur la gouvernabilité et le développement moderne. La reformulation des politiques et des lois qui favorisent les droits de l'individu parallèlement avec le développement économique et les processus institutionnels de normalisation des personnes ayant un handicap aux programmes sociaux et politiques, montrent cette association idéologique. La fusion des idéologies globales et locales sur le droit de citoyenneté, sur la normalisation et sur le développement a pour effet de reconstruire l'inclusion et l'exclusion dans le contexte du changement social au Viet Nam. Au sein du processus de changement institutionnel, le système éducatif joue un rôle essentiel dans la promotion de l'inclusion. L'éducation inclusive fait intégralement partie de ce processus social. Le discours contemporain sur l'inclusion dans le système éducatif du Viet Nam fait écho à l'ancien discours de l'éducation spécialisée et réfère également à l'actuel discours sur les droits et développement des personnes ayant un handicap. Ce discours institutionnalise la politique d'inclusion par l'intermédiaire des programmes de formation pour les élèves ayant un handicap dans l'éducation publique. Toutefois, l'intégration de ces élèves dans l'enseignement public, inspirée par les idéologies néo-libérales, a continué de favoriser l'exclusion en éducation. Ainsi, je postule que l'inclusion est mise à l'épreuve par les politiques d'exclusion, les pratiques et par la reconstruction des politiques qui autorisent de nouvelles formes d'exclusion dans l'éducation.Enfin, en traçant la re-conceptualisation des discours sur les personnes ayant un handicap dans le contexte moderne, je souligne que nos connaissances sur les différences individuelles ne sont pas objectives, naturelles, ou libres de biais. Elles sont plutôt  des processus socialement, historiquement et politiquement construits par nos valeurs, nos croyances et nos actions sociales. Ainsi, quoique l'inclusion ait un impact important sur la participation des personnes ayant un handicap dans le système éducatif traditionnel, le programme biopolitique d'intégration et de gestion doit être questionné comme une nouvelle façon de gérer cette problématique d'un point de vue social et éducatif. Par conséquent, cette étude ouvre de nouvelles façons de penser l'inclusion et l'exclusion dans le contexte global et local dans lequel l'éducation joue un rôle important dans la formulation des politiques et pratiques institutionnelles.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anthony W. Pare</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Claudia A. Mitchell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719r23k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xq729</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Sociology of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2677071k"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Naive CD4+ T-cell homeostasis in primary progressive and secondary progressive multiple sclerosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fitz-Gerald, Leslie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The peripheral naive CD4+ T-cell pool is maintained through homeostatic mechanisms, which balance thymic output, cell survival and death, and peripheral T-cell proliferative processes. Naive CD4+ T-cells are divisible into several subsets based on their surface expression of CD31: cells having highest levels of expression of CD31 correspond to recent thymic emigrants (CD4+ RTEs), whereas CD31-negative (CD31neg) naive CD4+ T-cells have lost CD31 expression and are distant in origin from the thymus. We report that SPMS patients have altered naive CD4+ T-cell homeostasis with increased TCR-signalling and loss of CD31 from naive CD4+ T-cells with increasing age. Second, we report increased proliferation of the CD31neg subset of naive CD4+ T-cells in both SPMS and PPMS compared to controls. PPMS patients had an increased frequency of CD31neg naive CD4+ T-cells expressing the Fas receptor CD95. We conclude in PPMS that CD31neg cells have an increased propensity for cell death following proliferation. Self-peptide-MHC induced TCR signalling helps maintain naive CD4+ T-cell survival. TCR signalling with loss of CD31 leads to loss of the immunoregulatory function of CD31 molecules in naive CD4+ T-cells, i.e. would favour the development of autoimmune processes. Furthermore, increased proliferation of CD31neg naive CD4+ T-cells is known to expand auto-reactive T-cells, i.e. may contribute to ongoing autoimmune processes in progressive MS. In conclusion, we report peripheral naive CD4+ T-cell homeostatic alterations in both SPMS and PPMS that have potential implications for ongoing immunopathogenesis of these MS subtypes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La population des cellules-T CD4+ naïves périphériques est maintenue par des mécanismes homéostatiques qui fonctionnent en balancent la sortie du thymus, la survie et la mort des cellules, et la prolifération périphériques des cellules-T. Les cellules-T naive CD4+ se divisent en plusieurs sous-ensembles en fonction de leur expression de CD31 en surface: Les cellules ayant un plus haut niveau d'expression de CD31 correspondent aux émigrants thymiques récents (CD4+ ETRs), alors que les cellules CD31-négatif (CD31neg) ont perdu l'expression de CD31 et sont éloignées de l'origine du thymus. Nous avons constaté que chez les patients atteints de SPPS, l`homéostasie des lymphocytes-T CD4+ naïves est alterée, et se caractérise par une augmentation de la signalisation des récepteurs des cellules-T (RCT) et par la perte de CD31 des cellules-T CD4 + naïves  avec l'âge. Deuxièmement, nous avons constaté une augmentation de la prolifération du sous-ensemble CD31neg des cellules-T CD4+ naïves chez les patients atteints de SPPS et SPPP comparé aux controles. Les patients atteints de SPPP avaient une fréquence accrue dede type CD31neg exprimant le récepteur Fas, CD95. Nous concluons que les cellules CD31neg des patients atteints de SPPP ont une propension accrue à la mort cellulaire après leur prolifération. La signalisation des TCR induite par le complexe auto-peptide-CMH-induit signalisation des TCR permet de maintenir la survie des cellules-T CD4+ naives. Le signalisation des TCR avec un perte de CD31 entraîne la perte des fonctions immunorégulatrices des molécules CD31 dans les cellules-T CD4+ naives ; i.e. favorisant le développement de processus auto-immunitaires. En outre, la prolifération des cellules-T CD4 + naïves de type CD31neg est une cause connue de l'augmentation des cellules-T auto-réactives, c'est-à-dire peuvent contribuer à l'établissement de processus auto-immunitaires dans la SP progressive. En conclusion, nous rapportons des modifications homéostatique périphériques des lymphocytes-T CD4 + naïves dans les deux SPPS et PPPS ayant des implications potentielles pour l'immunopathogènes de ces sous-types de SP.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David George Haegert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365921z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2677071k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mr521"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Collective value and expectancy: the influence of group-based perception of personal goals on behaviour and affect</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Débrosse, Régine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In many contexts, belonging to a group impacts the pursuit of one's goals. Research on motivation has shown that both the value that one personally attributes to a goal and the personal expectancy of attainment of that goal predict successful goal-oriented behaviour. Building on expectancy-value theories of motivation, I introduce the notions of collective value and collective expectancy. Two experiments were designed to test: (1) whether collective value and expectancy regarding a goal (in this case, initiating a romantic relationship) could predict goal-oriented behaviour (in this case, leaving contact information to be paired with a partner) and (2) if a collective/personal discrepancy in value or expectancy would lead to poorer affect. Experiment 1 (n = 69) tested the effect of collective and personal values, whereas Experiment 2 (n = 71) tested the effect of collective and personal expectancies. The first hypothesis – which stated that collective value and expectancy would predict goal-oriented behaviour, even when considering personal value and expectancy – was not supported. The second hypothesis, which stated that a collective/personal discrepancy value or expectancy would lead to poorer affect, received support, as participants in discrepant conditions experienced significantly lower positive affect. The contribution of both experiments is discussed, in terms of their implications for research on the academic underperformance of certain minority groups, the social dysfunction that characterizes certain Native communities in Canada and the influence of group-based perceptions on pursuing romantic relationships.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans de nombreuses circonstances, appartenir à un groupe a un impact sur la poursuite des buts. Les travaux sur la motivation ont démontré que la valeur que chacun attribue personnellement à un but et les attentes quant à ses chances de succès prédisent les comportements reliés à la poursuite de ce but. En reprenant le cadre offert par les théories motivationnelles sur la valeur et les attentes (expectancy-value theories), je propose d'introduire les notions de 'valeur collective' (collective value) et 'attentes collectives' (collective expectancy). Deux études expérimentales ont été effectuées afin de tester (1) si la valeur et les attentes collectives concernant un but prédisent les comportements visant à atteindre ce but; ainsi que (2) si l'écart entre les perceptions personnelles et collectives des valeurs et des attentes associées à un but a un impact sur l'affect. L'étude 1 (n = 69) a été conçue pour tester les effets des valeurs personnelle et collective et l'étude 2 (n = 71) pour tester les effets des attentes personnelles et collectives. La première hypothèse – selon laquelle la valeur et les attentes collectives prédisent les comportements associés à la poursuite d'un but, même en tenant compte de l'effet de la valeur et des attentes personnelles – n'a pas été supportée par les résultats. La seconde hypothèse – selon laquelle un écart entre les perceptions collectives et personnelles de la valeur et des attentes associées à un but devrait réduire l'affect positif – a été supportée par les résultats. La contribution des deux études expérimentales fait l'objet d'une discussion, qui porte sur les implications de ces études pour la recherche sur la performance académique de certains groupes minoritaires, la dysfonction sociale qui caractérise certaines communautés autochtones du Canada et l'influence des perceptions d'un groupe sur le fait d'initier des relations amoureuses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donald M. Taylor</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn868.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mr521</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Social</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w0327077"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The marine record of abrupt climate change at Bay of Islands, Newfoundland</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sandercombe, Simone</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude évalue la réponse de la végétation aux changements climatiques abrupts survenus entre 12,000 and 8000 ans BP, en utilisant un enregistrement palynologique de Bay of Islands sur la côte ouest de Terre Neuve. Cette région est à la frontière entre deux écozones majeures: la forêt boréale et la toundra. Cette zone de transition est très sensible aux changements climatiques. La carotte MD99-2225 a été prélevée à une profondeur de 104 m à environ 12 km de la rivière Humber. Des échantillons ont été analysés à intervalles de 10cm entre 10 et 25 m de profondeur dans la carotte. L'analyse pollinique a permis de retracer l'évolution de la végétation, et les proportions de taxons caractéristiques de la toundra et celles des arbres plus thermophiles ont servis à déterminer les changements d'écotones. Les données polliniques ont aussi permis de reconstituer les températures. L'enregistrement des kystes de dinoflagellés a permis de reconstituer les paramètres des eaux de surface, tels que la température, la salinité et la durée du couvert de glace saisonnier. Les résultats montrent d'importants changements dans la composition de la végétation et dans les assemblages de kystes de dinoflagellés, en réponse à trois épisodes de refroidissement climatiques. Au début du Dryas récent, les températures de l`air qui étaient de -15°C en février et de 16°C en août ont chuté de 5°C. Les températures des eaux de surface qui étaient de 15°C ont également chuté de 10°C, et la durée saisonnière du couvert de glace marin a augmenté pour atteindre 10 mois/an. Les conditions sont demeurées très froides entre environ 10800-10300 yr BP. La végétation était dominée par des arbustes et des plantes herbacées. Les assemblages de kystes de dinoflagellés étaient caractérisés par une faible diversité spécifique et une dominance par les taxons arctiques. Les températures de l'air et des eaux de surface se sont améliorées après le Dryas récent. Autour de 9000 yr BP, une autre détérioration climatique a été enregistrée en réponse à l'oscillation PréBoréale. Les arbustes et les plantes herbacées ont de nouveau envahi la région et les assemblages de kystes de dinoflagellés ont connu une baisse de diversité et une augmentation de la proportion de taxons arctiques. Le dernier événement climatique détecté dans cet enregistrement, le refroidissement de 8.2 ka, a eu un impact moindre. Les températures de l'air et des eaux de surfaces ont connues une baisse, mais pour un lapse de temps très court.  La proportion de pollen d'arbustes a augmenté légèrement, de même que celles des espèces indicatrices de conditions d'eaux de surface froides (Brigantedinium spp., I. minutum and P. dalei). </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study assesses vegetational response to abrupt climatic changes that occurred between ca. 12,000 and 8,000 yr BP using a palynological record from Bay of Islands (west coast of Newfoundland). Western Newfoundland is located near the boundary of two major ecozones: the boreal forest and the tundra. This transition zone is very sensitive to climate change. Core MD99-2225 was extracted from Humber Arm at a depth of 104m, roughly 12km from the Humber River. Samples were analysed every 10cm between 10 and 25 m down-core. Pollen analysis was used to track the evolution of vegetation, and the proportions of both tundra and more thermophilous hardwood taxa were used to determine changes in ecotone. The pollen record was also used to reconstruct air temperatures.  The dinoflagellate cyst record was used to reconstruct sea surface parameters, such as temperature, salinity and sea ice. Results reflect large shifts in the composition of the vegetation and of dinoflagellate cysts assemblages in response to three cold climatic events. At the onset of the Younger Dryas, air temperatures dropped by 5°C from -15°C in February and 16 °C in August, August SST dropped by 10°C from roughly 15°C, and the duration of the sea ice cover increased to 10 months yr-1. Conditions remained harsh between ca. 10,800-10,300 yr BP, Vegetation was dominated by shrubs and grasses and dinoflagellate cyst assemblages are characterized by low species diversity and dominance by arctic species, such as Brigantedinium spp. Sea surface and air temperatures improved following after the Younger Dryas. At ca. 9,000 yr BP, sea surface conditions and air temperatures decreased in the bay as a response to the Preboreal Oscillation. Shrubs and grasses re-invaded the region and dinoflagellate cyst assemblages showed a decrease in diversity and dominance by arctic species such as Brigantedinium spp. The last event to be detected in this record, the 8.2 ka cold period, had a smaller impact in the region. Sea surface temperatures as well as air temperature decreased, but for a short time. The proportion of shrub pollen increased slightly and cold water species (Brigantedinium spp., I. minutum and P. dalei) dominated the dinoflagellate cyst assemblages.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elisabeth Levac</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gail L. Chmura</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h3729.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0327077</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arf55zc83q"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Examining learners' discrete emotional responses to a pedagogical agents' tutoring strategies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harley, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine l'impact de deux stratégies didactiques (Avec Retour et Sans Retour) déployées par un agent pédagogique (AP) au sein d'un environnement d'apprentissage hypermédia multi-agents, MetaTutor, sur les émotions discrètes exprimées par des étudiants. Les participants ont été assignés au hasard à l'une des deux conditions didactiques de l'AP, qui étaient conçues de manière à aider les étudiants à définir trois sous-buts appropriés pour leur session d'apprentissage. Si les sous-buts proposés n'étaient pas optimaux, la stratégie didactique Avec Retour fournissait aux participants des informations sur la manière dont ils pouvaient améliorer leur proposition, leur donnait l'occasion d'essayer de nouveau, et les contre-propositions finalement faites par l'AP intégraient les éléments pertinents issus de leur proposition, tandis que la stratégie didactique Sans Retour proposait simplement le sous-but optimal le plus proche. FaceReader, un logiciel de reconnaissance automatique d'expressions faciales, a été utilisé pour analyser les expressions faciales des étudiants, afin de déterminer leur état émotionnel basique. FaceReader a fourni des dizaines de milliers de points de données  (données fréquentielles), qui ont été transformés en proportions pour l'analyse. Les résultats de cette thèse proviennent de deux analyses (Analyse 1, Université de Memphis et Université McGill, N = 18 ; Analyse 2, Université McGill, N = 24), examinant les réactions émotionnelles d'étudiants de premier cycle confronté à l'AP durant la phase initiale de définition de buts, alors qu'ils définissaient trois sous-buts pour leur session d'apprentissage de deux heures avec MetaTutor. Ces résultats démontrent que les apprenants ont ressenti davantage d'émotions négatives que d'émotions neutres ou positives durant leur interaction avec l'AP, et moins de colère et de joie mais plus de surprise dans la condition Avec Retour. Cette thèse fournit des preuves permettant de recommander l'utilisation de stratégies pédagogiques similaires à celles employées dans la condition Avec Retour examinée ici, ainsi que l'emploi de la théorie de contrôle-valeur des émotions d'accomplissement pour juger de l'impact émotionnel de stratégies didactiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examined the impact of two different tutorial strategies (Feedback and No-Feedback) deployed by a pedagogical agent (PA) in a multi-agent hypermedia-learning environment, MetaTutor, on college students' embodiment of discrete emotions. Participants were randomly assigned to one of the two PA tutorial conditions, which were designed to assist students with setting three appropriate sub goals for their learning session. The two conditions differed in that the Feedback tutorial strategy condition provided participants with more information on how they could improve their suggested sub goals, were given more opportunities to try again (when unsuccessful) and the PA's counterproposals integrated relevant components of participants' proposed sub goals, whereas the No-Feedback PA tutorial condition did not and simply proposed the most related sub goal. FaceReader, an automatic facial expression recognition program, was used to analyze videos of learners' facial expressions in order to determine their basic emotional states. Tens of thousands of emotional data points (frequency data) were provided by FaceReader, which were transformed into proportions for analysis. The results of this thesis came from two analyses (Analysis 1, University of Memphis and McGill University, N = 18; Analysis 2, McGill University, N = 24), which examined undergraduate students' emotional responses to the PA during the initial sub goal setting phase, while they set three sub goals for their two-hour learning session with MetaTutor. Results demonstrated that learners' experienced more negative than positive or neutral emotions during their interaction with the PA and less anger and happiness, but more surprise in the Feedback tutorial condition. This thesis provided evidence for recommending tutorial strategies similar to the Feedback tutorial strategy examined and the use of the control-value theory of achievement emotions to assess the emotional impact of tutorial strategies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roger Azevedo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj84m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zc83q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv935709h"><ual:graduationDate>2012</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic analysis of the TCA cycle enzyme 2-oxoglutarate dehydrogenase in Sinorhizobium meliloti</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al Maleh, Rawan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La caractérisation génétique de l'opéron mdh-sucCDAB qui encode des enzymes du cycle des acides tricarboxylique, a été effectuée. Isolement d'un mutant de sucA a été tentée par recombinaison homologue avec des plasmides portant une insertion dans le gène. Plusieurs souches ont été criblées pour le phénotype attendu d'un mutant de la déshydrogénase de 2-oxoglutarate. Le phénotype d'utilisation de carbone des souches testées n'ont pas révélé de modèles de croissance très dissemblables par rapport au phénotype sauvage. L'amplification par PCR de ces souches n'a pas donné la taille de la bande attendue d'une copie mutant du gène. L'analyse par Southern blot des mutants putatifs n'a pas été concluante pour confirmer leur identité. Par conséquent, l'isolement d'un mutant de sucA a échoué. L'expression des gènes du cycle des acides tricarboxylique a été examinée avec des conditions différentes grâce à qRT-PCR. L'inspection d'expression génétique de sucA n'a pas révélé une augmentation par rapport à la transcription de sucD.  Cela indique une possibilité de l'absence d'un promoteur indépendant contrôlant son expression. D'autres gènes du cycle des acides tricarboxyliques sont exprimés différentiellement par les mutants de mdh et de sucB, en comparaison au type sauvage. Les profils d'expression ne semblent pas varier considérablement selon les sources de carbone testées. Comparaison de l'expression de ses gènes a révélé induction significative de sucB avec l'arabinose dans se mutant respectif. L'observation de transcription dans les bactéroïdes serait élucider l'expression dans des conditions symbiotique. Une enquête plus approfondie d'une mutation de sucA sera nécessaire, afin de déterminer la possibilité d'un phénotype résultant mortelle.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Genetic characterization of the mdh-sucCDAB operon, encoding enzymes of the TCA cycle, was performed.  Isolation of a sucA knock-out mutant was attempted through homologous recombination with plasmids carrying a mutated fragment of the sucA gene.  Several strains were screened for the expected phenotype of a 2-OGD mutant.  Carbon-source utilization phenotype of the tested strains did not reveal highly dissimilar growth patterns in comparison to wild-type levels.  PCR amplification of these strains did not yield the expected band size of a mutant copy of the gene.  Furthermore, Southern blot analysis of the putative mutants was inconclusive in confirming their identity.  Therefore, a sucA mutant was not successfully isolated.  Expression of TCA cycle genes was examined under different growth conditions through qRT-PCR analysis.  The sucA gene did not reveal any increase in transcript levels relative to sucD, under all tested conditions.  This indicated the possible absence of a promoter independently controlling its expression.  Other TCA cycle genes were differentially expressed in mdh and sucB mutants in comparison to wild type.  Expression patterns did not appear to vary greatly across the tested carbon sources.  Comparison of expression of TCA cycle genes in mutants, relative to wild type, revealed significant induction of sucB with arabinose in its respective knock-out mutant.  Examination of transcript levels in bacteroids would elucidate the gene expression patterns observed in symbiotic conditions.  In addition, further investigation of the nature of a sucA mutation will be required, to determine the possibility of a lethal phenotype.     </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brian T. Driscoll</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hp51v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935709h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>