<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36tz10w"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heligmosomoides polygyrus (Nematoda) infection, dominance and the major histocompatibility complex as factors influencing chemical communication and mate choice in mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ehman, Kimberly Diane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Both major histocompatibility genes (MHC) and infection have  been shown to influence urinary odours in mice, and mice may use MHC-associated  odours to detect kin for the purpose of choosing communal nesting partners, or to  avoid mating with close relatives. Additionally, mice may use infection-related  odours to avoid mating with sick individuals or those genetically susceptible to  infection. I tested the above theories using urine as the source of odour. In a  series of odour preference experiments, employing two MHC-congenic strains of mice  (B10 and B10.Q), I tested the proposition that females prefer MHC-similar female  odours when choosing female relatives as nesting partners, and that females prefer  MHC-disparate male odours for the purpose of disassoratative mating. I found that  females did not display a preference for MHC-similar female odours or MHC-disparate  male odours. However, when B10.Q male urine donors were infected with 100 L3 larvae  of Heligmosomoides polygyrus (Nematoda), both strains of female displayed a  significant preference for the odours of uninfected B10 males. To determine whether  female odour preference for uninfected males extended to actual mate choice, I  subsequently examined female mate choice in a controlled setting. Using CD-1 outbred  mice, I found that females preferred to mate with uninfected males over males  subclinically infected with 200 L3 of H. polygyrus , as evidenced by first  ejaculation preferences. In this experiment, males were tethered, and as such, male  dominance interactions were prevented. Thus, in the final experiment, to assess  whether male dominance interactions influenced female mate choice, in addition to  infection, I tested female mate choice in a seminatural setting, which allowed for  social interactions to occur. In this study, paternity was ascertained through DNA  analysis and the resulting data indicated that neither male dominance status nor  infection had a substantial impact on fema Overall, the data do not support the theory that MHC-based  preferences occur through urinary odours. However, the results do substantiate  previous findings regarding female preferences for the odours of uninfected males.  Furthermore, data from the controlled mate choice assay indicate that female odour  preference for uninfected males extends to actual mate choice. Conversely, in the  seminatural setting neither dominance nor infection prevailed as factors driving  female mate choice. I suggest that this may be a consequence of the structural  complexity of my arenas.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Scott, Marilyn E.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nb78c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tz10w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Heligmosomatidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Helminthiasis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Courtship in animals</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice -- Parasites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Major histocompatibility complex</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j152q"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>David Cronenberg's body-horror films and diverse embodied spectators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Egers, Wayne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is an interdisciplinary study of David  Cronenberg's body-horror films in relation to their embodied spectators. In these  films, the horror is not only about the vulnerability of the mortal body, but also  about the horrific consequences of organizing culture around the philosophical  splitting of the mind from the body. To analyze this relationship, I utilize  Merleau-Ponty's phenomenology of the body, object-relations psychoanalysis,  especially D. W. Winnicott's theory of the intermeshed psyche-soma, various  pro-feminist approaches to horror films, and a concept of ideology informed by  nonverbal communication research. The historical arc of Cronenberg's body-horror  films has produced a unique cultural record of the impact of technological change on  physical bodies through dark fantasies of biological-medical technologies in  Shivers, Rabid, The Brood, and Scanners; video communication technologies in  Videodrome; and genetic-engineering technologies in The Fly . My primary thesis is that Cronenberg's body-horror films  encourage spectators to "read" not only with their rational-cognitive  skills but with their embodied experience as well, which includes emotional and  sensory memories, and fantasies, both archaic and contemporary. Cronenberg's appeal  to an integrated psyche-soma reading is crucial for understanding how the culturally  induced splitting of the mind from the body impacts on working class resistance to  exploitative ideology. In chapter one I argue that the diverse and contradictory  readings of Cronenberg's body-horror films are possible, because of the  interdependence of the cinematic text, historical and cultural context, and the  embodied experience of spectators-critics. Chapter two is a preliminary step towards  developing an alternative theory of the horror film spectator, by exploring the  productive tension between an active, creative and embodied real viewer, and an  ideologically determined, ideal subject of the cinematic apparatus. Chapter three  compares Cronenberg's fantasy of metamorphosis body-horror to the fantasy of  "leaving the body behind" depicted in many contemporary cyborg films.  Chapter four is a series of close readings, analyzing how Cronenberg embeds  "imaginary spectators" into his body-horror films through interweaving the  body language of his characters and the nonverbal communication of the mise en scene  with narrative strategies formulated through the plot.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marchessault, Janine</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b48h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j152q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Horror films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cronenberg, David, 1943- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Body, Human, in motion pictures</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515n94m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La chanson polyphonique française de la renaissance ca 1470-ca 1550 : les avatars du populaire</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Michaud, Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We show, by internal analysis of the texts and references to  other contemporary texts, that from 1470 to 1550 the French polyphonic chanson  reveals more than ever before a strong tendency to pertain to the  "popular" and its related categories, the "carnavalesque" and  the "grotesque". From a corpus of close to a thousand popular chansons  selected according to the courtly and "good life" "registers",  we can assert that, in spite of the essentially learned dimension of polyphonic  music, it is the textual component that seems to be popular. This is what indicates  the study of their carnavalesque images and the analysis of the grotesque structures  of the "cris", the combinative chansons, the "caquets" and the  "fricassees", the latter proving to be real crossroads where chansons of  the time parade. Our theoretical reflections on the notion of "popular",  necessary to justify the use of the concept in a corpus whose texts are usually  anonymous, prompts us to both avoid source studies and issues of production and  reception, by defining the "popular" as an aesthetic category based on  stylistic and rhetorical conventions. In this perspective, the principal  characteristic of these chansons consists in the omnipresence of the imperative  calls to the participation in the "good life", all of which belong to a  popular version of the carpe diem. While a type of carnavalesque chanson accumulates  the motifs "dansons", "chansons" and "buvons", many  constitute often obscene variants of "baisez-moi", and others multiply  military orders. The occurrences of these imperative motifs, usually appearing in  direct discourse, confirm, with partially imperative imprecations, a vocabulary of  the public place, onomatopeia and plays on words, the orality of the register and  its belonging to a popular level of discourse corresponding to a less elevated style  than the low style of rhetoric.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Desrosiers-Bonin, Diane</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x1934.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n94m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Polyphonic chansons -- France -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polyphonic chansons -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dd02b"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of CD4 dimerization in T cell activation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moldovan, Maria-Cristina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Key to development of immunotherapies and vaccines is a thorough  understanding of the complex pathways that govern T cell activation. On helper T  lymphocytes, the CD4 molecule is a critical player in the early stages of  activation, serving to enhance recognition of MHC-peptide complexes by the TcR and  to facilitate efficient p56lck recruitment in the vicinity of the engaged TcR:CD3  signalling module. Originally, the CD4 molecule was believed to exist as a monomer  on the cell surface; however, within the last years, a growing body of  crystallographic, computer modeling and functional studies has suggested that CD4  might assume a dimeric/oligomeric state. Here, we provide direct experimental evidence for the existence  of CD4 dimers on the surface of transfected cells from haematopoietic and  fibroblastic origin, as well as in primary T lymphocytes. Furthermore, we accurately  map the dimerization site at residues K318 and Q344 within the fourth extracellular  domain of CD4. More importantly, we demonstrate that dimer formation is essential  for the coligand and coreceptor functions of CD4 in T cell activation. Specifically,  we show that CD4 dimerization is required for efficient IL-2 production, yet appears  without effect on early TcR-associated signalling. Using FRET video microscopy to  visualize the dynamics of CD4 molecules during T cell activation, we reveal that CD4  dimers only promote immunological synapse formation, then further accumulate within  the synapse. Overall, the study presented in this thesis sheds light on the  refined molecular interplay of the various surface receptors and signalling modules  that dictates the efficiency of the T lymphocyte antigenic response.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sekaly, Rafick-Pierre</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149q43m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dd02b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386j74n"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Selective area epitaxy for indium phosphide based photonic integrated circuits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Greenspan, Jonathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ability to integrate multiple photonic devices on a single  substrate has turned out to be very advantageous in the fabrication of components  for optical communication networks. For example, improved fiber coupling can be  achieved by integrating a modulator with an optical mode converter. However, current  technology is very limited in its ability to fabricate such photonic integrated  circuits (PIC). We report on a selective area epitaxy (SAE) process suitable for  the fabrication of a PIC. The process includes a quantitative model, which for the  first time, is capable of predicting the growth rate and composition of thin films  selectively deposited by metalorganic chemical vapour deposition in areas close to  the dielectric mask as well as areas several microns away. The accuracy of the model  is demonstrated by comparing simulation results with experimental measurements of  the thickness and composition profiles obtained by surface profilometry and energy  dispersed X-ray respectively. The process is applied to the fabrication of an elecroabsorption  modulator and optical mode converter, monolithically integrated on an InP substrate.  As part of the fabrication, quantitative modeling of the converter waveguide core  deposition is employed to achieve a thickness profile previously designed by beam  propagation calculations. Modeling is also used to predict the composition and  strain shifts introduced by selective deposition, enabling the composition to be  designed such that the maximum strain is minimized. Device measurements demonstrate  that SAE is successfully used for the fabrication of a PIC with characteristics  superior to those found in conventional devices.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shih, Ishiang</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Puetz, Norbert</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j151f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j74n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r149x"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Diverse older women : narratives negotiating frailty</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grenier, Amanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores women's narratives from within and outside  of the frail/non-frail binary of public home care services. It focuses on the  stories that are commonly told about older women's needs and bodies and the  regulatory potential of these accounts. Considering power, language, diversity and  change, this study focuses on the way that twelve diverse older women at various  social locations (e.g., ability, age, culture, ethnicity, 'race', sexual  orientation, and socio-economic status) understand, make meaning, and negotiate the  concept of frailty in relation to their everyday lives. The sample includes six  women considered 'frail' in relation to service (i.e., according to clinical  judgement &amp; home care eligibility guidelines), as well as women not considered  'frail' (i.e., non-service recipients). The twelve older women's storied responses, illustrations and  experiences challenge the various stories that are told about them. Their complex  accounts both reflect and reject dominant notions, blur the boundary between the  frail and non-frail classifications, expose frailty as contextual, temporal and  relative, as well as illustrate the connections between medical and social needs.  Their individual accounts highlight how they make meaning of their life events in  relation to their diverse experiences and identities, as well as how these  identities and interpretations are key to their negotiations of life and needs. The  variations between the imposed stories about frailty and women's self-perceptions  highlight the research, policy and practice relevance of a narrative approach  focused on in-depth local accounts, raise questions about the current priorities  within home care services, as well as the future of social work practice with older  women considered frail.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brotman, Shari</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Racine, Guylaine</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x03f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r149x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Older women</dc:subject><dc:subject>Frail elderly</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb3978813"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Religion, rationality, and language : a critical analysis of Jürgen Habermas' theory of communicative action</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mesbah, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Jurgen Habermas is a second-generation social philosopher of the  Frankfurt school, the birthplace of critical theory. He suggests that modernity is a  project of substituting rationality for religion. In his analysis, such a succession  is the result of a process of social evolution, in which each developmental stage  has its basic concepts and modes of understanding subjective, objective, and social  worlds. For him, the salient feature of rationality consists of differentiation  between various validity claims of truth, truthfulness, and sincerity which are  indistinguishable in religious language. The rationalization of religion, hence,  progresses in terms of a differentiation between validity claims, a decentration of  human understanding, the disenchantment of the world, and the linguistification of  the sacred. Habermas proposes a universal pragmatics in which two modes of language  use are separated: instrumental-strategic, and communicative. He thinks that the  failure of the enlightenment movement to replace religion with reason stems from its  preoccupation with instrumental reason and language use, dispensing with  communicative rationality; and the remedy lies in communicative  rationality. Critically analyzing Habermas' theory of communicative action,  this study examines Habermas' basic idea of substituting communicative rationality  for religion in the light of his critique of Max Weber and of instrumental reason.  Ontological, epistemological, methodological, and conceptual presuppositions in his  argument are discussed and evaluated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boutin, Maurice</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612p15d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb3978813</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communication -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Philosophy and religion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Habermas, Jürgen -- Contributions in philosophy of communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>Habermas, Jürgen. Theorie des kommunikativen Handelns</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rationalism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj38607392"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular typing and genome expression profiling of organ- and host-specific «staphylococcus aureus» from bovine mastitis and human infections</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Said, Kamaleldin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Staphylococcus aureus est un problème majeur tant pour la santé publique que pour l'industrie laitière à cause de la rapide évolution de lignées spécialisées hôte/organe touchant l'Homme et les animaux à destiné alimentaire. Cependant, les mécanismes de spécialisation hôte/organe ainsi que la distribution de ses lignées clonales dominantes restent mal décrites. Nous avons postulé l'hypothèse que des marqueurs codants répétés dans la région intra-génique du facteur d'agglutination clfA permettraient de détecter et d'attribuer un groupe à des clones adaptatifs et d'en révéler ainsi les types prédominants et que l'étude de l'expression génomique totale de ces clones dans des conditions reproduisant celles de glandes mammaires privées d'oxygène pourrait potentiellement révéler des sous-groupes de gènes impliqués dans les mécanismes de spécialisation hôte et de sélection dans les glandes mammaires. Nous avons donc étudié le gène clfA et nos résultats indiquent que 80% des gènes clfA analysés avaient entre 44 et 57 copies-répétées. De plus, les isolats humains étaient polymorphiques alors que ceux provenant de mastite étaient clonaux. Les répétitions étaient stables durant les passages dans le lait, le bouillon nutritionnel et lors de l'invasion des cellules mammaires. Le gène clfA s'est aussi révélé utile pour attribuer un groupe aux lignées hôte spécifiques et établir que la dominance d'un motif clonal dans une mastite implique une sélection organe-spécifique dans la glande mammaire. Ceci fut examiné plus avant dans les isolats de différents organes de patients humains et de mastites bovines. Nos résultats montrent une corrélation significative entre les organes étudiés et la longueur du gène clfA. Vingt sur les 23 isolats d'expectoration avaient un faible taux de copies (43-48) alors que 21 des 24 isolats de peau avaient entre 55 et 63 copies. Il est aussi important de noter que les alignements d Nous avons ensuite standardisé clfA comme marqueur pour la mastite au cours d'une expérience comparative utilisant des méthodes références, l'électrophorèse en gel pulsé et le spa, et ainsi identifié sa distribution génotypique ainsi que ses types dominants au Canada. Nos résultats montrent que clfA présente le même indice de discrimination de 0.9 que la PFGE. Deux groupes de lignage PFGE dominants (A avec 48.3% et D avec 43.7 %) représentent les types des souches présentes dans le Canada occidental et oriental respectivement. Ceux-ci furent de plus subdivisés à l'aide de clfA en quatre sous-types. En conséquence, le typage par clfA, en plus d'être concordant avec ceux par PFGE et spa, s'est avéré utile pour établir le profil de sous-populations avec le même pouvoir discriminatoire. Par la suite, deux isolats bien caractérisés représentant des clones majeurs spécifiques pour l'Homme et les bovins ont été utilisés afin de révéler l'expression génomique totale durant l'invasion des cellules épithéliales mammaires sous des conditions normales ou réduites en oxygène. Dans l'isolat de mastite sous condition normale en oxygène, l'expression des régulateurs MerR, sigB, VraS, YycG/YycF, araC, et tetR indiqua des fonctions d'adaptation, de fixation et de protection. Le couplage du métabolisme fermentaire avec la virulence fut mise en évidence par la présence de la protéine catabolite A (ccpA), de la voie des pentoses monophosphate, et la régulation négative du cycle de Krebs. Considéré dans leur ensemble, les réponses rapides des isolats de mastite suggèrent fortement un phénotype adapté aux cellules mammaires. La description future du grand nombre de protéines hypothétiques pourrait potentiellement révéler un réseau précis de facteurs régulateurs qui sont spécifiquement exprimés dans la glande mammaire.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Staphylococcus aureus has become a major concern in public health and dairy industry due to the rapid evolution of host/organ specialized lineages adapted to humans and major food animals. However, the mechanism(s) of host- and organ-specialization as well as the distribution of dominant clonal lines of S. aureus is presently ill-defined. We hypothesized that coding repeat markers in the intragenic region of clumping factor A (clfA) gene would be capable of detecting and grouping adaptive clones and revealing predominant types and that whole genome expression of these clones in mammary mimicked reduced oxygen condition would potentially reveal subsets of gene(s) responsible for pathways and mechanisms of host-specialization and selection in the mammary gland. Thus, the suitability of clfA was explored. Results indicated that 80% of clfA analyzed had repeat-copies between 44 and 57.  Furthermore, human isolates were polymorphic, while mastitis isolates were clonal. The repeats were stable during passages in milk, nutrient broth, and invasion of mammary cells showing suitability for typing. In addition, dominance of a clonal motif in mastitis implied organ-specific selection in the mammary gland. This was further examined in isolates from different organs in human patients and from bovine mastitis. The results showed significant correlation between the organs sampled and the length of clfA. Twenty out of the 23 sputum isolates had lower copy-numbers of 43-48, while 21 out of the 24 skin isolates had 55-63 copies. Moreover, sequence alignments and phylogenetic analysis placed isolates from different hosts and organs into respective clusters. Subsequently, clfA was used as a typing marker for mastitis in a comparative experiment with pulsed-field gel-electrophoresis (PFGE) and spa typing, and identified genotype distributions and the dominant types across Canada. Interestingly, both clfA and PFGE had identical index of discrimination of 0.9. Two dominant PFGE lineage Groups A with 48.3% and D with 43.7 % represented Eastern and Western Canada strain types, respectively. These were further subdivided by clfA into four dominant subtypes X, Q, C, and Z which formed 82% and 43% of PFGE groups A and D, respectively. Thus, concordant with PFGE, clfA typing proved useful in rapidly profiling subpopulations with comparable discriminatory power. Consequently, two isolates representing major human- and bovine-specific clones were used for whole genome expression after their invasion into mammary epithelial cells under normal and reduced oxygen conditions, using high-throughput genome qRT-PCR. In the mastitis isolate under normal oxygen, expression of MerR, sigB, VraS, YycG/YycF, araC, and tetR indicated adaptation, environmental sensing, binding, and protection. Coupling of fermentative metabolism to virulence was evident by upgulation of the catabolite control protein A (ccpA), pentose monophosphate pathway, and down regulation of TCA cycle. Invasive phenotypes, potentially through sarU activation of agr and in vivo viability factors as staphopains and GntR operon, also occurred. However, under reduced oxygen it showed upregulation of fibrinogen-binding, isd operon, (isdA, isdC, isdH), and sdrH, indicating aggressive binding phenotype. Irrespective of oxygen, strain Wright was less aggressive than the mastitis isolate and showed intense intracellular signalling potentially through MerR and sigB, limited toxins, and many hypothetical genes. Interestingly, under reduced oxygen, universal down regulation in metabolic and regulatory pathways occurred showing persistence of Wright strain. Taken together, the quick response of the mastitis isolate strongly suggested adapted phenotype to mammary cells and that reduced oxygen induced persistence properties. Future annotation of hypothetical proteins would potentially reveal a more precise network of regulatory subsets that are expressed in the mammary gland.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Xin Zhao</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p7584.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38607392</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qm430"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of cold climate seasonal temperature regimes on bioremediation of petroleum hydrocarbon-contaminated soils</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chang, Won Jae</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'objectif global de cette recherche était d'étudier le taux et l'étendue de la biodégradation des hydrocarbures pétroliers totaux (HPT) dans les sols contaminés à partir d'un site subarctique, sous des régimes de température de sites pertinents touchés par des climats froids, et d'évaluer l'effet de différents régimes de température sur la biodégradation des HPTs. Une série d'expériences de biodégradation à échelle pilote a été réalisées en utilisant du sol âgé contaminé au pétrole expédié à partir d'un ancien site militaire de réseaux de radars, le Distant Early Warning (DEW), dans l'île Resolution, au Nunavut, Canada (61° 30' 1"N  65° 0' 1"O). Les taux et l'étendue de la biodégradation des hydrocarbures non volatils de masse moléculaire plus élevés (F3) a été significative et comparable aux taux et à l'importance de la biodégradation observés pour les semi-volatils, de masse moléculaire moins élevés (F2). Les constantes de vitesse de biodégradation du premier ordre pour les fractions d'hydrocarbures F2 et F3 étaient semblables les unes des autres. Cela était vrai dans  l'épandage contrôlé avec des nivaux de HPTs initiaux bas, ainsi qu'avec les nivaux de HTPs initiaux élevés, et cela est estimée de 0,011 à 0,024 jour-1 et de 0,016 à 0,019 jour-1, respectivement. Les modifications de ratios des concentrations résiduelles des alcanes C14, C16 et C18 avec une biodégradation progressive a été suivie à la trace, et cela a démontré qu'une réduction des niveaux de HTPs entraîne une diminution de l'abondance relative des alcanes à haut poids moléculaire. Les agrégats de sols avec des diamètres allant de 0,6 mm à 2 millimètres contenaient des HPTs résiduels qui ne sont pas donc biodisponibles, ont contrôlé le point d'aboutissement efficace de la biodégradation. Les variables de températures représentatives des changements de température du site entre 1° et 10 °C entre une période de deux mois ont considérablement influencé la vitesse et l'étendue de la biodégradation des hydrocarbures pétroliers par rapport aux taux et l'étendue obtenus sous une température d'incubation moyenne constante de 6 °C. Sous la température variable du site, une biodégradation plus rapide d'à la fois les hydrocarbures semi-volatils et non volatils s'est produite à un facteur de deux, près en raison d'une bioactivité accélérée, et d'une croissance des populations microbiennes indigènes qui prospèrent en décomposant les hydrocarbures. Une étude a été entreprise afin d'évaluer quantitativement la biodégradation des hydrocarbures pétroliers, ainsi que la respiration et réponse microbienne au cours des périodes de transition saisonnière précédant et suivant la saison d'été, où le gel et le dégel des couches superficielles du sol se produisent au site subarctique. Pendant la phase de congélation, une étendue statistiquement significative de la biodégradation de l'ordre de 13% des hydrocarbures semi-volatils s'est produite, ce qui a été corrélé avec l'émergence  des bactéries d'hydrocarbures biodégradables Corynebacterineae connexes et la croissance des populations microbiennes hétérotrophes. La biodégradation des hydrocarbures pétroliers, la respiration microbienne et les changements dans la taille et la composition des communautés microbiennes sont apparus sous des températures au-dessous de zéro, mais seulement ou il y avait du liquide non gelées substantiel dans les pores du sol, coexistant avec de la glace interstitielle. Un taux rapide d'augmentation de température a provoqué une poussée d'activités de respiration microbienne comme précédemment observée dans plusieurs études. Il a été constaté que cette activité microbienne a également entraîné de manière significative des réductions de concentrations d'hydrocarbures semi-volatils et non volatils allant jusqu'à 25% et 11%, respectivement.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Temperatures in cold climates are dynamic due to diurnal, periodic or seasonal temperature variations and variability in incoming solar radiation, and these temperature changes may influence on-site soil microbial activity. To date there has been very little research focused how variations in site temperatures and various seasonal temperature regimes influence biodegradation performance. The overall objective of this research was to investigate the rate and extent of total petroleum hydrocarbon (TPH) biodegradation in contaminated soils from a sub-Arctic site under site-relevant temperature regimes in cold climates and to assess the effect of different temperature regimes on TPH biodegradation activity. A series of pilot-scale biodegradation experiments was conducted using field-aged petroleum-contaminated soils shipped from a former military Distant Early Warning (DEW) line site in Resolution Island, Nunavut, Canada (61°30'N 65°00'W). Pilot-scale landfarming experiments were performed in a laboratory in soil tanks under site temperature profiles representative of the 3-year site air temperatures in July and August where temperature varied uniformly between 1 °C to 10 °C over 10 days. The rates and extent of biodegradation of the non-volatile, higher molecular weight hydrocarbons (F3) was significant and comparable to the rates and extent of biodegradation observed for semi-volatile, lower molecular weight fraction (F2). The first-order biodegradation rate constants for the F2 and F3 hydrocarbon fractions were similar to each other in both low initial TPH and high initial TPH landfarms and estimated to be 0.011 to 0.024 day-1 and 0.016 to 0.019 day-11, respectively. Changes in ratios of residual concentrations of C14, C16 and C18 alkanes with progressive biodegradation was tracked, and showed that as TPH levels declined, the relative abundance of the higher-molecular weight alkanes declined. Soil aggregates with diameters ranging from 0.6 mm to 2 mm contained residual TPH that was not bioavailable and thus controlled the effective endpoint of biodegradation. Variable temperatures representative of site temperature changes between 1 and 10 °C over two months dramatically influenced the rates and extent of biodegradation of petroleum hydrocarbons compared to the rates and extent obtained under a constant average incubation temperature of 6 °C. Under the variable site temperature condition, more rapid biodegradation of both semi- and non-volatile hydrocarbons occurred by over a factor of two due to accelerated bioactivity and growth of indigenous hydrocarbon-degrading microbial populations. Preferential biodegradation of semi-volatile hydrocarbons over non-volatile hydrocarbons was significant in the constant average temperature mode, but not under the variable temperature regime. A study was undertaken to quantitatively assess biodegradation of petroleum hydrocarbons and microbial respiration and response during the seasonal transition periods preceding and following summer where freezing and thawing of the surface soil layers occurs at the sub-Arctic site. During the freezing phase, a statistically significant extent of biodegradation of 13% of semi-volatile hydrocarbons occurred, which was correlated with the emergence of Corynebacterineae-related hydrocarbon-degrading bacteria and growth of heterotrophic microbial populations. Petroleum hydrocarbon biodegradation, microbial respiration and changes in the size and composition of microbial community occurred under sub-zero temperatures but only when there was substantial liquid, unfrozen pore waters coexisting with pore ice. A rapid rate of temperature increase caused a burst of microbial respiration activity as previously observed in several studies, and it was found that this microbial activity also resulted in significant reductions of semi- and non-volatile hydrocarbon concentrations of up to 25% and 11%, respectively.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Subhasis Ghoshal</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lyle Whyte</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83kz70h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qm430</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x185f"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A bibliometric analysis of Quebec's PhD students' contribution to the advancement of knowledge</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lariviere, Vincent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Graduate students are an important part of the academic workforce. However, little is known on their overall contribution to science. Using the participation in Web of Science indexed peer-reviewed publications of the complete population of doctoral students in Quebec over the 2000-2007 period (N=27,393), this thesis achieves three main contributions to the advancement of knowledge in the fields of information science, sociology of the scientific community and sociology of higher education. The first contribution is a technical one and involves the creation of an algorithm that allows the automatic attribution of a large proportion of individual researchers' papers. Indeed, using the patterns found in Quebec university researchers' use of keywords, cited references and discipline of publication, the algorithm automatically attributes or rejects at least one scientific paper to 88% of doctoral students. The second contribution is to provide a large-scale analysis of doctoral students' socialization to research, using the percentage of doctoral students who have published at least one paper during their program as an indicator. It shows that this integration varies greatly among disciplines, with students in the natural and medical sciences being more integrated into research than their colleagues of the social sciences and humanities. Collaboration is an important component of this socialization: disciplines in which student-faculty collaboration are higher are also those in which doctoral students are the most integrated into research. Access to research funds also influences doctoral students participation in peer-reviewed papers, as specialties where professors receive greater research funds are also those where students are the most likely to publish. Although the papers to which doctoral students contribute are most often written in collaboration, they are less likely to be the result of international collaboration. Such socialization to research is also positively linked with students' degree completion and the likelihood of a subsequent career in research. Finally, the third contribution of this thesis is to measure the percentage of the research output of the research system produced by doctoral students. It provides evidence that, for all disciplines combined, PhD students account for 33% of the publication output of the province, a percentage that is considerably higher than that of Quebec hospital researchers taken together and more than 5 times higher than that of federal and industrial researchers of the province. In terms of scientific impact, papers to which doctoral students have contributed obtain significantly lower citation rates than other Quebec papers to which they have not contributed, although the average impact factor of the journals in which they publish is significantly higher. This suggests that the scientific impact of doctoral students' papers may suffer from a Matthew Effect, the sociological phenomenon observed by which recognition for discoveries is more easily attributed to well known scientists than to others less known. Overall, this interdisciplinary thesis provides a significant insight into the extent, the context and the effect of socialization to research in the PhD curriculum, as well as a better understanding of the importance of doctoral students' scientific contributions within Quebec's research system. These findings should be of great interest to university administrators as well as for research councils and the science policy community in general.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les étudiants gradués comptent pour une part importante de la main d'œuvre académique. Toutefois, nous ne savons que très peu de choses sur leur contribution globale à l'avancement des connaissances. À partir des articles publiés dans des revues à comités de pairs — et indexés dans le Web of Science — par la population complète des étudiants au doctorat au Québec entre et 2000 et 2007 (N=27,393), cette thèse effectue trois contributions principales à l'avancement des connaissances en sciences de l'information et en sociologie de la communauté scientifique et de l'enseignement supérieur. La première contribution est de nature technique et consiste en la création d'un algorithme qui permet l'attribution automatique à un chercheur d'un pourcentage important de ses articles scientifiques. En effet, en utilisant les régularités trouvées dans les mots-clés, références citées et la discipline de publication des chercheurs universitaires québécois, cet algorithme permet l'attribution ou le rejet automatique d'au moins un article à 88% des étudiants de doctorat. La seconde contribution est l'analyse à grande échelle de la socialisation des doctorants à la recherche, en utilisant comme indicateur le pourcentage d'étudiants au doctorat qui ont publié au moins un papier au cours de leur programme. Les données montrent que cette intégration varie considérablement entre les disciplines : les étudiants des sciences naturelles et médicales étant plus intégrés à la recherche que leurs collègues des sciences sociales et humaines. La collaboration est un élément important de cette socialisation: les disciplines dans lesquelles la collaboration doctorant-professeur est la plus élevée étant celles où les doctorants sont les plus intégrés dans la recherche. L'accès à des fonds de recherche influence également la participation des étudiants à des publications; les spécialités où les professeurs reçoivent davantage de fonds étant également celles où les étudiants sont plus susceptibles de publier. Bien que les documents auxquels ont contribués les doctorants soient pratiquement tous écrits en collaboration, ils sont moins souvent le résultat d'une collaboration internationale. Cette socialisation à la recherche est également liée de façon positive avec l'obtention du diplôme et la poursuite d'une carrière en recherche. Enfin, la troisième contribution de cette thèse est la mesure de l'importance, dans l'ensemble de la recherche québécoise, des résultats de recherche auxquels des étudiants de doctorat ont contribué. On y constate que, toutes disciplines confondues, les doctorants ont participé à 33% de la production scientifique de la province, un pourcentage considérablement plus élevé que celui des chercheurs en milieu hospitalier de la province combinés et plus de 5 fois supérieur à celui des chercheurs du gouvernement fédéral et du secteur industriel. En termes d'impact scientifique, les articles auxquels les doctorants ont contribué obtiennent un nombre moyen de citations significativement plus faible celui des autres papiers québécois auxquels ils n'ont pas contribué, même si le facteur d'impact moyen de revues dans lesquelles ils publient est, au contraire, significativement plus élevé. Cela suggère que les articles des doctorants souffrent de l'effet St-Matthieu, phénomène selon lequel la paternité d'une découverte sera plus aisément attribuée à un chercheur reconnu qu'à un autre l'étant moins. Dans l'ensemble, cette thèse interdisciplinaire fournit une mesure unique de la prévalence, du contexte et de l'effet de la socialisation à la recherche dans les programmes de doctorat ainsi qu'une une meilleure compréhension de l'importance des doctorants au sein de la communauté scientifique québécoise. Ces résultats devraient être d'un grand intérêt pour les administrateurs d'université, les conseils subventionnaires ainsi que les chercheurs dans le domaine des politiques scientifiques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yves Gingras</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jamshid Beheshti</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c07v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x185f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Library Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n3791"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lagrangian blocks on Eulerian mesh for shallow-water wave computations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tan, Lai Wai</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des vagues en eau peu profonde sont calculées en déplaçant des blocs de l'eau dans la direction du flux par la méthode Lagrangienne. La masse et l'élan (momentum) dans les blocs sont redistribués sur la maille Eulérienne fixée pour minimiser la déformation à chaque incrément de temps. Cette méthode des blocs Lagrangiens sur la maille Eulérienne (LBEM) est présentée comme alternative aux méthodes classiques de volume finie. La méthode est positif-profondeur définie et exempte de l'oscillation numérique. Un grand nombre de calculs numériques sont effectués pour évaluer l'exactitude et la stabilité informatique de la méthode de LBEM. Les résultats de six publications en journaux et de neuf articles dans des actes de la conférence sont compilés pour produire le total de huit chapitres et de quatre annexes de ceci thèse manuscrit-basée. Des calculs suivre la méthode de LBEM avaient été conduits pour les vagues en eau peu profonde en une dimension et en deux dimensions. Ceux-ci incluent les calculs des vagues stationnaires bidimensionnelles dans une cuvette parabolique, de la propagation des vagues chocs obliques dans un bassin carré, du banc des vagues solitaires et les vagues périodiques par-dessus de la levée, des vagues de coupure de barrage par-dessus de digue, et du cheminement d'inondation à travers une ville idéalisée. Ces problèmes informatiques avaient été choisis parce qu'ils ont les solutions analytiques ou les données expérimentales disponibles. Quand les solutions exactes sont disponibles, des raffinements de bloc sont conduits pour montrer la convergence des calculs de LBEM vers les solutions exactes. Les buts de ces calculs sont de montrer comment la méthode de LBEM (i) peut tracer l'interface sèche-et-mouillée de l'eau sans employer le traitement d'interface, (ii) peut capturer le vague choc sans utiliser n'importe quel limiteur de flux ou de pente, et (iii) peut calculer le flux intermittent tel que la vag</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Waves in shallow water are computed by moving blocks of water in the direction of the flow by the Lagrangian method. Mass and momentum in the blocks are re-distributed onto the fixed Eulerian mesh to minimize distortion at each increment of time. This Lagrangian blocks on Eulerian mesh (LBEM) method is introduced as an alternative to the classical finite volume methods. The method is positive-depth definite and free of numerical oscillation. A large number of numerical computations are carried out to evaluate the accuracy and the computational stability of the LBEM method. The results of 6 publications in journals and 9 papers in conference proceedings are compiled to produce the total of 8 chapters and 4 appendices of this manuscript-based thesis. Computations using the LBEM method have been conducted for one-dimensional and two-dimensional waves in shallow water. These include the computations of the two-dimensional standing waves in a parabolic bowl, the propagation of oblique shock waves in a square basin, the shoaling of solitary waves and periodic waves over levee, the dam-break waves over dike, and the flood routing through an idealized city. These computational problems have been selected because they have either analytical solutions or available experimental data for comparison with the computations. When exact solutions are available, block refinements are conducted to show the convergence of the LBEM computations toward the exact solutions. The goals of these computations are to show how the LBEM method (i) can track the dry-and-wet water interface without using interface treatment, (ii) can capture shock wave without using any flux or slope limiter, and (iii) can calculate the intermittent flow such as the wave overtopping the levee. Although the tracking of interfaces, the capture of shock waves and the calculation of intermittent overflow are difficult problems for the classical methods, the block advection can compute these problems with absolute s</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vincent H. Chu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zn82q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n3791</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nf16r"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>AspectMatlab: an aspect-oriented scientific programming language</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aslam, Toheed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There has been relatively little work done in the compiler research community for incorporating aspect-oriented features in scientific and dynamic programming languages. MATLAB is a dynamic scientific programming language that is commonly used by scientists because of its convenient and high-level syntax for arrays, the fact that type declarations are not required, and the availability of a rich set of application libraries. This thesis introduces a new aspect-oriented scientific language, AspectMatlab. AspectMatlab introduces key aspect-oriented features in a way that is both accessible to scientists and where the aspect-oriented features concentrate on array accesses and loops, the core computation elements in scientific programs. One of the main contributions of this thesis is to provide a compiler implementation of the AspectMatlab language. It is supported by a collection of scientific use cases, which portray the potential of the aspectorientation for scientific problems. Introducing aspects into a dynamic language such as MATLAB also provides some new challenges. In particular, it is difficult to statically determine precisely where patterns match, resulting in many dynamic checks in the woven code. The AspectMatlab compiler uses flow analyses to eliminate many of those dynamic checks. This thesis reports on the language design of AspectMatlab, the amc compiler implementation, and also provides an overview of the use cases that are specific to scientific programming. By providing clear extensions to an already popular language, AspectMatlab will make aspect-oriented programming accessible to a new group of programmers including scientists and engineers.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Relativement peu de travail a été accomplis dans le milieu de la recherche du compilateur pour l'intégration des caractéristiques orientées à l'aspect dans les domaines scientifique et dynamique des langages de programmation. Matlab est un langage de programmation scientifique dynamique qui est couramment utilisé par les scientifiques en raison de sa pratique et la syntaxe de qualité pour des tableaux ; du fait que les déclarations de type ne sont pas nécessaires, et de la disponibilité de vastes bibliothèques d'applications. Cette thèse introduit un nouvel aspect de langue de recherche scientifique : AspectMatlab. AspectMatlab introduit fonctionnalités d'aspect orientées d'une manière qui est à la fois accessible aux scientifiques et où les fonctionnalités d'aspect orientées se concentrent sur les accès réseau et des boucles, les éléments de calcul de base dans les programmes scientifiques. L'une des principales contributions de cette thèse est de fournir une implémentation du compilateur du langage AspectMatlab. Il est soutenu d'une collection de cas d'utilisation scientifique, qui montre le potentiel de l'orientation aspect pour des problèmes scientifiques. L'introduction des aspects dans un langage dynamique comme Matlab représente aussi quelques nouveaux défis. En particulier, il est difficile de déterminer statiquement où les modèles coïncident, résultant dans de nombreux contrôles dynamiques dans le code tissé. Le compilateur d'AspectMatlab utilise le flux d'analyses pour éliminer un grand nombre de ces contrôles dynamiques. Cette thèse signale la conception du language d'AspectMatlab et l'implementation du compilateur amc. Elle fournit également un aperçu de l'utilisation des cas qui sont spécifiques à la programmation scientifique. En fournissant des extensions claires avec un langage déjà populaire, AspectMatlab rendra la programmation orientée à l'aspect accessible à un nouveau groupe de programmeurs y compris des scientifiques et des ingénieurs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurie Hendren</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j378.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nf16r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930bx55d"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic analysis of consumer based attributes for rice in Benin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mhlanga, Saneliso</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les consommateurs sont de plus en plus conscients des caractéristiques des différents produits rencontrés sur le marché et choisissent des produits qui correspondent le mieux à leurs goûts et préférences. Les caractéristiques de la qualité du riz ont des implications importantes pour les producteurs, les chercheurs et les décideurs politiques. Cette étude analyse la relation entre le prix et les attributs des produits et des préférences des consommateurs pour le cas du riz au Bénin, en utilisant l'approche des prix hédoniques et la modélisation des choix discrets et les données sur les ménages. L'analyse est basée sur la nouvelle théorie du comportement du consommateur de Lancaster (1966), qui postule que les produits sont consommés plus pour les caractéristiques qu'ils possèdent que le produit lui-même et sont associées à des préférences/utilité des consommateurs. Les résultats indiquent que les facteurs les plus importants sont la taille du grain, l'arôme, les corps étrangers, la couleur, le temps de cuisson et la présence de brisures. Les résultats montrent également que les consommateurs sont en mesure de différencier le riz local du riz importé et arrivent à exprimer leurs préférences sur la qualité. Bien que le riz soit déficitaire au Bénin et que la recherche sur les variétés à haut rendement continue d'être privilégiée, l'amélioration de la qualité du riz basée sur les caractéristiques sus identifiées devrait permettre d'amoindrir la concurrence entre les riz importé et local. Les décideurs politiques doivent examiner les incitations réelles et les contraintes à l'amélioration de la qualité au niveau des exploitations rizicoles.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Consumers are becoming more aware of the quality attributes of different commodities found in the market and are choosing products that closely match their tastes and preferences. The consumer behavior model postulated by Lancaster (1966), says that products are consumed for the characteristics they possess, other than the product itself, and are associated with consumer preferences/utility. For example, in the case of rice, the quality characteristics (attributes) have important price based implications in terms of incentives for producers and consumers. This study empirically analyzes the relationship between price and product attributes towards consumer's choice for rice in Benin, using the hedonic pricing approach and discrete choice modeling at the household level. The results of econometric estimation indicate that consumers pay a premium for grain size, aroma, color, wholeness and cleanliness of grain and convenience attributes across the different regions studied. Consumers (rural and urban) prefer parboiled and imported rice over domestic rice and raw rice. Country of origin was found to influence rice preference indirectly through perceived quality. Socioeconomic factors are not important in consumer purchasing decisions. The results from this study suggest that both domestic and imported rice varieties have positive and negative implicit prices this emphasizes the importance of quality based attributes in future breeding programs to make domestic rice more competitive to imported rice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anwar Naseem</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k53r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bx55d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics - Agricultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816m99b"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors and kinetics affecting platelet doublet formation in shear flow</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manfredi, Luca</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Platelet aggregation helps injured blood vessels heal. Activation of platelets without the need to repair injuries can lead to conditions such as thrombosis, embolism and strokes. Experiments with platelets and human aggregation factors are characterized by complexity, considerable variance, short raw material shelf life and high reagent cost. A model system based on the characteristics of fibrinogen-mediated aggregation was created using polyethyleneimine and ethanolamine covalently bound in a two-step process to carboxylate-modified microspheres. The functionalized spheres form aggregates in the presence of negatively-charged nanocrystalline cellulose and appear to simulate the behavior of fibrinogen-platelet systems well. The system aggregates fastest when approximately half of the available PEI chains are occupied. Increasing ion concentration leads to rapid decline of collision efficiency and ligand flocculation. Static incubation of spheres with excess ligand showed that excessive available ligand is not sufficient protection from unwanted aggregation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'agrégation des plaquettes aide à la réparation des vaisseaux sanguins. L'activation sans qu'un vaisseau ne soit endommagé peut causer des thromboses, congestions ou embolismes. Les expériences utilisant des plaquettes et le facteur d'agrégation humain sont complexes, difficiles à planifier, donnent des résultats variables, ont des constituants qui se dégradent rapidement et un coût des matières élevé. Un système modèle basé sur l'agrégation grâce au fibrinogène a été crée avec de l'éthanolamine et du polyéthyleneimine (PEI) liés de façon covalente, en deux étapes, à des sphères ayant en surface des groupements carboxyliques. Les sphères ainsi fonctionnalisées créent des agrégats en présence de cellulose nanocristalline ayant une charge négative et semblent bien simuler un système plaquettes-fibrinogène. L'agrégation la plus rapide s'obtient quand il y a suffisamment de ligand pour occuper la moitié des chaines de PEI. Une augmentation de la force ionique cause la floculation du ligand et une diminution de l'efficacité d'agrégation. Les résultats d'incubations statiques montrent qu'un excès de ligand ne garantit pas une protection suffisante contre l'agrégation indésirable.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Theodorus G. Van de Ven</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Reghan James Hill</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t51t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816m99b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892b257"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role for the transcription factor AML1/Runx1 in Olfactory Ensheathing Cell development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bocking, Sarah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les mécanismes intrinsèques de regulation de transcription sont requis au développement de l'hétérogénéité cellulaire.  Le runt-related gène, Runx1, est impliqué dans le développement des neurons de l'épithélium olfactif.  Les buts de ce projet étaient de caractériser les cellules exprimant Runx1 dans les bulbes olfactifs (BO) et de déterminer la fonction de Runx1 dans ces cellules.  Les cellules exprimant Runx1 forment un domaine défini dans une des couches superficielle du BO et dans le BO accessoire et ont été identifiées comme étant des "olfactory ensheathing cells" appartenant à la couche intérieure du nerf olfactif (iOECs). Les analyses des iOECs qui n'expriment pas Runx1 suggère une perturbation de leur distribution.  L'expression ectopique de Runx1 dans les cultures primaires d'OECs a été associée à une réduction du nombre d'OECs proliferatives. Ces résultats démontrent que Runx1 est exprimé par les iOEC et modifie leur distribution par modulation négative de leur capacité proliférative.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cell-intrinsic mechanisms of transcriptional regulation are vital for developing cell heterogeneity.  The runt-related gene, Runx1, regulates the development of neurons of the mouse olfactory epithelium.  This project's aims were to characterize Runx1-expressing cells in the olfactory bulb and to elucidate the function of Runx1 in those cells.  Runx1-expression is restricted to a defined 'band' of cells in the superficial region of the main olfactory bulb (MOB) and to the accessory olfactory bulb.  Runx1-expressing cells  correspond to olfactory ensheathing cells of the inner olfactory nerve layer (iOECs).  Analysis of Runx1-deficient embryos revealed a perturbation of the topology of MOB OECs in which Runx1 is normally expressed.  Ectopic Runx1 expression in OEC primary cultures resulted in a decreased number of proliferating cells.  These results demonstrate that Runx1 is expressed in a subpopulation of OECs and suggest a role in OEC topology by negatively modulation of their proliferation capacity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stefano Stifani</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zn81f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b257</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d697g"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Towards protecting-group-free total synthesis cardiobutanolide in water</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Jun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A green stereoselective total synthesis of cardiobutanolide is proposed, starting from 1,6-dibromohexa-2,4-diene.  The synthetic route consists of only 7 steps in total, where each step is performed in aqueous media, and no protecting groups are used.  One of the key steps in the synthesis involves a combination of cyanide substitution and intramolecular Pinner reaction in one pot.  Studies dealing with reaction process monitoring, tests of catalysts,  and condition optimization are reported.  A "no purification" process for the sequence of the first four steps of the synthesis is described.  The possibility of achieving the synthetic goal is discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une synthèse totale verte du cardiobutanolide est proposée à partir de 1,6-dibromohexa-2,4-diène.  La voie de synthèse se compose de seulement 7 étapes au total, où chaque étape est réalisée en milieu aqueux, et aucun groupe protecteur n'est utilisé.  L'une des étapes clés dans la synthèse implique une combinaison de la substitution de cyanure et de la réaction intramoléculaire Pinner dans un pot.  Le suivi de la réaction, les tests de catalyseurs et l'optimisation des conditions sont décrits.  Un processus "sans purification" pour la séquence des quatre premières étapes de la synthèse est décrit.  La possibilité d'atteindre l'objectif de synthèse est discutée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chaojun Li</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>R. Bruce Lennox</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk51t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d697g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f157n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social modulation and communication of pain in the laboratory mouse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Langford, Dale</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La sensibilité à la douleur est grandement influencée par un certain nombre de facteurs et pourrait être évaluée plus adéquatement selon un cadre bio-psycho-social. Bien qu'un tel cadre ait été appliqué à l'étude et au traitement de la douleur chez l'humain, le concept de douleur en tant qu'expérience multidimensionnelle chez le rongeur a bénéficié de beaucoup moins d'attention. Pourtant, il est démontré que la douleur est significativement modulée par un ensemble de facteurs psychosociaux; l'identification de ces facteurs demeure donc importante, particulièrement lorsqu'on considère l'usage considérable des rongeurs dans le domaine de la recherche sur la douleur. D'après une étude réalisée précédemment par notre équipe, les souris qui cohabitent et qui sont témoins de leur souffrance mutuelle sont plus sensibles à la douleur que les souris soumises au test à la douleur de manière individuelle. Ce constat de l'influence de la cohabitation et de l'ordre selon lequel les souris sont testées, évoquant l'existence d'une communication sociale, a inspiré les recherches décrites dans cette thèse. Utilisant de nouveaux paradigmes expérimentaux, nos travaux décrivent les effets de l'environnement social immédiat sur la sensibilité à la douleur chez la souris de laboratoire et, inversement, les effets de cette douleur sur ses interactions sociales. Les conditions sociales varient en fonction du degré de familiarité  (c.-à-d. souris consoeurs contre souris étrangères), du sexe et du niveau de douleur de la congénère, tous des facteurs qui semblent moduler de manière significative la sensibilité à la douleur et le comportement social. J'expose ici que la modulation sociale de la douleur constitue une preuve d'empathie chez la souris de sorte que des souris qui cohabitent et qui voient leurs consoeurs être en proie à la douleur affichent une hypersensibilité significative lors des tests de nociception; une telle modulation dépend de signaux visuels. Je démontre également que le changement de perception de menace sociale parmi une paire de souris mâles étrangères affecte leur sensibilité à la douleur, entraînant les réponses dépendantes à la testostérone et induites par le stress que sont l'analgésie, obtenue lorsqu'on permet un contact physique complet ou l'hyperalgésie, obtenue lorsqu'un tel contact est limité. Par ailleurs, je montre que les femelles manifestent une approche sociale plus marquée envers une consoeur en proie à la douleur, que cette approche se voit aussi chez des souris dépourvues du gène codant pour le récepteur oxytocine et qu'un tel comportement pourrait avoir des propriétés analgésiques. Enfin, à la lumière de notre découverte initiale révélant que la douleur est communiquée de façon visuelle, je présente un système de codage inédit des expressions faciales de douleur chez la souris. En résumé, ces résultats suggèrent l'importance de tenir compte des facteurs psychosociaux dans l'analyse des facteurs pouvant influencer la sensibilité à la douleur chez la souris de laboratoire et proposent des modèles animaux potentiels pour l'étude de processus sociaux complexes comme l'empathie et la prosocialité. Par ailleurs, l'expression faciale constitue une mesure dépendante originale susceptible de décrire de manière plus complète l'expérience de douleur chez l'animal.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pain sensitivity is importantly affected by a number of factors, and may best be evaluated using a biopsychosocial framework.  Although such a framework has been applied to the study and treatment of pain in humans, the concept of pain as a multidimensional experience in rodent models has been given considerably less attention.  There is evidence, however, that pain is significantly modulated by a variety of psychosocial factors; therefore, identifying such factors is important, especially considering the extensive use of rodent subjects in pain research. A previous study performed in our laboratory described a within-cage order-of-testing effect that suggested the social communication of pain amongst mice, a finding that inspired the research described in this dissertation.  Using novel experimental paradigms, the research presented describes the effects of the immediate social environment on pain sensitivity in the laboratory mouse, as well as the converse, the effect of pain on social interactions among mice.  Social conditions in pain experiments vary with respect to familiarity (i.e., cagemate versus stranger), sex, and pain state of the conspecific and such factors appear to significantly modulate both pain sensitivity and social behaviour. Here I present social modulation of pain as evidence for empathy in mice, such that mice observing a cagemate in pain exhibit significant hypersensitivity to a noxious stimulus; such modulation is dependent on visual cues. I also show that varying perceived social threat by permitting or limiting full physical contact in stranger male dyads significantly modulates pain behaviour resulting in testosterone-dependent stress-induced analgesia or hyperalgesia, respectively.  Furthermore, I show that females display heightened social approach toward a cagemate displaying pain behaviour, that this social approach is also observed in mice lacking the oxytocin receptor gene, and that such behaviour may have analgesic properties.  Finally, in light of our initial finding that pain is visually communicated, I present a novel coding system for facial expressions of pain in the mouse. In summary, these findings suggest the importance of accounting for psychosocial factors affecting pain sensitivity in the laboratory mouse, and suggest potential animal models for such complex social processes as empathy and prosociality.  Furthermore, facial expression is a novel dependent measure of pain that may provide a more complete description of an animal's pain experience.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jeffrey Mogil</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk05b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f157n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Experimental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am613mx97b"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Correlates of treatment outcomes of multidrug-resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB): a systematic review and meta-analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Akçakir, Yasemin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: Multi-drug resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB) is a major threat to global tuberculosis control. While observational studies have reported outcomes of MDR-TB treatment, there have been no randomized controlled trials for MDR-TB treatment outcomes. We did a systematic review and meta-analysis to examine individual and study-level factors associated with treatment outcomes for MDR-TB in the observational studies. Method: We searched MEDLINE, EMBASE, BIOSIS, Web of Science from 1970 to July 2008, for publications in any language that described at least one treatment outcome among at least 25 patients with microbiologically proven MDR-TB. Data were extracted and where missing, principle investigators were contacted for more information. Rates of treatment outcomes were pooled using random effects. Subgroup analyses and meta-regression models were used to explore sources of heterogeneity. Results: After screening 2187 titles and abstracts, 265 articles were identified for retrieval and full-text review, and of these, 72 articles met the inclusion criteria and were included in the meta-analysis. Data analysis was performed using the 64 unique cohorts reported by the 72 articles. The cohorts were quite heterogeneous in characteristics and outcomes. The mean size of the cohorts was 124 patients (range 25 to 1011). The mean age of participants in the cohorts was 39 years with females accounting for about one third. The median length of treatment was 18 months, and the average number of drugs in the regimen was five. The overall pooled rates of cumulative success (successful patients who did not relapse) was 50%, of cumulative failure (failure plus relapse) was 17%, of death was 13% and of default was 18%. These pooled outcome rates, however, must be interpreted with caution because of heterogeneity across studies. Subgroup and meta-regression analyses helped identify several factors associated with improved outcomes. Factors significantly associated with increased treatment success are treatment duration longer than 20 months, use of more than three sensitive drugs, individualized regimen, use of fluoroquinolones, or use of second-line agents in general. Factors that were significantly associated with high treatment mortality were high prevalence of HIV co-infection and use of three or fewer drugs. Low default rate was most strongly associated with shorter treatments and directly observed therapy. Use of second-line drugs was significantly associated with higher default rate. Considerable heterogeneity remained even within subgroups. Conclusion: Outcomes of MDR-TB appear to vary considerably across studies and populations. The heterogeneity among studies poses a challenge in interpreting the results of this meta-analysis for clinical care, underscoring the need for future research to clarify optimal treatment of MDR-TB.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte : La tuberculose multi-résistante (TB-MR) est une menace importante pour le contrôle de la tuberculose dans le monde. Tandis que les études d'observation ont rapporté des résultats de traitements de TB-MR, il n'y a eu aucune étude randomisée. Nous avons fait une revue systématique de la littérature et une méta-analyse afin d'examiner les facteurs liés aux résultats de traitement pour TB-MR, au niveau de l'individu et de l'étude, dans les études d'observation. Méthode : Nous avons cherché à l'aide de  MEDLINE, EMBASE, BIOS, et Web of Science, les publications dans toutes les langues qui décrivent au moins un résultat de traitement parmi au moins 25 patients atteints de TB-MR microbiologiquement prouvée, de 1970 à juillet 2008. Les données ont été extraites et les taux de résultats de traitement ont été mis en commun en utilisant le modèle d'effet au hasard random effect. Des analyses de sous-groupes et des modèles de méta régression ont été employés pour explorer les sources d'hétérogénéité. Résultats : Après avoir répertorié2187 titres et résumés d'articles, 265 articles ont été identifiés et sélectionnées afin de récupérer le texte intégral pour les réviser; 72 de ces articles ont répondu aux critères d'inclusion et ont été inclus dans la méta analyse. L'analyse de données a été exécutée en utilisant les 64 cohortes uniques rapportées par les 72 articles. Les cohortes étaient hétérogènes dans leurs caractéristiques et leurs résultats. La taille moyenne des cohortes était de 124 patients (25 à 1011). L'âge moyen des participants était de 39 ans et les femmes représentaient environ le tiers des participants. La longueur médiane du traitement était de 18 mois et les patients recevaient en moyenne cinq médicaments différents. Le taux global de succès cumulatif (patients guéris qui n'ont pas fait de rechute) était de 50%, d'échec cumulatif (échec plus rechute), 17%, de mort, 13% et d'abandon de traitement, 18%. Toutefois, ces taux doivent être interprétés avec prudence en raison de l'hétérogénéité à travers des études. Avec des analyses de sous-groupes et de méta régression plusieurs facteurs associées à succès de traitement ont été identifier, comme - durée de traitement plus que 20 mois, utilisation de 3 médicaments ou plus, traitement individualise, ou l'utilisation de médicaments de secondes lignes. Facteurs associe avec la mortalité étaient haut prévalence de VIH et utilisation de 3 médicaments ou moins. Un taux élevé de non-adherence etait associe avec traitement plus longue, auto administration de médicaments, et l'utilisation de médicaments de seconde ligne. Une importante hétérogénéité est demeurée même dans les sous-groupes. Conclusion : Les résultats de TB-MR semblent varier considérablement selon  les études et les populations. L'hétérogénéité parmi les études pose un défi dans l'interprétation des résultats de cette méta analyse, soulignant le besoin d'autre recherche afin d'évaluer le traitement optimal pour TB-MR.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madhukar Pai</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Richard Ian Menzies</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd12h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mx97b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asf268559t"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Distributed information fusion in sensor networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oreshkin, Boris</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse aborde le problème de la conception et l'analyse d'algorithmes distribuès servant à l'agrégation efficace et la fusion de l'information dans des reséaux capteurs sans fil. Ces algorithmes distribuès servent à addresser un bon nombre d'inconvénients qu'ont les approches de fusion centralisée telles que le point de défaillance unique, les protocoles de routage complexe, la consommation de puissance inégale dans les noeuds de capteurs, l'utilisation inefficace des voies de transmission sans-fil et l'extensibilité limitée. Ces inconvénients de l'approche centralisée ont comme effet de réduire la durée de vie du reséau, la robustesse des noeuds face aux défaillances et la capacité du réseau.  Les algorithmes distribuès atténuent ces problèmes en utilisant des simples protocoles de messageries entre les noeuds ainsi que du traitement d'information localisé. Toutefois, pour ces algorithmes, les pertes de précision et/ou de temps nécessaire pour effectuer une tâche peuvent être importantes. C'est pourquoi la conception et l'analyse d'algorithmes distribuès rapide et précis est importante. Dans cette thèse, deux problèmes spécifiques associés à l'analyse et le conception de tels algorithms sont abordés. En ce qui concerne l'algorithme de consensus sur la moyenne distribuè, une méthode d'accélération fondé sur la mémoire est proposée et sa convergence analysée. Pour les deux paramètres importants de cette méthodologie, les valeurs optimales pour le système sont déterminées et l'amélioration par rapport à l'algorithme de consensus de base est caractérisée de façon théorique.  Cette caractérisation correspond aux resultants d'expériences numériques et révèlent des gains importants et extensibles. Le régime distribuè d'initialisation en ligne est conçu.  Des expériences numériques révèlevent la faisabilité du régime d'initilisation proposé ainsi qu'un rendement supérieur à plusieurs approches existantes. Pour la méthodologie de traitement de signaux et d'information collaborative, un certain nombre de garanties théoriques de performance sont obtenues.  Ce cadre de travail consiste à activer seulement une grappe de capteurs sans fil pour effectuer les tâches de pistage d'objet au niveau deu chef de groupe en utilisant un filtre particulaire.  La grappe optimale est déterminée à chaque intervale de temps et le transfert du titre de chef de groupe est réalisé au besoin.  Pour réduire les coûts de communication, seulement une approximation de la distribution du filtre est envoyé pendant le transfert de responsabilités ce qui entraîne des erreurs supplémentaires.  Les garanties de performance uniformes dans le temps tenant compte de ces erreurs supplémentaires sont obtenues dans deux contextes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses the problem of design and analysis of distributed in-network signal processing algorithms for effcient aggregation and fusion of information in wireless sensor networks. The distributed in-network signal processing algorithms alleviate a number of drawbacks of the centralized fusion approach. The single point of failure, complex routing protocols, uneven power consumption in sensor nodes, ineffcient wireless channel utilization, and poor scalability are among these drawbacks. These drawbacks of the centralized approach lead to reduced network lifetime, poor robustness to node failures, and reduced network capacity. The distributed algorithms alleviate these issues by using simple pairwise message exchange protocols and localized in-network processing. However, for such algorithms accuracy losses and/or time required to complete a particular fusion task may be significant. The design and analysis of fast and accurate distributed algorithms with guaranteed performance characteristics is thus important. In this thesis two specific problems associated with the analysis and design of such distributed algorithms are addressed. For the distributed average consensus algorithm a memory based acceleration methodology is proposed. The convergence of the proposed methodology is investigated. For the two important settings of this methodology, optimal values of system parameters are determined and improvement with respect to the standard distributed average consensus algorithm is theoretically characterized. The theoretical improvement characterization matches well with the results of numerical experiments revealing significant and well scaling gain. The practical distributed on-line initialization scheme is devised. Numerical experiments reveal the feasibility of the proposed initialization scheme and superior performance of the proposed methodology with respect to several existing acceleration approaches. For the collaborative signal and information processing methodology a number of theoretical performance guarantees is obtained. The collaborative signal and information processing framework consists in activating only a cluster of wireless sensors to perform target tracking task in the cluster head using particle filter. The optimal cluster is determined at every time instant and cluster head hand-off is performed if necessary. To reduce communication costs only an approximation of the filtering distribution is sent during hand-off resulting in additional approximation errors. The time uniform performance guarantees accounting for the additional errors are obtained in two settings: the subsample approximation and the parametric mixture approximation hand-off.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mark Coates</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt18g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268559t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36tx93f"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of demand uncertainty on strategic gaming in the merit-order electricity pool market</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frem, Bassam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans le marché d'électricité mutuel, gouverné par l'ordre de mérite, les compagnies de production (Gencos) jouent avec leurs coûts différentiels offerts pour gagner une plus grande part du marché ainsi qu'un profit plus élevé, tout en  satisfaisant la demande des consommateurs. Toutefois, lorsque la demande est considérée comme une variable aléatoire au lieu d'une constante définie, les stratégies de jeu des Gencos deviennent beaucoup plus difficiles à gérer. Après une introduction sur les marchés d'électricité et la théorie des jeux, nous étudions les effets de l'incertitude de la demande sur les stratégies de jeu en deux parties : (1) la demande est traitée comme une variable aléatoire discrète (2) la demande  est traitée comme une variable aléatoire continue. Dans la première partie nous proposons un algorithme, l'algorithme de la stratégie stochastique discrète (DSS) qui nous donne un ensemble d'offres stratégiques visant de meilleurs profits pour les Gencos. Les offres calculées  par l'algorithme DSS ont été testées et comparées aux offres de l'algorithme d'équilibre Nash (NE) non-stochastique, basé sur la demande prévue. Utilisant les résultats de cette comparaison où on évalue l'espérance mathématique des profits des Gencos, nous avons conclu que la stratégie DSS donne un meilleur rendement stochastique que celle du NE non-stochastique Dans la deuxième partie de l'étude nous avons présenté trois stratégies de jeu : (1) Le NE non-stochastique (2) Sans-Risque (3) Avec-Risque. Les stratégies ont été testées et leurs performances vis-à-vis des profits des Gencos furent comparées utilisant deux outils d'évaluation : (a) Espérance mathématique et écart-type (b) Fonction de répartition inverse. Nous avons conclus que, malgré leurs performances plus élevées vis-à-vis des profits aves les conjectures correctes, les stratégies Avec-Risque sont très sensibles aux erreurs dans les conjectures à propos des décisions de jeu des concurrents. De ce fait,  même avec une performance moins favorable, la stratégie Sans-Risque fut considérée préférable.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In a merit-order electricity pool market, generating companies (Gencos) game with their offered incremental cost to meet the electricity demand and earn bigger market shares and higher profits. However when the demand is treated as a random variable instead of as a known constant, these Genco gaming strategies become more complex. After a brief introduction of electricity markets and gaming, the effects of demand uncertainty on strategic gaming are studied in two parts: (1) Demand modelled as a discrete random variable (2) Demand modelled as a continuous random variable. In the first part, we proposed an algorithm, the discrete stochastic strategy (DSS) algorithm that generates a strategic set of offers from the perspective of the Gencos' profits. The DSS offers were tested and compared to the deterministic Nash equilibrium (NE) offers based on the predicted demand. This comparison, based on the expected Genco profits, showed the DSS to be a better strategy in a probabilistic sense than the deterministic NE. In the second part, we presented three gaming strategies: (1) Deterministic NE (2) No-Risk (3) Risk-Taking. The strategies were then tested and their profit performances were compared using two assessment tools: (a) Expected value and standard deviation (b) Inverse cumulative distribution. We concluded that despite yielding higher profit performance under the right conjectures, Risk-Taking strategies are very sensitive to incorrect conjectures on the competitors' gaming decisions. As such, despite its lower profit performance, the No-Risk strategy was deemed preferable.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Francisco D. Galiana</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw714.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tx93f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vr36x"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of multiple interviews on children's verbal expressive behavior of true and fabricated events</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saykaly, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le comportement expressif des enfants donnant des rapports vrais et fabriqués au cours de nombreuses entrevues a été examiné. Soixante-dix-huit enfants d'âge scolaire (entre 4 et 11 ans) ont joué un jeu avec une assistante de recherche (AR) au cours de trois jours consécutifs. Les enfants ont ensuite été entraînés par leurs parents à donner un conte rendu vrais et fabriqués au sujet de leur interaction avec  la AR. Par la suite, les enfants ont été interrogés durant trois jours consécutifs au sujet des événements qui ont eu lieu une semaine auparavant. Suite aux interrogations, les discours on été transcrits et le comportement expressif des enfants analysées. Comparable à la littérature précédente, l'étude courante a trouvé que les rapports vrais donnés au cour de la première entrevue possèdent moins de processus cognitifs, moins de marqueurs temporal et plus de corrections spontanées que les rapports fabriqués. Contrairement aux prédictions, les rapports vrais possèdent moins d'admissions de doute que les rapports fabriqués, et démontrent aucune différence en termes d'autoréférences et verbosité. Cependant, ces différences n'étaient plus signifiantes lors due deuxième et troisième entrevue.  Les tendances développementales indiquent que les plus jeunes enfants ont le plus de difficultés à donner un discours non-contradictoire, indépendamment de la véracité et de l'entrevue. L'uniformité entre les rapports vrais et fabriqués à travers les entrevues sera également discutée. Les résultats suggèrent que les rapports vrais et fabriqués des enfants sont plus difficiles de détecter au cours d'entrevues multiples. Les implications psycho-légales et psychopédagogiques des résultats seront discutées.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Verbal expressive behaviour of children giving true and fabricated reports over multiple interviews was examined. Seventy-eight elementary aged children between the ages of 4 and 11 years played a game with a research assistant (RA) over three consecutive days. Children were then coached by their parents to state to give true and fabricated reports about their interaction with the RA.  Children were then interviewed over three consecutive days about events which transpired one week earlier. Transcripts of children's verbal expressive behaviour were analyzed for verbal cues to deception and consistency of reports over multiple interviews.  Consistent with previous literature, the current study found that in the first interview children's true reports had fewer cognitive processes, fewer temporal markers and more self corrections than fabricated reports. Contrary to the predictions, true reports had fewer admissions of lack of knowledge than fabricated reports, and there were no differences in terms of self-references and verbosity. However, these differences were no longer significant in Interview 2 and Interview 3. Developmental trends indicate that the youngest children had the most difficulties in reporting consistent statements, regardless of veracity and interview. Consistency between true and fabricated reports across interviews will also be discussed.  The results suggest that children's true and fabricated reports are harder to detect over multiple interviews.  The psycho-legal and psycho-educational implications of the above findings are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Victoria Talwar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t232v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vr36x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nf21m"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Walking volume, abdominal obesity, and selected cardiovascular risk factors in type 2 diabetes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manjoo, Priya Sonya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Objectifs: Pour déterminer si les associations de la marche avec des facteurs de risque cardio-vasculaires choisis [CVRFs : glycemia, dyslipidemia, hypertension (BP)] sont atténués par l'obésité abdominale (OA) dans les patients avec DM2. Méthodes: 94 femmes et 106 hommes avec DM2 ont été évalués (juin 2006-juin 2008) pour marcher (pedometer de 2 semaines); AO (taille à rapport de hanche, WHR ; circonférence de taille) ; glycemia (hémoglobine A1C, HbA1C) ; thérapie de dyslipidemia ; et tension artérielle (BP). Des associations entre marcher et CVRFs ont été examinées utilisant la régression multivariable, avec et sans l'ajustement pour l'ao et les confounders potentiels. fr Résultats: Un incrément quotidien de l'étape 1000 chez les femmes a été associé à un 0.13% (ci de 95% -0.25, -0.01) HbA1c inférieur, un 0.22 (ci de 95% : 0.63, 1.00) chances de la thérapie de dyslipidemia, -2.86 mmHg (ci de 95% : -4.32,) différence -1.40 dans systolique et -1.66 mmHg (ci de 95% : - 2.49,) différence -0.82 à BP diastolique. Avec l'ajustement pour l'ao, seulement les associations avec BP ont maintenu la signification. Le même incrément d'étape chez les hommes a été associé à un 0.10% (ci de 95% : -0.22, -0.02) HbA1c inférieurs et -0.77 une différence du millimètre hectogrammes à BP diastolique (ci de 95% : -1.55, 0.00). L'ajustement pour l'ao n'a pas effectué ces associations. fr Discussion: Un plus grand arrangement du rôle des changements de l'ao peut fournir la perspicacité dans des différences de sexe dans le risque de CVD dans DM2.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Objectives: To determine whether the associations of walking with selected cardiovascular risk factors [CVRFs: glycemia, dyslipidemia, high blood pressure (BP)] are mediated by abdominal obesity (AO) in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM2). Methods:  94 women and 106 men with DM2 were assessed (June 2006-June 2008) for walking (2 weeks pedometer); AO (waist to hip ratio, WHR; waist circumference); glycemia (hemoglobin A1C, HbA1C); dyslipidemia therapy; and blood pressure (BP). Associations between walking and CVRFs were examined using multivariate regression, with and without adjustment for AO  and potential confounders. Results:  A 1000 daily step increment in women was associated with a 0.13% (95% CI -0.25, -0.01) lower HbA1c, a 0.22 (95% CI: 0.63, 1.00) odds of dyslipidemia therapy, a -2.86 mmHg (95% CI: -4.32, -1.40) difference in systolic and a -1.66 mmHg (95% CI:-2.49, -0.82) difference in diastolic BP. With adjustment for AO, only associations with BP retained significance. The same step increment in men was associated with a 0.10% (95% CI: -0.22, -0.02) lower HbA1c and a -0.77 mm Hg difference in diastolic BP (95% CI: -1.55, 0.00). Adjustment for AO did not impact these associations. Discussion:  Greater understanding of the role of changes in AO may provide insight into sex differences in CVD risk in DM2.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kaberi Dasgupta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x65x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nf21m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rt77t"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A rapid, object-oriented approach to mapping and classifying wetlands at a regional scale in the central Congo river basin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bunker, Gregory</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tropical floodplain wetlands are important from various perspectives, including hydrology, biogeochemistry and conservation, while facing imminent threats aggravated by insufficient baseline information.  Recent advances in remote sensing and image analysis can address this problem.  The integration of radar imagery (L-HH) with topographic datasets (elevation, slope and waterbodies) in an object-oriented analysis was tested as a method of rapid wetland mapping in the Equateur Province, Democratic Republic of Congo.  Three classification schemes at different aggregation levels were produced to test thematic detail against accuracy.  The highest level classifications include upland, lake, river, flooded forest, nonflooded forest, shrub and herbaceous vegetation.  The maps range from 47% accuracy for the 7-class wetland map to 78% accuracy for the 3-class floodplain map compared to a reference map (FAO Africover).  The method shows promise for developing inventories and monitoring programs to support wetland management in the central Congo River basin and other tropical riverine environments.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les marécages tropicaux de zone inondable sont importants de diverses perspectives, incluant l'hydrologie, la biogéochimie et la conservation, tout en faisant face à des menaces imminentes aggravées par l'information insuffisante de ligne de base. Les avances récentes dans la télédétection et l'analyse d'image peuvent aborder ce problème. L'intégration des mosaïques de radar (L-HH) avec des ensembles de données topographiques (altitude, pente et cours d'eau) dans une analyse "object-oriented" a été examinée comme méthode de cartographie rapide pour les marécages dans la province d'Equateur, République Démocratique du Congo. Trois arrangements de classification à différents niveaux d'agrégation ont été produits pour examiner le détail thématique contre l'exactitude. Les classifications les plus detaillées incluent le terrain haute, le lac, le fleuve, la forêt inondée, la forêt non-inondée, l'arbuste et la végétation herbacée. Les cartes s'étendent de l'exactitude de 47% pour la carte de 7 classes à l'exactitude de 78% pour la carte de 3 classes comparée à une carte de référence (FAO Africover). La méthode se montre bien pour des inventaires et des programmes de surveillance qui soutiennent la gestion de marécage dans le bassin fluvial central du Congo et d'autres environnements riverains tropicaux.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bernhard Lehner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m456b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rt77t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415p984x"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Faith seeking understanding: Thomas Merton's interest in Karl Barth</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Scruggs, Ryan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude analyse l'intérêt de Thomas Merton pour Karl Barth, un intérêt centré sur deux figures importantes, bien que parfois incomprises, présentes dans la théologie de Barth : Anselme et Mozart. Merton voit chez Barth non pas une théologie qu'il approuve entièrement, mais plutôt une méthode théologique qu'il considère de la plus haute importance. Cette méthode est appelée 'la foi en quête de compréhension.' Merton et Barth débutent tous deux avec le Christ dans leur quête de compréhension: Barth, avec le Christ en tant que Logos de Dieu, et Merton, avec le Christ en tant que Sagesse de Dieu. Le mouvement de la révélation à la compréhension théologique et à l'expérience religieuse procure à Merton la liberté de s'ouvrir religieusement à l'autre, tout en évitant autant l'apologétique que le syncrétisme.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This study evaluates Thomas Merton's interest in Karl Barth, an interest centered on two important, though sometimes misunderstood, figures in Barth's theology: Anselm and Mozart. Merton finds in Barth not a theology that he can entirely agree with, but a theological method he considers primary. This method is called 'faith seeking understanding.' Both Barth and Merton begin with Christ in their search for understanding: Barth, in the Logos of God and Merton, in the Sophia of God. The movement from revelation to theological understanding and religious experience provides Merton the freedom to engage his religious other while avoiding both apologetics and syncretism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maurice Boutin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b282.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415p984x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion, Philosophy of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w774r"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fabrication and analysis of As2Se3 based microtapers and couplers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baker, Chams</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents the results of research on the fabrication and characterization of As2Se3 microtapers and couplers. Microtaper waveguide geometry has been chosen because it enhances the nonlinear phase-shift experienced by the guided waves. Such microtapers find applications as highly nonlinear media in optical signal processing devices. As an extension of the microtaper fabrication, couplers have been fabricated from the combination of microtapers. Finally, hybrid As2Se3-polysulfone tapered structures have been developed for the fabrication of mechanically robust microtapers and nonlinear couplers with sub-Watt switching threshold powers.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire présente le résultat de recherches sur la fabrication et la caractérisation de microfils et de coupleurs à base de As2Se3. La géométrie de guide d'onde en microfil a été préférée à cause de sa capacité à accroître le déphasage non-linéaire des ondes guidées. De tels microfils sont utilisés comme élément non-linéaire dans le dispositifs de traitement de signal optique. Pour leur part, les coupleurs ont été fabriqués à partir de la combinaison de microfils. Finalement, des structures hybrides à base de As2Se3 et polysulfone ont été développées pour la fabrication de microfils et de coupleurs non-linéaires mécaniquement robustes et avec un seuil de puissance d'opération inférieur au Watt.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Martin Rochette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k300z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w774r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>