<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cs60t"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of a locomotor test to evaluate motor performance in the adult rat : young-, middle- and old-age</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Partidas, Martha Helena</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The locomotor behavior of adult rats (n = 48) at different age periods was determined on five inclined plexiglass runways of different widths (24, 18, 12, 6 and 3 mm). Differences in the number (old  middle-age $&gt;$ young) were observed between the three age groups. For a subset of animals (n = 17), age-related changes were examined in the organization of the morphological properties of horseradish peroxidase (HRP)-labelled motoneurons in a representative hindlimb motoneuron pool. Data suggests that the loss of large motoneurons and soma atrophy play a role (p $&lt;$ 0.01) in the organization of the medial gastrocnemius (MG) motoneuron pool in aged animals. The relationship between the composite motor performance score and the number of MG alpha motoneurons for individual animals reflected the continuum from young to old.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Noven, Sharyn Vanden</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h162n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs60t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw62v"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamics and prospects of non-farm employment in the coastal regions of Bangladesh</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mathbor, Golam Mohammed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The coast of Bangladesh, comprising the complex delta of the Ganges-Brahmaputra-Meghna river system has immense resources for development. In the concept of present development efforts, this zone is among the most neglected in Bangladesh. It is very often affected by natural calamities and the situation is further aggravated by some man-made hazards, which cause heavy casualties in human lives, cattle, in reducing the size of the coastal areas and in severe damage of properties worth billions of dollars. This thesis envisages looking into the particular issue of non-farm employment. This is more important in an economy in which the land-person ratio is continuously on the decrease and dissemination of intensive crop culture has limitations. This study is exploratory in nature and uses both quantitative and qualitative methods, employing survey interviews for 80 households, 20 key informant interviews and a case study on an organization in order to assess the dynamics and prospects of non-farm employment in the coastal regions of Bangladesh. Findings of the study indicate that practically all of the non-farm field of the entire coastal belt is not yet a government priority. As such, there is need for some persuasive work in formulating some policies to develop sustainable harvests from the abundant maritime resources of the area. This will create provision for non-farm employment as well as producing a vast quantity of exportable commodities for the national well-being. It is expected that it will benefit the people of the area in particular and the entire country in general.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nichols, Barbara</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365733b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw62v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Marine resources -- Bangladesh</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coastal zone management -- Bangladesh</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bangladesh -- Economic conditions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214r26h"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tourette's Syndrome from a social work perspective : an exploratory study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rybak, Celina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tourette's syndrome (TS) is a chronic movement disorder characterized by motor and vocal tics. This report looks at TS through the eyes of three families and two adults diagnosed with the syndrome. The social and psychological reactions and adjustment to the disorder are examined. Three approaches were used to explore the issues: a literature review; field notes and unstructured biographical interviews. Social and psychological reactions include: depression, withdrawal and suicidal ideation. Unresponsiveness on the part of the health care and social service systems contributed to feelings of anger, powerlessness, guilt and shame. The families' and individuals' ability to lobby for services was an important factor in enhancing adjustment. TS is a multi-faceted disorder; it serves as a paradigm for issues and problems that are best served by a multi-disciplinary approach. Services must be coordinated; a case management approach would facilitate efficient coordination and delivery of services.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stainton, Tim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt11h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r26h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tourette syndrome -- Patients -- Services for</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tourette syndrome -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tourette syndrome in children -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537311x"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Perceptions of becoming a nursing home resident : a qualitative study of the impact on identity and self-esteem</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parfitt, Mary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a study about the experience of becoming a nursing home resident as it affects the identity and self-esteem of very old persons. In a qualitative study with six female residents of an English-speaking Centre d'Acceuil in Montreal, themes are explored in the light of theory about the effects of institutionalization. Consideration is given to the dynamics of relationships with family, friends, peers and staff. Loss of autonomy is singled out as the factor having the most impact on the individuals in the study. As life draws to a close, each of the women interviewed struggles in her own way with conflict between the value of self-determination and the value of acceptance of dependence on others. The author suggests that the attempt to reconcile these two values may be a "life-task" for very old institutionalized persons. Questions are raised at the level of planning for institutional policy and a direction is indicated for the education of social workers planning to work with an elderly clientele.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stainton, Timothy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg89q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537311x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nursing home patients -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older women -- Nursing home care -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz687"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>CRS regulations and the GATS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zur Hausen, Henning</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the course of the last decade, computer reservation systems have become the prime channel for the distribution of air transport services. While their benefits for consumers, travel agents and airlines are undisputed, CRS have caused considerable legal problems in both the CRS and the airline industries. As self-regulation did not prove to be effective, different authorities have issued instruments addressing the relevant issues. After a brief presentation of the CRS industry and of the main legal problems, the first part of this thesis will give a detailed analysis of three major CRS regulations: The Regulations on Carrier-Owned Computer Reservation Systems, issued by the United States Department of Transportation, the EEC Council Regulation on a code of conduct for computerized reservation systems and the Code of Conduct for the Regulation and Operation of Computer Reservation Systems, adopted by ICAO. The second part will deal with the General Agreement on Trade in Services, which forms part of the GATT and which will be applicable to CRS services. General remarks about services will be followed by an analysis of the GATS, emphasizing provisions which could be of relevance for the operation of CRS. The concluding third part of the thesis will comment on the impact of GATS on the CRS industry, on its suitability as a world-wide regime for the operation of CRS and on the relationship between GATS and ICAO.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm357.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz687</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fq978"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The legal implications of low earth orbit (LEO) : constellations of communication satellites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yug, Elliott D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores some of the legal implications of communication satellite constellations in Low Earth Orbit (LEO), specifically the satellite systems that plan to provide Personal Communication Services (PCS). The thesis begins with a brief history of long distance communications and their evolution from wire systems to space-based technology; the types of service providers and users are also indicated. Next, some of the perceived shortcomings of the current telecommunications technology are examined and suggestions are made as to how they could be overcome by LEO-based PCS satellites. The legal requirements, national and international, that need to be met to secure interference-free operation of these satellites and services are explored. Also some of the risks and potential liability producing events are discussed, as well as ways of dealing with them. The thesis concludes that LEO-based communication satellite constellations are feasible, both technically and legally, provided that the relevant legal and technical issues are resolved before the deployment of these systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vlasic, Ivan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg56p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq978</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Information Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj1394080"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the issues involved in the legal regulation of human embryo research and related practices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wise, Morag Barbara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The development of artificially assisted reproduction has challenged some of the fundamental values which underlie the legal systems of the Western world. This thesis attempts first to put in context the continuing debate over the use of early human embryos in scientific research by considering the nature of the medical technology involved. In the second section, several aspects of the controversy over embryo research are then examined. Attempts to classify the human embryo and endow it with a particular moral or legal status are considered with a view to recommending an approach which legislators could adopt in regulating research on embryonic life. Thirdly the nature and scope of some of the attempts to regulate embryo research which have already been made are examined to test the approach suggested in the second section. This thesis covers material up to and including September 1983. No account has been taken of any developments in policy or legislation which have occurred since then.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Somerville, M. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289m06p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1394080</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vj84f"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anti-avoidance techniques : Canada and the Netherlands :</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rooijen, Ada van</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Canada and the Netherlands have developed different anti-avoidance techniques. On 13 September 1987, a new general anti-avoidance rule came into effect in Canada. The scope of application of this new rule remains uncertain. Some writers have suggested that the rule incorporates the business purpose test and the step transaction doctrine, while others have contended that section 245 is a version of the abuse of rights doctrine. After a comparative analysis of Canadian and Dutch anti-avoidance techniques, it is suggested that section 245 is a Canadian version of the Dutch judicial doctrine of fraus legis. The two conditions for the application of both instruments, namely that the transaction was entered into with the motive or purpose to avoid tax, and that the avoidance transaction offends the object and spirit of the Act, are in fact the same.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc03q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj84f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km73p"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Limitation of liability in international air transport</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thachet, John Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Warsaw Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules Relating to International Carriage by Air was adopted when aviation was in its developing stage. In order to protect this infant industry, the Convention limited the liability of the air carrier in international air transportation to certain specified amounts. As time went by the Warsaw Convention was amended by several instruments. The end result is that there are several instruments to regulate the liability of air carriers engaged in international air transportation and most of these instruments provide only limited recovery to passengers. Often, passengers try to break the limits prescribed by the Convention alleging willful misconduct on the part of the carrier, his servants or agents or by bringing suits against potentially liable third parties like the aircraft manufacturer or by proving that the documents of carriage were faulty. In the mean time, Italy and Japan took matters into their own hands and raised the limits unilaterally. While Italy raised the limits to 100,000 SDR, Japan waived entirely the Warsaw systems limits of liability. In this thesis, the development of air law till the adoption of the Warsaw Convention and the various amendments carried out to the Convention over the years will be discussed in the first two chapters. The third chapter mainly concentrates on the rationales for ratifying the Guatemala City Protocol through Montreal Protocol No. 3. While arriving at a conclusion as to why the Montreal Protocols have to be ratified for the successful unification of air carriers liability in international air transport, the Italian and Japanese "solutions" will be evaluated and conclude why those solutions are to be rejected outright. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d868f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km73p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sz00b"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The supranational challenge : federal and decentralized unitary states within the European Union</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shapiro, Evan Joel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nation states, be they federal or unitary, monist or dualist, must incorporate the norms and precepts of international law into their domestic legal orders and implement its requirements. The constitutional or equivalent courts of Germany, Belgium, Italy and Spain have provided solutions to these and related problems. While some of the topic states have undergone decentralizing or federalizing reforms simultaneous with their involvement in the European Communities and Union, all have experienced centralizing pressures, some of which involve negative implications for democratic accountability. Overall, their constitutional and governmental systems have tended to converge with enhanced contact and cooperation. They also influence and are in turn influenced by European institutions and structures, which include most recently expanded Parliamentary powers and a new Committee of the Regions representative of subnational interests and aspirations at the supranational level. How these related, complementary and at times antagonistic spheres will continue to evolve and react in the future may involve Europe's greatest challenge.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DeNestral, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903199j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz00b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A73666672d"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>HIV : public health, criminal law and the process of policy development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Patterson, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper examines briefly the changing conceptions of HIV disease in the Canadian context. Historical reference is made to the increase in state involvement in the field of public health, and to the shift from an emphasis on environmental and behavioural factors to infectious agents as the causes of disease. The role of the state in the prevention of HIV disease is then discussed, with reference to human rights and changing perceptions of the role of the law. The paper then considers a specific issue: the criminal law and the sexual transmission of the virus. The Canadian legislation and case law is compared with the Australian response. It is suggested that the early focus on HIV legal policy in Australia led to a general agreement that the criminal law had a very limited contribution to make in this regard. The paper concludes with comments on the process of legal policy development, rather than specific recommendations for law reform.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Toope, Stephen J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv926.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666672d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canadian Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bk26j"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Civil Party in criminal trials : a comparative study-guide to the criminal procedure harmonization process in Cameroon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ntoko Ngome, Emmanuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study deals with the French action civile, whereby the victim of a criminal offence may participate, as civil party, in the criminal proceedings brought against the offender, and there claim reparation from such offender if he can prove that he has suffered loss or damage directly resulting from the offence. This procedure differs from what obtains in the common-law jurisdictions, where a crime victim's participation in the criminal trial is limited to being a witness for the prosecution, and can only bring an action for damages before the civil courts. In addition to examining the requirements for the admissibility of the action civile, the study elicits certain procedural and evidentiary issues, such as the burden and standard of proof, the Civilian approach to tortious liability, res judicata, the problem of judicial interpretation of code provisions by a common-law jurisdiction and the respective merits that justify the civil party action. These issues occasionally provide the background for a critical and comparative analysis in relation to common-law procedural practice. The study also seeks to demonstrate the need for greater victim participation in the criminal process and, thereby, attempts to defeat the generally-held view in common-law jurisdictions that the victim's place is the witness box. In this way, it may be a helpful source of reference for a common-law - Civil law mixed system, like Cameroon's, that is going through a legal harmonisation process, and other common-law jurisdictions that may want to adopt the civil party procedure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Healy, Patrick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc611.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk26j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology, Criminology and Penology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zd21n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>European Union external competence and external relations in air transport</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mencik von Zebinsky, A. A. (Aloïs Alexandre)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis includes, in Section I, an analysis of the European Union's internal and external competence in air transport and in matters including air transport within their scope, the nature of such competence and the procedures for conducting external relations. The thesis includes also a description of the progress in European Community competence in air transport, a new classification of the Community's secondary legislative measures in air transport in view of their external effect and the main obstacles to the acquisition by the European Union of external competence in air transport. Section II of the thesis includes an analysis of the use the European Union has made of its external competence in air transport in the areas of external relations with non-Member States and international organizations and of the various problems bearing upon such relations as well as the prospects for the future</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d628c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd21n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v762n"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Scots law : how can and why should it survive?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McDiarmid, Claire Robertson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis has two main themes: that law is of primary importance to Scotland as a nation and to Scottish nationalism and that the distinctiveness of Scots law is threatened by a discernible tendency towards anglicisation or standardisation with English law. The thesis examines the nature of culture and nationalism in general, and in the Scottish context in particular, and discusses the foundational elements of Scotland's nationhood. Law is specifically considered in the latter two contexts. Thereafter, some elements which substantiate the claim of distinctiveness made for Scots law are identified and one view of the mechanisms by which it is becoming anglicised is presented. Finally, justifications for actively pursuing the survival of the Scottish legal system as a distinctive body of norms are outlined and action which could be taken to ensure that survival is discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacDonald, Roderick A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505248g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v762n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History, European</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128ng797"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L' intégration au travail des personnes ayant des incapacités</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Legault, Lucie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research project analyses the employment status of disabled persons as well as the existing measures to enhance their integration in the work place. This analysis demonstrates that this group is confronted with patterns of systemic discrimination and that the actual integration measures bear numerous gaps. Different strategies are proposed in order to fill these gaps. A comparative study with foreign integration models contributes to the elaboration of these strategies. The proposed solutions reside in legislative reforms and modifications to employment rules and practices.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sheppard, Colleen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m160v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng797</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Business Administration, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881p13t"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les recours du vendeur de la chose mobilière</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Larochelle, Pierre, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>On January 1, 1994, the Civil Code of Quebec came into force. The study and the construction of the Code will certainly bring up a great number of discussions and litigations in the coming years, the new regime of the sale of moveables certainly being a part of these numerous debates. This thesis not only attempts to systematize and to understand the different recourses of the seller of moveables, but also to identify the different problems which will be faced in the years to come. In this thesis, the author also takes the opportunity to express his opinion on numerous issues which he brought up on this regime of the Civil Code of Quebec.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacDonald, Roderick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh70m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881p13t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161828b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regional open skies agreements : law and practice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lapointe, Hélène</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents an analytic review of the different definitions of "Open Skies Treaty". It mainly introduces American, Canadian and European views of Open Skies. We also propose our definition of Open Skies in a North American context including our NAFTA partner, Mexico. Then, the thesis conducts a detailed study of the law and practice pertaining to regional Open Skies Agreements in Europe, Latin America, Australasia and in the Asia/Pacific region. Afterwards, an analysis of the main provisions of the North American Free Trade Agreement is made with reference to air transport. Follows, an overview of the state of the Canadian air transport industry and policy. More importantly, a complete analysis of the New Air Transport Agreement Between Canada and the United States implementing an Open Skies regime as for 1995 is made in Chapter V. Finally, a critical analysis of this Open Skies Agreement is made and perspectives are given as to the future inclusion of Mexico, Chile and, later on, of all of Latin America.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq83w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161828b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aks65hf29q"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"ATC liability and the perspectives of the global GNSS" : (is an International Convention viable?)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lagarrigue, Ingrid</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the 1930's several International Organizations and the State of Argentina have attempted to draft an International Convention on Air Traffic Control Liability. All such attempts, however, failed. Although justified reasons favoured an International Agreement on the subject-matter, it seems that the reasons for the failures of these different Drafts are very understandable. Among them is that if States do ratify an Air Traffic Control Liability Convention, it will automatically infringe a part of their sovereignty. Despite the fact that a subject as important as this one requires careful study, it cannot be said that it has not been properly addressed, and it is evident that final conclusions can now be reached. An international solution should be abandoned. Two possibilities remain, as a compromise for the unification of laws in that matter, that is either a regional agreement among the different regions of the World or a Model Agreement which States would implement in their national laws. Conflict of laws and reliance upon a specified regulation of the subject-matter may be an even better solution.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps64x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hf29q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j324z"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Safety and economic regulation of air transportation in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fiorita, Dionigi M. (Dionigi Mario)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Federal Government, in the exercise of its exclusive constitutional jurisdiction over aeronautics, has adopted laws and regulations that address the various aspects of the aviation system. These laws and regulations have evolved significantly from the first piece of Federal legislation passed in 1919. Some of those laws and regulations have as their objective achieving and maintaining an adequate level of aviation safety, while others are intended to ensure that Canadians have access to an efficient and reliable national air transportation system. On the safety side, there are laws and regulations that establish standards of quality for the aircraft, standards of competence for air carriers and standards of competence and medical fitness of the personnel. There are also regulations that specify the conditions that must be met in order to register an aircraft in Canada. On the economic side, there are laws and regulations that set the terms and conditions for the operation of domestic and international air services. In the domestic context, such laws and regulations have gone from strict and almost complete government intervention, to giving effect to recent policies of less regulation and more competition. These same laws and regulations, while providing the regulatory authority with the necessary enforcement tools, also recognize the need to ensure that it does not act improperly or abusively. For such purpose, the stakeholders have access to several different recourses to challenge the actions of the regulatory authority.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss004.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j324z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795977j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reverse engineering computer programs under Canadian copyright law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Handa, Sunny</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The field of copyright law has been especially active in recent times as a result of its application to computer programs. Copyright law, not originally designed to protect such works, has had to adapt to suit the special nature of computer programs. This paper addresses the applicability of copyright law to the reverse engineering of computer programs. Reverse engineering is a method by which programmers may uncover the ideas and processes used within an existing computer program, thereby allowing the construction of compatible computer programs. Reverse engineering may also be used to create works which are directly competitive with the original program, and may also be used to assist in the piracy of computer programs. The mere act of reverse engineering computer programs, regardless of its purpose, potentially infringes the copyright of the computer program in question, notwithstanding whether the results of the process are used in an infringing manner. Recently both the European Union countries and the United States have accepted reverse engineering as an exception to copyright infringement. The European Union has opted for a legislative solution, whereas in the United States several courts have construed the fair use exception contained in that country's Copyright Act as allowing reverse engineering. In this paper, it is argued that Canada must also adopt a reverse engineering exception to copyright infringement. It is claimed that the implementation of such an exception is justified through examination of the underlying policy goals of copyright law in the context of an economic framework. Reverse engineering fosters the creation of standards which, it is argued, increase societal wealth. The existence of a reverse engineering exception is consistent with the balance between the economic rights of individual authors and societal technological progress, which copyright seeks to maintain. It is demonstrated that copyright exists as the only form of applicable intellectual property protection which can broadly limit the disclosure of concepts underlying computer programs. It is suggested that an effective exception should be statutorily based. It is felt that the existing fair dealing exception contained in the Canadian Copyright Act is juridically under-developed and too uncertain to provide an effective solution to the reverse engineering problem. A legislative solution would send a clear message to the software industry as well as to the courts, and could prohibit contracting out of the Copyright Act which would potentially be allowed were a judicial solution sought. It is further suggested that the statutory exception should broadly allow the process of reverse engineering as opposed to limiting it to cases where compatibility is sought. Narrowing the exception creates conceptual difficulties in applying limits to reverse engineering. Allowing a broad exception would avoid these difficulties while continuing to provide copyright holders with protection if, after the reverse engineering process is concluded, their protectable expression is used within another's software product.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Glenn, H. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z00q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795977j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Information Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Library Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj96022996"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Land and housing rights in South Africa and their compatibility with international human rights norms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Blois, Myriam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The April 1994 elections in South Africa, which witnessed the ANC gain a determinant majority in national government, shifted the struggle in that country from national liberation and enfranchisement to economic empowerment for the black majority. The South African Government, facing millions of restitution of land claims and a national demand for effective access to land and adequate housing, has had to elaborate concrete legal implementation mechanisms to deliver land and housing for the majority of the population. Constitutionalism, through the entrenchment of land rights in a bill of rights, and the creation of a national socio-economic program to meet the basic needs of landless and homeless South Africans (Reconstruction and Development Program or RDP), have been the methods favored by the Government of National Unity (GNU) to address land and housing issues in the new South Africa. Strong pressure has been put on Mandela's Government to bring about fundamental economic and social transformation. The GNU presently has the responsibility to ensure a speedy advance with its programs of housing and land redistribution and restitution. The international instruments on economic and social rights have inspired Chapter 3 of the Interim Constitution, which contains a Bill of Rights, as well as the drafting of the Reconstruction and Development Program. Although these two national legal documents guarantee substantial economic and social rights, the difficulty that lies ahead is the establishment of a process to implement these entitlements. The socio-economic transformation that will take place in South Africa in the coming years will serve as a test-case and will hopefully encourage legal scholars and practitioners to become more sensitive to the importance of designing delivery mechanisms for these rights. With the high level of expectations and violence experienced in South Africa's rural and urban areas, a great deal is at stake in relation to land reform and t</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Toope, Stephen J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg92w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96022996</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Urban and Regional Planning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hb968"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aviation law in Israel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dan, Moshe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Civil Aviation Laws in Israel began their development since the independence of the State in 1948. They comprise of five main Aviation Acts and various executive regulations which facilitate the conduct of the civil aviation industry. The basic aviation act, although modified and supplemented by native Israeli aviation laws is the Air Navigation Act: It was drafted in the 1920's by Great Britain and was incorporated into the legal system of the newly born state. A review of the development of civil aviation law in Israel has not yet been completed by a single study considering its fundamental provisions, namely providing analysis of international and domestic sources, aviation organizations and policies. Historically, the political situation in the Middle East has exerted influence on Israel's civil aviation policies. Now that the region is on the verge of a new era of peace, Israeli policy in this field will further be affected. Undoubtedly, a new way of thinking will have to emerge in order to face the possibilities and challenges that peace will bring. The purpose of this thesis is therefore to describe, analyze and evaluate the basic features of aviation law and aviation policies of Israel.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d629n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb968</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g715d"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of the application of Sharia law on the rights of non-Muslims in the light of international principles : the case of Sudan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Awad, Siham Samir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The idea of exploring the topic of the thesis has been promoted by the revival of Islam as a legal system in a number of Islamic nation states, as an assertion and part of their identity. This development is regarded by some as adversely affecting non-Muslim citizens in such states when looked at in the light of international principles. Sudan, a multireligious state, declared the application of Sharia laws in 1983. The thesis addresses the impact of the application of Sharia law on non-Muslims within the historical, political and legal context of Sudan. This is examined in the light of international principles. To this end, the thesis uses a comparative methodology, entailing the identification of the areas of inconsistencies between rules of Sharia governing non-Muslim subjects and international norms. Thus, an examination of Sudanese laws based on Sharia having an impact on non-Muslims is made.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patrick, Glenn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t414b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g715d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>History, African</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:subject>History, Middle Eastern</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sj33s"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stowage of goods in international Maritime transport</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Andersen, Lars</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The paper presents and discusses the carrier's stowage duties under the Hague and Hague/Visby Rules and contrasts them with similar duties created in the Hamburg Rules. Particular attention is paid to stowage responsibilities in relation to the carriage of dangerous goods. A subsidiary examination considers the extent to which international stowage regulations adopted to protect safety and the environment may affect what constitutes proper stowage under the contract of carriage.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tetley, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv91f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj33s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Environmental Sciences</dc:subject><dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mh61c"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role and design of competition law and policy in developing countries : issues and problems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Amos, Jude Thaddeus</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The economic reforms under way in most developing countries are directed towards the establishment of an open market economy. These efforts have been initiated in the belief that it is within such an environment that resources could be best utilised in furtherance of economic development. Increasing attention is being directed towards competition law and policy as an essential tool for the attainment of this objective. However, the role and design of competition law and policy ought to reflect the peculiar economic, political and social conditions prevalent in developing countries. Thus, one cannot expect that models of competition suited to developed market economies are applicable ipso facto to developing ones. This thesis identifies some of the peculiarities of the developing country environment, including the nature of domestic markets, and the confluence of political and economic power, and suggests the manner in which these may have to influence competition law and policy in such countries.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h163x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh61c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>