<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans064794g"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>X : for chamber orchestra (1998)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yamanaka, Keiko, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>X is a composition for a chamber orchestra with a duration of approximately 13'30′. The title X (read as "cross") refers to a cross-weave pattern created by superimposing the trills and written-out tremolos in the piece. While the trills and tremolos are used throughout the piece to create a sense of textural variety, they have an important function in controlling the formal structure of the piece. The texture, which is one of the important features of the composition, makes the overall form apparent.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cherney, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pz12c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064794g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chamber orchestra music -- Scores</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77ft57m"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language/><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Incidental music of my mind</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bolton, Rose A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Instrumentation: 1*(1.=picc.)-1-2*(2.-Bb+bass cl.)-1 / 1-1-1-0 / 2 perc., 1 keyb. (piano+celesta) / 1-1-1-1-1 The work is approximately 14 minutes long, and consists of six movements which make up a series of musical tableaux, placing greater emphasis on their contrasting characters instead of on gradual and continuous development of material. These movements take their inspiration from activities or situations encountered in everyday life, thus revisiting the old tradition of "character pieces" as encountered, for example, in the music of many composers such as Schumann, Grieg or Mussorgsky. It is followed by an analysis which examines the harmonic syntax and the language of the work as it relates to the program suggested by the title.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bouliane, Denys</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3013472.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft57m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Instrumental ensembles -- Scores</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289m11j"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Long-term results of user participation in housing rehabilitation : the Community Design Workshop in Pointe St. Charles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>You, Danhui, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>User participation has been regarded as an empowerment tool to help low-income people to improve housing at a low cost. It was implemented by the Community Design Workshop during the attempts at housing rehabilitation in Pointe St. Charles in the early 1970's. This thesis is focused on the long-term results of user participation employed by the CDW. Both the current physical conditions of the CDW's projects and the inhabitants' attitudes towards participation, one generation after its implementation, were studied. The research shows that the CDW's efforts involving users in housing rehabilitation not only resulted in improved housing conditions for the urban poor in the long run but had some positive impacts on the inhabitants as well. The success and failure of the CDW's work also provided empirical lessons for later participatory practice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bhatt, Vikram</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf757.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m11j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Housing rehabilitation -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic -- Conservation and restoration -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Community development, Urban -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Citizen participation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pointe-Saint-Charles (Montréal, Québec)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xg95q"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vecindades in the Traza of Mexico City</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rebolledo, Alejandro M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The word "vecindad" in Spanish means neighborhood, but the word is also used to describe a dwelling form. The vecindad is usually known as a row of one-room dwellings surrounding an open space or patio. This kind of dwelling form exists in most Latin American countries as well as in Spain, however the word "vecindad" is used exclusively in Mexico. This dwelling form existed in Spain under the name of "corrales" and it was brought to Mexico in the XVI century with the Conquest of 1521. Initially, vecindades were built as multi-family tenements to rent to low-income artisans or workers in Mexico. There are two kinds: the multi-storied ones which were built within the Traza, which was the first design of Mexico City by the Spaniards; and the one-storied buildings built in the Indian barrios located on the periphery of the Traza. While each vecindad is different, they share the same elements such as the zahuan (entrance), the patio, the dwellings and the accesorias (commercial spaces). The number and dimensions of these elements vary depending on the characteristics of each vecindad. From the XVI century until the early XX century, vecindades comprised the majority of the housing stock in Mexico City. In the 1940's, due to the ideas of Functionalism, vecindades ceased to be built and were relegated as an old and traditional dwelling form in the center of the city. This thesis presents the origin, evolution and present condition of vecindades within the Traza of Mexico City. Their adaptability to fulfill social, cultural and political circumstances throughout the history of Mexico City reveals their importance as the city's main collective urban dwelling form.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bhatt, Vikram</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn60q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg95q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Courtyard houses -- Mexico -- Mexico City -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apartment houses -- Mexico -- Mexico City -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Room layout (Dwellings) -- Mexico -- Mexico City</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5712m893s"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>From royal bed to boudoir : the dissolution of the space of appearance told through the history of the French Salon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Plumb-Dhindsa, Pamela</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The space of appearance emerges from the practice of speech and action in the presence of others. Although it predates the public sphere as a formal construction, it exists in the context of a particular place. With the transformation of the ancien regime and the emergence of the bourgeois public sphere, the meaning of public and private was obscured by the rise of the 'social.' The public realm was transformed from a space of disclosure to a realm defined by the necessities of survival---a process by which speech and action lost much of their former power. In the spectacular relations of the ancien regime, public ritual revolved around the royal bed. Through the analogy of language and architecture, seventeenth-century aristocratic women defined new patterns of social practice. In the convergence of the spectacular relations of the court and the world of letters, a space of appearance arose. At the turn of the century, Salon discourse moved from the daybed to the sofa of Rococo salons. Responding to emerging dichotomies, discourse, architecture and Salon practice took on gendered implications. Its decline as a space of appearance coincided with the emergence of the boudoir. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv969.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m893s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Salons -- France -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in public life -- France -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- France -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rk235"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le collage à travers l'oeuvre du Merzbau de Kurt Schwitters</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lafontaine, Diane, 1960-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Work of a lifetime and linked intimately to his own life, Kurt Schwitters' Merzbau is the expression of the MERZ collage, in a work that brings together architecture, theatre, sculpture, painting and literature. His work evolves through time, based on two specific moments: the extraction of fragments, and the assembly of these elements into a new harmonious and meaningful entity. To Schwitters, the MERZ collage is not the mere manipulation of forms; it is the continuous process of transformation, from their initial state, of various fragments found in his daily environment, including material doomed to destruction: debris, rubbish, scrap, trash, remnants, etc. This transformation consists of one fundamental theme: uniting two opposing forces of reality---art and non-art---into one world: the Merzgesamtweltbild. Art is singled out as the supreme value of human existence, which has the power of transforming waste matter into a work of art. What is seen, through the artist's eyes and soul, is a colour, a light, a shadow, a line, a form, a space, a depth...What occurs in the MERZ collage is the true metamorphosis of the visible, sensible ordinary world.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gomez, Alberto Perez</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v45q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk235</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Schwitters, Kurt, 1887-1948. Merzbau</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225d14b"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The machines of Francesco Di Giorgio : demonstrations of the world</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guess, Alice C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an exploration of the chapters of Francesco Di Giorgio's Trattati di Architettura, Ingegneria e Arte Militare, that pertain to mechanical devices. While it is difficult to imagine actually constructing Di Giorgio's machines from the drawings and descriptions in his treatises, given their apparent inefficiencies and ambiguities, the Aristotelean science and philosophy referenced throughout the Trattati provides a basis for looking at them as demonstrations of concepts beyond their immediate applications for architecture and engineering. By considering these devices in Di Giorgio's own terms, terms suggested by his own experiences, as well as his writings and paintings, strong associations can be made to the science, philosophy and the theology of his time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn85k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d14b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Machinery -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Martini, Francesco di Giorgio, 1439-1502. Trattati di architettura, ingegneria e arte militare</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gv81h"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Native women and their homes : gender, housing and identity : case study : Chisasibi, Northern Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chagny, Maïti</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cree communities in Northern Quebec have been going through rapid changes since the first arrival of the Eurocanadians on their lands. Their customs, their houses and their eating habits have been deeply influenced by western living patterns. Today, the houses and the community designs remind more of the suburban Canadian landscape. Yet, Native social, cultural and natural environment still differs from non-Native communities in Canada. Traditionally, women used to play an important role in the domestic area. Due to colonization, Native women have lost their status and are not part of the decision making process of their homes. Despite that, Native women have continued to play a special role in fostering a sense of identity in their communities. It is therefore important to involve them in housing projects in order to find designs more adapted to the needs of their families. The case study took place in Chisasibi, a Cree village at the North of James Bay, which has been relocated 17 years ago, and been living in fully equipped houses based on western designs. This thesis aimed at revealing the opinion of Native women about their domestic environment and collect their suggestions for future improvements. The results showed that Native families' lifestyles have become more and more diversified: some want to incorporate traditional behavior patterns, other on the contrary, are more inclined in living the western way. Of course age and social background play an important role in their opinions. Still, the major critic concerns the inappropriate designs, the lack of space and storage which tend to influence the way people use the space in the house. The thesis pointed out the importance of defining housing layouts in accordance to the Native families' choices and sense of identity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bhatt, Vikram</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d215r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv81h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cree Indians -- Québec (Province) -- Chisasibi -- Dwellings</dc:subject><dc:subject>Room layout (Dwellings) -- Québec (Province) -- Chisasibi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cree women -- Québec (Province) -- Chisasibi -- Dwellings</dc:subject><dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic -- Québec (Province) -- Chisasibi</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p685d"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Paper threshold : the drawings of Michelangelo</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carroll, Michael, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following thesis is a meditation on the drawings of Michelangelo that are connected to his three projects at San Lorenzo and a series of 'gift' drawings for Tomasso de'Cavalieri. The drawings offer a glimpse of his radically inventive imagination that calls for an architecture rooted in the soul and based on the appearance of a 'live' and an emotive body. Engaged within a holistic fabrication of architecture, both the recto and the verso of the sheet are constructed as palimpsests comprised of design sketches, figurative studies, poetic fragments and pragmatic calculations. As instruments of communication, Michelangelo's paper templates are intermediaries between the 'Divine One's' mindful hand and the scarpellini's chisel. A line can be traced from the outline of his disegno , the profillo of a face and the cut line of his modani. Poetry and profiles cross-pollinate in a poiesis of architecture that culminates at a threshold---the hinge between being and becoming---the place where Love tosses in his sleep.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462756w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p685d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Drawing, Italian</dc:subject><dc:subject>Michelangelo Buonarroti, 1475-1564 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drawing, Renaissance -- Italy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544br61b"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>BIST fault diagnosis in scan-based modules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zia, Victor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Testing digital devices constitutes a major portion of the cost and effort involved in their design, production, and use. Built-In Self-Test (BIST) has been warmly embraced by the Integrated Circuits (IC) industry as a solution for the continuously aggravating testing problem. BIST provides a simple go/no-go test screening answer. However, when test fall-out is high, it becomes necessary to diagnose faults to improve the yield. Signature Analysis (SA) is typically used in a BIST environment to compact the outputs of a module into a final signature. Several SA-based diagnostic schemes have been developed in the past. An overwhelming majority of these techniques assume the presence of very few error bits in the Test Response Sequence (TRS). However, this assumption is generally unrealistic since a faulty device in a practical BIST environment can generate an enormous number of erroneous bits in the TRS. In this thesis, a comprehensive survey of the current SA-based BIST diagnostic schemes is presented first. Then, novel BIST fault diagnosis techniques for scan-based VLSI modules are presented, based on multiple signature analysis. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rajski, Janusz</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hf34k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br61b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd472z51c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intelligent gripper, with multi-sensor finger pad, for the sarcos dextrous arm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Ping, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents the Intelligent Gripper, a low cost instrumented robot finger pad which is equipped with an 8 x 8 tactile sensing array and a 2 x 2 proximity sensing grid. The complete system is composed of three modules. The capacitive tactile sensing array utilizes a dual strip construction to improve its robustness and simplicity, a technology initially developed by Sarcos Research Inc. The proximity network is based on infrared range sensing technology. The microprocessor based interface module gives the system intelligent capability. In order to reduce the noise and to improve the system modularity, all electric circuitry is localized. The modular architecture gives the system excellent portability. Following the comprehensive evaluation and characterization of the tactile sensing array and its associated electronic system, an experimental exploration to use the tactile sensor in transient contact force control is presented. It is found that using feedback from tactile sensor stabilizes the force control. However, the highest performance for transient force control is achieved from a combined feedback from tactile sensor and joint force sensor.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Buehler, Martin</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hollerbach, John M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc654.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z51c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418q307"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The design and control of Scout I, a simple quadruped robot</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yamazaki, Kenneth S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new type of quadruped robot has been developed, the Scout class. Each leg utilizes only one actuated degree of freedom (as opposed to a typical three) to reduce complexity and cost. The design of the first of these robots, Scout I is presented. In modelling Scout, impacts are assumed instantaneous with angular momentum being conserved about the impacting toe. Stance phases are modelled as a double inverted pendulum with one input and a pin joint with the ground. Walking controllers requiring a minimum of sensing are then developed and examined both in simulation and experiments. Small errors in impact modelling coupled with high setpoint sensitivity are found to result in discrepancies. However, despite this stable open loop walking is achieved in all cases examined. Additional behaviors for Scout are presented, including turning, side stepping, sitting and laying down, and step and stair climbing.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Buchler, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x1283.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q307</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859h760"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Simultaneous recording of multiple single cells in the abducens nucleus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wilson, Thomas R., 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The tetrode is a multi-tipped recording device designed to improve single unit discrimination in multi-unit recordings. Traditionally, it consists of four insulated wires that have been twisted and glued together. The tips are cut and thereby exposed producing four closely-spaced but independent leads for one recording device. It has been used for recording in the rat hippocampus and the cat striate cortex. Here, a tetrode that has been designed for recording in the abducens nucleus of the cat is described. Results presented consist of descriptions of the usefulness of four separate designs for the tetrode. In particular, the ability of each to improve single unit discrimination from multi-unit motoneuron recordings is discussed. As well, a brief discussion of population activity of multiple neurons in the abducens nucleus is presented.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guitlon, Daniel</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Galiana, H. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt89j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h760</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jb09g"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparison of Knelson concentrator and jig performance for gold recovery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vincent, Frédérique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A 7.6 cm Laboratory Knelson Concentrator was used to evaluate the performance of one jig circuit (Snip Operation), four Knelson Concentrators circuits (Meston, Est Malartic, Aurbel and Hemlo) and one classification circuit (Agnico-Eagle). To determine the size-by-size unit performance of all units, total and gravity recoverable gold contents were measured in the feed, concentrate, tails, underflow and overflow. Sample dilution with silica was used as a tool to enhance LKC recovery in samples with a high sulphide content. The data generated from the Knelson and the jig was used in a model designed to simulate an actual grinding and gravity circuit, and to predict its GRG recovery. It describes gold liberation, breakage and classification behaviour, and the GRG recovery performance curve of the chosen gravity unit. The simulation of the Snip circuit reproduced the recoveries obtained at the plant, and predicted that the use of a 20" Knelson, replacing the jig, would bring the recovery from 3 3% up to 43%. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laplante, A. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d2161.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb09g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375z56h"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An h-adaptive control-volume finite element method for steady, two-dimensional fluid flow and heat transfer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Venditti, David A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An unstructured-grid, h-adaptive control-volume finite element method (CVFEM) was formulated, implemented, and tested for the simulation of steady, viscous, incompressible fluid flow and heat transfer in arbitrarily shaped two-dimensional domains. The h-adaptive procedure is based on a posteriori error estimation using a superconvergent recovery or smoothing technique. The CVFEM is based on a co-located, equal-order formulation that deals directly with the primitive variables. A set of sufficient conditions is presented for guaranteeing that the algebraic approximations to the diffusion terms in the integral conservation equations contribute positively to the coefficients in the discretized equations. An additive-correction multigrid method, based on an adaptive volume-agglomeration technique, was implemented for the purposes of accelerating iterative convergence in the solution of the discretized equations. An extended Richardson extrapolation technique for unstructured grids is proposed: A discrete solution is obtained from an h-adaptive analysis in which the estimated error is reduced to a predetermined level and uniformly distributed over each element. The resulting mesh is then used as a base grid in constructing a hierarchy of grids via uniform element subdivision. A closed-form, analytical solution to the steady, two-dimensional, incompressible Navier-Stokes equations was obtained by prescribing a divergence-free velocity field and a consistent pressure field, substituting them into the momentum equations, and deriving the implied volumetric source terms. This analytical solution was used to test several numerical algorithms implemented in this work. Lid-driven, viscous flow in a triangular cavity was also used as a test problem.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baliga, B. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq70b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z56h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107111s"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ultrasonic digital beamformation : a comparative study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vasudevan, Sunil</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Real-time ultrasonic imaging systems have been available for more than fifty-five years and are becoming an important tool in the practice of modern medicine. During this time much has occurred to the basic architecture and functions of these clinical systems and their beamformers, which are, in many ways, the most important components of these systems. Throughout most of the 30 years of real time imaging, analog beamformers have been the mainstay of all ultrasonic instruments. But at the present time the industry is undergoing a major shift toward digital beamformation with the introduction of several commercial systems. The thesis will look at the evolution of digital ultrasound beamformers, some of the changes that have occurred and will discuss current trends in beamformer design. Typical analog and digital beam formers have been simulated and their performance compared in terms of beam width, side lobe levels and signal-to-noise ratio. Also the effect of apodization on images have been examined. Experimental investigations have been carried out to compare delay-sum-add and synthetic aperture imaging on different phantoms. The technical challenges in digital beamformation win be reviewed, as also the constraints introduced by today's market place. Finally, the future of digital beamformation in the context of advances in computer and microelectronics technologies is discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Watkin, Kenneth L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m6172.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107111s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42n9953"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Seismic response of reinforced concrete walls with steel boundary elements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tupper, Bryce</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A reinforced concrete ductile flexural wall requires the placement of well-detailed concentrated reinforcement at the ends of the wall. This often results in congestion in these heavily reinforced regions, resulting in labourious construction. Two flexural wall specimens, containing structural steel boundary elements, were constructed and tested under reversed cyclic loading to evaluate the performance of this new construction technique. For comparison, a third wall specimen meeting the requirements of a standard reinforced concrete ductile flexural wall was constructed and tested under reversed cyclic loading. One of the composite walls used rectangular hollow structural sections (HSS) as boundary elements which were connected to the wall by welding the transverse bars directly to both HSS elements. The second wall used steel channels connected to the wall with headed studs welded to the channels. These studs overlapped with the transverse reinforcing bars, which had headed ends. The details of these three walls were chosen such that all of the walls had approximately the same flexural capacity. The reversed cyclic responses of the three walls showed that each wall had similar hysteretic properties. Following significant yielding of the structural steel, local buckling of the steel boundary elements in the composite walls was observed. The design used for ductile flexural walls was modified to enable comparable design of reinforced walls with steel boundary elements.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z753f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n9953</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d871r"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Operating strategies for a nitrogen deficient waste using a continuously fed cyclically aerated sequencing batch reactor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tauvette, Geoffrey Yvon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two 28 L continuously fed cyclically aerated sequencing batch reactors were operated at a constant sludge age and hydraulic residence time of 15 and 2, 3, 4 or 8 days, respectively, and an organic load of 7, 14 or 65 g of COD/day to investigate operation strategies to treat whey (a nitrogen unbalanced waste). The systems were equipped with a membrane filter that automatically removed effluent during the settling period. To observe performance, biomass appearance and settling behaviour under various nitrogen-limiting conditions, nitrogen was added at rates to maintain COD/N of approximately 20 to 60. The cyclic aeration generated a selector effect in the sludge blanket and controlled bulking. The N-balanced system could be used without the membrane filter and effluent BOD and solids were below 20 mg/L and 25 mg/L, respectively. The effluent of the N-unbalanced systems had BOD below 20 mg/L but generated solids varying between 60 and 100 mg/L. The membrane filter significantly reduced the effluent solids. Moreover, the clarity of the filtrate was enhanced when the sludge bulked severely due to an excessive number of filaments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gehr, Ronald</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Zaloum, Ronald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km81c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d871r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Environmental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t421r"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Variant selection during the austenite-to-martensite transformation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sum, Maisie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Variant selection rules are described that predict the austenite-to-mariensite transformation textures of an Fe-30% Ni alloy. The occurrence of variant selection is explained in detail using the crystal plasticity model of Bishop and Hill and the Kurdjumov-Sachs transformation relationship. A correlation is established between the slip systems of the former and the rotation axes of the latter. The selection criteria are based on a combination of slip activity, that is, active slip systems defined in terms of positive shears, and permissible dislocation reactions. Thus some of the variants selected are associated with slip systems that are active, while the remainder are accounted for by the in-plane reaction of active dislocations to form inactive or unstressed dislocations. The variant selection criteria are tested against two strain paths; plane strain rolling and axisymmetric compression. Extensive studies were conducted on the former strain path and revealed excellent agreement between the measured and predicted transformation textures. A more detailed analysis is still required for the axisymmetric compression strain path, although, the results obtained indicate that the variant selection model does indeed generate a transformation texture that is consistent with the experimental one.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jonas, J. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x76m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t421r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sj39f"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of 3D deformable models for intraoperative visualization and quantification of cerebral tissue resection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sinasac, Michael John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of the project described in this thesis is to provide intraoperative feedback to the neurosurgeon using the equipment comprising a typical IGNS environment. The project accomplishes this task through the use of physically based, deformable models. The major objectives for this mode of intraoperative feedback are to provide useful visual and quantitative feedback to the neurosurgeon about the progress of tissue resection during a surgical procedure using the equipment available in a typical IGNS environment and to be simultaneously being unobtrusive to the surgeon's work. An overview of the current state of IGNS is presented, followed by a logical association between current work and the significance of the project developed for this thesis. The mathematics of deformable models as a means for providing intraoperative feedback are developed and a thorough description of the work completed for this thesis is presented. A series of increasingly realistic validation studies that were undertaken for the project are described, followed by a discussion of the use of the software in intraoperative applications. Finally, conclusions are made as to the utility of the project as a viable means of providing intraoperative feedback and future work is extrapolated from the project. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peters, T. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b55c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj39f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000220w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fusion of synthetic and infrared imagery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simard, Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research presents the concept of an Enhanced and Synthetic Vision System (ESVS) that could help aircraft pilots see in low visibility conditions. The basic idea is that synthetic and infrared imagery would be fused to maximize image content. Three fusion algorithms were implemented and tuned for this particular purpose. Artificially generated infrared images as well as synthetic images were used to evaluate the algorithms' performance. An observer experiment, based on a typical search and rescue scenario, showed that image fusion leads to an increase in useful information. Different registration conditions were also simulated to investigate their effect on a potential ESVS.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ferrie, Frank</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k017s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000220w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Aerospace</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55md97d"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The industrial application of a multiple technique paper dryer simulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sidwall, Shaun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Drying Doctor, a multiple technique simulator of the paper drying process, has been developed at the Pulp and Paper Research Centre, McGill University. This thesis examines the different approaches to the modeling of this process, provides a rigorous validation of the simulation program and demonstrates its utility with four containerboard machines of Norampac Inc. Several features differentiate this simulator from others. When heavy grades of paper are produced or when high intensity drying processes are used even with thin sheets, substantial thickness direction gradients of moisture content and temperature develop across the sheet, demonstrating the necessity of a fully microscale model such as employed by Drying Doctor. Using industrial and laboratory data for a variety of paper grades and drying processes, 31 uncalibrated simulations for machine speed showed a standard deviation of only 3.4% from known speeds. Through simulation of modified operating conditions such as steam pressure, spoiler bars, pocket air conditions and addition of the high intensity drying process, Yankee air impingement dryers, substantial production rate increases for the industrial partner's papermachines through use of the Drying Doctor simulator were shown possible.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Douglas, W. J. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289m12t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md97d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture, Wood Technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rn43t"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aeroelastic oscillations of a delta wing with bonded piezoelectric strips</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shrivastava, Swapna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Piezoelectric materials offer an alternative method for active control of aeroelastic oscillations, that is potentially cheaper, lighter, and more effective than conventional control methods. In this thesis, the aeroelastic oscillations of a delta wing under the combined effects of unsteady, supersonic aerodynamic loading and bonded piezoelectric strips are studied. The delta wing is modelled as a cantilevered triangular plate undergoing small transverse oscillations. Using the structural model developed here, the natural frequencies of the wing are obtained. A hybrid analytical-numerical method is developed for the unsteady supersonic aerodynamics of the wing, in order to determine the unsteady pressure distribution and the generalized aerodynamic forces on the wing. It is shown that the method adopted here to obtain the pressure distribution is more accurate than the analytical method based on frequency expansion, and computationally were efficient than the numerical methods using the Mach Box approach. Finally, in the presence of bonded piezoelectric strips, the transient and dynamic responses of the wing are studied without and with aerodynamic loading, respectively. It is found that with particular combinations of voltages and the number of piezoelectric strips, the amplitude of the aeroelastic oscillations can be reduced. These required combinations change as the periodic frequency of wing oscillation is varied. Additionally, the piezoelectric actuators aligned with the span are more effective than the chord-aligned piezoelectric actuators, which produce little or no reduction in the oscillations. It is further found that even a small number of strips can effectively reduce the magnitude of the oscillations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Misra, A. K.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mateescu, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g475h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn43t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Aerospace</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354h453"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vapor and liquid equilibria in porous media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shin, Youn-Ok, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The alteration of the vapor and liquid equilibrium (VLE) of volatile organic mixtures by using porous media at the liquid-vapor interface was studied. Kelvin, assuming ideal behavior of fluids, first introduced the vapor pressure of liquid over a meniscus as a function of its surface tension and the radius of the curvature. A thermodynamic model (SSmod model) predicting the VLE of non-ideal organic mixtures in porous media was developed as a function of pore sizes based on the pressure equations available in literature. The model was used to predict the VLE of two aqueous alcohol solutions, ethanol-water and propanol-water, and two binary alcohol solutions, methanol-isopropanol and ethanol-octane. Experiments were conducted using sintered metal and fritted glass plates as porous media and compared with the model predictions. The model predictions for the actual pore diameters tested showed good agreement with the experimental results.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Simandl, Jana</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj16w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h453</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pq18p"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Control of running in a quadruped robot with actuation only at the hips</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sarkis, Joseph, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Over the last few decades, much research effort has been focused on legged robots to mimic human or animal behaviors. The main motivation for this research is the fact that the majority of the earth's land mass is inaccessible to wheeled vehicles. It is therefore necessary to develop robots which can deal with a variety of terrain and overcome obstacles---legged locomotion seems to be the answer. With a new class of four-legged robots---the SCOUT class---maximum mechanical simplicity is achieved with only one actuated degree of freedom per leg. This platform with stiff legs has already been proven by Anca Cocosco to be capable of stable walking with a set of control algorithms based on controlled momentum transfer. By adding compliance in the legs and changing the control strategy to one that resembles Raibert's three-part controller, it has become possible to achieve running gaits in SCOUT-I and SCOUT-II. This will be demonstrated through simulations using the Working Model [8] software package. This thesis demonstrates that with a very simple mechanical design, simple control strategy, and only one actuated degree of freedom per leg, stable running is possible in SCOUT-II, and this for a variety of speeds and under different initial conditions. This research, along with other research on walking and stair-climbing presently being conducted at the Ambulatory Robotics Laboratory, will pave the way for robots that are inexpensive and of simple mechanical design, yet highly mobile and functional.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Buehler, Martin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m8942.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq18p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>