<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42n957p"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interactive effects of non-structural elements on the behaviour of tall building structures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gaiotti, Regina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The lateral stiffening effects of cladding and partition walls, which are usually unaccounted for in a building structure's design, are investigated in this research project. Direct and iterative, linear elastic finite element analyses of representative modules of these components and their supporting primary structure were performed. These were used to study their general lateral load behaviour, and to establish their modes of interaction and induced forces. As a result, new and practical analogous strut models have been devised to allow their incorporation in, and the analysis of, the total building structure. The strut models permitted the effects of the non-structural elements' interaction on the static and dynamic responses of tall building structures to be studied. The ultimate objective of this work has been to contribute towards the development of new procedures of analysis and design of building structures braced by precast concrete cladding panels and non-loadbearing concrete blockwork walls.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h1158.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n957p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gv26f"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Awakening internalist archaeology in the aboriginal world</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yellowhorn, Eldon Carlyle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is one step in defining the parameters of archaeology in an aboriginal context. It is designed to be a practical guide for imagining the past from an internalist perspective because archaeological methods offer the opportunity to represent antiquity that is simultaneously rational and familiar. However, an ancillary objective is to utilize symbols from antiquity as markers of modern Indian identity. Archaeology appeared on the radar of First Nations because their growing populations demand housing and economic opportunities. Recent settlement of land claims has brought large tracts of land under the control of Native people. Archaeological sites, by their very nature, are defined by their geographical location. Artifacts and sites are the products of past human labour and as such are a unique cultural legacy that must be understood within the context of a generalized world history. Internalist archaeology mediates between a local understanding of antiquity and the ancient history of humanity on a global scale. It is a product of the dialogue that began when the world system intruded on the local experience of aboriginal people. Modern prehistory was accessible only by employing archaeological methods and traditional history, as related in story, was relegated to the margins along with its authors. Myths were discounted as plausible sources of explanation for antiquity as archaeologists constructed their theories to explain the data they accumulated during their excavations. Internalist archaeology is an analytical tool that will play a prominent role in rehabilitating oral narratives by deploying methods to search for the signatures they would leave in the archaeological record. It is also a means to examine folklore so as to discover the messages that are encoded in myths. Myths act as mediating devices which connect the high levels of abstraction, those informing the traditional worldview, with lower levels of abstractions, as represented by customs. Ecological messages are encrypted in narratives which are then transmitted between generations. Each generation must decypher the meaning embedded in a myth to benefit from it. For internalist archaeology, mythology is a reservoir of explanation that has been ignored by mainstream research but which can be the basis for this brand of archaeological research. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Trigger, Bruce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db61d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv26f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Siksika mythology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Archaeology -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ethnoarchaeology -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Archaeology and history</dc:subject><dc:subject>Archaeology -- Political aspects -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt303"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular mechanisms regulating mammalian neurogenesis : roles of GrouchoTLE, BF-1 and HES1 proteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yao, Jing, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Drosophila development has provided a useful model system to study the molecular mechanisms that regulate neurogenesis. Recently much progress has been made in our understanding of how neural progenitor cells undergo commitment and become mature neurons. Studies have shown that a series of transcription factors plays fundamental roles in these neuronal developmental events. From Drosophila to mammals, evolutionarily conserved molecules regulate similar biological processes. The major hypothesis advanced in this thesis is that mammalian homologues of the Drosophila protein Groucho, namely the TLE proteins, share a conserved function in the regulation of mammalian neurogenesis. To investigate the molecular mechanisms regulating mammalian forebrain development, a number of studies were performed focusing on the function of the Groucho/TLE proteins and their partners, Hes1 and BF-1, as transcriptional regulators of mammalian neurogenesis. Groucho regulates neurogenesis by interacting with Drosophila HES proteins genetically and molecularly. Through these interactions, Groucho acts as a transcriptional co-repressor for HES proteins to suppress the transcription of genes promoting neural fate, therefore, inhibiting neurogenesis. Although some of the molecular properties of Groucho/TLE proteins were known, their involvement in mammalian neurogenesis is still poorly understood. In order to define the molecular function of Groucho/TLE1 in these processes, a series of studies were carried out. This thesis comprises three consecutive projects presenting studies of: (1) the expression pattern of TLE proteins during mammalian CNS development and during in vitro neural induction and chondrocyte differentiation, (2) the effect of altered TLE1 expression during in vivo mammalian neurogenesis, and (3) the functional partnerships of Groucho/TLE with other proteins involved in regulating mammalian telencephalon development. In these studies, we have demonstrated that individual Groucho/TLE proteins are expressed in the developing nervous system in a combinatorial fashion, suggesting a non-redundant function. Furthermore, persistent expression of TLE1 in post-mitotic neurons results in neuronal loss in the developing telencephalon. In addition, TLE proteins physically and functionally interact with HES and BF-1 proteins. Through these associations, Groucho/TLE proteins regulate the transcriptional repressive function of these proteins. These studies provide evidence that Groucho/TLE proteins act as transcriptional co-repressors in controlling neurogenesis in both invertebrate and vertebrate species.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stifani, Stefano</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz19q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt303</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860856x"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computer aided display of 3D angiograms, using graphics and haptics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yi, Dingrong, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current visualization methods for large volume angiograms share the difficulty of having to display depth information using conventional two-dimensional screens, while static viewing conditions between two consecutive rotations are often required. This thesis presents new directions towards the interactive display of and navigation through cerebral vessel networks. To reduce the computational load and storage requirements; a method is developed to extract a centerline representation of the vessel network from volume images. Shape attributes such as the position of the center point as well as the cross-sectional size, tangent, curvature, torsion and bifurcation of the vessel, are either contained in the representation or can be obtained from it by simple finite differences. A computer agent is introduced to convey depth information. Its first function is to assist a user to trace interactively the vessels without effort. This is accomplished by mapping the user's two dimensional input to three dimensional space, where the vessel centerlines are represented. The agent, programmed to track the centerlines, eliminates the topological ambiguities associated with the projection of three dimensional lines on a two dimensional screen. It also conveys quantitative depth information in the graphic and haptic domains. In the graphic domain, its visual appearance uses shape and color cues to indicate unambiguously its movements in the depth direction. In the haptic domain, the user experiences force cues that also indicate its movements in the depth direction. User performance studies indicate that the graphic and haptic depth cues provide equivalent assistance to a user in coping with the missing depth information. This suggests that in a variety of circumstances, the haptic modality can be used to release the visual modality from the task of depth discrimination, resulting in reduced visual fatigue. It also makes it possible to allocate graphic space to the display of other types of information. The developed user-interactive multimodal display techniques can be integrated in current display platforms for volume angiograms due to the small computational load they require. These techniques can also be applied to the display of more general shapes by replacing the centerline of vessels by the user movement curve that, is constrained on a more general three-dimensional surface.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hayward, Vincent</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz18f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860856x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816p19t"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thermodynamic parameters obtained from the van't hoff analysis of the binding of bile salts by cationic adsorbents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Williams, Celia K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The binding of aqueous solutions of sodium cholate and chenodeoxycholate with a lightly cross-linked polyacrylamide resin carrying N,N,N-trimethylammonium dodecyl chloride pendants (QPDA12) have been studied by HPLC data under various conditions. The goal of this thesis was to determine the relative enthalpic and entropic contributions to the binding that would aid in establishing the molecular basis of the process and in the development of effective resins that sequester bile salts. The binding constants were extracted from the fit of the isotherms to the Langmuir equation and their temperature dependence was employed to evaluate the thermodynamic parameters associated with the process. The binding was endothermic and entropy-driven. Stronger binding was always associated with a higher enthalpy barrier. Enthalpy-entropy compensation was observed encompassing data for both cholate and chenodeoxycholate binding under the influence of a variety of perturbations to the solvent. A compensation temperature of 293 K was obtained, which is characteristic of processes in which water plays a central role. The parameters observed were used to rule out earlier molecular descriptions of the process, and an alternate mechanism was proposed that emphasised the significant role of hydrophobic hydration changes in the sequestering of the bile salts. The temperature dependence studies were extended to the binding of sodium cholate with a lightly cross-linked hydrophilic resin possessing lysine-containing peptide pendant groups. In sharp contrast with the Langmuir behaviour of the isotherms found with the QPDA12 resin the binding behaviour with the peptide resin was of a complex nature. There was a very distinct sigmoidal feature in the binding process, which is the signature of cooperative binding. A weaker binding manifested itself in the latter half of the binding isotherms. An analysis of the temperature dependence revealed that the binding was exothermic throughout the isotherm. However, while the initial weak binding was in part entropy-driven, the subsequent stronger cooperative interactions resulted in binding that was associated with negative entropy changes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Galley, W. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs57w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p19t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085m93p"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stochastic models for multipath fading channels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Menemenlis, Nickie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main contribution of this work is to extend the present multi-path fading channel (MFC) models in two directions. First, the wireless communication system is viewed as a dynamical system where the channel constitutes the main plant of such a system. The random variables characterizing the magnitude of each multi-path component are generalized to random processes with time-varying statistics. It is claimed that the dynamics of both the log-normal shadowing and short-term fading channels is captured by the use of stochastic diffusion processes which emerge from mean-reverting Ornstein-Uhlenbeck processes, implying that signal envelope variations can be modeled using stochastic differential equations. Explicit expressions for signal envelope distributions and second order statistics of the received signal are derived. Further, the short-term dynamical model is cast into a state-space representation and a nominal model is derived, based on which robust analysis and design can be performed in order to capture additional channel uncertainties. The dynamical channel models introduced here are in accordance of the physical principles of electromagnetic wave propagation, they are parametric and able to describe diverse propagation environments. Second, a unified statistical analysis framework is introduced in order to compute the various statistics, second-order properties and densities of the overall received signal of the MFC's. To this end, the MFC model is formulated as a general shot-noise process brought forward by Rice. By extending and adapting the shot-noise analysis to complex signals the statistics of the overall received signal are derived, with explicit computations of the various moments and second-order statistics. The analysis includes the case of moving scatters (i.e. rain droplets) which it is shown to affect the dynamical temporal characteristics of the channel. It is also shown here that samples of the received signal approach a jointly Gaussian density, as certain parameters tend to their limits. Further, when the density of the received signal does not approach the Gaussian density, the Edgeworth series expansion is employed to compute the non-Gaussian density. This analysis brings forward the parameters responsible for Gaussianity of the received signal, parameters which designers can use in order to tailor their transmitter/receiver design. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Charalambous, Charalambos D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj769.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085m93p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j957x"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of high pressure treatment of milk on cheese making process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pandey, Pramod Kumar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Raw milk cheese has unique flavor and textural characteristics not obtainable in cheese from pasteurized milk. Several specialty cheeses made from raw milk are marketed worldwide, especially in Europe. However, because of safety concerns, many countries have imposed stringent restrictions on production and sale of raw milk cheeses. The purpose of this thesis research was to use high pressure (HP) treatment as a novel alternative for conventional pasteurization so that raw milk quality cheese could be produced without compromising food safety. The specific objectives of this research were to evaluate (i) the effect of HP treatment of milk on its coagulation and gelation characteristics, (ii) the destruction kinetics of microorganism and enzymes in milk, (iii) cheese making characteristics of HP treated milk as compared to the raw, pasteurized and micro-filtered milk (controls) and, finally (iv) to evaluate ripening characteristics of cheddar cheese made from HP treated milk in comparison with the controls. Three coagulation parameters of milk---lag time, mean coagulation rate, and inflexion time (time for reaching the point of maximum coagulation rate)---were evaluated as a function of pressure (200--400 MPa), temperature (3--21°C) and holding time (10--110 min) using a response surface methodology. In general, the lag time and inflexion time decreased while the mean coagulation rate increased with an increase in pressure, holding time or a decrease in temperature: The rennet gel characteristics were evaluated as gel strength (GS) and water-holding capacity (WHC). With a decrease in pressure level, temperature and holding time, there was a decrease in water-holding capacity and an increase in the gel-strength of the rennet curd. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ramaswamy, H. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d149c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j957x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>High pressure (Technology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cheese -- Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Raw milk cheese</dc:subject><dc:subject>Milk -- Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cheesemaking</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z251d"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biosorption of anionic metal species</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Niu, Hui, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Certain types of dead, inactive biomass can very effectively immobilize and concentrate heavy metals. In this work, a (bio-)sorption process has been studied using the biomass of waste crab shells which is particularly suited for extracting anionic metal species such as gold-cyanide, chromate and vanadate. These metal species are much difficult to remove from solutions. The current work demonstrated the crab-shell biosorbent potential. Acid Washed Ucides cordatus Shells (AWUS) removed more metal than other excellent biosorbents such as Bacillus (bacterium), Penicillium (fungus) or Sargassum (alga), with metal uptakes up to 0.79 mmol V/g dry AWUS, 0.54 mmol Cr/g, and 0.17 mmol Au/g. The bound metals could easily be eluted from the biosorbent (AWUS) by a simple alkali wash. Repeating 3 adsorption-desorption cycles without performance deterioration indicated the reusability of the biosorbent. The mechanism of anion biosorption was confirmed to be adsorption by electrostatic attraction. FTIR analyses indicated amide groups as the key sites for metal anion binding. They are particularly effective at low pH when they become fully protonated. The anionic metal speciation in the solution also played important role affecting the anion uptakes. Biosorption study in the V-Cr binary system established that the presence of vanadate greatly depressed the Cr uptakes, however, vanadate uptake was not interfered by chromate. The developed one-site anionic metal species adsorption equilibrium model, considering the non-ideality in the liquid phase and the interference of Cl -, agreed reasonably well with the anion adsorption by AWUS as a function of solution pH and ionic strength. Multi-metal equilibrium adsorption models extended from the Langmuir model effectively described the metal interference behaviour.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Volesky, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q3124.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z251d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dr24c"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The analytic center cutting plane method with semidefinite cuts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oskoorouchi, Mohammad R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We propose an analytic center cutting plane algorithm for semidefinite programming (SDP). Reformulation of the dual problem of SDP into an eigenvalue optimization, when the trace of any feasible primal matrix is a positive constant, is well known. We transform the eigenvalue optimization problem into a convex feasibility problem. The problem of interest seeks a feasible point in a bounded convex set, which contains a full dimensional ball with ε(&lt;1) radius and is contained in a compact convex set described by matrix inequalities, known as the set of localization. At each iteration, an approximate analytic center of the set of localization is computed. If this point is not in the solution set, an oracle is called to return a p-dimensional semidefinite cut. The set of localization then, is updated by adding the semidefinite cut through the center. We prove that the analytic center is recovered after adding a p-dimensional semidefinite cut in O(plog(p + 1)) damped Newton's iteration and that the ACCPM with semidefinite cuts is a fully polynomial approximation scheme. We report the numerical result of our algorithm when applied to the semidefinite relaxation of the Max-Cut problem.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goffin, Jean-Louis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk37x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr24c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematical optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Linear programming</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354g928"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular mechanisms of estrogen receptor signaling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eng, Frank Chung Sing, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The estrogen receptor (ER) is a ligand dependent transcriptional activator that belongs to the steroid/nuclear receptor superfamily. To probe the structure and function of the ER ligand binding domain (LBD), we developed a genetic screen in yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae using a library of reverse ERs screened with a low affinity estrogen agonist, 2-methoxyestrone. Mutants isolated from this screen demonstrated altered ligand binding and/or transactivation properties. One of these mutants, L536P, showed high levels of constitutive activity in several transiently transfected cells and a HeLa line that stably propagates an estrogen-sensitive reporter gene. This suggests that substitution of a proline at position 536 in the wild type ER (HEGO) induces a reversible conformational change in the region of AF-2 that partially mimics activation of the receptor by hormone binding. Activation of transcription by the ER requires the recruitment of different classes of coactivators. L536P interacted with coactivators in the absence of hormone and this constitutive interaction can be abolished by antiestrogens. We conclude that constitutive activity of L536P-HEGO is manifested to in part from constitutive coactivator binding. We also demonstrated that different classes of coactivators do not recognize the ER LBD in the same manner and can compete for binding to the ER LBD suggesting that different classes of coactivators recognize distinct but overlapping binding sites. Interestingly, coexpression of RIP140 blocked enhanced transactivation by HEGO observed in the presence of TIF-2, suggesting that RIP140 may play a negative role in ER signaling. Using a yeast two-hybrid system with the ER LBD as bait, we isolated a novel estrogen receptor cofactor (ERC) that interacts with the ER LBD in a hormone dependent manner. The primary structure of ERC consists of 4 ankyrin repeat domains, 2 LXXLL motifs and an ATP/GTP binding domain. ERC is highly expressed in ovary, testes, and spleen, with moderate levels in heart, brain, and placenta. ERC repressed ER transactivation in several cell lines in the presence of estradiol suggesting that ERC may function as a novel estrogen dependent repressor of the ER. Immunohistochemistry and confocal microscopy localized ERC to the cytoplasm with partial nuclear staining. Recently, synphilin-1, a novel protein that has been implicated in the pathogenesis of Parkinson's disease was isolated and is identical to ERC. A role for ERC in intracellular signaling through a membrane bound ER in the brain is currently being investigated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>White, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806150v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g928</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp72h"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Denitrification and nitrous oxide dynamics in the soil profile under two corn production systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elmi, Abdirashid A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Concerns for environmental quality stimulate the development of various management strategies that mitigate nutrient losses to the environment. Field experiments were conducted at St. Emmanuel, Quebec, from 1998 to 2000 to investigate the combined effects of water table management and N fertilizer application rates on corn yield, concentrations of NO3- -N in the soil profile and tile subsurface drainage water, denitrification and N2O production rates, and N2O:N2O+N 2 production ratios in the soil profile. There were two water table treatments: free drainage (FD) with open drains at a 1.0 m depth from the soil surface and subirrigation (SI) with a water table depth of 0.6 m below the soil surface, and two N fertilization rates: 120 kg N ha-1 (N120) and 200 kg N ha-1 (N 200) arranged in a split-plot design. Compared to FD, subirrigation reduced NO3--N concentration in the soil by up to 50% and in drainage water by 55 to 73%. Water table had little effect on corn yield during the study period. Greater denitrification rates under SI were not accompanied with greater N2O emissions as ratios of N2O:N2O+N2 were lower under SI than in FD plots. Denitrification rate, N2O emissions, and their ratios were unaffected by N rate. A second field experiment was initiated from 1999 to 2000 to assess impacts of tillage systems on NO3--N, denitrification, N2O, and ratios of denitrification end-products (N2O:N 2O+N2). The experiment was conducted on long-term momocropped corn experimental plots under conventional tillage (CT), reduced tillage (RT), and no-till (NT), located at the Macdonald Research Farm, McGill University. Soil NO3--N concentrations tended to be lower under RT than under NT or CT. Denitrification and N2O were similar among tillage systems. Approximately 50% of soil denitrification activity was measured within the 0.15--0.45 m soil layer. Consequently, we propose that sampling the 0--0.15 m soil layer alone, as is usually done, may not give an accurate picture of soil denitrification activity. Dissolved organic carbon concentrations remained high in all soil depths sampled, but was not affected by water table, N rate or tillage system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madramootoo, C.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hamel, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z006f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp72h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Soils -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Denitrification -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corn -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tillage -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hk80p"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Jewish Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The organization and use of documentary deposits in the near east from ancient to medieval times : libraries, archives, book collections and genizas</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Du Toit, Jaqueline Susann</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A multidisciplinary approach is utilized to assess the organization and use of ancient and medieval Near Eastern textual deposits. An elaborate survey of the published material in ancient Near Eastern studies and library and archival studies indicates a general and pervasive insensitivity to and misuse of key terminological constructs. The indistinct portrayal of the nature of ancient libraries and archives is identified as of particular concern; as well as a widespread disregard for the recognition of textual collections older than the famed Library of Alexandria. This dissertation endeavours to indicate the presence of distinct textual collective units in the ancient Near Eastern context on equal footing with their much later counterparts and more broadly defined than the traditional library and archive, to include entities such as the geniza, building and foundation deposits, and so forth. Furthermore, the ancient temple library, as a restricted and well-regulated collective entity, is suggested as representative of literary standardization in the Near East, and the canonization process of the Hebrew Bible, in particular. Ancient archives are attested as equally prevalent textual units, clearly distinguishable from adjunct textual deposits, often loosely, but incorrectly, termed "archives" in modern scholarly discourse. In conclusion, this dissertation reconsiders the status of the two traditionally most valued ancient textual entities, the Library of Assurbanipal and the Library of Alexandria, and concludes that these entities are atypical examples of ancient textual collections. As closest claimants to the improbable and often religiously imbued ideal of universal collection of information, these libraries erroneously became the impossible standards by which all ancient collections were measured and found wanting. As alternate, the applicability of the theoretical constructs proposed in the earlier part of this dissertation, such as the introduction of an in</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levy, B. Barry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b491h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hk80p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History, Medieval</dc:subject><dc:subject>Library Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>History, Ancient</dc:subject><dc:subject>History, Middle Eastern</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h116j"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Iron acquisition by Histophilus ovis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ekins, Andrew John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Five strains (9L, 642A, 714, 5688T and 3384Y) of Histophilus ovis were investigated with respect to iron acquisition. All strains used ovine, bovine and goat, but not porcine or human, transferrins (Tfs) as iron sources for growth. In solid phase binding assays, total membranes from only two (9L and 642A) of the five strains, grown under iron-restricted conditions, were able to bind Tfs (ovine, bovine and goat, but not porcine or human). However, when the organisms were grown under iron-restricted conditions in the presence of bovine Tf, total membranes from all strains exhibited Tf binding (as above); competition experiments demonstrated that all three Tfs (ovine, bovine and goat) were bound by the same receptor(s). An affinity isolation procedure allowed the isolation of two putative Tf-binding polypeptides (78 and 66 kDa) from total membranes of strains 9L and 642A grown under iron-restricted conditions, and from membranes of all strains if the growth medium also contained Tf. A gene encoding a Pasteurella multocida TbpA homologue was shown to be present in each of two representative strains (9L and 3384Y); these genes were sequenced and determined to be the structural genes encoding the 78-kDa Tf-binding polypeptides. The identification of a fur homologue and a Fur box within the promoter region of tbpA in both strains indicated that Fur (and iron) is responsible for the iron-repressible nature of Tf-binding activity. Although tbpA transcripts were detected by reverse transcription (RT)-PCR with RNA isolated from strains 9L and 3384Y grown under iron-restricted conditions, with strain 3384Y, and depending on the primer pair, tbpA transcripts were detected by RT-PCR predominantly when the RNA was isolated from cells grown under conditions of iron-restriction in the presence of Tf. The presence of an additional G in the tbpA gene of strain 3384Y grown under iron-replete conditions, compared to organisms grown under iron-restricted conditions plus bovine Tf, is</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Niven, D. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm63t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h116j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gram-negative bacteria -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iron -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microbial metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4j03d1504"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of [delta] opioid receptor function in rat brain by pharmacological and antisense techniques</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fraser, Graeme L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The opioid family of G-protein coupled receptors comprises four known receptor subtype genes (delta, mu, kappa, ORL1) and further receptor heterogeneity within each opioid receptor subfamily has been proposed. All four genes are expressed throughout the central nervous system and are believed to modulate a variety of behavioural responses including analgesia. Opiate drugs such as morphine that are selective for the mu receptor subtype are effective analgesics, but their chronic use is limited by the appearance of side effects such as respiratory depression, constipation and dependence. Consequently, the analgesic potential of agonists selective for other opioid receptors is under investigation. In this regard, previous studies suggest that delta agonists mediate antinociception, yet produce fewer adverse effects than mu agonists. To further investigate the cloned delta opioid receptor (DOR) as a target for novel analgesics, the pharmacological role of DOR in brain was evaluated in rats. First, we characterized delta agonist binding sites and receptor activation in rat brain membranes. We also introduced a novel antagonist radioligand, [125I]AR-M100613, to label tissues with low delta opioid receptor expression in order to support follow-up studies where radioligand binding was performed on rat brain membranes following antisense treatment. Second, we examined the behavioural response to delta agonists in rats. Deltorphin II and SNC80 (i.c.v.) were shown to induce antinociception in acute pain assays, and to reverse hyperalgesia following tissue inflammation induced by Freund's adjuvant with even greater potency. These findings indicate that delta receptors play an enhanced role in the modulation of descending pain pathways following tissue injury. Deltorphin II and SNC80 (i.c.v. ) were also shown to induce hyperlocomotor activity. Third we used antisense studies to demonstrate that the antinociceptive and locomotor stimulant effects of delta agonists are modulated by the cloned delta opioid receptor (DOR). In contrast to other delta agonists, the antinociceptive effects of DPDPE were not modulated by DOR antisense treatment but rather were blocked by a selective mu antagonist (CTOP) suggesting that DPDPE may activate mu sites in the brain rather than an alternate delta receptor subtype. Finally, we demonstrated that peptide nucleic acids (PNA, i.c.v.) can act as target-specific and sequence-selective antisense agents. In total, these findings demonstrate that DOR is an appropriate target for the development of novel analgesics and that PNA can serve as effective antisense agents for the determination of gene function for CNS targets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clarke, Paul B. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd41n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d1504</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Pharmaceutical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sh87w"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The heart rate response to alcohol intoxication and its relationship with alcohol consumption, delinquency, and intoxicated aggressive and disinhibited behaviors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Assaad, Jean-Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Alcohol abuse/dependence frequently co-occurs with antisocial personality disorder (ASPD) and conduct disorder (CD). Furthermore, crime studies have generally found that alcohol is involved in over 50% of violent crimes, and experimental studies support the notion that acute alcohol consumption indirectly increases the likelihood of aggressive and disinhibited behaviors in the laboratory. However, the mechanisms underlying alcohol's association with such behaviors remain unclear. The goals of this thesis were therefore to further elucidate potential mechanisms underlying (a) alcohol-induced aggressive, disinhibited behaviors and (b) the high comorbidity between delinquent, aggressive behaviors (characterizing CD/ASPD) and alcohol misuse/abuse/dependence. Thus, four studies were conducted, focusing on individual differences in the physiological response to alcohol intoxication. Specifically examined was the elevated heart rate (HR) response to alcohol, which is thought to reflect an increased sensitivity to alcohol-induced reward. Results of Study I indicated that high HR Responders to alcohol self-reported increased multiple year delinquency (physical aggression, theft, and destruction of property), as well as more alcohol consumption and an increased positive subjective feeling following intoxication, as compared to low HR Responders. Furthermore, a high HR response was related to increased extraversion, disinhibition, boredom susceptibility, and total sensation seeking. Study II revealed that Aggressive Sons of Male Alcoholics (Agg-SOMAs) had the highest intoxicated HR response, and reported the most alcohol consumption, as compared to Non-Agg-SOMAs, or Agg - or Non-Agg - Non-SOMAs. Studies III and IV revealed that intoxicated high HR responders exhibited the most physical aggression (assessed by the Taylor Aggression Paradigm), as well as the most behavioral disinhibition (assessed by the Go/No-Go task) as compared to sober high HR Responders, or sober/intoxicated low HR responders. In summary, individuals with a high HR response to alcohol appear to have an increased propensity for multiple addictive, disinhibited and aggressive behaviors. This determines a phenotype of both potential heuristic and clinical importance. These findings are discussed within the context of a hypothetical model of (a) the high comorbidity between alcohol use/misuse and aggression/ASPD, and (b) the increased likelihood of alcohol-induced aggressive, disinhibited behaviors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pihl, R. O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v88x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sh87w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aggressiveness -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alcohol -- Physiological effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antisocial personality disorders</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537276j"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Surface-based characterization of intra-surgical brain deformations in image-guided surgery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Audette, Michel A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Image-guided surgery (IGS) is a technique for localizing anatomical structures on the basis of volumetric image data and for determining the optimal surgical path to reach these structures, by the means of a localization device, or probe, whose position is tracked over time. The usefulness of this technology hinges on the accuracy of the transformation between the image volume and the space occupied by the patient anatomy and spanned by the probe. Unfortunately, in neurosurgery this transformation can be degraded by intra-surgical brain shift, which often measures more than 10 mm and can exceed 25 mm. I propose a method for characterizing brain shift that is based on non-rigid surface registration, and can be combined with a constitutively realistic finite element approach for volumetric displacement estimation. The proposed registration method integrates in a unified framework all of the stages required to estimate the movement of the cortical surface in the operating room: model-based segmentation of the pre-operative brain surface in magnetic resonance image data, range-sensing of the cortex in the OR, range-MR rigid transformation computation, and range-based non-rigid brain motion estimation. The brain segmentation technique is an adaptation of the surface evolution model. Its convergence to the brain boundary is the result of a speed term restricted to white and grey matter voxels made explicit by a classifier, and the final result is post-processed to yield a Closest Point Map of the brain surface in MR space. In turn, this Closest Point Map is used to produce the homologous pairs required to determine a highly efficient, 2D spline-based, Iterative Closest Point (ICP) non-rigid surface registration. The baseline for computing intra-operative brain displacement, as well as the initial starting point of the non-rigid ICP registration, is determined by a very good rigid range-MR transformation, produced by a simple procedure for relating the range coordinate system to that of the probe, and ultimately to that of the MR volume. Finally, this thesis also features a review of image guidance for brain surgery, a published survey of anatomical surface registration, and a literature review of biomechanical modeling of brain tissue.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Siddiqi, Kaleem</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Peters, Terry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p94t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537276j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp73s"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Price schedules coordination for electricity pool markets</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Legbedji, Alexis Motto</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We consider the optimal coordination of a class of mathematical programs with equilibrium constraints, which is formally interpreted as a resource-allocation problem. Many decomposition techniques were proposed to circumvent the difficulty of solving large systems with limited computer resources. The considerable improvement in computer architecture has allowed the solution of large-scale problems with increasing speed. Consequently, interest in decomposition techniques has waned. Nonetheless, there is an important class of applications for which decomposition techniques will still be relevant, among others, distributed systems---the Internet, perhaps, being the most conspicuous example---and competitive economic systems. Conceptually, a competitive economic system is a collection of agents that have similar or different objectives while sharing the same system resources. In theory, constructing a large-scale mathematical program and solving it centrally, using currently available computing power can optimize such systems of agents. In practice, however, because agents are self-interested and not willing to reveal some sensitive corporate data, one cannot solve these kinds of coordination problems by simply maximizing the sum of agent's objective functions with respect to their constraints. An iterative price decomposition or Lagrangian dual method is considered best suited because it can operate with limited information. A price-directed strategy, however, can only work successfully when coordinating or equilibrium prices exist, which is not generally the case when a weak duality is unavoidable. Showing when such prices exist and how to compute them is the main subject of this thesis. Among our results, we show that, if the Lagrangian function of a primal program is additively separable, price schedules coordination may be attained. The prices are Lagrange multipliers, and are also the decision variables of a dual program. In addition, we propose a new form of a</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Galiana, F. D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dh41d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp73s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r4765"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Margen y centro : dramaturgia femenina Brasileña contemporánea</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vieira de Andrade, Ana Lúcia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this thesis is to give an account of the position taken by certain women dramatists in the context of both box-office success and theatre criticism in Brazil in the latter half of the twentieth century in order to provide a panoramic view of the way the Brazilian theater canon reacts to the work of women authors, by either incorporating it or not, according to political and social circumstances. It is hoped then that a more comprehensive vision of these dramatists will result than that of the traditional academic criticism which either elevates by acceptance or dismisses by ignoring or playing down their work. The production of three dramatists will be analysed here, namely, those plays by Leilah Assuncao, Maria Adelaide Amaral and Isis Baiao which fall into the period 1969--1999, and which exemplify two key tendencies in the Brazilian theatre of the last thirty years. These tendencies are: first, the attempt to widen the traditional horizon of politicized theatre by adding to its socio-political concerns a focus on the individual and his/her particular agenda, and, secondly, the break with any specifically aesthetic or conceptual format on stage in a blurring of the legacies of tradition and the vanguard, in which a "hybridism" of form and language is particularly noticeable in the privileging of a kind of writing that is not bound by formal limits. Such an analysis has made it possible to highlight how determined types of reaction may be altered along the time when different interpretive parameters are used by the critical community and by the public. While a certain sympathy is shown here for the feminist reading of the ideological bases of the literary canon, this is done not only to corroborate the masculine bent of such a canon to the exclusion of the Other, but also to prove that the criteria regulating excellence are products of a specific ideology which changes according to its sociohistorical context. The ultimate goal here is, thus, to make</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sibbald, K. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md49r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r4765</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brazilian drama -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women dramatists, Brazilian -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b778b"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of human class I 1,2-mannosidases involved in N-glycan biosynthesis and the role of murine 1,2-mannosidase IB in embryogenesis and development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tremblay, Linda O.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Class I alpha1,2-mannosidases (glycosylhydrolase family 47) form the Man5GlcNAc2 substrate for the synthesis of complex and hybrid N-glycans that are absolutely required for mammalian development. A human alpha1,2-mannosidase cDNA encoding endoplasmic reticulum alpha1,2-mannosidase I was characterized. This enzyme hydrolyses the terminal middle arm alpha1,2-linked mannose residue of Man9GlcNAc2, thus forming Man 8GlcNAc2 isomer B. It has been implicated in targeting misfolded glycoproteins for degradation. Furthermore, two novel human Golgi alpha1,2-mannosidase cDNAs, IB and IC, encoding distinct activities that trim Man9-8GlcNAc2 to Man5GlcNAc2 were characterized. The Golgi alpha1,2-mannosidases do not form Man8GlcNAc2 isomer B and are thus complementary to the endoplasmic reticulum enzyme. The genes encoding the human enzymes are localized on different chromosomal regions but their genomic organization is highly conserved. Therefore, late evolutionary gene duplication likely gave rise to this gene family. Northern blot analysis revealed that both the human and mouse Golgi alpha1,2-mannosidase paralogs, IA, IB and IC, display distinct tissue-specific expression thus the genes are independently regulated. Furthermore, mouse Golgi alpha1,2-mannosidase gene expression is developmentally regulated. During early postimplantation development, Northern blot analysis revealed Golgi alpha1,2-mannosidase IA and IB transcripts are expressed at relatively high levels whereas alpha1,2-mannosidase IC transcript expression remains relatively constant throughout embryogenesis. The Golgi alpha1,2-mannosidase IB gene was ablated in the mouse germline in order to investigate its physiological roles. Preliminary results suggest that Golgi alpha1,2-mannosidase IB plays a critical role in the synthesis of N-glycans required for embryonic development and that it is required for neonatal viability.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Herscovics, Annette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838219g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b778b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m5647"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"We shall be one people" : early modern French perceptions of the Amerindian body</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Van Eyck, Masarah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation analyzes seventeenth- and eighteenth-century French perceptions of the bodies of Indians in New France and Louisiana. It reveals that all French authors who visited New France in the early seventeenth century believed that human differences were mutable and, with instruction and land cultivation, Indians would physically and culturally assimilate into French colonial society---if Europeans did not degenerate from life in the wilderness first. Beginning in the late seventeenth century, missionary disillusionment, colonial projections of order and later Enlightenment concepts of natural rights and systems of nature prompted authors to reformulate these early perceptions. As Indians appeared unwilling or unable to adopt civilized manners, some authors concluded that natives did not possess the reason needed to do so. By the late eighteenth century, some colonial officials and European naturalists suggested that the physique and morals of North American Indians were not mutable but, instead, that Indians in French North America were permanently and essentially incapable of "improving" either their bodies or their minds. Historians studying seventeenth- and eighteenth-century colonial perceptions of North American Indians have generally analyzed European depictions of Indians with twentieth-century understandings of human difference. By examining French perceptions of Indians with early modern understandings of the body, this thesis seeks to see natives through the eyes of the authors who described them. The sources for this study include French travelogues and missionary accounts from New France and Louisiana which were published contemporaneously, correspondence and memoirs which have since been published and archived letters from colonial administrators writing from Canada and Louisiana.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boulle, Pierre H.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Morantz, Toby</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t62p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m5647</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canada -- History -- To 1763 (New France)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indians of North America -- First contact with Europeans</dc:subject><dc:subject>Body, Human</dc:subject><dc:subject>Public opinion -- France</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indians of North America -- Public opinion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gf651"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relaxational dynamics of random heteropolymers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Villeneuve, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We investigate the equilibrium properties and the relaxational dynamics of random heteropolymers in three dimensions. We proceed by studying an isolated random heteropolymer without an explicit solvent before studying different types of random heteropolymers in a monomeric solvent. Both equilibrium and relaxational data were obtained by performing extensive off-lattice molecular dynamics simulations. An equilibrium "phase diagram" is determined in all cases which facilitates the determination of a characteristic temperature separating extended states from collapsed states of the heteropolymer. This temperature is an increasing function of the strength of the random interactions and of the solvent density. It allows us to determine the appropriate initial and final temperatures to be used for the quenches from an extended coil to a collapsed globule. In particular for long isolated chains the heteropolymer collapse is a process which involves two distinct time regimes; both are energetically of stretched exponential form. Our simulation clearly shows the nature of the relaxation process where the formation of locally collapsed clusters takes place first followed by a global aggregation of the local blobs leading to the two collapse time regimes. Finally, we determine the effect of an explicit solvent on the collapse dynamics of a random heteropolymer. We bridge the difference between implicit and explicit solvents in two steps. First, we consider a heteropolymer with random interaction between the monomers, immersed in a purely repulsive solvent and we find that the rate of collapse increases with the strength of the random interaction but remains almost independent of the solvent density for higher values of the strength of the random interaction. Secondly, we look at a random heteropolymer with random interaction between the monomers and the solvent particles and we find that the rate of collapse increases slightly with density but is almost constant at low dens</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zuckermann, Martin</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Guo, Hong</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm10m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf651</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z708z38r"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bodies imaged : women, self-objectification and subjectification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robinson, Shelagh Wynne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Research on the psychology of women, and women's negative embodied experiences, frequently implicates societal practices of objectification as catalysts for the internalization of objectification in women, or self-objectification. While extant models and theories provide excellent frameworks for identifying the causes, consequences and development of self-objectification in women, much detail is required before these formulations achieve their full clinical application. Information on women's immediate emotional, cognitive, and behavioural responses to objectifying social experiences would assist clinicians and clients to identify common concomitants of objectification and self-objectification, particularly those that aggregate over time into long-term negative psychological outcomes. In the present study, hypotheses regarding women's social experiences of objectification and self-objectification were tested on 228 college-age women who completed the Objectification Response Questionnaire (ORQ; Robinson, 2001), and measures assessing Objectified Body Consciousness (OBC; McKinley &amp; Hyde, 1996) and Self-Objectification (SOQ; Noll &amp; Fredrickson, 1997). On the ORQ, participants report on emotional and cognitive responses, as well as behavioural responses in the form of social looking, to hypothetical scenarios depicting social experiences of objectifying gazing by a stranger. ORQ responses were unrelated to SOQ scores, but were related to OBC Self-Surveillance and Control Beliefs subscales. Interactions of OBC scores and observer characteristics of gender and attractiveness were also significantly related to ORQ scores. Results are discussed in the context of augmenting prevailing theories and models in the area of women and self-objectification, specifically in the form of clinical applications to disrupt certain social experiences of objectification and self-objectification, and facilitate behaviours, thoughts and attitudes associated with resilience, competence and subjectification.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lavers, Robert</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Maroun, Ted</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw653.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z38r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women -- Psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Body image in women</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gaze -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311r00m"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sweet blood and power : making diabetics count</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rock, Melanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As recently as 1995, sweet blood did not resonate broadly as an urgent transnational concern. This thesis chronicles how diabetes mellitus, sweet blood, became recognized as a social problem besetting Canada, among many other countries. This ethnographic study brings anthropological theories---developed for the most part to analyze the lives of "non-Western" peoples---to bear on "Western" philosophy, science, medicine, mass media, governments, and commerce. Throughout, this thesis challenges received wisdom about disease, technologies, kinship, commodification, embodiment, and personhood. This thesis argues that a statistical concept, the population, is the linchpin of both politics and economics in large-scale societies. Statistically-fashioned populations, combined with the conviction that the future can be partially controlled, undergird the very definition of diabetes as a disease. In turn, biomedical knowledge about diabetes grounds the understanding of sweet blood as a social problem in need of better management. The political economy of sweet blood shows that, under "Western" eyes, persons can remain intact while their bodies---down to their very cells---divide and multiply, both literally and figuratively. As members of statistically-fashioned populations, human beings have a patent existence and many "statistical doubles." These statistical doppelgangers help shape feelings, actions, identities, and even the length of human lives. They permit countless strangers and "lower" nonhuman beings---among them, mice, flies, and bacteria---to count as kin. Through the generation and use of statistics, people and their body parts undergo valuation and commodification, but are neither bought nor sold. The use of statistics to commodify human beings and body parts, this thesis finds, inevitably anchors biomedical practice, biomedical research, health policies, and the marketing of pharmaceuticals and all other things known to affect health.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lock, Margaret</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qn64z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r00m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diabetics -- Canada -- Social conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diabetes -- Social aspects -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397983v"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Low temperature magnetic force microscopy studies of superconducting niobium films</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roseman, Mark A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Low temperature magnetic force microscopy studies of superconducting niobium films have been undertaken with the goal of studying the interplay between artificial pinning centers and magnetic vortices. Measurements were performed using a custom built low temperature magnetic force microscope, capable of operation at temperatures ranging from 4.2 K to room temperature. Special attention has been paid to optimizing the instrumentation through a detailed study of the noise characteristics, with particular emphasis placed on achieving a large signal-to-noise ratio and corresponding high force gradient sensitivity. Magnetic force spectroscopy data has been used to deduce the critical temperature of the superconducting samples, based upon the repulsive Meissner interaction between the magnetic tip and the sample. Images of vortices as a function of applied magnetic field demonstrate the expected linear relation between vortex density and field strength, and confirms that only single vortices, each carrying one flux quantum, are observed. Two different methods are put forward to determine the magnetic penetration depth; one using magnetic force spectroscopy, the other using constant height imaging of vortices. Images of vortices as a function of temperature demonstrate that as temperatures rise, vortices become more easily depinned during the scanning process through interactions with the magnetic field of the tip. Dissipation images of vortices suggest eddy current damping as well as vortex motion within potential wells as major sources of energy loss. Studies on a patterned niobium film show that only interstitial vortices are easily detectable by MFM, but that a strong tip influence results in significant tip induced motion of these vortices around the antidots.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grutter, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c13g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397983v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956h546"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The hermeneutical theory of Naṣr Ḥāmid Ab ̄ưZayd : an analytical study of his method of interpreting the Qurān</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rahman, Yusuf, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Through an examination of the writings of Naṣr Ḥamid Abu Zayd (b. 1943), this dissertation attempts to study his theory and method of interpretation. Not only are these analyzed within the socio-political and historical contexts that tended to inform the development of his thought, but also in the light of hermeneutics and of modern approaches to the Qur'an. Since his writings have led certain Egyptian Islamists to charge him with the crime of apostasy, the thesis also examines the main reasons for their objections. It argues that the crux of the problem lies not so much in the novelty of Abu Zayd's theories as it does in the theological opposition of the Islamists to the liberal Muslims.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boullata, Issa J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d151d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h546</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Abū Zayd, Naṣr Ḥāmid</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>