<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dd00s"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Internally headed constructions in Japanese : a unified approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hosoi, Hironobu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis discusses Internally Headed Constructions in  Japanese, specifically, the "Counter-Equi NP" (CENP) construction and the  "Internally Headed Relative Clause" (MC) construction. In both of these  constructions, an NP within the embedded clause is interpreted as an argument of the  matrix clause. There are two major goals in this thesis. The first goal is to  provide a unified syntactic and semantic analysis of the CENP and IHRC  constructions. I argue that the CENP construction is basically the same as the IHRC  construction, even though some previous researchers have assumed the contrary  (Kuroda 1992, 1999, Ohara 1996, Shimoyama 1999, among others). Furthermore, I argue  that both the CENP NP and the MC NP are arguments of the matrix  verbs. The second goal is to closely examine the syntactic and semantic  properties of the CENP construction and the IHRC construction. As discussed by Hoshi  (1995) and Shimoyama (1999), the interpretation of the argument which is  "modified by the IHRC" in these constructions is quite similar to that of  E-type pronouns (Evans 1977a,b; 1980). In addition, there are some facts that show  that the event of the embedded clause is linguistically connected to the event of  the matrix clause. Regarding all these properties, the CENP construction behaves in  the same manner as the IHRC construction. In this thesis, adapting the E-type  pronoun analyses of the IHRC (Hoshi 1995 and Shimoyama 1999), I propose an  alternative analysis of the CENP construction and the IHRC construction to capture  those properties. Moreover, even though the CENP construction and the IHRC  construction share many properties with each other, there are some differences  between them (Shimoyama 1999, among others). In particular, the CENP cannot appear  as the subject of the matrix clause, whereas the IHRC can. However, we observe  restrictions on possible internal heads with regard to the subject IHRC, in contrast  to the CENP. This thesis tries to account for those differences under a unified  analysis of the CENP construction and the IHRC construction, together with an  analysis of the subject MC, which adapts Shimoyama's (1999) analysis of the  IHRC.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, Mark</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838108r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dd00s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Japanese language -- Syntax</dc:subject><dc:subject>Japanese language -- Relative clauses</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62f868g"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Urban metaphors in Hong Kong media art : reimagining place identity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jim, Alice Ming Wai, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines representations of the city and media  art in Hong Kong from the late 1980s to the present to establish a link between the  ways in which the city's place identity is re-imag(in)ed. Charting the course of  media art in Hong Kong in relation to the parallel development of contemporary art  in the region, it provides critical analyses of dominant urban metaphors that play a  significant role, both locally and internationally, in the current representation of  Hong Kong and its artistic practices. Specifically, the study explores how media  artists have been dealing with four central urban metaphors that frequently arise in  discussions of Hong Kong in relation to its place identity: City in Transition,  Panoramic City, Compact City, and Mobile City. The hypothesis of this essay concerns  the ways in which both the selected media artists and their works negotiate central  urban metaphors in their search for Hong Kong's place identity. I designate each of  these negotiations as a 'spatial portrait': a space of representation in which  social experiences and relations are reconstructed and investigated. Through the  critical analysis of these spatial portraits, I consider the development, shifts and  imbrications of urban metaphors for Hong Kong and their contributions to, as well as  their limitations for, understandings of artistic representations of urban space.  Recognizing the local-global nexus from which these works emerge through  considerations of the imaging of Hong Kong in the media and tourism industries, I  propose an interpretation of the metaphor of the Mobile City as an updated version  of the City of Transition. Ultimately, this dissertation offers an understanding of  urban metaphors in Hong Kong media art in relation to the re-imag(in)ing of place  identity situated between globalization discourse and the cultural politics of urban  space, location and representation. It concludes that contemporary art's  contribution to t</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ross, Christine</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547r86f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f868g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Video art -- China -- Hong Kong</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hong Kong (China) -- In art</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074v63q"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The architectural theory of the Mānasāra</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jacob, Jose, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The extant Manasara is one of the authoritative treatises of  vastusastra, traditional Indian architectural theory. The dissertation addresses the  question of the nature of vastusastra, traditional architectural theory, as  enunciated in the Manasara, and the relationship of theory to traditional practice.  Vastusastra claims itself to be a priori with respect to practice. Two aspects of  theory, theology and nomology, constitute the ontological and epistemological  foundation and structure for this claim. From this sastraic perspective, practice is  understood as mere application of rules. However, a closer hermeneutical reading of  the text reveals the dialectical nature of theory itself, in both its theological  and nomological aspects. This dialectic obtains in the relationship between theory  and practice as a certain reciprocity between them, and in the parallelism between  making the temple (the paradigmatic architectural object) and writing the treatise.  Thus, a more precise understanding of the nature of traditional theory and its  relationship to traditional practice is arrived at through this exercise. Such a  calibrated understanding of vastusastra is indispensable in addressing the issue of  the proper role that it may play in contemporary Indian architectural practice which  is constituted in the modern scientific and technological mode.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd49n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v63q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture -- India -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zb595"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Imperialist intent - colonial response : the art collection and cultural milieu of Lord Strathcona in nineteenth-century Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pierce, Alexandria, 1949-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses the nineteenth-century art collection of  Donald Alexander Smith, Lord Strathcona (1820--1914), in relation to intersecting  questions of imperialism, colonial relations, and cultural status. Both the  formation of the collection and its dispersal are linked to a dialectic of cultural  hegemony and national identity in nineteenth-century Canada. Smith came penniless to  Montreal from Scotland in 1838, became the wealthiest man in Canada by the end of  the century, and is known as Lord Strathcona after being raised to the peerage by  Queen Victoria in 1897. My discussion of the rise and fall of Strathcona's  collection is informed by postcolonial theory and its critical re-reading of  imperialism. While British imperialism was the ideology that governed Strathcona's  activities, Anthony Giddens's structuration theory is introduced to account for how  personal agency remains operative within this dominant ideology. Strathcona formed a significant collection of European paintings  and Asian art, which was, however, largely dispersed by the institution charged with  its care, thus reducing its significance. Krzysztof Pomian's concept of collectors  as select individuals who mediate symbolic cultural power through semiotic  constructs provides an important methodological anchor for an analysis of the  collector and his collection, as does Carol Duncan's work on the motivation to  collect art and to structure cultural identity through control of museums. As well,  the princely model of collecting reveals the humanist values operative throughout  the centuries by comparison of Strathcona to the Medici in terms of the deployment  of spectacle. This thesis makes use of primary source materials to compare  Strathcona's collection to several of his peers in order to place him in his  cultural milieu during a time in Canadian history when Montreal was a British  enclave in a French province. Analysis of fragmented primary source inventories,  catalogues, personal letters, and records held by the Montreal Museum of Fine Arts  and the National Archives of Canada, identification of paintings documented in the  Notman photographs of 1914--1915, and my tracing of the public portraits of  Strathcona by Robert Harris still on view in Montreal institutions allowed me to  create useful inventories that previously did not exist.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83kz86d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb595</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art -- Private collections -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Imperialism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strathcona and Mount Royal, Donald Alexander Smith, Baron, 1820-1914 -- Art collections</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rh50n"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Alternative mechanisms to generate short CDPCux isoforms in cancer cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goulet, Brigitte Nicole</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>CDP/Cux is a transcription factor involved in the control of  cellular differentiation and proliferation. It contains four DNA binding domains,  three Cut Repeats (CR) and a Cut homeodomain (HD). The full-length p200 protein  makes an unstable interaction with DNA via CR1CR2 and is responsible for the CCAAT  displacement activity of CDP/Cux. A more stable DNA binding activity could also be  detected. This particular activity increased as cells progress from G1 to S phase of  the cell cycle following two events. One event is the dephosphorylation of CR3HD by  the by the cdc25A phosphatase. The other event involves the proteolytic processing  of the full length CDP/Cux protein into a p110 isoform. At the transcriptional  level, the p110 protein is able to repress the P21waf1/ Cip1 gene promoter and to  activate the DNA polymerase alpha gene promoter as well as other S phase specific  genes. In human uterine leiomyomas, an increase in the steady state levels of p110  was observed compared to the normal surrounding myometrium. The goal of my project was to identify the protease involved in  the proteolytic processing of CDP/Cux. I showed that the "lysosomal"  cysteine protease cathepsin L translocates to the nucleus in a cell cycle dependent  manner and was able to cleave p200 CDP/Cux into the p110 form. I also demonstrated  that this protease was translated at downstream AUGs to produce truncated proteins  devoid of signal peptide. These truncated cathepsin L species were unable to enter  the endoplasmic reticulum and be routed to the lysosomes. In transformed cells, I  found that CDP/Cux processing was increased and no longer regulated in a cell cycle  dependent manner. This correlated with the enhanced expression and nuclear activity  of cathepsin L. I also identified a novel shorter CDP/Cux isoform, which contains  only CR3HD as DNA binding domains and is translated from an mRNA initiated within  the intron 20 of CUTL1. Interestingly, the intron20-initiated mRNA was distributed  in a tissue specific manner, and was expressed only weakly or not at all in normal  breast tissue and in human mammary epithelial cells. However, it was detected in  many breast tumor cell lines and invasive lobular carcinomas. These results  indicated that in cancer, several mechanisms could generate shorter active CDP/Cux  isoforms, and that these amino-terminally truncated CDP/Cux proteins play a role in  tumorigenesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nepveu, Alain</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fm00s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh50n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qc66p"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Large scale integer programming : a novel solution method and application</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gzara, Fatma</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Integer programming is a powerful modeling tool for a variety of  decision making problems such as in telecommunications network design and in routing  and scheduling. Integer programming models of realistic problems are large in size  and pose serious challenge to available software. This creates an urgent need for  solution methodologies that can deal with their size and complexity. In this thesis,  we focus on the theoretical development, implementation and testing of a novel  methodology: an interior-point branch-and-price algorithm with cut generation for  large scale integer programming. The methodology applies to any integer program but is built for  a general class of integer programming that has a large, possibly exponential set of  constraints. It starts by applying a decomposition method to the complicating  constraints. We focus on Lagrangian relaxation or Dantzig-Wolfe decomposition; both  lead to a master problem with an exponential number of variables and constraints.  The same analysis applies when one starts by relaxing the exponential constraints  and then applying a decomposition method. In both cases, one has to solve  iteratively a master problem that is updated by appending violated cuts and columns.  For that, we propose a cut and column generation algorithm based on analytic  centers. The cut and column generation algorithm solves a restricted  master problem using a primal analytic center cutting plane method to obtain a bound  on the original problem. The bound may be poor in quality since most of the  complicating constraints are relaxed. To strengthen the bound, we generate violated  constraints and append them to the master problem. At this point we use available  information to warm-start the solution of the updated restricted master problem.  This is done using a dual Newton method to calculate the next analytic center, after  which we proceed with the primal method. The bound is then embedded within a branch-and-bound algorithm  leading to a branch-and-price algorithm. In fact, the algorithm is more than a  branchand-price since it is able to deal with valid cuts added at the level of the  master problem. This is a major step towards an interior-point  branch-andcut-and-price algorithm. For an efficient integration of the cut and  column generation algorithm within branch-and-bound, we use available information  from a parent node to warm-start the calculation of the bound at child nodes. This  is achieved by a dual Newton method.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goffin, Jean-Louis</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f637n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qc66p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integer programming</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r144j"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Differential effects of left-and right-hemisphere brain damage on the ability to use context in lexical ambiguity resolution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grindrod, Christopher M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent research has argued that the intact functioning of both  the left (LH) and right cerebral hemispheres (RE) is integral for comprehending  lexically ambiguous words (Chiarello, 1998; Faust &amp; Chiarello, 1998; Faust &amp;  Gemsbacher, 1996). While studies of neurologically intact individuals have  attributed specific functions to the LH and RH, studies of brain-damaged patients  have failed to provide complementary evidence for these hemispheric abilities. In  addition, the majority of studies have focused on ambiguity resolution in  single-sentence (local) contexts, and, as such, do not address whether each  hemisphere is sensitive to different types of context, a factor which could  potentially serve to modulate brain-damaged patients' ability to resolve ambiguity.  To illuminate the role of the cerebral hemispheres in ambiguity resolution and to  explore the sensitivity of each hemisphere to different types of context, three  studies were undertaken in this thesis. The first study examined  left-hemisphere-damaged (LHD) nonfluent aphasic, right-hemisphere-damaged (RHD) and  non-brain-damaged (NBD) control subjects' ability to use a single-sentence local  context to resolve lexically ambiguous words. Results indicated that both patient  groups were unable to use this type of context. While LHD patients activated both  meanings regardless of context at a short (0 ms) ISI and no meanings at a longer  (750 ms) ISI, RHD patients only activated more frequent first meanings at both ISIs.  The second study explored these same groups' ability to use a two-sentence global  context. Results of this experiment in part paralleled those of the previous one,  showing that LHD patients were unable to activate any meanings at either ISI,  whereas RHD patients, at both ISIs, again activated more frequent meanings  regardless of context. The final study investigated these individuals' ability to  use a four-sentence discourse context. Findings of this study, across all groups,</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Shari</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35695096.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r144j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741s308"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the improvement of calcium uptake into micropropagated potato</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Habib, Ahsan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Various aspects of Ca2+ uptake into greenhouse-grown potato  plants and micropropagated potato plantlets were examined, including the movement of  Ca2+ into potato plants and tubers, identification of Ca-packing genotypes and  assessment of the effect of improved medium Ca2+ level on different parameters such  as plantlet growth, microtuber induction, yield and tissue Ca concentration. The  effect of exogenous vitamin Ds and UV-elicited endogenous vitamin D synthesis on  regulation of 45Ca 2+ uptake into plantlet shoots was also examined. Safranin dye  was not as suitable as the tracer 45Ca2+ for monitoring translocation of Ca2+ into  tubers. Uptake of Ca2+ into tubers occurred indirectly through the main basal roots  and stolon roots and directly through tuber periderm. Liquid scintillation counting  and flame atomic absorption spectrophotometry were used to screen six potato  cultivars and two wild species for ability to take up Ca2+ from treatment solutions  containing high or low Ca2+ levels. In vitro potato micropropagation,  microtuberization, and tissue calcium concentration were compared for six cultivars  when Murashige-Skoog basal medium Ca2+ level was increased from 3, to 5 or 15 mM.  All aspects of growth including shoot dry weight, early microtuber induction,  microtuber yield and tissue Ca concentration were improved when medium Ca2+ level  was 15 mM. Cultivar Bintje was the most efficient genotype at accumulating Ca 2+  from treatment solutions or growth media containing high or low Ca2+ levels. Vitamin  Ds improved 45Ca 2+ uptake into shoots of micropropagated potato plantlets and D 3  was more efficient in this regard than D2 or a combination of D3 and D2. Plantlets  had increased 45Ca 2+ uptake when exposed to UV irradiation compared with the  untreated control plantlets. Plantlets given a 24 hour interval in the dark after UV  exposure had even greater 45Ca2+ uptake, suggesting that vitamin D, metabolites,  specifically calcitriol (1, 25(OH)2-v</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donnelly, D. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z135t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s308</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Potatoes -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calcium</dc:subject><dc:subject>Potatoes -- Micropropagation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354f744"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanism of endoplasmic reticulum localization and oligomerization state of Saccharomyces cerevisiae [alpha] 1, 2-mannosidase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Massaad, Michel Jean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, the mechanism of endoplasmic reticulum  localization of Saccharomyces cerevisiae alpha1,2-mannosidase is studied.  alpha1,2-mannosidase is a type II membrane glycoprotein localized in the endoplasmic  reticulum, yet it does not have any of the known endoplasmic reticulum localization  signals. Immunofluorescence studies show that the endoplasmic reticulum  localization of alpha1,2-mannosidase depends on the Golgi protein Rer1p, since in  rer1-deleted cells, alpha1,2-mannosidase migrates to the vacuoles. Furthermore,  alpha1,2-mannosidase acquires Golgi-specific carbohydrate modification. These  results show that the steady state endoplasmic reticulum localization of  alpha1,2-mannosidase involves recycling from the Golgi apparatus. The transmembrane  domain of alpha1,2-mannosidase is important for endoplasmic reticulum localization  since fusing it to the Golgi protein Kre2p results in the endoplasmic reticulum  localization of the chimera in an Rer1p-dependent manner. Mutation of the polar  residues in the transmembrane domain do not affect endoplasmic reticulum  localization of alpha1,2-mannosidase, nor Rer1p-dependent recycling, indicating that  the polar residues are not important for these processes. alpha1,2-Mannosidase and  Rer1p interact, determined using the split-ubiquitin system, a genetic method  adapted to study membrane protein interactions in vivo. Therefore, the transmembrane  domain of alpha1,2-mannosidase mediates recycling from the Golgi apparatus in a  mechanism that involves interaction with the Golgi protein Rer1p. When solubilized and subjected to gel filtration analysis,  endogenous alpha1,2-mannosidase is eluted on Sephacryl S-200 as twice the molecular  weight of the purified recombinant enzyme lacking its transmembrane domain.  Immunoprecipitation studies show that alpha1,2-mannosidase can form a homodimer.  Furthermore, mutation of the asparagine residue at position 3, or the tyrosine  residues at positions 20 and 21, prevents dimerization.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Herscovics, Annette</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf08t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f744</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494900b"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acylation stimulating protein : identification of a novel effect, receptor interaction and intracellular signaling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maslowska, Magdalena H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Obesity is an ever-growing problem of our society and,  therefore, understanding the underlying endocrine causes is vital to both the  prevention and treatment of this disease. This present thesis work was undertaken to  better understand the impact of Acylation Stimulating Protein (ASP), an adipokine,  on the physiology and pathophysiology of the adipose tissue. I have demonstrated,  for the first time, that ASP participates in the recruitment of preadipocytes to  become adipocytes (differentiation process). Although, the ASP effects were  comparable to those of insulin, preliminary microarray analysis indicates that the  early intracellular signaling pathways are likely quite different for both hormones.  Furthermore, I have identified and begun to characterize an ASP receptor initially  identified as C5L2. I have demonstrated that binding affinity of ASP and C3a  (immediate ASP precursor) to C5L2 is similar to that observed in cells that are  responsive to ASP (triglyceride synthesis stimulation, TGS). I have also shown, for  the first time, that C5L2 is expressed in human adipose tissue, human skin  fibroblasts and 3T3-L1 preadipocytes. Finally, the ASP signaling pathway resulting  in increased TG synthesis has began to be explored using a "shot gun"  approach. This initial phase of research has provided evidence of the involvement of  phospholipase C and phosphoinositide 3-kinase in ASP signaling. Overall, the data  presented in this thesis defines more clearly ASP-cell interaction and reveals  potential targets for pharmacological agents that may prevent or slow down  development of obesity in the future.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cianfione, Katherine</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v358.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494900b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732d951z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of a model system for the mechanistic study of gene targeting</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paiement, Jean-Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gene targeting is a process of recombinational exchange between  a foreign molecule of DNA and its homologous chromosomal counterpart whereby the  cellular machinery involved in homologous recombination accomplishes sequence  exchange. The widespread use of gene targeting as a basic research and/or  therapeutic tool has been precluded by its inherent inefficiency. Although many  studies have reported improved gene targeting efficacy via manipulation of  homologous recombination-associated proteins, reports examining the underlying  molecular mechanisms of gene targeting are scant. Improvement in our understanding  of these molecular mechanisms will undoubtedly lead to advancements in the study of  genetic disease, and perhaps to the development of viable human gene therapy. To  this end, the following is a report of the development and preliminary assessment of  a model system for the study of the molecular mechanisms of gene targeting.  Specifically, this system entailed the investigation of recombinational exchange  between isogenic, non-functional copies of HSV-tk contained in a targeting plasmid  and a stably integrated target plasmid, in Ltk-cells. Results showed an absolute  random integration frequency of our targeting construct in the range of 10-4---a  value ten-fold lower than classically associated with random integration. Also,  linearization of our targeting plasmid outside the region of homology to our stably  integrated chromosomal target appeared to be associated with an undetectable level  of targeting. Similarly, non-homology---in the form of three non-silent point  mutations in our target sequence---appeared to impede gene targeting. These initial  results suggest that the design of this model system needs to be revised to allow  proper investigation of the molecular mechanisms underlying gene  targeting.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k630.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d951z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vh27m"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reducing measurement uncertainty in a DSP-based mixed-signal test environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taillefer, Chris</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>FFT-based tests (e.g. gain, distortion, SNR, etc.) from a  device-under-test (DUT) exhibit normal distributions when the measurement is  repeated many times. Hence, a statistical approach to evaluate the accuracy of these  measurements is traditionally applied. The noise in a DSP-based mixed-signal test  system severely limits its measurement accuracy. Moreover, in high-speed  sampled-channel applications the jitter-induced noise from the DUT and test  equipment can severely impede accurate measurements. A new digitizer architecture and post-processing methodology is  proposed to increase the measurement accuracy of the DUT and the test equipment. An  optimal digitizer design is presented which removes any measurement bias due to  noise and greatly improves measurement repeatability. Most importantly, the  presented system improves accuracy in the same test time as any conventional  test. An integrated mixed-signal test core was implemented in TSMC's  0.18 mum mixed-signal process. Experimental results obtained from the mixed-signal  integrated test core validate the proposed digitizer architecture and post  processing technique. Bias errors were successfully removed and measurement variance  was improved by a factor of 5.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b371.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh27m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Signal processing -- Digital techniques</dc:subject><dc:subject>Systems on a chip -- Testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mixed signal circuits -- Testing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913q44m"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of the behavior of PalNiCro brazing alloy for stainless steel joints</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Edelmann, Fabian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Brazing is a low-cost process used extensively in manufacturing  and repair of component assemblies in the aerospace industry. For stainless steel  joints requiring an airtight seal, the brazing metal Pd-Ni-Cr-Si-B (PalNiCro) is  commonly applied. However the underlying mechanisms of the brazing process are not  well understood, which has precluded optimization of the brazing parameters and  reduced the cost-effectiveness of the production process. To address these issues,  the role of processing conditions on the wetting characteristics of austenitic AISI  347 and martensitic AISI 410 stainless steel was studied in this work using PalNiCro  as the brazing alloy. Sessile drop tests were conducted to assess the effect of  time, temperature and surface roughness on the wettability conditions between the  stainless steel substrate and brazement. The effect of time and clearance on the  microstructure and hardness of the brazement was then examined. A brazing temperature of 980ºC and a surface roughness  from 600 grit SiC grinding paper were determined as the optimal wetting conditions.  Under such conditions, the value of the equilibrium contact angle for the AISI 347  and AISI 410 stainless steels was determined to be approximately 10º after  100 seconds of melting. Examination of the brazements produced using optimized  wetting conditions revealed the formation of borocarbide (Mx(C,B) y) and boride  (MxBy) precipitates primarily confined to the grain boundaries and some locations  within the interior of the grains, which resulted from the diffusion of boron from  the brazing metal. The microstructure of the joint seam consisted of the three  distinct regions: (1) a soft ductile nickel solid solution with dissolved palladium  and chromium (hardness ~ 220 HV) and (2) palladium silicide (over 600 HV)  surrounding (3) very hard Ni-rich islands (over 1000 HV) with the presence of nickel  borides. An increase in brazing time showed a slight increase in the maximum brazing  clearance (MBC) with also an increase in the diffusion layer for both AISI 347 and  AISI 410. The volume fraction of the secondary phases within the joint seam  exhibited marked increases up to a clearance of 150 mum with a decrease thereafter  and an estimated value of 300 mum as the maximum attainable  clearance.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p771p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q44m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977v39c"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rheological yield stress measurements of mine paste fill material</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saebimoghaddam, Abdolreza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses rheological characterization of mine  tailings and paste materials as saturated solid-liquid or homogenous mixtures.  Thickened tailings and paste fill can be classified as viscoplastic or  time-independent non-Newtonian fluid material. Viscoplastic fluids deform  plastically when the applied shear stress is less than a critical stress, which is  known as "yield stress". When the shear stress exceeds the yield stress  this type of fluid flows like a viscous material with finite  viscosity. In terms of pipeline design for transportation of mine tailings  or paste material, one of the most important rheological parameters that must be  measured would be yield stress. There are numerous techniques and equipment that can  be used for rheological characterization and specifically for yield stress  measurements. Literature review shows that the vane method is one of the best  rheometery techniques for determining the yield stress of homogeneous fluids  directly. There is also a method for calculating the yield stress from  slump height. Any geometry of slump moulds, cone or cylinder, with different  dimensions can be applied in this method. The standard conical slump test is  basically used for controlling the workability of fresh concrete. This method was  then modified for yield stress and viscosity calculation of cemented mixtures. These  slump tests can be categorized as in-situ methods of yield stress  measurements. Several rheometery and in-situ experiments were carried out to  measure the yield stress of two mine tailings samples in this study. A rheometer was  used in controlled shear rate and controlled shear stress modes for yield stress  measurements with the vane method. The results were satisfactory for cemented and  non-cemented mixtures. The effect of mixing time on the yield stress of material  combined with cement was also assessed using the vane method. No significant  difference emerged between increased yield stress of the mixtures after 4 minutes  and 12 minutes of mixing. The accuracy of calculated yield stress values using in-situ  methods was also determined by drawing comparisons between these series of data and  actual yield stresses measured using a rheometer. Modified conical slump tests  overestimated the values of yield stress and did not obtain reliable data for  viscosity calculation of the mixtures.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fx377.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v39c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sk137"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamics analysis of anterior-posterior forces in the knee joint during normal walking</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anisuzzaman, Muhammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The temporal pattern of the anterior-posterior force acting at  the human knee joint during walking is determined in the present study. A  three-dimensional anatomically based dynamics model, which includes the bones and  the muscles working across the knee joint, is developed and the redundant inverse  dynamics problem is formulated. The muscle redundancy is resolved by reducing the  number of unknowns based on certain logical assumptions. In addition, a parametric  study is conducted to study the effect of antagonistic muscle activity on the joint  force. The developed dynamics model is then exercised to calculate the  anterior-posterior knee joint force for normal and ACL-deficient knees. The  anterior-posterior knee joint force obtained from the normal knee analysis indicates  that a posterior force is present for the majority of the gait cycle with a maximum  force of 0.25 BW (body weight), whereas anterior force acts shortly after the  beginning of the stance phase reaching a maximum of 0.4 BW. Among the muscles  working across the knee joint, the quadriceps, gastrocnemius and the tensor fascia  latae produce an anterior force at the knee joint whereas the hamstrings, sartorius  and the graclilis generate a posterior force. For the ACL-deficient knee, the  results reveal that it is possible for patients to adapt to the injury by changing  their walking pattern to avoid or minimize quadriceps activation in the stance  phase, thus reducing or entirely avoiding the anterior force at the knee joint. The  study also reveals that it is necessary to strengthen the hamstring muscles for the  rehabilitation of the ACL-deficient knee patients to reduce the anterior force at  the knee joint.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b657c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk137</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0p096758h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Efficient model order reduction method for the analysis of electromagnetic interference</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roseanu, Toma Sebastien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With the advent of high speed interconnects, signal integrity  issues resulting from incident electromagnetic fields are becoming a significant  challenge for circuit designers. It is necessary therefore to be able to efficiently  and accurately simulate interconnect networks affected by this type of interference  in order to have a clear picture of how the signal on the interconnect is affected.  Since models for interconnect networks affected by incident electromagnetic fields  tend to be very large, traditional circuit simulation techniques require a  significant CPU cost. In order to address this problem, this thesis introduces a  model order reduction technique that allows for the quick frequency domain  simulation of large interconnect networks affected by incident electromagnetic  fields. Furthermore, a model order reduction algorithm is presented that produces a  small, accurate and provably passive macromodel of an interconnect network affected  by incident fields, which is very well suited for quick and efficient simulation in  both the time and frequency domain. For both cases, projection based model order  reduction is used to obtain the desired results. Several examples are provided in  order to prove the viability of each proposed new approach.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j71t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096758h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021f74n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of preoperative status and timing on outcome following total hip arthroplasty</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aljassir, Fawzi F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction. Total hip arthroplasty (THA) has been well  documented to enhance patient function, but patient outcome is dependent on  preoperative status. The exact timing of surgery to optimize patient outcome after  THA remains unknown. This study determines the ideal timing for surgery to obtain  the best possible functional outcome. Methods. Prospective, multicenter, cohort studies of 175 hybrid  THAs. General health (SF-36) and disease specific (WOMAC and Harris Hip Score (HHS))  questionnaires were used to determine preoperative and 2 year final outcomes.  Student's t-test, 95% confidence intervals, receiver operator characteristic curves,  simple regression analysis and probability were measured. Results. All functional scores were improved significantly  postoperatively (p&lt;0.001). Patients with a HHS ≥ 65 preoperatively had  a 100% probability of having an excellent result postoperatively. A preoperative HHS  value of 34 and preoperative WOMAC (physical function) value of 50 were the best  cutoff points to attain a significantly better postoperative functional  outcome.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz02r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021f74n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m223p"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mental health of South Asian women : dialogues with recent immigrants on post-migration, help-seeking and coping strategies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Agarwal-Narale, Tulika</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As Canada, and particularly metropolitan cities like Montreal,  becomes increasingly diverse, it is important to explore and understand the culture  and needs of immigrant communities. This Masters thesis focuses on the mental health  of South Asian immigrant women in Montreal, Quebec. This original research is a  qualitative descriptive study based on in-depth interviews with nine women from  India and Pakistan. The interviews focus on the intersection of gender and culture  with post-migration experiences, help-seeking patterns and coping strategies for  distress in South Asian women. The women's narratives provide pertinent information  for researchers and practitioners that could be applicable to the design of future  research, outreach, health promotion, and models of care on mental health. The  following four chapters provide a thorough discussion of the methodology, findings  and conclusions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tf94g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m223p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women's Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b405f"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of the nutritional correlates of growth of early and middle stage HIV-infected children in Uganda and zinc content of Ugandan food plants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Achen, Jasinta H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A cross-sectional survey was carried out to evaluate the  nutritional correlates of growth in 93 HIV-infected children in the early and middle  stages of infection. Also, as zinc is important for growth and immune function,  foods commonly eaten by these children were evaluated for zinc content. Foods with  relatively high zinc were identified in Uganda, and these food items were legumes  and cereals. A high prevalence of stunting and wasting was found in HIV-infected  children. The study also found that the frequency of past week oil/fat and staples  consumption was non-significantly correlated to weight-for-height at the early  stage, while household size was negatively, but non-significantly, associated with  WHZ in all HIV-infected children. Few caregivers reported feeding certain foods to  HIV-infected children based on beliefs.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd249.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b405f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children -- Uganda -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zinc in the body</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children -- Nutrition -- Uganda</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIV-positive persons -- Nutrition -- Uganda</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r366q"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computational electromagnetics in microwave hyperthermia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Duong, Lawrence</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Microwave hyperthermia is a cancer treatment used in combination  with radiotherapy and/or chemotherapy. Hyperthermia sensitizes cancer cells to the  primary treatment by sublethal heat. An antenna array non-invasively launches  electromagnetic waves, targeting cancer cells, and produces preferential heating.  This thesis discusses the two-arm Archimedean spiral antenna as a possible antenna  to deliver such energy. Simulations are performed on a homogeneous cylindrical numerical  phantom using the finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) method. FDTD is well-suited  for the analysis of the interaction between electromagnetic waves and complex  media. This thesis explores two types of input signals to the antenna  array: a continuous wave and a pulse. By strategically changing the phase of the  continuous wave or the delay of the pulse of individual antenna elements, spots of  maximal energy deposition within the phantom can be controlled. In the case of  pulse-excited antenna array, temperature distribution is also  computed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv690.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r366q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117p427"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The vertical limit of state sovereignty</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reinhardt, Dean N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is no international agreement on the vertical limit of  State sovereignty, the boundary between territorial airspace and outer space. The  need for defining this boundary has been debated for over 50 years. Today, the need  to settle this gap in the law is growing in importance. This thesis concludes that  setting a low vertical limit on State sovereignty is the best approach because it  will allow all States free access to space and enable uniform international rules to  be set at a relatively low altitude. Chapter I discusses territorial sovereignty and examines the  evolution of vertical sovereignty. It then compares this to the evolution of the law  governing territorial seas and concludes by examining the airspace laws of several  States. Chapter II reviews the reasons demarcation is important. Chapter III  discusses past proposals for demarcation and recommends setting a low vertical limit  on State sovereignty.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0967577.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p427</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sovereignty</dc:subject><dc:subject>Airspace (International law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zn937"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of annealing texture in nonoriented electrical steels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Park, Jong-Tae, 1962-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nonoriented electrical steels are mainly used as the core  materials in motors and generators. The magnetic properties required for these  materials are low core loss, high magnetic induction and high magnetic permeability.  These magnetic properties of nonoriented electrical steels are mainly influenced by  grain size and crystallographic texture. All research to improve the magnetic  properties so far has focused on grain growth through the control of chemical  compositions and various processing parameters. However, in the manufacturing  techniques of nonoriented electrical steels, the control of grain size is  approaching its limit. Since there is still enough room to improve the magnetic  properties through the control of texture, future research in nonoriented electrical  steels should be concentrated on the optimization of crystallographic  texture. Recrystallization texture itself has long been a subject of  research because the origin of recrystallization texture provides a high level of  scientific interest. Despite much research on recrystallization texture, the  mechanism of the formation of recrystallization texture is still disputed. This  dispute is associated with the complexity of microstructural inhomogeneity formed in  the deformed state, different nucleation rates for different orientations of  deformed grains and different growth rates of nuclei into the neighboring deformed  matrix. However, the advent of Orientation Imaging Microscopy (OIM) has contributed  to a remarkable progress in the area of recrystallization texture, and stimulated  research on the annealing texture in low carbon and interstitial free steels.  Conversely, no systematic research on the evolution of the annealing texture in  nonoriented electrical steels has yet been done. The mechanism of texture evolution during recrystallization in  the nonoriented electrical steels containing 1% and 2% Si respectively, a main  objective of this thesis, is investigated from electron backscatter diffraction  (EBSD) measurements on the materials with different recrystallization fractions.  Based on obtained results, the mechanism for the formation of the recrystallization  texture is proposed. The behavior of deformed grains of specific orientations is  also discussed in terms of image quality value introduced by EBSD techniques. In  addition, the origin of nuclei of specific orientations is suggested from observed  EBSD results. The texture development during grain growth, another main  objective of this thesis, is investigated. Furthermore, a mechanism of texture  development during grain growth is proposed based on the misorientation angle  distribution with adjacent grains and the average size of grains of specific  orientations. Some useful means to optimize the magnetic properties through  texture control in nonoriented electrical steels are studied. The effect of initial  grain size prior to cold rolling on texture evolution during both the  recrystallization stage and the grain growth stage is clarified. In addition, the  effects of temper rolling reduction and annealing time on texture development during  final annealing are examined. A mechanism of texture transformation by strain  induced boundary migration (SIBM) is suggested by means of the introduction of image  quality value in EBSD techniques. Finally, the effect of heating rate on texture  development during final annealing is investigated, and the reason for texture  change due to different heating rates is discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Szpunar, Jerzy A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731449j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zn937</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246s60x"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bulat Okudzhava : bard and voice of a waking Russian nation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Romanska, Magdalena</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bulat Shalvovich Okudzhava, the originator of the style of  Russian bards, was the first to express his nation's disillusionment over the  country's political system and government in a new and alternative  way. For this purpose, he used the direct impact of his poetry, a  part of which he would sing for audiences, accompanied only by his guitar. This sort  of communication between the writer and his interlocutors remained in sharp contrast  with the means traditionally used by the official Soviet mass culture. The spreading  of guitar poetry was impossible to control by authorities, since for popularization  it used not only public gatherings, but also a new piece of technology at the time,  tape recorders, a medium brilliantly used by Magnitizdat. As opposed to Okudzhava's prose, the body of his poetry is  largely understudied. One of the possible approaches to his poetic works may be that  of classifying them according to their themes. In the poetry of Bulat Okudzhava, several distinctive thematic  categories can be distinguished. The themes that dominated the poet's creative years  interpenetrate and overlap one another, as well as provide a reference for his  secondary themes. In the present thesis, the dominant themes will be analyzed from  a biographical and historical angle. War will be the first major theme explored.  This will be followed by a description of Okudzhava's works dealing with the cult of  Stalin and the associated personal tragedy of the author, who witnessed the  execution of his father and deportation of his mother. Subsequently, the themes of  work, creator and creativity, poet and poetry, music and painting will be discussed.  Other themes typical for Okudzhava are those of the city (especially Moscow), the  street (especially the Arbat), nature, folklore, and Georgia. The body of the  present thesis will conclude with the description of the basic thrusts of  Okudzhava's ethics and philosophy, that are most clearly expressed in his  "philosophical" verses (concerning belief, hope, love, destiny, women,  friends, and man's inner world). Since Okudzhava's poetry is heavily grounded in the historical  context of the Stalin and post-Stalin era and is an alternative voice to what was  imposed by official literature, it is natural and valuable to see it against the  background of the Socialist Realist canon of Soviet state-controlled literary  production.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patera, Tatiana</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085k62g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246s60x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Russia -- In literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Okudzhava, Bulat Shalvovich, 1924- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soviet Union -- In literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tm530"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les procédés de déréalisation dans les récits de Julien Gracq</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laval, Cédric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, I propose an analysis of Julien Gracq's  fictional works, based upon a dual methodological approach inspired by Genettian  naratology and the phenomenological theories of reading. I argue that  "derealization" is an important element of Julien Gracq's writing, which  is often perceived in binary terms (classical and/or modern, alternately real and  unreal, realistic and magical). This hypothesis leads me to develop a conceptual  framework for a notion that, while it has on occasion been invoked by critics, has  never been properly defined. In this framework, derealization is defined both as a  textual product and a reading effect. As a textual product, it is primarily an  interstitial phenomenon insofar as it operates between the different levels of the  text (enonciative levels, temporal levels, referential levels), creating confusion,  competition, and what I have called "subordinating inversion". As a  reading effect, it tends at once to disturb the reader's horizon of expectations, to  prevent referential stability (defined as a textual construct and in relation to the  reading experience), and to introduce a tension in the reading process without  completely hindering the reader's progress. This tension manifests itself in the  form of uncertainty, a blurring or subverting of diegetical content, persistent  instability or a powerful determinism whose limits are unclear. In the final  analysis, derealization can be described as a syncretic concept that reconciles, on  the one hand, the immanent structures of the text and the phenomenological  experience of reading, and, on the other hand, the stable, "ureassuring"  dimension of the traditional novel and its modernistic undermining. Seen in this  light, the concept of derealization could prove to be a useful tool for the study of  certain contemporary works that seek to rejuvenate traditional literary forms  without rejecting them entirely. Julien Gracq's works are a perfect example of just  su</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mercier, G. Lane</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m471f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm530</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gracq, Julien, 1910- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827c237"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Jihād and the establishment of Islamic global order : a comparative study of the worldviews and interpretative approaches of Abū al-A ʻlā Mawdūdī and Jāved Aḥmad Ghāmidï</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iftikhar, Asif</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study presents a comparative analysis of the interpretative  approaches and the religious Weltanschauungs of two Islamic revivalists of Pakistan,  especially in relation to jihad and the establishment of Islamic global order. Abu  al-A'la Mawdudi (1903-1979) argues that the correct understanding of certain key  Qur'anic terms makes it incumbent upon every Muslim to strive for the achievement of  the basic objective of Islam, which is to establish an Islamic global order (  izhar-i din) to implement the Divine laws ( iqamat-i din) so that all  un-Islamic (and, therefore, oppressive) "systems" of the world be replaced  by the "ideal Islamic rule" (khilafat) of "the Islamic State."  To strive fully to achieve this end is jihad, which may assume the form of an armed  struggle (qital) when the situation so demands and Islamic conditions for it are  fulfilled. Mawdudi gives various arguments to assert that this jihad is not a bane  but a boon for mankind, and in it lies the only hope for mankind's prosperous  existence in this world and the next. Contradicting Mawdudi's worldview, Javed  Aḥmad Ghamidi (1951- ) asserts that the basic purpose of Islam as a  religion is to purify the human soul to enable a person to worship and serve God as  His true subject and servant. The qital done by the Prophet and his companions was  essentially and for most part a form of Divine punishment against Divinely specified  peoples for denying the truth of the Prophet's message and position after this truth  had become evident to them. This form of jihad ended with the Prophet and his  companions, and the only valid moral basis for qital now is to end oppression and  injustice. Jihad (as qital) cannot be waged to propagate religion or merely to  eradicate a non-Islamic "system." This study looks at the implications of  these ideas and also delves into the concepts and interpretative approaches on which  they are founded.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg933.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827c237</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islam -- Doctrines</dc:subject><dc:subject>G̲ẖāmirī, Jāved Aḥmad</dc:subject><dc:subject>Maudoodi, Syed Abul ʻAla, 1903-1979</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jihad</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>