<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gn04q"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ibn Qayyim's reformulation of the fatwā</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nurbain, Nawir Yuslem</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a study of Ibn Qayyim's approach to the fatwa as defined in his $I sp{c}l bar am al$-$Muwaqqi sp{c}in.$ This treatise deals primarily with the role of the mufti/ the procedure of issuing a fatwa and the necessary sources for a fatwa. Lawful application of these criteria ensures a proper and viable fatwa. Ibn Qayyim, however, highlights the misuse of fatwas, specifically those on hiyal. By questioning this misapplication, Ibn Qayyim hoped to redefine the entire use of the fatwa in Islamic jurisprudence. This argumentation is supplemented by a section addressing the dynamic essence of the fatwa. By examining the underlying $ sp{c}illa$ of a ruling and the maslaha as the main goal of its application, Ibn Qayyim believed that most rulings were, in some way, influenced by the surrounding elements of time and space. If the $ sp{c}illa$ changed due to changing circumstances, Ibn Qayyim surmised that the fatwa itself could undergo changes. This line of discourse helped establish the fatwa as an adaptable tool of law, further indicating the ability of Islamic law to accommodate unprecedented situations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hallaq, Wael B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p032n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn04q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fatwas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ibn Qayyim al-Jawzīyah, Muḥammad ibn Abī Bakr, 1292-1350</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5h73pz10t"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Causality and its relation to the unity of existence according to Mullâ Ṡadrâ's view</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Namazi, M. (Mahmoud)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problem of causality and its relation to the unity of existence is one of the peculiar themes of Mulla Sadra (1571-1640). Although the treatment of and solutions to the problem of "causality" and the problem of "unity of existence" were considered by previous Islamic philosophers, no one considered these two problems could complement each other. Sadra, through the law of causality, proves the unity of existence. The applications of Sadra's principles (of the fundamental reality of existence and the analogical gradation of existence) which are the central principles of his entire thought, provide his unique theory of "unity of existence." By this theory he attempted to convince mystics that although there is in the world one reality, that reality manifests itself in various degrees of classifications and intensity of existence.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landolt, Hermann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8061981.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pz10t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ṣadr al-Dīn Shīrāzī, Muḥammad ibn Ibrāhīm, d. 1641</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mk995"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Substantive motion according to Mullā Ṣadrā Shīrāzī</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mesbah Moosavi, S. M. Kazem</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis will examine Mulla Sadra's theory of substantive motion. Mulla Sadra (1571-1640) challenged those philosophers who restricted motion to accidents and held that the substance of nature is unmovable, otherwise insurmountable problems arise. In order to solve the dilemmas, Mulla Sadra sought various ways to prove that motion is identical with nature and that no stable entity exists in the corporeal world. Here, time is one of the most important elements in the proofs for the theory of substantive motion, where, for the first time in intellectual history, Mulla Sadra introduced time as the fourth dimension of corporeal being. This implies mobility of nature, including its substances. This evolutionary motion in the case of body extends from the material realm to the emergence of soul, which is immaterial. By solving problems like the one concerning the eternity or temporality of the world debated between theologians and philosophers, this theory played a significant role in Islamic philosophy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landolt, Hermann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd21n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk995</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ṣadr al-Dīn Shīrāzī, Muḥammad ibn Ibrāhīm, d. 1641</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z010"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Human cognitive development in the transcendental philosophy of Ṣadr al-Dîn Shîrâzî and the genetic epistemology of Jean Piaget</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mesbah, Ali</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Human cognitive development is a matter of interest for different disciplines among which are philosophical epistemology and cognitive psychology. Shi razi (Mulla Sadra), a Muslim philosopher, deals, among other issues, with the problem of human cognitive development through his 'Irfani -philosophical methodology on the basis of the principles of his philosophy. These principles are the principality and gradation, tashki k, of existence and substantial motion through which Shi razi relates cognitive development to the existential progress of the human being. Piaget from the Western tradition of cognitive psychology focuses his work on the problem of human cognitive development, investigating the issue through a semi-experimental methodology and interpreting his findings on the basis of the principles of genetic epistemology, namely, the analogy between cognitive and physical organisms in terms of assimilation, accommodation and equilibrium. These two perspectives are studied and compared in this thesis with respect to their underlying principles, their scopes and methodologies. Finally, a multi-disciplinary approach is proposed for the study of human cognitive development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landolt, Hermann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq242.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z010</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ṣadr al-Dīn Shīrāzī, Muḥammad ibn Ibrāhīm, d. 1641</dc:subject><dc:subject>Piaget, Jean, 1896-1980</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jt30z"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Robert E. Park's theory of newspapers and news</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McLelland, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The essay examines Robert E. Park's theory of the role news and newspapers have in processes of social interaction, and of the role they consequently play in the constitution of society. Park's theoretical work is often cited for its appreciation of the dynamic aspects of social interaction. This perspective is evident in his analysis of news and newspapers. In The Immigrant Press and its Control (1922), Park examined how immigrant groups responded to the experience of immigration and how their newspapers contributed to that response. Park adopted from American pragmatism a definition of pragmatic or 'rational' social interaction and applied it to interaction over news. For Park, attention to newspapers and discussion of news tended not to favour adherence to tradition, but encouraged a pragmatic or rational attitude. In articles on news and public opinion written in the 1940's, Park saw attention to news as a potential threat to belief systems and as a source of social conflict. Challenges ta fundamental values lead to blind, defensive reactions and the behavior proper to a 'crowd'. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robinson, G. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg53p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt30z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>American newspapers -- Foreign language press</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social interaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Park, Robert Ezra, 1864-1944</dc:subject><dc:subject>Immigrants -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Newspapers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225d12s"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Samuel Beckett and the Irish grotesque tradition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maloney Cahill, B. Claire</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>By fusing many of the established hypotheses on the source of the grotesque in Irish literature, this study establishes that these writers' impatience with all boundaries and limitations, physical or mental, led them to exploit the indeterminacy of the grotesque to achieve their particular aesthetic and epistemological objectives. After an initial chapter on the relevant theoretical and national considerations, the prodigious cloacal visions of Beckett and Joyce are compared, with emphasis on their use of the grotesque to demythologize the creative process. A fourth chapter compares O'Brien's and Beckett's exploitation of the grotesque to undermine hegemonic philosophical and epistemological systems. Like most writers of the grotesque tradition, Joyce and O'Brien assume a degree of moral responsibility by affirming, explicitly or implicitly, some traditional or utopian values and standards, while Beckett's deliberations on the complex relationship between Nature, the mind and the body end in negation, impotence and the hope of silence.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ronsley, Joseph</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tp05r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d12s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grotesque in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Irish literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Beckett, Samuel, 1906-1989 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t4175"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of reason in the search for Nirvāṇa</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mai, Tong Ba</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Early Buddhists undisputably considered Nirvana to be the ultimate goal of their practice. However, not only was the meaning of Nirvana disputed, but so were the means (e.g., right view and no view) conducive to its achievement. The thesis proposes to examine the controversial status that scholars have accorded to faith and reason as elelments of the path. In this respect, the Buddha's attitude toward tradition, reasoning and experience is examined, along with the epistemological foundations of Pali canonical thought. Related issues such as identifying the ultimate criterion of reality advanced by Buddhism are also discussed. Moreover, since the Buddha suggested various ways leading to Nirvana, an attempt is made to discover how the paths of sila, samadhi and panna relate to each other and to the final goal.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hayes, Richard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0969286.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t4175</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Buddhism -- Doctrines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nirvana</dc:subject><dc:subject>Faith and reason -- Buddhism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans064792x"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Faith in words : liberalism, Islam and the philosophy of ethics in The Satanic Verses affair</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lynch, Brian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis argues that the shortcomings of modernist liberal defences of Salman Rushdie's The Satanic Verses have helped to draw debate over the book into a stalemate. It also attempts to demonstrate how aspects of this stalemate might be broken. Chapter One contains a brief philosophical survey of the debate, juxtaposing the framework relativism propounded by Rushdie and many of his advocates with the absolutism of Rushdie's Muslim detractors. The chapter closes with an analysis of the contradictions present in Rushdie's relativistic defence of his novel. Chapter Two opens with a short argument against existing blasphemy laws. The philosophical sketches in Chapter One are applied to the contents of the novel itself, producing an outline of the contending views of "literary contest" and "authorial intention" held by the two sides in the debate, and illuminating Rushdie's apparent confusion about the purposes of his novel. Chapter Three proposes a solution--based on philosopher Alasdair McIntyre's thought--to defects in modernist liberal defences of The Satanic Verses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Livingston, Paisley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306793.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064792x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rushdie, Salman. Satanic verses</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440v82v"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>U.S. foreign policy towards Cuba and prospects for democratisation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Long, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the post-cold war era, debate has been renewed regarding the United States' foreign policy towards Cuba. One aspect of this debate concerns the link between U.S. policy and prospects for future democratisation in Cuba. The thesis examines three theories ("squeeze", "communication" and "normalization"), which suggest that either increasing or decreasing economic and diplomatic ties with Cuba will encourage prospects for democratisation. The paper assesses the validity of these theories by using a theoretical framework to explain regime legitimacy, and considers which policy offers the greatest potential for regime change. Next, the paper looks at the current Cuban political and economic environment to understand the strengths and weaknesses of the Castro regime. To conclude, the author suggests that the current U.S. policy of opposing trade and diplomatic links with Cuba will have a counter-productive effect in encouraging democratisation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Oxhorn, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967581q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v82v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cuba -- Foreign relations -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>United States -- Foreign relations -- Cuba</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257h03b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of lesions to the anterior thalamic nuclei on two spatial, working memory tasks in rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leri, Francesco</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The experiments reported in the present thesis investigated the effects of lesions to the anterior nuclei of the thalamus (ATN) on the acquisition of two spatial, working memory tasks performed on the eight-arm radial maze. In the task used in Experiment 1 and 2, the animals were required to discriminate and remember all the eight arms of the maze simultaneously. Lesions of the ATN produced impairments in the acquisition of this task, but the degree of impairment depended on the amount of damage within this region. In the task used in Experiment 3, the animals were required to discriminate and remember only two arms at once. Lesions of the ATN were shown to impair its acquisition even though performance was facilitated by the addition of visual intra-arms cues. These experiments suggest that the ATN may be involved in spatial learning and in the retention of non-specific information over time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Petrides, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q6272.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257h03b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rats -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Short-term memory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thalamus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Maze tests</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g2300"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ibn Taymiyya's theory of knowledge</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lamotte, Virginie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis highlights a new interpretation of the writings of Ibn Taymiyya. Previous scholarship has stressed the legalistic, social or religious aspect, often at the expense of the philosophical content of Ibn Taymiyya's works. The explanatory insight of a study on the theory of knowledge, hitherto neglected, is evidenced by its capability to demonstrate the convergence of elementary, religious, intuitive and rational principles. The theory illustrates the concerns of a synthetic mind whose attempt was to broaden and not restrict the domain of knowledge vis-a-vis the Divine. Knowledge is not man's privilege and is available to all of creation. All created entities have the capacity to know their Creator. This thesis attempts to shed light on the mechanisms of the acquisition of knowledge about the Divine in their modes of availability to the creatures and to man. Tensions of the human predicament thus participate in the logical framework of the discussion. The attempt is to define the domain of knowledge, its components, and its parameters in the quest for a perfect acquisition of knowledge.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fk14h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g2300</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ibn Taymīyah, Aḥmad ibn ʻAbd al-Ḥalīm, 1263-1328</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wj12s"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le sublime dans les relations des jésuites de Nouvelle-France</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laflamme, Marc-Olivier</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This master's essay of literary analysis studies the rhetorical notion of the sublime in a number of discourses drawn from the Relations des jesuites de Nouvelle-France, including harangues pronounced by Amerindian leaders, panegyrics, letters of missionaries and dream accounts. In view of models of the sublime proposed by rhetoricians of classical Antiquity, this study shows the close bond which unites ethics and aesthetics in the Jesuit's mind. The criterions according to which the missionaries are affected by the great discourses are considered. This study also emphasizes the influence of the sublime, which provides the impetus for the apostolic vocation and the mystical quest of the Jesuits.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Doiron, Normand</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892d012.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wj12s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Jesuits. Letters from missions (North America)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sublime, The</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jesuits -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289m087"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>In pursuit of the ideal society : H.G. Wells and Russia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Krivokapich, Militsa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The celebrated interviews Lenin and Stalin accorded H. G. Wells are a part our century's troubled political history, and as such well-documented both on the Soviet side and in the West. It is less widely known that Wells's interest in Russia antedates the October Revolution, indeed, that he visited that country with his russophile friend Maurice Baring on the eve of the First World War, at a time when Wells had already acquired a remarkable literary reputation. There, he was admired by writers as disparate as Tolstoy, Zamyatin, Nabokov, and Gorky with whom he formed a close friendship, abetted by their mutual love of the Baroness Budberg. These Russian connections of Wells's, as well as his three journeys to Russia and the Soviet Union have not been previously explored against the background of his attitudes to socialism, which in turn played a crucial part in Wells's own search for an ideal society. For Wells, this quest was inseparable from his idea of a federal world state and his perception of the Russian revolutions of 1917 as its harbinger. Although he had many doubts about the Bolshevik regime, he attempted to persuade the English people that Lenin--whom he met in 1920--and his party were the only possible option at a time when few governments were prepared to recognize the Bolsheviks. His own doubts became genuine misgivings in 1934, after his disappointing encounter with Stalin. Nevertheless, Wells's final disenchantment with Russia did not mirror that of other fellow travellers or the period, such as Arthur Koestler and George Orwell, Before his depth in 1946, Wells's profound and inconsistent feelings towards the U.S.S.R. were further complicated by the Second World War and the role the Red Army would play in the struggle against Hitler.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Senior, Hereward</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv92q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m087</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946 -- Journeys -- Russia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A37720g039"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Jewish Immigrant Aid Services : an ethnic lobby in the Canadian political system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kilpatrick, Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study is to examine the Jewish Immigrant Aid Services (JIAS) as an example of an ethnic lobby in the Canadian political system. The research explores how in-group and external political factors influence the techniques and effectiveness of JIAS within the immigration policy arena. Specifically, this paper examines how JIAS' lobbying efforts are influenced as a result of issues emerging from within the organization (e.g. structure, hierarchy, leadership, etc), and those arising from within the organization's constituency: Canadian Jews as a whole, and other organizations within the Jewish polity. Further, the broader context of public opinion and the Canadian immigration system are explored to determine how each affects JIAS' advocacy efforts. The political system is examined from the perspective of the structure and agendas operating at three levels of government involved in the development and implementation of immigration policy (the Department of Immigration, Legislative and Senate committees on immigration and employment, and the Cabinet).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Weinfeld, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d631p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g039</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Jews -- Canada -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jewish Immigrant Aid Services of Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Emigration and immigration -- Government policy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lobbying -- Canada -- Case studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m1614"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L' idéal et les liquides chez Apollinaire</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kerkerian, Cécile</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This master's thesis examines how the liquid metaphor articulates the creative/creation ideal in Guillaume Apollinaire's collection of poems Alcools. Our analysis is inspired by Gaston Bachelard's theories, notably the ones found in his books, L'eau et Les reves (1942) and La psychanalyse du feu (1949). The first chapter analyses the link between the artistic ideal and moving water imagery. It seems that this mobility is a live and human characteristic of art. The second chapter deals with three types of celestial metaphors, all representing the ideal, that is, the Sun, the Moon and the Milky way. The third chapter focuses on the theme of alcohol, which is a sort of "supermetaphor" of poetic distillation, encompassing all the other metaphors. The successive examination of these varied liquid images in Alcools suggests that the poet's ideal involves a happiness based on the tranquillity originating in the "sentiment maternel" and a sense of artistic satiety.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Everett, Jane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr70g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m1614</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Apollinaire, Guillaume, 1880-1918. Alcools</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h6560"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The state of the Anglican Church in England in the late twentieth century : its role and its tribulations as reflected in the writings of A.N. Wilson</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jenkins, Jean, 1937-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A. N. Wilson is a distinguished contemporary English author and journalist whose writing constantly displays the depth of his understanding of and concern for the Church of England. Himself once a devout Anglican, albeit one of the Church's more vocal watchdogs, Wilson now writes as an outsider and an unbeliever. Yet he is still widely read and highly regarded as a commentator on the institution, and as one who is never reluctant to confront the ills which he believes responsible for its demise. Wilson takes the church hierarchy to task for neglecting spiritual matters in favour of "issues". He employs satire to illustrate what he believes to be the general mediocrity of the clergy. In his journalism Wilson continues to lambast liturgical changes and to question modern biblical criticism. By using representative selections from Wilson's writings as novelist, biographer, polemicist and journalist, and by chronicling his own highly publicised religious quest, this study seeks to show the dilemma of a substantial body of contemporary English Anglicans. Furthermore, the inability and impotence of the Established Church in England to meet the needs of its traditional and more moderate worshippers is adequately reflected in Wilson's work.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hall, Douglas J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494b422.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h6560</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wilson, A. N., 1950-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church of England -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128d03k"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Constructing Italian ethnicity : a comparative study of two Italian language newspapers in Australia and Canada, 1947-1957</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iuliano, Susanna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is broadly concerned with how an ethnic group defines itself through the medium of the press. It contends that newspapers do more than simply 'reflect' the experience of ethnic groups, they in fact help to 'construct' ethnic identity. The specific focus of this study is the Italian language press and its attempts to shape the ideals of italianita of Italian migrants in Canada and Australia in the immediate post-war period. This work is based on two newspapers, Montreal's Il Cittadino Canadese and La Fiamma published in Sydney, New South Wales. All available editions from the decade 1947 to 1957 are examined in order to determine which symbols and causes were used to promote Italian ethnic cohesiveness. In the course of this thesis, it is argued that La Fiamma used religion as the basis of its ideal of italianita, while the Italo-Canadian paper Il Cittadino Canadese made the issue of Italian political representation in Canadian government structures the basis of its quest to unite Italian migrants into an ethnic 'community'. Some possible reasons for the difference in focus between the two newspapers are presented in the conclusion. Also, suggestions are made for future comparative research between Italian ethnic communities in Canada and Australia which may help to better explain the differences laid bare in this paper.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd22x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d03k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Italian newspapers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italian newspapers -- Australia -- Sydney (N.S.W.) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italians -- Australia -- Sydney (N.S.W.) -- Ethnic identity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Ethnic identity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107109r"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L' analyse contextuelle de Joshua Meyrowitz, ses sources et fondements : vers un nouvel ordre systémique d'interaction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hubert, François, 1960-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an attempt at understanding the theoretical work of Joshua Meyrowitz in communication. The self-proclaimed specificity of his "contextual" media analysis will be recognized as well as its relevance for the development of a general logic of social change. The sources and foundations of Meyrowitz's media analysis will be respectively reconstructed in terms of the schools of thought which informed it and of a metatheoretical typology of the social sciences. The contextual logic of social change will be framed as a type of formal functionalism dealing with self-regulated systemic changes and integrating aspects of a more comprehensive sociology. It will be evaluated in view of recent empirical studies of some (post-)modern transformations in community life. The integrity of Meyrowitz's work in regard to his sources, the contribution of his media analysis to the development of community studies, and the foundations of his logic of social change will be here in question.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robinson, Gertrude J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw19g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107109r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meyrowitz, Joshua. No sense of place</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social change</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mass media -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Communication -- Social aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vn054"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Knowledge by presence (al-ʻilm al-ḥuḍûrî) : a comparative study based on the epistemology of Suhrawardî (d. 5871191) and Mullâ Sadrâ Shîrâzî (d. 10501640)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hejazi, Sayyed Mohammad Reza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is a comparative study of the epistemology of Suhrawardi and Mulla Sadra Shi razi, two Muslim thinkers of the 6th/12th and 11th/17th century. It focuses on two main issues: Illuminative theory of knowledge and, in the framework of this theory, Mulla Sadra's doctrine of knowledge by presence (al-'ilm al-huduri) studied in the context of his philosophical system (al-hikmah al-muta'ali yah). I have also discussed his methodology which is multidimensional. The aim of this study is not to elaborate on Mulla Sadra's theory of knowledge in general, but rather to present what Mulla Sadra meant by knowledge by presence, al-'ilm al-huduri. However, it is my opinion that his doctrine of knowledge by presence is the corner stone of his epistemological system. In the light of this doctrine, he gives a new definition of knowledge, a novel interpretation of its division into al-'ilm al-huduri and al-'ilm al-husuli, and, finally, a systematic chain of various kinds of knowledge by presence (e.g., self-knowledge, God's knowledge of His Essence and God's knowledge of things). These three aspects of his doctrine have been surveyed and, in comparing them with Suhrawardi's theory, evaluated in this thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landolt, Hermann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr99p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vn054</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Suhrawardī, Yaḥyá ibn Ḥabash, 1152 or 3-1191</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ṣadr al-Dīn Shīrāzī, Muḥammad ibn Ibrāhīm, d. 1641</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j105n"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Motor performance and fitness of children with an attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harvey, William, 1578-1657</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to describe the gross motor and fitness characteristics of children with an attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD). Nineteen children with an ADHD, between the ages of 7 years, 0 months and 12 years, 11 months (M = 9 years, 4 months) participated in this study. The 17 boys and 2 girls had IQs between 80 to 100, were not affected by specific learning disabilities, and behavioral problems were the primary reason for acceptance into their clinical center. Children with additional psychiatric diagnoses were excluded. All children were tested individually. Gross motor performance was measured by the Test of Gross Motor Development (Ulrich, 1985). Fitness variables were measured by selected items from the Canadian Standardized Test of Fitness (1986), the Canada Fitness Survey (1985), the CAHPER Fitness-Performance II Test (1980), and The Twenty Meter Shuttle Run Test (Leger et al., 1984). A counterbalanced Latin-Square testing order was used to avoid practice effects. Statistical analysis involved converting raw scores to percentile scores which were graphed to provide individual and group profiles of performance. The present study identified the physical fitness and gross motor performance of these children as below average. Programming implications and recommendations for future study are provided.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, Greg</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d834.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j105n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Motor ability in children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attention-deficit-disordered children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644t642"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le village comme espace romanesque; suivi de Smorzando et Le récital</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gratton, Nathalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master's thesis in literary creation comprises two parts. The first part is an analysis of the village as a setting in novels and draws upon a corpus of seven novels, from Madame Bovary to Chronique d'une mort annoncee. It will be shown that the main characteristics of the physical space and human space of the village scarcely vary from one novel to another, and constitute a sort of archetype which determines the esthetical purpose of each author. The second part is comprised of two short stories, respectively titled Smorzando and Le recital. These short stories deal with two betrayals, one carried out in cold lucidity and the other unconsciously. The world of music is the background of both these short stories.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g40m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t642</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Villages in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644t65b"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Videoconferencing pathways to interaction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goldberg, Lydia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rapid convergence of technologies of communication into a multimedia environment taking place over the last decade has created a new interest in the possibilities offered by videoconferencing systems. We are thus beginning to see the expansion of the potential for various levels of human interaction mediated by video in both business and educational domains. Through the support of the technologically mediated environment, people now have the capability to travel across time and space, meeting with other individuals, seemingly as if face-to-face. The purpose of this thesis is to explore more fully some of the issues of the new communication technologies (differences between face-to-face and mediated communication, changes to our conceptions of time and space, and problems of privacy and surveillance) and specifically how they apply to various videoconferencing scenarios as well as to a more detailed case study of a teleteaching experiment conducted recently at a French research institute.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crowley, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw678.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t65b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Distance education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Teleconferencing in education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Videoconferencing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A73666674z"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Authenticity of Nahj al-Balāghah</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghassemi Zavieh, S. Mohammad H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study undertakes two major issues concerning the authenticity of Nahj al-Balaghah, namely, the compilation and composition of the book. Shii scholars, with almost no exception, have credited the compilation of Nahj al-Balaghah to al-Sharif al-Radi In contrast, Sunni scholars and Orientalists hold different opinions about the matter. The early scholars among Sunnis and their western counterparts mostly credited Murtada with Nahj al-Balaghah, while later scholars generally vacillate between the two brothers. This study attempts to resolve misconceptions concerning the compilation of the book. It also suggests that in all probability Radi is the compiler while there is hardly any evidence to credit Murtada. The problem of the composition of Nahj al-Balaghah, namely, the attribution of its contents to Ali ibn Abi Talib is more problematic. Unlike the Sunni scholars, the Shiis believe that the contents of the book represent Alis discourses. This thesis examines the most important arguments of both opponents and proponents of the authenticity of Nahj al-Balaghah and suggests that since a large portion of the book is present in the earlier sources, the generalization of some Sunni scholars in doubting the entire book cannot be sustained. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hallaq, Wael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt770.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666674z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sharīf al-Raḍī, Muḥammad ibn al-Ḥusayn, 969 or 70-1016. Nahj al-balāghah -- Authorship</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311r492"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gnose et philosophie : une étude du Ta'wîl ismaélien d'après le livre des sources d'al-Sijistânî</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gagnon, Jean-François, 1954-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study asks the following question: to what degree do the categories of philosophical knowledge apply to the original work of Abu Ya'qub al-Sijistani? In order to answer the question, the study tries to characterize al-Sijistani's thought as expressed in the Kitab al-Yanabi'. The textual analysis emphasizes the role of Sijistani's theory of Sources and theory of kalimah, which allow useful comparisons with aspects of the hermetic and hermeneutic traditions. The analysis aims at demonstrating that the hermeneutical thought of al-Sijistani, although gnostic in character, integrates in its spiritual itinerary the conceptual expression characteristic of philosophical knowledge. The possibility of such an integration rests on the ta'wi l's function of synthesis. The various aspects of the synthesis are finally discussed by reference to the ismaili conception of prophecy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landolt, Hermann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg54z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r492</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Abū Yaʻqūb al-Sijistānī, Isḥāq ibn Aḥmad, 10th cent. Yanābīʻ</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ismailites -- Doctrines -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sj35b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L' autobiographie et le personnage de fiction chez Simone de Beauvoir</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fudge, Heather Lynn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The corpus of this project consists of the five volumes of Simone de Beauvoir's memoirs: Memoires d'une jeune fille rangee, La force de l'age, La force des choses I, La force des choses II and Tout compte fait. In this study, we have considered the difficulties of self-analysis and examined the limitations and demands of the genre of autobiography. A memoir is not simply the reconstruction of the author's past, but a personal interpretation of this past which often includes discrepancies between the narrative and the reality of his or her life. The autobiographer's primary objective is not to deliver the historical facts of his or her existence, but to show a self beneath the person that appears to the world. In our research, we have found that the value and truth of Simone de Beauvoir's autobiography arise from her creation of a character she sees as embodying her own distinct personality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pascal, Gabrielle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128d04v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj35b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Beauvoir, Simone de, 1908-1986 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>