<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nd47s"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Penalized regression methods for interaction and mixed-effects models with applications to genomic and brain imaging data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bhatnagar, Sahir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In high-dimensional (HD) data, where the number of covariates (??) greatly exceeds the number of observations (??), estimation can benefit from the bet-on-sparsity principle, i.e., only a small number of predictors are relevant in the response. This assumption can lead to more interpretable models, improved predictive accuracy, and algorithms that are computationally efficient. In genomic and brain imaging studies, where the sample sizes are particularly small due to high data collection costs, we must often assume a sparse model because there isn't enough information to estimate ?? parameters. For these reasons, penalized regression methods such as the lasso and group-lasso have generated substantial interest since they can set model coefficients exactly to zero. In the penalized regression framework, many approaches have been developed for main effects. However, there is a need for developing interaction and mixed-effects models. Indeed, accurate capture of interactions may hold the potential to better understand biological phenomena and improve prediction accuracy since they may reflect important modulation of a biological system by an external factor. Furthermore, penalized mixed-effects models that account for correlations due to groupings of observations can improve sensitivity and specificity. This thesis is composed primarily of three manuscripts. In the first manuscript, we propose a method called sail for detecting non-linear interactions that automatically enforces the strong heredity property using both the ℓ₁ and ℓ₂ penalty functions. We describe a blockwise coordinate descent procedure for solving the objective function and provide performance metrics on both simulated and real data. The second manuscript develops a general penalized mixed effects model framework to account for correlations in genetic data due to relatedness called ggmix. Our method can accommodate several sparsity-inducing penalties such as the lasso, elastic net and group lasso and also readily handles prior annotation information in the form of weights. Our algorithm has theoretical guarantees of convergence and we again assess its performance in both simulated and real data. The third manuscript describes a novel strategy called eclust for dimension reduction that leverages the effects of an exposure variable with broad impact on HD measures. With eclust, we found improved prediction and variable selection performance compared to methods that do not consider the exposure in the clustering step, or to methods that use the original data as features. We further illustrate this modeling framework through the analysis of three data sets from very different fields, each with HD data, a binary exposure, and a phenotype of interest. We provide efficient implementations of all our algorithms in freely available and open source software.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Avec des données de grande dimension (GD), où le nombre de covariables (??) dépasse largement le nombre d'observations (??), l'estimation peut profiter du principe miser sur la sparsité, c'est à dire, seulement un petit nombre de prédicteurs de la variable réponse sont réellement pertinents. Cette hypothèse permet d'obtenir des modèles interprétables, améliore leur précision et facilite l'implémentation d'algorithmes efficaces sur le plan des calculs. Dans les études d'imagerie génomique et cérébrale, où la taille des échantillons est particulièrement faible en raison des coûts élevés associés à la collecte de données, nous devons souvent supposer un modèle sparse car l'information est insuffisante pour estimer les ?? paramètres. Pour ces raisons, les méthodes de régression pénalisées telles que lasso et group lasso ont suscité un intérêt considérable, car elles permettent d'obtenir des estimés des coefficients du modèle égaux à zéro. Dans le cadre de la régression pénalisée, de nombreuses approches ont été développées pour les effets principaux. Cependant, il y un besoin d'adapter ces approches pour les modèles d'intéraction et les modèles mixtes. En effet, une capture précise des interactions permettrait de mieux comprendre les phénomènes biologiques et d'améliorer la précision des prédictions, car elles reflètent souvent une modulation importante d'un système biologique par un facteur externe. De plus, les modèles mixtes pénalisés qui tiennent compte des corrélations dues aux regroupements d'observations peuvent améliorer la sensibilité et la spécificité. Cette thèse est composée principalement de trois manuscrits. Dans le premier manuscrit, nous proposons une méthode appelée sail pour détecter les interactions non linéaires qui applique automatiquement la propriété d'hérédité forte à l'aide des pénalités ℓ₁ et ℓ₂. Nous décrivons une procédure de descente de coordonnées par blocs pour optimiser la fonction objective, et nous démontrons la performance sur des données simulées et réelles. Le deuxième manuscrit développe un cadre général de modèles mixtes pénalisés pour tenir compte des corrélations dans les données génétiques issues de familles. Notre méthode, appelée ggmix, peut tirer profit de plusieurs pénalités, telles que lasso, elastic net et group lasso. Elle permet également d'intégrer des informations d'annotation antérieures sous forme de poids. Notre algorithme a des garanties théoriques de convergence et nous évaluons à nouveau ses performances à l'aide de données simulées et de données réelles. Le troisième manuscrit décrit une nouvelle stratégie appelée eclust pour la réduction de la dimension des variables qui exploite les effets d'une variable d'exposition ayant un impact important sur les mesures GD. Avec eclust, nous avons constaté une amélioration de la performance prédictive et de la sélection de variables par rapport aux méthodes qui ne tiennent pas compte de l'exposition lors de l'étape de clustering ou des méthodes utilisant les données d'origine comme des effets principaux. Nous illustrons ensuite ce cadre de modélisation en analysant trois ensembles de données provenant de domaines très différents, chacun avec des données GD, une exposition binaire et une variable réponse. Nous fournissons des implémentations efficaces de tous nos algorithmes dans les logiciels gratuits et à source ouverte.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Celia M. T. Greenwood</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Yi Yang</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj310.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd47s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sz20t"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stabilization of levansucrase, modulation of its specificity and a search for the improved synthesis of novel fructooligosaccharides and levans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hill, Andrea</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Levansucrase (LS, EC 2.4.1) est un catalyseur intéressant qui accomplit le transfert non-Lenoir d'un fructose à partir d'une molécule donneuse désactivée jusqu'à une molécule acceptrice, produisant ainsi β-(2-6)-FOSs, neoFOSs et un levan. À travers la modification du microenvironnement, l'immobilisation du LS produite par Bacillius amyloliquefaciens a été étudiée avec, pour objectifs simultanés, l'amélioration de sa stabilité thermale et l'augmentation de la préférence de cette enzyme pour la trans-fructosylation par rapport à l'hydrolyse (T/H). La plus grande activité résiduelle a été obtenue avec le Sepabeads® HA (98.8 %) ionique et le glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu (67.0%) covalent. La plus grande stabilité a été observée lors de l'immobilisation du LS sur le glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu et sur le glyoxyl agarose avec des facteurs de stabilisation respectivement 14 et 106 fois plus élevés. L'immobilisation sur le Sepabeads® HA permettait un ratio T/H 2,3 fois plus grand que le LS d'origine. Il a été montré que le glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu produisait les meilleurs résultats en termes d'immobilisation. Les facteurs affectant l'immobilisation du LS ont été examinés et optimisés en utilisant la méthodologie de surfaces de réponses. Il a été montré que les conditions d'immobilisations optimales (formation de liens pré-covalents) étaient d'une part, une quantité de protéines de 9,09 mg de protéines/g de support et de l'autre, une molarité de tampon de 608 mM à un pH de 6,8 en utilisant un temps d'immobilisation de 49h. La formation des liens covalents permanents a été remplacée par le polymère ionique polyethylenimine (PEI) à une concentration de 0,1% (v/v). Le glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu/PEI résultant avait une activité résiduelle de 70,9% avec un rendement en protéines de 44,7% et un rendement en activité de 54,7%; tout en exhibant une demi-vie 4,7 fois plus élevée que le LS d'origine à 50°C.Par ailleurs, puisque l'activité du LS varie significativement dépendamment de sa source bactérienne, on retrouve potentiellement une activité catalytique intéressante chez un LS non découvert. L'exploration du génome a été utilisée pour trouver de nouvelles LS intéressantes en s'appuyant sur un ensemble de références de 26. Dix enzymes potentielles ont été sélectionnées en fonction de l'activité totale, de la production de glucose et de levan. Une examination des capacités de ces LS a révélé que le LS provenant du Gluconobacter oxydans produisait un levan de grande taille (6986 kDa). Des ratios élevés de T/H ont été trouvés dans les LS provenant de Vibrio natriegens, Streptococcus salivarius K12 et G. oxydans respectivement de 1,55, 1,44 et 1,33. Le LS du paraburkholderia graminis a révélé avoir une stabilité thermique très élevée avec une demi-vie de 291 minutes lorsque chauffé à 50°C. Il a été montré que l'efficacité catalytique pour la trans-fructosylation de S. salivarius était bien plus élevée (presque doublée) avec 4058 s-1mM-1 par rapport à l'efficacité catalytique de l'hydrolyse. Les LS provenant du S. salivarius K12, Novosphingobium aromaticivorans et P. graminis avaient un plus grand renouvellement catalytique que le taux d'hydrolyse. Enzymes sélectionnées ont été examinés plus à travers leur profil de produit, leurs spécificités d'accepteurs et leur site actif. Les LS du G. oxydans et du N. aromaticivorans ont produit des FOS allant jusqu'à une longueur de 13 unités. La production de FOS provenant du LS de P. graminis représentait plus du double de la quantité (164 g/L) en comparaison avec le reste des enzymes. Il a été montré que toutes les enzymes étaient capables d'utiliser sorbitol, tandis que toutes les enzymes provenant de V. natriegens, N. aromaticivorans, P. graminis et B. indica subsp. indica étaient capables d'utiliser catechol, comme accepteur pour le fructose, ouvrant ainsi la voie à la production de nouveaux produits trans-fructosylés.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Levansucrase (LS, EC 2.4.1) is an interesting catalyst that performs the non-Lenoir transfer of fructose from a non-activated donor molecule to an acceptor molecule, producing β-(2-6)-FOSs, neoFOSs and levan. The immobilization of LS from Bacillus amyloliquefaciens was studied with the goal of improving its thermal stability while augmenting the enzyme's preference for transfructosylation in place of hydrolysis through a modification of the microenvironment. The greatest retained activity was achieved with the ionic Sepabeads HA (98.8 %) and the multi-point covalent glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu (67.0%) supports. The highest stability was experienced by the LS immobilization onto glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu and glyoxyl agarose with stabilization factors of 14 and 106 times that of the native enzyme. Immobilization onto Sepabeads HA was found to provide the greatest modulation of the enzymatic microenvironment with transfructosylation over hydrolysis ratio 2.3 times higher than the native LS. Glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu was found to be the overall top support for the immobilization of LS.Factors which affected the immobilization of LS were examined and optimized using response surface methodology. Retention of activity was found to be most influenced by the interactions between buffer molarity/immobilization time and the interactions between buffer pH and buffer molarity. The optimized immobilization conditions (pre-covalent bond formation) were found to be: protein loading of 9.09 mg protein/g support, buffer molarity of 608 mM at pH 6.8 using an immobilization time of 49h. The formation of the permanent covalent bonds was replaced with the ionic polymer polyethylenimine (PEI) at a concentration of 0.1% (v/v). The resulting glyoxyl agarose-IDA/Cu/PEI had a retention of activity of 70.9% with a protein yield of 44.7% and an activity yield of 54.7%, with a half-life 4.7 times higher than the native free LS at 50°C.With the LS activity varying per bacterial source, novel catalytic activity potentially lies within undiscovered LSs. Genome mining was used to search for new LSs using a reference set of 26 enzymes. 10 potential LSs were selected from the resulting screening. An in-depth examination of these LSs revealed that the LS from Gluconobacter oxydans produced levan of a large size (6986 kDa). High transfructosylation versus hydrolysis ratios were found for the LSs from Vibrio natriegens, Streptococcus salivarius K12 and G. oxydans of 1.55, 1.44 and 1.33 respectively. The LS from Paraburkholderia graminis was revealed to have a very high thermal stability, with a half-life of 291 minutes when heated at 50°C. The kinetic parameters of a select few high performing LSs were determined. The catalytic efficiency for transfructosylation was found to be much higher (almost double), 4058 s-1mM-1 that of the catalytic efficiency for hydrolysis 2256 s-1mM-1 for the LS from S. salivarius K12; while that enzyme and the LS from B. indica subsp. indica had higher catalytic turnover for transfructosylation than for hydrolysis. LSs from G. oxydans, Novosphingobium. aromaticivorans, Beijerinckia indica subsp. indica, P. graminis and V. natriegens were further examined in terms of their product profile, acceptor specificity and active site. Both LSs from G. oxydans and N. aromaticivorans produced FOSs up to 13 units in length. LS from P. graminis produced more than double the amount of FOS (164 g/L). The largest amount of levan (84 g/L) was produced at 12 h by the LS from V. natriegens. The LSs from V. natriegens, N. aromaticivorans and P. graminis preferred raffinose instead of the substrate sucrose. In the acceptor specificity study, all of the LSs were able to utilize the alditol, sorbitol, to a varying degree while the enzymes from V. natriegens, N. aromaticivorans, P. graminis and B. indica subsp. indica were able to utilize catechol as an acceptor for fructose, opening up the possibility for the production of new novel transfructosylated products.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Salwa Karboune</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4307004.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz20t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580p89k"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Living with a visible difference: Assessing body image and appearance concerns in Scleroderma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jewett, Lisa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>People living with visible appearance differences, whether present from birth or acquired through injury or illness, often experience psychosocial and psychological challenges. These include negative self-perceptions such as low self-esteem, shame, body image dissatisfaction, and depression; as well as challenges related to social interactions such as fear of negative evaluation, social avoidance, and social anxiety. Systemic sclerosis, or scleroderma (SSc), is a rare, chronic, autoimmune connective tissue disease that leads to significant physical appearance changes, which have been linked to negative outcomes including body image dissatisfaction, social discomfort and anxiety, as well as general psychological distress. In order to advance research in this area, however, and support the design of adequate psychosocial interventions, more disease-specific patient-reported outcome measures related to body image concerns are needed. In addition, an increased understanding of how disease and sociodemographic factors are associated with these outcomes is required to inform intervention content. In order to address these gaps, four independent studies were conducted and included in this thesis. Study One involved the development and validation of a new patient-reported outcome measure of body concealment and avoidance behaviours specific to SSc, the Body Concealment Scale for Scleroderma (BCSS), including examination of its basic psychometric properties. Study Two constituted a replication of Study One, with the extension of determining the measurement equivalency of BCSS items across sex and age groups. The findings of this study replicated those of Study One and further demonstrated that BCSS scores can be compared and combined across females and males with SSc and those of different ages without concern that measurement differences influence results. Study Three examined the measurement equivalency of a commonly used measure of social discomfort and body image dissatisfaction relative to acquired disfigurements in SSc, the Satisfaction with Appearance Scale (SWAP), across language groups. Findings from this study enhanced existing psychometric evidence by showing that SWAP items do not function differently across English-and French-speaking Canadian SSc patients and that scores can be pooled across these language groups. Study Four explored the association of key sociodemographic variables with the presence of appearance concerns among patients living with SSc. Main findings from this study revealed that female patients had significantly higher odds of reporting appearance concerns than male patients and that older age was significantly associated with a reduction in the odds of reporting appearance concerns. There was no significant difference in the odds of reporting appearance concerns between Black and White patients, after accounting for the influence of sociodemographic and disease characteristics. Finally, women and men with SSc were more likely to report appearance concerns than members of the general population. In sum, the body of the presented research involved the creation of a new disease-specific patient-reported outcome measure and potentially useful clinical assessment tool of body concealment behaviours in SSc, including establishing its psychometric properties. This thesis also highlighted the importance of evaluating the measurement equivalency of body image questionnaires across diverse groups of patients with SSc and demonstrated differences in key sociodemographic and disease characteristics, such as sex, age, and presence of hand contractures, in the experiencing of body image concerns. Implications and future directions for research are discussed. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les personnes vivant avec des différences visibles au niveau de l'apparence éprouvent souvent des difficultés psychosociales et psychologiques. Ces difficultés regroupent une faible estime de soi, un sentiment de honte et la dépression. Certains défis rencontrés sont liés aux interactions sociales telles que la peur d'être jugé négativement et l'anxiété sociale. La sclérodermie systémique, ou sclérodermie (SSc), est une maladie du tissu conjonctif rare et chronique qui entraîne des changements importants au niveau de l'apparence physique. Ces changements ont des conséquences négatives comme une insatisfaction liée à l'image corporelle, un inconfort social, de l'anxiété sociale. Cependant, afin de faire avancer la recherche dans ce domaine et de soutenir l'élaboration d'interventions psychosociales adéquates, il faut davantage de mesures de résultats déclarés par les patients, spécifiques aux maladies et liées aux problèmes d'image corporelle. De plus, une meilleure compréhension de la façon dont la maladie et les facteurs sociodémographiques sont associés à ces résultats est requise pour développer le contenu de ces interventions. Afin de combler ces lacunes, quatre études indépendantes ont été menées et intégrées dans cette thèse. La première étude constituait le développement et la validation d'une nouvelle mesure de résultats déclarés par les patients sur la dissimulation corporelle et de comportements d'évitement spécifiques à la SSc, la Body Concealment Scale for Scleroderma (BCSS). La deuxième étude comprenait une réplication de la première étude, à laquelle s'ajoutait la détermination de l'équivalence de mesures des items entre les sexes et les groupes d'âge. Les résultats de cette étude ont reproduit ceux de la première étude et ont démontré que les scores BCSS peuvent être combinés entre les femmes et les hommes atteints de SSc issus de différents groupes d'âge. La troisième étude évaluait l'équivalence de mesure de l'échelle de satisfaction de l'apparence physique (SWAP) qui est couramment utilisée pour mesurer l'inconfort social et l'insatisfaction de l'image corporelle dans la SSc, à travers les groupes linguistiques. Les résultats de cette étude ont montré que les items du SWAP ne fonctionnent pas différemment chez les patients anglophones ou francophones du Canada. Ainsi, les scores peuvent être combinés entre ces groupes linguistiques. La quatrième étude portait sur l'association des variables sociodémographiques principales à la présence de préoccupations en lien avec l'apparence chez les patients atteints de SSc. Les principaux résultats ont révélé que les femmes avaient des probabilités significativement plus élevées de déclarer des problèmes d'apparence que les hommes et qu'un âge plus élevé était significativement associé à une probabilité plus faible de déclarer des problèmes d'apparence. Il n'y avait pas de différence significative dans les probabilités de déclarée les problèmes d'apparence entre les patients d'ethnicité noire ou blanche. Enfin, les femmes et les hommes atteints de SSc étaient plus susceptibles de déclarer des problèmes d'apparence que les membres de la population générale. En somme, la présente recherche a impliqué la création d'une nouvelle mesure et d'un outil d'évaluation clinique potentiellement utile pour les comportements de dissimulation du corps avec la SSc, y compris l'élaboration de ses propriétés psychométriques. Cette thèse a également permis de souligner l'importance de l'évaluation de l'équivalence des questionnaires d'image corporelle entre divers groupes de patients atteints de SSc. Elle a également démontré les différences entre les principales caractéristiques sociodémographiques et caractéristiques en lien avec la maladie telles que le sexe, l'âge et la présence de contractures aux mains, à travers l'expérience de préoccupations en lien avec l'image corporelle. Les implications et les pistes de recherches futures sont discutées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Annett Korner</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Brett David Thombs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq40f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p89k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x366n"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating food environment disparities using digital supermarket transactions for fruits and vegetables in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jahagirdar, Deepa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Consommer des légumes et fruits au quotidien pourrait réduire le risque de plusieurs maladies chroniques. Malgré les campagnes de promotion de la santé, des disparités socio-économiques dans la consommation demeurent évidentes. Pour faire face au problème, de nombreux gouvernements en Amérique du Nord et en Europe ont fondé des interventions axées sur l'accessibilité, principalement à travers un meilleur accès géographique aux supermarchés. Toutefois, peu de données probantes démontrent une association de la présence de supermarchés à une consommation accrue de fruits et légumes. Par conséquent, il y a un besoin d'études portant sur d'autres dimensions de l'environnement alimentaire.  Ces dimensions incluent le prix, les choix santé offerts et la variété des produits offerts. Dans cette thèse, j'utilise six ans (2008-2013) de données numériques des transactions de supermarchés au Québec pour étudier ces dimensions de l'environnement alimentaire.  Les données de transactions des supermarchés offrent une alternative aux études in situ pour mesurer l'environnement alimentaire. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Consuming fruits and vegetables can help to prevent chronic disease and illness. Despite widespread awareness campaigns, socioeconomic disparities in fruit in vegetable consumption remain. To address this issue, many governments in North America and Europe have aimed to improve geographical access to stores selling healthy foods in vulnerable areas, mainly supermarkets. However, there is little to suggest that having access to more supermarkets improves diet. As a result, calls to shift away from accessibility and enhance research related to other food environment dimensions are increasingly prevalent. These dimensions include affordability (cost), availability (the selection of healthy items) and variety (the varieties of each available item). In this manuscript-based thesis I used six years (2008-2013) of weekly automatically-collected digital grocery store transaction data to study the under-investigated dimensions of the food environment. Digital scanner data is an alternative to in-store measurement that could enhance future research on the food environment. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Amélie Quesnel Vallée</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>David Buckeridge</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c2927.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x366n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bw73n"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Phenomenology of boredom coping: understanding students' lived experiences of coping with boredom in college</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hubbard, Kyle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'ennui a été identifié comme étant l'une des émotions académiques les plus fréquemment et intensément éprouvées, et préjudiciables à l'apprentissage, la motivation,l'autorégulation et la réussite des élèves; et pourtant, peu d'études ont été menées sur la manièredont les étudiants s'adaptent ou régulent leur ennui dans un contexte académique tel que la salle de classe, les couloirs, ou la bibliothèque, et pendant qu'ils étudient ou complètent leurs devoirs. Par conséquent, nous comprenons très peu l'expérience des étudiants en matière d'ennui. A l'aide d'une méthode de recherche phénoménologique herméneutique, la présente étude vise à combler le manque de littérature sur la question par l'analyse thématique de l'expérience vécuespar quinze étudiants au collège. Les participants ont complété deux entrevues individuelles ettrois entrées dans un journal en ligne, au cours d'un seul semestre, dans lesquelles ils ont décrit leurs expériences de l'ennui et d'adaptation à l'ennui. Les analyses thématiques ont révélé quatre thèmes relatifs à l'ennui (manque d'implication, malaise et aversion, vide, et désire d'évasion) et quatre thèmes relatifs à l'adaptation à l'ennui (être respectueux, se détourner de l'ennui, se tourner vers l'ennui, et rechercher du sens). Ces résultats contribuent de manière significative à une meilleure compréhension de l'expérience des étudiants au collège en matière d'ennui et d'adaptation à l'ennui, et pourraient servir à informer les enseignants et personnels administratifs qui cherchent à aider les étudiants à faire face et s'adapter à leur ennui académique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Boredom has been identified as one of the most frequently and intensely experienced academic emotions and detrimental to student learning, motivation, self-regulation, and achievement; yet, there has been limited research into how students cope with or regulate their boredom in academic contexts such as the classroom, hallway, or library, and while studying or completing assignments. Consequently, we currently understand very little about the student's experience of coping with boredom. Using a hermeneutic phenomenological research method, the present study sought to fill this gap in the literature through the thematic analysis of fifteen college students' lived experience descriptions of academic boredom and coping. Participants completed two one-on-one interviews and three online journal entries across the course of a single semester wherein they provided experiential accounts of boredom and coping in college. Thematic analyses revealed eight boredom themes (lack of engagement, discomfort and aversion, emptiness, a desire to escape, nothing to do, feeling physically tired, time slowing down, and wasting time) and four boredom coping themes (being respectful, turning away from boredom, turning toward boredom, and seeking meaning). These findings make significant contributions toward better understanding of college students' experience of academic boredom and boredom coping, and may serve to inform professors and college administrators seeking to support students in adaptively coping with their academic boredom.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nathan Hall</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d2268.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw73n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fr13f"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ultrafast electron diffuse scattering and its application to 2D materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stern, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La nature du couplage entre le réseau d'atomes et les porteurs de charges d'un cristal est centrale au domaine de la physique de la matière condensée. Malgré leurs rôles fondamentaux, les couplages électron-phonon et phonon-phonon demeurent mystérieux. La diffraction ultrarapide diffusé par électrons permet de répondre aux questions concernant l'occupation des populations phononiques dans l'entièreté de l'espace réciproque. Plus spécifiquement, les excitations optiques sur un cristal de graphite, initiées par une impulsion laser femtoseconde, génèrent une population électronique excitée particulière, appelée cônes de Dirac. Ces excitations creés un plasma d'´electrons et de trous de densité variable, contrôlée par l'intensité de l'impulsion laser. Cette thèse présente une analyse sophistiquée de données de diffraction ultrarapide diffusé par électrons faisant la lumière sur la relaxation du système électronique excité par impulsion ultrarapide, passant par le couplage avec le réseau d'atomes, puis finissant en relaxation des modes phononiques avec l'environnement. Dans le cas du disélénure de titane (TiSe2), le couplage électron-phonon est mesuré de façon complètement différente; en observant l'effet de la photo-excitation sur les fréquences de phonons renormalisées aux vecteurs d'ondes caractéristiques de la phase d'ondes de charges de TiSe2. A travers la sensitivité aux occupations phononiques temporaires, la diffraction 'ultrarapide diffusé par électrons permet de d´ecortiquer la physique des phases complexes de la matière, et d'élucider la relation entre le système ´electronique et le réseau d'atomes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The nature of the couplings within and between lattice and charge degrees of freedom is central to condensed matter and materials physics. Despite their fundamental role, detailed momentum-dependent information on the strength of electron-phonon and phonon-phonon couplings across all momenta has proved elusive. Ultrafast electron diffuse scattering provides the answer by measuring momentum-dependent phonon population dynamics similar to how time and angle resolved photoemission spectroscopy views the momentum-dependent occupation dynamics of electronic states. This method proves particularly effective in the study of 2D materials. A sophisticated analysis applied to ultrafast electron scattering measurements of graphite, follows the cascade of electron-phonon and phonon-phonon couplings after pulsed laser excitation in this well studied benchmark system. In a similar experiment on titanium diselenide, electronphonon coupling is measured by observing the effect of photoexcitation on the renormalized phonon frequencies with the characteristic momentum of titanium diselenide's charge density wave transition. Through its sensitivity to transient phonon occupancies and frequencies, ultrafast electron diffuse scattering is a novel and powerful method to unravel the physics of complex phases and properties determined through interplay between the electron and lattice systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bradley Siwick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk445.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr13f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cs79j"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A search for Fermi LAT pulsars in archival VERITAS data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tyler, Jonathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les pulsars sont des sources extraterrestres de rayonnements périodiques que l'on pense être constitués d'étoiles à neutrons fortement magnétisées et à rotation rapide. Lorsque l'étoile à neutrons tourne, des faisceaux de rayonnement peuvent devenir visibles à un observateur à différentes phases de rotation, provoquant l'observation d'un signal périodique. Les pulsars sont principalement détectés aux fréquences radio, mais sont également détectés avec la lumière optique, les rayons X et les rayons gamma. L'émission radiative des pulsars n'est actuellement pas bien comprise. Les questions principales dans ce domaine d'étude sont les mécanismes d'émission de rayonnement et l'emplacement des régions d'émission. Ce travail décrit la recherche de pulsations à partir de 14 pulsars avec VERITAS, un observatoire rayon gamma à très hautes énergies situé sur la Terre. En ce moment, seulement deux pulsars ont été détectés en rayons gamma a très hautes énergies: les pulsars Crabe et Vela. Cette recherche a été entreprise pour augmenter ce nombre et pour contraindre les scénarios d'émission de rayons gamma. L'ensemble de données est constitué de données d'archives, où des pulsars détectés par le Large Area Telescope (LAT) à bord du Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope ont été observés directement ou étaient présents dans le champ de vision pendant des observations d'autres sources astronomiques. Les données VERITAS pour chaque pulsar ont été analysées avec trois ensembles de coupes de sélection de données, et deux tests de périodicité pour chaque ensemble de coupes. Aucune pulsation a été découverte pour ces analyses. Les limites supérieures du flux ont été calculées pour chaque pulsar au niveau de confiance de 95% pour chaque ensemble de coupes en utilisant deux méthodes distinctes. Les limites pour chaque pulsar sont contextualisées avec des spectres produits à partir de données du LAT, et les résultats sont interprétés dans le contexte des scénarios actuels d'émission de rayons gamma par les pulsars. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pulsars are extra-terrestrial sources of periodic radiation thought to consist of highly magnetized, rapidly rotating neutron stars. As the neutron star rotates, beams of radiation may become visible to an observer at different rotational phases, causing an observed periodic signal. Pulsars are mostly detected at radio frequencies, but are also detected in optical light, X-rays and gamma rays. Radiative emission from pulsars is currently not well understood. The main open questions in the field are the radiation emission mechanisms and the location of the emission regions. This work describes the search for pulsations from 14 pulsars with VERITAS, a ground-based very-high-energy (VHE) gamma-ray observatory. Currently only two pulsars have been detected at VHE energies: the Crab and Vela. This search was undertaken in order to increase this number, and to constrain pulsar gamma-ray emission scenarios. The data set consists of archival data, where pulsars detected by the Large Area Telescope (LAT) on-board the Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope were observed directly or were present in the field of view during observations of other sources. The VERITAS data for each pulsar were analyzed with three sets of data selection cuts, and two periodicity tests for each set of cuts. No pulsations were discovered for any of these analyses. Flux upper limits were calculated for each pulsar at the 95% confidence level for each set of cuts using two separate methods. The limits for each pulsar are contextualized with spectra produced from LAT data, and the results are interpreted within the context of current pulsar gamma-ray emission scenarios. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kenneth J. Ragan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j76w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs79j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795996r"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>trope en trop</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goddard, Christopher</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An extended work in two movements, trope en trop is scored for a mixed chamber sextet of flute (doubling piccolo), clarinet (doubling bass clarinet), violin, cello, percussion, and piano. It uses as its basic sonority the consonant triad, which is re-purposed from the music of common practice tonality to serve a new structural role. Central to my approach in this work is an exploration of the triad's potential for voice leading and harmonic coherence outside the functionality of tonal syntax. The dissertation divides into two parts: the musical score and an analysis of the work. The analysis first outlines contributions from recent and historical music theorists concerning triadic behavior in tonal and post-tonal music, followed by an examination of how contrasting pitch spaces might affect triadic usage. It then situates trope en trop among compositional models both from the canonical repertoire and from my own oeuvre. A full musical analysis of the composition follows, with a preparatory discussion of my goals for the work followed by a close examination of its two movements. Items addressed in this discussion include local and large-scale pitch processes, polyphonic rendering of those processes, and formal design with regard to pitch, tempo, and instrumentation. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un travail étendu en deux mouvements, trope en trop est écrite pour un sextuor mixte : flûte (aussi, piccolo), clarinette (aussi, clarinette basse), violon, violoncelle, percussion et piano. Il utilise comme sonorité de base la triade consonante, qui est réadaptée de la musique tonale afin de servir dans un nouveau rôle structurel. Au cœur de mon approche se trouve une exploration du potentiel de la triade pour la conduite des voix et la cohérence harmonique en dehors de la fonctionnalité de la syntaxe tonale. La thèse se divise en deux parties : la partition musicale et une analyse de l'œuvre. L'analyse pré-sente d'abord les contributions de théoriciens de la musique récents et anciens en ce qui concerne le fonctionnement triadique dans la musique tonale et post-tonale ; ceci est suivi d'un examen de la manière dont les espaces-hauteur contrastés pourraient affecter l'utilisation triadique. Il situe ensuite trope en trop parmi les modèles compositionnels du répertoire canonique et de ma propre œuvre. Une analyse musicale complète de la composition suit, avec une discussion préparatoire de mes objectifs pour le travail suivi d'un examen attentif de ses deux mouvements. Les sujets abordés dans cette discussion comprennent les processus de la hauteur à petite et à grande échelle, le rendu polyphonique de ces processus et la conception formelle en ce qui concerne les hauteurs, le tempo et l'instrumentation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Rea</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3435.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795996r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kq41q"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploring TB patient journeys and the emergence of MDR-TB in India and South Africa:A multi-methods study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Law, Stephanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: Today, about 5% of all tuberculosis cases and 15% of all tuberculosis (TB) deaths are due to isolates that are multidrug-resistant (MDR), that is, resistant to isoniazid and rifampicin, the most potent TB drugs (WHO 2017a). The emergence of MDR-TB is largely due to incorrect and insufficient treatment. TB patient treatment journeys – from the onset of TB symptoms to completion of treatment, or death – include frequent encounters with multiple health care providers, over long periods of time, from six months to more than two years.  Exploring these patient journeys could provide insight into potential interventions to prevent further emergence of drug resistance.  Objective: This dissertation used quantitative and qualitative methods to explore TB patient journeys in India and South Africa, two countries with a high burden of MDR-TB. These two countries served as case studies to investigate potential patient-, provider-, and systems-level interventions to improve patient retention-in-care and adherence, and their impact on TB and MDR-TB epidemics. Methods: 1) A dynamic Markov model was constructed to represent India's TB epidemic, including a probabilistic framework reflecting complex TB treatment-seeking pathways. This model explored the impact of the different health care sectors (private, public and informal) on the emergence of drug-resistance. 2) A qualitative study was conducted to explore TB patient treatment journeys and potential strategies to improve patient retention-in-care in Cape Town, South Africa. 3) A systematic review was conducted to evaluate the effectiveness of psychosocial, educational and materials support interventions to improve MDR-TB treatment adherence and retention-in-care. 4) The dynamic Markov model constructed in part 1 was adapted to represent South Africa's TB epidemic, and used to explore the impact of strategies targeting different stages of the TB cascade of care on the emergence of drug-resistance and TB mortality. Findings: In both India and South Africa, strengthening existing care for TB patients in the public system - with a focus on reducing poor treatment adherence and losses to follow-up - would lead to greater reductions in drug resistance and mortality than other strategies, such as expanding access to new TB drugs. Strategies to promote treatment adherence and retention-in-care were suggested by the qualitative study in South Africa and the systematic review. The former study revealed the importance of establishing patient-provider trust. The latter study found that MDR-TB patients who received individual counselling or home visits by trained health workers, had lower rates of loss to follow-up than others who did not. Conclusion: There is an urgent need to address patient-, provider- and systems-level issues affecting patient retention-in-care and treatment adherence, as these are major drivers of the global MDR-TB epidemic. This is particularly important to protect new drugs being introduced into routine treatment, such as bedaquiline and linezolid, to help prevent the development and further transmission of resistance to these drugs. Future research should develop and rigorously assess interventions that promote adherence and retention-in-care to prevent further worsening of the global DR-TB epidemic.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte : Présentement, environ 5% de tous les cas de tuberculose (TB) et 15% de tous les décès dus à la TB sont causés par des isolats multirésistants (MR), c'est-à-dire résistants à l'isoniazide et à la rifampicine, les médicaments antituberculeux les plus puissants (WHO 2017a). L'émergence de la TB-MR peut être attribuée à des traitements inadéquats. Le parcours du patient, depuis l'apparition des premiers symptômes jusqu'à la fin du traitement ou le décès, comprend plusieurs rencontres avec de multiples prestataires de soins de santé, sur de longues périodes, de six mois à plus de deux ans. L'analyse de ces parcours pourrait donner un aperçu des interventions possibles visant à prévenir l'apparition ultérieure d'une résistance aux médicaments. Objectif : Cette thèse a utilisé des méthodes quantitatives et qualitatives pour explorer le parcours de patients tuberculeux vivant en Inde et en Afrique du Sud. Ces deux pays servent d'études de cas pour évaluer les interventions potentielles au niveau des patients, des prestataires et des systèmes de santé visant à améliorer la rétention et l'adhésion au traitement des patients, ainsi que l'impact de ces interventions sur les épidémies de TB et de TB-MR. Méthodes : Les méthodes utilisées pour  les quatre études de cette thèse étaient : 1) l'élaboration d'un modèle de Markov dynamique représentant l'épidémie de TB en Inde, y compris un cadre probabiliste reflétant la complexité des parcours de traitements antituberculeux, afin d'évaluer l'impact des différents secteurs (privé, public et informel) sur l'émergence de la pharmacorésistance; 2) l'étude qualitative des parcours de traitement des patients tuberculeux et des stratégies potentielles pour améliorer la rétention des patients à Cape Town, en Afrique du Sud; 3) une revue systématique de l'efficacité des interventions psychosociales, éducatives et du soutien matériel ayant pour but d'améliorer l'adhésion au traitement et la rétention des patients atteints de TB-MR; et 4) l'adaptation du modèle de Markov, construit lors de la première étude, afin de représenter l'épidémie de TB en Afrique du Sud. Ce modèle adapté fût utilisé pour étudier l'impact des stratégies ciblant les différents stades de la cascade de soins sur l'émergence de la pharmacorésistance et sur la mortalité par TB. Résultats : En Inde et en Afrique du Sud, le renforcement des soins existants pour les patients tuberculeux dans le système public - en mettant l'accent sur le faible taux d'adhésion au traitement et de rétention  - conduirait à des réductions plus importantes de la résistance aux médicaments et de la mortalité que d'autres stratégies, comme l'amélioration de médicaments. L'étude qualitative menée en Afrique du Sud et la revue systématique suggèrent des stratégies pour améliorer l'adhésion au traitement et la rétention. L'étude qualitative a révélé l'importance d'instaurer un climat de confiance précoce entre les patients TB et leurs prestataires. La revue systématique a démontré des taux de rétention supérieurs chez les patients ayant bénéficié de conseils individuels ou de visites à domicile par des intervenants en santé qualifiés. Conclusion : Il est urgent d'adresser les enjeux qui affectent la rétention des patients et leur adhésion au traitement, tant au niveau des patients, des prestataires et des systèmes, puisque ces problèmes sont les principaux moteurs de l'épidémie mondiale TB-MR.  Ceci est particulièrement important afin de protéger les nouveaux médicaments introduits dans le traitement de routine, tels que la bédaquiline et le linézolide, et de prévenir le développement et la transmission de TB résistantes à ces médicaments. Les recherches futures devraient développer et évaluer rigoureusement les interventions visant à promouvoir la rétention des patients et leur adhésion, afin d'empêcher une aggravation de l'épidémie mondiale de TB-MR.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dick Menzies</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv22v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kq41q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n2041421"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Invisible wounds: trauma, gender, and the lived experience of Sri Lankan Tamil refugee men</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Affleck, William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse se focalise sur trois domaines distincts mais liés : la santé mentale des réfugiés, la santé mentale des hommes et l'effet des traumas sur le fonctionnement psychologique et émotionnel. Cette thèse aura pour but d'atteindre plusieurs objectifs spécifiques. Le premier est de familiariser le lecteur avec le thème de la santé mentale des hommes. Ce domaine, qui est émergent dans la recherche, a seulement récemment suscité l'attention de la psychiatrie générale. Mon second objectif est d'explorer et de documenter les nombreuses façons par lesquelles les hommes psychologiquement et émotionnellement vulnérables, plus particulièrement les hommes réfugiés, sont devenus invisibles dans le domaine de la santé mentale, que ce soit en recherche ainsi qu'en pratique. Cet objectif sera la focalisation des chapitres 1, 2, 3, et 4. Mon troisième objectif concerne les problèmes éthiques dans la recherche des stress traumatiques, un domaine auparavant non exploré. Les chapitres 4 et 5 porteront sur ce sujet. Mon quatrième et dernier objectif est de mieux comprendre comment le genre, spécifiquement la masculinité, interagit avec la culture des hommes réfugiés qui souffrent de traumatismes de guerre et/ou de l'expérience de réinsertion. Cette idée sera l'objet du 6ème chapitre. En répondant à ces objectifs, cette thèse s'inscrit aux domaines de la psychiatrie culturelle, des responsabilités éthiques dans la santé mentale, et à la recherche et pratique clinique dans la sphère de la santé mentale des hommes. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses broadly on three distinct yet inter-related areas: men's mental health, refugee mental health, and the effect of trauma on psychological/emotional functioning. I have a number of specific aims. My first aim is to introduce the reader to the field of men's mental health. This is an emerging field of research, which has only begun to gain attention in the psychiatric mainstream. My second aim is to explore and document the myriad ways that emotionally and psychologically vulnerable men, and specifically refugee men, are rendered invisible in the field of mental health research, policy, and practice. This is the focus of chapters 1, 2, 3, 4. My third aim is to highlight previously unexplored ethical issues in traumatic stress research. This is the focus of chapters 4 and 5. My fourth and final aim is to better understand how gender, specifically masculinity, insects with culture in the war-trauma and resettlement experience of refugee men. This is the aim of the 6th and final chapter. By fulfilling these three aims, this thesis contributes to the fields of cultural psychiatry, mental health ethics, global mental health, and men's mental health research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert Whitley</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jaswant Guzder</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d94n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2041421</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychiatry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q78n"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Robot-assisted therapy for upper limb rehabilitation in individuals with stroke: effectiveness, role of environment, and evaluation of a novel "Assist-As-Asked" protocol</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Norouzi Gheidari, Nahid</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to determine the effectiveness of robot-assisted therapy (RT) in upper limb (UL) rehabilitation of stroke patients, we first systematically reviewed and analyzed the literature. We found that when the duration/intensity of conventional therapy (CT) is matched with that of the RT, no difference exists between the intensive CT and RT groups in terms of motor recovery, activities of daily living, strength, and motor control. However, depending on the stage of recovery, extra sessions of RT in addition to regular CT are more beneficial than regular CT alone in motor recovery of the hemiparetic shoulder and elbow of patients with stroke; the gains are similar to those that have been observed in intensive CT. It has been shown that stroke patients with mild-to-moderate UL motor impairment benefit from training with a virtual reality rehabilitation system. However, during robot-assisted movements, it remains to be determined whether movements made in a virtual environment are similar to those made in a physical environment. Thus, we examined the role of training environment, whether virtual or physical, on robot-assisted reaching movements in chronic stroke and healthy individuals, within a single session. Fifteen subjects participated in this study divided into three groups: 5 chronic stroke individuals able to perform a reaching task with no need for the robot assistance, 5 chronic stroke individuals who needed the robot assistance to complete the reaching task, and 5 healthy individuals. The task was to reach for six target buttons in two identical physical and virtual environments. The outcomes consisted of kinematic measures and a custom questionnaire to assess how participants perceived and experienced the reaching task in both environments. We found no differences between the two environments in terms of the outcome measures in any of the groups. We concluded that the choice of environment, whether physical or virtual, is not a key factor in designing a robot-assisted reaching protocol for stroke survivors. Finally, we conducted a proof-of-concept study to identify clinical benefits and potential adverse effects of a novel, custom-developed RT protocol, named "Assist-As-Asked", aiming at improving arm function of chronic stroke subjects with moderate-to-severe UL motor impairment and to investigate whether practicing in a physical or virtual environment would make any difference in the outcomes of interest. Four chronic stroke subjects participated in 10 half-hour sessions to practice reaching six targets in both virtual and physical environments. The robotic arm provided gravity support, and with the "Assist-As-Asked" paradigm, helped subjects to complete movements when they requested it. Kinematics of the reaching movements and the subjects' perception about the reaching practice in both environments were the primary outcome measures of interest. Change in scores of FMA-UE was the secondary outcome measure. Following the RT sessions, all the subjects noticeably improved their reaching performance, which was accompanied by 3-5 points improvement in FMA-UE score. There were no differences between the two environments in terms of kinematic measures even though subjects had different opinions about environment preference. We concluded that moderate-to-severe chronic stroke survivors may benefit from RT using the "Assist-As-Asked" paradigm. In designing an RT platform for moderate-to-severe chronic stroke survivors, the choice of environment, either physical or virtual, does not necessarily influence the outcome of therapy sessions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Afin de déterminer l'efficacité de la thérapie assistée par un robot (RT) dans la réadaptation du membre supérieur (MS) chez les patients ayant subi accident vasculaire cérébral (AVC), nous avons d'abord systématiquement analysé la littérature pour identifier des essais contrôlés randomisés portant sur l'utilisation d'appareils de robotique pour la réadaptation du MS des personnes ayant subi un AVC. Nous avons trouvé que lorsque la durée / intensité de la thérapie conventionnelle (TC) est comparée avec la RT, aucune différence n'existe en terme de récupération motrice, de performance dans les activités de la vie quotidienne, de force, et de contrôle moteur. Cependant, dépendamment de la phase de récupération, des séances supplémentaires de la RT en plus de la TC sont plus bénéfiques que la TC seule pour la récupération motrice de l'épaule et du coude des patients ayant subi un AVC; les bénéfices sont similaires à ceux observés en TC intensive. Il a été démontré que les patients ayant subi AVC avec un déficit moteur léger à modéré du MS bénéficient d'un entraînement avec un système de réadaptation en réalité virtuelle. Cependant, lors des mouvements assistés par robot, il reste à déterminer si les mouvements effectués dans un environnement virtuel sont similaires à ceux réalisés dans un environnement physique. Nous avons donc examiné le rôle de l'environnement, virtuel ou physique, sur les mouvements assistés par un robot. Quinze sujets ont participé à cette étude divisée en trois groupes: 5 individus atteints d'AVC chronique capables d'accomplir une tâche sans avoir besoin du robot, 5 individus atteints d'AVC chronique ayant besoin d'une assistance robotique pour accomplir la tâche et 5 individus en bonne santé. La tâche était d'atteindre six cibles dans deux environnements physiques et virtuels identiques. Les résultats comprenaient des mesures cinématiques et un questionnaire pour évaluer comment les sujets ont perçu et vécu la tâche d'atteinte dans les deux environnements. Nous n'avons trouvé  aucune différence pour les résultats entre les deux environnements et entre les groupes. Nous avons conclu que le choix de l'environnement, qu'il soit physique ou virtuel, n'est pas un facteur important dans la conception d'un protocole d'assistance avec un robot pour les personnes ayant subi un AVC. Enfin, nous avons mené une étude pour identifier les avantages cliniques d'un nouveau protocole RT personnalisé, appelé «Assist-As-Asked». Ce protocole vise l'amélioration la fonction du MS chez des sujets ayant subi un AVC et une déficience motrice modérée à sévère du MS. De plus, nous avons examiné si la pratique dans un environnement physique ou virtuel avait un impact au niveau des mesures ciblées. Quatre sujets ayant subi un AVC ont participé à 10 séances d'une demi-heure. La tâche était de pratiquer l'atteinte de six cibles dans des environnements virtuels et physiques. Le bras robotisé aidait les sujets au moyen du paradigme «Assist-As-Asked» (assistance à effectuer des mouvements lorsqu'ils le demandaient). Les principales mesures étaient la cinématique des mouvements du bras et la perception des sujets de la pratique dans les deux environnements. Le changement dans les scores du FMA-UE était la mesure secondaire. Après les séances de RT, tous les sujets ont nettement amélioré leur performance au niveau des mouvements du bras, accompagné d'une amélioration de 3-5 points du score FMA-UE. Il n'y avait aucune différence entre les deux environnements pour les mesures cinématiques, même si les sujets avaient diverses préférence sur l'environnement. Nous pouvons conclure  que les personnes ayant subi un AVC modéré à sévère pourraient bénéficier de la RT en utilisant le paradigme «Assist-As-Asked». En concevant un protocole de RT pour les individus avec un  AVC chronique modéré à sévère, le choix de l'environnement, soit physique ou virtuel, n'influence pas le résultat des séances de thérapies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joyce Fung</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Philippe Archambault</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w55k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q78n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical &amp; Occupational Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r9675995"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"A raised, restless, and frightened imagination": unconventional reading in the romantic-period novel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taylor, Megan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>À la fin du dix-huitième siècle en Grande-Bretagne, la taille et la diversité du public de lecteurs augmentent rapidement. On observe une croissance impressionnante dans la production des livres, périodiques et journaux, et le développement d'un réseau plus ouvert, accessible, et sophistiqué pour la circulation de tels matériaux. De plus en plus de gens lisent, et lisent plus que jamais auparavant. Pour des raisons morales et esthétiques cette prolifération de lecteurs cause une anxiété largement répandue parmi les auteurs et penseurs de la période. Certains critiques s'inquiètent d'une détérioration potentielle de la culture littéraire qui serait polluée par un nombre croissant d'auteurs amateurs publiant des oeuvres inférieures. D'autres craignent que certains nouveaux lecteurs intellectuellement vulnérables — les femmes, serviteurs, et autres membres des basses classes— pourraient être corrompus par la lecture trop absorbée et affective que la fiction populaire encourage. La critique littéraire récente du dix-huitième siècle et du Romantisme se concentre sur la prévalence et la variété de ces réponses négatives face au bourgeonnement de la culture de l'imprimerie de la Grande-Bretagne — mais cette position ne raconte qu'une partie de l'histoire. En examinant les représentations des lecteurs dans les oeuvres de six romanciers proéminents de la période Romantique — Jane Austen, Eaton Stannard Barrett, Frances Burney, Maria Edgeworth, Mary Shelley et Walter Scott — cette thèse démontre que ces réponses négatives ne sont pas aussi répandues que ne le montrent les études. De nombreux critiques soutiennent que la plupart de ces auteurs seraient opposés à, ou au moins suspicieux de, l'expansion et la diversification du public de lecteurs. En fait, ils constituent certains des plus intéressants porte-paroles du phénomène. Contrairement aux moralistes conservateurs de leur temps, ces romanciers dépeignent la lecture irréfléchie, absorbée ou émotionnelle comme un objectif désiré, ainsi que, souvent, un puissant moyen de créer une communauté et d'encourager l'amélioration de soi. Ces portraits positifs de la lecture affective ou plaisante dans la période Romantique – un temps durant lequel la culture de l'impression de la Grande-Bretagne change de façon imprévisible –  nous encouragent, aujourd'hui, à épouser les transformations de notre propre culture de la lecture alors que l'ère digitale reconfigure nos relations avec toutes sortes de textes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In Britain at the end of the eighteenth century, the reading public's size and diversity were rapidly increasing. There was an impressive growth in the production of books, periodicals, and newspapers, and a more open, accessible, and sophisticated network was developing for the circulation of such material. More people were reading, and people were reading more, than ever before. This proliferation of readers caused widespread anxiety among writers and thinkers of the age, for reasons both moral and aesthetic. Some critics worried that literary culture would deteriorate, polluted by the growing number of hack authors publishing inferior work. Others feared that certain intellectually vulnerable new readers – women, servants, other members of the lower classes – would be corrupted by the overly absorbed or affective reading that popular fiction encouraged. Recent eighteenth-century and Romantic literary criticism has focused on the prevalence and variety of these negative responses to Britain's burgeoning print culture – but this stance tells only one side of the story. By examining the representation of readers in the work of six prominent Romantic-period novelists – Jane Austen, Eaton Stannard Barrett, Frances Burney, Maria Edgeworth, Mary Shelley, and Walter Scott – this dissertation demonstrates that such negative responses were not as pervasive as studies have suggested. Many critics have contended that most of these writers were opposed to, or at least suspicious of, Britain's expanding and various readership. In fact, they are some of its most interesting advocates. In contrast to cautionary moralists of their time, these novelists depict thoughtless, absorbed, or emotional reading both as a desirable end in itself and also, often, as a powerful means to foster community and encourage self-improvement. Such positive portrayals of affective or pleasurable reading in the Romantic-period, at a time when Britain's print culture was changing so unpredictably, encourage us, today, to embrace the transformations of our own reading culture, as the digital age reconfigures our relationships with texts of all kinds.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Sabor</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h57w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9675995</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278w56v"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Examining the potential of utilzing geothermal energy from ejected mine water towards mine heating and peliminary assessment of deep lake cooling systems for deep underground mines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dabbas, Mohannad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>  L'énergie renouvelable est en train de devenir un sujet clé de nos jours avec des thèmes de recherche croissants autour de l'énergie durable. L'industrie minière au Canada consomme une grande quantité d'énergie non renouvelable, ce qui contribue énormément aux émissions de gaz à effet de serre du pays. Par conséquent, cette thèse étudie de nouvelles possibilités pour l'industrie minière d'accroître sa dépendance à l'égard de sources d'énergie renouvelables non polluantes. La première partie de la thèse porte sur l'énergie géothermique potentielle pouvant être obtenue à partir des eaux éjectées des exploitations minières souterraines actives. La thèse illustre le potentiel économique et environnemental de 15 mines au Canada. Des visites sur place ont été effectuées dans toutes ces mines souterraines et des informations sur les eaux de mine éjectées, telles que la température et le taux de pompage, ont été utilisées dans cette analyse. L'étude commence par une évaluation préliminaire de l'économie et de l'environnement pour les 15 mines utilisant des catalogues de pompes à chaleur. Ensuite, des réunions avec des fournisseurs de pompes à chaleur géothermiques ont fourni un scénario réel grâce à un refroidisseur conçu sur mesure qui répond aux exigences de pompage de l'eau de une mine de chois.   La deuxième partie de cette thèse démontre le potentiel d'utilisation de masses d'eau de surface profondes pour le refroidissement des exploitations minières souterraines actives. Une mine candidate a été sélectionnée pour cette évaluation et les visites sur place. Des informations sur le lac et la mine ont été recueillies sur tout le site. Les catalogues des unités de traitement de l'air donnent une évaluation économique et environnementale préliminaire du refroidissement des lacs profonds pour les mines souterraines actives. Les résultats de ces études montrent des résultats prometteurs pour les applications de ces ressources d'énergie renouvelable dans l'industrie minière.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>  Renewable energy is becoming a key topic nowadays with increasing research topics surrounding sustainable energy. The mining industry in Canada consumes a great amount of non-renewable energy resulting in huge contribution to the nation's green house gas emissions. Therefore, this thesis investigates new possibilities for the mining industry to increase their dependence on renewable, non-polluting, sources of energy. The first part of the thesis illustrates the potential geothermal energy that can be obtained from the ejected water of active underground mining operations. The thesis illustrate the economic and environmental potential of 15 mines within Canada. Site visits were conducted to all of these underground mines and information about the ejected mine water, such as the temperature and pumping rate, was used in this analysis. The study starts with a preliminary economical and environmental assessment for the 15 mines using specifications of heat pumps catalogues. Then, a mine was selected for a real life scenario by providing a custom designed chiller that fits the water pumping requirements for that particular mine, which involved meetings with a geothermal heat pump suppliers.    The second part of this thesis demonstrate the potential of utilzing deep surface water bodies towards the cooling of active underground mining operations. A candidate mine was selected for this preliminary assessment and site visits were conducted. Information about both the lake and the mine were gathered throughout site visits. Then, Air Handling Unit (AHU) catalogues were used to give preliminary economical and environmental assessment of deep lake cooling for active underground mines. The results from both studies show promising results for the applications of these renewable energy resources within the mining industry. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Faramarz P. Hassani</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0969528.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w56v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining and Materials</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jb25v"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Establishments of trust: Intimate partner violence social workers and workplace social support</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brend, Denise Michelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Exposure to the aversive details of traumatic events has been shown to present a risk to the personal and professional well-being of intimate partner violence (IPV) social workers.  My dissertation presents a study, comprised of three manuscripts, that describes current knowledge on workplace social support as well as presents insights derived from interviews with five IPV social workers on their understandings and experiences of workplace social support.  The first manuscript is a scoping review that looks specifically at experiences, potential impacts, and factors related to human service professionals' exposure to the aversive details of IPV.  This review is guided by the research question "What has been found in the empirical, peer-reviewed, scholarly literature examining exposure to the aversive details of IPV amongst human service professionals?"  Thirteen relevant empirical, scholarly studies investigating exposure to the aversive details of IPV and human service professionals were identified.  The results of this scoping review support previous research that has found IPV human service professionals to be at elevated risk of harm as a result of their work.  Workplace social support emerges as a protective factor against adverse impacts on human service professionals' well-being and a gap is identified in how workplace social support is conceptualized.  To address this gap, I designed a study using interpretive phenomenological analysis that explores workplace social support experiences and sense-making amongst five IPV social workers.  The results of this study are presented in two manuscripts.  The first takes up the following questions: "How do IPV social workers describe experiences related to their workplaces that they perceive as socially supportive?" and "How do experiences that are perceived as socially supportive or unsupportive impact them?"  As will be seen, I argue that mentalization—a theory describing how people make sense of themselves, make sense of their work and regulate their emotions through relational interactions (Bateman, Bales, &amp; Hutsebaut, 2014; Bateman &amp; Fonagy, 2013; Freeman, 2016) — can help us understand the process, as described by IPV social workers, that brings about experiences perceived to be workplace social support.  In the second manuscript, I present findings that respond to the research question "How do IPV social workers make sense of their experiences related to workplace social support?"  Epistemic trust as described by Fonagy, Luyten, Allison, and Campbell (2017) is proposed as a framework through which to rethink what constitutes these IPV social workers' descriptions of effective workplace social support.  Workplace social support can therefore be understood as trusting engagement resulting from the perception and availability of interactions characterized by good mentalization.  This novel way of conceptualizing workplace social support proposes a process of social engagement that promotes IPV social workers capacities to cope with, and adapt to, challenging experiences inherent in IPV practice.   These theoretical models synthesized with current knowledge about IPV social workers' workplace social support make an important contribution to the social work, IPV, trauma, mentalization and epistemic trust literatures.  As such, recommendations are made for practice, education, training and future research.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'exposition aux détails d'évènements traumatiques est connue comme étant un risque pour le bien-être personnel et professionnel des travailleuses sociales œuvrant dans le domaine de la violence conjugale.  Ma thèse, comprenant trois manuscrits, présente une étude qui décrit les connaissances actuelles sur le soutien social au travail et présente des conclusions découlant d'entrevues avec des travailleuses sociales spécialisées en violence conjugale sur leur compréhension et leurs expériences du soutien social au travail.  Le premier manuscrit est une recension des écrits (scoping review) sur les expériences, impacts potentiels et facteurs reliés à l'exposition des professionnels en services sociaux aux effets négatifs de la violence conjugale. Cette recension est guidée par la question : « Qu'est-ce qu'on retrouve dans la littérature empirique et académique, examinée (étudiée?) par les pairs, sur l'exposition aux effets négatifs de la violence conjugale pour les professionnels en services sociaux? »  Treize études empiriques pertinentes sur le sujet ont été identifiées.  Les conclusions de cette recension soutiennent les recherches antérieures démontrant que les professionnels œuvrant dans le domaine de la violence conjugale sont exposés à un risque élevé de conséquences néfastes reliées à leur travail. Le soutien social au travail apparaît comme étant un facteur de protection contre les effets négatifs sur le bien-être de ces professionnels et identifie également une lacune dans la conceptualisation du soutien social au travail. Afin de remédier à cette lacune, une étude utilisant une analyse interprétative phénoménologique a été menée auprès de cinq travailleuses sociales spécialisées en violence conjugale pour analyser leurs expériences de soutien social au travail et le sens qu'elles y donnent.  Les résultats de cette étude sont présentés dans deux manuscrits.  Le premier répond aux questions suivantes : « Comment les travailleuses sociales spécialisées en violence conjugale décrivent-elles leurs expériences reliées au travail et qu'elles perçoivent comme étant aidantes? » et « Comment les expériences perçues comme aidantes ou négatives les affectent-elles? » Comme vous pourrez le constater dans mon exposé, je soutiens que la mentalisation – une théorie qui décrit comment les gens se comprennent eux-mêmes, comprennent leur travail, et expriment leurs émotions lors d'interactions relationnelles (Bateman et al., 2014; Bateman &amp; Fonagy, 2013; Freeman, 2016) – peut être instrumentale dans la conceptualisation du sens que donnent les travailleuses sociales au soutien social qu'elles reçoivent dans leur milieu de travail.  Dans le deuxième manuscrit, je présente les conclusions qui répondent à la question : « Comment les travailleuses sociales spécialisées en violence conjugale donnent-elles un sens à leurs expériences de soutien social au travail? »  Mon analyse suggère que les éléments du soutien social au travail qui ont été identifiés comme étant importants pour elles sont décrits par le processus théorique qui mène à la confiance épistémique, tel qu'élaboré par Fonagy et Allison (2004).  Ces modèles théoriques synthétisés avec les connaissances actuelles sur le soutien social que les travailleuses sociales œuvrant dans le domaine de la violence conjugale reçoivent au travail constituent une contribution importante à la littérature sur le travail social, la violence conjugale, le trauma, la mentalisation et la confiance épistémique.  Par conséquent, des recommandations pour la mise en pratique, l'éducation, la formation et la recherche sont aussi présentées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Julia Krane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j344f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb25v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tb682"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The view from here: Cooperating teachers perspectives on how school administrators can encourage and support student teacher mentors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Benn, James Hammel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le stage en enseignant est un élément important des programmes de formation des enseignants et il est essentiel de comprendre comment obtenir des résultats positifs dans ce stage afin de former des éducateurs de la plus haute qualité. Beaucoup de recherches ont été faites sur le sujet, mais elles sont majoritairement orientées vers le stagiaire. Cette thèse se concentre sur les besoins des enseignants associés et sur la manière dont les directeurs d'écoles peuvent encourager et soutenir les enseignants qui servent de mentors aux stagiaires. En interrogeant trois enseignants associés de différents milieux scolaires, j'ai découvert de multiples façons d'aider les administrateurs à développer une culture scolaire qui valorise la formation des stagiaires et qui reconnaît comment l'école dans son ensemble, peut bénéficier du travail des enseignants associés qui servent de mentors aux stagiaires.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The student teaching practicum is a significant element of teacher training programmes and understanding how to achieve positive outcomes in that practicum is critical in developing educators of the highest quality. There is much research on this topic, but it is heavily oriented toward the student teacher. This thesis focuses on the needs of cooperating teachers and how school administrators can encourage and support teachers who serve as mentors to student teachers. By interviewing three cooperating teachers from different educational backgrounds, I discovered multiple ways in which administrators encourage the development of a school culture which values student teaching and which recognises how the whole school can benefit from the work of cooperating teachers who mentor pre-service teachers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lisa Starr</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074x37h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb682</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623f842"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The evolution of views from a teacher perspective about participation in a mathematics professional learning community: the project that has made math more than math</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frechette, Sandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Professional Learning Communities have been shown to be effective vehicles of change for fostering school communities that value collective learning with the aim of improving school success. Multiple studies have focused on the characteristics of successful collaborations and supports for their implementation and sustainability. However, few studies have illustrated how these collaborations evolve over time, especially from a teacher perspective. This qualitative research uses a case study methodology to illustrate how teachers, in a mathematics professional learning community, changed their views about the purpose of their collaboration in a four-year project. Teacher responses from end-of-year interviews were used to conduct a constant comparative approach. A qualitative and quantitative analysis yielded the discovery of themes that show an evolution, in three phases, of teachers' views about the nature and purpose of the professional learning community: a) the conversation, b) the collaboration with trust and c) the self-reflection via community collaboration. The study provides an analysis, through the lens of the communities of practice theory, that illustrates the progression of social learning through the development of teacher community. The results provide recommendations to inform educational leaders in the development of professional learning communities in mathematics and more broadly.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les communautés d'apprentissage professionnelles sont un facteur de changement qui favorise des valeurs d'apprentissage collectif dont l'objectif est d'améliorer la réussite scolaire. De multiples études ont porté sur les caractéristiques de collaboration et de soutien de leur mise en œuvre et de leur pérennité. Toutefois, peu d'études ont illustré l'évolution de cette collaboration, particulièrement du point de vue des enseignants. Cette étude qualitative fondée sur la méthodologie d'étude de cas illustre comment les enseignants de mathématiques dans les communautés d'apprentissage professionnelles ont modifié leurs perspectives sur l'objectif de leur collaboration tout au long de leur projet qui s'étalait sur quatre ans. Nous avons analysé les réponses d'enseignants lors d'entrevues de fin d'année au moyen d'une méthode comparative constante. Une analyse qualitative et quantitative a mené à une découverte de thèmes qui montrent une évolution, en trois phases, des opinions des enseignants à propos de la nature et de la raison d'être des communautés d'apprentissage professionnelles : a) la conversation, b) la collaboration avec confiance et c) l'introspection par la collaboration communautaire. L'étude fournit une analyse, dans l'optique de la théorie de la communauté de pratique, qui illustre la progression de l'apprentissage social. Les résultats peuvent être utiles afin d'informer les leaders en matière d'éducation sur le développement des communautés d'apprentissage professionnelles. De plus, cette recherche vise à soutenir et à augmenter la qualité de l'éducation des mathématiques. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alain Breuleux</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Marta Kobiela</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q6450.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f842</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vq74p"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning to discipline students in Montreal schools: An administrator's perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cheff, Nathalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Using the lens of educational institutional ethnography, this dissertation explores how the disciplining of students is textually and socially organized in Montreal (Quebec) schools. This qualitative study investigates, first how school administrators learn to discipline students. Secondly, this research project considers how different stakeholders in schools (e.g., teachers, administrators, students and parents) view school discipline differently. Concentrating on the school administrators' description of the work they do on a daily basis in elementary and high schools, I used ethnographic data (interviews, textual analysis and journaling) to discover how discipline is organized and how administrators learn to do it and think about it in the ways that they do.  Findings suggest that new vice-principals learn to do their work in action with the people they work with and through coaching from their principal, rather than simply basing their decision-making process on common sense and professional judgement as they initially suggested. The study also found that teachers play an important role in how students are disciplined in a school and have a tendency to favor exclusionary disciplinary measures when other measures have failed. Both of these findings bring about concerns for biases and discrimination against students with special needs and from visible minorities who could be targeted by these exclusionary disciplinary measures. Finally, the research project illuminated a disconnect between teachers and administrators' expectations in relation to disciplining students.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En s'inspirant de la théorie de l'ethnographie institutionnelle en éducation, cette thèse explore comment la discipline des élèves est organisée textuellement et socialement dans des écoles montréalaises (au Québec). Cette étude qualitative enquête premièrement sur la façon dont les directeurs d'école apprennent à discipliner les élèves. Deuxièmement, ce projet de recherche tient compte de la façon que les nombreux partenaires de l'école (enseignants, directeurs, élèves et parents) considèrent différemment la discipline des élèves. En me concentrant principalement sur la description du travail fait au quotidien par les directeurs d'écoles primaires et secondaires, j'ai utilisé des données ethnographiques (entrevues, analyse textuelle et écriture d'un journal professionnel) pour découvrir comment la discipline était organisée, apprise et perçue par les différents partenaires. Les résultats suggèrent que les nouveaux directeurs-adjoints apprennent leur travail, incluant la discipline des élèves, en travaillant au quotidien avec leurs collègues et à travers le mentorat des directeurs avec lesquels ils travaillent étroitement, plutôt que d'utiliser le bon sens et leur jugement professionnel tel que suggéré au départ. L'étude a aussi démontré que les enseignants jouent un rôle très important dans la discipline des élèves dans une école et vont en arriver à préférer les moyens disciplinaires d'exclusion lorsque d'autres moyens de discipline progressive ont échoué. Ces deux résultats amènent des préoccupations par rapport aux jugements biaisés et à la discrimination envers les élèves à besoins particuliers et ceux de minorités visibles qui pourraient être visés par ces mesures disciplinaires d'exclusion. Finalement, ce projet de recherche démontre une discorde quant aux attentes des enseignants et celles des directeurs au sujet de la discipline des élèves.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Naomi Nichols</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f3636.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq74p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am039k741s"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The quasi-regulatory regime of the international air transport association (IATA) and its impact upon the airline industry and the consumer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hettiarachchi, Don Lasantha I</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>ABSTRACTThe growth of global trade and commerce has contributed to an increase of private non-state entities making transnational rules and standards which regulate industries around the word. IATA is such a non-governmental international organization. Established in 1945 as a trade association of scheduled international airlines, its professed objective was to promote safe, regular and economic air transport for the benefit of the public through mutual cooperation amongst members. At its advent, IATA provided a conference mechanism facilitating airline members to meet, confer, compare costs and agree on air fares and rates applicable for scheduled air transport around the world. This function of tariff coordination, performed with the acquiescence of national governments, was also used by IATA to prescribe rules for service standards, travel agent administration and a multitude of other matters covering international air transport. These rules, formulated as contractual obligations imposed on its members and accredited agents, created direct and indirect implications for airline consumers. Numerous influences such as regulatory pressures, the discontinuation of antitrust immunity, economic challenges from non-scheduled operators and airline alliances that IATA encountered in its seven decades of existence resulted in a significant transformation of the organization. Contemporary IATA is a dynamic and robust commercial enterprise whose sustenance is solely predicated on the revenue generated by supplying products and services to the airline industry. IATA's commercial pursuits are seamlessly integrated into its regime of rules and standards that are made for members and agents. However, IATA rules invariably also affect the rights and interests of many stakeholders in the airline industry and notably the consumer. Although a considerable amount of academic literature has been produced on IATA and its quasi rules, most of these predate IATA's transformation into a predominantly commercial enterprise. This thesis therefore proposes to examine contemporary IATA and its transnational quasi-regulations which affect the airline industry in general and the consumer in particular. An analysis of specific IATA resolutions relating to passenger services and travel agents is presented to show the mandatory compliance features contained in these resolutions which affect consumers and third parties. By tracing the historical evolution of IATA and its current commercial pursuits, this thesis seeks to justify increased national regulatory oversight of IATA and its quasi-rules as essential for the protection of consumers. In concluding that states should not abdicate their responsibilities for protecting citizens, this thesis proposes recommendations for national regulatory and oversight measures that will ensure IATA and its quasi-rules are consistent with their declared objective to promote safe, regular and economic air transport for the benefit of the peoples of the world.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>RÉSUMÉLa croissance du commerce et des échanges mondiaux a contribué à l'augmentation du nombre d'entités privées non étatiques qui décident des règles et normes transnationales régissant les industries autour du monde. L'AITA est une telle organisation internationale non gouvernementale. L'AITA fut établie en 1945 en tant qu'association professionnelle de compagnies aériennes internationales régulières avec pour objectif de promouvoir un transport aérien sûr, régulier et économique dans l'intérêt du public grâce à une coopération mutuelle de ses membres. À son avènement, l'AITA prévoyait un mécanisme permettant aux membres des compagnies aériennes de se rencontrer, de se concerter, ainsi que de comparer les coûts et de se mettre d'accord sur les tarifs applicables au transport aérien régulier dans le monde. Cette fonction de coordination tarifaire, assurée par les gouvernements nationaux, a également été utilisée par l'AITA pour imposer des règles prévoyant des standards de service, d'administration des agents de voyages et une multitude d'autres questions concernant le transport aérien international. Ces règles, formulées comme des obligations contractuelles imposées à ses membres et agents accrédités, ont créé des implications directes et indirectes pour les consommateurs aériens. De nombreuses influences telles que les contraintes réglementaires, l'abandon de l'immunité antitrust, les défis économiques des opérateurs non réguliers et les alliances aériennes que l'AITA a rencontrées au cours de ses sept décennies d'existence ont entraîné une transformation significative. Ainsi, l'AITA contemporaine est une entreprise commerciale dynamique et robuste dont la subsistance est basée sur les seuls revenus générés par la vente de produits et de services à l'industrie du transport aérien. Les activités commerciales de l'AITA sont parfaitement intégrées dans son régime de règles et de normes créées pour ses membres et agents. Cependant, les règles de l'AITA affectent également inévitablement les droits et les intérêts de nombreuses parties prenantes de l'industrie du transport aérien tel que le consommateur. Bien que l'AITA, ainsi que ses quasi-règles, aient fait l'objet de nombreuses études, la majeure partie de cette littérature et de ces analyses sont antérieures à la transformation de l'AITA en tant qu'entreprise commerciale. Cette thèse propose donc d'examiner l'AITA contemporaine et ses quasi-réglementations transnationales qui affectent tant l'industrie du transport aérien en général que le consommateur en particulier. Une analyse des résolutions de l'AITA relatives aux services de passagers et aux agents de voyages est présentée afin d'illustrer les caractéristiques de conformité obligatoires contenues dans ces résolutions qui affectent les consommateurs et les tiers. En retraçant l'évolution historique de l'AITA et ses activités commerciales actuelles, cette thèse cherche à justifier le renforcement de la surveillance réglementaire nationale de l'AITA et de ses quasi-règles en tant qu'éléments essentiels pour la protection des consommateurs. En concluant que les États ne devraient pas renoncer à leurs responsabilités de protection des citoyens, cette thèse émet des recommandations telles que des mesures nationales de régulation et de contrôle qui assureront que l'AITA et ses quasi-règles sont conformes à leur objectif déclaré de promouvoir un transport aérien sûr, régulier et économique au profit des peuples du monde.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Stephen Dempsey</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139429r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k741s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air and Space Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107126d"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The journey of ladders and snakes: help-seeking among mothers and fathers of children with neurodisabilities (ND)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Glidden, Gina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Help-seeking is an ongoing endeavour for mothers and fathers of children with neurodisabilities (ND), yet little is known about what their seeking process entails: the mechanisms, structures, and interpersonal engagements that coincide during their quest to seek help. Further, current knowledge about 'parents' of children with ND, stems from research conducted with samples composed largely of mothers, thus what is known about parents is more precisely about mothers, lacking the perspectives and experiences of fathers. This manuscript-based social work doctoral dissertation was designed to explore how mothers and fathers of children with ND seek help, for their child and for themselves, within both informal (e.g., family, friends, neighbours), and formal (e.g., pediatric hospitals and rehabilitation centers, health and social service organizations) networks of support. It is composed of six chapters, two of which are manuscripts that report findings related to the Constructivist Grounded Theory study on help-seeking, being prepared for submission in journals of qualitative social work research, and disability.The first article describes the Journey of Ladders and Snakes, the substantive theory that emerged from the analysis of interviews conducted with 6 mothers and 6 fathers (representing 6 co-parenting dyads) of children between the ages of 8 and 15 years. The theory characterises help-seeking as an ongoing journey that is focused primarily on mothers and fathers seeking for their child, through complimentary roles that reflect their personalities, personal preferences, and skillsets. The article describes elements that facilitate seeking (parental transformation, privilege, complementarity, relationships), as well as those that render seeking more challenging (negative encounters with professional helpers, difficulty navigating formal support networks, and gendered support availability). The second article describes a Cyclical Process Model of Help-Seeking, a practical representation of the substantive theoretical knowledge that emerged from the study. The model depicts help-seeking as a reoccurring process that involves three elements: (1) mothers and fathers identifying that a situation is one they are unable to deal with themselves (one that is current, in the near future or anticipated later), (2) a process of active seeking (within informal and formal networks, online, social media), and (3) a period of settling back into family life (adjusting and moving on).  Help-seeking is identified as a cyclical process that is unique to each need, that reoccurs along a continuum of time during which needs change, and that is characterized by improvement in parent knowledge and familiarity with the seeking process given their relatively fixed roles.Implications for practice, policy, and future research are presented in the final chapter followed by a general conclusion. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La recherche d'aide est un effort continuel pour les mères et pères d'enfants atteints de troubles neurodéveloppementaux (TN), pourtant, très peu est connu de ce que comporte leur processus de recherche: les mécanismes, structures et engagements interpersonnels qui coïncident lors de leur  recherche d'aide.  De plus, les connaissances courantes sur les « parents » d'enfants atteints de TN proviennent principalement d'études portant sur des échantillons de recherche composés majoritairement de mères. Par conséquent, ces connaissances sur les parents sont essentiellement des connaissances sur les mères, occultant ainsi les perspectives et les expériences des pères. Cette thèse de doctorat en travail social composée d'articles vise à  explorer de quelle façon les mères et pères d'enfants atteints de TN cherchent de l'aide pour leur enfant et pour eux-mêmes, tant dans des réseaux de soutien informels (p. ex. les familles, les amis et amies, les voisins et voisines) que formels (p. ex. les hôpitaux pédiatriques et les centres de réadaptation, les organismes de la santé et des services sociaux). La thèse compte six chapitres, deux d'entre eux font état des conclusions d'une étude sur la recherche d'aide axée sur l'approche constructiviste de la théorie ancrée (ACTA). Ces chapitres sont préparés aux fins de publication dans des revues de recherche qualitative en travail social. Le premier article présente la recherche de doctorat empirique et décrit le Parcours des échelles et des serpents, une théorie concrète dégagée de l'analyse des données d'entrevues réalisées avec six mères et  six pères (correspondant à six dyades co-parentales) d'enfants âgés entre huit et quinze ans. Cette théorie caractérise la recherche d'aide comme un parcours continu axé essentiellement sur la recherche d'aide par les mères et les pères pour leur enfant, par une complémentarité de rôles qui reflètent leur personnalité, leurs préférences personnelles et l'ensemble de leurs compétences. L'article définit des éléments qui facilitent la recherche d'aide (la transformation parentale, les privilèges, la complémentarité, les relations), ainsi que d'autres qui rendent la recherche plus difficile (des rencontres négatives avec des aidants professionnels, la navigation difficile des réseaux de soutien formels et la disponibilité du soutien sexospécifique). Le deuxième article présente et décrit le Modèle de processus cyclique de la recherche d'aide, une représentation pratique de la connaissance théorique dégagée de l'étude. Le modèle définit la recherche d'aide comme un processus récurrent qui comprend trois éléments : 1) une reconnaissance par les mères et pères qu'une situation donnée les dépasse (une situation courante, imminente, ou anticipée), 2) un processus de recherche active (au sein de réseaux informels et formels, en ligne, sur les médias sociaux) et 3) une période de reprise de la vie de famille (ajustement et « tourner la page»'). La recherche d'aide est définie comme un processus cyclique unique à chaque situation, qui se répète sur un continuum de temps au cours duquel les besoins changent et qui se caractérise par une augmentation des connaissances des parents et de leur familiarité avec le processus de recherche en fonction des rôles qui demeurent relativement fixes.Les implications pour la pratique, les politiques et les projets de recherche à venir sont résumées dans le dernier chapitre, suivi d'une conclusion général.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lucyna Maria Lach</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xx18x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107126d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arf55zb00r"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Unraveling the role of the X chromosome in cancer: characterization of FOXP3 Isoforms and PR70 in cutaneous melanoma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Redpath, Margaret</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>De nombreux cancers ont une incidence, un comportement et une réponse au traitement différents chez les hommes et chez les femmes. Traditionnellement, ces variations spécifiques liées au sexe ont été attribuées à des différences entre les sexes dans les habitudes, l'exposition professionnelle et le statut hormonal. Plus récemment, il a été reconnu que certaines de ces différences peuvent être attribuées à la génétique. Nous avons été particulièrement frappés par l'augmentation significative de l'incidence et de la mortalité du mélanome chez l'homme. L'objectif de ce projet était de caractériser la contribution du chromosome X à cet effet. L'analyse globale des altérations génomiques a révélée qu'une perte somatique d'un chromosome X chez les femmes est associée de manière significative à un pronostic plus défavorable du mélanome. Nous avons en outre montré que c'est le X inactif qui est perdu dans tous les cas. Cela a conduit à l'hypothèse qu'une mutation activatrice d'un oncogène, ou une mutation inactivatrice d'un gène suppresseur de tumeur sur le chromosome X restant chez ces patients contribuent à l'agressivité de la tumeur. PPP2R3B et FOXP3 ont été identifiés comme des gènes justifiant une investigation plus poussée en tant que gènes suppresseurs de tumeurs liés au chromosome X dans le mélanome en raison de leur comportement dans d'autres types de tumeurs. Nous avons démontré que ces gènes sont exprimés dans la majorité de nos lignées cellulaires au niveau de l'ARNm et des protéines. L'expression de PR70 endogène et exogène est significativement corrélée à une diminution de la prolifération. Dans le mélanome humain, il existe une forte corrélation entre les faibles taux d'expression de l'ARNm du PR70 et la faible survie sans métastase à distance par les analyses multivariées. Dans cette optique, une expression nulle ou faible de la protéine PR70 est associée à une faible survie globale dans trois cohortes indépendantes de mélanome. La surexpression de PR70 exogène diminue la prise de tumeur et la croissance chez les souris nues, contrairement à la baisse de l'expression de PR70 induite par shRNA qui l'augmente. PR70 et le FOXP3 sont tous deux associés à une diminution dose-dépendante de la prolifération cellulaire du mélanome avec une accumulation de cellules dans la phase G1 du cycle cellulaire. Ces résultats sont d'importance in vivo car la prolifération est l'un des facteurs pronostiques indépendants les plus forts dans le mélanome.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Many cancers have a different incidence, behavior and response to treatment in men and women. Traditionally these sex-specific variations have been attributed to differences in habits, occupational exposures and hormones. More recently it has been recognized that some of the dissimilarities can be attributed to genetics. We were particularly struck by the significant increase in the incidence and mortality of melanoma in men. The objective of this project was to characterize how the X chromosome contributes to this effect. Global analysis of genomic alterations revealed that a somatic loss of one X chromosome in females was significantly associated with a worse prognosis in melanoma. We further showed that it was the inactive X that was lost in all cases. This led to the hypothesis that an activating mutation of an oncogene, or inactivating mutation of a tumor suppressor gene, on the remaining X chromosome in these patients was contributing to tumor aggressiveness. PR70 and FOXP3 were identified as warranting further investigation as candidate X-linked tumor suppressors in melanoma based on their behaviour in other tumor types. The PPP2R3B gene (Xp22.33) encodes for PR70, the regulatory subunit of a protein phosphatase that plays a critical role in cell cycle progression. In melanoma a strong correlation is demonstrated between low levels of PR70 mRNA expression and poor distant metastasis-free survival by multivariate analyses. In line with this, no or low PR70 protein expression is associated with poor overall survival in three independent sample sets of melanoma. Endogenous and exogenous PR70 expression levels are shown to have an inverse correlation with the rate of melanoma cell proliferation. Exogenous PR70 overexpression decreases tumor take and growth in nude mice compared to shRNA-mediated downregulation that increases it. The FOXP3 gene (Xp23.11) encodes a transcription factor that is important for T-regulatory cell development. Interestingly, FOXP3 was also found to be expressed in the majority of our melanoma cell lines at both the mRNA and protein level.  All five of the known isoforms of FOXP3 were shown to localize to the nucleus in melanoma cell lines and demonstrated isoform- and cell line-specific effects on gene transcription. Both PR70 and FOXP3 are associated with a dose-dependent decrease in melanoma cell proliferation with an accumulation of cells in the G1 phase of the cell cycle. These findings are significant because proliferative rate is one of the strongest independent prognostic factors in melanoma. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alan Spatz</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b522.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zb00r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gz48h"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Jabal Āmil: The production of space in an Islamicate context from the birth of Islam to the nineteenth century</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abidor, Pascal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Where is Jabal ʿĀmil? What is Jabal ʿĀmil? Though today Jabal ʿĀmil is widely considered to be the folk name for what is now called "South Lebanon," this dissertation answers these questions by examining the history of the idea of Jabal ʿĀmil as an instance of the production of space in an Islamicate context. To examine how Jabal ʿĀmil was produced as a space by various authors operating within and outside of a self-identifying ʿĀmilī-Shiʿi historiography, the period under consideration spans the dawn of Islam through to the nineteenth century. This analysis begins by looking at the first associations of the Banū ʿĀmila, Jabal ʿĀmil's eponym, with al-Shām (Greater Syria) as mentioned in Prophetic hadith and traces the gradual development of Jabal ʿĀmila as an increasingly complex geographic object that is connected to a Shiʿi community within diverse genres of Arabic-Islamic historiography. The study then focuses on the production of Jabal ʿĀmil as a space from the seventeenth to nineteenth centuries. Three texts by different authors from Jabal ʿĀmil, a biographical dictionary, a list of the region's villages, and a fragment chronicle, are examined for the different ways they portrayed Jabal ʿĀmil and the underlying logics of those portrayals. The examination of different iterations of Jabal ʿĀmil reveals that the region was not merely portrayed differently by various authors but possesses multiple modes of existence. This ontologolically pluralistic approach also reveals the existence of an alternative spatial conceptualization of the region: Bilād al-Matāwila, named after the Matāwila, the Ottoman era name for the Shiʿa of western al-Shām who engaged in politics and political conflicts.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Où est Jabal ʿĀmil? Qu'est-ce que Jabal ʿĀmil? Bien qu'aujourd'hui Jabal ʿĀmil est considéré le nom folklorique pour ce qu'on appelle le "Liban Sud," cette thèse repond à ces questions en examinant l'histoire de l'idée de Jabal ʿĀmil en tant qu'instance de la production de l'espace dans un contexte "islamicisé." Afin d'examiner comment Jabal ʿĀmil a été produit comme un espace par divers auteurs qui opèrent à l'intérieur et à l'extérieur d'une historiographie ʿāmilite-chiʿite auto-identifiante, la période considérée va de l'avènement de l'Islam jusqu'au dix-neuvième siècle. On commence par examiner les premières associations des Banū ʿĀmila, éponyme de Jabal ʿĀmil, avec al-Shām (la Grande Syrie) mentionné dans les hadiths prophétiques, avant de tracer le dévelopement graduel de Jabal ʿĀmil comme un objet géographique de plus en plus complexe et connecté à une communauté chiʿite dans des genres divers d'historiographie Arabe-islamique. L'étude continue par se concentrer sur la production de Jabal ʿĀmil comme un espace du dix-septième au dix-neuvième siècle. Trois textes, par auteurs differents de Jabal ʿĀmil, un dictionnaire biographique, une liste des villages de la région et un fragment d'une chronique, sont examinés pour les façons différentes dont ils représentents Jabal ʿĀmil et les logiques sous-jacentes de ces representations. L'examen des iterations differentes de Jabal ʿĀmil révèle que la region n'a pas été simplement décrite differement par divers auteurs, mais possede des modes multiples d'existence. Cette approche, ontologiquement plurastique, révèle aussi l'existence d'une conceptualization spatiale alternative de la région: Bilād al-Matāwila, nommé pour les Matāwila, le nom, dans l'époque ottomane, signifiant Chiʿites de al-Shām Occidentale engagés dans la politique et les conflits politique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rula Abisaab</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qp39t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz48h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islamic Studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289m265"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An emotional conceptual lens on part-time teaching in a university context: A case study approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dali, Yosra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les universités canadiennes comptent de plus en plus sur des professeurs contractuels à court terme. Il en résulte un plus grand nombre d'enseignants universitaires à temps partiel, ainsi qu'une plus grande visibilité de ces groupes. Les instructeurs à temps partiel sont des enseignants à part entière ; ils démontrent également une conscience plus développée de la précarité de leurs conditions de travail. Dans cette thèse, j'explore sous un regard conceptuel émotionnel, les perceptions de trois instructeurs à temps partiel de leur enseignement et de leur statut d'enseignants universitaires à temps partiel. Une approche conceptuelle de l'émotion dans le contexte des expériences d'enseignement universitaire à temps partiel permet de comprendre les liens, les tensions et les opportunités qui caractérisent le travail et le statut contractuels, tout en mettant en avant les investissements personnels et professionnels des instructeurs à temps partiel. Mon étude s'est concentrée sur les questions de recherche suivantes : 1) Comment les instructeurs à temps partiel perçoivent-ils le rôle de l'émotion dans leur enseignement ? 2) Comment les instructeurs à temps partiel perçoivent-ils leur statut à temps partiel ? En m'appuyant sur une approche narrative, j'ai construit une recherche qualitative fondée sur une étude de cas pour étudier les expériences de trois professeurs universitaires et instructeurs de cours de premier cycle à temps partiel dans une grande université de la province du Québec. Les entrevues libres ont porté sur le rôle des émotions au sein et autour de leur enseignement ; ceci incluait une réflexion sur leur statut précaire. Les données des entrevues ont été analysées par thèmes, des récits ont été construits, puis réanalysés. L'analyse thématique a révélé l'importance de certains thèmes dans les deux questions de recherche, notamment la vulnérabilité, la flexibilité, le sentiment de conflit et les sensations de précarité par rapport à la réalité complexe vécue par les participants. La thèse se termine par des recommandations en lien avec le statut et la pratique d'enseignement des professeurs d'université à temps partiel. Pour mes participants, l'enseignement à temps partiel comportait des expériences émotionnelles à plusieurs niveaux : ils aimaient beaucoup enseigner, mais leur insécurité d'emploi créait une double contrainte pour eux. Compte tenu de la demande croissante de professeurs contractuels, il est impératif que les perspectives de ces groupes soient étudiées en profondeur et prises en compte dans tous les domaines, de la sécurité d'emploi à la prestation des programmes.Des recherches plus approfondies doivent étudier des moyens pour mieux suivre les données sur les professeurs à temps partiel. Ceci permettrait de révéler des tendances sans lesquelles des politiques efficaces, des pratiques fondées sur des preuves et de nouvelles stratégies ne pourraient pas être développées. De plus, il est important d'examiner plus en profondeur la diversité des conditions de travail et des nominations universitaires, y compris une tendance relativement récente : le corps enseignant permanent dans les universités canadiennes. Les recherches futures doivent également aborder la pertinence et les implications du statut à temps partiel pour le bien-être et l'enseignement, ainsi que pour le développement personnel et professionnel.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In recent years, Canadian universities are increasingly relying on shorter-term contract faculty. This has led to a larger number of part-time university teachers, as well as a stronger visibility of these groups. Part-time instructors are demonstrating a more acute awareness of the precariousness of their working conditions; despite the fact that they are teachers in their own right. In this thesis, I bring an emotional conceptual lens to explore three part-time instructors' perceptions of their teaching, and of their part-time status as university teachers. My study focused on the following research questions: 1) How do part-time instructors perceive the role of emotion in relation to their teaching? 2) How do part-time instructors perceive their part-time status?Drawing on a narrative approach, I constructed a case study qualitative research design to study the experiences of three sessional university teachers and part-time instructors of undergraduate education courses at a major university in the province of Quebec. An emotion lens facilitated the participants' provision of self-reported descriptions of part-time teaching experiences. Open-ended interviews focused on the subject of the role of emotions in and around their teaching; this included reflection on their precarious status. The interview data was analyzed thematically, narratives were constructed, and then re-analyzed. Thematic analysis revealed the salience of such themes as vulnerability, flexibility, feeling conflicted and precariousness to the complex reality lived by the participants.The thesis concludes with recommendations for part-time university teachers' status and teaching practice. For my participants, part-time teaching constituted layered emotional experiences: they greatly enjoyed teaching, yet their job insecurity created a double-bind for them. Given the growing importance of contract faculty, it is imperative that the perspectives of such groups are thoroughly studied and taken into account on everything from employment security to program delivery. A conceptual focus on emotion in the context of part-time university teaching experiences helps understand the links, tensions and opportunities which are constitutive of contractual work and status. Further research should address ways of keeping better track of data on part-time faculty as this would help reveal trends without which effective policies, evidence-based practices, and new strategies may not be developed. Moreover, it is important to further investigate the diversity of academic work conditions and appointments, including a relatively recent trend: permanent teaching-stream faculty in Canadian universities. Future research could look more deeply at the relevance of part-time teaching experiences for wellness and teaching, aspects which may have implications for both personal and professional development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Teresa Strong</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mm21g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m265</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sz213"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The synthesis of three dimensional haptic textures, geometry, control, and psychophysics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Campion, Gianni</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The synthesis and rendering of haptic textures is extremely sensitive to the characteristics of the haptic devices employed to deliver the force stimulation, and the simplifications introduced in the synthesis algorithms bear significant consequences for the final quality of the haptic experience. When the limits of the device are exceeded or when the algorithm is poorly calibrated, a number of artifacts can corrupt the haptic interaction. In this thesis, the problem of generating artifact-free textures is tackled from three different sides. First, a novel framework of six conditions is introduced. These conditions can identify the sources of rendering artifacts related to the hardware properties of the haptic device, and specify the range of textures that can be reliably generated by each haptic device. The second component of the thesis is a complete analysis of currently available haptic texture algorithms carried out with a tool called characteristic number. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La synthèse et le rendu de textures haptiques sont extrêmement sensibles aux caractéristiques des dispositifs haptiques employés pour produire une stimulation par retour d'effort. Les simplifications introduites par les algorithmes de synthèse ont des conséquences significatives sur la qualité finale de l'expérience haptique. Quand les limites du dispositif sont dépassées ou quand un algorithme est mal calibre, un certain nombre d'artefacts peuvent corrompre l'interaction haptique. Dans cette thèse, le problème de la génération de textures sans d 'artefacts est attaque sur trois fronts. Tout d'abord, un ensemble de six conditions est introduit. Ces conditions permettent d'identifier les sources d'artefacts reliées aux propriétés matérielles de l'appareil haptique et spécifier la gamme des textures qui peuvent être générées de façon fiable pour un dispositif haptique donne. La seconde composante de cette thèse est une analyse complète des principaux algorithmes de textures haptiques disponibles aujourd'hui qui est effectuée a l'aide d'un outil appelé le nombre caractéristique. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hayward, Vincent</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bf046.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz213</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pantograph -- Design and construction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Haptic devices -- Design and construction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945t21t"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of questioning on the quality of electronic interaction in a learning community</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rojas Fernández, Gilda Teresa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of this study was to determine the influence of higher-order questioning on the amount and quality of electronic interaction in an asynchronous learning environment (a University course). The assessment of the quality was accomplished by quantitative, qualitative and graphical methods. For the quantitative part, a system for the analysis of the electronic interaction transcripts, based on Scardamalia and Bereiter's (1999) conceptions of knowledge building and Mercer's (1996) notions of ways of talking, was developed; for the qualitative part, a survey was applied at the end of the course. In addition, the threaded discussion was mapped by means of a graph. Data obtained from these three sources provided a rich picture about the amount, the characteristics of the electronic interaction, and the reasons why the students participated in the way they did.  […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette étude avait pour objectif de déterminer l'influence de questions de niveau supérieur sur la quantité et la qualité des échanges électroniques dans un environnement d'apprentissage asynchrone (un cours universitaire). L'évaluation de la qualité a été faite par des méthodes quantitatives, qualitatives et graphiques. Pour la partie quantitative, un système d'analyse des interactions électroniques a été développé à partir des conceptions de la co-élaboration de connaissances de Scardamalia et Bereiter (1999) et des types de discours de Mercer (1996). Pour la partie qualitative, un questionnaire a été utilisé. Les discussions ont aussi été représentées sous forme graphique. Les données obtenues de ces trois sources permettent de dresser un portrait détaillé des niveaux et des types d'interactions électroniques, des caractéristiques de ces échanges, et des raisons pour lesquelles les étudiants ont participé comme ils l'ont fait. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Breuleux, Alain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vt15k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945t21t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Group work in education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education -- Data processing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n559z"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The comparative biology of phenotypic variability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cabana, Gilbert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse traite de la variabilité phénotypique de certains caractères morphométrique et démographiques de populations animales et végétales. La section méthodologique traite en particulier de problèmes statistiques associes à la mesure de la variabilité. Premièrement, deux mesures statistiques de la variabilité utilisées en écologie, l'Indice de Gini (G) et le Coefficient de Variation (CV) sont comparées. Il est démontré a l'aide d'exemples hypothétiques et réels que ces deux indices sont fortement relies entre eux et qu'ils représente donc deux mesures redondantes de la variabilité. De plus, une comparaison des deux indices suggère que G devrait être rejeté au profit du CV. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present thesis deals with the study of the phenotypic variability of some morphometric and life history characters. The methodological section deals with some statistical problems associated with the measurement of variability. First, two statistical indexes of variability currently used in the biological literature, the Gini Index (G) and the Coefficient of Variation (CV), are compared. It is shown through the use of hypothetical and real data sets that the two indexes are strongly correlated and therefore represent redundant measures of variability. Itis then argued that CV should be used instead of G in the comparative study of variability. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bell, Graham</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v076c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n559z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Variation (Biology) -- Statistical methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Variation (Biology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>