<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pm00x"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors Affecting the Binding and Synthesis of Acetylcholine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brodkin, Elliot</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Feldberg and Schilf (18) have given the name 'Gewebshormone' to pharmacologically active substances which are formed unspecifically by a number of organs and whose normal metabolic action seems to be a local one although they are capable of acting on organs some distance from their site of formation. Acetylcholine and histamine are two such substances.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elliott, K. A. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dx10s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pm00x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80j027q"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Corrosion Behaviour of Welded Low Alloy Steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Briggs, David C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of many corrosion problems confronting engineers is the failure of metal structures caused by specific corrosive attack at welds. Such attack is especially dangerous when more rapid than the normal corrosion rate of the material, and usually occurs in the following forms: (a) Specific attack of weld metal; (b) Specific attack of parent metal adjacent to a weld deposit; (c) Intergranular corrosion of weld or parent metal in stainless steel due to "sensitization".</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yates, H. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956k66d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j027q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Metallurgical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d127k"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>a Microelectrode Study of Betz Cells in the Unanesthetized Cat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Branch, Charles L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The need for continued investigation into the mechanism of motor function has been emphasized recently by Bucy (1957) in a critical review entitled, "ls there a pyramidal tract?" and by Lassek, Woolsey, Walker, and Boshes (1957) in a symposium of inquiry into the state of our knowledge of the pyramidal tract presented before the eighth annual meeting of the American Academy of Neurology. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v642h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d127k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687m92k"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Two-level representation of the atmosphere</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boville, Byron. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper discusses the adequacy of representing the constant pressure surfaces in the atmosphere by considering only two levels, 1000 mb and 500 mb. The equations of motion and the thermodynamic equation are reviewed, together with the formulation of the Sawyer-Bushby and Godson two-level models. The height data for eight standard pressure levels from 1000 mb to 100 mb for January 1956 were used to determine linear correlation among the various levels. The multiple regression equations, so determined, were tested against independent data in 1958. It is found that the two levels account for most of the contour height variance up to 300 mb. The degree of representation drops above 300 mb and is quite variable at 100 mb. The experiment suggests that two-level representation of the synoptic scale contour height patterns is adequate, up to the 300 mb level.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm92s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687m92k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meteorology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f489j"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The communist conquest of power in Yugoslavia 1941-1945</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bosnitch, Sava. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Communist Party of Yugoslavia (CPY) was formed in 1919 through a fusion of various socialist parties and non-organized radical elements in the territory of the new Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes, later known as the Kingdom of Yugoslavia. This unification took place under the impact of the Bolshevik Revolution. It was achieved through peremptory acceptance of a platform which advocated “repudiation of the traitorous policies of the Second International, refusal to participate in the Coalition Government and abstention from the work of the Interim National Assembly”.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brecher, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw208.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f489j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics and Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182p82t"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparison of embryo sacs and haustoria in selected species of Impatiens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Biard, Joan. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The object of this problem was to study the ovule development of selected species of Impatiens. Special emphasis was placed on the occurrence, origin, and nature of the haustoria in these species. The genus, Impatiens, is of embryological interest for two reasons. The conflicting statements concerning the types of embryo sacs in certain of the species must be reconciled (Maheshwari, 1955). The synergid, embryo sac and endosperm haustoria present interesting research material which may aid in the clarification of this family’s phylogenetic position.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wilson, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pm016.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182p82t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j904g"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adaptations to adoptive parenthood</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bedoukian, Marjorie</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Casault, Micheline</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Cherow, Miriam</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Linck, Patricia</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Schiff, Shirley</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Singer, Louise</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Townshend, Ruth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This project studied the parental self-picture of adopters, processes of adjustment to adoption, assessment of adjustment, and adopters’ attitudes regarding racially mixed adoptions. The adopters had been unable to procreate their families, and in this respect were different from natural parents. Some adopters might be conscious of this difference, while others might- feel that the adoptive family approximates the natural. These feelings of “sameness” or “difference” were thought to affect the adopters’ adaptability to adoption.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2677040k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j904g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02871073m"><ual:graduationDate>1942</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the genus Baculites in the Bearpaw formation of western Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robinson, Harold Ross</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Bearpaw formation consists of marine shales with some non-marine beds which outcrop over a large part of southern Saskatchewan, parts of southern Alberta, and extend south into Montana. The search for geological structures favorable for the accumulation of natural gas and petroleum has made the determination of the stratigraphic horizons of individual exposures of this formation important. A paucity of outcrops in many areas, combined with a lack of variation in lithology throughout the formation, makes this difficult. so far the study of the mega-fossils of the Bearpaw formation has given little information which could be used to establish useful fossil zones. One of the main reasons for this has been that most fossil collecting has been done without observing carefully the horizon in which the fossils occurred. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, T. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m3102.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871073m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences, Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79408173c"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some aspects of atmosphere-earth energy relationships</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beall, George. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>All geological processes taking place at the surface of the earth are either influenced or caused by the energy relations between the sun, the surface of the earth, and the atmosphere. Since the surface and atmosphere, unlike the sun, cannot be divorced from the effects of surface geological processes, it follows that these processes, in turn, affect the energy relations between the earth and atmosphere. In short, there is a relationship between geological and atmospheric phenomena which is of utmost importance in both geology and paleoclimatology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saull, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jz10s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408173c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jz112"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the hemicellulose of milkweed floss (Asclepias syriaca, L.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barth, Fred. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Seed-hairs are fibers located on the seeds of various plants, designed by nature to make it possible for the seeds to spread by the wind. One of these seed fibers, cotton, is exceptional in its high content of cellulose and has attained an importance far exceeding that of any other material of its kind. Other sources include kapok, tree cotton, cat-tail floss, milkweed floss and cotton grass. Kapok is a seed fiber, cultivated in the East Indies and is commonly used for upholstery and lifebelts. None of the others have shown much commercial importance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Timell, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j96s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jz112</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rj06w"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three-body forces in hypernuclei</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bach, Glen. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An investigation is made to ascertain the relative importance of three and two-body /\-nucleon potentials which have the same order of coupling constant. The three-body potential, which is derived using perturbation theory from a pseudoscalar interaction, is found to be weakly singular and hence much smaller than the two-body potential. ln addition, the largest terms are non-central. In the hypertriton where correlations are large, it is found that three-body forces are repulsive for S states and may amount to 4%. D state admixture tends to make the three-body force less repulsive.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sharp, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k929.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rj06w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d128v"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The geology of the East Sullivan Deposit, Val d’Or, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Assad, Robert. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The East Sullivan copper-zinc deposit is one of a group of simil.ar ore deposits situated along an east-west belt in the Noranda - Val d’Or district of Northwestern Quebec. The Horne Mine at Noranda, the Waite-Amulet deposits and the Normetal Mine are three other important producers of this group. The purpose of this study of the East Sullivan Mine is to present a description of the geology and ore deposits and to discuss the general problem of origin of the ores. There is no published work on this mine and but little study, outside that required for mine development, has been carried out.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stevenson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z675.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d128v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sf14t"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Teachers’ views on the problem of mental health in the schools</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Argles, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In modern democratic societies the right of the individual to develop his capacities to the fullest for his own happiness and for the benefit of society is of fundamental importance. One of society's major tools in furthering this ideal has been free and ''universal11 elementary education. Formal education has traditionally concerned itself with the intellectual aspects of a child’s development.  “Emotional education” has remained the function of the family. A modern child has the opportunity to learn ideas foreign to his parents, but his emotional life is often restricted by his parents' limited emotional capacities. Society now has a valuable new tool to aid the individual in his development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd38h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sf14t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89db15t"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of chronic encephalitis in the pathogenesis of epilepsy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aguilar, Mary. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper presents histopathological evidence that chronic encephalitis may play a pathogenetic role in some cases of focal cerebral seizures. Correlation of the pathological findings with the clinical picture in such cases demonstrates a fairly constant interrelationship. Furthermore, the clinical data, including the history, physical findings, electroencephalographic and radiological studies, laboratory findings, psychological test data, findings at surgery, and follow-up information, suggest a unique clinical syndrome. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rasmussen, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612s27t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89db15t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd4731110"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patterns of living of elderly people in Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Adefrissew, Demissie</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Cooperberg, Arlene</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Driedger, Florence</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Driedger, Otto</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Ferguson, Janet</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Gerima, Yohannes. W.</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Sims, Valerie</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Weinstein, Herbert</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Zukerman, Harold</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is an enquiry into the manner of living of a group of non-institutionalized old people residing in an urban setting. The present introductory chapter is divided into three sections. Section A is a general orientation to the present study. Section B considers the theoretical background to the current trends of research in the field of old age. In Section C, the scope and method of the present study will be described. In recent years an increasing attention has been directed to the phenomenon of an ageing population and to the implications which this has for the individual and for society. This trend has derived from a combination of factors, some of which will be briefly indicated here.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vg14x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd4731110</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hd456"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A petrographic study of the granite wash in the clear hills area, Alberta</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zwartendyk, Jan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>“Granite wash” refers to partly reworked residual material overlying the basement and underlying marine strata. Its distribution is irregular and its age varies from place to place. Recent oil discoveries have made the Granite Wash economically interesting. Representative samples from a cored wall, Gulf Clear Rills 14-10, on the northern flank of the Peace River high, were subjected to detailed petrographic examination. Only the lowest few feet of core, if any, were found to be basement, consisting of tectonized granitoid gneiss. The rock types studied indicate no mineralogical variations in the source rock, only variations in degree of crushing and hence grain size.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stearn, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2688984.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hd456</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02871074w"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Sacred Theology</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Ukrainian protestant missions in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zuk, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Ukrainians, numbering about four hundred thousand in Canada, belong to the Slavonic family of the Aryan group whose birthplace is to be found in the Pripet River basin. Some archeologists would trace their origin to the area between the Elbe, the Vistula, and the Oder and Bug Rivers. Pressure from the neighbouring tribes forced the Slavs to migrate as early as 500 B.C. from the land of their birth into the basin of the Dniester and the Dnieper Rivers which is known today as the territory of the modern Ukraine.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Walsh, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n66b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871074w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Divinity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wk82p"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reactions of hydrogen atoms with amines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wright, Archibald. N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Free radicals have been produced by thermal decomposition of stable molecules (1), photolysis of alkyl compounds (2), interaction of sodium vapour and alkyl halides at moderate temperatures (3), electric discharges in gases (4,5), and photosensitization (6). The emphasis of chemical kinetics has been increasingly directed toward the study of reactions of free radicals with stable molecules and, more recently, with atoms and other free radicals. Steacie (7), in his treatise "Atomic and Free Radical Reactions" has made a comprehensive review of the voluminous literature on this subject up to 1954 and consequently the introduction to this thesis has been restricted to a review of those reactions directly related to the present study.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vm62t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk82p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920g149t"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of thiouracil and progesterone on the responses of the immature pullet to estrogen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wright, Leebert. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Remarkable morphological and physiological changes may be brought about by the administration of estrogenic hormones to the prepuberal pullet. These changes may include increases of the oviduct weight, liver weight, liver protein and liver lipid as well as of the levels of calcium, phosphorus, protein and lipid in the blood. There is some experimental evidence that these responses may be conditioned by the effects of the thyroid hormones. There is a somewhat more limited literature on the effects of the antithyroid agent, thiouracil, on estrogen-induced changes of serum calcium, serum protein, liver weight, liver protein and liver lipid.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Common, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z68f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g149t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dk288"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hydrothermal experiments with variable pore pressure and shear stress in part of the MgO – SiO2 – H2O system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wolofsky, Leib</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the systematic hydrothermal investigation or mineral systems in modern laboratories, the influence of several variables can be determined. In most recent studies the variables have been three: composition of the solid phase, temperature, pressure of water in contact with the solid phase. In general the investigators have varied each of these three properties of the systems and have determined the shifts in mineral equilibria caused by each change. In nature, mineral assemblages are undoubtedly controlled by other r variables in addition to these three. The present paper is concerned with an attempt to determine experimentally whether changes in other physical conditions are reflected by changes in the minerals present at a given temperature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s8558.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk288</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827g54v"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La période de transport dans ses relations avec la responsabilité du transporteur de personnes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wojcik, Tadeusz. Z.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le problème de la responsabilité du transporteur des personnes envers ses voyageurs occupe une place importante dans le droit des transports; ce problème est particulièrement important dans le plus jeune mode du transport - le transport aérien. Ce problème évidemment n'est pas simple,- il embrasse plusieurs questions, dont une est la détermination du moment dans lequel la responsabilité du transporteur des personnes commence et quand elle prend fin. Ce moment, naturellement, n'est pas le même dans chaque mode de transport et il peut varier selon le caractère et la nature de ce mode ainsi qu’en dépendance des risques et dangers qu'il crée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pépin, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v643s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827g54v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International Air Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f7305"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spontaneous ignition delay of lean hydrocarbon mixtures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Winship, David. R.</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Mordell, D. (Supervisor)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this age of industry and mechanization the production of power plays a most important role in our economy and a large part of this power is supplied by the burning or controlled explosions of hydrocarbon compounds. In order to achieve the most economical production of power by these methods a suitable combustion cycle must be used to transfer heat energy to useful mechanical or electrical work. The subject of this thesis, ignition delay, plays an important part in the combustion cycle. The practical problems still not completely solved add impetus to the research work in combustion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thompson, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg57v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f7305</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vv59v"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Peripheral circulatory changes in experimental frostbite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wilson, William. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>True Frostbite is not uncommon in civilian life (1, 17), but among acclimated travellers and natives of arctic and subarctic regions, serious cases are rare (165). The greatest incidence of frostbite has occurred among armed forces during military campaigns. Napolèon' s surgeon, Baron Larrey (101) encountered huge numbers of cold injuries in French troops during the retreat from Moscow. Lewis (108) is of the opinion that these were trench foot injuries, while Arena (5) refers to themas examples of true frostbite. During both World wars non-freezing wet cold injuries predominated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p1865.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vv59v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r4819"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reactions of active nitrogen with phosphine and hydrogen chloride</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wiles, David. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The passage of electrical discharges through diatomic gases at low pressure has been round to dissociate the molecules into atoms. Although the processes that may occur in a discharge are of interest in the present work, the information available on the subject is largely empirical and qualitative and the theoretical treatment is far from complete. Nevertheless the descriptions given in the literature (2, 4, 5) of the dissociation processes resulting from electrical excitation are adequate for consideration of the problem at hand. Hydrogen atoms have been produced from molecular hydrogen in flow systems with continuous, condensed or high frequency electrodeless discharges.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv60m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r4819</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90f000j"><ual:graduationDate>1957</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Investigative Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of senescence on thyroid function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wilansky, Douglas. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The functional statue of the thyroid in old age and its role in the genesis of some manifestations of senescence have been subjects of speculation tor many years. Numerous studies have been done but few, if any, conclusions based on sound evidence have been reached. The ovary has a life span shorter than that of the total organism, and concomitant with a decline in ovarian function undesirable physical and emotional disturbances may occur. Some features of human senescence are similar to those of the hypothyroid states for example, one sees in both diminished motor activity, impaired muscle strength, dryness or the skin, diminished cold tolerance, and falling of the hair.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoffman, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644w37k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90f000j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>