<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gt49j"><ual:graduationDate>1974</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electrowinning of copper from Cu-Fe matte</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Minto, Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bv46j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gt49j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Iron -- Electrometallurgy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Smelting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copper -- Electrometallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b7020"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Apocalyptic imagery in four twentieth-century poets : W.B. Yeats, T.S. Eliot, Robert Lowell and Allen Ginsberg</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sarwar, Selim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In twentieth-century poets such as W. B. Yeats, T. S. Eliot, Robert Lowell and Allen Ginsberg, the literary apocalyptic--identifiable by its homology with the major elements of the biblical Apocalypse--undergoes progressively complex transmutations. While in the early Yeats the apocalyptic is evocative of earnest Romantic moods, in his later work it is complicated by irony, yoked to the cycles of Yeatsean history, and counteracted by exaggerated postures of defiance. In Eliot, a reductive juxtaposition of the apocalyptic and the contemporary foreshortens the traditional paradigms to a diminutive modern-day scale. In Lowell, the apocalyptic is manifested variously as a bitter inversion of American Puritan eschatology, the telescoping of the personal and the cosmic, and a catastrophe in slow-motion. The climactic point of distortion, however, is reached in Ginsberg's poetry in which apocalyptic horrors form a bizarre combination with humour and bathos. While their treatment of the eschatological is widely divergent, an element common to all four poets is their ambivalence towards the paradigms of an apocalyptic new world.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w42b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b7020</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Yeats, W. B. (William Butler), 1865-1939 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apocalyptic literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lowell, Robert, 1917-1977 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>English poetry -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526d26q"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The state and economic development : an analysis of the role of the state in the economic development of Bangladesh</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Islam, Syed Serajul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the nature of the state in Bangladesh and its role in the economic development of the country until President Ziaur Rahman's assassination in 1981. Two basic questions have been of central importance: who controlled the apparatus of the state? and was the state "relatively autonomous" or simply an instrument of the dominant class(es)? The study argues that the state in post-colonial Bangladesh has not, contrary to Hamza Alavi's position, followed a single uniform direction. Initially, nationalist political leaders, mostly belonging to the intermediate class, controlled the state apparatus, which can therefore be described as an "intermediate state." However, subsequently, both "overdevelopment of the bureaucracy" and "socio-political dynamics" enabled the civil-military bureaucracy to assert dominance over the state apparatus, which can consequently be characterized as an "administrative state." Since the nature of the state has varied, it has played a changing role--autonomous or instrumental--in the economic development of Bangladesh, with the "intermediate state" working as an instrument of the dominant intermediate class and the "administrative state" playing a "relatively autonomous" role.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t79h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d26q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bangladesh -- Economic conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economic development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bangladesh -- Economic policy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n2040034"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dictionnaire de la théorie et de l'histoire littéraires</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Armantier, Louis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It seems that henceforth the development and renewal of terminology will be linked to contemporary scientific theories. Each discipline, with the aid of its specialized vocabulary, will possess a set of up-to-date conceptual tools adapted to its purpose. Unfortunately, there is no lexicon of literary terminology in French, and this at a time when the literature on analytical matalanguage is in major competition with the literature on ordinary language. Presently, various epistemological mutations such as those of the structuralists are having a strong effect on the contemporary terminological movement. It is hoped that this dictionary will, in a modest way, make good this deficiency by offering a systematic inventory of the notions used in literary theory and the history of literature, especially those relating to the use of the most common neologisms, borrowed interdisciplinary words, fundamental semiotic concepts, and the principal procedures of contemporary critical analysis.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634461k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2040034</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Semiotics -- Dictionaries -- French</dc:subject><dc:subject>Literature -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Criticism -- Dictionaries -- French</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Glossaries, vocabularies, etc</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jv572"><ual:graduationDate>1983</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Essays on the financial management of pension funds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jog, Vijay M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The dissertation deals with four issues affecting Employer Sponsored Pension Plans: (a) the rationale for their existence and growth, (b) the impact of taxation on funding decisions, (c) the development of an investment model for such funds, and (d) the evaluation of the historical investment performance of 83 Canadian pension funds. The proposed investment model integrates the fund's assets with the firm's assets. It is operationalized for four Canadian firms, using a universe of 192 common stocks and eleven bond portfolios. The results indicate that the optimal pension fund is firm-specific, in terms of both asset mix and security selection. The evaluation of investment performance emphasizes the equity portfolios of the 83 Canadian funds. The results show non-superior performance by these funds; the conclusions are robust across holding periods, benchmarks, performance measures and time periods. The study has major implications for the funding and investment policies of the pension funds and their investment performance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096786p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jv572</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pensions -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pension trusts -- Canada -- Finance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pension trusts -- Taxation -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nh93p"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relation of inorganic ions to the maintenance of the integrity of the cell envelope of gram-negative marine bacteria</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laddaga, Richard A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Twenty-three marine and two terrestrial gram-negative bacteria were examined by electron microscopy for the effect on the outer membrane of the cells of washing the organisms successively in 0.5M NaCl and 0.5M sucrose. Six marine bacteria lost their outer membranes completely, three lost large segments but not all of their outer membranes, and six retained their outer membranes but with either gross distortions of the outer membrane and/or segments of outer membrane removed from some cells. The remaining eight marine and two terrestrial bacteria appeared to have continuous outer membranes after application of the wash procedure. Eighteen of the twenty-three marine bacteria employed in the wash treatment study and two terrestrial bacteria were examined for the effect of washing and suspending the organisms in various solutions with respect to lysis of the cells and Optical Density (O.D.) changes of suspensions. A spectrum of lytic susceptibility was observed among the marine bacteria ranging from those organisms which lysed in distilled water after exposure to Mg('2+) through organisms which lysed upon suspension in distilled water after pre-exposure to NaCl but which failed to lyse in distilled water if pre-exposed to Mg('2+) to organisms which failed to lyse in distilled water even after exposure to NaCl. E. coli and Ps. aeruginosa also fell within this spectrum. After exposure to NaCl and subsequent suspension of these organisms in decreasing concentrations of either NaCl, KCl or MgCl(,2), concentrations of KCl two to three times that of NaCl or ten to four hundred times that of MgCl(,2) could protect most marine organisms from lysis or larger decreases in the O.D. of their suspensions. However, three marine and both terrestrial bacteria required only equal concentrations of KCl or NaCl to effect protection. No overall distinction can therefore be made between marine and terrestrial bacteria with respect to the status of the outer membrane of these organisms after washing them in NaCl and sucrose solutions or the sensitivity of the two groups of organisms to lysis in distilled water after pre-exposure to NaCl or MgCl(,2).</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zv23z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh93p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Marine bacteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gram-negative bacteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cell membranes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418p11t"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Secretion of lipoproteins by isolated rat hepatocytes : influence of dietary and hormonal factors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Krul, Elaine Susan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nature of nascent lipoproteins secreted by hepatocytes from euthyroid, hypothyroid and hypothyroid, cholesterol - fed (hypercholesterolemic) rats was investigated using suspensions of hepatocytes incubated in a lipid - deficient medium. The effects of diet and hormonal status on hepatic lipoprotein secretion was investigated to determine the contribution of the secretory products to the serum pool of abnormal lipoproteins in hypothyroid or hypercholesterolemic rats. The total lipid, apo-B and E secreted by hypercholesterolemic hepatocytes was markedly elevated. Triglyceride and phospholipid secretion were slightly increased by hypothyroid rat hepatocytes whereas, apo-B, E and AI secretion rates were unaffected. Gel filtration of the nascent lipoproteins demonstrated that compared to normal, proportionately more apo-B and E from hypercholesterolemic hepatocytes and apo-E from hypothyroid hepatocytes were secreted in association with larger lipoproteins. Hypercholesterolemic hepatocytes secreted abnormal cholesterol - rich particles, a significant proportion of which were discoidal. Hypothyroid hepatocytes secreted spherical lipoproteins having normal nascent lipoprotein lipid composition. These data are consistent with the hypothesis that in hypothyroidism the accumulation of beta-migrating lipoproteins results from impaired removal of lipoprotein catabolites from the serum, whereas in hypothyroid, cholesterol - fed rats, this defect would only serve to exacerbate the accumulation of the abnormal lipoproteins directly secreted by the liver.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq213.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p11t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227mq66x"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development, habitat, and behaviour of Trichuris muris in the laboratory mouse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Panesar, Tarlochan S (Tarlochan Singh), 1936-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Trichuris muris is parasitic in the large intestine of the mouse. This study has investigated aspects of the growth, moulting pattern, site-selection, hatching process and the behaviour of the nematode. The intra-luminal environment of the caecum presents optimal conditions for egg hatching which is the major reason for the nematode's specificity for this site. In caecectomised mice, the worms established in the ileum. The newly-hatched larvae penetrated the epithelium after entering the caecal gland lumen. A mechanism for hatching under caecal content stimulation is described on the basis of volumetric changes in the eggs and the ovic larvae. By using a closed-circuit television and video-tape recording system, behavioural activities of adult worms in their intraepithelial locations were observed and quantified. A new order of detail was obtained for the somatic movements, feeding, defaecation and oviposition, which emphasised the coordination and integration of these activities.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx411.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mq66x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Helminths</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adenophorea</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nematodes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nc095"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Revision of the American species of Mimesa (Hymenoptera : Pemphredonidae : Pseninae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Finnamore, Albert T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mimesa is a Holarctic genus of predatory sphecoid wasps of which 36 species are found in America. The present study is a revision of the American fauna presenting keys to species, standardized descriptions, distribution maps and biological information for each species. Fourteen species are here described as new: M. cahuilla, M. cheyenne, M. chiricahua, M. gabrieleno, M. ipai, M. jicarilla, M. klamath, M. miwoka, M. nisenan, M. senijextee, M. serrano, M. tequila, M. tolteca and M. zapoteca. In addition one subspecies, M. gregaria simplex, has been raised to species rank and 7 previously recognized species have been synonymized as follows: M. polita with M. dawsoni, M. atriventris with M. cressonii, M. iroquois with M. ezra, M. impressifrons with M. edentata and M. basirufa, M. nebrascensis and M. mallochi with M. lutaria. A lectotype has been designated for M. mexicana. A total of 365 illustrations are presented to supplement keys and descriptions.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s35d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc095</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sphecidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hymenoptera -- North America -- Identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wasps -- North America -- Identification</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn009z747"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anger arousal in child abuse counselling : an experimental evaluation of systematic desensitization and cognitive self-control training procedures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Davis, Gerald Albert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study was designed to evaluate the effectiveness of systematic desensitization and cognitive self-control training procedures in reducing anger arousal, overt hostility, and aggression; and their effectiveness in increasing constructive action in therapists conducting counselling interviews with child abusers. Thirty graduate social work students who indicated that they sometimes become at least mildly angry toward parents or caretakers who physically abuse children participated in the study. The students who volunteered for the study were randomly assigned to three treatment conditions in a pretest/posttest control group design. Anger was aroused experimentally in the subjects using laboratory provocations which consisted of six imaginal interviews with abusive and non-abusive parents. The imaginal interviews were conducted in a language laboratory using an automatically synchronized slide-tape program. The systematic desensitization and cognitive self-control treatments consisted of two one-hour training sessions administered within the same week. The criterion measures employed in the experimental study included (a) Reaction Inventory (Evans &amp; Stangeland, 1971), (b) Buss-Durkee Hostility Inventory (factor analytic version--Bendig, 1962), (c) Hostility Scale Applicable to Verbal Samples (Gottschalk, Winget, &amp; Gleser, 1969), (d) Self-Report Rating of Anger Scale (Novaco, 1975), (e) Self-Report Rating of Aggression Scale (Novaco, 1975), and (f) Self-Report Rating of Constructive Action Scale (Novaco, 1975). Analysis of covariance of the experimental data indicated no statistically significant treatment differences on any of the six dependent measures. Although statistical significance was not achieved, the pre-treatment and post-treatment means showed changes in the desired direction on the six dependent measures for the systematic desensitization treatment group. The cognitive self-control treatment group means showed changes in the desired direction on five of the dependent measures. The empirical results were discussed with reference to theoretical concepts of anger arousal, and the research literature on experimental studies of training procedures relevant to anger control.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tv94k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z747</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Self-control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interviewing in child abuse</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anger</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social work education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dn240"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The stereochemistry of ligand substitution reactions of cyclopentadienyl-rhodium complexes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Quinn, Susan M. (Susan Mary)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diastereomers of CpRh{C(O)Me}(P*)I, (P* (TBOND) (S)-Ph(,2)PNHCH(Me)Ph), have been prepared and separated. Decarbonylation with AgBF(,4) gave a single diastereomer of CpRhMe(CO)(P*)(.)BF(,4) and subsequent treatment of the salt with anions likewise gave single isomers of CpRh{C(O)Me}(P*)X (X = Cl, Br, I, SCN, NCS). The high stereospecificity of these transformations is attributed to the ability of the acyl ligand to undergo stereospecific reversible decarbonylation such that the methyl group occupies the site vacated by the iodide ligand, i.e., inversion. Addition of N(,3)('-) and MeO('-) to the salt resulted in the stereospecific formation of CpRhMe(P*)X' (X' = NCO, COOMe). Metathesis of CpRh{C(O)Me}(P*)Cl with I('-) proceeded with retention of configuration at rhodium. The chiral complexes (1-C(,9)H(,6)Cl)Rh(COD), (COD (TBOND) 1,5-cyclooctadiene), and (1-C(,9)H(,6)X)Mn(CO)(,3), (X = Cl, Br, I) have been synthesized via diazoindene insertion. Only the pentahapto bonding mode has been detected for these complexes. Photochemical and chemical decarbonylation of trans-CpFe(CO)(,2){C(O)CH=CHR}, (R = Ph, Me), proceeded with retention of geometry about the double bond to give trans-CpFe(CO)(,2){CH=CHR}.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074v950.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn240</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Organometallic compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rhodium</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chirality</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ligands</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r184h"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expectancy and the experience of childbirth : the effect of the relationship on postpartum affect</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Phillipson-Price, Adrienne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Giving birth to a child can have a major impact on a woman's feelings about herself and her newborn, influencing perceptions and interactions, and having both short and long term implications. In this study the effect of an experience of labour and delivery discrepant or not discrepant with expectations on mood and level of distress postpartum were investigated. Thirty primaparas were pretested on a Labor and Delivery Expectation scale and posttested on an Experience scale two days postpartum. Two mood measures and a Distress scale were administered at this time. The influences of formal preparation for childbirth and of personality variables on the childbirth experience and postpartum mood were also investigated. It was found that a positive mood and low distress postpartum were related to an experience of labour and delivery better than had been expected. An experience more negative than expected resulted in low mean scores for mood with high distress levels.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472x30d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r184h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pregnancy -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Childbirth -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vr72s"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hemisphere differences in bilingual language processing : a task analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vaid, Jyotsna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Five tachistoscopic studies were conducted to investigate patterns of hemispheric specialization for different types of word pair comparisons among monolinguals and fluent bilingual adults. Bilinguals were further grouped as "early" or "late" depending on whether their second language was acquired in infancy or in adolescence. All groups were faster at making orthographic comparisons for left visual field input but were faster in the right visual field for phonological and syntactic judgments. Semantic comparisons yielded no visual field asymmetries for monolinguals or late bilinguals but yielded a left visual field superiority for early bilinguals. Group differences in response strategy were also noted whereby early bilinguals favoured semantic processing and late bilinguals surface processing. The results are interpreted to suggest that lateralization patterns are primarily influenced by task-related processing demands but that early versus late onset of bilingualism predisposes the use of different processing strategies for performing a particular task.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bc48v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vr72s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cerebral hemispheres</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bilingualism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psycholinguistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laterality</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m501z"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Improvement of memory for classically condition associations by post-training self-stimulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Coulombe, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of post-training self-stimulation on associations formed during classical conditioning was studied. In the first three experiments, rats experienced tone-shock, tone-water and tone-light pairings, respectively. Control groups experienced the same situations except that the temporal relationship between the stimuli excluded the possibility of an association being formed. Following this training period, the experimental animals pressed a bar for electrical self-stimulation of the brain; control animals did not self-stimulate. Retention of the association between the training stimuli was evaluated by measuring conditioned suppression of drinking (experiments 1 and 3), or extinction of secondary reinforcement. The results showed that self-stimulation can retroactively and non-contingently improve memory for associations in various classical conditioning situations, independently of the presence of a natural reinforcer or of the responses they elicit. In another experiment, the effects of varying amounts of tone preexposure (latent inhibition) and of varying amounts of post-training self-stimulation on retention of a tone-shock association, measured by the amount of tone-induced suppression of drinking, were studied. Increasing amounts of tone pre-exposure produced decreased retention over all levels of self-stimulation, and increasing amounts of self-stimulation produced increased retention over all levels of pre-exposure. The interaction of these two factors suggests that they both acted on the strength of the tone-shock association: the pre-exposure acted proactively to weaken the association; the self-stimulation acted retroactively to strengthen it. The effect of delaying the post-training stimulation for various times after the tone-shock pairings was also investigated. Retention was improved by self-stimulation delayed for 15 or 30 minutes, but was not affected by self-stimulation delayed for an hour. These experiments suggest that direct activation</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505136g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m501z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brain stimulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rats -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Classical conditioning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reinforcement (Psychology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h278h"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Helplessness, depression, and mood in end-stage renal disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Devins, Gerald Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>End-stage renal disease (ESRD) and its treatment are generally considered to be highly stressful and the associated loss of control over important life dimensions is believed to induce widespread depression. This situation was employed as a "living stress laboratory" in which to test the reformulated learned helplessness theory of depression. Results indicated that reduced perceived control over a variety of life dimensions was importantly related to increased depression, although the attributional reformulation of helplessness theory was not supported. Moreover, reanalyses of these data from a social learning theory perspective indicated that perceived self-efficacy contributed uniquely to this negative correlation in addition to expectancies regarding response-outcome contingency (Rotter I-E scores). The hypothesis that the negative correlation between depression and perceived control might also be explained in terms of patients' psychological differentiation and the intrusiveness of ESRD was subsequently examined. Results revealed that perceived intrusiveness contributed uniquely to perceived control and to affect, indicating that perceived control and intrusiveness each contribute independently to mood. Surprisingly, a low prevalence of clinical depression was observed, contradicting the general consensus that helplessness and depression are unavoidable psychological sequelae to ESRD. These findings are equally applicable to several other chronic and life-threatened patient populations (e.g., cancer, cardiac, diabetic) and thus underline the need for a general theory of the emotional impact of illness.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fs17f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h278h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Depression, Mental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mood (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chronic renal failure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Helplessness (Psychology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap5547s28r"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analyse d'une situation d'apprentissage d'opérations numériques au debut du secondaire</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Côté, Benoît</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents an analysis of a learning situation of positive and negative integers. It is considered as a case study within the more general context of the development of school learning analysis tools based on cognitive psychology. An analysis of error patterns obtained from a group of 55 secondary I level students has shown: (1) that the acquisition of the integer concept can imply several levels of integration of the sign and the numerical aspect; (2) that the set of all possible addition and subtraction items can be classified according to their possibility of being related to previous numerical knowledge; (3) that errors in addition and subtraction can be explained by either the utilisation of previous knowledge that was contrary to what was taught, or by systematic transformations of the procedures that were taught, or by problems with the integer concept. The thesis ends with a discussion of the properties of an information processing system that could generate the observed performances, and of the pedagogical implications of that kind of analysis.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537202r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s28r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Learning, Psychology of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Number concept</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xc64n"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patterns of teacher interaction in an immersion school in Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cleghorn, Ailie, 1940-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The interactions of a linguistically mixed teaching staff of an immersion school in Montreal were explored to determine their influence on the integrative objectives of immersion programs. Teachers' formal and informal interactions were observed to feature the predominant use of English and the use of silence to avoid code switching and functioned to manage conflict to the detriment of integrative immersion goals. Conflict among the staff arose from disagreements about immersion programs, conflicting societal and professional norms and the school's organizational divisions. A projective technique was used to determine if perceptions of linguistic norms of 176 grades 1 to 6 pupils reflected the interactions of eight immersion and four English stream teachers. The study underlines the importance of the interactional context and organization of schools with mixed staff groups of achieving bilingual education goals. Attainment of integrative objectives may hinge on the degree of correspondence between stated aims and actual practice.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc237.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xc64n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education, Bilingual -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interpersonal relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bilingualism -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f660f"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Prostaglandins and hematological aspects of neuromuscular disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morgan, Reginald Owen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present investigations were aimed at providing an empirical basis for implicating altered prostaglandin (PG) and thromboxane (TX) biosynthesis in the aberrant heme metabolism and erythrocyte membrane properties which have been found to exist in hereditary muscular dystrophy and ataxia. Picomolar concentrations of PGE(,1) and PGE(,2) were shown to exert opposing, biphasic effects on osmotic fragility, the hemolytic response to ouabain (without any direct effect on cation-activated adenosine triphosphatases), and echinocyte transformation of normal human erythrocytes. Ex vivo erythrocyte porphyrin analysis pointed to a mild depression of erythropoiesis in dystrophic mice that responded to dietary polyunsaturated fatty acids. The discovery of a paraporphyria in patients with hereditary ataxia was extended to in vitro porphyrin studies using 3-acetylpyridine as an experimental model of ataxia. Systematic pharmacological studies in a newly designed, serum-free liver cell culture model and in ovo, together with chromatographic-fluorometric PG analysis, established that a certain rate or pattern of PG biosynthesis was required for optimal induction of hepatic (delta)-aminolevulinate synthase and porphyrin-heme biosynthesis. Moreover, the dramatic accumulation of protoporphyrin caused by putative, selective inhibitors of thromboxane synthase, and the exacerbation of experimental porphyria by phospholipase inhibitors provided unique evidence for a physiological, regulatory role of PGs and possibly TXA(,2) in heme biosynthesis at the level of mitochondrial ferrochelatase activity. Original data obtained about PG effects on heme biosynthesis and erythrocyte properties may prove useful in devising effective therapies and monitoring clinical responses in anemias, porphyrias and hematological aspects of neuromuscular disease.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m059.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f660f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s1045"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A transform method and semiconductor detector system applied to regional cerebral blood flow analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Meyer, Ernst</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new transform analysis method is described for the quantitative analysis of radioactive inert gas washout curves to measure regional cerebral blood flow (rCBF) by the intra-arterial bolus injection technique. This method is based upon a transformation of the original data, recorded with a unique semiconductor miniature detector system. It combines the valid features of the two most frequently used analysis techniques, namely, the compartmental and the stochastic, or height-over-area (H/A) methods. At the same time, the method avoids the recognized limitations or deficiencies of these two approaches. It gives for the first time information about the 'spectral' distribution of blood flow in various vascular compartments. The transform method, together with the combined use of beta-emitting krypton-85 and gamma-emitting xenon-133, has thus made possible a more exact interpretation of dynamic changes in rCBF as illustrated by its application in a variety of experimental and clinical models of disordered cerebral circulation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bz03v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s1045</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pn811"><ual:graduationDate>1979</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The economic allocation of government expenditures in Canada and the role of social rate of return analyses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matossian, Nicolas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study concerns itself with the process of public sector resource allocation in Canada from 1965-1975. An examination of the Federal Government's own procedure manual for program evaluation, and the analysis of several program evaluations for Departments of Health, Education and Manpower, reveal that the analytical procedures and economic precepts used depart significantly from accepted norms of economic theory. Consequently, the rates of return claimed for these programs are distorted and, where they are used for the rationing of public sector resources, collective welfare will not be optimized. The major causes of these problems are improper analytical methodology and the failure to adhere to basic economic principles of resource allocation. Support for this hypothesis derives from accepted economic theory with respect to welfare maximization and the allocation of public expenditures.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t82t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn811</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Expenditures, Public -- Rate of return</dc:subject><dc:subject>Government spending policy -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Appropriations and expenditures</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021g09j"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The arrangement of integrated polyoma sequences in transformed cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moreau, Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The frequency of transformation of rat cells obtained with recombinant plasmid DNAs which contained an intact early region of the polyoma genome (Bam clones) was not significantly different from those which carry an interrupted early region (Eco RI clones) or even part of the early region (Hind III-1 fragment transformant). The viral DNA within several Bam and Eco RI clones as well as fragment transformants was examined by Southern blotting. These cell lines contain integrated viral sequences which sometimes are tandemly arranged. We also found that the presence of large T antigen in transformed cells does not significantly alter the frequency at which tandem integration occurs. Furthermore, Rat-1 cells in culture were transformed with cellular DNA isolated from one Hind III-1 fragment transformant. These studies showed that the oncogenic potential of the viral DNA is maintained after integration. These findings demonstrate that only part of the polyoma early region is required to initiate and maintain transformation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000087v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g09j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh66s"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rheo-optical transients in spherioidal suspensions : a thesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cerda, César Manuel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The behavior of bimodal suspensions of oblate spheroids undergoing simple shearing flow has been described by analyzing the frequency spectra of orientation-dependent macroscopic properties. In particular, the frequency spectra of rheo-optical transients in turbidity and angular light scattering obtained experimentally from mono- and bimodal suspensions of human and frog erythrocytes showed peaks corresponding to the dominant frequencies of the particles in the flow. The method can, in principle, be applied to multimodal dispersions to obtain information on particle geometry. The effect of high polydispersity on the rheo-optical transients of sheared suspensions have been studied. The time-dependent behavior of such systems is neither determined by the period of rotation defined by the mean axis ratio nor by the mean period of rotation amongst particles, but by the most probable period of rotation (i.e. the value corresponding to the maximum in the distribution of periods of rotations). Rheo-optical transients in polydisperse kaolin (clay) suspensions have been experimentally obtained. Here the oscillations, in contrast to the slightly polydisperse suspensions studied previously, are highly damped. Frequency spectra obtained from these experiments have peaks near 2/T(,m) , where T(,m) is the most probable period in the ensemble. Finally, the influence of the rotary Brownian motion on the rheo-optical transients of sheared spheroidal suspensions is considered by using simulation procedures such as those employed previously to analyze rheological properties and memory loss. The rotary Brownian motion induced two effects: damping of oscillations and a shift in the extrema of the oscillations resulting in variation in the apparent mean period of rotation. Experiments with human erythrocytes at low Brenner number confirmed such behavior. Also a system with strong rotary Brownian motion was observed for which the rheo-optical transients showed monotonic changes. The observations made in this work contribute to a better understanding of the transient rheo-optical properties of flowing suspensions.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz647.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh66s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Suspensions (Chemistry) -- Spectra</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spheroidal state</dc:subject><dc:subject>Suspensions (Chemistry)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wk084"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the regulation of erythropoiesis on fetal calf liver cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Canas, Patricio Eudardo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mechanism of action of erythropoietin (EPO) and the effects of different cyclic nucleotides on hemoglobin synthesis have been studied using a serum-free system of fetal calf liver cells. dbcAMP, dbcGMP and cCMP stimulated hemoglobin synthesis at different concentrations, and their effects were quite different depending on the type of hemoglobin being synthesized. The analysis of (alpha) and (gamma) chains by high pressure liquid chromatography (HPLC) indicated that both the (alpha) and (gamma) globin chains are stimulated by the three cyclic nucleotides. Furthermore, Step III sheep plasma EPO stimulated the synthesis of cGMP in fetal calf liver cells. On the other hand, only cGMP stimulated the nuclear RNA polymerases measured at low ionic strength in the presence of methyl-isobutyl-xanthine (MIX), an inhibitor of phosphodiesterase. These results indicate that cGMP could be one of the second messengers of EPO on the stimulation of RNA synthesis and probably hemoglobin synthesis. EPO also stimulated the RNA polymerase activities of fetal calf liver cells after one hour of incubation in vitro. This stimulation seems to be mediated by some factors present in the cytoplasm of treated cells, because nuclei incubated with this cytoplasmic preparation had a higher RNA polymerase activity than those incubated with cytoplasmic preparations of control cell cultures. The nature of these cytoplasmic factors are heterogenous, because the type of RNA polymerase stimulated is dependent of the method used in its preparation.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h039n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wk084</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1g05fc54h"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of submersed macrophytes in phosphorus cycling</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carignan, Richard, 1951-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The specific activity of the ('32)P labeled sediment-P taken up by submersed macrophytes was shown to be identical to the specific activity of the sediment mobile P, as measured by isotopic dilution. The mobile P therefore represents the sediment-P available to aquatic macrophytes. The ability to accurately measure the specific activity of the available sediment-P was applied to problems pertaining to the role of macrophytes in P cycling. The relative contribution of water and sediments in supplying P to macrophytes was measured by growing macrophytes in situ, rooted in ('32)P labeled sediments, and with the shoot in free contact with the unlabeled overlying water. Macrophytes grown in mesotrophic and eutrophic sites derived more than 95% of their P from the sediments alone. When grown in a hypertrophic site, the sediments still supplied 70% of the P. Rates of P release by macrophytes and significance to their periphyton and surrounding phytoplankton were estimated by using fully labeled plants. The periphyton derived only 6.5% of its P form the macrophytes. Myriophyllum released 0.32 ug.g('-1).h('-1) P, most of which being readily available to phytoplankton. The high vertical mobility of the available sediment-P was demonstrated both by experimental manipulations and direct observations.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq676.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fc54h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plants -- Effect of phosphorus on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Macrophytes -- Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xg01f"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of lithium on rats' activity levels and on reaction to environmental stimulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cappeliez, Philippe, 1951-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research investigated the effects of different doses of lithium on rats' behavior in an attempt to understand lithium's therapeutic mechanism of action in major affective disorders. Although high doses (1.50 mEq/kg LiCl) decreased rats' open field activity, low doses (0.15 mEq/kg LiCl) increased activity, which is a new finding. A study of the effects of these two doses on reaction to environmental complexity and novelty suggested that, irrespective of dose, lithium increases readiness to engage in inspective exploration of a novel environment and promotes longer inspective exploration of a known complex environment. This was interpreted as increased selective attention to stimuli providing relevant information about the environment. The prediction derived from these findings, that both doses would decrease distractability, was supported in an experiment on tone-induced suppression of licking. A two factor (activity, selective attention) model of lithium's action was proposed and its relevance to lithium's clinical efficacy in major affective disorders was discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296wz88z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg01f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lithium -- Testing</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>