<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr1721881"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sterling area as an economic entity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Petrogiannis, Demetrios. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Sterling Area can be tentatively defined as the monetary union existing mainly between the United Kingdom and the overseas Cornrnonwealth, with the important exception of Canada. Membership has been extended from time to time, formally or only de facto, to countries outside the political framework of the Commonwealth as well. In its technical aspects this monetary union can be described as an association of the United Kingdom with certain countries whose trade is financed mainly in sterling and whose reserves are mainly held in sterling (underlined by the writer, ref (1) p. VIII ). Some basic characteristics such as trade financing mainly in sterling and holding of members’ reserves in sterling have been substantially present throughout the life of the old British Empire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brecher, I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f727.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1721881</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn572"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An automatic phase plotter for the measurement of microwave fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pavlasek, Tomas. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problem of phase measurement at microwave frequencies has been investigated and an automatic, recording system developed for use in microwave optics studies. The phase plotter operates at 9.3 Kmc/s and measures phase and intensity of a field continuously along chosen scanning lines. The phase measurement is essentially independent of intensity variations of up to 40 db and the follow-up response during automatic operation is over 90° per second. The accuracy is + 5° in automatic operation and + 2° when operated manually. The system's operation depends on the Homodyne technique. Automatic operation is made possible by the development of a novel modulator using ferrite microwave components.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jj206.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn572</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62fc97j"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The pathogenic nature of finely particulate silica</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parsons, Timothy. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Silicon is the second most abundant element in the earth's crust. Because of the solubility of silicates of alkali metals a considerable quantity of silicon is absorbed by plants and variable amounts are ingested with plants by animals. Of the amount ingested a small proportion gains an entrance into the body and is distributed in all tissues. The question which has been entertained by many workers is whether silicon is an essential element in animal metabolism. On certain theoretical grounds silicon is considered to be classified among those possibly essential (1).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g91f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc97j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92gb943"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The quantum theory of cyclotron resonance in graphite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murphy, Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The power absorption due to cyclotron resonance and magneto-optical absorption is calculated for pure graphite at absolute zero temperature. The spin of the electron and the electron - lattice relaxation time are neglected. The formalism adopted for calculating the momentum wave functions and the matrix elements of the electric perturbation is that of Luttinger and Kohn. It is found that the power absorption due to cyclotron resonance should not be symmetrical with respect to a change in sign of the magnetic field.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wallace, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vc295.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb943</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qq854"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the effect of partial biliary obstruction in dogs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murphy, Frederick. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bile is a product of secretion and excretion of the liver. Its composition and function is most complex. Volumes have been written on various aspects of the biliary tract and bile. One of the most complexing problems has been that of partial biliary obstruction. We are all only too familiar with the clinical course of the “acquired biliary stricture,” and the “post-cholecystectomy syndrome” which result from an impairment of biliary outflow. Because of the rather confusing clinical picture that such conditions present and the difficulty encountered in attempting to follow these cases in a serial fashion, it was felt that an experimental study incorporating well established liver function tests, pathological and bacteriological methods should be attempted.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq37q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq854</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k610t"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geology of the area between Carol Lake and Wabush Lake, Labrador</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mumtazuddin, Mohammed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This report is based on the Field Work carried out by the writer during the summer of 1957, and on subsequent laboratory investigations at McGill University during the ensuing winter. The map-area forms part of the concessions in Labrador held by the Iron Ore Company of Canada. The area mapped lies within the "Labrador Trough” which oonta1ns a folded and faulted assemblage of Precambrian sedimentary series intruded by volcanic and plutonic igneous rocks. The first part of this report deals with the general character of the country and the Regional Geology. The second part is a detailed study of the Kaniapiskan (Huronian System) of upper Precambrian, west of Wabush Lake, with emphasis on the iron formation and the iron ore deposits in it.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967733g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k610t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920g148j"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The international direction of social security</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moughton, Barry. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recent developments in solving social problems have created a new International Law of Social Security. Attempts to control the direction of its development have not produced a clear pattern of principles. Coverage is correctly based on Residence for primary liability and Ordinary Residence for secondary liability. Qualifying Periods are correctly an aspect of Definition which is based on a division into long or short term contingencies and income-decreasing or expenditure-increasing contingencies. Benefit rates are correctly based on earnings and subsistence for the first two categories and assumed average need for the last.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cohen, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c1955.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g148j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26z178w"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The chemistry, mineralogy, and metamorphism of the standing pong amphibolites, Hanover quadrangle, New Hampshire-Vermont</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morse, Stearns. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An investigation was made of chemical variation within garnet, chlorite, and plagioclase in the metamorphosed Standing Pond amphibolite of the Hanover quadrangle, New Hampshire-Vermont. The mineral assemblages epidoteplagioclase, sphene-rutile, ilmenite-rutile, garnet-rutile- ilmenite, and kyanite-muscovite are also discussed. Little correlation was round between metamorphic zone, ironmagnesium ratios and calcium and manganese content of the various minerals. The theoretical grounds for such correlation are discussed, and it is concluded that the apparent metamorphic grade fluctuates within zones because of minor differences in temperature-pressure conditions and bulk composition.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webber, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt651.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z178w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj67317673"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The response of cadelle Tenebroides mauritanicus (L.) in the vacuum fumigation of jute with methyl bromide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Monro, Hector. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work described in this thesis has contributed to scientific knowledge in the following ways: (1) For the first time it has been shown that the response of insect to poison gas at reduced pressures may follow a complex rather than a regular curve when mortality is related to pressure. (2) A zone of high resistance between 30 and 50 mm. has been demonstrated with larvae and adults of Tenebroides mauritanicus (L.). Resistance in this zone is related to the effects of reduced pressure and is connected in some way with reduction of the visible activity of the insects at these pressures. The response in this zone is apparently independant of humidity. (3) It has been shown that at pressures lower than the zone of high resistance the mortality of T. mauritanicus is due more to dessication than to the action of the fumigant.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DuPorte, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k401.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67317673</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b4745"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the utilization of induced tetraploids in the improvement of red clover (Trifolium pratense L.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mittelholzer, Alexander. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Red clover, Trifolium pratense L., is a member of the Leguminosae family. It is one of the most important seeded legumes used in the province of Quebec, in both hay and pasture mixtures. Breeding work with red clover began early in the twentieth century, and Steppler (1955) reported that work of this nature was initiated at Macdonald Collage in 1911. Red clover is a cross-pollinated species and is entomophilous. It is highly self-incompatible, as determined by a series of s-alleles through which the plants are maintained in a constant state or heterozygosity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steppler, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dx091.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b4745</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn3015113"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sorptive properties and pore structures of lignin and cellulose</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McKnight, Theodore. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The vapour-phase sorption of water, methanol, ethanol, benzene, sulphur dioxide, phenol and nitrogen by periodate lignin has been investigated. Large amounts of water, methanol, and ethanol and small amounts of the non-polar substances benzene and nitrogen were taken up. The sorption of benzene was greatly enhanced by freezedrying from benzene. Sulphur dioxide was found to be irreversibly sorbed; about one eighth of a B.E.T. monolayer could not be degassed. The sorption of water was depressed both by a hot aqueous treatment and by the presence of benzene occluded during the solvent-exchange procedure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mason, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139577m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3015113</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x499d"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The geology of the Mount Logan area, Gaspé, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mattinson, Cyril. R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The northern flank of the Gaspesian extension of the Appalachian Mountain System is dominated by a belt of hills 2 to 12 miles in width which begins some 15 miles east of Lake Matapedia and extends 65 miles northeastward to end with the Tabletop mountains. This high belt, known as the Shickshock mountains, forms a physiographic but not geological unit, its eastern end being composed of intrusive granite and serpentine bodies whereas, to the west, over some two-thirds of its length, the peaks are the dissected remnants of a great block of Lower Paleozoic metavolcanic and associated metasedimentary rocks.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sf13j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x499d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924g429"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The partial specific volumes of macromolecules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martin, William. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Of the many properties of interest in the vast and important domain of macromolecules, one of the most essential is the molecular weight or distribution of molecular weights. In several of the methods that are available for determining these quantities, an accurate value for the partial specific volume, V, (1) of the macromolecular species is necessary. The present study is concerned with the critical evaluation of V for several different polymeric materials by different techniques. High polymers or macromolecules are formed from atoms, or groups of atoms linked by primary valences to form chains, two-dimensional laminated sheets, or three-dimensional networks. Only the first type will be considered in this work since it is difficult to envisage a discrete molecular weight in the other types.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q080w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924g429</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zj15s"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economics of retailing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martin, Fernand</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As in any ether firm the retailer has decisions to take about output and prices. Most of the time he is a price-maker and an output-taker. The price to be established and the output to be produced, depend upon profit considerations. It is assumed, that firms are in business for maximum profits, and as long as profits are compatible with survival and growth; they can safely be relied upon as the beat index available to determine the performance of the firm. The “profit plan” of the firm for each economic period shall now be established. The retailer, as any other entrepreneur, has to find the most profitable output.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beach, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh31k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zj15s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics and Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arf55zc352"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The biology of the Atlantic walrus Odobenus rosmarus rosmarus (Linnaeus), Eastern Canadian Arctic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mansfield, Arthur. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The walrus, Odobenus rosmarus, is a circumpolar species of arctic and sub-arctic waters and is geographically isolated into three or more morphologically distinct groups. The Eastern Canadian Arctic and West Greenland group ranged as far south as Sable Island and the Gulf of St. Lawrence in historic times, but unrestricted commercial exploitation led to a serious decline in numbers and a withdrawal of the group to the more northern and inaccessible parts of its range. The advent of the rifle into the Eskimo economy with consequent wasteful methods of hunting caused further serious reductions in the walrus herds and necessitated the introduction of restrictive hunting measures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dunbar, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c90p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zc352</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Zoology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vp65s"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heat and mass transfer to decelerating finely-atomized sprays</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manning, William. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The transfer of heat, mass and momentum in the nozzle zone of sprays produced by internal-mixing, pneumatic and hollow-cone, pressure nozzles was determined for both co-current and cross-current drying air flow patterns. The Nusselt Numbers for the evaporating .drops were correlated by means of the equation proposed by Ranz and Marshall for stationary drops in a rnoving air flow. Values of the drag coefficients for the decelerating drops, over a range of Reynolds Numbers of 1 to lOO, were approximately one tenth of those predicted by the standard curve for spheres, and a dependance on the drop diameter was observed. Methods of measuring the physical properties of the water-air system were developed and tested with special attention devoted to the determination of drop velocities and air humidity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gauvin, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j2684.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp65s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject/></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sh32v"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An experimental study for evaluation of surgical procedures in the treatment of coronary artery insufficiency</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mahanti, Biresh. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the past thirty years the report concerning coronary heart disease have increased almost geometrically. We are still far from solving the problems of this serious disease as is evidenced by the continuous flood of papers. The greatest advance has been on the diagnostic front of myocardial infarction and its allied picture of coronary insufficiency. Practically all the schools of the world have contributed in the clinical study. The names of Parkinson, Bedford in England, Barnes, Whitten, Woolfirth, Wood, White, Levine, Wright, Levy, Master in the U.S.A. are closely associated with this work.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g871z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sh32v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x500z"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pressure-contour variance and kinetic energy over the arctic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Macfarlane, Mona. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A theoretical relationship between the variance of height (geopotential) and the variance of the geostrophic wind was tested in the Arctic at 500 mb. As had been expected, a high correlation was found to exist between these two quantities although the form of the relationship (linear in the logarithms of the standard deviations of height and wind) was totally unexpected. The Arctic data from previous papers, concerned with the relationship between the time variances of height and wind, were then reanalysed and the relationship between them was found to be of the same form as for the space variances. In both cases the standard error of estimate was too large to be able to calculate accurately the wind variance from the height variance, but the relationships do allow climatological estimates of the mean kinetic energy and the size of the dominant wave systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r9077.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x500z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fs50s"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of ethionine on some plant growth systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lowther, Ruth. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order for a chemical compound to be defined as an antimetabolite it must be structurally similar to the metabolite and inhibit a biochemical pathway involving the metabolite. By definition this inhibition must be reversed by the metabolite. Ethionine is a synthetic compound which is structurally related to methionine in that it is formed by replacing the terminal methyl group of methionine by an ethyl group (Figure 1). Ethionine has been shown to be an antimetabolite to methionine in a number of biological systems involving animals and microorganisms (Martin, 1951; Wooley, 1952; Rabinovitz et al, 1954).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boll, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505413s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fs50s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526g92q"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The anodic oxidation of bivalent manganese to tetravalent manganese</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lemay, Henri. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Natural manganese dioxide pyrolusite has been known since the time of Pliny as an agent for decolorizing glass. Pyrolusite is usually found mixed with ferric oxide, since both are deposited by atmospheric oxidation of their bicarbonates. It contains about 63 per cent manganese. Minerals of manganese are listed in Table I. The different ores of manganese may also be classified according to the fields in which they are used. This classification can be seen in Table II.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacEwan, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35697909.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g92q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metallurgical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t9994"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electronic analog multiplication using transistors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Enerst. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An investigation of the solution of a problem by analog computation consista of examining the behavior or a particular physioal system conceived in such a way that the different variables which describe it develop according to laws analogous to those which describe the system under study.Machines which use the laws governing electrical phenomena as analogs have an advantage over other machines in that very rapid operation is possible, which permits condensing into a short time a long operation, and the expansion of rapid phenomena to cover relatively long times.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Farnell, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k6113.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t9994</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569791k"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inter- and intra-varietal crosses in the improvement of timothy, red clover and birdsfoot trefoil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lawson, Norman. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Red claver (Trifolium pratense L.) and birdsfoot trefoil (Lotus corniculatus L.) are entomophilous cross-pollinated species classified in the natural order Leguminoseae. The former is a biennial or short lived perennial with a diploid chromosome number of 2n = 14; the latter is a perennial with a tetraploid chromosome number of 2n = 28 and is thought to be an autotetraploid because it exhibits tetrasomic inheritance (Bubar, 1957). They are known to have incompatibility systems precluding close inbreeding and are almost completely self-sterile. Timothy (Phleum pratense L.) is an autohexaploid (Nordenskiold, 1953) with 48 chromosomes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bubar, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b36t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569791k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0p096b75s"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The structure of left H-star algebras</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laufer, Philip. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The basic results for finite dimensional algebras are due to Wedderburn [1]. Every finite dimensional algebra A which contains a non-zero nilpotent ideal has a non-zero radical R, and A/R is semi-simple (has a zero radical) and contains a unit element. Every semi-simple algebra is uniquely expressible as a direct sum of a finite number of simple algebras, each with a unit element. In the infinite dimensional case the above structure theory still persists to some extent; that is, in certain cases a semisimple Banach algebra is a suitably generalized direct sum of suitably generalized matrix algebras.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peck, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666840j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b75s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246w65x"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soviet Price Mechanism and Economic Theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kovalski, V.I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper is an attempt to study the Soviet price-mechanism with reference to economic theory. It is particularly devoted to the aspect of control over prices and to the functions of these prices in ensuring economically efficient utilization of the material and human resources of the country.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beach, E. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hd43n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246w65x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80j026f"><ual:graduationDate>1958</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agronomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Establishment Studies of Certain Forage Species in Pure and Mixed Seedlings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Knutti, Hand Jakob</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Today Canada's pasture and range land is estimated at some sixty million acres. The most extensive acreage is found as native grass range land in the prairie provinces. In Eastern Canada there are fourteen millions of acres of pasture land which were formerly wooded and then cleared.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p819.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j026f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject/><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>