<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58pd19x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The validity of swimming rubrics for children with and without a physical disability</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jin, Tae-Sang, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the psychometric properties of swimming rubrics. The 10-level rubrics were designed to assess the front crawl. Participants were children, aged 8 to 13 years, with and without a physical disability (n=19) from a "reverse integration" school in Montreal. Participants swam 20 meters with each deciding if a floatation device was necessary. They evaluated themselves as well as peers using the rubric format. The physical education teacher and two teaching assistants participated as teacher assessors. Teacher, peer, and self assessments produced similar scores. In peer assessment, students with disability produced lower scores than students without disability. Boys did not differ from girls. In self assessment, students with and without a disability showed similar competence in comparison to teachers. Also, boys and girls produced similar competence in comparison to their teacher as well. Finally, video assessment was significantly correlated with assessment done immediately after performance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139223p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd19x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Swimming -- Evaluation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Swimming -- Study and teaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sports for children with disabilities</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn999694w"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hedges in Japanese English and American English medical research articles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iida, Eri</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study analysed the use of hedges in English medical research articles written by Japanese and American researchers. The study also examined the relationship between Japanese medical professionals' employment of hedges and their writing process. Sixteen English medical articles: eight written by Japanese and eight by Americans were examined. Four of the Japanese authors discussed their writing process through questionnaires and telephone interviews. The overall ratio of hedges in articles written by the two groups differed only slightly; however, analyses revealed a number of specific differences in the use of hedges between the groups. For example, Japanese researchers used epistemic adverbs and adjectives less frequently than the American researchers. The results were discussed in relation to the problems of nonnative speakers' grammatical competence, cultural differences in rhetorical features, and the amount of experience in the use of medical English.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn106z34h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999694w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medical literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Discourse analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Grammar</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language and culture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pragmatics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x424s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Temps morts : la femme qui tue la mort chez Théophile Gautier</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jeannotte, Valérie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyses the figure of the mythicized women as an attempt to escape the threat of time and death that is typical in Gautier's fictional narratives. In "La Cafetiere", "Omphale", "Le Pied de momie", "La Morte amoureuse" and "Arria Marcella", the feminine characters belong to both earthly and heavenly opposite realities. This study is based on several works such as Gilbert Durand's Structures anthropologiques de l'imaginaire, Georges Poulet's Etudes sur le temps humain and Mircea Eliade's Aspects du mythe. In the creation work part, nostalgia is introduced through characters that are overwhelmed by the death or the disappearance of a loved one.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mf741.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x424s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Death in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gautier, Théophile, 1811-1872 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A736664763"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Friendship in inclusive physical education from the perspective of students with and without physical disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seymour, Helena</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The role of a best friend for students with and without a disability in inclusive physical education has been conspicuously neglected in sport psychology and adapted physical activity research. Although the last decade has seen an increase in empirical research pertaining to the perceived experiences of students with a physical disability in inclusive physical education (Blinde &amp; McCallister, 1998; Goodwin &amp; Watkinson, 2000; Hutzler, Fliess, Chacham, &amp; Van den Auweele, 2002), the effect of a best friend for both students with and without a disability has generally been overlooked. Thus the current study compared friendship in inclusive physical education from the perspective of students with (n=8) and without (n=8) physical disabilities. All participants attended a reversely integrated school and were interviewed using an unstructured, open-ended interview format. An interview guide from Weiss, Smith, and Theeboom (1996) that explored friendship in the sport domain was adapted to account for the context of inclusive physical education. Four categories emerged from the analysis: spectrum of friendship, best friend, preferred physical activities and outcomes, and dealing with disability. Specifically, similarities and differences were noted in best friendship, between the two groups regarding physical activity patterns, and features of best friendship valued in physical education.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rk57r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736664763</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical fitness for children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical education for children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inclusive education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical education for children with disabilities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Friendship in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425k999s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Crossing the line : the changing nature of highlander cross-border trade in northern Vietnam</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schoenberger, Laura</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates how changing Vietnamese state control over the Vietnam-China border has impacted cross-border trade networks and livelihoods of border residents in Lao Cai province, North Vietnam. The investigation uses information from qualitative research with 91 marketplace traders and border officials at four crossing points in the province. I find that state control over the border and cross-border trade has increased as this trade has been progressively brought within legal parameters from 1954 to 2005. By taking a commodity chain approach to investigate the trade networks of three locally produced goods that move across the border I discuss the complex interactions of state policy, social relations and location factors in shaping contemporary cross-border trade. This investigation suggests that state policy to encourage small scale cross-border trade and new tradable commodities are increasing the livelihood options available to border residents in the province.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j829j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425k999s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>China -- Commerce -- Vietnam (Democratic Republic)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lào Cai (Vietnam : Province) -- Economic conditions -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vietnam (Democratic Republic) -- Commerce -- China</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322d50f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Affecting change : aspects of rhetoric, poetics and logic in the minor poems of Guido Cavalcanti</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saunderson, Andrea</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis studies the use of rhetoric, poetics and logic in thirteenth-century Italian poetry, specifically that of Guido Cavalcanti. The poetic production of Cavalcanti is examined as an example of the synthesis of science and poetry, and secondly as an example of the use of persuasive techniques. In particular, I examine his so-called minor poems as examples of the theory of love expressed in "Donna me prega". My work hinges on two aspects: the fact that the central metaphor in the poetry of Cavalcanti represents the phenomenology of love as a passion of the body using medical terminology from Avicenna, and that the radical Aristotelianism (marginalised by the ecclesiastical condemnations) defines Cavalcanti's philosophical and scientific discourse. Cavalcanti combats the opposition of his readership to his radical Aristotelianism with persuasive techniques, rhetorical and poetic, and with logic found in Aristotle, his commentators Gundisalvus, al-Farabi, Avicenna, Averroes, and Roger Bacon.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s5088.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d50f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cavalcanti, Guido, d. 1300 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698777w"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Armenians in the Ottoman legal system (16th-18th centuries)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Setrakian, Aida Alice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the participation of Armenians in the shari'a courts of the Ottoman Empire from the 16th to the 18th centuries. Scholars have traditionally thought that Armenians in the Ottoman Empire resolved their disputes within their own communities' legal systems. However, new studies of Ottoman court records reveal that Armenians in the Ottoman Empire frequently used the shari'a courts to resolve a wide variety of disputes. There are several possible reasons to account for this frequent shari'a court use by a community that theoretically had its own courts. The first is that the Armenian millet's legal structures were perhaps exaggerated or misunderstood by previous scholars. The second is that Islamic law was not as unfavourable to dhimmis as presumed and that the shari'a courts were adequate for their needs. Finally, the way the courts applied Islamic law was sometimes advantageous to certain dhimmis.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483j59s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698777w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Armenians -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Turkey</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islamic law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w256n"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The acquisition of coaching knowledge of a unique sample of expert team sport coaches</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carter, Adam D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to identify how coaches who have surpassed their athletic achievements acquired their coaching knowledge. Six University coaches from basketball, volleyball, and hockey, with a combined total of fourteen coach of the year awards were selected to participate. Each coach was coaching at a higher level (e.g., University level) than he had competed as an athlete, had a winning percentage greater than .500 at the University level, and had been the head coach at their current program for a minimum of five years. Semi structured, open-ended interviews were conducted using an interview guide created exclusively for this study and based on the tenets of Cote, Salmela, Trudel, Baria, and Russell's (1995) Coaching Model and Chelladurai's (1978) Multidimensional Model of Leadership. Data analysis followed the guidelines forwarded by Cote, Salmela, Baria, and Russell (1993). Results of this analysis revealed three higher order categories which indicated the path coaches had taken to reach their current positions including the many ways knowledge was acquired. These were (a) career path which discussed the journey of knowledge acquisition of these coaches, from their earliest sport participation to their current coaching position, (b) personal factors, which included how the coaches' journey of knowledge acquisition had been influenced by who the coaches were, and (c) coaching knowledge, which involved the participants' current level of coaching knowledge. Despite the idiosyncratic nature of each coach's career progression many common themes emerged, including the different ways knowledge was acquired, the coaches' personal characteristics, and the level of coaching knowledge accumulated. Many of the findings that emerged were similar to those highlighted in previous studies pertaining to expert coach development (e.g., Cregan, Bloom, &amp; Reid, in press; Salmela, 1994; Schinke, Bloom, &amp; Salmela, 1995) which suggests that while athletic experiences may be helpful in expert coach development, they are not essential. The results provided evidence that sources of knowledge acquisition are accessible to aspiring coaches to acquire the necessary coaching knowledge, regardless of their athletic background. The current findings could potentially enhance the quality and standard of formal coach education and training programs in Canada by illustrating how a unique sample of coaches acquired the knowledge to achieve success at the university level.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687h70x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w256n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Coaching (Athletics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coaches (Athletics)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd472w72q"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computer vision methods for guitarist left-hand fingering recognition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burns, Anne-Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a method to visually detect and recognize fingering gestures of the left hand of a guitarist. The choice of computer vision to perform that task is motivated by the absence of a satisfying method for realtime guitarist fingering detection. The development of this computer vision method follows preliminary manual and automated analyses of video recordings of a guitarist. These first analyses led to some important findings about the design methodology of such a system, namely the focus on the effective gesture, the consideration of the action of each individual finger, and a recognition system not relying on comparison against a knowledge-base of previously learned fingering positions. Motivated by these results, studies on three important aspects of a complete fingering system were conducted. One study was on realtime finger-localization, another on string and fret detection, and the last on movement segmentation. Finally, these concepts were integrated into a prototype and a system for left-hand fingering detection was developed. Such a data acquisition system for fingering retrieval has uses in music theory, music education, automatic music and accompaniment generation and physical modeling.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161645k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472w72q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer vision</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human-computer interaction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95050792"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning strategies of Mi'kMaq (Aboriginal) students</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Caplin, Tammy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this qualitative research study, First Nation students in high school participated in an interview study designed to (1) describe how their school experiences related to academic success and (2) to identify learning strategies used to achieve success. Participants described the importance of achieving academic success to ensure future economic security. In their approaches to learning, participants preferred multiple modes of learning. Various types of learning strategies included both visual and verbal methods such as teacher demonstrations, reading, and writing. Motivational influences were also identified as contributing to their educational success which came from a variety of sources such as teachers, parents, peers, and community leaders. Educational success for these Aboriginal students is both multi-dimension and multi-modal. Implication of the research and future direction will be discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w7505.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95050792</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Micmac Indians -- Nova Scotia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Learning strategies</dc:subject><dc:subject>High school students -- Nova Scotia -- Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33rw90h"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Negotiating identity : the Shī'ite ulama and the colonial state in Iraq, 1914-1924</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chowdhury, Rashed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with the political role of the Shi`te ulama in Iraq between the British invasion of 1914 and the expulsion of leading Shi`ite mujtahids from Iraq by King Fayṣal I in 1924. The thesis argues that the conception of identity propagated by the Shi`te mujtahids underwent a transformation during this period. Whereas the mujtahids stressed the need for Islamic unity and encouraged an Iraqi national identity in the early years of this period, in later years some of them formulated a sect-based Iraqi Shi`ite identity in response to discrimination in favour of Sunnis by the monarchy.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/474299452.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rw90h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Iraq -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ulama -- Iraq</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iraq -- History -- 1534-1921</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569469f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mathematical modelling of Osprey process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhong, Guisong, 1961-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Osprey process is a new kind of metal forming technology. In this process, a stream of liquid metal is atomized into a spray of molten droplets by a high velocity inert gas jet. The atomized droplets are accelerated towards a substrate of suitable shape and size. At the same time, they are rapidly cooled by the surrounding relatively cold gas and thereby partly solidified. After a certain flight distance, the droplets impinge on the cold substrate, and solidification continuous on the substrate. Near-net shaped products can be manufactured by this process. In this study, a simple mathematical model is established to describe the atomizing gas velocity profile and the velocity, thermal and solidification profiles of rapidly cooled metal droplets of different sizes during the in flight droplet-gas interaction. Given the relevant spray parameters, the model allows to predict quickly the transient droplet velocity, temperature, and solid fraction contents of individual droplets at various spray distances from the substrate. This model can be used to ascertain the suitability of the nozzle-substrate distance in Osprey process. The developed mathematical model has been used to predict thermal history and solidification behavior of atomized droplets of gamma-TiAl alloy. The model predicts undercooling, nucleation temperature, nucleation position and the extent of solidification of the in flight droplets of sizes ranging from 20 mum to 500 mum.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mp92b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569469f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42n8192"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Taxing charities, imposer les organismes de bienfaisance : harmonization and dissonance in Canadian charity law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chan, Kathryn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>For many years, the determination of which organizations should qualify for the significant tax benefits accorded to "registered charities" ( "organismes de bienfaisance enregistres") under the Canadian Income Tax Act has been based, in all provinces, on the concept of charity developed by the English common law of charitable trusts. However, there are other sources of meaning for the concept of "charity" ( "bienfaisance") in Canada, including ancient, civil law sources that continue to form part of the basic law of Quebec. This study challenges the longstanding, unijural approach to the registered charity provisions on the basis of the constitutional division of powers, and the federal government's commitment to respecting bijuralism and bilingualism in its legislative texts. It explores the diverse, legal sources concerning charity and the devotion of property to the public good that form part of the law of property and civil rights in the provinces. Finally, it examines how these diverse provincial sources might affect the current approach to the registered charity provisions, and the project of ensuring that federal laws are accessible to each of Canada's Francophone civil law, Francophone common law, Anglophone civil law and Anglophone common law audiences.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v570x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n8192</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nonprofit organizations -- Taxation -- Law and legislation -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5x21tf61x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Can lessons from game theory be applied to family law negotiations?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>O'Hanlon, Johanne Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The author suggests using lessons from Game Theory to improve the negotiation process and to construct more fitting agreements upon the breakdown of the family unit in the cases of separation or divorce. Currently many settlement agreements are inappropriate for the parties for a variety of reasons, including not establishing the parties' true interests during the negotiations. Furthermore, an inappropriate agreement may not be reopened by the court, given strict procedural and jurisprudential requirements. Game Theory lessons promote communication, cooperation, and forgiveness without allowing either party to be manipulated. These elements, already found in Collaborative Law, favour incorporating the lessons from Game Theory into this negotiation process.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f614b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tf61x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Domestic relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Game theory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tm19p"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The legitimacy of the International Civil Aviation Organization's universal safety oversight audit programme</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Detra, Zachary D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Based on the International Civil Aviation Organization's (ICAO's) evolution into the realm of safety regulation, which is unforeseen by the Chicago Convention, this thesis analyzes the legitimacy of the Universal Safety Oversight Audit Programme (USOAP) and ICAO's authority to regulate the sovereign states that enable its existence as an international organization. It concludes that ICAO's creation and operation of the USOAP is legitimate and sustainable based on: (1) an examination of international organizations generally; (2) the history and evolution of aviation safety audits; and (3) the relevant provisions of the Chicago Convention. Possible amendments to the Chicago Convention with the purpose of enhancing the USOAP are also considered and recommended.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rk581.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm19p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aeronautics -- Safety regulations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp37v"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Turbo equalization using frequency-domain shortening filter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Monfet, Frederic</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Turbo equalization provides excellent performance but the complexity associated with this technique prohibits its use in application with severe inter-symbol interference (ISI) channel; the turbo equalizer complexity increases exponentially with the length of the channel impulse response (CIR) and the modulation level used for data transmission. In this work, a combined frequency-domain pre-equalizer with a turbo equalizer is proposed in an attempt to reduce the length of the CIR used by the turbo equalizer and hence the complexity of the receiver. The optimum selection of coefficients of the frequency-domain pre-equalizer and desired channel impulse response is discussed. With the proposed receiver, the complexity of the turbo equalizer can be controlled by pre-selecting the length of the desired channel impulse response. This complexity reduction is achieved at the cost of an increase in the noise level, which degrades the performance. The effect on the performance of such pre-equalizer is studied analytically. The overall performance of the proposed receiver for different length of the desired channel impulse response is studied via analytical comparison and simulation. Simulation results on performance in various frequency-selective fading channels indicate a substantial performance gain when compared to a conventional feed-forward equalizer (FFE) plus decision-feedback equalizer (DFE) receiver. Finally, in cases where a large alphabet is used for modulation, the reduced-search BCJR (Bahl, Cocke, Jelinek, and Raviv) [1] algorithm is utilized in the proposed receiver to further reduce the complexity of the receiver.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dv80g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp37v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sq39x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On blind channel estimation without channel ambiguity for single-rate and multi-rate space-time block coded CDMA systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nicolov, Eugene Borislavov</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this work we study the downlink transmission of Code Division Multiple Access (CDMA) systems using the Alamouti code in order to provide space time diversity. We will propose a novel spreading signature assignment technique for space-time coded single rate CDMA system, which, compared to other signature assignment methods, allows to reduce the number of spreading signatures necessary in order to solve the channel ambiguity problem while performing blind channel estimation. This encoding method is called "rolling signatures". We also introduce a new method for combining the Alamouti space-time code with multi-rate CDMA. Instead of block coding entire CDMA symbols we will apply Alamouti coding at the chip-level. Such a coding method is called "chip-level" block coding. We present for our chip-level coding technique, various linear decoding structures both joint and disjoint. In the case of joint decoding, space-time and CDMA filtering at the mobile's end is done simultaneously by a single linear receiver. In the case of disjoint decoding, there are two dedicated receive filters, one performing space-time decoding and the other CDMA filtering. We also introduce a blind channel estimation technique and provide a thorough performance analysis of our estimator, in the form of mean-square-error performance analysis. Finally, we provide the Cramer-Rao Bound for our channel estimator.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35694706.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sq39x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569471g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implementation of robotic visual attention motivated by human physiology and behavior</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Michmizos, Konstantinos P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is Zeus' anathema on biomedical engineering that we should agonise between the Scylla of the simulation of the physiological and anatomical findings and the Charybdis of the efficient implementation of a system. Previous simulations on the addition of the perceptual velocity tracking of a target to a biomimetic controller developed by Galiana allow the implementation of a novel oculomotor system (OCS) in a hardware device comprising two cameras and a neck, each of which able to produce yaw and pitch movement. The robotic system uses visual inputs and a variety of movements in order to track targets, namely slow pursuit (slow phase), saccades (fast phase), conjugate and vergence. The addition of prognosis and memory to the controller, leads to the need for new tactics to be presented that address the problem of fixating a target more efficiently. Since the length and the flatness of the pursuit bandwidth of the new controller are essential for the minimization of the need for saccades, a greater harmonization among the parameters of the controller is basic. The resulting OCS can now be used to label with a significance factor each target presented on the visual field and track the one which is the most conspicuous. The intensity and the speed of the target are the criteria used to select a target and to alternate the alertness state of the robot.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mf76k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569471g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Robotics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vb542"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parallel implementation of hierarchical tetrahedral - octahedral (HTO) subdivision for 3-D finite element mesh refinement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Park, Chulhoon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Parallel computing is being used more and more frequently in 3-D finite element (FE) mesh generation in electromagnetics, due to its improvements in efficiency. When applying parallel computing, the computational problem usually needs to be broken into discrete pieces, so that it can be solved simultaneously with multiple compute resources. Less time is then required than with a single compute resource. In this thesis, an algorithm for hierarchical tetrahedral---octahedral (HTO) subdivision was studied and implemented with a parallel message passing interface (MPI). The data structure was designed in such a way as to store the geometric data during the mesh computation. Also, broadcasting and data gathering was used to build up the final geometric file. The experimental results and the enhancement of system performance are presented, comparing sequential computing with parallel computing. The program was implemented in C language/MPI, and the results obtained have made use of the CLUMEQ1 supercomputer Centre facilities at McGill University. 1CLUMEQ stands for Consortium Laval UQAM McGill and Eastern Quebec for high performance computing.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nr26q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb542</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kg52m"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of cutting tool coating on the machinability of Inconel 718</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bhatt, Abhay</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research is an assessment of the machinability of a nickel-based alloy Inconel 718 using a finish turning operation with carbide coated and uncoated tools having fine and medium grain size substrates, and the same tool geometry (a round tool shape geometry with a 0° rake angle and 7° clearance angle). In addition, orthogonal machining tests were carried out to generate experimental data for future identification of the constitutive laws of Inconel 718 (its behavior under high stress, strains, strain rates, and temperatures). The finish turning of this alloy was evaluated in terms of tool life, tool wear mechanisms, cutting forces, surface roughness, and chip formation process. The cutting speed range evaluated was from 50 to 100 m/min, and the feed range was from 0.075 to 0.125 mm/rev. Throughout the machining tests, the depth of cut was kept constant and equal to 0.25 mm. Tungsten carbide uncoated tool having fine grain size (&lt;1 μm), strong and sharp cutting edges were found to be the most suitable tool material and tool geometry for the finish turning of Inconel 718 at a cutting speed of 50 m/min, and, moreover, yielded the best tool life of 53 minutes. When finish turning at a cutting speed of 75 m/min, a single layer PVD (TiAlN=3μm) carbide tool yielded the best tool life of 12 minutes. At a cutting speed of 100 m/min, triple layer CVD coated tools (TiCN/Al2O3/TiN=15 μm) produced the best performance, yielding an 8 minutes of tool life. During the machining tests, the common wear mechanisms of the three different tools were adhesion, abrasion, and diffusion. Flank wear was the dominant tool failure mode of all three tools. The analysis of chip morphology showed that no phase transformation existed even though the material was deformed. The increase of micro-hardness was confirmed by micro-hardness measurements on chips, as compared to the initial micro-hardness of the material (Inconel 718). Cutting forces for all the different tools were relatively low (&lt; 300 N) when the cutting edge was new. For the finish turning operation, surface roughness of (&lt;1 mum) was achieved in all the cutting tests.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296wz42b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kg52m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jt894"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A programmable analog Gaussian noise generator for test applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aouini, Sadok</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a robust programmable analog Gaussian noise generator suitable for mixed-signal test applications. Unlike conventional methods, noise generators employing a linear feedback shift register (LFSR) or resistor thermal noise amplification techniques, the user has full control over the characteristics of the Gaussian signal. Indeed, the frequency band, the mean, and the variance of the distribution are fully programmable over the voltage range within the supply rails. The method consists of digitally encoding the specified Gaussian signal in a random access memory (RAM), using pulse-density modulation, followed by filtering the output bit stream using an analog low-pass filter. It is demonstrated that the quality of the generated noise signal is independent of the quality of the filter used; hence, making the noise source highly robust. The output of the noise generator accurately models a real Gaussian signal, even at high sigma values; thus, making it a very effective and predictable dithering signal. Two applications of the proposed Gaussian noise source are demonstrated: histogram testing of analog-to-digital converters (ADCs) and high-resolution digitization. In addition, a high-voltage automotive test instrument that supports the high-resolution digitization process proposed is outlined.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b17h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jt894</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80hv57f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Infrared behavior of structure I methane and carbon dioxide hydrates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bancroft, Naomi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy is commonly used in solution crystallization studies to monitor the crystal formation process. This analysis reflects the molecular vibrations within the solution. A crystallization process that is currently a very popular area of study is hydrate formation due to the possible application of gas hydrate research in the energy sector. A study of molecular vibrations was performed on two types of structure I gas hydrate, methane and carbon dioxide. Experiments were performed with a specialized high pressure sample cell placed inside an FTIR spectrometer. The experimentation was carried out at 253.15 K for both the methane and carbon dioxide systems and a pressure range of 2100 to 6800 kPa for the methane system and 1400 to 1700 kPa for the carbon dioxide system. This line of experimentation was able to assist in mapping the IR behavior of the hydrates studied and establish the presence of hydrate within a sample.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214p33h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hv57f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rh27v"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Khul' : between past and present</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zantout, Mida R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates past and present understandings and applications of khul', synthesizing existing scholarship on the subject as well as H&amp;dotbelow;anafi juristic doctrines. As khul' is part of a larger concept, namely, divorce initiated or approved by women, attention will also be given to the other options that Islamic law---or, on some points, cultural practices---grants women in order to obtain release from the marital bond. A comparative analysis between the application of marriage and divorce laws under the Ottomans and in contemporary Egypt will then be conducted with a view to shedding light on the effect that the rise of the nation-state has had on gender inequality.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd264.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh27v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Divorce (Islamic law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am900nt773"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Political parties and their competitors : party development in Russia's regions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gibson, James, 1982-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The variation in expansion of national political parties into regional politics in Russia poses a fundamental challenge to theories of party development by presenting an empirical puzzle: why have national politics dominated in some regions yet failed to elect or even present candidates in others? Conventional explanations for party weakness in Russia invoke cultural constraints or poor institutional incentives but neither provide sufficient variation to explain these outcomes at the regional level. These failures correspond to a larger lacunae in the party literature on the process by parties become nationalized and eliminate their regional competitors. This study addresses these empirical questions by re-examining regional elites and their ability to create informal alternatives to parties. I argue that the failure of national political party development in Russian regional politics is not simply the product of poor institutional incentives but rather due to the active opposition of regional elites. Where regional elites successfully mobilized the resources made available during transition, they prevented the entry of national parties by furnishing their own candidates with powerful financial resources and lending them reputation that resonated with the electorate. These outcomes were not predetermined by legacies of the Soviet era, however, but were rather contingent on the ability of regional executives to rapidly construct winning coalitions, particularly through the mobilization of administrative resources and the construction of patronage networks. Hence, the successful development national parties in regional politics was as much a story of weak regional regimes as it was a story of successful regional party branches.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qp86z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nt773</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political parties -- Russia (Federation)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236229k"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An exploration of feature selection as a tool for optimizing musical genre classification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fiebrink, Rebecca</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The computer classification of musical audio can form the basis for systems that allow new ways of interacting with digital music collections. Existing music classification systems suffer, however, from inaccuracy as well as poor scalability. Feature selection is a machine-learning tool that can potentially improve both accuracy and scalability of classification. Unfortunately, there is no consensus on which feature selection algorithms are most appropriate or on how to evaluate the effectiveness of feature selection. Based on relevant literature in music information retrieval (MIR) and machine learning and on empirical testing, the thesis specifies an appropriate evaluation method for feature selection, employs this method to compare existing feature selection algorithms, and evaluates an appropriate feature selection algorithm on the problem of musical genre classification. The outcomes include an increased understanding of the potential for feature selection to benefit MIR and a new technique for optimizing one type of classification-based system.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b1496.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236229k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Information storage and retrieval systems -- Music</dc:subject><dc:subject>Machine learning</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>