<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xv223"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sound travels : mapping trajectories of musical recordings towards and within sites of meaning-making</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anestopoulos, Karolina Anastazja</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores how musical recordings circulate within various sites of metacultural analysis, such as print music publications, music blogs, community-based campus radio music programmes and music podcasts. Drawing on theories about cultural production, the circulation of cultural objects, and metaculture (circulation of ideas about cultural objects, rather than the objects themselves), the author traces how an independent record label discursively positions musical recordings for movement towards and within these meaning-making spheres. Print music publications and music blogs facilitate recognition and consecration of recordings in different capacities, particularly in relation to music publicity. Community-based campus (c/c) radio and music podcasts situate recordings within new cultural objects--radio texts--that engage with listeners in different ways. In this manner, all sites are stakeholders in shaping the meaning of a musical recording and propel its actual and metacultural circulation along various trajectories.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse explore comment les enregistrements musicaux circulent à travers différents lieuxd'analyse métaculturelle, comme les publications imprimées traitant de musique, les bloguesmusicaux, les émissions de musique des radios communautaires et universitaires ainsi que lesbaladodiffusions musicales. Basé sur les théories de la création de la culture, de latransmission des objets culturels et métaculturel (la circulation d'idées à propos d'objetsculturels plutôt qu'à propos des objets eux-mêmes), l'auteur démontre les méthodesdiscursivement employées par une étiquette indépendante afin d'encourager le mouvement deses enregistrements musicaux au sein de ces sphères créatrices de sens. Les publicationsimprimées et les blogues musicaux facilitent la reconnaissance et la consécration desenregistrements musicaux, notamment à travers la promotion de la musique. Les radioscommunautaires et universitaires ainsi que les baladodiffusions musicales placent cesenregistrements à l'intérieur d'un nouvel objet culturel- le contenu radiophonique -lesquelsattirent l'attention de l'auditoire de différentes façons. Ainsi, tous ces environnementscontribuent à donner un sens à l'enregistrement musical et à le propulser, au sens propre et ausens métaculturel, vers ses trajectoires variées.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj673.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xv223</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sound recordings -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Popular music</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intercultural communication</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214p327"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Farmers' local ecological knowledge in the biotech age : a multi-sited ethnography of fruit farming in the Okanagan Valley</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Askew, Hannah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this Master of Arts Thesis in Anthropology I examine the controversy in the Okanagan Valley over the introduction of GM seed technologies into local agricultural processes. I explore via a multi-sited ethnography how local fruit farmers in this region view GM seed technologies and their perception of how these technologies will impact their farming practices. I argue that (a) the use of GM seeds as currently regulated in Canada threatens to erode farmers' local knowledge of plant breeding and that (b) this erosion is of consequence not only to local farmers but to society generally because the environmental knowledge and skills possessed by local farmers is crucial to the protection of biodiversity, environmental sustainability, and food security.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cq726.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214p327</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fruit growers -- Okanagan River Valley (B.C. and Wash.) -- Attitudes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fruit -- Genetic engineering -- Okanagan River Valley (B.C. and Wash.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Traditional ecological knowledge -- Okanagan River Valley (B.C. and Wash.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fruit -- Breeding -- Okanagan River Valley (B.C. and Wash.)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816m825"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Plato's political imagination</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Anderson, Linda Viktoria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Traditional interpretations of Plato see him either as an enemy of the imagination in his views of philosophic discussion, or as a purveyor of imaginative lies in his authoritarian and anti-democratic view of politics. Instead this thesis challenges both these interpretations by showing how the imagination is both philosophical and democratically political. In the Republic images and stories balance and enrich rational argumentation. I first analyze the imaginary aspects of Plato's ideal city. Secondly, I look more closely to the role of images in education and poetry by focusing on Plato's distinction between good and bad images. Thirdly, I discuss the role of images in relation to notions of the ideal and democracy. I propose that images are crucial in crafting and acquiring a vision of the ideal in speech. Finally, I end by stressing that philosophic discussion, and its use of images, not only contains democratic elements but that it also is more likely to thrive in a democratic space and context, marked by freedom of speech and pluralism.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh38p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816m825</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Imagination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plato. Republic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rp00x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>You are what you speak : the secret language of an Iraqi girl</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Askren, Hana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis I discuss the technical linguistic aspects of `Aliya Mamduḥ's Ḥabbat al-naftalin using postcolonial language theory, showing how these techniques contribute to Mamduḥ's literary goals. This is in contrast to much of English scholarship on Arab women authors, which has instead focused mainly on the social and political questions that Arab women's writing raises. Mamduḥ uses circular language and a child's narrative voice in order to portray her narrator growing up in 1950's Baghdad. The Arabic in the novel is a hybrid, mixed language with elements of classical language, colloquial language and Iraqi/Baghdadi dialect, and it facilitates the expression of women in the novel. Mamduḥ intertwines these language techniques with politics, fear and history to create a uniquely postcolonial work that explores women's words, women's stories, and women's agency.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f6132.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp00x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mamdūḥ, ʻĀliyah. Ḥabbāt al-naftālīn</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mamdūḥ, ʻĀliyah -- Literary style</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xf52q"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microstructure and texture development in AZ31 magnesium alloy processed by equal channel angular pressing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vuong, Linda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Enhancement of the ductility is very important for the successful commercialization of magnesium alloys. Among other methods, this can be achieved by refining the grain structure through equal channel angular pressing (ECAP) or extrusion. Preliminary work was conducted using as-cast AZ-31, but this was found to be of low ductility and extruded bars were used for the rest of the experimentation. These were annealed at 350°C for 1 hour and extrusion was carried out at three temperatures, 200, 250 and 300°C, using routes A, BC and C at a speed of 5 mm/s for up to 8 passes. It is apparent that increasing the operating temperature increases the final grain size as a result of grain growth. Conversely increasing the number of passes results in a finer grain size because of the accumulation of shear. However, grain growth can affect the final grain size for all three routes. After one ECAP pass, a preferred orientation with the basal planes inclined at 45° to the ECAP axis is observed. For route A, as more and more passes are employed, the original fiber texture tends towards a rolling texture. By contrast, for route C, repeating the ECAP steps does not change the texture, which retains the 45° preferential orientation. The mechanical properties indicate that using a path with shearing in more directions, such as route C, results in increased ductility, with a wider flow curve than for route A. As the temperature of ECAPping is increased, the strength of the extruded product increases and the ductility decreases. This appears to be due to the coarser grain size of the 300°C product and indicates that the effect of grain refinement is greater than that of texture.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fp25t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xf52q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cb05g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Combined application of voxel-based morphometry and magnetization transfer ratio for group analysis of magnetic resonance images</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Woo, Vivian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is conventionally used for macroscopic qualitative observations. However, increasingly there is a need for quantitative MRI measures, which may lead to enhanced detection sensitivity. Two quantitative techniques that may be used to make neuroanatomical inferences about a population or between different populations are magnetization transfer ratio (MTR) and voxel-based morphometry (VBM). VBM involves the statistical analysis of smoothed segmented white or gray matter maps to reflect increases or decreases in the probability of classifying a voxel as either white or gray matter. MTR provides a measure of the interaction of water and semi-solids within tissue, and thus is indicative of its macromolecular density and microstructural integrity. An MTR group analysis may detect variations of these semi-solid tissue characteristics within or between populations. This thesis investigates the relationship between information attained from VBM and MTR population studies carried out in the context of the Saguenay Youth Study. Additionally, through this study, the effects of age and gender on brain neuroanatomy are explored using the above techniques. The observed age and gender VBM and MTR effects were consistent with existing literature, but also offered new findings. Overall, applying MTR in conjunction with VBM allows for further insight into the origins of specific anatomical changes, and the discovery of areas that undergo within-tissue development without corresponding white or gray matter volume changes.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257f313.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb05g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45q916b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Algorithms for efficient dynamics simulation of space robotic systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wong, Pang Fei</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The algorithms used for solving the forward dynamics problem of a complex multibody system are essential for an efficient simulation of robotic systems. The efficiency is measured by the CPU time and the number of operations per number of bodies in the system. In this work, we discuss the solution of the forward dynamics problem for real-time simulations of space robotic systems using the so-called Articulated Body Method. Traditional methods use the calculation of the inverse of the generalized mass matrix. This makes the required number of operations proportional to the cube of the number of bodies in the multibody system. For real-time simulations of complex systems, O(n) algorithms seem to be the best choice because the number of operations is linearly proportional to the number of bodies. They become more efficient than O( n3) algorithms as soon as the number of bodies in the system exceeds 12--14. In this thesis, we will present a detailed discussion of O(n) algorithms derived based on the Articulated Body Method (ABM). This algorithm can be presented using Lagrangian and Hamiltonian variables. Such algorithms can be used for the real-time simulation of robotic systems by taking into account both joint-flexibility and approximations for the gear-ratio effect. A unified derivation of the ABM algorithms using both Lagrangian and Hamiltonian variables will be discussed. The intended, primary application of the algorithms is to develop real-time simulation engines for the complete robotic system of the International Space Station. The implementation and use of these algorithms will be analyzed in detail.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268539b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45q916b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b633s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A linear stability analysis of the destabilizing effects of wall permeability in channel flows</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tilton, Nils G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We perform a three-dimensional linear stability analysis of a laminar flow in a channel delimited by rigid, homogeneous, isotropic, porous blocks. We consider porous materials in which the permeability is small and the inertial effects can be neglected. We solve the coupled linear stability problem, arising from the adjacent channel and porous flows, using a spectral collocation technique. We consider symmetric flows in channels with two identical porous walls and skewed flows in channels with only one porous wall. In both cases, permeability significantly affects the Orr-Sommerfeld spectrum; however, the homogeneous Squire modes remain damped. In channels with two porous walls, permeability destabilizes up to two Orr-Sommerfeld wall modes and introduces two new damped wall modes on the left branch of the spectrum. In channels with only one porous wall, permeability destabilizes up to one wall mode and introduces one new damped wall mode on the left branch of the spectrum. In both channels, permeability also introduces a new class of damped modes associated with the porous regions. We find that very small amounts of wall permeability can dramatically decrease the stability of the channel flow. The neutral curve becomes significantly larger and the critical Reynolds number can decrease to only 10% its Poiseuille value.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct124.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b633s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722h9121"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Statistical downscaling and simulation of daily temperature extremes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Qinglan, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is now a broad scientific consensus that the global climate is changing in ways that could have a profound impact on human society and the natural environment over the coming decades. In particular, changes in the frequency and magnitude of extreme temperatures are likely to have more substantial impacts on the environment and human activities than changes in the mean temperature. The present study is therefore addressing three main objectives: (a) to propose a systematic data analysis method for characterizing the variability of daily extreme temperatures at different sites; (b) to develop new statistical downscaling models that could accurately describe the linkage between large-scale climate variables and the characteristics of temperature extremes at a local site; and (c) to develop a stochastic method for simulating accurately the extreme temperature processes. Firstly, a systematic data analysis procedure was proposed for analyzing the variability of daily maximum (Tmax) and minimum (Tmin) temperature characteristics. The suggested procedure consists of performing a detailed statistical analysis of twelve relevant temperature indices that are important for various practical application purposes: mean of diurnal temperature range, frost season length, growing season length, freeze and thaw cycle, 90th percentile of Tmax, 10th percentile of Tmin, means and standard deviations of Tmax, Tmin, and the daily mean temperature. The suggested method was applied to the analysis of daily Tmax and Tmin data for 20 stations in Quebec. The available records used are different from station to station, varying from 44 years to 107 years. In general, it was found that, depending on the temperature index considered as well as on the particular season of the year, there are some significant increasing or decreasing trends at some locations in Quebec. Results of this analysis would provide valuable information on the temporal and spatial variations of daily extreme temperature processes in the region. Furthermore, it can be observed that no systematic spatial variability of the increasing or decreasing trends of any of the twelve temperature indices considered could be identified for a given area in Quebec. Secondly, two new statistical downscaling models were proposed using the stepwise and robust regression methods in order to describe the linkage between largescale climate variables and the characteristics of Tmax and Tmin at a local site. The performance of these two models was tested using daily extreme temperature data available at Dorval Airport station in Quebec and the NCEP data for 25 different climate variables for the 1961-1990 period. It was found that the proposed stepwise and robust regression downscaling models can provide accurate estimates of fundamental statistical and physical properties of Tmax and Tmin. In addition, it has been observed that three climate variables, the mean sea level pressure, the 850hPa-geopotential height, and the near surface specific humidity, had the most significant effect on Tmax and Tmin at Dorval Airport. Furthermore, as compared with the popular SDSM model, the stepwise and robust regression models can provide more accurate estimates of the local Tmax and Tmin characteristics. In particular, the robust regression model was found to be the most accurate. Finally, a new stochastic simulation procedure was developed in this study for simulating the Tmax and Tmin temperature time series at a local site using the combination of the first-order autoregressive AR(1) model and the SVD technique. Results of the evaluation of the proposed AR(1)-SVD simulation method using daily extreme temperature data at Dorval Airport for the 1961-1990 period have indicated the feasibility of this method in describing accurately the observed basic statistical properties (mean, standard deviation, and first order autocorrelation) of the daily Tmax and Tmin time series at a local site.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085k25b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722h9121</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh13r"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Morphology study of structure I methane hydrate formation on water droplets in the presence of kinetic inhibitors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lessard, Lindsay Dianne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gas hydrates are non-stoichiometric crystalline compounds that occur when water molecules hydrogen bond to form cavities which can be stabilized by the presence of a guest molecule such as a gas or volatile liquid. Hydrates have been problematic in the oil and gas industry for several years as they may block pipelines and damage equipment. It is therefore of great interest to find environmentally safe inhibitors which can prevent hydrates from forming or from growing large enough to block pipelines. The purpose of my study was to observe the effect of kinetic inhibitors on the morphology of methane structure I hydrate using a high pressure crystallizer. Two kinetic inhibitors were studied, poly(VP/VC), a lactam ring copolymer, and antifreeze protein. Experiments were carried out on droplets with and without memory at pressures ranging from 5000 kPa to 10,000 kPa. There was no evident trend in induction times since nucleation is a stochastic process. Surface coverage time of each droplet was measured and found to be fastest on the water droplet followed by that of the poly(VP/VC) droplet and finally the AFP droplet, confirming that the two kinetic inhibitors studied were in fact effective at inhibiting hydrate growth. Since hydrate growth, unlike nucleation, can reliably be measured we can definitively conclude that AFP has a greater kinetic inhibiting effect on hydrate growth. During hydrate decomposition, it was observed in all experiments that the water droplet decomposed first followed by the poly(VP/VC) droplet and the AFP droplet. It is proposed that since the polymer chains and protein molecules bind to the hydrate crystals, this reduces the surface area of hydrate skin exposed, slowing the rate of decomposition.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pn145.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh13r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79407x487"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Magnetic resonance imaging relaxometry of normal pediatric brain development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leppert, Ilana R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis establishes normal age-related changes in the magnetic resonance (MR) T1 and T2 relaxation time constants using data collected as part of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) MRI Study of Normal Brain Development. This ongoing multi-centre study of normal brain and behaviour development provides both longitudinal and cross-sectional data and has enabled us to investigate the relaxation time constant evolution in several brain regions for children within the range of 0-4.5 years. Due to the multi-centre nature of the study and the extended period of data collection, periodically scanned inanimate and human phantoms were used to assess intra and inter-site variability. The main finding of this thesis is the parametrization of the mono-exponential behaviour of both the T1 and T2 relaxation time constants from birth until 4.5 years of age. This behaviour is believed to reflect the rapid changes in water content as well as myelination processes observable during neonatal brain development. These results, comprising over 200 subject scans, represents a subset of a publicly available normative pediatric MRI database, providing a basis for comparison for studies assessing normal brain development and deviation due to various neurological disorders.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tf626.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x487</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nf04z"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The adaptation of self-cycling fermentation to a continuously-stirred tank reactor for xenobiotic degradation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lennox, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The technique of self-cycling fermentation (SCF) was adapted to a continuously-stirred tank reactor (CSTR) using the production of CO2 as the monitored parameter in the feedback control loop, mechanical level switches to determine the volumes removed and replaced during reactor cycling and a non-50% harvest fraction. Previous work with the technique indicated the potential for improvement of SCF by applying these changes. The work was performed to develop a system that can be used to study the degradation of xenobiotic compounds when exposed to microbial cultures. The development of the experimental apparatus was done using the degradation of the plasticizer di-(2-ethylhexyl) adipate by Rhodococcus rhodochrous. The experimental results demonstrated that CO2 production could be used in the feedback control loop to successfully trigger cycling of the reactor. The use of a 65% harvest fraction demonstrated that a 50% harvest fraction was not necessary to operate SCF.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gw46j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nf04z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732d9217"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Knowing is not enough : Akrasia and self-deception in Shakespeare's Macbeth</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shugar, Seth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Traditionally, Macbeth has been read as a morality tale about the perils of ambition. The question that has implicitly animated most treatments of the play is, "Why does Macbeth kill Duncan?" By shifting the emphasis away from Macbeth's motives for killing Duncan onto his inability to refrain from killing him, I draw attention to the striking fact that, in killing King Duncan, Macbeth acts against a fully considered better judgment not to. This suggests the possibility that Macbeth's much-discussed ambition can be understood as a subset of the broader theme of akrasia , the condition in which an agent is unable to perform an action he knows to be right. After identifying and exploring the theme of akrasia in several of Shakespeare's plays, I go on to situate Macbeth's murder of Duncan in the context of the long literary and philosophical debate on incontinence. I then suggest four interrelated explanations of Macbeth's akrasia. First, Macbeth's connection to the motivational conditions of his knowledge is shallow; he does not feel what he knows. Second, Macbeth's lack of self-control is habitual because his weak connection to the conative dimension of his knowledge prohibits him from appealing to techniques of skilled resistance. Third, his habitual lack of self-control renders him vulnerable to Lady Macbeth's taunts, which not only deplete the motivation supporting his better judgment but also prevent him from giving full deliberative weight to his better judgment. Finally, Macbeth also engages in a consistent pattern of self-deception that not only facilitates his akratic slaughter of King Duncan but also enables him to murder Banquo and MacDuff's family. My explanation of how Macbeth is able to act self-deceptively against his better evidence echoes my account of how he is able to act akratically against his better judgment: he does not feel what he knows.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tv387.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d9217</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Macbeth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-deception in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rt57b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Performing female artistic identity : Lavinia Fontana, Elisabetta Sirani and the allegorical self-portrait in sixteenth and seventeenth-century Bologna</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rocco, Patricia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Artemisia Gentileschi's self-portrait, Allegory of Painting, painted in 1630, has activated a complex discussion of female artistic identity in which performance is tied to concerns with status. This thesis addresses an earlier history of development in allegorical self-portraiture in the work of the sixteenth-century Bolognese artist, Lavinia Fontana, and her seventeenth-century successor, Elisabetta Sirani. I argue that the female artist's negotiation for status was played out in the transformation from a more official mode of self presentation, such as Fontana's Self-Portrait at the Keyboard , to a deliberate performative shift of embodied personification in her self-portrait as Judith with the head of Holofernes and her later self portraits as St. Barbara in the Apparition of the Madonna and Child to the Five Saints. This negotiation of artistic status continues with Sirani's self-portraits in Judith and the Allegory of Painting, and as what I suggest are more ambiguous and ambitious representations of anti-heroines, Cleopatra and Circe. I also discuss the important role that the emerging genre of biography plays in the female artist's struggle for status. The thesis explores the shift in visual conventions in relation to discourses of artistic identity, gender and genre---such as the donnesca mano---that circulated in Renaissance historiography in Italy, and more specifically, in the cultural milieu of Bologna.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301169p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rt57b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sirani, Elisabetta, 1638-1665</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-portraits, Italian</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women artists -- Italy -- Bologna -- History -- 17th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fontana, Lavinia, 1552-1614</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women artists -- Italy -- Bologna -- History -- 16th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827b940"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation into diglossia, literacy, and tertiary-level EFL classes in the Arabian Gulf States</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rivard, Jane Nathalie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates whether the remedial tertiary-level EFL classes in the Arabian Gulf States optimize the process of acquiring English for the majority of the students, namely the graduates of government high schools. I have endeavoured to uncover, by reference to my three years as an EFL teacher in the Gulf and the pertinent literature, why so much time and effort invested by myself and my students resulted in such a disproportionate lack of progress in reading and writing. I show how three major factors (diglossia, a linguistic trichotomy, and low literacy levels) conspire to impede students from learning to read and write in English through second language methodology and compare this situation to the one in Quebec. I conclude with two suggestions to make tertiary-level EFL classes more efficient and effective: the use of more familiar methodology and the teaching of reading and writing through a literacy framework. I also propose some longer-term solutions to deal with the linguistic trichotomy, a problem the Gulf Arabian States may wish to address if they intend to pursue the goal of providing a world-class education to their children.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w752q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827b940</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Persian Gulf States</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Arabic speakers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh141"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effectiveness of a team goal setting program on cohesion in sport</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Senécal, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of the present study was to determine whether the implementation of a team goal setting program increased perceptions of cohesion. The participants came from eight female high school senior basketball teams from the Montreal region. A team goal setting intervention program was implemented over the course of the regular season with four teams. The remaining four teams were placed into the no-treatment control condition. Each participant completed a questionnaire that assessed cohesion within the first four weeks of the competitive season and at the end of the season. Results showed that participants in the team goal setting condition did not significantly increase perceptions of cohesion. However, athletes in the control condition significantly perceived a decrease in cohesion from the start of the season to the end of the season. The team goal setting intervention appeared to keep cohesion levels from decreasing throughout the season. Practical implications are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb06r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh141</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Teamwork (Sports)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Goal (Psychology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m194f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Non-linear effects and clustering in estimation of propensity scores</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mahmud, Mamun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In observational studies, propensity scores are used to reduce bias and to increase precision of the treatment effect estimation. Previous studies on propensity scores methodology, and its applications in epidemiological studies, have consistently relied on conventional multiple logistic regression methods that rely on the assumption of independent outcomes. Yet, in most epidemiologic studies, one may expect that several patients have been treated by the same physician resulting in the inter-correlation between treatments prescribed to individual patients of the same physician. In such situations, one may expect an important violation of the independence assumptions, and failure to account for such correlations will lead to incorrect statistical inferences. Another limitation is that conventional logistic regression relies on the assumption that the relationship between a continuous covariate and logit of the outcome is linear, which may be incorrect in many applications. All these problems may affect the estimation of propensity scores, influencing the selection of covariates to be included in the model and estimated effects of these covariates. In this thesis, I have investigated the above mentioned two issues to evaluate the potential benefits of using more refined methods, such as Generalized Additive Modeling, Generalized Estimating Equations and Generalized Linear Mixed Model, at the stage of estimation of the propensity scores. First, I analyzed an empirical database and then ran a small scale simulation. GAM modeling revealed a statistically significant non-linear effect of age and Charlson Comorbidity Index in predicting the choice of benzodiazepine (Lorazepam vs. Oxazepam or Lorazepam vs. Flurozepam). However, these results did not have any impact on the estimates of propensity score as very high correlation (&gt;0.99) was detected between the propensity scores from different models. In a simulation study, I investigated in particular the clustering issue. The results show that, in contrast to conventional logistic model, both GEE and GLMM models do account for variance inflation due to clustering and, therefore, yield reasonably accurate coverage rates. However, as revealed in empirical analysis, propensity scores from different models were almost perfectly correlated (&gt;0.99), even though these estimates have been obtained under different assumptions and under different methods. Overall, my results confirm that non-linearity and, to a lesser extent, clustering require more advanced statistical methods to be applied in epidemiological studies. However, both empirical results and a small simulation suggest that a failure of most previous pharmaco-epidemiological studies to account for such methodological complexities likely had only a minimal impact on the accuracy of the estimated propensity scores.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gw47t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m194f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214p34s"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression of defence-related genes in sugar beet plants infected with Rhizoctonia solani and treated with benzo-(1,2,3)-thiadiazole-7-carbothioic acid S-methyl ester (BTH)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maios, Claudia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The chemicals inducers SA, BABA, and BTH were tested as seed treatment and soil drench on a partial-resistant cultivar of sugar beet grown in sand infested with the Rhizoctonia solani AG 2-2IIIB. In another series of experiments, BTH was applied as soil drench on sugar beet plants inoculated with R. solani. The chemical inducers were ineffective in reducing pre-emergence damping-off and post-emergence plant mortality. Despite these results, treatment with BTH altered the levels of expression ratios of four defence encoding genes associated with systemic resistance: chitinase, peroxidase, chalcone isomerase, and chalcone synthase. BTH sensitised sugar beet plants without the necessity of R. solani infection to up-regulate substantially the transcript level ratios of chalcS and chit3, while levels of chalcI were down-regulated levels below 1. Of interest, was the significant increase of transcript levels of chit3 in sugar beet plants infected with R. solani and treated with BTH. In conclusion, sugar beet plants were capable of over expressing selected genes in response to a chemical inducer, but contrary to what had been reported, gene activation in sugar beet as a result of BTH treatment does not confer disease resistance against R. solani.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pq60d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214p34s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rhizoctonia solani</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sugar beet -- Disease and pest resistance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vk39j"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The composition, biological trafficking and cholesterol-lowering efficacy of sugarcane-derived policosanol supplements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marinangeli, Christopher P. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The cholesterol-lowering efficacy of the original sugarcane-derived Cuban policosanol (OPC) supplement has been attributed to an exclusive policosanol purity and composition. The first objective of the following study was to compare the purity and composition of the OPC and alternative sugarcane derived policosanol (APC) products. Second, to measure blood lipids and policosanol levels in tissues, plasma and feces in hamsters receiving diet fortified with no policosanols, OPC, or an APC (APC1) product. Results indicated that the policosanol purity and composition of the OPC and APC formulations are similar. Lipid levels were not significantly different between groups. Policosanols were undetectable in the plasma and tissues of any animals following policosanol supplementation. Policosanols were excreted at a higher rate in animals consuming APC1. Sugarcane-derived policosanols are not an efficacious cholesterol-lowering therapy. The purity and relative percent composition of the OPC supplement cannot account for its efficacy as a lipid lowering agent.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494873n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk39j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dietary supplements</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sugarcane</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fatty alcohols</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anticholesteremic agents</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042t370"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Holomorphic curves in projective spaces</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malkoun, Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>If f : C → Pn is a holomorphic curve in complex projective n-space whose image does not lie in a hyperplane, and if xi1, . . . xin+2 are n + 2 hyperplanes of Pn in general position, then the curve f must intersect one of them. We will prove a quantitative refinement of this theorem for n ≤ 2, the so-called defect relations, by expanding the material in Chern's paper [4].</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569475k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042t370</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr171x509"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identifying quantitative trait loci involved in radiation-induced lung disease in mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bégin, Michelle Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of this thesis was to identify genetic loci involved in radiation-induced lung disease in mice. Phenotypic analysis was completed for alveolitis, pulmonary fibrosis, survival time, mast cells/mm2 and cell counts in bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) to assess lung damage. Genome scans and linkage analysis were completed for two backcross cohorts (75%C3H/HeJ-25%C57Bl/6J or 25%C3H/HeJ-75%C57BU6J) using each of the phenotypes measured. Putative susceptibility loci were identified for alveolitis on chromosomes 12 (LOD=3.35), 14 (LOD=2.22) and 19 (LOD=1.7) in the mostly C3H/HeJ backcross cohort and on chromosome 14 (LOD=2.7) in the mostly C57BI/6J backcross cohort. Linkage using the pulmonary fibrosis scores provided supportive evidence for a quantitative trait loci (QTL) on chromosome 17 (LOD=2) in the mostly C57BI/6J background, and two unique putative linkage regions were localized on chromosome 2 (LOD=2.2) in the mostly C3H/HeJ cohort and 14 (LOD=2) in the mostly C57BI/6J cohort. Supporting evidence for linkage on chromosomes 12 and 14 in the mostly C3H/HeJ background and chromosome 14 in the mostly C57BI/6J background was obtained using cellular markers. Additionally, survival time mapped to the linkage regions isolated for alveolitis and pulmonary fibrosis, suggesting that the development of radiation-induced lung disease influences the survival time of the mice. Within each cohort there were sex dependent linkage intervals, indicating that male and female mice may possess different factors involved in the development of alveolitis and/or pulmonary fibrosis. These results suggest that there are multiple genetic loci involved in the development of radiation-induced lung disease in mice.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hf81q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171x509</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dp95x"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The fossil record as an archive of biological information in marine ice-scoured environments : Canadian Arctic Ocean</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bibeau, Karine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Post-mortem alteration of bivalve shells on arctic ice-scoured shelves helps illucidate the fidelity of death and fossil assemblages in these settings. Degradation rates and processes were constrained by (1) characterizing the taphonomic signature of death assemblages, (2) evaluating the live-dead fidelity of the benthos, and (3) net changes in experimentally deployed shells. Results revealed an extremely harsh taphonomic mill controlled by bioerosion, fragmentation and dissolution. Only select species accumulated in death assemblages, resulting in low taxonomic fidelity; at the habitat level 50% of the live species are found dead. 100% of the dead species are found alive, suggesting no temporal or spatial exotic contributions. Selectively preserved species could be time-averaged over 1 000s of years based on a preliminary model, yet high damage profiles suggest shorter scales of time-averaging. Skeletons are highly degraded compared to assemblages from temperate or tropical seas and reflect only a portion the living skeletonized community.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r8209.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dp95x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Paleontology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p058h"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Jet reconstruction in the DØ experiment trigger system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélanger-Champagne, Camille</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The DO experiment at Fermilab records the results of high energy collisions between protons and antiprotons. These high energy particle collisions often result in the production of collimated jets of secondary particles. The trigger system selects, in real time, collision events to be analysed via a detailed reconstruction. A fast reconstruction and identification of particle jets and other physics objects is done in the trigger system in the event selection process. Two possible improvements to the jet reconstruction software algorithm for the trigger system were implemented. The improvement that emulates the offline reconstruction software was found to yield a jet trigger rate reduction of up to 14% without reducing the trigger system performance. As such, it is favored for use in the online trigger system. The performance of the trigger system at reconstructing jets is measured from data. Biases of the measurement methods are identified and quantified. Measured efficiencies are then used to emulate the online trigger response in simulated events.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p2909620.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p058h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g051b"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A high-pressure vibrational study of metal pyrophosphate materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Baril, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of high external pressures on the Raman spectra of various metal pyrophosphate salts has been investigated with the aid of a diamond-anvil cell and a Raman microspectrometer. The pressure dependences of the Raman-active bands were determined from the wavenumber vs. pressure plots. The KMHP2O7·2H2O [M = Co(II), Mn(II), Zn(II) and Mg(II)] series of salts was studied at pressures up to about 50 kbar (ca. 50,000 atm). The Co(II) salt displayed an irreversible, pressure-driven, structural transformation at around 29 kbar. The M4(P2O 7)2·10H2O [M = Zn(II) and Mn(II)] salts were also investigated. A reversible phase transition was observed to take place for the Zn(II) salt in the pressure range of 15-20 kbar. Three other pyrophosphate materials, K4P2O7, Co 2P2O7·6H2O and Ca2KH 3(P2O7)2·3H2O, were also examined at high-pressure, but no pressure-driven phase transitions were observed in these cases.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm58m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g051b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jt90w"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Purification and characterization of trypsin from the pyloric ceca of hoki (Macruronus novaezealandiae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shi, Changying, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fish viscera are produced in large quantities in the fishing industry and represent a waste disposal and environmental pollution problem. However, this material is a rich source of trypsins that may have some unique properties, such as high molecular activity at low processing temperature, low thermostability, and high pH optimum/pH stability, for both basic research and industrial applications. The main objectives of this project were to extract, purify and characterize trypsin from the pyloric ceca of hoki (Macruronus novaezealandiae ), which is by far the most important commercial fish in New Zealand. Trypsin was purified from the pyloric ceca of hoki by ammonium sulfate fractionation, followed by acetone fractionation and affinity chromatography on SBTI-Sepharose 4B. The purified extract was simultaneously desalted and concentrated by ultrafiltration, and then characterized using N-alpha-benzoyl-DL-arginine-p-nitroanilide (BAPNA) as substrate. The affinity fraction migrated as a signal band in SDS-PAGE gels as well as in isoelectric focusing gels. The molecular weight of the isolated trypsin was determined by SDS-PAGE to be approximately 26,000 Da, whereas the MALDI-TOF MS method of analysis indicated a molecular weight of 23,791 Da. The isoelectric point was determined as 6.5. The kinetic properties, temperature, pH and inhibition effects on the activity of the purified trypsin were verified. On the basis of the kinetic properties, hoki trypsin showed better amidase activity than bovine trypsin. The hoki trypsin had alkaline pH optimum (pH 9.0) and was stable at a high pH. Hoki trypsin had a higher optimum temperature (60°C) and still had relative higher activity at lower temperature. On the other hand, hoki trypsin was unstable at higher temperature. The enzyme was inhibited by well known trypsin inhibitors (SBTI, aprotinin, benzamidine and PMSF). The N-terminal residues of hoki trypsin, IVGGQECVPNSQPFMASLNY, displayed considerable homology with other fish trypsins. Based on the above characteristics, it is suggested that the hoki enzyme is authentic trypsin with potential for use in food industry and related applications.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k756t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jt90w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Trypsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hoki</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>