<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qk432"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La modernité religieuse dans la pensée sociologique : Ernst Troeltsch et Max Weber</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gendron, Pierre, 1948-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is centered on the social question as addressed and defined by Ernst Troeltsch (1865--1923) and by Max Weber (1864--1920); it pertains mainly to the rise of religious modernity and its conditions of possibility; based on a comparative analysis of the socio1ogy of religion of Troeltsch and Weber, it deals with the question how religious modernity has to be thought from a sociological perspective. Along with modern historical science and scientific rationality in general, the social question challenged religion in the nineteenth century; this study brings out the originality of Troeltsch's vision of a modernity compatible with belief in the future of religion. Motivated by the debate on the social question, Troeltsch's concern was the social foundations of the Christian doctrine in its relation to secular domains of activity, and this calls for a new outlook on the issue of the relation between religion and culture. Eventually, the comparative approach of the sociological thought of Weber and Troeltsch pursued in the present work, while providing new insight into Weber's views on religion, brings about a better understanding of Troeltsch as a theologian and a philosopher of religion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boutin, Maurice</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn94x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk432</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Troeltsch, Ernst, 1865-1923</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion and sociology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weber, Max, 1864-1920</dc:subject><dc:subject>Civilization, Modern</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap5547t15w"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Développement et évaluation d'une stratégie d'observation de conditions à risque pour la manutention</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Denis, Denys</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is accepted that material handling is an activity presenting a high risk for injury, particularly to the back. In this study, an observation strategy has been developed and validated in order to evaluate the presence of these risky conditions while performing a handling task. Moreover, certain future utilisation conditions were specified. Fifty-one observation variables were identified and an observation structure was elaborated from three data sources. These sources were: a literature review on observation grids, interviews with expert handlers and video sequences of a laboratory manual handling study where 10 inexperience subjects performed a total of 1500 container transfers. Observational data entry was recorded from a sample of these 174 sequences for which biomechanic measures were also done. The results show that observations can be reliable and valid and that the diversity of observation objects can be important and extend beyond postural variables. The observations performed on an uninterrupted video sequence are the ones that present the most difficulties. The observers' experience does not seem to be an important factor in obtaining reliable results. On the other hand, the observation criteria, the training and the breakdown of variable classes are factors susceptible to influence reliability. Many observation variables for balance had a significative impact on the biomechanical measure of balance, particularly when the object is taken and put down. This is the case with the number of foot supports, the weight distribution at the base of support and the position of the object, especially it's lateral deportation with respect to the body. The backward movement of the pelvis, which enables to compensate for the added external weight to the body, was significantly associated to balance. In general grouped variables, have more impact on the measure of balance than variables taken individually. Grouped variables are also less prone to variations when handling contexts are changed. For asymmetry, shoulder orientation with respect to the pelvis, back flexion, parallelism of the shoulders to the ground, and the position of the hands on the object handled all had a significative impact on the effort asymmetries when the object was taken from the plate-form. For the control and fluidity, a difficulty in finding a corresponding biomechanical measure or reliability problems did not enable us to verify whether our observations could have permitted to evaluate the risky conditions. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lortie, Monique</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rossignol, Michel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j962s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t15w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cv67x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Influence of coil characteristics on heat transfer to Newtonian fluids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prabhanjan, Devanahalli G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A water bath thermal Processor was designed and built to study the influence of helical coil characteristics on heat transfer to Newtonian fluids like water and base oil with three different viscosities. The system consisted of a thermally insulated water bath, an electric heater, pump to re-circulate water in the bath and for pumping the processing fluid through the coil, copper helical coils and a storage tank for the processing fluid. Comparative study has shown that the outer and total heat transfer coefficients were significantly lower in natural than in forced convection water bath. However, inner heat transfer coefficient was not significantly affected. Flow rate as low as 0.001 m.s-1 in the water bath improved the outer and total heat transfer coefficients by 35 and 22% respectively. One could expect a higher rate with an increase in water re-circulation rate inside the water bath. Percent rise in heat transfer was limited to seven with respect to inner heat transfer. With the Pearson correlation, it was possible to express total heat transfer rate directly in terms of outer and inner rates. Significant interactions were observed between variables and constants. Experiments with 2 pitch cases were conducted with water to water heat transfer using coils to determine the Nusselt number correlation for natural convection. Characteristic lengths were changed in the models. The Nusselt number was under-predicted by 25 to 37% for water bath temperatures of 75° and 95°C respectively. Flow rate inside the coil had slight effect on Nusselt number due to change in the temperature gradient along the length of the coil. Studies conducted with three base oils have shown significant difference in viscosity after heating the oil for several turns. Each fluid was heated in a distinct flow regime. The observed Nusselt number inside the coil for low Reynolds number was as high as an order of magnitude than the predicted values calculated by Seider-Tate relation for laminar flow. Vorticies formed associated with the eddy structure could very well be the cause for this kind of rise in the value. Preliminary study conducted has shown a higher rise in temperature of processing fluid in case of helical coil compared to that of a straight tube. Larger the diameter of the tube better was the heat transfer. An elevated bath temperature had higher heat transfer.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raghavan, Vijaya</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r480r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv67x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tubes -- Fluid dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Newtonian fluids</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heat -- Transmission</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q3213"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic regulation of vascular and floral patterning in Arabidopsis thaliana</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deyholos, Michael K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mechanisms that genes use to direct patterns of development are of fundamental interest. Using Arabidopsis thaliana as a model, I have investigated aspects of these mechanisms in the separate processes of vascular and floral development. Specifically, I conducted a screen for vascular-defective mutants, and analyzed a region of the genome that regulates the expression of the floral homeotic gene, AGAMOUS ( AG). In this report, I describe the identification of over forty mutants that are abnormal in tracheary element development or vein patterning. The spectrum of mutant phenotypes that I observed indicates that the mechanisms that pattern primary and secondary veins of leaves or cotyledons are at least partially separable; that among the genes that affect vascular development, a significant proportion are repressors of vascular differentiation; and that the majority of vascular mutants that can be identified in this type of screen have pleiotropic phenotypes. I characterized two of the mutants, varicose ( vcs) and scarface (sfc), in more detail. vcs mutants are temperature sensitive, and at the non-permissive temperature, accumulate distended tracheary elements around veins. VCS is also required at an early stage of leaf development for normal vein patterning, and interacts with the AUXIN RESISTANT 1 gene in this process. sfc mutants fail to develop normal, contiguous vein networks in cotyledons, leaves, sepals, and petals. It is specifically the secondary and higher order veins in these organs that are affected by the mutation. sfc mutants have exaggerated responses to exogenous auxin, and the SFC gene overlaps in primary and secondary vein patterning functions with an auxin-response factor gene MONOPTEROUS. This report also includes an analysis of the cis-regulatory regions that control expression of AGAMOUS, a gene that when properly expressed in two central domains of the developing flower, directs the formation of carpels and stamens. My dissection of an AG intragenic region demonstrated that AG expression in stamens can be activated independently of carpels. Moreover, the stamen-specific expression pattern was found to be independent of APETALA2, a known negative regulator of AG, while the carpel-specific expression pattern was shown to be independent of LEUNIG, another negative regulator of AG.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sieburth, Leslie E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt403.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q3213</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Flowers -- Morphogenesis -- Molecular aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Morphogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214q782"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of blowing snow in the hydrometeorology of the Mackenzie River Basin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Déry, Stephen J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite being ubiquitous in the Mackenzie River Basin (MRB) of Canada, the role of snow in its energy and water budgets are still open to much speculation. This thesis presents a multi-scale analysis of the contribution of blowing snow to the hydrometeorology of the MRB. A climatology of adverse wintertime weather events is first presented and demonstrates that blowing snow events are rare within the forested sections of the MRB but become more frequent in the northern parts of the basin covered by Arctic tundra. It is these areas which experience the largest impacts of blowing snow transport and sublimation due to large-scale processes. To further assess the mesoscale and microscale effects of blowing snow to the northern regions of the MRB, the development of a bulk blowing snow model is then described. The single- and double-moment versions of the PIEKTUK blowing snow model are shown to produce equivalent results as a previous spectral version of the numerical model while operating about 100 times faster. The application of the double-moment PIEKTUK model (PIEKTUK-D) to a Canadian Arctic tundra site near the northern tip of the MRB reveals that blowing snow sublimation depletes ≈3 mm snow water equivalent (swe) from the snowpack over a period of 210 days during the winter of 1996/1997 at Trail Valley Creek, Northwest Territories. Various assumptions on the state of the background thermodynamic profiles and their evolution during blowing snow, however, can yield significantly higher (&gt;300%) rates of sublimation over the same period. PIEKTUK-D is then coupled to the Mesoscale Compressible Community (MC2) model for an interactive simulation of a ground blizzard at Trail Valley Creek. This coupled mesoscale simulation reveals that moistening and cooling of near-surface air associated with blowing snow sublimation is observed but mitigated in part by advective and entrainment processes. Combined, blowing snow sublimation and mass divergence are then shown to rem</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yau, M. R. (Peter)</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv686.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q782</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xd408"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mobilizing Canada : the National Resources Mobilization Act, the Department of National Defence, and compulsory military service in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Byers, Daniel Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Compulsory military service took on the most organized, long-term form it has ever had in Canada during the Second World War. But few historians have looked beyond the politics of conscription to study the creation, administration, or impact of a system that affected more than 150,000 men. This thesis examines the Army's role in creating and administering the compulsory military training system, and particularly the influence of Major-General H. D. G. Crerar and other senior officers. Faced with the federal government's policy of conscripting manpower only for home defence in 1940, and influenced by their own personal and professional desires to create a large, powerful Army that could take a leading role in the fighting overseas, Army leaders used conscripts raised under the National Resources Mobilization Act to meet both purposes. In this development can be found the origins of the "big army" of five divisions that fought for Canada overseas. Ultimately, thanks to the burden created by the "big army," and the entry of Japan into the war in late 1941, the NRMA failed to meet the huge demands imposed on the nation's manpower resources. The result was the political crisis that almost brought down the federal government in October and November 1944. This thesis also explores the origins and background of the conscripts themselves, and the impact of the NRMA on their lives. As the NRMA became more and more central to the Army's plans after 1941, conscripts were exposed to a number of pressures designed to convince them to volunteer for overseas service. By late 1944, the only ones who remained were those who had most strongly resisted these efforts, a fact that the country's generals understood better than its politicians. The events of late 1944 brought the Cabinet to an awareness of the situation, but only at the cost of the prestige and influence that the Army had built up over the earlier years of the war. Thus, the way that the Army managed the NRMA came very much to shape the political debates that took place, and the place of the Army in Canada after the war.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Miller, Carman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w917j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd408</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canada -- History -- 1939-1945</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Draft -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mn956"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Se creer des ancetres. : les ecrits historiques et genealogiques des de Forest et des Forest d'Amerique du Nord, 19e et 20e siecles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Caron, Caroline-Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the exercise of genealogy in North America in the 19th and 20th centuries through an analysis of the historical and genealogical writings by and about the (real and presumed) descendants of two Walloon brothers, Jesse (c 1580--1624) and Gerard de Forest (1583--1654). It also follows genealogy's slow democratization, from its late 19th century bourgeois users to the explosion of its popularity since 1977. A thorough theoretical base was needed to compensate for the absence of historical studies on the subject. The thesis then follows the construction over the course of 140 years of the de Forest and Forest historical narrative, through the successive publications of various versions of this story, fundamentally one of identity. From research project to research project, these genealogists were influenced by the time period, the social, cultural, and commemorative settings in which they wrote, in New England, New York, Acadia, Quebec, Louisiana, and Ontario. Their research techniques, their processes for acquiring and exchanging knowledge, and the manner in which they wrote their narratives, revealed their aspirations, their self-representations, those of their families and their ancestors, as well as their gender, class, and ethnicity. Their ancestor biographies showed a desire to make public the true history of their ancestors, for their family's glory, whether or not their ancestry was real or invented. In the hope of unifying the family, boaster the popularity of a famous ancestor or of an interest group, these genealogists constructed histories based on oral traditions, primary sources, and in response to the works of their predecessors. Through the years, the material conditions of genealogical research and publication changed greatly, particularly with the advent of computing, but the most important influences on genealogy writing have been the feminisation of genealogists, the multiplication of descendants willing to write, and the chao</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elbourne, J. Elizabeth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm54q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn956</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>United States -- Genealogy</dc:subject><dc:subject>De Forest family -- Genealogy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Forrest family -- Genealogy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Genealogy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genealogy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp76m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Professors' post-class reflection : a case study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cao, Li, 1957-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The topic of teacher reflection has been gaining greater attention in the education literature. Nevertheless, teachers' reflective processes have not been well understood. This study attempted to describe characteristics and content of professors' post-class reflection. More specifically, it attempted to determine whether professors engage in the reflection process consciously and ways in which this process can be characterized. Eight professors, representing two levels of teaching experience, teaching a lecture or seminar undergraduate class in humanities or engineering, participated in this case study. Interviews, classroom observations, and instructional plans and materials comprised the data sources. Transcripts of the interviews were analyzed thematically, using QSR NUD*IST 4. Findings indicate that professors' post-class reflection became a routine: it happened at different points of time, mostly right after the class, and as a continuous process. Their reflection involved a mixture of having intuitive feelings about the class as well as thinking logically about how the class unfolded. They reflected intentionally and for two major purposes: to get ready for the next class and to improve teaching in general. They were either unable to characterize their way of reflecting on the class or were very clear that their reflection was more an intuitive process than a rational one. They reflected mostly on their teaching performance, on the content covered in class, on the students, and on instructional contexts. Based on the results, a conceptual framework is proposed that describes professors' post-class reflection as interrelated with rational and non-rational information processing. The study contributes to a better understanding of the complex process of teacher thinking and informs the design of faculty development interventions that aim at promoting reflective practice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saroyan, Alenoush</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x3091.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp76m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Teaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reflection (Philosophy)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Teachers -- Training of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x5682"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tailored ammonium-bearing and ammonium-binding copolymers : pharmaceutical and industrial applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cameron, Neil S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The post-polymerization functionalization, characterization and application of block copolymers, hydrogels and cross-linked polymeric micro-beads to particular pharmaceutical and environmental applications are the focus of this thesis. The synthesis of a new amphiphilic and cationic block copolymer, polystyrene- b-poly(N,N,N-trimethylammoniumethylene acrylamide chloride) (PS- b-PTMEACl), from polystyrene-b-poly(tert-butylacrylate) (PS-b-P(tBuA)) is presented. The morphology of the self-assembled copolymers in water is assessed, and finally, we evaluate the potential of this nanoscale system as a bile acid sequestrant. Bile salts represent the major elimination route for cholesterol from the body and bile salt sequestrants have an established reputation as highly effective agents in the facilitation of this elimination. We also present the functionalization of a series of carbomers and their favorable bile salt binding properties. The synthetic methods were adapted from the post-polymerization functionalization of PS-b-PtBuA. The peculiar insolubility of ammonium tetraphenylborate in water was the fundamental property exploited in the research described in the final Chapter, where rather than ammonium-ion bearing polymers, ammonium-ion binding polymers are presented. Cross-linked PS resins were functionalized to contain pendent tetraphenylborate moieties and the ammonium-ion sequestering properties of this novel material were investigated. (Organo)ammonium ions from chemical and agro-industrial sources represent a major environmental hazard and our efforts contribute to the elimination of these toxins from effluent.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brown, G. R.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Eisenberg, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc779.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x5682</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bw19v"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of ion beam irradiation on interfacial structure in bilayers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abdouche, Randa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present thesis, we study the change in structural properties induced by ion beam irradiation of Ni/Fe and Co/Cu bilayers using various x-ray scattering techniques. These bilayers exhibit interesting GMR and magnetotransport properties. We show that an N-step model is useful in simulating any given electron density profile. We test four different interface profile functions in fitting the reflectivity and conclude that the error-function profile best describes our samples. Different types of interfaces are introduced, namely graded and rough interfaces, together with a discussion of their representation and their effect on both specular reflectivity and non-specular x-ray intensity. We develop a data acquisition and processing method in order to separate the specular and diffuse components of x-ray scattering and to obtain the normalized reflectivity. A computer program in C was developed to calculate the x-ray reflectivity (XRR) and diffuse scattering intensity and to fit the theoretical calculation to the experimental data using a non-linear least-squares fitting method. By fitting the XRR data of six bilayers of Ni/Fe and Cu/Co of different thicknesses and deposition sequence, the electron density profiles are constructed for different irradiation doses, ϕ. The intermixing at interfaces is found to increase with increasing ϕ. No change in the bulk materials electron density is observed upon irradiation of four single layers of these materials. A more detailed study is performed on Si/Ni(500A)/Fe(500A) bilayers. From diffuse-scan fits we find that as ϕ increases the interfaces become rougher, more jagged and the height-height correlation length of the roughness decreases. The intermixing can be approximated using the ballistic model of ion mixing. Using high-angle x-ray diffraction (XRD) measurements, the samples are found to be polycrystalline with a strong texture of fcc Ni(111) and bcc Fe(101) parallel to the substrate surface. Both plane-view and cross-sectional transmission electron microscopy (TEM, XTEM) images show that in-plane and out-of-plane grain sizes increase with ϕ, in good agreement with out-of-plane grain sizes calculated from Bragg peaks. The high-angle x-ray Bragg peak positions agree well with selected-area electron diffraction (SAED) rings. The iron oxide parameters obtained from XTEM and SAED patterns agree well with XRR results.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sutton, Mark</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0199.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw19v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515p996"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rape perceptions and the impact of social relations : insights from women in Beirut</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wehbi, Samantha</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Conducted within a feminist framework and guided by the principles of grounded theory methodology, this dissertation reports on the findings of a study of women's rape perceptions, undertaken in Beirut, Lebanon. The study relied on 38 interviews, participant observation, and a review of newspaper articles (1996--1999) and organizational documents. In this dissertation, I argue that perceptions of rape reflect, reinforce, and are supported by dominant social relations based on elements of social location such as gender, religion, socioeconomic status, disability, ethnicity and race. More specifically, I maintain that the relationship between perceptions of rape on one hand, and social relations on the other, is mediated by the centrality of marriage. This mediation is reflected in two processes. First, social relations lead to differential constructions of womanhood and perceived marriageability, which in turn play a large role in shaping perceptions of what counts as rape. Concretely, this impacts on which women are perceived to be consenting to sex and those perceived to be rape victims. Second, social relations construct a marriage that adheres to specific conditions as the only acceptable union between a man and a woman in Beiruti society. In consequence, these constructions of acceptability shape what counts as "real" rape versus consensual sex. Concretely, this means that relationships that fall outside this construction of acceptability are more readily labeled as rape. In the first four chapters of the dissertation, I provide background information about the study's theoretical framework, location within the broader empirical scholarship on rape perceptions, and methodology. I also provide detailed information about the Beiruti/Lebanese context. Chapters 5, 6 and 7 are empirical chapters relating some of the findings of the study as they relate to the centrality of marriage and perceptions of rape and consent. Chapter 8 concludes the dissertation with a discussion of the themes of women's agency, the line between sex and rape, and the impact of social relations. Through this discussion, I offer concrete insights for the further development of theory, research and practice with the issue of rape.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Krane, Julia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt66q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515p996</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rape -- Lebanon -- Beirut</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Lebanon -- Beirut -- Social conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex role -- Lebanon -- Beirut</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women, Arab -- Lebanon -- Beirut -- Social conditions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj67315611"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Prosaposin : a glycoprotein with multiple functions and dual destinations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhao, Qing, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Prosaposin is a multifunctional glycoprotein with different molecular masses and dual destinations. A 65 kDa form of prosaposin is targeted to lysosomes and converted by partial proteolysis, into four smaller non-enzymatic saposin A-D required for the hydrolysis of glycosphingolipids. However, the 65 kDa protein may be further glycosylated to a 70 kDa secretory form that is found in various biological fluids and suspected to have a trophic activity. Mutations of the prosaposin gene are linked to several lysosomal disorders. This thesis examines various aspects of the synthesis, targeting and function of prosaposin, and for practical purposes, the results and discussion were divided in three main sections. The first part deals with the cloning of the mouse prosaposin gene, the analysis of its transcribed mRNA and translation products. The second section examines the mechanism of targeting of the 65 kDa protein to lysosomes using mutagenic analyses. The third part deals with the effect of the inactivation of the prosaposin gene on the development of the male reproductive system. Sequence analysis revealed that the mouse prosaposin gene is over 20 kb in length and composed of 15 exons and 14 introns. Two forms of alternatively spliced mRNA (including or excluding exon 8) were found by RT-PCR in a tissue specific manner. Structure analysis and secondary structure predictions among mouse, rat and human prosaposins illustrated a common framework of amino acids forming amphiphatic helices enclosing an internal hydrophobic core implicated on their interaction with lipids. Mutagenic deletions of functional domains of prosaposin demonstrated that its C-terminus was required for the lysosomal targeting of this protein. Further evidence from chimeric constructs of albumin attached to various functional domains of prosaposin, suggested that the C-terminus plus at least one saposin domain are necessary for the targeting of albumin to lysosomes. Investigation of the effect of p</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morales, Carlos R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3656911.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67315611</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d830h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The regulation of murine Hoxd4 expression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Feng, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Hox genes encode homeodomain-containing transcription factors that specify positional identity along body axes during animal embryogenesis. Correct spatially and temporally restricted expression of Hox genes is critical for normal embryonic development. The alteration of Hox gene expression may result in homeotic transformation or malformation of the embryo. Using transgenic assays, we found that a previously mapped 5' retinoic acid response element (RARE) was not required for Hoxd4 gene expression in the central nervous system (CNS), but contributed to a 5' mesodermal enhancer. Neural and mesodermal enhancer activity of the gene were mapped to a 3' 4 kb region (region A). Removal of this region virtually abolished Hoxd4 expression in the CNS and posterorized expression in the somitic mesoderm by one somite. Further deletional analysis of the neural enhancer led to the identification of a 3' RARE. Mutation of this element virtually abolished transgene expression in the CNS. Analysis of permanent transgenic lines showed that this element was required not only for the initiation but also for the maintenance of Hoxd4 expression in the neural tube. In addition, this element is required for the Hoxd4 response to retinoic acid (RA). The second regulatory element we identified (TTTTCTG) is 2 bp downstream to the 3' RARE. It resembles a CDX binding site, but failed to interact with human CDX1 protein. Mutation of this site posteriorized transgene expression in the CNS. Although other regions required for murine Hoxd4 expression in the CNS were also mapped, our results suggest that Hoxd4 lacks an autoregulatory element (ARE). This is in contrast to the regulation of Hoxb4, where expression is initiated by the conserved RARE and subsequently maintained by an ARE. Together with other findings, this suggests that Hox genes sharing similar expression pattern may be regulated in a diverged manner.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Featherstone, Mark S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505218r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d830h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s644b"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Deactivation of Pb-contaminated sphalerite by polyphosphate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rashchi, Fereshteh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Activation of sphalerite by lead ions in the presence of ethyl xanthate was investigated by microflotation, zeta potential measurements, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and extraction by ethylenediaminetetraacetate (EDTA). The source of lead, either from solution or contact with galena particles, proved immaterial. From EDTA extraction data flotation response was determined as a function of surface concentration of Pb ([Pb]surf, mg/cm2). A critical [Pb]surf ≃ 0.5 x 10-4 mg/cm2 causing activation was estimated. By combining with a Pb ion production model from the literature, the possibility of Pb activation for an ore of given Pb grade was explored. Ores with as little as 0.1% Pb are candidates for accidental activation. A mechanism of lead interaction is proposed: at weakly acidic to mildly alkaline conditions Pb2+ and PbOH+ adsorb on sphalerite and react with xanthate to form PbX2 and Pb(OH)X; at high pH, hydrophilic Pb(OH)2(s) precipitates depress flotation. Various candidate deactivators were compared using microflotation. The reagents were diethylenetriamine (DETA), sodium bicarbonate (NaHCO3), silica sol (SS), sodium phosphate (Na3PO4·12H 2O) and sodium polyphosphate (NaPO3)n. The latter had the strongest effect and was selected for detailed study. The mechanism of polyphosphate action was investigated by SEM and XPS. The results show that polyphosphate acted to remove Pb ("clean") from the sphalerite by forming soluble complexes. The polyphosphate (PP) to lead (Pb) ratio in the complexes was determined from conductometric titration of lead nitrate vs. polyphosphate. It was found that initially a precipitate formed with PP/Pb of 1/3. The precipitate dissolved in excess polyphosphate, resulting in a variety of complexes with PP/Pb of 1/2, 1/1, 3/2, 2/1, and 3/1. Knowing the amount of Pb to be removed and taking the lowest PP/Pb ratio, 1/2, the quantity of polyphosphate required to solubilize the Pb can be calculated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Finch, J. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m5736.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s644b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km36j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of the rat Tal a-tubulin gene promoter</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rogers, David Howard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mature nervous system is composed largely of two cell types, glial cells and postmitotic neurons. All postmitotic neurons of the mature nervous system derive from proliferating neural precursor cells. To generate a neuron, a precursor must cease dividing and express a number of genes that are characteristic of the neuronal phenotype. How these changes in cell behaviour and phenotype are brought about in mammals is still poorly understood. This thesis describes experiments that were designed to explore cell intrinsic mechanisms regulating the generation of neurons from neural precursor cells. Specifically, the regulatory region of the rat Talpha1 alpha-tubulin gene, which encodes an isoform of alpha-tubulin expressed in neurons throughout the nervous system immediately following cell cycle exit, was analyzed to identify DNA sequences directing early neuronal gene expression. A novel 10-nucleotide regulatory sequence, named the neuronal restriction element (NRE), has been identified. In the context of the Talpha1 gene, the NRE inhibits precocious expression in neural precursor cells. Interestingly, the NRE is conserved in the alpha-1 alpha-tubulin gene and is found in a number of neural genes expressed widely and early in development. As such, the NRE may affect the onset time of a battery of neuronal genes and modulate the timing of neuronal differentiation. In vitro , the NRE binds Su(H), a highly conserved transcription factor involved in the repression of neuronal differentiation. A second novel regulatory element has been identified, the forebrain response element (FRE), which acts to enhance gene expression specifically in the neocortex. The FRE overlaps the NRE and also contains a conserved 30-nucleotide sequence constituting a putative homeodomain recognition sequence. We speculate that the FRE consists of two subelements that act synergistically to promote gene expression in newborn and mature neocortical neurons.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Miller, Freda D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0202.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km36j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abn9998354"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Conflict resolution strategies of children with depressive symptomalology in hypothetical and observational peer conflict</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rinaldi, Christina M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Children with depressive symptomatology are at a higher risk for experiencing social functioning difficulties (Stark et al., 1996). The research reviewed suggests a connection between type of social problem-solving strategies employed by children and levels of depressive symptomatology. Participants were grade four, five, and six students (n = 315), who were divided into a depressive symptomatology (DS) group (n = 57) and a nondepressed (NONDEP) group (n = 57). Using Felner, Lease, and Phillips' (1990) quadripartite model of social competence as a theoretical guide, the present study was conducted to compare children with and without depressive symptomatology on: (a) strategies and goals as assessed in hypothetical conflict situations; (b) types of conflict resolution strategies employed in observed conflict situations; (c) peer rated social behaviours (aggressive, isolated, sociable); (d) self-perceptions of social conflict resolution efficacy; and (e) strategies and goals as assessed in both hypothetical and actual conflict situations by gender. Results indicated that the two groups differed on the types of conflict resolution strategies but not conflict goals chosen in hypothetical situations. The two groups did not differ in the amount of solutions generated to conflict situations, but in the type of solutions, and in the effectiveness of solutions generated. In observed dyadic exchanges, the DS group employed more destructive strategies than the NONDEP group. Boys and girls differed in the types of strategies and goals chosen in response to hypothetical conflict. Significant interactions between DS group and gender emerged. Implications for assessment and interventions are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Heath, Nancy L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96022511.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998354</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Depression in children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conflict management</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mx08p"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The design, layout, and characterization of VLSI optoelectronic chips for free-space optical interconnects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rolston, David Robert Cameron</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The design and testing of very-large-scale-integrated optoelectronic (VLSI-OE) microchips will be described in the context of a free-space optical backplane system. The optical backplane has the potential for providing an enormous amount of bandwidth for telecommunication switching systems and massively parallel computing machines. A free-space optical backplane uses optical design techniques to relay beams of light from the surface of one microchip to the surface of another. By using light to interconnect microchips, the problems associated with high-speed electronic interconnects are avoided. By exploiting the 2-dimensional surface area of the microchips, large numbers of parallel optical interconnections are possible using minute optoelectronic devices patterned on the surface of the chips. By using appropriate optical designs and microchip layouts, massively parallel high-bandwidth interconnects can be implemented within a volume comparable with standard electronic interconnects such as buses and backplanes. This thesis will begin by describing a specific VLSI-OE chip architecture as well as two free-space optical designs used to interconnect VLSI-OE chips. Details of the design and layout of four separate VLSI-OE chips will then be given and the results of optical and electrical testing of these chips will follow. Finally, the topic of global synchronization will then be considered. Synchronization among many VLSI-OE chips in a multiple-node system requires special attention. A novel approach of providing synchronized clock signals to a multitude of distance points will be discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Plant, David V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz841.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx08p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw146"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of soil pH on heavy metal transport in the vadose zone</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elzahabi, Malak</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research study provides the experimental information necessary for numerical analyses, structured to account for vadose zone transport of heavy metals. Particular attention is payed to the effect of degree of saturation, the presence of carbonate, soil pH and heavy metals concentrations. In addition, attention is directed to an evaluation of the coupled solute-water transport mechanisms. A method that fully describes the coupling effects on the transport coefficient based on experimental evidence provides successful predictions of the rate of transport of the heavy metals through the unsaturated soil in a pH-controlled environment. In the experimental part of this research, one dimensional solute and moisture flow (leaching) tests, using different heavy metal permeants, were conducted on an unsaturated illitic soil at varying pH values. Experimental results showed that the retention and migration of heavy metals are highly dependent on the soil pH, the presence of carbonates, the degree of saturation, the influent concentration and the time duration. At high soil pH and carbonate content, heavy metals were retained in the soils if the buffering capacity was high enough to resist the acidic input solution, and sorption processes will prevail in the carbonate phase. As the soil pH decreases, the dissolution of carbonates increases and cation exchange capacity becomes the more dominant process in heavy metals retention. The numerical study developed a model to analyse and predict the transport of the contaminant in unsaturated clayey soils in which some of the species were adsorbed on clay particles surfaces. The proposed mathematical model was based on the postulates of irreversible thermodynamics and is also applicable in a one-dimensional case. In this model, various solute transport mechanisms such as diffusion and sorption were considered. Results indicated that the diffusion coefficient is necessary to provide a good agreement between the experimentally measured and the theoretically predicted values of contaminant transport through the soil. The numerical results of the coupled solute and moisture equations showed that the transport coefficients strongly and accurately depend on solute and volumetric content. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong, R. N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d5926.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw146</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Environmental Sciences</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161793f"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Accuracy control in the optimization of microwave devices by finite element methods</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gavrilovic, Milorad Minya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Computational optimization methods have long been used to aid the design of microwave devices. Cost functions are commonly defined to be functions of S-parameters that are often unavailable analytically. With the ever-increasing speed of computer processors, it is becoming standard practice for designers to use field-based computer-aided design tools as "black boxes" to calculate as accurately as possible the cost functions for such devices. However, demanding high accuracy from every cost function evaluation (CFE) of the optimization can lead to excessive computational costs. These costs can be reduced by two means: use a black box that calculates the gradient of the cost function very cheaply and vary the accuracy of CFEs throughout the optimization. This thesis presents a system for automatically controlling the accuracy throughout an optimization. A gradient-based, constrained optimizer is combined with a 2-D finite element p-adaptive scheme that calculates the gradient at a low cost. The accuracy of a CFE is controlled through a link from the optimization to adaption. The accuracy link is based on the last computed gradient of the cost function and serves as an error tolerance used to terminate the adaption. A new error estimator is developed to assess accurately the error in the gradient, used for the termination. Three H-plane, rectangular waveguide test cases are used for validation: a waveguide T-junction with inductive post; a miter bend with dielectric column; a two-cavity, iris coupled filter. Numerical tests show that the system is very effective in reducing the computational costs of an optimization without sacrificing the accuracy of the final answer. Compared to an optimization system with no link to the adaption, there is a speed-up in computation by at least an order of magnitude for each problem.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webb, J. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b2751.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161793f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149r33k"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A model for improving emergency services of Hospital Universitario San Vicente de Paul, Medellin-Colombia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>González Echeverri, Germán</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Colombia is a developing country with high mortality rates from trauma. The Valle de Aburra region centred around the city of Medellin has particularly high rates of intentional trauma. Improving emergency medical services could reduce mortality rates. At the time of this investigation, there was no pre-hospital emergency care services in the Valle de Aburra. Thus, this thesis examines predictors of mortality from a case series of 1395 persons presenting to the Emergency department of the Hospital Universitario San Vicente de Paul (HUSVP). Overall mortality for this series was 9.31% and 37.5% of these deaths were retrospectively identified as preventable. Mortality for injuries involving the central nervous system (CNS) was higher at 14.4%. Using the TRISS method, higher than expected death rates were noted from pedestrian-motor vehicle incidents and trauma associated with firearms use. Determinants of mortality and length of stay were identified using logistic regression. These included factors associated with the mechanism and site of injury and also with the process of care, both pre-hospital and in-hospital. Based on these identified determinants, policies for integrated pre-hospital and hospital emergency care in the Valle de Aburra can be developed. Regionalizing these services could be expected to reduce both mortality rates and preventable deaths.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Battista, Renaldo N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838224b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r33k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c20w"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Early environmental regulation of adult stress responses and maternal care</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Francis, Darlene Deborah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Variations in maternal care permanently alter the expression of behavioral and endocrine responses to stress. Thus, in the rat, increased levels of maternal licking and grooming over the first week of life are associated with decreased hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal and behavioural responses to stress in the offspring in adulthood. Interestingly, such variations in maternal care are associated with individual differences in the neurochemistry and fearfulness of the dams themselves. Adult female rats which are more fearful exhibit less licking and grooming of their pups than do less fearful mothers. These more fearful females also possess greater levels of corticotropin-releasing hormone (CRH) receptors in the amygdala and the locus coeruleus. Oxytocin receptor expression is also different in these animals. The females which exhibit greater levels of licking and grooming of their pups have more oxytocin receptors in the medial preoptic area (MPOA) as well as the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis (BNST). The differences in maternal behavior may constitute a mechanism for the non-genomic, transgenerational transmission of fearfulness from parent to the offspring. The results of these thesis studies support this idea and also demonstrate that environmental events during early development that decrease fearfulness can serve to break the cycle of transmission.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meaney, Michael</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd44g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c20w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Behavioral</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429b86h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inflectional morphology and second language learning systems : an investigation of the dual-mechanism model and L2 morphology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murphy, Victoria A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pinker and Prince (1988, 1994) propose that there are two separate systems involved in linguistic representation and processing; one system is rule-governed, and incorporates symbolic hierarchical linguistic representations, the other is associative with linguistic information represented in a more distributed fashion. One particular linguistic feature of English said to exemplify the principles of this dual-mechanism model is inflectional morphology. Pinker and Prince (1988; 1994) present a range of evidence showing that native speakers of English process regular inflectional items in ways that are both quantitatively and qualitatively different from irregular inflectional items. This dual-mechanism model has been largely investigated within the context of first language (L1) learning, and has received considerable support from investigations using a number of different research paradigms. Nonetheless, there have been a number of serious criticisms in that the apparent behavioural distinctions between regular and irregular inflectional items can be supported by an alternative associative system (Elman, Bates, Johnson, Karmiloff-Smith, Parisi &amp; Plunkett, 1996). The research presented in this dissertation investigates how knowledge of second language (L2) inflectional morphology might be processed and represented. The research is grounded within the theoretical framework provided by the dual-mechanism model and evaluates whether the claims and assumptions of this model are relevant to how L2 learners process, represent and learn about inflectional morphology. Three experiments are presented which address the issues of: compounding with regular and irregular noun plurals (Experiment 1); past tense generalization with regular and irregular verbs (Experiment 2); and finally, the development of knowledge of a new inflectional paradigm (Old English noun plurals, Experiment 3). Each of these experiments provides findings which are difficult for the dual-mechanism model</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Spada, Nina</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2040832.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429b86h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Inflection</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021g932"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"In the forest is our money" : the changing role of commercial extraction in Tawahka livelihoods, Eastern Honduras</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McSweeney, Kendra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The uneven success of tropical forest product marketing initiatives over the past decade has illuminated our poor understanding of forest peasant livelihood systems. This dissertation explores how , when and why peoples living within biodiverse tropical forests turn to the sale of forest products to meet their needs over time, through a detailed examination of commercial forest extraction by the Tawahka Sumu (pop. 1,000) of the Mosquitia region, eastern Honduras. The study uses a multi-method, multi-scalar approach that incorporates conceptual insights from cultural ecology, agricultural economics, and peasant studies. A detailed household census (n = 116, or 88% of Tawahka households in 1998) was used to establish patterns of reliance on commercial extraction. As a group, the Tawahka were found to manage a diverse market income portfolio in which commercial extraction contributed some 18% in 1997--98 (US$23/capita). At the household level, however, reliance on the extractive sector varied from 0--93%. Analysis of multi-year income data suggests that households move easily into, and out of, the sector. Statistical analysis indicates that the most important determinants of this sporadic engagement are unanticipated household-level calamities (illness, crop shortfall). This ex post insurance function of commercial extraction was also demonstrated over longer time scales by a detailed historical analysis of the Mosquitia's dugout canoe trade, which revealed that the sale of dugout canoes has provided local peoples with an important fall-back during periods of economic recession. Discussion highlights the dynamism of peasant livelihoods, in which forest product sale is seen as only one response to householders' changing needs over both the lifecycle of the household and larger economic cycles in the region. The modern dynamics of the canoe trade appear to have changed little over two centuries, emphasizing the little-recognized continuity within native exchange systems despite market penetration and monetization. During the 1990s, the Tawahka sold half of the approximately 500 canoes they made, mainly to Miskito buyers. The future of canoe commerce is threatened by pressures on the forests of the newly-created Tawahka Asangni Biosphere Reserve, including high internal growth rates, ladino colonization, and agricultural reorganization in the wake of Hurricane Mitch. The implications of the study's findings to conservation and development initiatives in the neotropics are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Coomes, O. T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0968786.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g932</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Forests and forestry -- Honduras</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sumo Indians -- Honduras</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g907j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Women and children in context : Laura Muntz and representation of maternity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mulley, Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with several aspects of the life and work of the Canadian painter Laura Muntz (1860--1930). It examines in particular Muntz's images of women and children both within the cultural themes and ideologies of the period and from the perspective of contemporary twentieth-century theories of gender. The introduction and literature review outline the broad issues surrounding the artist in her time and present a summary of her critical fortunes in Canadian art historical literature. Chapter one provides a discussion of Muntz's life and artistic production between 1860 and 1898, the year in which she returned to Toronto after a decade of study and work in Europe. The following two chapters are conceived as case studies of single paintings, observed in the context of various discourses that surround them. Chapter two analyses Muntz's Madonna and Child in terms of hereditarian theories, eugenics, maternal feminism and the Canadian social purity movement and considers the broader, psychological implications of gender, specifically in the fin-de-siecle associations of femininity and death. Chapter three examines the imagery in Muntz's Protection with reference to North American Symbolist painters and their relationship to the constructs of the feminine ideal. As a whole, the thesis elucidates the complex layers of meaning that Muntz's images of women and children contributed to the popular conceptions of femininity and motherhood current in her time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ross, Christine</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b06f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g907j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children in art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Painting, Canadian -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Painting, Canadian -- 19th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in art</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muntz, Laura -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Painters -- Canada -- Biography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1g05fd45r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gabrielle Roy épistolière : la correspondance avec Marcel Carbotte</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcotte, Sophie, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gabrielle Roy kept up, throughout her literary life, a regular correspondence with relatives, friends, business relations and readers: to date, more than 2000 letters have been preserved in different archive collections. The 482 letters she wrote to her husband, Doctor Marcel Carbotte, between 1947 and 1979, form the largest subset of the correspondence; a critical edition of these hitherto unpublished letters is presented in the second part of the thesis. Surprisingly, the correspondence contains few reflexions of an aesthetic nature, and few explicit traces of the novelist's published work, apart from occasional references to the texts she is working on at the moment she is writing to Marcel. Instead, it is the details of her day-to-day life that Roy describes most abundantly. In the first part of the thesis, we study the letters to Marcel in the light of a possible connection with Roy's canonical work: we start by examining the link between the letter and autobiographical genre; we then show that the letters to Marcel can be read as a personal diary; finally, we suggest that the "autobiographical turn" taken by Roy in both her published work and her letters to Marcel indicates that the letters form part of the same system as the autobiographical works.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ricard, Francois</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Everett, Jane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r021b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd45r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Roy, Gabrielle, 1909- -- Correspondence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carbotte, Marcel -- Correspondence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women authors, French-Canadian -- Québec (Province) -- Correspondence</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>