<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289j41v"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dependability-oriented model-driven requirements engineering for reactive systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mustafiz, Sadaf</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Errors made during requirements development of dependable systems are very expensive to fix later in the lifecycle, and can result in minor to catastrophic failures. Discovering and documenting potential abnormal situations and irregular user behavior that can interrupt normal system interaction is of tremendous importance in the context of dependable systems development. Exceptions that are not identified during requirements elicitation might eventually lead to an incomplete system specification during analysis, and ultimately to an implementation that lacks certain functionality, or even behaves in an unreliable way. This thesis introduces a model-driven requirement development process that systematically guides the developer to consider reliability and safety concerns of dependable reactive systems. Our Dependability-Oriented Requirements Engineering Process (DREP) comprises of five phases: requirements elicitation, requirements specification, dependability assessment, dependability-based refinement, and requirements summary. Our approach extends use case-based elicitation with ideas from the exception handling world. It leads the developer to explore exceptional situations arising in the environment that change user goals and service-related exceptional situations that threaten to fail user goals. The process requires the developer to specify means that detect such situations, to define the recovery measures that attempt to continue to provide service in a dependable manner, to offer degraded services where applicable or to ensure system and user safety. The need for exceptional modes of operation is also taken into account. The notions of dependability are integrated in activity diagrams and communication diagrams, which are used as specification models. We also propose a probabilistic extension of statecharts to formally model the interaction requirements defined in the use cases. The formalism, DA-Charts, allows a modeller to use success and failure probabilities to model the unreliable behaviour of the environment. Subsequently, the model can be probabilistically analyzed to determine achievable reliability and safety of the system interactions. A visual modelling environment for DA-Charts supporting automatic probability analysis has been implemented. We show that the proposed methodology leads to notable improvement in system dependability by applying our work to three case studies: the Elevator Control System, the 407 Express Toll Route System, and the Crisis Management System.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Lorsque l'on développe des systèmes fiables, les erreurs ou oublis qui pourraient éventuellement se glisser dans la spécification du système peuvent avoir des conséquences néfastes, et pas seulement du point de vue monétaire. Il est par conséquent impératif de découvrir et d'analyser toute situation anormale ou comportement irrégulier d'un utilisateur du système qui pourrait interrompre le fonctionnement et les interactions habituelles du système. Une telle exception, qui n'aurait pas été découverte pendant la phase d'analyse des besoins, produirait une spécification de l'application à développer contenant des lacunes, ce qui, à la fin, causerait une implémentation de l'application à laquelle il manquerait des fonctionnalitées, ou qui se comporterait d'une manière peu fiable. Cette thèse présente un processus de développement orienté modèle qui mène le développeur à prêter une attention particulière à la sûreté et à la fiabilité du système en développement. Notre approche, nommée DREP, est constituée de cinq phases: la découverte des besoins, la spécification des besoins, l'évaluation de la fiabilité, le raffinement, et le résumé des besoins. Notre phase de découverte des besoins se base sur les cas d'utilisation. Elle mène le développeur à considérer des situations exceptionnelles qui pourraient surgir dans l'environnement et changer les buts des utilisateurs du système. Le développeur est également poussé à réfléchir aux situations qui pourrait empêcher le système de fournir un service avec succès. Dans ces cas, DREP demande au développeur de spécifier les démarches à suivre pour traiter cette situation, si possible en continuant à fournir le service demandé, ou à défaut, en fournissant un service diminué, ou simplement  en s'assurent que le système s'arrête sans causer de dommage. DREP intègre également la notion de modes exceptionnels d'opération du système. DREP propose des extensions au diagrammes d'activités et de communication d'UML pour permettre au développeur d'exprimer la fiabilité dans les modèles de spécification du système. Une extension des diagrammes d'états intégrant les probabilités permet de modéliser les pannes qui pourraient surgir dans l'environnement. Un outil d'analyse permet ensuite de déterminer la sûreté et la fiabilité atteignable du système. On démontre que notre approche génère des spécifications de systèmes plus fiables avec trois cas d'études: un contrôleur d'ascenseur, un système de collecte de payage d'autoroute, et un système de gestion de crises.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jorg Andreas Kienzle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rx14w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289j41v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j142g"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Generalized linear mixed models for binary outcome data with a low proportion of occurrences</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beauchamp, Marie-Eve</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many studies in epidemiology and other fields such as econometrics and social sciences give rise to correlated outcome data (e.g., longitudinal studies, meta-analyses, and multi-centre studies). Parameter estimation of generalized linear mixed models (GLMMs), which are frequently used to perform inference on correlated binary outcomes, is complicated by intractable integrals in the marginal likelihood. Penalized quasi-likelihood (PQL) and maximum likelihood estimation in conjunction with numerical integration via adaptive Gauss-Hermite quadrature (AGHQ) are estimation methods that are commonly used in practice. However, the assessment of the performance of these estimation methods in settings found in practice is incomplete, particularly for binary outcome data with a low proportion of occurrences. To begin with, I considered graphical representations of the distributions of cluster-specific log odds of outcome ensuing from random intercepts logistic models (RILMs) converted to the probability scale with the inverse logit transformation. RILMs are special cases of GLMMs. These representations are helpful to comprehend the implications of RILM parameter values for the distributions of cluster-specific probabilities of outcome. The correspondence of these distributions with beta distributions, also used for random effects models for binary outcomes, was graphically assessed and a generally good agreement was found. Afterwards, I evaluated via a simulation study the performance of the PQL and AGHQ methods in several realistic settings of binary outcome data with a low proportion of occurrences. Different features determining the number of occurrences were considered (number of clusters, cluster size, and probabilities of outcome). The AGHQ method produced nearly unbiased fixed effects estimates, even in challenging settings with low proportions of occurrences or a small sample size, but mean square errors tended to be larger than with PQL for small datasets. Both methods produced biased variance component estimates when the number of clusters was moderate, especially with rarer occurrences. Finally, through further analysis of the simulation results, I assessed if a number of indicators quantifying different aspects of the rarity of the events in a dataset, all measurable in practice, could explain patterns of bias in the parameter estimates. The selected rarity indicators quantify the overall number of events and their distribution across the clusters.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Plusieurs études en épidémiologie et autres domaines, tels que les sciences sociales, donnent lieu à des données de réponse corrélées (par exemple, les études longitudinales et multi-centres). L'estimation des paramètres des modèles linéaires généralisés mixtes (MLGM), souvent utilisés pour les données de réponse corrélées, est compliquée par des intégrales sans solution analytique dans la fonction de vraisemblance marginale. La méthode de quasi-vraisemblance pénalisée (QVP) et l'estimation par la maximisation de la vraisemblance conjointement avec la technique d'intégration numérique de quadrature Gauss-Hermite adaptée (QGHA) sont souvent utilisées. Cependant, l'évaluation de la performance de ces méthodes en pratique est incomplète, en particulier pour les données de réponse binaires avec faible proportion d'événements. Dans un premier temps, j'ai considéré la représentation graphique de distributions du logarithme de la cote spécifique à chaque groupe résultant de modèles logistiques avec intercepts aléatoires (MLIA) transformées à l'échelle des probabilités avec la transformation logit inversée. Les MLIA sont des cas particuliers des MLGM. Ces représentations sont utiles pour comprendre les implications des valeurs des paramètres sur la distribution de la probabilité de réponse spécifique à chaque groupe. La correspondance avec la loi bêta a été évaluée graphiquement et une bonne concordance fut observée. Par la suite, j'ai évalué avec une étude de simulations la performance des méthodes QVP et QGHA pour plusieurs cas réalistes de données de réponse binaires avec faible proportion d'événements. Différentes caractéristiques déterminant le nombre d'événements furent considérées (nombre et taille des groupes et probabilités d'événement). La méthode QGHA a produit des valeurs estimées presque sans biais, même dans des situations avec faible proportion d'événements ou petite taille d'échantillon, mais les erreurs quadratiques moyennes étaient souvent plus élevées qu'avec la méthode QVP pour les petits échantillons. Les deux méthodes ont produit des valeurs estimées biaisées pour la composante de variance lorsque le nombre de groupes était modéré, particulièrement lorsque les événements étaient rares. Finalement, j'ai évalué si un nombre d'indicateurs de rareté des événements, tous mesurables en pratique pour un jeu de données, pouvaient expliquer le biais dans les valeurs estimées des paramètres. Les indicateurs sélectionnés quantifient le nombre total d'événements et leur distribution dans les groupes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James Anthony Hanley</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Robert William Platt</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn55n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j142g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mf94h"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ions released from metal-on-metal hip implants: «in vitro» and «in vivo» investigations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tkaczyk, Cathy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Studies have shown that Co and Cr particles and ions can enter the bloodstream and accumulate in tissues and organs of patients after metal-on-metal (MM) total hip arthroplasty (THA). These ions can generate reactive oxygen species (ROS) that can be deleterious for cells. We first assessed the biological effects of Cr(VI), Co(II), and Cr(III) by testing their effect on antioxidant enzymes (SODs, CAT, GPx, HO-1) that represent a primary defense system against ROS. We demonstrated that Cr(VI) induced the protein expression (translation) of antioxidant enzymes, whereas it had no effect on the mRNA expression (transcription). Co(II) induced the expression of both protein and mRNA of HO-1 only. Cr(III) had no effect on the activity of these enzymes. We then suggested that a difference in molecular structure may be at the origin of their differential effects and showed that Cr(III) can form precipitable complexes, whereas Co(II) and Cr(VI) cannot form complexes in the same experimental conditions. These Cr(III) complexes, formed in simulated-physiological fluids, were constituted by an organic phase (amino acids, phosphate) tangled with an inorganic phase (Cr, Ca, Na). Interestingly, these Cr(III) complexes interacted only with albumin in presence of fetal bovine serum, whereas they interacted with 8 different human serum proteins in presence of human serum. The interaction of Cr(III) complexes with serum proteins affect their internalization by macrophages, complexes formed with human serum being more easily internalized than those bound to bovine proteins. Lastly, results suggested that the levels of Co and Cr ions in patients with MM THA are not sufficient to induce significant oxidative stress in the blood of these patients, bringing optimism over concern for the long term biological effects of Co and Cr ions released from metal-metal bearings. In conclusion, this thesis gives very valuable information on the biological effects of Cr and Co ions and gives insight i</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>De nombreuses études ont montré que les particules et ions métalliques (Cr(III), Co(II) et Cr(VI)) générés par l'usure de prothèses de hanche métalliques (PHM) se retrouvent dans le flux sanguin des patients et s'accumulent également dans leurs tissus et leurs organes. Ces ions peuvent génèrer des radicaux libres qui peuvent à leur tour être nocifs pour la cellule. Nous avons déterminé les effets de ces ions sur les enzymes antioxidantes (SODs, CAT, GPx, HO-1) qui représentent la première ligne de défense cellulaire contre les radicaux libres. Nos travaux ont révélé que le Cr(VI) induit l'expression de ces protéines (traduction) mais non l'expression de leur ARNm (transcription). Le Co(II) induit l'expression de la proteine et de l'ARNm de HO-1 seulement alors que le Cr(III) n'a aucun effet sur l'expression de ces enzymes. Nous avons par la suite suggéré, que la structure moléculaire de ces ions pouvait avoir une influence sur leurs différents effets. Les résultats ont montré que le Cr(III) formait des complexes constitués d'une partie organique (acides aminés et phosphates) et d'une partie inorganique (Cr, calcium et sodium), alors que ni le Co(II), ni le Cr(VI) ne formaient de complexes dans les mêmes conditions expérimentales. En présence de sérum bovin fétal, les complexes de Cr(III) pouvent se lier seulement à l'albumine, alors qu'en présence de sérum humain, ces mêmes complexes intéragissent avec 8 protéines de nature differente. Cette intéraction avec les protéines humaines semble augmenter l'internalisation des complexes par les macrophages. Finalement, les résultats démontrent que la concentration d'ions Co et Cr présents dans le sang de patients portant une PHM est insuffisante pour induire un stress oxydant et apportent un souffle optimiste sur les effets à long terme des ions métalliques chez les patients. Dans son ensemble ce projet apporte de nouveaux éléments de connaissances sur les effets biologiq</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Olga Huk-Papanastasiou</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Maryam Tabrizian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903037b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mf94h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fx334"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quantitative architectonic analysis of the ventromedial and orbital frontal cortex in the human and the Macaque monkey brain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mackey, M Scott</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Significant discrepancies between the various published architectonic parcellations of the ventromedial and orbital frontal cortex of the human and the macaque monkey brains present a formidable obstacle for research directed at understanding the normal cognitive function of this region in the healthy brain and its involvement in a spectrum of psychiatric diseases. The present thesis addresses this problem by describing a revised parcellation of the ventromedial and orbital frontal cortex based upon quantitative measurements of cortical architectonic features which distinguish between spatially discrete areas in the human brain and between comparable areas in the macaque monkey brain. To facilitate the communication of results within the general neuroscience community, the boundaries of the parcellated areas will be identified by stereotactic coordinates and in terms of their relation to the sulcal morphology of the cortex. Considerable emphasis is placed on describing the method of sampling the cortical architecture developed as a part of this thesis and designed specifically to measure features of the cortical architecture which can serve in cross species comparisons.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il existe des anomalies importantes publiées entre les parcellisations architectoniques du cortex frontal ventromedial, orbital humain, et celui des singes macaques. Cela présente un défi interessant pour les chercheurs qui tentent de comprendre la fonction cognitive normale de cette région dans le cerveau sain, ainsi que son rôle dans un éventail de maladies psychiatriques. Cette thèse aborde ce problème en décrivant une parcellisation révisée du cortex frontal ventromedial et orbital. Elle se base sur des mesures quantitatives de caractéristiques architectoniques corticales, tout en distinguant entre les régions de l'espace discret  du cerveau humain et les régions comparables dans le cerveau du singe macaque. Pour faciliter la divulgation des résultats, au sein de la communauté générale des neurosciences, les frontières des régions parcellés seront identifiées par leurs coordonnées stéréotactiques et leurs relations avec la morphologie sulcale du cortex. Il est à noter qu'un accent particulier est mis sur la description de la méthode d'échantillonnage de l'architecture corticale. Cette méthode, partie intégrale de la thèse, est concue spécifiquement pour mesurer les caractéristiques de l'architecture corticale et peut servir à faire des comparaisons hétérospécifiques entre espèce.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michalakis Petrides</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc655.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx334</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xf71x"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression, regulation and modulation of Fas Ligand during T lymphocyte activation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Drury, Gillian Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les maladies auto-immunes découlent d'une incapacité d'éliminer les lymphocytes T qui reconnaissent l'hôte. En général, l'apoptose suit lors qu'un lymphocyte T devient activé ou répond aux peptides dérivés de l'hôte. Une des molécules principales qui induit l'apoptose dans les lymphocytes T est une protéine membranaire nommée Fas ligand qui se lie au récepteur Fas pour activer la cascade de caspases ce qui entraine la mort cellulaire. En conséquence, la production de Fas ligand est strictement contrôlée pour entretenir l'homéostase immunitaire. HuR est une protéine qui lie l'ARN qui est important pour les fonctions des lymphocytes T. HuR agit par des effets post-transcriptionels sur les ARNm de plusieurs cytokines par stabilisation, relocalisation et l'efficacité de traduction. HuR promeut ses fonctions en liant des régions riches en AU dans les parties non-traduites des ARNm. Nous démontrons que Fas ligand est régulé de façon post-transcriptionel par HuR via des régions AU riches et U riches, et nous examinons dans quels contextes cette régulation est importante.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Auto-immune diseases stem from an inability to eliminate immune cells that react to "self" peptides.  In particular, when T lymphocytes react to self peptides, or become activated, they undergo elimination in a process of programmed cell death or apoptosis.  In T lymphocytes one of the key effectors of apoptosis is a membrane protein, Fas ligand, since it engages Fas, the caspase cascade, and ultimately cell death.  Therefore the biosynthesis of Fas ligand is tightly controlled to maintain immune homeostasis.  HuR is an RNA binding protein that has been shown to have an important role in all aspects of T lymphocyte maturation and function. HuR is known to be important in the posttranscriptional regulation of many cytokines by stabilizing, relocalizing and promoting the translation of their mRNAs.  The effects of HuR are mediated through binding to AU rich elements in the untranslated regions of these mRNAs.  We find that HuR posttranscriptionally regulates Fas ligand through AU rich and U rich motifs in its mRNA and explore the contexts in which this regulation is important.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Imed Eddine Gallouzi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vt80m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xf71x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hg028"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Organizing heterodoxies : the Israeli Committee Against House Demolition and the Israeli radical left, 1997-2000</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goldberg, Avrum</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Based on nineteen months of ethnographic field research in  Israel/Palestine (including participant observation and in-depth interviews), this  study presents an analysis of the Israeli Committee Against House Demolition  (ICAHD). First formed in 1997, it is a coalition of social movement organizations  (SMOs) in the Israeli radical left peace and human rights movement. This project  traces significant organizational, and wider movement, dynamics from the time of  ICAHD's inception until the outbreak of the second Palestinian Intifada in September  2000. While countless scholars investigate historical and contemporary  aspects of the political conflict between Israelis and Palestinians, relatively  little research attention is directed towards the efforts of Israeli and Palestinian  activists towards conflict resolution. Following a brief description of the  development of the Israeli peace movement, this study identifies and analyzes  several mobilization issues relevant to organized activist forces in the Israeli  radical movement in the final years of the Oslo peace process. Building on recent collective action theories, this dissertation  endorses analytical openness to the structuralist, rationalist, and culturalist  dynamics of contentious politics. ICAHD members, as well as its organizational  constituencies, are characterized by wide ideological and strategic heterogeneity,  and in the first three years of its existence, this informal movement organization  faced several overlapping strategic dilemmas. Investigating the historical and  day-to-day dynamics of the committee, this study analyses various factors that  influenced the strategic choices individual, and teams of, activists made during  multiple types of mobilizations. By examining the impact of ICAHD's constituencies  on how core leaders and activists engaged with dilemmas of organizational structure,  strategic vision, inter-organizational alliances, mobilizing and funding  opportunities, and overall goal selection, this dissertation identifies mechanisms  (structural, organizational and cultural) that affected strategic decisions  regarding mobilization, and outcomes of contentious politics. The study concludes with a discussion of the relevance of its  findings for the sociological study of collective protest. It suggests the extension  of future research on these themes in more transnational and macro-theoretical  directions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx51h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg028</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Israel -- Politics and government -- 1993-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peace movements -- Israel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Israeli Committee Against House Demolitions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848r037"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mass diplomacy : foreign policy in the global information age</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pahlavi, Pierre Cyril Cyrus Teymour</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A sophisticated and high tech form of state-to-foreign  population diplomacy based on the use of the latest communication technologies has  developed rapidly in recent years and has acquired an increasingly important  position within a significant number of foreign affairs systems. Pioneered by the  heavyweights of the international stage, the phenomenon has spread rapidly to  secondary powers and is progressively extending itself to varying degrees to all  states around the globe. This thesis grapples with the enigma raised by the brisk  re-emergence of this foreign policy concentration by attempting to understand the  reasons behind both the quantitative increase in public diplomacy activities and the  qualitative evolution of these activities in terms of planning, organisation and  implementation. The first argument that this thesis broaches is that the sudden  growth of public diplomacy is the result of the shift to a new phase of the  information revolution (necessary enabling force) which has been amplified by  contingent factors: the explosion of global terrorism (accelerator) and the  perception of leaders and foreign policy makers of this new environment (prism). The  second argument is that, beyond quantitative growth, the new operational context  born of the advent of the global information society provoked a qualitative  evolution of the public diplomacy inherited from the Cold War towards what is today  mass diplomacy. The result is the appearance of a market driven diplomacy employing  persuasive techniques borrowed from the world of public relations and marketing. The  new diplomacy is an entrepreneurial diplomacy that limits governmental leadership to  a necessary minimum and encourages the participation of private and foreign  sub-contractors. It is also a cyber-space diplomacy equipped with new diplomatic  instruments such as high-resolution satellite imagery, high-speed networks, digital  broadcasting and other marvels of the late twentieth cen</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dc98z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r037</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mass media and propaganda</dc:subject><dc:subject>Digital communications -- Political aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Technology and state</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gn66d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploring population structure and migration with surnames : Quebec, 1621-1900</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Henry, Kevin A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research uses isonymy (same-surname) methods and models to  examine the population structure and migratory history of Quebec, Canada. Through a  case study using 1765 and 1881 census and marriage records from 1621-1900, I explore  the accuracy of sources as well as develop, test and apply different statistical  methods, and experiment with mapping techniques that reveal paths and patterns of  French Canadian surnames. Each investigation explores and evaluates a particular  method. I noted that multivariate methods, including cluster analysis, relevance  networks, and correspondence analysis, not traditionally used in surname analysis  offer reliable and informative results, and insights into the hierarchical structure  of populations not easily gleaned from traditional surname methods. The spatial and  temporal components of Quebec surname distributions revealed that groups of names  which populate and distinguish certain regions were in place by 1800, and  cross-river relatedness became less significant as the population expanded upstream  away from the St. Lawrence River. I also found that surnames unique to certain  regions remained strongly clustered until the mid-nineteenth century when  urbanization and the settlement of new territory led to the fusion of name pools  (diversification) in and around urban areas, while at the same time causing losses  of names in some rural areas. The marriage records provided evidence, through their  measure of random mating, that surnames within different regions in Quebec  continually diversified throughout the nineteenth century. Overall, I found surnames  to be an informative variable for inferring population relatedness and migratory  paths. Because surnames are readily available in a number of sources researchers  involved with historical migration research should find that the methods presented  in this work will provide a time-saving technique which can overcome the  restrictions of spatial and temporal scale an</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm81d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gn66d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Names, Personal -- Québec (Province) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Québec (Province) -- Population -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Migration, Internal -- Québec (Province) -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603qx96t"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An exploratory study of derogation in Quebec : the case of three students</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pazzia-Guiducci, Olga</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This qualitative study investigates the consequences of  advancing three preschoolers into kindergarten in the province of Quebec, where the  derogation exemption enables younger children to start school before they reach the  age of admission of five years by September 30th. The rationale for this study came  from an interest to discover the perspectives of the students, their teachers, and  their parents on the topic of derogation. This study examines how these students,  one in grade 4 and two in grade 6, feel about being the youngest in the class, and  how teachers and parents perceive them as learners and socializers. The research  design is based on an exploratory qualitative case study approach. The methods used  to collect the data consist of interviews conducted with the three selected  students, their homeroom teachers, and two parents; observations of the students in  their school settings, and the analysis of documents such as field notes and journal  entries. The interviews are analyzed within a socio-cultural interpretive framework  in order to examine the way that derogation has affected the social and emotional  lives of the three selected children. Vygotsky's zone of proximal development is  explored. This concept presents the idea that children develop their learning  potential in a setting where they can learn with more capable peers and adults who  provide guidance and support. When these younger children are advanced into a  kindergarten class, they are placed in a setting with older peers and adult  teachers. One of the issues addressed in this study is how the social milieu  encourages derogated children to develop their cognitive approach to problem solving  and learning. The themes that emerged from this study include the importance of  parental support, peer acceptance, and self-esteem. The younger derogated students  are more likely to experience success in their academic and social-emotional lives  if they have good parental support, a</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cq947.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qx96t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Derogation (Law) -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>School age (Entrance age) -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Readiness for school -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azp38wd185"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immobilization of selected enriched polyphenol oxidases and their biocatalysis in organic solvent media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hossain, Abzal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Polyphenol oxidase (PPO) enzymatic extracts were recovered from  apple fruit and potato tubers and enriched by an acetone precipitation. The enriched  PPO extracts were immobilized by adsorption onto a wide range of inorganic supports,  including chitin, alumina oxide, glass beads, Celite, Dowex and Silica gel using  selected media, including water, sodium phosphate buffer and a ternary micellar  system. The highest immobilization efficiencies and specific activities were  obtained when the PPO extracts were suspended in sodium phosphate buffer and  adsorbed onto alumina oxide. Biocatalysis of the free and immobilized PPO extracts  was investigated in selected organic solvent media, including hexane, heptane,  toluene and dichloromethane, using chlorogenic acid, catechin, and the endogenous  phenolic compounds from apple fruit and potato tubers as substrate models. In the  organic solvent media, the free PPO extracts from apple and potato demonstrated  optimal enzymatic activities at 28°C and between 25 to 35°C,  respectively, whereas the immobilized extracts both showed optimal enzymatic  activities at 30°C. The free and immobilized extracts from apple and potato  also showed similar pH values for optimal enzymatic activity in the range of 6.0 to  6.5. The immobilized apple and potato PPO extracts demonstrated a 1.5 to 1.8 and 2.1  to 3.2-fold increases in PPO activity, respectively, compared to those observed with  their free counterparts, and the lowest Km values were obtained with chlorogenic  acid followed by catechin and the endogenous phenolic compounds. The immobilized and  free PPOs from apple and potato also showed higher Vmax values in the hexane medium  followed the heptane, toluene and dichloromethane media. The end products of PPO  biocatalysis were purified by size-exclusion chromatography and detected at 280 nm  for the residual catechin and endogenous phenolic compounds, and at 320 nm for the  PPO-catalyzed end products. Spectroscopic scanning</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt32j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wd185</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Polyphenol oxidase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apples</dc:subject><dc:subject>Potatoes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Enzymatic browning</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343s673"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Educational reform : an investigation of democracy and the place of the self in Québec education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rabinovitch, Lori Diane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Province of Quebec launched a province-wide reform of its  schools and adult education centres in 1997 to respond to the exigencies of an  increasingly multicultural population, and the requirements of a knowledge-based  society. The reform aims to enhance democracy and citizenship. Based on the recent  explosion in philosophical literature about varying models of democracy, and the  concept of self advanced by each model, it is important to investigate what vision  of democracy and concept of self is proposed for Quebec through this reform and what  institutional measures are being adopted by the educational community to ensure its  realization. This paper uses the principles of applied philosophy for an  investigation of the reform from three perspectives: a study of theories about  democracy, education, and the development of self; a critical text analysis of the  reform's formative document; the creation of a study group inside a school board  implementing the reform in its schools. The conclusion of the present investigation  is that a model of deliberative democracy and dialogical concept of self is not the  model of democracy that dominates Quebec's current reform project despite evidence  that such a model is most likely to ensure that this reform will successfully  address the needs of the population.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296wz56p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s673</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Self</dc:subject><dc:subject>Educational change -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Democracy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s065p"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Secrecy, information control and power building in the Ottoman Empire, 1566-1603</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Peksevgen, Sefik</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Conventionally, the era that begins after the death of  celebrated Ottoman sultan Suleyman I in 1566 is seen as the beginning of Ottoman  decline. In line with the decline paradigm, late sixteenth century is also accepted  as a time of political turmoil. This period is characterized by constant power  struggles among Ottoman ruling elite and the deterioration of the classical Ottoman  political order. Concerning the rise of new power elite (favourites) in the court  and bureaucracy vis-a-vis the decreasing power of the sultans and grand vezirs,  "evil counsellors" and the inaccessibility of the Ottoman sultan were  chronic themes in the Ottoman Empire. Yet, at the same time, in most of the Ottoman  political treatises access to and privacy with the sultan is restricted to a very  limited number of the servants of the court and bureaucracy. Especially the  communication between the sultan and the grand vezir is advised to be a secret. In  view of this important political dictum, in the present study it is argued that the  power also came from and built by the monopoly on information about the matters of  state by the least number of people. In accordance with this view, the power  politics of the late sixteenth century Ottoman political arena is analyzed as  struggles over controlling the flow of information about the matters of  state.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw28m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s065p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Turkey -- History -- Ottoman Empire, 1288-1918</dc:subject><dc:subject>Official secrets -- Turkey -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qc62k"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Apoptosis-related molecules in cell adhesion and development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Houde, Caroline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Apoptosis is a programmed cell death process essential for  development and homeostasis and its deregulation is involved in many diseases. The  caspases are a family of cysteine proteases present as inactive pro-enzymes in all  cell types and activated following apoptotic stimulation. These proteases cleave a  particular subset of protein substrates which results in the organized break down of  the cells which shrink and are cleared through phagocytosis. In this thesis, many  apoptotic processes are discussed. First, the CEACAM1-L cell-cell adhesion molecule  is identified as a caspase-3 substrate during apoptosis. This cleavage event alters  CEACAM1-L adhesion properties which might affect apoptotic cell clearance. Second,  the brain development defect phenotype of Caspase-3-null mice is investigated. The  mouse strain specificity of that mutation allowed the identification of caspase-7 as  a compensating enzyme for the loss of caspase3 in precursor neurons. Finally, new  functions are elucidated for Hippi, a pro-apoptotic molecule involved in the  neurodegenerative Huntington's disease. Hippi-targeted deletion revealed its role in  node cilia assembly and in Sonic hedgehog signaling during early mouse embryo  development. Altogether, these findings provide new insights into several aspects of  the apoptosis program.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h9385.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qc62k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343s66t"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modelling the spatial structure of image surrounds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hernández-Alonso, Diana Anabel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, the statistical nature of surround or context  and the relationship between a scene feature and its interaction with its  environment are studied. In particular we look at the conditional distribution of  surround pixel values given the center pixel value. We then examine the physical  mechanisms (ecological effects) by which the surround pixel values are generated to  explain the form of the conditional distributions observed in the natural  images. A new statistical model is proposed for the spatial structure of  the surround using principal component analysis (PCA). To this end, a linear model  is described for pixel surrounds conditioned on the hue value. Finally, we define an  algorithm to implement a PCA appearance-based method for obtaining statistical  models of the image patches conditioned on hue. To end this thesis, we provide an  extension of the Zhu-Wu-Mumford FRAME to texture synthesis, where our approach is  applied to characterize color textures.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj851.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s66t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bh73h"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development and validation of the Child and Adolescent Dysfunctional Attitudes Scale : tests of Beck's cognitive diathesis-stress theory of depression, of its causal mediation component, and of developmental effects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>D'Alessandro, David U.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Beck's cognitive diathesis-stress theory has generated much  research into the etiology of depression. Central to the theory are depressogenic  schemata that interact with stressors, resulting in increases in depressive  symptomatology. These schemata are commonly assessed using the Dysfunctional  Attitudes Scale (DAS). Importantly, the DAS was not designed for use in  children---it has been validated with adults and contains advanced language. Thus,  the Child and Adolescent Dysfunctional Attitudes Scale (CADAS) was  developed. Study 1 sought to psychometrically validate the CADAS. 453  children completed the CADAS item pool and measures assessing divergent validity.  The CADAS was readministered 3 weeks later. Items were retained based on item-total  correlations, internal consistency, and factor analyses. The finalized CADAS is a  22-item self-report measure with a unidimensional factor structure and sound  psychometric properties. Study 2 tested Beck's theory using the CADAS to assess  depressogenic schemata as a vulnerability factor for depression. An independent  sample of 241 children completed the CADAS and a measure of depression one week  before receiving school report cards (Time 1). The morning after receiving reports  (Time 2), stress was assessed by obtaining parents' reactions to reports, and with  an index of children's subjective acceptable grades compared to actual grades. Five  days later (Time 3), depression was reassessed. As hypothesized, regression analyses collapsing across age  revealed that Time 1 CADAS interacted with Time 2 parental stress to predict changes  in depression from Times 1 to 3. High-CADAS children showed greater increases in  depression relative to low-CADAS children when facing the stress of parental anger  and disappointment regarding their grades. Consistent with cognitive-developmental  theory, planned supplemental analyses indicated that the CADAS x stress interaction  predicted depressive changes only in older, formal-operational children. The  relationship between the CADAS x stress interaction and depressive changes was  mediated by negative views of the self, but not by views of the world or of the  future. This work yields a measure of depressogenic schemata in  school-aged children that further contributes to understanding their etiology of  depression. These schemata, together with negative views of oneself, may be  important targets for modification in the cognitive therapy of childhood  depression.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Koestner, Richard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv487.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bh73h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Behavioral assessment of children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Problem children -- Psychological testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Problem youth -- Psychological testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Behavioral assessment of teenagers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq977v33q"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Du silence à l'affirmation : women making history in Point St. Charles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kruzynski, Anna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Women made, and continue to make history in Point St. Charles,  and in doing so, transform selves, groups and community. Building on the literature on class and gender in community  organising, read through the conceptual lens of "translocational  positionality" (Anthias, 2002a), I tell a story of the journeys of a group of  ten women activists through four decades of neighbourhood organising. I show that  although all the women were first involved in citizens' committees around practical  needs such as housing, welfare, urban renewal and education, most of them,  stimulated by feminist agitators in their midst, came to new awareness about gender  inequalities, to new and deepening analyses, and to individual and collective  actions around strategic gender needs. Part and parcel of this spiral of change  (Nadeau, 1996) were the tensions that emerged with their families, friends and  neighbours, and even with the agitators themselves. Out of these tensions came  transformations at the macro level---community, public opinion and government, at  the meso level---organisational structures and cultures, and at the micro  level---family and selves. Next I do a metanarrative on the methodology that underlies the  project upon which my thesis is based, one that borrows from feminist community  organising practice (Gutierrez &amp; Lewis, 1994) to deal with the many ethical  dilemmas inherent to feminist life history methodology (Geiger, 1990). In line with  the notion of "translocational imaginings in dialogue", the project was  conceptualised to pre-figure power-with (Starhawk, 1987) in order to construct  narratives of belonging that break with processes of differentiation and  stratification. The project is about doing community history with the people who  make that history. Because of this, when tensions emerged around power relations,  instead of paralysis, individual, interpersonal and collective transformations  emerged. Through this work, I am not only releasing new voices into the  collective narrative, but I am also contributing to debates on life history  methodology. And, my thesis, and the other historical products that will emerge from  this project, will enable organisers and activists to learn from the past, and will,  hopefully, entice younger people to get involved in community  activism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shragge, Eric</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m2214.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v33q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in community development -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Pointe-Saint-Charles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pointe-Saint-Charles (Montréal, Québec) -- Social conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pointe-Saint-Charles (Montréal, Québec) -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d703d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic modelling of rock fracturing by destress blasting</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saharan, Mani Ram</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Rockburst control measures have been in practice with continued  efforts for improvements since the beginning of the 20th century. The thesis  concentrates on the evaluation of destress blasting, which is an important  pro-active rockburst control measure. The concept of destress blasting is based on  the fracturing of highly stressed rock mass by detonating explosive charge within  it. The concept has been carried out ever since the first reported use in a Canadian  coal mine circa the early 1930s. Since then, many mines across the continents have  applied this technique using a trial-and-error approach with mixed successes. To  date, the application lacks scientific base. The aim of this thesis is to identify the governing mechanisms  associated with destress blasting applications. A holistic approach is undertaken,  which involves a critical analysis of the reported field evidences, development of a  numerical procedure and detailed investigations at the micro-mechanical level to  investigate the fracturing of rock under confinement by different types and  magnitudes of explosive energy. A numerical procedure is developed in the thesis that carries  promising potential to improve the understanding on rock fracturing by explosive  energy as well as provides a platform to develop means for enhancing explosive  energy utilization. The procedure is validated with reported field  observations. Analyses of destress blasting is made through dynamic modelling  by simulating discrete fractures using the developed procedure. A normalized  parameter ℓ ci is introduced to investigate fracturing extent after destress  blasts. The investigations revealed that destress blasting produces limited  fractures aligned along the principal stresses. The fracturing extent reduces with  the increase in the confinement. The study indicates that the current practice of  destress blasting seemingly provides more psychological benefits than factual  benefits from the desired destressing. The study also introduces a non-dimensional parameter, betaij ,  which characterizes destressing effects. The parameter not only adequately explains  destressing phenomenon, but also offers clarifications to seemingly inexplicable  reported field observations of destress blasting. Local fractures around the  boreholes aligned along the principal stresses are found to be the cause of reported  local stress concentration and rock stiffening post to destress blasting against the  desired stress relaxation and softening.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitri, Hani S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x446t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d703d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qs436"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La rhétorique des origines dans l'Histoire de la Nouvelle-France de Marc Lescarbot</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lachance, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Histoire de la Nouvelle-France (1609, 1611, 1612, 1617,  1618) by Marc Lescarbot (v. 1570--1641) is read as a symbolic foundation for the  young colony of Port-Royal, Acadia (Annapolis, Nova Scotia), a construct which  functions as a valid genesis for French America (thus, "New France" in the  title refers specifically to this habitation as well as to the men who contributed  to its making). Chapter I is devoted to a reading of the work's abundant paratext  and identifies the topics at stake in the unfavourable rumours about the Acadian  expeditions as well as about the lieutenant of Port-Royal, Jean de Biencourt, sieur  de Poutrincourt. Moreover, this chapter explores the subjective marks, disseminated  in the paratext, that build up the historian's ethos, which works as a proof of the  validity of his object. This chapter investigates as well the metadiscursive  comments on the writing of history and their incidence on the referentiality of the  work. Chapter II compares the compilation of travel accounts contained in the  Histoire with its sources. This comparison shows how the alteration of these  accounts of travellers---who recorded themselves the result of their American  expeditions---strengthens the division of the stereotyped dichotomy between the man  of letters and the man of action, two functions respectively assigned to Lescarbot  and Poutrincourt in the Histoire. The order of this compilation as well as the  organisation of its various parts according to a diegetical logic shape specific  places where a tension emerges between a reliable discourse, intended to a  readership interested in the actual conditions of a colonial establishment, and the  production of a textual "coating" aiming at attracting a courtly  readership, to which the Jesuits, who challenged Poutrincourt's colonial project,  addressed their requests. In chapter III, where are confronted the written and  mapped representations of Port-Royal, this tension is even more manifest.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Desrosiers-Bonin, Diane</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967418r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs436</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>New France -- Discovery and exploration</dc:subject><dc:subject>America -- Discovery and exploration -- French</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lescarbot, Marc. Histoire de la Nouvelle-France</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acadia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indians of North America</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indians of North America -- Nova Scotia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w782f"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Impossible fictions? : reflexivity as methodology for studying women teachers' lives in development contexts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kirk, Jacqueline E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis interweaves issues of feminist methodology with  theories, policies and practices of gender and development, around a central focus  on women teachers' lives. It addresses the position of women teachers in relation to  theories and practices of gender, education and development. It examines appropriate  research methodology for working with, understanding and interpreting the lives of  women teachers in Karachi, Pakistan. Drawing on the multiple traditions of feminist  narrative inquiry in the field of education, and on the methods and forms emerging  in alternative forms of ethnographic practice, the study is a situated one. Lived  experiences are foregrounded, and time, place, context made explicit. Interview,  discussion group and fieldnote data are collected whilst working with women teachers  in Karachi, Pakistan. After an unexpected departure after September 11, 2001,  additional questionnaire data are collected from a distance. The thesis is a study researching women teachers' lives but also  a critical reflection on the dominant development practices in which research takes  place. As text it constitutes a form of feminist practice in and of itself. It  analyzes the lived, and embodied experience of teaching, learning and researching,  and rewrites this into the predominantly male-dominated literature and theory of  education in development. In the traditions of feminist inquiry, the study is also  oriented towards change for women. Given the stated importance of gender equity, and  especially the attention to girls' education of the international development  community, the study has important implications for the ways that development  planners think about women teachers, and design programs and policies for them.  Shifting attention from natural nurturing and caring abilities of women teachers, to  subjective issues of relational power dynamics, and to the individual and collective  positionings of women's bodies within institutions and organizations, this study  places women's lived experience as central to theories of pedagogy, curriculum,  educational leadership, and to research in gender, education and  development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, Claudia</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg908.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w782f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women teachers -- Pakistan -- Karachi</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct35f"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Noite dos tambores silenciosos : for symphony orchestra</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moura, Eli-Eri Luiz de</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this paper the compositional issues and techniques employed  in my D.Mus. Thesis Composition Noite dos Tambores Silenciosos (for symphony  orchestra) are discussed. The piece, constituted of three linked parts, exhibits a  counterpoint of three distinct kinds of music as the main vehicle of the musical  discourse. Two of these musics are connected with Maracatu de Baque Virado  and Maracatu Rural, popular musical manifestations found in Pernambuco, a state in  northeast Brazil. In a "defragmentation" process, reference materials from  the Maracatus are abstractly fragmented and reconstructed according to a technique I  call Zin-Zout, implementing in the music a continuous state of transformation, back  and forth between micro and macro dimensions. The third kind of music, free of folk  references, follows a transformational process built up according to a  "palimpsest" technique. In this transformation the hierarchy of the  musical parameters changes along with the units of the musical  content. These procedures involve not only pitch and rhythm, but also  other parameters like timbre, density and register in a structural way, as building  elements of the content and form of the work. The defragmentation process establishes some predetermined  compositional paths, but permits micro- and macro-level decisions based on intuitive  considerations, especially in the manipulation of orchestration and micro rhythms.  More systematic, the organization of pitch involves a limited serialism and a  variety of modal treatment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cherney, Brian</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806026k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct35f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Moura, Eli-Eri Luiz de. Noite dos tambores silenciosos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orchestral music -- Analysis, appreciation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orchestral music -- Scores</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j146k"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Walking between two worlds : the bicultural experience of second-generation East Indian Canadian women</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Justin, Monica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Second-generation East Indian women represent a visible ethnic  minority group in need of culturally sensitive research to facilitate an  understanding of their integration into Canadian society. There is a scarcity of  systematic qualitative inquires into the experience of this contemporary  second-generation population within a North American context. Hence, the primary  objective of this study is to understand the bicultural experience of a select group  of second-generation East Indian women using a focused ethnography as a research  tool. The central questions guiding this inquiry are (a) What are the salient  aspects in the subjective experience of second-generation East Indian women as they  grow up within both an East Indian and Canadian cultural context? (b) What are some  of the challenges they face as a result of their biculturalism, and (c) How do they  negotiate these challenges? The sample pool consisted of 16 second-generation East Indian  women between the ages of 20 and 40 years who were either working or attending  university and who were English speaking. Data collection focused on individual and  follow-up interviews, each lasting 60 to 90 minutes. A latent content analysis was  used to analyze the interview data and focused on looking for general themes,  patterns and trends in the data set. Results suggest that the bicultural experience  of this population is a complex and multifaceted phenomenon that reflects the  intersection of multiple identities including race, ethnicity, gender and cultural  values.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maroun, T. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z1338.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j146k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>East Indian Canadians</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930bx676"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Systematics of Thricops and phylogeny of the Azeliini (Diptera:Muscidae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Savage, Jade</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A phylogenetic analysis of the tribe Azeliini (Muscidae) was  conducted, as well as a revision and phylogenetic analysis of the genus Thricops  Rondani. Forty-four valid species and two subspecies of Thricops were recognised,  including six species new to science. All species of this genus have been  redescribed and illustrated, and a key to the world fauna is presented. An  exemplar-based phylogenetic analysis of Thricops was conducted using three different  sources of data: morphological characters of the adults, nucleotide sequence from  the nuclear gene white and nucleotide sequence from the subunits I and II of the  mitochondrial gene cytochrome c oxidase. The monophyly of Thricops sensu lato was  supported by the analysis of all individual and combined data sets. Combination of  data sets increased resolution for the smaller taxon sets, where there was little  missing data. The mitochondrial sequence generally provided finer resolution and  better branch support than white. The phylogenetic analysis of the Azeliini was  based on adult morphological characters of 32 exemplar species representing ten  genera. The monophyly of the Azeliini was well supported by eight apomorphic  characters. The genus Australophyra Malloch was removed from synonymy with Hydrotaea  R.-D. and reinstated, Megophyra Emden was synonymized with Neohydrotaea Malloch, and  Crucianella Xue &amp; Mang was synonymized with Xestomyia Stein. A number of new  combinations resulted from these new synonymies. A generic key to the Azeliini was  presented, and all genera redescribed according to the new limits defined in this  study.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wheeler, T. A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8060259.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bx676</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muscidae -- Phylogeny</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muscidae -- Classification</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5x21tf92x"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sirius on earth : 2001-2003, a chamber opera in five scenes, in full score</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frehner, Paul (Paul Anton)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Sirius on Earth is a chamber opera that deals satirically with  social and political issues that are pertinent to a Western multicultural urban  setting. Angela Murphy wrote the libretto, which is based on an original dramatic  scenario conceived of by the composer. This dissertation consists of two parts: the  opera in full score and an analysis of the opera. Sirius on Earth is scored for a  cast of eight singers and an ensemble of fifteen players. The analysis is related to  the overall objectives of the work which include representing and satirizing the  musical and cultural diversity inherent in multicultural Western cities, symbolized  in the opera by the city of Sirius, through the composer's individual approach to  musical pluralism. Important musical and dramatic features of the opera are  discussed in the analysis, including modal organization, musical characterization  and techniques of recontextualization such as allusion and parody. Conclusions  dissect the opera's underlying satirical and dystopian viewpoint.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bouliane, Denys</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm16z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tf92x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Operas -- Analysis, appreciation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Operas</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wn398"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluating the potential of alder-Frankia symbionts for the remediation and revegetation of oil sands tailings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mehta, Punita</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tailings are the waste produced as a result of the extraction of  oil from the tar sands in northern Alberta. Many avenues for the reclamation of  tailings are being researched, but one area that has received little attention is  phytoremediation. The Alder-Frankia symbiotic relationship in the tailings was  investigated for its potential in revegetation and remediation of the tailings. Two  species of alders were examined Alnus glutinosa and A. rugosa. The impact of the  alders was monitored through the investigation of the differences in the microbial  community present in the oil sands tailings and composite tailings (CT) with and  without alders. For our investigation we used culture dependent techniques (plate  counts and mineralization assays) and culture independent techniques (16S rRNA gene  PCR, catabolic PCR and DGGE). The alders lowered the pH of the tailings, increased  rates of mineralization, increased the general microbial population in the tailings  by one to two orders of magnitude and increased the microbial  diversity. A. rugosa however, had a greater impact on the mineralization of  poly aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) and, being native to Alberta, was chosen for  further experimentation, using only composite tailings. The aim of the experiments  was to determine the effect of a Frankia inoculum on the growth of A. rugosa in (CT)  and the associated microbial community. The microflora in the bulk soil, rhizosphere  and inside the root of inoculated and non-inoculated A. rugosa were compared through  microbial enumerations of the community, with general and selective media and  mineralization assays. A. rugosa inoculated with Frankia was taller and the roots  were more developed and the endophytic community of inoculated A. rugosa had greater  rates of naphthalene mineralization. The results indicate that A. rugosa inoculated with Frankia  could be used for the phytoremediation of tailings and for the re-establishment of a  forest ecosystem.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q195g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wn398</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Frankia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tailings (Metallurgy)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oil sands extraction plants -- Waste disposal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phytoremediation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alder</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dw07p"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ontological characterization of high through-put biological data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iacucci, Ernesto</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A result of high-throughput experimentation is the demand to  summarize and profile results in a meaningful and comparative form. Such  experimentation often includes the production of a set of distinguished genes. For  example, this distinguished set may correspond to a cluster of co-expressed genes  over many conditions or a set of genes from a large scale yeast two-hybrid study.  Understanding the biological relevance of this set will encompass annotation of the  genes followed by investigation of shared properties found among these annotations.  While the set of distinguished genes might have hundreds of annotations associated  with them, only a portion of these annotations will represent meaningful aspects  associated with the experiment. Identification of the meaningful aspects can be  focused by application of a statistic to an annotation resource. One such annotation  resource is Gene Ontology (GO), a controlled vocabulary which hierarchically  structures annotation terms (classifications) onto which genes can be mapped. Given  a distinguished set of genes and a classification, we wish to determine if the  number of distinguished genes mapped to that classification is significantly greater  or less than would be expected by chance. In estimating these probabilities,  researchers have employed the hypergeometric model under differing frameworks.  Assumptions made in these frameworks have ignored key issues regarding the mapping  of genes to GO and have resulted in inaccurate p-values. Here we show how dynamic  programming can be used to compute exact p-values for enrichment or depletion of a  particular GO classification. This removes the necessity of approximating the  statistics or p-values, as has been the common practice. We apply our methods to a  dataset describing labour and compare p-values based on exact and approximate  computations of several different statistics for measuring enrichment. We find  significant disagreement between commonly employ</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v3613.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw07p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>