<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b0323"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Between ethics and interests : human rights in the north-south relations of Canada, The Netherlands, and Norway</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gillies, David, 1952-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines human rights in the North-South relations of three internationalist countries: Canada, the Netherlands, and Norway. It pays special attention to the integration of human rights in development aid policy, particularly the use of political conditionality. The theoretical framework examines the explanatory power of political Realism. A hypothesis linking policy assertiveness with the perceived costs to other national interests is tested by selecting Western states most likely to disprove Realist assumptions, and by choosing at least two Third World cases for each aid donor: one where economic, political and strategic interests are high, and another where the same interests are minimal or low. Three frameworks to (1) document human rights abuses; (2) evaluate national human rights performance; and (3) gauge foreign policy assertiveness serve as the methodological lenses to analyze Western statecraft and test the hypothesis. Each donor's search for moral opportunity is visible in an emerging agenda to promote human rights and democratic development. However, if the resolve to defend human rights beyond national borders is gauged by a state's willingness to incur harm to other important national interests, then Canada, the Netherlands, and Norway are seldom disposed to let human rights trump more self-serving national interests. The potential for consistent and principled human rights statecraft is frequently undermined by Realism's cost-benefit rationality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nayar, Baldev Raj</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv310.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b0323</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Netherlands -- Foreign relations -- Developing countries</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human rights -- Developing countries</dc:subject><dc:subject>Realism -- Political aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Norway -- Foreign relations -- Developing countries</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Foreign relations -- Developing countries</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zc672"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Supersingular reduction of Drinfeld modules</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>David, Chantal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let $ phi$ be a rank 2 Drinfeld A-module over the ring A of polynomials over some finite field $F sb{q}$. We give a bound on the norm of those primes p of A which are factors of $P sb{d}(j sb phi)$ for two distinct polynomials d $ in$ A. We then show that the number of supersingular primes of $ phi$ with norm smaller than x is $ gg log log$ x. We investigate the endomorphism rings of supersingular Drinfeld A-modules over finite fields. Under a mild hypothesis, this leads to an upper bound of $x sp{3/4} log sp2 x$ for the number of supersingular primes of $ phi$, with even degree, and norm smaller than x. Finally, we present the problem of the average distribution of supersingular primes of Drinfeld modules.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murty, Ram</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn81v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc672</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk13k"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The formulation of a thermocline model and application[s] to ocean-climate studies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Sheng, 1956-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we formulate a new 3-dimensional planetary geostrophic (PG) ocean general circulation model in spherical coordinates for use in ocean-climate studies. The model equations consist of full prognostic temperature and salinity equations and diagnostic momentum equations. The model is verified by comparison with results obtained by the well known Bryan-Cox model at coarse resolution. Extensive process studies are carried out to determine the roles played by various processes in determining the thermocline structure and the thermohaline circulation, especially the role of convective overturning. A secondary circulation theory which treats the thermohaline circulation as a geostrophic flow instead of frictional current is proposed, and the implications of the results to 2-dimensional latitude/depth models are discussed. The model is also used to examine the stability and variability of the thermohaline circulation, especially the role played by air-sea heat flux at the surface. We show that the large reduction in the surface heat flux under mixed boundary conditions (restoring on temperature and flux on salinity) is essential for the occurrence of the "polar halocline catastrophe" (F. Bryan. 1986). Replacing the infinite heat capacity atmosphere implied by mixed boundary conditions with an atmosphere that can adjust thermally to the ocean, the amount of the heat flux reduction is less and thus the polar halocline catastrophe is less likely to occur; when it does occur, it is less severe. This is demonstrated by coupling our model to a simple zero heat capacity atmosphere (Schopf, 1983). Instead of a total collapse of the thermohaline circulation, the results show a decaying oscillation of 20 years period. The ocean model is next coupled to a thermodynamic sea ice model to examine the effect of sea ice on the stability and variability of the thermohaline circulation. A robust 17-year period oscillation is obtained, and a new mechanism involving a feedback between ice cover and temperature is proposed. Conceptual models are formulated for further interpretation of the results, and to compare the thermal insulation and salinity rejection effects due to an anomalous ice cover, on the density of the surface water. The heat budget required for ice formation leads to a constraint on the convective overturning, and hence the transfer of heat and salt from the deep ocean to the bottom of the ice. As a result, the thermal insulation effect is dominant, at least for the case of annual mean surface forcing examined here.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Greatbatch, R. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lin, C. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw11d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk13k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655j155"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adjustment to disconfirming evidence in a covariation judgment task : the role of alternative predictive relationships</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vallée-Tourangeau, Frédéric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This project investigated the impact of sustained disconfirmation on an acquired belief in a covariation judgment task. Both epistemology and the philosophy of science suggest that data which oppose a hypothesis might not dictate the revision of the hypothesis unless an alternative hypothesis can explain the negative evidence and replace the previous hypothesis. As well, the literature on human categorization and reasoning documents a preference for examples and test instances which confirm rather than disconfirm a prior hypothesis. It was therefore predicted that upon the presentation of negative data for an acquired correlational expectation, subjects would abandon their disconfirmed hypothesis with greater ease if the negative evidence was supplemented with alternative hypotheses. A series of four experiments examined this prediction. Using a within-subjects design, subjects first learned that certain predictor variables signalled the presence of certain outcome variables. In a second phase, the outcomes were systematically presented in the absence of the predictors. Adjustment to the negative evidence was measured on the basis of estimates of correlation and the subjects' tendency to predict the presence of the outcomes on trials where the predictors were present. There were three experimental conditions. In the first, an alternative predictor was present on all trials where the outcomes occurred in the absence of the original predictor. In a second, an alternative outcome was present on all trials where the original outcome was absent. In a third, the negative evidence was not framed in terms of either alternative predictors nor alternative outcomes. While all three conditions produced the same reductions in correlation estimates, the condition without alternatives produced perseverance in outcome predictions in the presence of the predictors. This pattern of adjustment was observed in a simulated medical diagnostic task (Experiment 1), and in a nonmedical s</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, A. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q440.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j155</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Reasoning (Psychology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wh55c"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental study of the structure of Ni-Zr metallic glasses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xu, Yan, 1963 Jan. 31-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a structural study of Ni-Zr metallic glasses. It is the first time that a careful complete and systematic investigation into the structure of a glassy metallic system has been carried out. The results have improved our understanding of the structure of metallic glasses and clarified confusion in previous studies. The total structure factors of melt-spun and sputtered amorphous Ni$ sb{x}$Zr$ sb{1-x}$, 0.25 $ le$ x $ le$ 0.86, were obtained with an accuracy of 1-4%. Accurate partial structure factors of Ni$ sb{0.33}$Zr$ sb{0.67}$ and Ni$ sb{0.67}$Zr$ sb{0.33}$ were obtained using x-ray and neutron diffraction while those of Ni$ sb{0.33}$Zr$ sb{0.67}$ were also obtained independently using isomorphous substitution. The results confirmed the reliability of the isomorphous substitution method for Ni-Zr glasses. We have found a strong correlation between the local atomic structure and the electron transport properties of Ni-Zr glasses. No structural difference between melt-spun and sputtered Ni-Zr glasses was found. Our results show that the Faber-Ziman partial structure factors of Ni-Zr glasses is strongly composition dependent. The local topological order in amorphous Ni$ sb{0.33}$Zr$ sb{0.67}$ is found to be quite similar to that in the BCT NiZr$ sb2$ compound whereas a discrepancy in the structure is found between amorphous Ni$ sb{0.67}$Zr$ sb{0.33}$ and the FCC Ni$ sb2$Zr compound. Our results have also shown that the Ni-Zr glasses are an almost random mixture of Ni and Zr atoms and that there is no correlation between the pre-peak in the neutron structure factor and the chemical short-range order in the metallic glass.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Muir, W. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d282.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh55c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rm87p"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Advances in pulse width modulation techniques</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Xiao, 1956-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The phase angle control of the Two-Level Sinusoidal Pulse Width Modulation (SPWM) strategy has been studied in Part I of this thesis, and applied to a new voltage-source type PWM High Voltage Direct Current (HVDC) transmission system. The PWM-HVDC station exercises direct control over the voltage phase angle, the amplitude and the frequency at the ac terminals using the phase angle lock loop (PLL) control of the SPWM. The parallel connection of multi-terminal PWM-HVDC stations can be achieved through simple local feedback control. The feasibility studies for the system, based on laboratory experiments and numerical analysis, are reported in the thesis. In Part II of the thesis, the Three-Level SPWM technique has been studied and applied to the controls of a 3-chase, 6-valve, current-source PWM rectifier. A new Dynamic Three-Level SPWM strategy together with its Decoupler Pre-Processor has been proposed. The strategy enables each of three phase currents of the converter to be controlled independently and linearly, so that the dynamic feedback can be channelled. The Pole Placement control method has been implemented successfully, using a real-time digital control scheme. The scheme also succeeds in active filtering. The experimental results are obtained from a 1-KVA size laboratory model with a real-time controller using three TMS320C25 DSPs. The three DSPs operating in parallel are necessary to compute the feedback algorithms with minimum delays so as to ensure sufficient frequency bandwidth.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ooi, Boon-Teck</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d138v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rm87p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qk318"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Field performance and in vitro hardening studies of micropropagated red raspberry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deng, Ribo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Field performance of micropropagated (MP) and conventionally propagated (CP) red raspberry (Rubus idaeus L. cv. Comet and Festival) was examined under hedgerow and stool cane management systems for 3 seasons (1989 to 1991). All MP plants established well compared to 58% survival rates 45 days after planting and 92% survival rates after replanting for CP plants. The MP plants were more vigorous compared with the CP plants for the duration of this study as indicated by more and taller canes. MP 'Festival' in 1990 yielded 2.2 MT$ cdot$ha$ sp{-1}$, almost half the yield of established commercial plantings in Quebec, while yields from CP 'Festival' and MP and CP 'Comet' were negligible. The MP 'Festival' crop (8.42 MT$ cdot$ha$ sp{-1}$) also outyielded CP 'Festival' (6.8 MT$ cdot$ha$ sp{-1}$) and both MP (5.72 MT$ cdot$ha$ sp{-1}$) and CP (4.91 MT$ cdot$ha$ sp{-1}$) 'Comet' in the second fruiting year. Propagation method had no effects on winter hardiness, photosynthetic capacity nor leaf and stem morphology of either cultivar. The results indicated that MP plants were superior to CP plants for both nursery propagation and fruit production due to their more consistent establishment and increased vigor. Red raspberry plantlets were successfully hardened in vitro on low-sucrose or sucrose-free media through CO$ sb{2}$ enrichment (1500 ppm) and relative humidity reduction (90%) using a forced ventilation system in specially constructed plexiglass chambers. Enriched CO$ sb{2}$ significantly increased general vigor, root formation, root growth, plantlet growth and plantlet photosynthetic capacities. Sucrose in the medium promoted plantlet growth but depressed photosynthesis. In vitro relative humidity at 90% decreased stomatal apertures and improved plantlet ex vitro performance but did not affect the CO$ sb{2}$ uptake rates of cultured plantlets or ex vitro transplants. The maximum CO$ sb{2}$ uptake rates of plantlet leaves were about 52-69% that of greenhouse control pla</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donnelly, D. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k68g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk318</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Raspberries -- Propagation -- In vitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>Raspberries -- Growth</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd375x950"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Nursing</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Physiological and behavioural responses of premature infants to a tissue-damaging stimulus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stevens, Bonnie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to (a) describe the physiological and behavioural responses of premature infants to a tissue-damaging stimulus and (b) determine how severity of illness and behavioural state influenced these responses. A convenience ample of 124 premature infants between 32 and 34 weeks gestational age was obtained from one neonatal unit in a Montreal teaching hospital. Physiological (heart rate, oxygen saturation, intracranial pressure) and behavioural (facial expression and cry) data were collected during the baseline, warming, stick and squeeze phases of a routine heelstick procedure. Behavioural state and severity of illness were assessed using instruments by Prechtl (1974) and Georgieff, Mills and Bhatt (1989). Demographic data were collected from the medical record. Data analysis was performed utilizing repeated measures multivariate analysis of variance (RM MANOVA), multivariate analysis of variance (MANOVA) and repeated measures multivariate analysis of covariance (RM MANOVA). There were significant differences in physiological and behavioural parameters between baseline and stick including: (a) an increase in maximum heart rate, (b) a decrease in minimum oxygen saturation, (c) an increase in intracranial pressure and (d) an increase in the proportion of all facial actions. For those infants who cried during both the stick and squeeze phase, the fundamental frequency, harmonic structure and peak spectral energy were significantly increased during the stick as compared to the squeeze. Behavioural state was found to modify the facial expression variables and severity of illness modified the acoustic cry variables. An interaction between behavioural state and severity of illness influenced maximum heart rate. There was no significant relationship between physiological and behavioural outcomes. Both categories of outcomes provide important but different information about the premature infant's response to a tissue-damaging stimulus. A multidimen</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Johnston, Celeste</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x553f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375x950</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nursing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fj662"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stress memory measurement using the Kaiser effect of acoustic emission</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Momayezzadeh, Mohammed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigates in detail the stress memory of hard rocks under uniaxial compressive conditions as a time-saving and inexpensive alternative to traditional in-situ stress measurement techniques. Extensive laboratory experiments are carried out to assess the influence of parameters such as transducer/amplifier frequency response, signal definition parameters, stress rate, strain rate, specimen size, stress level, delay time, temperature, water content, confining pressure, and directional loading on the Kaiser Effect of Stanstead granite and other rock types. Based on these findings and a new data processing techniques developed for estimating the previous stress level, a testing procedure is suggested and used to determine in-situ stresses from core samples with respect to their drilling orientations. In two case studies, the estimated stresses using the Kaiser Effect phenomenon are in good agreement with values obtained from conventional techniques while in the third study, no stress value was obtained due to the inability of the rock type to generate acoustic emissions. The results of this investigation show that the Kaiser Effect could become an economical method of stress measurement in hard and isotropic rock types.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hassani, F. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g182j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj662</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b033c"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification and characterisation of mannoprotein emulsifier from Baker's yeast</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cameron, David R. (David Robert)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mannoprotein of Saccharomyces cerevisiae, baker's yeast, is an emulsifying agent which could be used in foods and cosmetics. This glycoprotein emulsifier can be extracted simply with very good yield by autoclaving yeast cells in neutral buffer. The spent yeast from the beer and wine industries is a suitable raw material for its production. Protein detected by binding of Coomassie blue dye was essential for emulsifying activity. Components of the heat extracted material with greatest emulsifying activity included a high molecular weight fraction ($&gt;$200 kDa) which provided viscous and durable emulsions, and a low molecular weight fraction ($&lt;$14 kDA) which was very surface active and readily generated nonviscous emulsions. Mannoprotein and the small molecule surfactants lecithin and cetyltrimethylammonium bromide interacted synergistically to increase emulsifying activity at a weight ratio of 100:1 mannoprotein to surfactant. A correction was made to the formula for the Emulsifying Activity Index (Pearce, K. N. and J. E. Kinsella. 1978. J. Agric. Food Chem. 26:716-723), a measure commonly used for comparing protein emulsifiers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Neufeld, R. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Idziak, E. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf31x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b033c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Emulsions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brewery waste</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5d86p188f"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>DNA repair and mutagenesis in the UV-sensitive mutant UVSI of Aspergillus nidulans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chae, Suhn-Kee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects of a newly mapped DNA repair-defective mutant, uvsI, on mutagen sensitivities and mutation were investigated. Results showed that uvsI differs for most of the investigated properties from other uvs mutants of A. nidulans which are known to belong to three different epistatic groups, "UvsF", "UvsC", and "UvsB". Most of these mutants are sterile and many of them alter mitotic recombination frequencies, while uvsI exhibits normal levels of meiotic and mitotic recombination. In addition, uvsI strains are not more sensitive than wild type to MMS (methyl methanesulfonate) to which all other uvs strains are sensitive. However, the uvsI mutant was found to be very sensitive to the killing effects of UV light and the chemical mutagen, 4-NQO (4-nitro-quinoline-N-oxide). In line with the distinct phenotype of uvsI, no epistatic interactions were found for this mutant with any members of the established three epistatic groups. The effects of uvsI on mutagenesis are highly specific and dependent on the mutational test systems. In the uvsI mutant, two types of forward mutation were not affected, but spontaneous and UV-induced reversion frequencies of choA1 and pabaA1 were significantly reduced. Specific effects were further demonstrated in reversion tests of various sC alleles originally isolated as selenate resistant mutants by treatment with EMS (ethyl methanesulfonate), which leads mainly to G:C to A:T transitions. After EMS treatment uvsI mutants showed highly reduced reversion frequencies for all these sC alleles (except one) compared to $uvs sp+$ strains. These results suggest that the uvsI mutation may be defective in AT to GC transition mutagenesis, while increasing transversion(s) from A:T base pairs. In contrast, uvsI affected the frequencies of spontaneous and UV-induced reversions for these sC alleles in a variety of ways. Thus, uvsI may well represent a fourth functional and epistatic group of DNA repair and possibly be involved in a minor mutagenic DN</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kafer, Etta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dn90k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p188f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ultraviolet radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aspergillus nidulans</dc:subject><dc:subject>DNA repair</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mutagenesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xt24q"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intra-ethnic differences of the perceptions of aged Italian women in receiving care</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bonar, Rita Aguzzi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is qualitative study of the perceptions of aged Italian women in receiving care. It examines intra-ethnic group differences between Italian-Immigrant and Italian-Canadian women, and their definition of the experience of receiving care. Also, it addresses gender, class, and ethnicity issues which have implications for social work practice, policy, and research. Sixty-one interviews were conducted with thirty participants, over the age of sixty-five. Participants were interviewed in their treatment environments with follow-up interviews in their home settings. Semi-structured in-depth interviews documenting these women's life histories, as well as participant observation, were the qualitative methods used to collect data. Interview transcripts and field notes were analyzed qualitatively to identify similarities and differences in participants' perceptions as care-receivers. A feminist theoretical perspective was applied to the discussion of the data. The study suggests that differences exist between aged Italian-Immigrant and Italian-Canadian women care-receivers. These differences are directly related to specific personal and social factors which nurture and oppress them. Aged Italian-Canadian women were found to have more resources, greater independence with their supportive alliances, and higher levels of self-esteem and life satisfaction than aged Italian-Immigrant women. The findings provide insight into resources these women developed to deal with the constraints imposed on them by their gender, class, and ethnicity. The study suggests an integrated-interactive approach of practice, policy, and research to implement changes so as to meet the needs of these individuals. The study recommends that a feminist social work approach be adopted in the educational curriculum for the training of social work professionals.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacLean, M. J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236370h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt24q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dependency (Psychology) in old age</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italians -- Home care -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Feminist theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older women -- Home care -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10wr781"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attentional direction in two-part contrapuntal dictation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beckett, Christine Alyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explored undergraduate music majors' strategies in two-part dictation. Sixty volunteers answered a questionnaire on their musical background, learning styles, and dictation methods. They then took part in three dictation sessions. Two sessions directed attention to rhythm first or pitch first, and one session was a non-directed control dictation. Treatments were counterbalanced across 6 groups (n = 10). Dependent measures were pitch and rhythm accuracy scores on dictations. Analysis of variance showed no order effects. A repeated measures MANOVA (pitch and rhythm by 3 conditions) showed a significant effect for condition ($p &lt; .0001$). Higher rhythm accuracy resulted from the rhythm-first condition, compared to the non-directed ($p &lt; .05$) and pitch-first ($p &lt; .0001$) conditions. Pitch accuracy was not affected by condition. Accuracy was unrelated to any of the covariates examined (instrumental information, years of theory and counterpoint study, keyboard skill, learning style and private strategy). Results suggest that in polyphonic dictation, attending to rhythm first and pitch afterwards may be an effective way of maximizing rhythmic accuracy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wapnick, Joel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp66c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr781</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Attention</dc:subject><dc:subject>Musical dictation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Counterpoint</dc:subject><dc:subject>Auditory perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ear training</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956h44z"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Individual differences in knowledge representation and problem- solving performance in physics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Austin, Lydia B. (Lydia Bronwen)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Concept mapping in college-level physics was investigated. The study was carried out in three parts. First, an attempt was made to validate concept mapping as a method of evaluating student learning at the junior college level (ages 16-21). Several measures were found to be sensitive to differences in students' achievement. Second, the effectiveness of concept mapping as an instructional strategy was investigated. It was found that the strategy led to improvement in multistep problem-solving performance but not in performance on single step problems. Third, the concept maps made by experts in the field were compared with the maps made by high achieving and average achieving students to see if this is yet another way in which high performance and expertise are related. It was found that the high achieving students made maps which more nearly resembled the maps made by experts than those made by average achieving students.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shore, B. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b750.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h44z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Problem solving</dc:subject><dc:subject>Knowledge representation (Information theory)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569602g"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stabilized combi-molecules for the treatment of breast cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacPhee, Meaghan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We recently developed a novel strategy termed “combi-targeting” that seeks to design “combi-molecules” which are able to not only block EGFR but to also damage DNA. Previous studies that sought to stabilize triazene based combi-molecules were based on masking the 1,2,3-triazene chain with a 2-acetoxymethylene group, leading to the synthesis of RB24 and RB107. The half-lives of these two molecules proved to be only about 5 minutes longer than their parent triazenes. The novel series of molecules presented herein were designed containing hydrolysable groups to modulate the kinetics of their degradation,. These include vinyl, acetoxymethyloxyl, and p-nitrophenol carbamates. Kinetic studies determined that the vinyl carbamate ZRL2 was the most stable of the series. However, its vinyl counterpart ZRL1 designed to be cleaved by a basic neighbouring group was the least stable. The half-lives of all of the other molecules were significantly longer than that of RB107. Specifically, ZRL1 had a half-life approximately 20 min longer and ZRS1, ZRL4, ZRL5 40-55 min longer. The molecules were designed to release a fluorescent aminoquinazoline, FD105, upon degradation. This allowed us to observe its intracellular release by fluorescent microscopy. ZRL1 generated the highest level of fluorescence and its more stable counterpart, ZRL2, produced levels that were barely detectable. Studies directed at determining the dual EGFR-DNA targeting abilities of the molecules showed that: (a) all of the compounds were capable of blocking the EGFR tyrosine kinase activity in an isolated enzyme assay and in MDAMB468 cells, (b) all of the molecules, except for the most stable compound ZRL2, were capable of inducing dose-dependent DNA damage, and (c) induction of DNA damage was associated with cell cycle arrest in G2/M. Using a growth inhibition assay, it was determined that all of the molecules could: (a) block the growth of MDAMB468 cells and (b) preferentially inhibit the EGFR transfe</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Nous avons récemment mis au point une nouvelle stratégie dénommée “combi-ciblage” : cette stratégie est basée sur des agents appelés “combi-molécules”, capables non seulement de bloquer l’EGFR, mais aussi d’induire des lésions de l’ADN. Des études antérieures réalisées au laboratoire et ayant pour but de masquer la chaîne 1,2,3-triazène de certaines combi-molécules par un groupement 2-acétoxyméthylène afin de les stabiliser ont conduit à l’obtention des composés RB24 et RB107. Ces travaux n’ont toutefois pas permis d’augmenter de manière significative les temps de demi-vie de ces deux molécules, puisqu’ils n’étaient supérieurs que d'environ 5 minutes aux temps de demi-vie des molécules triazéniques initiales. Les nouvelles séries de molécules présentées dans cette thèse contiennent un groupement carbamate hydrolysable permettant d’optimiser leur cinétique de dégradation. D’autres modifications ont été également appliquées, notamment l'ajout de différents groupements tels que des vinyl, acétoxyméthyloxyl, et p-nitrophénol carbamates. Ainsi, les études cinétiques ont montré que le vinyl carbamate ZRL2 est le plus stable de ces séries. En revanche, son homologue vinylique ZRL1, conçu pour être clivé par un groupement basique voisin, s’est avéré être le moins stable avec un temps de demi-vie toutefois supérieur d’environ 20 minutes à celui du RB107. Les temps de demi-vie des autres composés se sont significativement allongés, notamment pour ZRS1, ZRL4, et ZRL5, dont les temps de demi-vie dépassent de 40 à 55 minutes celui du RB107. De plus, ces molécules ont été conçues pour libérer un groupement fluorescent de type aminoquinazoline (FD105) au cours de leur dégradation. Par conséquent, nous pouvons observer leur localisation intracellulaire, de même que leur abondance, par microscopie à fluorescence. Ainsi, ZRL1 génère la plus grande quantité de fluorescence, tandis$</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bertrand Jean-Claude</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp486.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569602g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Chemotherapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff365683b"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soil organic carbon in tree-based intercropping systems of Quebec and Ontario, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bambrick, Amanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>ABSTRACT  M.Sc.Amanda D. BambrickNatural Resource Sciences  Tree-based intercropping (TBI) is an agroforestry system where a crop, generally an annual, is planted between established tree rows.  TBI systems have a greater potential for carbon storage than conventional cropping systems because carbon is stored in the biomass of growing trees and trees provide additional carbon inputs (leaves, roots) that contribute to the soil organic carbon (SOC) pool. Differences in the litter quality and amount of litter deposited in the tree row versus the intercropped space are expected to generate spatial heterogeneity in the SOC pool. The objectives of this work were to evaluate the spatial variability of the SOC pool in TBI systems, to compare SOC stocks in the TBI system with a nearby conventional agroecosystem, and to describe the SOC dynamics in a TBI system using the ecosys model. Research sites included in this study were 4-year old TBI sites at St. Paulin and St. Edouard (Quebec, Canada), an 8-year old TBI site in St. Remi, Quebec, and a 21 year old TBI site in Guelph, Ontario, Canada. Spatial heterogeneity in SOC pools due to the presence of trees was observed in two of the four sites, but obscured by field variability at one site and even distribution of leaf litter associated with large trees at the oldest TBI site. The SOC pool increased in older TBI sites, relative to the nearby conventional agroecosystem, but the magnitude of SOC change was affected by the land use history. A simulation of changes in SOC using the ecosys environmental model predicted a 5.0% decrease in SOC pools twenty-one years after the site was converted to TBI, while field experiments showed a 12% increase in the SOC pool compared to the conventional agroecosystem. A spatial algorithm that describes the distribution of trees and crops in TBI systems would improve ecosys model predictions. Overall, field results suggest that the trees growing in TBI systems will increase SOC levels after a n</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>RESUMÉM.Sc.Amanda D. BambrickSciences de ResourcesNaturellesUn système de culture intercalaire (SCI) est un système d’agrosylviculture où une récolte, généralement annuelle, est établie entre les rangées d'arbres plantées. Le SCI a un potentiel important pour être adoptés dans les régions tempérées dû aux avantages environnementaux liés à ces systèmes. Un tel avantage environnemental fourni par SCI est le stockage accru de carbone dans les sols et la biomasse des plantes. Le SCI a un potentiel important pour le stockage de carbone (C) car il contienne de carbone dans la biomasse des arbres croissants, et l’ajout au sol des résides d’arbres (feuilles, racines) contribuent au C organique du sol (SOC). On s'attend à ce que des différences dans la qualité et la quantité des résides organiques déposées dans la rangée d'arbre contre l'espace intercalaire produisent de l'hétérogénéité spatiale de SOC. Les objectifs de cette thèse étaient i) d'évaluer la variabilité spatiale de SOC dans le SCI, ii) comparer des stocks de SOC dans le SCI à un agro-écosystème conventionnel, et iii) décrire la dynamique de SOC dans le SCI utilisant le model ecosys. Les sites expérimentaux incluant dans cette étude étaient des emplacements de quatre ans à St. Paulin et St. Édouard (Québec, Canada), de huit ans à St. Rémi, Québec et de 21 ans à Guelph (Ontario, Canada). L'hétérogénéité spatiale au SOC due à la présence des arbres a été observée dans deux des quatre sites, mais obscurcie par la variabilité de terrain a un site et par la distribution égale de feuillage liée à de grands arbres à l'emplacement de SCI le plus ancien. Le stock de SOC accrue dans des sites de SCI le plus anciens, relativement à l'agro-écosystème conventionnel, mais l'importance de changement de SOC a été affectée par l'histoire d'utilisation de la terre. Une simulation des changements du SOC utilisant le modèle ecosys a prévu une diminut</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joann Karen Whalen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k69r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365683b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Soil Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483k84b"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Differential function of costal and crural diaphragm in the awake canine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Easton, Paul A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>These investigations examined the relative function of costal and crural diaphragm segments. This work produced the first direct measurements of length and electromyogram (EMG) of the diaphragm in an awake, intact animal. Examination of diaphragm function following laparotomy revealed a consistent pattern of postoperative segmental recovery, and showed the inadequacy of EMG alone as an indicator of diaphragm activity. Segmental contraction during airway occlusion was confirmed to be non-isometric and different per segment. The basic relation between segmental velocity of shortening and mean inspiratory flow, was confirmed for diaphragm but not for intercostal musculature. Anesthesia produced a distinctive alteration in the resting length of crural compared to costal segment, suggesting a difference in inherent segmental tonic activity. Costal and crural activity during hypoxic and hypercapnic stimulated breathing revealed different, stimulant-specific activities of the segments; hypoxia elicited prominent crural post inspiratory activity (PIIA). During thermal panting, peak crural shortening was out of phase with costal shortening and inspiratory airflow. This unique segmental asynchrony may represent a natural analog to high frequency ventilation. We conclude that costal and crural diaphragm segments can function as individual segment-muscles, exhibiting distinctive, differential activities under certain conditions of respiration.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grassino, Alex</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n271w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k84b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nc69m"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Prolactin in human breast cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gould, David R. (David Ross)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The function of prolactin in human breast cancer was studied using four different approaches. First, purification and characterization of the prolactin receptor from breast cancer cells indicated that the receptor has a molecular mass of 88 000 Da, 67 000 Da being protein, and the other 21 000 Da presumably carbohydrate. Secondly, prolactin was tested for mitogenic activity in breast cancer in vitro. No consistent mitogenic response to prolactin could be demonstrated in these experiments. Thirdly studies upon the regulation of the prolactin receptor in breast cancer cells indicated that the prolactin receptor is stimulated by lactogen, estrogen and progesterone at the protein level. Estrogen, progesterone, thyroid hormone, and forskolin (but not lactogen) increase prolactin receptor steady state RNA levels, and the phorbol ester PMA and retinoic acid inhibited receptor RNA levels. However, effects at the RNA level were of a much lesser magnitude than effects at the protein level. Mechanisms other than transcriptional regulation alone are likely involved in prolactin receptor regulation. Fourthly, prolactin receptor and prolactin inducible protein/gross cystic disease fluid protein (PIP/GCDFP-15) RNA levels were examined in breast cancer tumors. Highly significant correlations were observed between the prolactin receptor and the progesterone receptor; the prolactin receptor and PIP/GCDFP-15; and PIP/GCDFP-15 and progesterone receptor.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kelly, P. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph86w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc69m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mn824"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of Eclipse© Monte Carlo dose calculation for clinical electron beams using heterogeneous phantoms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lagmago Kamta, Gérard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Accurate dose calculations of photon and electron transport in tissue materials are an important step in the appropriate delivery of cancer radiotherapy. Various commercial treatment planning systems used in radiotherapy provide algorithms for fast dose calculations. It is the responsibility of medical physicists to commission and evaluates these algorithms. In this work, we have evaluated the electron Monte Carlo (MC) algorithm in Eclipse using solid water phantoms with various tissue heterogeneities (water, lung, cortical bone, air) embedded, and using CT data from a real patient. For heterogeneous phantoms, the evaluation is done by comparing dose profiles and percent depth doses (PDDs) calculated on Eclipse with measurements, and with MC simulations using DOSXYZnrc. Measurements of dose profiles and PDDs are taken using EBT Gafchromic films, and we have developed a piece of software in Matlab for extracting dose from EBT Gafchromic films. For the real patient case, we use DOSXYZnrc results as a benchmark against which Eclipse is evaluated. Although Eclipse has been evaluated previously, the originality of the present work lays on the use of digitally reproduced phantom copies on Eclipse and DOSXYZnrc instead of CT scanned phantoms, the use of absolute dose for all comparisons, and the consideration of a real clinical patient. In addition, we have developed a tool for extracting absolute dose profiles and PDDs from EBT Gafchromic films. Our results indicate that, MC results agree in general better with measurements (within 5% or less) than Eclipse MC, whose discrepancies with measurements can be as high as 15% for physical phantoms used and as high as 10% in the case of real patient CT data. Largest discrepancies between measurement (or MC) and Eclipse MC occur at depths near and below tissue heterogeneities with relatively sharp density gradients. The slightly better performance of Eclipse for the real patient case is related to the smoother changes in hetero</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les calculs précis de dose déposée dans les tissus par les photons et les électrons constituent une étape préliminaire cruciale dans tout approche de thérapie de cancer par la radiation. Plusieurs entreprises commerciales offrent de nos jours des programmes de planification des thérapies qui incluent des algorithmes de calcul de dose dans les tissus. Il est de la responsabilité du physicien médical de vérifier que ces algorithmes effectuent les calculs de dose avec une précision acceptables selon les standards actuels de radiothérapie. Dans ce mémoire, nous avons effectué une évaluation de l’algorithme Monte Carlo (MC) de calcul de dose (pour les faisceaux d’électrons) du programme de planification en radiothérapie connu sous le nom d’Eclipse. Dans cette évaluation, nous avons utilisé des fantômes solides contenant des tissue de densités diverses (eau, poumon, os, air) ainsi que des images scanner d’un patient réel (humain). Pour les fantômes solides notre évaluation a été faite en comparant les calculs d’Eclipse à des mesures expérimentales utilisant des films EBT Gafchromic d’une part, et d’autre part à des calculs MC plus rigoureux utilisant DOSXYZnrc. Pour le cas d’un patient, nous évaluons Eclipse en le comparant aux résultats MC obtenu via DOSXYZnrc, parce que nous ne pouvons placer un dosimètre à l’intérieur du patient. Nos résultats indiquent que les résultats MC sont plus proches des mesures expérimentales (écarts de l’ordre de 5% ou moins) que ceux d’Eclipse, lesquels ont un écart pouvant atteindre a peu près 15% par rapport aux mesures dans le cas des fantômes et 10% par rapport aux résultats MC pour le cas du patient réel. Les pires imprécisions d’Eclipse MC se retrouvent dans les tissus au voisinage des régions où il y a de fortes hetérogénéités et où les gradients de densités sont importants. En effet, les résultats obtenus par d’Eclipse MC pour le cas d’un patient ré</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brigitte Reniers</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p11p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn824</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn568"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Estimation of intensity duration frequency curves for current and future climate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Desramaut, Nicolas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La variabilité et les changements climatiques devraient avoir des impacts considérables sur le cycle hydrologique aux différentes échelles spatio-temporelles. Afin de construire des systèmes de drainage durables, les ingénieurs se doivent de prendre en considération ses modifications probables dans leur simulation. Toutefois, si les Modèles de Circulation Globale (MCG) sont capables de reproduire raisonnablement bien les caractéristiques à grande échelle du climat, leurs résolutions sont trop grossières pour permettre une utilisation immédiate de leurs informations dans les modélisations urbaines.Cette étude propose une approche de mise à l’échelle statistique, basée sur les propriétés d’invariance d’échelle, afin d’incorporer les résultats des MCG dans la conception des courbes Intensité-Durée-Fréquence (IDF) futures. Ces courbes sont ensuite utilisées pour l’estimation de l’évolution des quantités de ruissèlement. Enfin, une analyse régionale permet une évaluation des paramètres de réduction d’échelle pour des stations partiellement jaugées, voir non jaugées. C’est ainsi que des courbes IDF peuvent être construites avec un nombre limité de données.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Climate variability and change are expected to have important impacts on the hydrologic cycle at different temporal and spatial scales In order to build long-lasting drainage systems, civil engineers and urban planners should take into account these potential impacts in their hydrological simulations. However, even if Global Climate Models (GCM) are able to describe the large-scale features of the climate reasonably well, their coarse spatial and temporal resolutions prevent their outputs from being used directly in impact assessment models at regional or local scales.   This study proposes a statistical downscaling approach, based on the scale invariance concept, to incorporate GCM outputs in the derivation of Intensity-Duration-Frequency (IDF) curves and the estimation of urban design storms for current and future climates under different climate change scenarios. The estimated design storms were then used in the estimations of runoff peaks and volumes for urban watersheds of different shapes and different levels of surface imperviousness using the  popular Storm Water Management Model (SWMM). Finally, a regional analysis was performed to estimate the scaling parameters of extreme rainfall processes for locations with limited or without data. In summary, results of an illustrative application of the proposed statistical downscaling approach using rainfall data available in Quebec (Canada) have indicated that it is feasible to estimate the IDF relations and the resulting design storms and runoff characteristics for current and future climates in consideration of GCM-based climate change scenarios. Furthermore, based on the proposed regional analysis of the scaling properties of extreme rainfalls in Singapore, it has been demonstrated that it is feasible to estimate the IDF curves for partially-gaged or ungaged sites.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Van-Thanh-Van Nguyen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz752.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn568</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Hydrology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nc70c"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating techniques to accurately calibrate non-standard fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sutherland, Justin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Récemment, le domaine de la radiothérapie par faisceaux externes a vu une augmentation de l’utilisation de champs non-standards; ceux-ci composés de plusieurs petits champs ou bien de champs où les conditions de déséquilibre des particules chargées existent. Puisque les protocoles actuels de dosimétrie de référence ne couvrent pas les conditions de ces champs non-standards, un nouveau formalisme pour la dosimétrie de référence des petits et non-standards champs a récemment été proposé, introduisant un champ de référence spéciﬁque pour chaque classe (localisation) de plan de traitement. Ce champ de référence spéciﬁque représenterait une classe spéciﬁque de traitement non-standard et fournirait une étape intermédiaire entre le champ de référence et un traitement clinique. Le but de cette étude était de créer un champ de référence spéciﬁque pour un traitement IMRT ORL et d’établir une méthode déterminant le facteur de correction de qualité du champ de référence spéciﬁque. Ce facteur de correction est utilisé pour passer des conditions de référence aux conditions du champ de référence spéciﬁque. La méthode créée incluait l’utilisation d’une chambre d’ionisation, les mesures d’un ﬁlm Gafchromic ainsi que l’utilisation des ﬁchiers MLC dynalog, utilisés avec les simulations Monte Carlo EGSnrc, pour déterminer le facteur. La méthode était trouvée eﬃcace lorsque le facteur de correction de qualité du champ de référence spéciﬁque était déterminé pour toute la réalisation du plan mais échouait sous l’examen faisceau par faisceau du facteur.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Recently, the ﬁeld of external beam radiation therapy has seen an increase in the use of non-standard ﬁelds; those composed of many small ﬁelds or any ﬁeld where charged particle disequilibrium conditions exist. Since current clinical reference dosimetry protocols do not cover the conditions of these non-standard ﬁelds a new formalism for reference dosimetry of small and non-standard ﬁelds has recently been proposed, introducing a plan-class speciﬁc reference ﬁeld (pcsr ). This pcsr would represent a speciﬁc class of non-standard delivery and provide an intermediate step between the conventional reference ﬁeld and a clinical delivery. The purpose of this study was to create a pcsr for an ear-nose-throat IMRT delivery as well as to establish a method of determining the pcsr quality correction factor used to convert calibration coeﬃcients in reference conditions to those under pcsr conditions.  The method created included the use of ionization chamber and GafChromic ﬁlm measurements to determine the factor as well as the use of MLC dynalog ﬁles to be used with EGSnrc Monte Carlo simulation to calculate the factor. The method was found to work well in determining the pcsr quality correction factor for the full  delivery of the pcsr plan but failed under a beam-by-beam examination of the factor.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jan Peter Frans Seuntjens</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935454q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc70c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945s43n"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relativistic hydrodynamics and electromagnetic radiation in relativistic nuclear collisions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Labrecque, Rémi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le model d'évolution hydrodynamique relativiste a décrit avec succès les propriétésd'ensemble des données sur les hadron "soft" produit au RHIC, incluant le flot elliptique. Dans ce travail, nous avons appliqué l'hydrodynamique relativiste aux phasesde plasma de quark et de gluons (PQG) et hadronique créées dans les collisions àhautes énergies aux Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider et Super Proton Synchrotron.Nous étudions le spectre et le flot elliptique des dileptons produits dans ces collisionsd'ions lourds.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Relativistic Hydrodynamics has successfully described the bulk of the data on soft hadrons at the Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider (RHIC), including the elliptic flow and the momentum spectra. In this work, we apply the hydrodynamic evolution model to the quark-gluon plasma (QGP) and hadronic phases created in relativistic heavy-ion collision at RHIC and at the Super Proton Synchrotron for different systems and energies. In these conditions, we calculate the spectra of dileptons and their elliptic flow.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Charles Gale</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n015f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s43n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Theory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gv15x"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>New virtual screening tools for molecular discovery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Corbeil, Christopher</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dans le domaine pharmaceutique, le criblage virtuel de large bibliothèques de molécules est une alternative moins couteuse et souvent au moins aussi efficace que le criblage à haut débit. D’ailleurs, le développement de tels outils –et plus particulierement de méthodes de "docking"–  a permis au criblage virtuelle de devenir pratique courante dans l’industrie pharmaceutique. Cependant, la plupart des méthodes de docking ne prennent pas en compte la dynamique des complexes protéine/ligand et plus spécifiquement la flexibilité des protéines et la présence de molécules d’eau nécessaires à une liaison optimale. Dans cette optique, FITTED1.0 a été développé et validé sur un jeu de 33 complexes protéine/ligand. Ainsi, FITTED1.0 permet de modéliser des complexes ternaires protéine/ligand/eau entièrement flexibles. D’autres développements ont ensuite été nécessaires pour en accroître la rapidité et permettre son utilisation pour le criblage de larges bibliothèques. Cette version améliorée, FITTED1.5, a été appliquée au criblage de la bibliothèque Maybridge sur la polymérase du virus de l’hépatite C et a permis la découverte de deux nouveaux inhibiteurs. Après ces résultats très encourageants, une étude comparative a été entreprise visant spécifiquement à évaluer l’impact des données d’entrées sur le pouvoir prédictif des programmes de docking les plus couramment utilisés incluant FITTED2.6. Nous avons alors démontré que la présence d’eau, la conformation du ligand et de la protéine au départ du calcul ont un impact majeur. En parallèle, nous avons bénéficié de notre expertise pour développer un second outil de criblage virtuel ACE1.0 mais cette fois appliqué au criblage de catalyseurs asymétriques. Dans le domaine de la catalyse asymétrique, il nous fallait prédire la structure et l’énergie potentielle des états de transition et ce, dans un temps raisonnable. Pour ce faire, ACE cr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In the field of molecular discovery, virtually screening large libraries of compounds proved to be often more cost-efficient than the traditional experimental approaches. In fact, it has now become common practice thanks to the virtual screening tools available to chemists in the pharmaceutical industry, specifically docking. Most docking programs do not account for the dynamics associated with protein-ligand binding whether it is protein flexibility or the inclusion of displaceable water molecules. FITTED1.0 was developed to include these specific two features and has been validated on a testing set of 33 protein-ligand complexes. Further developments were needed to increase the speed of FITTED to enable its application as virtual screening tool. This enhanced version, FITTED1.5, has been applied to the screening of the Maybridge library onto the HCV polymerase and revealed FITTED’S ability to identify active substances. With this and other successful applications of FITTED, a comparative study was performed against other docking programs, with a specific interest in the effect of the ligand and protein input conformation and the inclusion of bridging water molecules on the accuracy of docking programs. All three had major effects on accuracy and led to suggestions on how to better conduct comparative studies. In parallel, we applied our expertise in the virtual screening area to the field of asymmetric catalyst development and led to the creation of ACE1.0. When creating a tool for predicting steroselectivities, one has to describe the transition state with great accuracy although within a reasonable amount of time. To tackle this problem, ACE creates the transition states from linear combinations of reactant and product interactions. A genetic algorithm is then exploited as a conformational search engine to optimize the TS structure. ACE has been applied to the Diels-Alder cycloaddition and the proline-catalysed aldol reactions and has showed good correlatio</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nicolas Moitessier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418p77x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv15x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Pharmaceutical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128ng18h"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Physical interface design for digital musical instruments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marshall, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse porte sur l'étude de l'interaction ayant lieu, en situation de jeu,entre un(e) instrumentiste et un instrument musical numérique (IMN).A l'inverse des instruments acoustiques traditionnels, il n'existe aucun couplageentre le dispositif de production du son et l'interface sur laquelle agit l'instrumentistedans le cas des IMN. L'une des implications de cette observation est que cesinstruments ne procurent pas la rétroaction tactile normalement présente dans lesinstruments de musique traditionels. Par conséquent, les IMN sont souvent perçuspar leurs interprètes comme manquant d'âme, de personnalité.Le but de ce travail de thèse est d'avancer quelques solutions permettant d'insuer un peu plus âme à un instrument musical numérique. Le point focal de larecherche étant l'étude et la conception de l'interface physique (corps de l'instrument,capteurs et dispositifs de rétroaction utilisés) d'un tel instrument.Ce mémoire présente, en premier lieu, une étude détaillée de la théorie et de lapratique actuelles dans le domaine de la conception d'interfaces physiques pour lesIMN. L'inventaire des 266 instruments recensés depuis la création de la conférenceNIME constitue l'un des points majeurs de cette partie du travail. En effet, ce tour d'horizon permet de faire ressortir les incohérences entre théorie et pratique. Cesdifférences sont particulièrement frappantes en ce qui concerne les capteurs et lesdispositifs de rétroaction.Le travail de recherche de cette thèse a donc pour objectif de mieux comprendrecomment réduire ces incohérences. Des expériences portant sur le choix optimaldes capteurs à utiliser dans un IMN ont donc été menées. Différents dispositifs derétroaction vibrotactile ont aussi été étudiés en regardant d'abord quels actuateursutiliser, et en évaluant les effets de la modication de leur réponse en fréquencesur la discrimination fréquentielle de stimuli vibrotactiles chez des sujets humains.Des exemp</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with the study of performer-instrument interaction during the performance of novel digital musical instruments (DMIs).  Unlike acoustic instruments, digital musical instruments have no coupling between the sound generation system and the physical interface with which the performer interacts. As a result of this, such instruments also lack the direct physical feedback to the performer which is present in an acoustic instrument. In fact in contrast to acoustic musical instruments, haptic and vibrotactile feedback is generally not present in a DMI contributing to a poor feel for the instrument. The main goal of this thesis is to propose ways to improve the overall feel of digital musical instruments through the study and design of its physical interface: the instrument body, sensors and feedback actuators.   It includes a detailed study of the existing theory and practice of the design on physical interfaces for digital musical instruments, including a survey of 266 existing DMIs presented since the inception of the NIME conference. From this, a number of differences become apparent between the existing theory and practice, particularly in the areas of sensors and feedback.  The research in this thesis then addresses these differences. It includes a series of experiments on the optimal choice of sensors for a digital musical instrument. This is followed by research into the provision of vibrotactile feedback in a digital musical instrument, including the choice of actuator, modification of actuator frequency response, and the effects of response modification on human vibrotactile frequency discrimination.  Following this, a number of new digital musical instruments are presented, which were created during the course of this work. This includes an instrument designed specifically to follow the results of research in this thesis and also instruments designed as part of larger collaborative projects involving engineers, composers and performers.   Fro</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marcelo Wanderley</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f79m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng18h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p8661"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A longitudinal study of changes in physical activity during adolescence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bélanger, Mathieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>BACKGROUND: The majority of people worldwide, including 90% of Canadian adolescents, do not meet recommendations on physical activity. A better understanding of how, when, and why physical activity declines during adolescence is needed.   OBJECTIVES: Among adolescents, 1) document how weather conditions affect physical activity; 2) determine whether participants enrolled in organised physical activities maintain healthier activity levels; 3) identify periods of marked decline in participation in specific physical activities; and 4) describe patterns of physical activity participation over five years.  METHODS: A 7-day physical activity recall was completed by 1293 adolescents, initially aged 12-13 years, every 3 months over 5 years. The association between number of physical activity sessions daily, and each of season and weather conditions was assessed in Poisson regression models with random effects. Generalized estimating equation Poisson regressions were used to compare rates of decline in number of activity sessions per week between students who participated in organised physical activity in grade 7 and those who did not. We used survival analyses to ascertain when discontinuation of specific activities occurred among adolescents who reported the activity at baseline. Finally, latent class growth curve models were used to identify classes of participants with similar physical activity trajectories during adolescence.    RESULTS: First analysis: Levels of physical activity were lowest during winter. Because warm-month increases did not compensate for winter decreases, activity declined by 7% yearly on average. Although statistically significant, the effect of weather on activity was modest. Second analysis: Adolescents who participated in organised physical activities in grade 7 reported 42% more activities on average than other active adolescents. However, organised activities did not protect against declines in physical activity. Third analysis: Within two</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>PROBLÉMATIQUE : La plupart des gens à travers le monde, incluant 90% des adolescents canadiens, n’atteignent pas les niveaux d’activité physique recommandés. Une meilleure compréhension de comment, quand, et pourquoi les niveaux d’activité physique des adolescents décline est essentielle.   OBJECTIFS : Chez les adolescents, 1) documenter comment les conditions météorologiques influencent la participation à l’activité physique; 2) déterminer si les participants impliqués dans des activités physiques organisées maintiennent des niveaux d’activité physique plus sains; 3) identifier les périodes où la participation à des activités physiques spécifiques décline de façon marquée; et 4) décrire les profils de participation à l’activité physique sur une période de cinq ans.MÉTHODES : Un questionnaire de rappel des activités physiques des sept derniers jours a été complété par 1293 adolescents, initialement âgés de 12 à 13 ans, à tous les trois mois pendant cinq ans. L’association entre le nombre d’activités physiques par jour et les saisons et les conditions météorologiques a été évaluée à partir de régressions de Poisson avec effets aléatoires. Des régressions de Poisson dans un contexte d’analyses populationnelles ont été utilisées pour comparer les rythmes de déclins du nombre de sessions d’activité physique par semaine entre les élèves impliqués dans des activités organisées en 7e année scolaire et d’autres qui ne l’étaient pas. Nous avons utilisé des analyses de survies pour déterminer le moment où les adolescents interrompaient des activités physiques spécifiques. Finalement, des analyses de croissance de classes latentes ont servi à identifier des groupes de participants présentant des trajectoires similaires en termes de participation à l’activité physique.  RÉSULTATS : Première analyse: Les niveaux d’activité physique sont plus bas pendant l’hiver. Parce que l</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Katherine Gray-Donald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j272d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p8661</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>