<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892d411"><ual:graduationDate>2017</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating the role of mitochondrial-anchored protein ligase in: cell migration, the actin cytoskeleton and oligodendrocyte development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dixon, James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mitochondrial-anchored protein ligase (MAPL) is a mitochondrial E3 SUMO (Small Ubiquitin-like Modifier) ligase. Our lab has shown that through its substrates, it regulates a variety of cell processes, from apoptosis to hepatic bile acid synthesis. Here, the role of MAPL is investigated in three areas of cell biology: cell migration, actin cytoskeleton and oligodendrocyte development.Firstly, using MAPL knock out (KO) mouse embryonic fibroblasts and thymocytes, we characterized an actin phenotype and defect in directional cell migration. This work identified a role for MAPL in the regulation of cell migration and the actin cytoskeleton. These insights can help us better understand the role of mitochondria in physiological processes where cell migration is implicated, such as during cancer metastasis and in the immune system.Secondly, we demonstrated oligodendrocyte development as a potential model to investigate MAPL function. Preliminary work here has shown that over wild type oligodendrocyte development there is: an expansion of peroxisomes and mitochondria, distinct populations of peroxisomes, and peroxisomes within the myelin sheath in vitro. Early work suggests that de novo peroxisome biogenesis may not be occurring in these cells. Preliminary investigation of MAPL KO oligodendrocytes revealed a potential role for MAPL in cell spreading and oligodendrocyte differentiation. This work positions oligodendrocytes as an excellent model to interrogate MAPL function. This work also provides novel insights into oligodendrocyte organelle biology and oligodendrocyte development. These insights can help develop therapeutic avenues for those living with demyelinating diseases such as Multiple Sclerosis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mitochondrial-anchored protein ligase (MAPL) est une E3-SUMO ligase localisée à la mitochondrie et dans une sous-population de peroxisomes. Notre groupe a démontré qu'en modifiant ses substrats, MAPL est capable de réguler plusieurs processus cellulaires comme par exemples l'apoptose ou la synthèse d'acide biliaire. Dans cette thèse, j'explore le rôle de MAPL dans trois processus pour lesquels le rôle de MAPL n'est pas déjà connu : la migration cellulaire, le cytosquelette d'actine, et le développement d'oligodendrocytes. D'abord, en utilisant des fibroblastes embryonnaires et des thymocytes de souris MAPL-/, je caractérise un phénotype d'actine et un défaut dans la migration directionnelle des cellules. Ces résultats indiquent un rôle pour MAPL dans la régulation de la migration cellulaire et du cytosquelette d'actine. Ces idées offrent une compréhension plus profonde au sujet du rôle de la mitochondrie dans des processus physiologiques pour lesquels la migration est nécessaire, comme la métastase du cancer et pendant l'infection. Deuxièmement, je démontre le potentiel d'utilisation du développement d'oligodendrocyte pour investiguer le rôle de MAPL. Les travaux préliminaires indiquent que pendant le développement d'oligodendrocyte normal, il y a : une expansion des mitochondries et peroxisomes, des populations distinctes de peroxisomes, et des peroxisomes dans la gaine de myéline in vitro. Les résultats préliminaires suggèrent que la synthèse de novo de peroxisomes ne se produit pas pendant ce stade de développement, et les oligodendrocytes MAPL-/- démontrent un rôle potentiel pour MAPL pendant l'écartement cellulaire et la différenciation de l'oligodendrocyte. Ces résultats suggèrent que l'oligodendrocyte est un modèle idéal pour investiguer la fonction de MAPL.  Ce travail a fourni des idées nouvelles sur la biologie des organelles dans les oligodendrocytes, ce qui pourrait mener au développement d'avenues thérapeutiques pour les gens atteints de maladies démyélinisantes comme la sclérose en plaques.   </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Heidi McBride</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29bb24n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892d411</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>