<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b6837"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stochastic and sampling processes for the logarithmic series distribution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shorrock, Richard William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several stochastic and sampling processes leading to the logarithmic series distributions and related distributions are studied. An attempt has been made to present a unified picture, using a single notation, of the various derivations and approaches that appear in the literature. These derivations and approaches are compared and some of the relationships among them are brought out. Though the work is mainly interpretative, there are a few results that seem to be new. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Seshadri, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p60j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b6837</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Statistics, Mathematical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stochastics processes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj139546m"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Petpides of the hypothalamus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shome, Sasudev</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The hypothalamus is that part of the forebrain which forms the floor of the third ventricle in immediate topographical relation with the pituitary gland (1). The limiting boundary of the hypothalamus is ill-defined. It extends, without any sharp line of demarcation, into the parolfactory region of the telencephalon anteriorly and into the tegmental part of the mid-brain posteriorly. Laterally the hypothalamus is direct1y continuous with the subthalamus (1). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Saffran, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb78g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139546m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33s104f"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immunochemical studies of the nervous system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sherwin, Allan L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is concerned with the demonstration of the immunochemical specificity of central and peripheral nervous system antigens. Early observations of occasional "neuroparalytic" accidents following immunization with rabies vaccine containing nervous tissue antigens gave rise to speculations that immunological reactions could lead to clinical disease (Stuart, 1925). In subsequent years, neurological syndromes following inoculation of various vaccines, injections of foreign serum or associated with certain infectious diseases such as measles have become increasingly recognized (Miller, Stanton and Gibbons, 1956). These hypersensitivity reactions affect various parts of the nervous system resulting in encephalitis, myelitis or neuritis. In addition, many spontaneously occurring neurological disorders such as the Guillain-Barré syndrome (Melnick, 1963) and neurological complications associated with the collagen disorders are suspected of being the result of hypersensitivity reactions (Gell and Coombs, 1964). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cosgrove, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s409.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s104f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mg28d"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nucleolar characteristics in purkinje cells of the mouse during postnatal differentiation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shea, John R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nucleoli of differentiating cells have long attracted the interest of investigators because of their variahility in number, volume and cytochemical features. Such variations have commonly been related to the physiochemical and cytochemical organization of the nucleolus. Specifically, the nucleolus has been considered an organelle of extreme plasticity, consisting of an apparently homogeneous ground substance (nucleolar matrix) which occasionally contains one or more vesicles (intranucleolar vacuoles or nucleolini). Relevant cytochemical and biochemical studies have indicated that these structural phases are composed of acid and basic proteins and RNA in the form of ribonucleoproteins. In brief, the classical concept of nucleolar structure recognized two intranucleolar structural phases -- nucleolar matrix and intranucleolar vacuoles -- composed of nucleolar ribonucleoproteins (reviews, Montgomery, 1898; Oates, 1942; Vincent, 1955; Stich, 1956; Hertl, 1957; Swift, 1959; Sirlin, 1962; Busch et al, 1963). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leblond, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c5988.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mg28d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd3761075"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biosynthesis of C19 steroids in normal human adrenal tissue</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shapiro, Martin I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The fundamental discovery by investigators at the Worcester Foundation that perfused bovine adrenals can hydroxylate steroids (1, 2) opened the way for numerous studies concerning the biosynthesis of steroids in endocrine tissue. To catalogue the reported findings which have since been published would not be possible in a thesis. As a result, the survey of the literature in this section will be confined to those reports which are most relevant to the investigations to be described. A number of comprehensive reviews and chapters are referred to which have discussed the biosynthesis of steroids fully (3-12). In addition, this author would like to refer to the excellent review of cholesterol biosynthesis by Tchen (13) and to a survey of the literature on adrenal androgens by Dorfman (5) . [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Solomon, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm64v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd3761075</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1619634"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relation between environmental factors and transfer in learning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shannon, Elizabeth Baillie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present investigation is concerned with the relation between environmental factors and the ability to transfer. Although many studies in the past have shown that differences in environment result in differences in I.Q., as measured by conventional intelligence tests, there has been less research measuring environmental effects on learning and transfer abilities. The typical approachof studies which deal with either differences in intelligence, or in learning and transfer abilities, has been to select subjects from different environments and, by testing, demonstrate significant differences in the ability in question. Using this method, the results invariably favor subjects from whichever is the "better" environment in the study. The present study treats environment as an independant variable, holding I.Q. constant, and attempts to show differences in transfer ability, the dependent variable, under these conditions. On the basis of the theoretical considerations and empirical results reviewed below, it was hypothesized that, with I.Q. held constant,children raised in a "restricted" environment would show greater facility for transfer than children from a "free" environment.  [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ferguson, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903337z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1619634</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human beings -- Effect of environment on</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A765374360"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Architecture</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Architecture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The clustering of skyscrapers with special reference to Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shank, Wesley Ivan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>All experience combines the esthetic, visual experience with other 1evels of experience -- from the pbilosophical 1evel to the practical leve1 of how to find one's way around. Thus, I have considered a broad range of information relating to the clustering of skyscrapers. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Spence-Sales, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j68m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765374360</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Architecture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Skyscrapers -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Buildings, structures, etc</dc:subject><dc:subject>Skyscrapers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Skyscrapers -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wk46t"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Carboydrate metabolism in normal and regenerating rat liver</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seshachalam, Dutta</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The phenomenon of regeneration in various animals as a distinct form of growth has interested classical biologists for over two centuries and it has been viewed as a particular case of a general phenomenon of growth. The literature pertaining to this historical era of development in morphological thought has been adequately reviewed by D'Arcy Thompson (1). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j54s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk46t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dg99v"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Carbohydrate metabolism in normal and regenerating rat liver</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seguin, Maurice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The system Fe-C-0-S was studied in detail in the temperature range 75°-800°C. In general, when H2o was added to the system, it lowered the stability of the assemblages by some l5°-20°C. The limit of stabi lity of siderite in presence of the following assemblages was determined for total pressures of 2OOO, 1000 and approximate1y 1 bar. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb79h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dg99v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395wb96d"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The parliamentary question in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Segal, Norton Hart</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many of the institutions of Canada are modelled upon those of Great Britain. Since the origin of the Canadian question period are founded on those of Great Britain, a brief preliminary discussion of the British practices is necessary. Thus the first chapter of this thesis will be devoted to a study of the question period at Westminster, from its origins in 1731 until it evolved into its modern form in the closing years of the nineteenth century. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mallory, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60d099m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb96d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada. Parliament</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pk630"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of German</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Die Gestalten im erzählerischen Werk Heinrich Bölls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schwarz, Wilhelm Johannes, 1929-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Der erste Weltkrieg endete mit einer nur unvollkommenen Niederlage Deutschlands. Zur Zeit des Waffenstillstandes standen deutsche Heere in Rußland, in der Ukraine, in Belgien und in Frankreich. Wilsons vierzehn Punkte schienen eine bessere Zukunft zu verheißen, dooh es zeigte sich sehr bald, daß England und Frankreich nicht gewillt waren, auf die Früchte eines vierjahrigen Kampfes zu verzichten. Wilson verlor das Vertrauen seiner Landsleute, und Amerika zog sich sehließlich entmutigt von allen weiteren Verhandlungen über das Schicksal der besiegten Machte zurück. Wilsons Selbstbestimmungsreoht der Volker wurde allen zivilisierten Nationen zugestanden-- außer den besiegten Mittelmächten. Osterreioh bemühte sich um Eingliederung in das Deutsche Reich, die ihm jedoch von den Alliierten verweigert wurde. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reiss, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sx29c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk630</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Böll, Heinrich, 1917-1985 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>German Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nj110"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship of antibodies to autologous hepatocellular antigens and liver damage in experimental animals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sargent, Austin U.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Prometheus, creator of mankind, stole fire from the chariot of the sun and in defiance of the all-powerful Zeus gave it to mankind. Zeus, enraged, had Prometheus chained to a mountain pillar where greedy vultures tore at his liver all day, year in and year out. There was to be no end to Prometheus' punishment since each night his liver grew whole again (1). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rose, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q921.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj110</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asf268870f"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Entropy and the control of stochastic processes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sankoff, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis will deal with a problem involving the concept of "entropy production". General formulations of most parts of this problem will be given, as well as a complete solution to a specific example.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Seshadri, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149t020.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268870f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vv294"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The organizational factor in the economic development of traditional and peasant societies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sankoff, Gillian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis I shall consider the process of economic change in tribal and peasant societies, and show how traditional principles of social and economic organization within these societies are related to such change. I shall be aoncerned with how far "organization" may be treated as a factor in development apart from and in conjunction with such factors as "capital", "values", "innovation", etc. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Salisbury, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw012.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vv294</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Peasants</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antrhopology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rural development</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d570104t"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relativistic wave equations and the equations of motion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sanders, John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Many theories have been advanced which avoid the difficulties of the Maxwell Electrodynamics; most of these have been quite successful classically, but present difficulties upon quantization. The theory that will be discussed here is a linear one which is closely related to those of Feynman (1) and Lehmann (2), and which is perhaps more easily adaptable to a quantum theory than to a classical one. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morris, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh04p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570104t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z427r"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The biology and dynamics of the oystershell scale, Lepidosaphes Ulmi (L.) (Homoptera: Coccidae), on apple in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Samarasinghe, Srimathie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The quantification of population and mortality data for insect pests of apple is necessary if we are to gain fundamental insight in the dynamics of insect populations of the orchard ecosystem. The need to quantify has recently been emphasized (LeRoux, 1964a; 1964b) and the greater application, practical and scientific, or the quantitative results obtained for agricultural and forest insect pests has been demonstrated (LeRoux et al., 1963). [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leroux, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30px25h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z427r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apples -- Diseases and pests</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oyster-shell scale</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kt84v"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining Engineering and Applied Geophysics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Adsorption of hexyl mercaptan on sphalerite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Salman, Talat M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a report on the construction, calibration and use of the universal B.E.T. apparatus for the determination of the specific surfaces, and the adsorption-desorption isotherms of a vapour phase mercaptan on solid adsorbent systems. Examples are given for the determination of large (to 2000 m2jg) and small (200 cm2/g - 1 m2/g) specific surfaces. A gravimetric McBain-Bakr micro balance is incorporated in the B.E.T. apparatus for the determination of the adsorption isotherms of hexyl mercaptan vapour on synthetic sphalerite, zinc sulphide and zinc oxide. Adsorption isotherms are given for hexyl mercaptan on synthetic sphalerite at 25°C, 0.5°C and 50°C; on zinc sulphide at 25°C and 1.5°C and on zinc oxide at 25°C. All these isotherms are sigmoidal with a definite change in slope at the monolayero The amount of mercaptan adsorbed after the monolayer increases almost linearly with relative pressure to P/P0 = 0.8. Above this value the amount adsorbed increases very rapidly vrith relative pressure. Hysteresis loops appear in the isotherms for all adsorption-desorption cycles. These loops are completely reversible. It is not possible to desorb the mercaptan monolayer from any of the adsorbents even at elevated temperatures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robertson, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z4281.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kt84v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r659x"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inelastic pion-nucleus scattering</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saif-Ud-Din</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the near future it is expected that one will have large enough fluxes of charged pions such that these mesons will make good nuclear probes. They interact strongly with the nucleus and yet do not form a compound state. Since pions form an isotopic triplet state allowing both single and double charge exchange scattering, new isobaric states can be investigated. In general the nucleus which is formed by π + to π double charge exchange is proton rich and has not been produced before. Another interesting aspect of pions at about 400 MeV energy is their predominant p-wave interaction with the nucleus and the ability of the pion to be totally absorbed, dumping 140 MeV into the nucleus at once. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Margolis, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m634.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r659x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881q47v"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nuclear reactions induced in yttrium-89 by 5-85 Mev protons</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saha, Gopal B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Excitation functions for the (p,xn} (x = 1-4) and (p,pxn) (x= l-5) reactions induced in Y89 by 5-85 Mev protons have been measured by radiochemical techniques. The measured excitation functions have been compared with the statistical theory and cascade-evaporation calculations. Comparison shows that compound nucleus formation is the principal reaction mechanism at energies up to 25-30 Mev. At higher energies the probability of compound nucleus formation decreases and direct interactions predominate. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Porile, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf57g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881q47v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn3014788"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of nucleic acids in transplantation immunity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sabbadini, Edris</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Before immunity was demonstrated to be a major factor in homograft rejection, sorne hypotheses have been suggested to explain the destruction of the transplants. Sorne of them could have still importance although the immunological hypothesis is well established. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bg077.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3014788</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75rc348"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental studies on oesophageal replacement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rygiel, Witold W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The earliest description of oesophageal atresia as a pathological entity was given by William Durston (1) in 1670. The first typical case of oesophageal atresia with tracheo-oesophageal fistula was recognized by Thomas Gibson (2) in 1697. Since then an increasing number of reports appeared. In 1861 Hirschsprung (3) presented 10 cases of oesophageal atresia in 1880 Mackenzie (4) collected 37 cases, in 1919 Plass (5) collected cases reported to that date numbering 136. Rosenthal (6) in 1931 reviewed the world literature pertaining to the subject and collected 255 cases. In the last 25 years the malformation has been recognized with increasing frequency and numerous large series have appeared in the literature. Attention has been centered not only on the correct diagnosis but also on the surgical treatment of this anomaly. Varied concepts of surgical approach and a large body of experimental work have found their way into the medical journals. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murphy, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301479j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc348</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apn89d989d"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parental perceptions of the school and work plans of adolescent boys</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ryant, Joseph C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...] It is in response to these three facts that parents become concerned with and involved in preparing their son to choose: (1) there is a real choice to be made, (2) the choice is a critical one in terms of its implications for future social status, and (3) there is the expectation that it is the son, and not the parents, who will make it. The involvement is inevitable insofar as the process of occupational choice has its roots back in childhood when the child is very much under the control and influence of the parents. The process of socialization interacts with the process of occupational choice, and it is the purpose of this study to trace some of the interconnections between the two processes. It will examine parental perceptions of the child, of the kinds of choices that should be made, of the various mechanisms available to parents as means of influencing their sons and of those means which they actually employ in order that their influence be felt. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dodd, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gx117.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d989d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655k87m"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Metabolism of 16 alpha hydroxylated steroids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ruse, James L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The occurrence of neutral 16-hydroxylated steroids in biological materials has been recognized for many years. In 1940, Marker and Turner (1) demonstrated the presence of a 16-hydroxy group in a steroid isolated 7 years previously by Smith et al from pregnant mares urine (2). It was not until 1945 however that Hirschmann (3) showed the compound to be 5α-pregnan-3ß,l6α,208-triol. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Biochemistry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq109.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k87m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fq304"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The pattern of politics and foreign policy advocacies in Burma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rudner, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a study of the pattern of politics and its effects on foreign policy advocacies in contemporary Burma. The focal point of the analysis is an examinatian of the various Burmese societal interests and their respective foreign policy demands.1 The methodology employed defines Burma's societal interest groupings in terms of ideology, interests, and objectives, While providing a functional mode! for the understanding of Burmese political processes. Foreign policy demands are to be classified as to bilateral relations with neighbours, to the Southern Asian international system, and to the global state system. The purpose of this study is to discover the socio-political mainsprings of the foreign policy demands articulated by both incumbent and competing societal interests. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steingberg, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g837n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fq304</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>BURMA -- FOREIGN POLICY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BURMA -- POLITICS</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128f46k"><ual:graduationDate>1966</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Depletion and repletion of spermatogonia following X-irradiation of the rat testis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dym, Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...] The affects of irradiation on the rat's testis will be the subject of the present work. It is hoped that the results will throw an additional light on the behaviour of the heterogenous spermatogonial population following irradiation, and in particular will explain how repopulation of the seminiferous epithelium takes place. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clermont, Y.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z155k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128f46k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>