<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924d770"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dualities in operational form</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Egger, Jeffrey M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In (2), Brian Davey poses the question: "Which finite algebras admit a duality?" The answer to this question has eluded mathematicians for many years and a simple characterization of those algebras which are dualizable (in a reasonable way) seems an unlikely feat. I will consider the question "Which finite (operational) algebras admit a duality which may be expressed in a purely operational form?". This is a substantially less ambitious question, for there are many algebras which are dualizable but not operationally so. However, it does have a clear answer.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Makkai, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw118.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d770</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343v11n"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Capillary flow of non-Newtonian fluids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ducharme, Réjean, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The flow of a two-dimensional incompressible non-Newtonian fluid, showing a viscoelastic behavior, has been studied using the White-Metzner model with a phenomenological law for the viscosity, the Spriggs' truncated power-law model. Our goal was to determine if these models could generate the oscillating instabilities appearing in such fluids at very high driving force. We studied the effect of various quantities on the time-dependent numerical simulations and noticed that the mesh length was not very important for the accuracy of the results. However, the time constant modulus appearing in the White-Metzner model and the applied pressure were of paramount importance for the relaxation time of a disruptive flow. We thus showed that this model was effective only at low pressure and that without adding new aspects to the study of the flow, such as compressibility, we could not obtain any oscillating flow at high pressure. Despite this fact, exact steady-state solutions, as well as a time-dependant solution in the case of very small Reynolds number ($R to$ 0), have been given.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grant, Martin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v371.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v11n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z7436"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Determination of peroxide value and anisidine value using Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dubois, Janie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lipid oxidation has important consequences in the edible oil industry, producing compounds with sensory impact and thus reducing the economic value of the products. This work focused on the development of two Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy methods for the measurement of peroxide value (PV) and anisidine value (AV), representing the primary and secondary oxidation products of edible oils. The infrared method developed for PV determination was based on a mathematical treatment by the partial least squares method of the information contained in the spectral region between 3750 and 3150 cm$ sp{-1}$. The second method developed considered aldehyde content and anisidine value, a measure of secondary oxidation products. The two methods developed are rapid ($ sim$2 min/sample) and have the advantage of being automatable. An infrared system coupled to a computer can collect the spectrum of an oil, analyze it and present a report without the need for personnel trained in FTIR spectroscopy. The cost of such a system would rapidly be absorbed through savings on personnel cost, time and chemical reagents required for conventional chemical methods and as such provides a useful advance in quality control methodology for the edible oils sector. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Voort, Frederick R. Van de</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq90b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z7436</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lipids -- Oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aldehydes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oils and fats, Edible -- Analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peroxides</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pc53b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of Fusarium oxysporum as a bioherbicide for the control of Striga hermonthica (Del.) Benth</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Diarra, Cheickna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Growth chamber trials were performed to investigate optimal conditions for the small scale production of isolate M12-4A of Fusarium oxysporum on substrate materials that are locally available to subsistence farmers in West Africa. Field trials were conducted in Mali to evaluate the effectiveness of F. oxysporum for the control of Striga hermonthica and to determine the host range of F. oxysporum. F. oxysporum grew and colonized substrates over a range of temperatures (24, 28 and 32 C). Chopped sorghum straw pieces, straw fibres, and glumes supported abundant mycelial growth. Full colonization of the substrates was observed within 10 days. Production of infective propagules (microconidia and macroconidia) was optimum at 28 C. Optimum wetness of the substrates was obtained by soaking straw or glumes overnight. In field studies, the incorporation of 2.6 g of dried ground straw inoculum per sorghum seed pocket (120 cm$ sp2$), at a depth of 5 or 10 cm, resulted in a 60% reduction of emerged S. hermonthica 82 days after sowing. At harvest, biomass of Striga was also reduced by 70% and sorghum grain yield was almost doubled compared with the control. Sorghum, millet, maize, rice, fonio, cotton, cowpea, groundnut, okra and sorrel were immune to isolate M12-4A.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289m019.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc53b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fusarium oxysporum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Purple witchweed -- Biological control -- Mali</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515q542"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Human Communication Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le rôle de l'hémisphère droit dans le traitement des mots connotant une émotion et des mots dénotant une émotion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Delyfer, Annie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A lexical decision task and a semantic judgment task were conducted with eight right brain-damaged, six left brain-damaged and eight control subjects to explore the role of the right hemisphere in the processing of words that connote an emotion and of words that denote an emotion. Accuracy and reaction time data were measured in each experiment. Despite differences in the detailed patterns of responses across groups, there was little evidence to suggest that the right hemisphere is involved in the processing of the two kinds of emotional words. Valence (positive vs negative) had no influence on the results. Nor was there a difference between words that connote and words that denote an emotion. The results that were obtained are discussed in relation to hypotheses about the right hemisphere's role in the processing of emotional words.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, S. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v754z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q542</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Psychobiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language, Linguistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rq802"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of eastern James Bay Cree women's diets</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Delormier, Treena Wasonti:io</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Food use and nutrient intake were studied with Cree women of Wemindji and Eastmain, Quebec. Twenty-four hour recalls and food frequency questionnaires were used among three age groups of women and in two seasons. Age had an effect on the mean amount of traditional food consumed (p $&lt;$ 0.0001). Species and amounts of traditional food consumed varied by season. Ninety-four percent of women exceeded 2/3 of the recommended nutrient intake (RNI) for protein and 80% exceeded 2/3 of the RNI for iron, despite lower than recommended reported energy intakes. Calcium intakes of less than 1/2 the RNI were reported by 44% of women. Mean total fat intake reported by young and middle adults was greater than 30% of total energy. Qualitative inquiry into changing food use revealed that most women agree that traditional food use has declined for a variety of reasons, and that community residents should use more traditional food.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kuhnlein, Harriet V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x952.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq802</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cree women -- James Bay Region -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diet -- James Bay Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asb397b280"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of the potential of the exotic larval parasitoid Peristenus digoneutis Loan as a biological control agent against the tarnished plant bug, Lygus lineolaris (Palisot de Beauvois), in lettuce and celery crops in muck soils of southwestern Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carignan, Sylvie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the agricultural muck soil area of southwestern Quebec, two native parasitoids, Peristenus pallipes and P. pseudopallipes (Hymenoptera: Braconidae) were found to parasitize nymphs of the tarnished plant bug Lygus lineolaris (Hemiptera: Miridae), on various flowering plants and on cultivated lettuce. Parasitism levels (ranging from 1.3% to 92.3%) varied with host plant species sampled, and with methods used for the calculation of percentage parasitism. The percentage parasitism of tarnished plant bug populations was expressed as pooled values from all samples in the season (method 1), and by the Southwood and Jepson's graphical method (method 2). Phenology of parasitism, defined as the time during which female parasitoids are active in the field, was evaluated for both native parasitoid species. The cold-hardiness of P. digoneutis, a European nymph parasitoid introduced in northern United States, was evaluated in the laboratory by measuring the supercooling point and cumulative cold damage at sub-zero temperatures. When compared to the native P. pallipes and P. pseudopallipes the exotic parasitoid showed the same capacity to withstand cold temperatures. Prior to introduction, the evaluation of the impact of P. digoneutis on indigenous species will require a rapid identification to species level. The development of immature stages of P. digoneutis was studied to find taxonomic and developmental differences between the three species. At $21 pm1 sp circ$C, the egg matures in five days, and there are three larval instars, the first two molting inside the host while the third emerges from the host, three to four weeks after egg deposition. Adult characters of the pre-imaginal stage can be used to distinguish the exotic P. digoneutis from the two native species since mouth sclerites of the final instar larvae of P. digoneutis, P. pallipes and P. pseudopallipes do not possess reliable distinguishing characters. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boivin, Guy</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Stewart, Robin K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx46b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b280</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Celery -- Diseases and pests -- Biological control -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lettuce -- Diseases and pests -- Biological control -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tarnished plant bug -- Biological control -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peristenus digoneutis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10ws388"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis, characterization and a study of the physical properties of pyridinepyridinium based dialkynyl monomers, oligomers and polymers : enhancing conjugation by pyridine nitrogen quaternization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bunten, Kevin Andreas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The synthesis, characterization and an evaluation of the physical properties including infrared, UV-Vis absorption and fluorescence spectra, quantum yields and thermal stability of a variety of 2,5- and 2,6-diethynylypyridine based organic and Pt(II)-$ sigma$-acetylide monomers, oligomers and polymers, are reported. Quaternization of the pyridine-nitrogen in these compounds via solution nucleophilic substitution reactions with methyl iodide and methyl triflate yield stable pyridinium analogs. The introduction of positive charge into the backbone by this simple solution chemistry has a significant effect on the $ pi$-electron delocalization. For example, quaternization of the pyridine-nitrogen is accompanied by strong red-shifts in the UV-Vis absorption spectra. The latter is indicative of enhanced $ pi$-electron delocalization along the backbone upon quaternization. These compounds exhibit strong fluorescence, with quantum yields of 0.015 to 0.058 for the monomers, and 0.060 to 0.223 for the polymers. Quaternization is also observed to enhance fluorescence intensities and quantum efficiencies. These polymers are insulators in the ground state, however, upon doping with iodine exhibit semiconducting behavior. The $ pi$-electron delocalization is maintained through Pt(II) centers in the organometallic polymers, and similar effects of quaternization are observed in these highly soluble polymers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kakkar, Ashok</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sj30z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws388</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ang451k66h"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bilingual lexical organization in compound vs. subordinate normal subjects : an examination of the processing of cognates vs. noncognates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bourque, Michelle A. (Michelle Anne)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study investigated bilingual lexical organization in two groups of French-English bilinguals: (1) Compound bilinguals, who acquired both languages in early childhood and speak both with high proficiency; and (2) Subordinate bilinguals, who started speaking their second language during or after adolescence and have reduced L2 proficiency. Subjects were tested on a cross-language auditory primed lexical decision task containing translations and associated words with both cognate and noncognate equivalents. Both subject groups demonstrated significant translation and associative priming, indicating that both groups of subjects had access to a conceptual route of processing. However, no significant facilitation was found for cognates over noncognates in the auditory modality, contrary to previous studies using visual presentation. A general model of compound bilingual lexical organization is derived, and the results are discussed in terms of their implications for second language acquisition.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Shan R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz61q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k66h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Cognitive</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language, Linguistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mk96b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Solar drying of cocoa beans (Theobroma cacao) in St. Lucia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bonaparte, Anthony</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An indirectly heated solar drier fitted with a flat plate collector and a directly heated solar drier were compared with open air sun drying of cocoa beans under field conditions in St. Lucia. Sun drying was conducted on two surfaces, perforated steel and non perforated wood. The methods were examined for the ability to adequately dry fermented beans and effect on quality. Loading rates of 13.5, 26.9 and 40.4 kg/m$ sp2$ were examined. Temperature increases of 15$ sp circ$C and 20$ sp circ$C above ambient were achieved in the indirect and direct drier, respectively. The solar driers were more efficient than sun drying units at removing moisture throughout at loading rates of 26.9 and 40.4 kg/m$ sp2$ but only in the initial stages at 13.5 kg. External mould development was therefore reduced. Open air sun drying on the wooden surface proved more effective in the final stages at 13.5 kg/m$ sp2$. The dried beans were of similar internal quality despite faster drying in the driers. The various drying methods and loading rates produced beans of similar pH while only loading rates affected titratable acidity differently. The direct solar drier achieved lower final moisture levels at high loads and was the cheaper alternative.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alikhani, Zaman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b48z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk96b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Solar dryers -- Saint Lucia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cacao beans -- Drying -- Saint Lucia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pc54m"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of fungal leaf decomposition in relation to biological control of the apple scab pathogen, Venturia inaequalis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bernier, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Venturia inaequalis, the causal agent of apple scab, overwinters in apple leaves on the orchard floor. To develop a control strategy based on the prevention of the maturation of overwintering pseudothecia, a sampling of fungi colonizing dead apple leaves was conducted from different orchard floors in Quebec during the spring and fall of 1993. A total of 345 different isolates were obtained, from which fifteen genera have never been previously recorded as colonizers of apple leaves in North America. Small differences were detected in genera richness among orchards but the fungal composition of each orchard was fairly unique. Different tests on growth on amended media and leaf decomposition demonstrated that leaf degradation is not a reliable parameter alone to screen antagonist against V. inaequalis. No significant relation between growth on amended media, leaf rheology and ascospore inhibition was detected. However, 40 fungi reduced significantly ascospore production more than 87% compared to the control (V. inaequalis only). Of these antagonists, 30% decomposed apple leaves, suggesting that competition for the substrate is involved in the mode of action of at least one third of the antagonits detected. Other possible modes of antagonism are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paulitz, Tim</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m393k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc54m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Venturia inaequalis -- Biological control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apples -- Diseases and pests -- Biological control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fungi -- Ecology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Leaves -- Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apple scab</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qr61h"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of the endothelin system in normal development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bayan, Farideh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Three known mammalian endothelins, ET-1, ET-2, and ET-3, are each encoded by separate genes and expressed in a variety of vascular and nonvascular tissues. Two subtypes of endothelin receptors have been identified and termed endothelin-A and endothelin-B receptors (ET-A and ET-B). In the first part of this study, the ET-A gene was disrupted in mouse embryonic stem cells to generate mice deficient in ET-A. In the second part of this study, we investigated a targeted disruption of the mouse ET-B gene that results in aganglionic megacolon associated with coat color spotting, resembling a hereditary syndrome of mice, humans and other mammalian species (Waardenburg syndrome). In the third part of this study, we demonstrated that a targeted disruption of the mouse endothelin-3 ligand (ET-3) gene produces a similar recessive phenotype of megacolon and coat color spotting. Two types of endothelin converting enzymes (ECE-1 and ECE-2) have been recently identified. In the last part of this study, we investigated the expression of ECE-1 in human tissues using immunohistochemistry and in situ hybridization, and compared it to those of ET-1 and big ET-1. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giaid, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g224v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr61h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hb88k"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of cross-linking on the binding of bile acids by poly(acrylamide) resins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Asgari, Farajollah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The primary goal of this study was to investigate the effect of the density of positively charged groups on the binding of bile acids by poly(acrylamide) resins with amine-containing pendent groups. For this purpose, lightly cross-linked poly(methyl acrylate) beads were functionalized by the reactions with diamines using two different methods, one of which eliminated additional cross-linking during the functionalization procedure. A comparison was made between the swelling characteristics, the isotherms for the binding of cholate anions, and the degree of cooperativity of these resins. Interestingly, the elimination of additional cross-linking not only improved the capacity of the resins to bind cholate anions but it also increased the selectivity for bile acid anions as well as their degree of positive cooperativity. The high degree of cooperativity minimally cross-linked poly(acrylamide) in binding bile acid anions probably indicates the existence of bile acid micelles or mixed micelles within the beads cavities. To rationalize the effect of cross-linking density on the in vitro sorption efficiencies, a microstructure model for three dimensionally cross-linked beads was introduced. This model was developed according to the local degree of cross-linking and is based on the size of functional units and bile acids. Furthermore, for the first time the effect of various organic counter-ions, such as propionate, acetate, benzoate, and salicylate on the in vitro sorption of cholate by poly(acrylamide) resins was studied. It was determined that the sorption efficiency can be improved significantly by replacing the chloride counter-ions with organic counter-ions of low relative affinity. It was demonstrated that functionalized poly(acrylamide) resins having acetate and propionate counter-ions possess a relatively better binding behavior for cholate anions than those resins with Cl$ sp-$ or I$ sp-$ counter-ions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brown, G. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w34t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb88k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j322d"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Improvement of acoustic models in automatic speech recognition systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aboul-Hosn, Rafah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores the use of efficient acoustic modeling techniques to improve the performance of automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems. The principal idea behind this study is that the pronunciation of a word is not only affected by the variability of the speaker and the environment, but largely by the words that precede and follow it. Hence, to accurately represent a language, one should model the sounds in context with other sounds. Furthermore, due to the large amount of models produced when every sound is represented in every context it can appear in, one needs to use a clustering technique by which sounds of similar properties are grouped together so as to limit the number of models needed. The aim of this research is two fold: the first is to explore the effects of using context dependent models on the performance of an ASR system, the second is to combine the context dependent models pertaining to a specific sound in a complex structure to produce a context independent model containing contextual information. Two such complex structures are designed and their performance is tested.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Demori, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn354.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j322d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w9460"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Improvement of inertia effects in slender-body theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tabatabaei, Seyed Mahmood</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research develops an analytical method for predicting the hydrodynamic force experienced by a long slender solid body of arbitrary cross-sectional shape and body centreline configuration, subjected to an unbounded uniform fluid flow. It is assumed the slenderness parameter, K (the ratio of the body cross-sectional length scale the body length) is small ($ ll 1$), the body centreline radius of curvature is everywhere large (of order body length), the cross-sectional shape varies slowly alone the body length, and the Reynolds number $R sb{e}$, based on the body length is of order unity. The inner flow solution for an arbitrary cross-section is illustrated by applying the complex variable method for a body with an elliptical cross-section, which is extendable to any cross-sectional shape. The novelty of this research is the improvement of the approximation of the force per unit length in slender body theory when inertia effects are not negligibly small. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ven, T. Van de</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf91c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w9460</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z744g"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental apparatus for the investigation of human knee dynamics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Steszyn, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis details the design, construction and validation of an experimental apparatus suitable for the investigation of human knee dynamics in vivo. Current research has centred on fixed-axis joints such as the thumb, elbow and ankle, however, due to its size and varying axis of rotation, the dynamic characteristics of the experimental system include a 20 ms rise time to a 1 mm step input, and a frequency bandwidth extending to 35 Hz. Validation of the experimental system was done using inertial systems with properties similar to those expected of the leg. Preliminary human results are presented with an analytical model of the knee. The knee is modelled as a second order system with a natural frequency of approximately 5 Hz and stiffness k of 120 Nm/rad. The results demonstrate that the experimental system is capable of applying position perturbations suitable for system identification of a human knee. This apparatus represents an experimental tool for the quantitive examination of human knee dynamics in vivo.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kearney, R. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dh82n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z744g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajs956h93w"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A computational study of transport phenomena in RH-ladles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sadomba, Clara P. (Clara Petronella)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A numerical study was carried out to predict three dimensional turbulent flow heat and mass transfer in RH-ladles. To model the turbulence in the system, the popular Launder and Sharma (7) version of the low Reynolds number k-$ varepsilon$ model was employed. The governing equations for fluid flow and heat transfer were solved using a control volume-based finite difference method. The buoyancy effect in the axial momentum equation was incorporated through the Boussinesq approximation. From the fluid flow and turbulence characteristics predicted by the numerical model, the mass transfer occurring from the dissolution of steel rods immersed in the liquid steel was computed using the Sherwood number correlation recently proposed by Mazumdar et al. (25). The parameters studied include: the flow rate of steel, the heat flux from the solid walls and various radial positions of the vertically immersed steel rod. The fluid flow results are presented as vector plots. The heat transfer aspects are shown through temperature contours at various vertical planes and the mass transfer results are graphically presented in plots showing variance of mass transfer coefficients with key parameters. The flow field results were found to be in qualitative agreement with previously reported 3D numerical studies for similar systems. Due to the lack of any experimental or numerical results related to heat and/or mass transfer in RH-ladles, the heat and mass transfer results obtained in the present study could not be compared and verified.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hasan, Mainul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306768.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h93w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz78p"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A database for an intensive care unit</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saab, Emile</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rapid growth of medical sciences and technologies created the need to manage data generated by sophisticated medical equipment (e.g. lab results, vital signs, etc.). This class of equipment, especially in the modern Intensive Care Unit (ICU), emits large quantities of latient data which medical staff usually records on log sheets. This thesis presents a database design that allows abstract definition of data types, and offers a unified view of data during the development phase, distinct levels of data management and a higher degree of system flexibility. This database model is an implementation of a database for a Patient Data Management System (PDMS) developed for use in the ICU of the Montreal Children's Hospital. The PDMS has a variety of application modules that handle and process various types of data according to functionality requirements.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malowany, Alfred S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462747x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz78p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Information Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236412t"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rheological and mechanical behaviour of high volume fly ash cement grouts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roy, Vincent, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The society is becoming increasingly more energy and environmentally conscientious, which has forced development of construction materials, which are both inexpensive and require very little energy to produce. One way of producing such materials is to utilize by-products of industrial processes. High-volume fly ash cement based grouts are tributary of such developements. This thesis outlines the results of a detailed study of the grain size distribution, three rheological properties and five mechanical properties of high-volume fly ash grouts (60% cement replacement for fly ash by weight) with or without the use of superplasticizers and/or anti-washout agents. The rheological properties are reported for eight water/cement + fly ash (water/solids) ratios. The effect of superplasticizers and anti-washout agents on the flow time of low water/solids ratio grouts and the stability of high water/solids ratio grouts are investigated. The study revealed that: (1) The addition of fly ash reduces significantly the flow time of low water/solids ratio grouts (0.4 to 0.65). (2) The stability of cement grout is improved by the addition of fly ash for water/solids ratios greater than or equal to 0.65. (3) The use of fly ash reduces the early compressive and bond strength, when compared to the reference grout (pure cement). However, as they mature their strengths are closer to those of the pure cement grouts. (4) Fly ash reduces the amount of drying shrinkage compared to pure cement grout with an equivalent water/solids ratio.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mirza, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f801p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236412t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d6230"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic response of overhead transmission lines to ice shedding</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roshan Fekr, Masoud</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main objective of this research was to study dynamic effects of ice shedding on overhead transmission lines using a reliable numerical model. Overhead transmission lines are subjected to various static and dynamic loads. Ice shedding from the conductors is one of the dynamic loads occurring in cold regions. This phenomenon happens when glaze ice formed on the cables suddenly falls under certain temperature and wind conditions. In extreme instances, clashing and breakage of insulator and conductors are potential consequences of these dynamic forces. Maximum vertical cable jumps and drops in unloaded and loaded spans, and axial cable stresses are particular concerns. The main assumptions and limitations of the proposed numerical model are discussed in detail, with appropriate stiffness, mass, damping, and ice-shedding load modelling. A nonlinear finite-element model using a commercial software (ADINA) was used to carry out simulations of 21 different ice-shedding scenarios varying the number of successive spans involved, the amount of ice accreted on the cables, different elevations of the central support, partial and sub-span ice shedding and the configuration and sequence of the shedding in adjacent spans. The analysis of the results focuses on the peak cable tensions generated, the insulator string swings and the maximum transient in-span cable displacements. Some of the results are compared with the design procedures used at Hydro-Quebec, which is based on static analysis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McClure, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c97n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d6230</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77ft48n"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hydrocarbon utilization by Corynebacterium dioxydans</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Quesnel, David M. (David Marc)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Batch fermentations of Corynebacterium dioxydans were performed using aliphatic hydrocarbons as substrates. The production of carboxylic acids was monitored throughout these fermentations. A relationship between the carbon chain length of the hydrocarbon substrate and the carboxylic acids was observed. The maximum yield of carboxylic acid was found to occur in the exponential growth phase, with the initial complete medium. Cell hydrophobicity is the proposed hypothesis for the residual hydrocarbon found in these fermentations. The addition of synthetic surfactant increased the yield of carboxylic acids, but posed problems in extraction of these acids. In spite of a variety of different approaches, it was not possible to avoid contamination of the carboxylic acid products with residual hydrocarbon. The persistence of this residue was attributed to the hydrophobicity of the cell.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cooper, D. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p650.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft48n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m394v"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Packaging of two dimensional optoelectronic device arrays for optical backplanes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Otazo, Marcos R. (Marcos Rafael)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of existing packaging techniques for microelectronics are studied in terms of their applicability to the packaging of optoelectronic device arrays for photonic inter-connect applications. In particular, the packaging of smart pixel arrays for free-space optical backplanes is quantitatively explored. This assessment is made from three basic perspectives: thermal management capabilities, connectivity and bandwidth, and alignment to a free-space optical system. In the assessment, a smart pixel array design space analysis is derived which shows that, by constraining the smart pixel array characteristics, the use of existing packaging technologies is possible. This leads to the derivation of expressions which relate both system and smart pixel array parameters to representative packaging parameters. It is seen in the analysis that while the thermal management imposes constraints on the window size, smart pixel density and size, the alignment imposes constraints mostly on the window size. The architectural characteristics of the smart pixel array are mostly affected by the connectivity and bandwidth of the packaging technology. The integration of packaged smart pixel arrays into optical backplane demonstrators is also discussed, and the design and implementation of an optical backplane demonstrator is presented. This is complemented by the design, implementation and characterization of an optomechanical assembly which uses the interface between a single chip carrier and a socket to provide means of alignment in three degrees of freedom. Pre-aligned and modular plug-in device array integration is demonstrated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Plant, David V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tp01n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m394v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88cj674"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Purification of Buckminsterfullerenes by thin film fractional sublimation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manoliadis, Platon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Thin film fractional sublimation (TFFS) is a distillation process which is used to separate mixtures of solids having a difference in sublimation temperatures of less than 100$ sp circ$C. TFFS employs a moving packed bed to move the solid phase downwards through the column, countercurrently to the vapour phase. The potential of using TFFS to separate fullerenes from a crude extract composed of C$ sb{60}$ and C$ sb{70}$ was investigated. A 22 mm diameter TFFS column with a moving packed bed was constructed to evaluate the efficiency of the process. This column was capable of fractionally sublimating 40 mg samples of fullerenes under total reflux conditions. The heated column could be operated under inert atmosphere at low to atmospheric pressure. The effect of operating variables such as temperature, carrier gas flow rate and packed bed movement speed, was investigated. Starting from a crude extract composed of 80 wt% C$ sb{60}$ and 20 wt% C$ sb{70},$ milligram quantities of 92 wt% C$ sb{60}$ and 89 wt% C$ sb{70}$ were obtained. Also, a column height equivalent to a theoretical stage (HETS) as low as 2.5 cm/stage was achieved under certain conditions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tsantrizos, P. G.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Meunier, J.-L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s6874.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj674</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p6780"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Energy considerations in power system damping by reactorcapacitor switching</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maksimcev, Mirko D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Flexible AC transmission systems (FACTS) technology is an emerging new technology which can be efficiently used in power system damping. Objectives of this study are the considerations of the energy flow involved in power system damping by functional switching of series capacitors and/or reactors. The principal questions are how the energy transiently flows through the network and what is its impact on damping of mechanical oscillations. The analytical studies (covered in Chapter 1) reveal that the magnetic and electrostatic energy are constantly stored in the reactive components of the transmission system. The energy stored in a series compensated line is greater than the energy stored in an uncompensated line of equal transmission capability. The transient energy flow caused by characteristic switching in transmission systems is studied analytically in Chapter 2. Switching of an additional line or switching of series capacitors initiates transient charging/discharging of the line towards its new steady-state energy level which is always associated with losses. Power transfer characteristics of the systems which are equivalent in steady-state operation (parallel lines vs. an equivalent series compensated line) have quite different transient power transfer characteristics. These differences are related to different stored energies in such systems. System sources participate in all transient energy flow phenomena. The impact of series compensation switching upon the mechanical oscillation damping was demonstrated by simulations presented in Chapter 3. Thyristor switched variable series compensation (VSC) is simulated in order to verify the conclusions of the analytical studies regarding the charging/discharging energy of the line. The switching of reactive power components for the purpose of power system oscillation damping involves significant energy impulses in and out of the machines. Therefore, stability studies have to be performed by simulation which involves detailed representation of electromagnetic phenomena (EMTP for example).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gavrilovic, Monicilo M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v7557.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p6780</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bh13b"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Singular Stewart-Gough platforms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hartmann, Dominik, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A special type of singular Stewart-Gough Platform exhibits continuous motion of one or more degrees of freedom, while all of its six or more legs are locked at fixed length. The equation describing point motion is introduced and then applied to parallel platforms. Line geometric analysis shows that all legs remain in a continuously varying linear complex, linear congruence, or quadric. Base and platform joints are restricted to lie on two congruent, skewed hyperbolids of one sheet. One of these constitutes those points on the rigid body of the platform that move on spheres, the other, those on the fixed base which constitute the sphere centres. An equivalent mechanism is developed and used to visualize the design parameters of the motion. The selection, as platform joints, of points on a line generator results in a two degree of freedom platform. Specific designs of such overconstrained mechanisms are investigated and illustrated. Line geometry is used, to explain the special relationship among the platform legs. Numerical examples are given and illustrated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zsombor-Murray, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s2190.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh13b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>