<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z169n"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Range search and nearest neighbor search in k-d trees</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chanzy, Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents an analysis of the expected complexity of range searching and nearest neighbor searching in random 2-d trees. We show that range searching in a random rectangle $ Delta sb{x} times Delta sb{y}$ can be done in $O lbrack Delta sb{x} Delta sb{y} n+( Delta sb{x}+ Delta sb{y}) n sp alpha +{ rm ln} n rbrack$ expected time. A matching lower bound is also obtained. We also show that nearest neighbor searching in random 2-d trees by any algorithm must take time bounded by $ Omega lbrack n sp{ alpha-1/2}/({ rm ln} n) sp alpha rbrack$ where $ alpha=( sqrt{17}-3)/2$. This disproves a conjecture by Bentley that nearest neighbor search in random 2-d trees can be done in O(1) expected time.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x47h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z169n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m2613"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reproducibility of electrodynogram testing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turchyniak, Ronald John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated the reproducibility of test results of the Langer Electrodynogram (EDG) foot sensor system which quantifies discrete pressures and temporal episodes at the interface of the foot and appropriate surface. In phase one of the study, the effects of transducer placement errors were evaluated by manipulating sensors. In the single subject studied, results suggested that placement errors of a single transducer within ${ pm1}$ cm from its original location do not significantly affect the temporal components of gait, though errors as low as ${ pm0.5}$ cm from an initial position significantly affected pressures. In phase two, ten healthy subjects performed 25 straight line barefoot walks on each of two separate days at an average natural cadence of 111.06 steps/min. with identical transducer placements on each day. Twenty-five gait variables were analysed for unilateral and asymmetries estimates. Analyses of variance revealed few significant differences among trials. Further, while there were no significant overall differences between days, there were significant subject-by-day interactions due to between-day differences in individual subjects, in part related to inherent subject-performance variability. Since clinicians are interested mainly in individual subject analyses rather than a mythical average subject, caution is advised in data interpretation when monitoring a subject on different days, even with as many as 25 trials per session and identical landmark placements. Pressures, while reliable within a single testing session, should not be used for inter-day comparisons and may not be appropriate for monitoring asymmetries because slight variations in placement will account for the measured differences between limbs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cartwright, G. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440t294.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m2613</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gait in humans</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t283b"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attitudes of undergraduate university students toward people with physical disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Voyatzakis, Mary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research explored the attitudes of McGill University undergraduate students toward people with physical disabilities. First and third year students in six different faculties were further subdivided into a Human Service discipline which included Education, Social Work, and Nursing students, and a non Human Service discipline which included Management, Engineering, and Agriculture students. The effects of gender, having had previous contact with persons with a disability, and having had a course on the topic of disability on attitudes toward people with disabilities were also examined. One hundred and forty-four women and 79 men served as the subjects for this study. Subjects completed the Attitude Toward Disabled Persons Scale (ATDP) Form B, and descriptive information giving the variables under investigation (gender, faculty, etc.). The analysis of the data collected showed that there was a significant positive difference in attitudes among students following a Human Service discipline than students following a non Human Service discipline. There was a significant interaction effect between faculty and year of study with Agriculture, Engineering, and Nursing student scores increasing in their third year, and Management, Education, and Social Work student scores decreasing in their third year. No significant differences on attitudes toward people who are physically disabled were found according to faculty enrolled in, year of study, gender, previous contact with persons with disabilities, or previous course on the topic of disability.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mager, George</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x222c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t283b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>College students -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes</dc:subject><dc:subject>People with disabilities</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602167q"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The British government's reception of, and reaction to, information from intra-German opposition to Hitler and other sources, 1938-1939</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vourkoutiotis, Vasilis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>From 1938 to the outbreak of war in 1939, German opponents of Hitler made numerous contacts with the British government. While the information sent came from a variety of sources, most of the reports landed on the desk of Sir Robert Vansittart, the former Permanent Under-Secretary of the Foreign Office. His "internal-exile" to the position of Chief Diplomatic Advisor, as well as his personality conflicts with his successor, Sir Alexander Cadogan, and Lord Halifax, led to inefficient use of the information received from Germany. German warnings of Hitler's plans and ambitions, when listened to at all, were awkwardly and ineffectively incorporated into British foreign policy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoffman, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n425x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602167q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anti-Nazi movement -- Germany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- Germany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Germany -- Foreign relations -- Great Britain</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xs56s"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ita</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La poesia di E.A. Mario</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trani, Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present work examines the poetry in neapolitan language and particularly the works of E. A. Mario, fin de siecle poet and melody writer, who contributed considerably to the song history. The first part introduces us to the neapolitan regional poetry as well as to its language to finally conclude with the poetry set to music: the song. The ideal atmosphere is the cafe-chantant. The poets of the time including Salvatore Di Giacomo and the generation after are surveyed. The second part deals with the author. It describes his life, his art and his works, rich of popular and especially classical elements, which crowned him with success.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gilardino, Sergio Maria</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b681.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs56s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Popular music -- Italy -- Naples -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mario, E. A., 1884-1961 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870w786"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Procedural and declarative knowledge of ball-catching in children with physical disabilities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kourtessis, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It was hypothesized that children with physical disabilities would show a deficit in procedural and declarative knowledge of ball catching compared to age-matched non-disabled children. The first group of children consisted of sixteen children with physical disabilities, three girls and thirteen boys, aged from 6 years and 5 months to 12 years and 6 months. Sixteen children, five girls and eleven boys, comprised the second group. Their age range was from 6 years and 4 months to 12 years and 2 months. All children were tested individually. Procedural knowledge of ball catching was measured by a 15-task ball-catching hierarchy. The difficulty of the tasks ranged from easy, static tasks to more difficult ones which required some expertise. Non-disabled children demonstrated higher scores in procedural knowledge than children with physical disabilities. Higher scores in procedural knowledge of ball catching were also shown by older non-disabled children compared to their younger non-disabled peers, as well as by ambulatory children with physical disabilities compared to their non-ambulatory peers. Declarative knowledge of ball catching was assessed by a 14-item multiple choice questionnaire. The two groups exhibited very similar declarative knowledge. Moreover, no differences regarding declarative knowledge were found between older and younger non-disabled children or between ambulatory and non-ambulatory children with physical disabilities. Further investigation revealed that the association between procedural and declarative knowledge of ball catching was only moderate. It was suggested that procedural and declarative knowledge do not develop at the same rate and a deficit in procedural knowledge does not necessarily lead to a deficit in declarative knowledge. The relationship between the two types of knowledge may be more complex than initially hypothesized. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612p497.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870w786</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children with disabilities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cognition in children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ball games</dc:subject><dc:subject>Motor ability in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644s41j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Community perspectives, Caribou user participation and the Beverly-Qamanirjuaq Caribou Management Board in Northcentral Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kendrick, Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The conservation of wildlife species plays a profound part in development issues in northern areas. In recent years, northern wildlife management has become a complicated process of cross-cultural communication. This thesis begins with an outline of the relations between First Nations and Euro-Americans in the context of the dynamics between wildlife scientists and aboriginal subsistence-based communities. The current economic, social and political characteristics of subsistence systems are discussed. The emergence of co-management systems is described in a review of wildlife management institutions existing in northern Canada and Alaska. An analysis of the activities of the Beverly-Qamanirjuaq Caribou Management Board (B-Q CMB) and the relative participation of traditional users and government wildlife scientists forms the core of an exploration of the nature of wildlife co-management. In order to understand some of the perspectives of local caribou-using communities within the co-management framework, interviews were held with members of the Inuit community of Arviat, Nunavut and the Sayisi-Dene community of Tadoule Lake, Manitoba. Finally, the general role of co-management institutions in securing the viability of communal property regimes is discussed with specific reference to the case of the B-Q CMB.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mueller-Wille, Ludger</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h9759.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644s41j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Beverly and Kaminuriak Caribou Management Board</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wildlife management -- Canada, Northern</dc:subject><dc:subject>Caribou -- Canada, Northern</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vh63g"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The use of violence and language in the works of Timothy Findley</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jushkevich, Paulanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with violence in the language of Timothy Findley's work: both the language of narration and the language of dialogue between the characters. In the thesis, I will examine the way language is violated for the purpose of re-assembling it into a more competent vehicle for communication. Bakhtin's theory of dialogics and Robert Kroetsch's theory of violent silence will be examined with regard to Findley's consistent focus on the way language must be violated to render it useful, and why any character of Findley's who refuses to violate language and chooses instead to submit to silence, is destroyed. According to Findley, the only means of validating existence and literature is to dispel silence with dialogue. I will prove that Timothy Findley treats violence as a positive and necessary precursor to any sort of creativity, asserting again and again through his texts that nothing can be constructed until something is first torn down.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lecker, Robert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n2041.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh63g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Findley, Timothy -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xv886"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fyodor Dostoevsky's Netochka Nezvanova</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaderabek, Sarah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The complex nature of Netochka Nezvanova, one of Fyodor Dostoevsky's early pieces, makes this work an interesting and revealing point from which to study the evolution of the writer's craftsmanship. Written under the influence of major Russian, French, and German prose works of the period, it reflects Dostoevsky's process of creative emulation of the achievement of European realist writing and a process of reworking of Russian Romanticism into what would later be called "psychological realism." The unfinished nature of Netochka Nezvanova testifies to Dostoevsky's struggle with the previous literary tradition and to his search for a new literary form. The character types, themes, and stylistic devices with which Dostoevsky experimented in this work would come to play a central role in the creation of his later masterpieces.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roll, Serafima</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032391x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xv886</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, 1821-1881. Netochka Nezvanova</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, 1821-1881. Netochka Nezvanova</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arf55z873v"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ringed seal mortality patterns as an aid in the determination of Thule Eskimo subsistence strategies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Danielson, Robert A. (Robert Alden)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dental annuli analyses were performed on 170 ringed seal (Phoca hispida) canines recovered from five Thule semisubterranean houses located at site PaJs-13 at Hazard Inlet, Somerset Island in the central Canadian Arctic. Season of death results indicate greater seal hunting during the spring. Age at death results were used to produce mortality profiles which, when compared with idealized patterns, revealed a prime-dominated pattern indicating the presence of some selective factor in the subsistence strategy. Based on ethnographical studies of traditional seal hunting techniques, conscious selection was eliminated as a factor. Biological studies of ringed seal demonstrate that during the spring, older, sexually mature seals, occupy breeding areas in stable fast ice formations located close to the coast in complex coastal areas. Younger immature seals, on the other hand, occupy areas of unstable pack ice formations either further from the shore in complex coastal areas, or along simple coastlines. The archaeological mortality patterns do not clearly resemble either complex or simple coast modern populations, although a trend toward simple coasts was observed. This observation is consistent with the site location, which allows greater access to pack ice formations. The appearance of selective biological factors affecting random human subsistence strategies indicates that caution must be utilized when interpreting mortality patterns.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Savelle, James</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r880r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z873v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sealing -- Nunavut -- Somerset Island -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thule culture -- Nunavut -- Somerset Island -- Hunting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ringed seal -- Nunavut -- Somerset Island</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj430569n"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The spiritual aspects of Joseph Campbell's hermeneutics in mythology : an examination leading to implications for religious education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Costandi, Samia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Joseph Campbell's comparative studies in mythology revealed to him that culturally bred mythologies, despite their ethnic inflections, continually point to universal archetypes and a common human identity. Campbell's belief in the common human identity stems from his adherence to Carl Jung's mystical perspective on myth, where archetypes of the personal and collective unconscious help us understand humankind in the past, present and future. Myth, like art, Campbell believed, should be interpreted metaphorically, in terms of connotation instead of denotation. Failure to interpret myth poetically leads to religious, social, and political divisiveness. Examples of consequences of a literally interpreted mythology prevail in contemporary ethnic and global warring. This thesis examines the prominent themes in Campbell's alternative philosophy of mythology, and particularly the interpretation of some selected notions in Biblical mythology which, he suggests, have to be reviewed and re-interpreted metaphorically. With the collapse of cultural boundaries due to modernity, the world community needs a mythology for the whole planet. This thesis will discuss the serious implications for religious education of Campbell's hermeneutics of mythology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood, Elizabeth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb292.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430569n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Campbell, Joseph, 1904-1987</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mythology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zb93g"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A preliminary field-report on the Bön community of the Songpan area of North Sichuan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>DesJardins, J. F. Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following essay is the result of approximately two years of research and fieldwork on the Bon religious community of the Songpan Prefecture in the Sichuan Province, People's Republic of China. The research was carried on between September 1991 to Spring 1993. The candidate uses translations of Tibetan Bon historical texts and information provided during field work by Bonpos informants to summarize the view of the Bonpos and contrast it with the historical data available in Western writings to establish a provisional definition of Bon. Translations from a Chinese historical report on the major events of Tibetan religion in Songpan from the period preceding Liberation to today's situation follow with descriptions of Bon monastic settlements and places of pilgrimage. A summary description of the major Bon religious and meditative practices with references to their corpus of ritual manuals and main commentaries used by monks and hermits then conclude the exposition of modern Bon religion as it is presently practiced in Songpan.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dean, Kenneth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558f19d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb93g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Songpan (China : Prefecture) -- Religion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bon (Tibetan religion) -- China -- Songpan (Prefecture)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sr02g"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dorothy Livesay and William Blake : the situation of the self</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dougherty, Karen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis traces the connections between Dorothy Livesay and William Blake, especially with respect to the construction and symbolization of the self. Models of influence relevant to Livesay and Blake are examined resulting in a contextual model of influence which considers artists' "anxiety" and the importance of gender issues. Archival documents supplement, and sometimes transform the implications of, Livesay's poetry and other published works in relation to Blake. The discussion moves from tracing the general points of intersection between Livesay and Blake (ancestors, traditions), to focusing on the different levels of influence that can be claimed between the two poets. The presence of Blake in Livesay's writings is examined closely, especially with respect to the imaginative states which each sets up to describe the self. Finally, Livesay's construction of the journey of her own life and her movement towards an ideal of self-completion which culminate in her celebratory late works are compared with Blake's ideal of the self as set forth in his Prophetic Works.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Trehearne, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62f919r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr02g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Livesay, Dorothy, 1909- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blake, William, 1757-1827 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zp241"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mobile robot localization using model-based maps</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacKenzie, Paul R. (Paul Richard)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the coupled tasks of using a mobile robot to construct a map with noisy range sensors (sonar) of an initially unfamiliar environment, and using such a map to determine the robot's position and orientation. The map need not necessarily represent the actual spatial structure of the environment so much as it is meant to represent the major structural components of what the robot perceives. These "features" of the environment are modeled as straight line segments and are assembled together to form a map. One problem with this approach is that maintaining an absolute coordinate system for the map is difficult without periodically calibrating the position and orientation of the robot, due to the unbounded accumulation of positional errors as the robot moves and rotates. An approach to calibrating the robot's position, known as localization, is presented. In suitable environments, it is possible to use sonar data to perform this operation given coarse estimates of position and orientation, which are iteratively refined to high accuracy using the map and a set of sonar measurements from a single position. Provisions are made for verification of the results of localization using quality indicators, which give a measure of the confidence in the accuracy of a refined position estimate. The approach is then generalized to allow global localization, where position and orientation estimates are not available. Using a number of sample environments, experimental results show that in spite of the inherent noisiness of sonar sensors, accurate localization of a mobile robot is achievable. In addition, the constructed maps are general enough to be used for purposes other than localization, such as path planning and collision avoidance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dudek, Gregory</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x50t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zp241</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n4266"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Object oriented database subsystem for CAD frameworks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcotte, Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the research and design of a new CAD framework and implements a working prototype of the system. The strengths and weaknesses of some existing systems and the needs of modern tool development are described. An architecture is defined. The architecture uses object oriented programming methods and is implemented using the "C++" language on workstations running the UNIX operating system. This thesis describes the basis of an object oriented server and a base class library to be used by the client applications to obtain object persistence, transparent access to multiple servers, version control, rich modeling capabilities and operations in a heterogeneous network of workstations. There is also a discussion of methods for implementing advanced features like notification and project and version management. Finally, the working prototype is evaluated and the results show that with some performance improvements, the system could be used as a foundation for a highly versatile and expandable CAD framework.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dagenais, Michel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm34c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n4266</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848r51w"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analog signal generation using delta-sigma modulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lu, Albert K. (Albert Keishi)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis introduces a method by which low-frequency analog waveforms may be generated using delta-sigma modulation. The technique centers around a delta-sigma based oscillator which, with the exception of a continuous-time low-pass filter, is entirely digital and provides precise control over the oscillation frequency, amplitude, and phase. The incorporation of a delta-sigma modulator inside the resonator loop leads to an efficient implementation requiring 4 multi-bit adders, 4 delay elements, and a 2-input multiplexer. Two additional circuits, which generate multi-tone and piece-wise linear waveforms, are presented as extensions of the original single-tone design. Prototypes of the proposed designs have been assembled using Field-Programmable Gate Array, and BiCMOS technologies. The test results have successfully verified the validity of the proposed concepts indicating dynamic ranges exceeding 80 dB and 60 dB for the single and multi-tone generators respectively.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roberts, Gordon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v81c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r51w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pn83k"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A low-delay code excited linear prediction speech coder at 8 kbit/s</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Madour, Lila</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of this thesis is to design a high quality low-delay 8 kb/s speech coder. This research is motivated by the need of the telecommunication industries to standardize a high quality, low-delay and low rate speech coder. To meet these requirements, we use a coder based on code-existed linear prediction. To meet the demands of high quality and low bit rate, a vector quantizer is used to code the excitation signal. To meet the low-delay requirement, a backward adaptation technique of the synthesis filters is used. The focus of the research is on comparing different pitch synthesis filters in the CELP coder. From the three-order pitch synthesis filter, the first-order integer delay pitch synthesis filter and the first-order fractional delay pitch synthesis filter that are experimented in this research, the latter produces the best quality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kabal, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg84m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn83k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zb951"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A numerical experiment on the steady state meridional structure of the stratosphere</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rao, Vupputuri Rama Krishna</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053g947.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb951</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Numerical weather forecasting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stratosphere</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wn64m"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reactions of active nitrogen with phosphorus, cyclic compounds, and isobutane</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roscoe, Sharon Grace</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hw307.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wn64m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Isobutane</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cyclic compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phosphorus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Active nitrogen</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mj88f"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electron spin resonance in degenerate semiconductors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Raudorf, Thomas Walter</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g84q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj88f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electron paramagnetic resonance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t016c"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'image chez Bachelard</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roy, Jean Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859g60w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t016c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bachelard, Gaston, 1884-1962</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50ts48b"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Madeleine Copper Mine, Gaspé, Quebec : a hydrothermal deposit</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Girard, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430571p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts48b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology -- Québec (Province) -- Gaspé Peninsula</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copper ores -- Québec (Province) -- Gaspé Peninsula</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copper mines and mining -- Québec (Province) -- Gaspé Peninsula</dc:subject><dc:subject>Madeleine Copper Mine, Gaspé, Québec</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494941k"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Immunochemical studies of myoglobin with synthetic peptides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Givas, Joan Katherine</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35695427.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494941k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Peptides</dc:subject><dc:subject>Immunoglobulins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Immunochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Myoglobin</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g102m"><ual:graduationDate>1971</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Multi-unit correlates of sensory processing in the visual system of the cat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gijsbers, Karel J.</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2686060.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g102m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cats</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vision</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychophysiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z170d"><ual:graduationDate>1970</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of the crystallization of polyethylene during polymerization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Georgiadis, Theodore</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zv26s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z170d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polyethylene</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>