<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nq494"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behavioural innovation and the evolution of cognition in birds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Overington, Sarah Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cognition shapes the interactions of an animal with its environment. Species vary greatly in all aspects of cognition, and studying the relationship between this variation and ecology is crucial for understanding how intelligence has evolved. In this thesis, I approach questions about the ecology and evolution of cognition that are often ignored because cognition is difficult to quantify. I use innovation rate as an operational measure and residual brain size as a correlate of general cognition in birds. I first examine the link between cognition and ecology through comparative analyses of the relationships between residual brain size, innovativeness, and measures of ecological generalism across a broad sample of the avian phylogeny, and within a single clade (Icteridae). I find that innovation is positively correlated with habitat breadth but not diet generalism, and that neither measure of generalism is associated with residual brain size. Although residual brain size and innovation rate are strongly correlated with one another, they each appear to have different relationships to a species' ecology. Further analysis finds that the relationship between innovativeness and residual brain size is driven by innovations that involve the use of novel foraging techniques and not the ingestion of new food items. Comparative studies use the traits of extant species to infer their evolutionary history, but can only speculate on the forces driving changes in a trait. The latter half of my thesis focuses on these underlying forces and behavioural mechanisms. Using a game theory model, I show that unpredictable food availability might drive both behavioural flexibility and sociality, two traits strongly associated with cognitive complexity. Finally, I focus on innovativeness at the intraspecific level and examine foraging innovation in a large-brained grackle species, Quiscalus lugubris. I find that this gregarious species is slower to innovate when conspecifics are nearby, and that individuals differ in their ability to solve novel problems. I use these differences to describe the process of innovation, and show that novelty responses, attention, persistence, and flexibility are all important factors underlying individual variation in the ability to innovate.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La cognition dirige les interactions d'un animal avec son environnement. Les espèces varient énormément dans tous les aspects de la cognition, et étudier les relations entre ces variations, l'écologie et l'évolution est crucial pour comprendre comment l'intelligence a évolué. Dans cette thèse, j'aborde les questions de l'écologie et l'évolution de la cognition souvent ignorées, la cognition étant difficile à évaluer quantitativement. J'ai utilisé le taux d'innovation comme une mesure opérationnelle, et la taille résiduelle du cerveau comme un corrélat de la capacité cognitive générale des oiseaux. J'ai d'abord examiné le lien entre la cognition et l'écologie en procédant à des analyses comparatives des relations entre la taille résiduelle du cerveau, la capacité innovatrice, et des mesures du généralisme écologique à travers un large échantillon de la phylogénie aviaire, et dans un clade unique (Icteridae). J'ai trouvé que la capacité innovatrice est corrélée positivement avec l'étendue de l'habitat, mais non avec le régime généraliste, et qu'aucune mesure du généralisme n'est associée avec la taille résiduelle du cerveau. Bien que la taille résiduelle du cerveau et le taux d'innovation soient fortement corrélés entre eux, chacun d'eux semble avoir des relations différentes avec l'écologie de l'espèce. Une analyse plus poussée a montré que la relation entre la capacité innovatrice et la taille résiduelle du cerveau est déterminée par les innovations impliquant l'utilisation de nouvelles techniques d'approvisionnement, et non l'ingestion de nouveaux types d'aliments. Les études comparatives utilisent les traits d'espèces existantes pour en déduire leur évolution, mais peuvent seulement spéculer sur les forces conduisant les changements d'un trait. La seconde moitié de ma thèse se concentre sur ces forces sous-jacentes et les mécanismes comportementaux. En utilisant un modèle de théorie des jeux, j'ai montré que l'imprévisibilité de la disponibilité alimentaire peut mener tant à la flexibilité comportementale qu'à la socialité, deux traits fortement associés à la complexité cognitive. Enfin, je me suis concentrée sur la capacité innovatrice au niveau interindividuel et j'ai étudié l'innovation lors de l'approvisionnement chez le Quiscale merle, Quiscalus lugubris, une espèce possédant un gros cerveau. J'ai trouvé que cette espèce grégaire est moins rapide à innover lorsque des congénères sont à proximité, et que les individus diffèrent dans leur capacité à résoudre de nouveaux problèmes. J'ai utilisé ces différences pour décrire le processus de l'innovation, et montré que la réponse à la nouveauté, l'attention, la persistance et la flexibilité sont d'
		importants facteurs sous-jacents de la variation interindividuelle de la capacité à innover. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Louis Lefebvre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4629551.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nq494</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gm61n"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Street law's sites, sights, and media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bouclin, Suzanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this dissertation, I deploy film studies' lexicon and concepts to imagine law cinematically and I advance a critical legal pluralist hypothesis to imagine film as law.  The central element of this study is the rule-governed interactions between street-involved people and their interlocutors; these interactions I consider as one instantiation of a plurality of rule-governed interactions that constitute 'street law'. I organize my research around three themes.  First, the sites of street law (where governance of and by street-involved people is constituted).  Second, the sights of street law (how it is we perceive the multiple normative matrices that govern interactions on the street).  Third, the media of street law (some of the modes through which such governance is constituted).  I suggest that cinema provides a conceptual apparatus for grappling with street law's sites (spaces), sights (perspectives) and media (modes) which are currently not apprehended through orthodox and dominant symbolizations of street law.   I endeavour to provide such conceptual apparatuses in three ways: I use concepts from cinema to think about the street law in a metaphorical register; I interpret specific film sequences as jurisgenerative; and I produce a non-linear, collaborative and explicitly interactive film to apprehend street law.  Each of these attempts serves to further my broader project: cinematically symbolizing interactions between street-involved people and their interlocutors as governed by rules.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse j'exploite le discours et les théories des Études cinématographiques pour repenser le droit en termes cinématographiques et proposer une hypothèse de pluralisme juridique critique  en vue d'imaginer le cinéma en tant que droit. La composante principale de cette étude est constituée d'interactions réglementées entre des personnes vivant en situation d'itinérance et leurs interlocuteurs-trices; je considère ces interactions comme étant une instanciation d'une pluralité d'interactions réglementées qui constituent le 'droit de la rue'. Ma recherche s'articule autour de trois axes: d'abord, les lieux du droit de la rue (où se constituent les gouvernances à laquelle sont assujetties les personnes vivant en situation d'itinérance et dont elles sont les créatrices); ensuite, les visualisations du droit de la rue (comment nous percevons les multiples matrices normatives qui régissent les interactions dans la rue); enfin, la médiation de ce droit (certaines modalités par lesquelles ces multiples gouvernances sont constituées). Je propose que le cinéma fournit un appareil conceptuel pour étudier les lieux (espaces), les visualisations (perspectives) et la médiation (modalités) qui ne sont pas couramment saisis par le biais des symbolisations orthodoxes et dominantes du droit de la rue. Je tente de fournir de tels appareils conceptuels de trois façons: j'utilisedes concepts empruntés à la cinématographie pour repenser le droit de la rue en termes métaphoriques, j'interprète certaines séquences cinématographiques comme étant génératrices de normes et je réalise un film documentaire non-linéaire, collaboratif et explicitement interactif dans le but de symboliser le droit de la rue. Chacune de ces tentatives sert à faire avancer un projet plus vaste, celui de symboliser par le truchement du cinéma, les interactions entre les personnes vivant en situation d'itinérance et leurs interlocuteurs-trices telles qu'elles sont gouvernées par des règlements. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roderick A. Macdonald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wp43b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gm61n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5x21tk69z"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Influence of perinatal anoxia and adolescent stress on the adult locomotor response to psychostimulants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wall, Michelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This project focused on the influence of perinatal anoxia and adolescent stress onthe adult locomotor response of rats to psychostimulants. Epidemiological evidencesuggests that obstetric complications can increase the risk for mental disorders includingschizophrenia and that early onset schizophrenia may be precipitated by stress duringadolescence. Taken together we hypothesized that these insults during two crucialperiods of brain maturation may manifest developmental alterations in dopamine (DA)function evident only at adulthood. Thus, I investigated the influence of perinatal anoxiaand chronic unpredictable adolescent stress (CUAS) on the adult locomotor response toamphetamine (AMPH) and cocaine (COC). In Study 1 I found that perinatal anoxia alonedid not affect the adult locomotor response to AMPH however caesarean birth aloneenhanced the adult locomotor response to both acute and repeated COC administration. In Study 2 I found that CUAS following perinatal anoxia did not affect the adultlocomotor response to AMPH but enhanced the adult locomotor response to acute COCadministration and resulted in a sensitized response to repeated COC administration notseen in animals born vaginally or by caesarean birth. These studies demonstrate thatcaesarean birth alone or with an added period of anoxia interact differently with CUASenhancing the adult locomotor response to COC but not to AMPH.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ce projet porte sur l'influence de l'anoxie périnatale suivie par le stress enadolescence sur la réponse locomotrice de rats adultes à la suite de l'introduction depsychostimulants. Les données épidémiologiques suggèrent que les complicationsobstétricales peuvent augmenter le risque de désordres mentaux, y compris laschizophrénie, et que la schizophrénie précoce peut être déclenchée par le stress durantl'adolescence. Étant donné ces faits, nous avons pris comme hypothèse que ces atteintesau cours de deux périodes cruciales de la maturation du cerveau pourraient se manifesterdans des altérations développementales du fonctionnement de la dopamine (DA) qui neseraient évidentes qu'à l'âge adulte. Ainsi, j'ai étudié l'influence de l'anoxie périnatalesuivie par le stress chronique imprévisible en adolescence (CUAS) sur la réponselocomotrice à l'amphétamine (AMPH) et à la cocaïne (COC) à l'âge adulte. Dans lapremière étude, j'ai constaté que l'anoxie périnatale seule n'affecte pas la réponselocomotrice adulte à l'AMPH, cependant naître d'une césarienne a augmentéindépendamment la réponse locomotrice des adultes à l'administration aiguë et répétée dela COC. Dans la deuxième étude, j'ai constaté que le traitement CUAS suivant l'anoxiepérinatale n'a pas affecté la réponse locomotrice adulte à l'AMPH mais a augmenté laréponse locomotrice adulte suite à l'administration aiguë de la COC, et en plus, a abouti àune réponse sensibilisée à l'administration répétée de la COC qui n'a pas été vue chez lesanimaux nés par voie vaginale ou par césarienne. Ces études démontrent que la naissancepar césarienne seule et avec une période d'anoxie interagit différemment avec letraitement CUAS et produit une réponse locomotrice adulte augmentée à la COC, maispas à l'AMPH.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alain Gratton</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m824w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tk69z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z709188j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nitrogen to phosphorus ratio of plant biomass versus soil solution in a tropical pioneer tree, «Ficus insipida»</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Garrish, Valerie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is commonly assumed that the N:P ratio of a terrestrial plant reflects the relative availability of N and P in the soil in which the plant grows.  Here it was assessed for a tropical pioneer tree, Ficus insipida.  Seedlings were grown in sand and irrigated with nutrient solutions containing N:P ratios ranging from &lt; 1 to &gt; 100.  The experimental design further allowed investigation of physiological responses to N and P availability.  Homeostatic control over N:P ratios was stronger in leaves than in stems or roots, suggesting that N:P ratios of stems and roots are more sensitive indicators of the relative availability of N and P at a site than N:P ratios of leaves.  The leaf N:P ratio at which the greatest plant dry mass and highest photosynthetic rates were achieved was about 11, whereas the corresponding whole-plant N:P ratio was about 6.  Plant P concentration varied as a function of the transpiration rate at constant nutrient solution P concentration, possibly due to transpiration-induced variation in the mass flow of P to root surfaces.  Transpiration rate varied in response to nutrient solution N concentration, but not to nutrient solution P concentration, demonstrating nutritional control over transpiration by N but not P.  Water-use efficiency varied as a function of N availability, but not as a function of P availability.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il est couramment admis que le rapport N:P pour les plantes terrestres reflète la disponibilité relative d'azote et de phosphore dans sol où croît la plante.  Ici, le rapport N:P a été évalué pour un arbre tropical pionnier, le Ficus insipida.  Les semis ont été plantés dans le sable et irrigués avec des solutions nutritives contenant des rapports N:P allant de  1 a 100.  Ce concept expérimental a permis une évaluation des réponses physiologiques à la disponibilité d'azote et de phosphore.  Le contrôle homéostatique sur le rapport N:P était plus élevé dans les feuilles que dans les tiges ou les racines, ce qui peut signifier que le rapport N:P des  tiges et des racines est un indicateur plus sensible à la disponibilité relative d'azote et de phosphore dans un site donné que celui des feuilles.  Le rapport N:P de feuilles auquel les taux les plus élevés de masse sèche et de photosynthèse ont été obtenus était d'environ 11 alors que le rapport N:P pour l'ensemble de la plante était d'environ 6.  La concentration de phosphore dans les plantes variait en fonction du taux de transpiration à des niveaux constants de concentration de phosphore dans la solution nutritive, ce qui est possiblement dû à des variations dans le débit de phosphore à la surface des racines provoquées par la transpiration.  Le taux de transpiration variait en fonction du niveau de concentration de l'azote dans la solution nutritive, mais pas à celui du phosphore, indiquant un contrôle nutritionnel sur la transpiration par l'azote mais pas par le phosphore.  L'efficacité de l'utilisation de l'eau variait en fonction de la disponibilité de l'azote mais pas en fonction de celle du phosphore.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomas C. Meredith</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f5434.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709188j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000004234"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Potassium channel control of neuronal frequency response</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ellis, Lee David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The processing of sensory signals is an important, yet complex task in which a system must extract behaviorally relevant stimulus patterns from a vast array of sensory cues. When a neuron within a major sensory area is presented with a stimulus, one of the important characteristics used to distinguish between types of input is frequency. Often sensory neurons are tuned to narrow stimulus frequency ranges and are thus charged with the processing of subtypes of sensory signals. The weakly electric fish Apteronotus lepthorhynchus senses it's environment through modulations of a self-generated electric field. Two main types of sensory signals can be distinguished based on their frequency patterns. Prey stimuli cause low frequency perturbations of the electric field, while communication signals often result in high frequency signals. Pyramidal neurons in the electrosensory lateral line lobe (ELL) encode the low frequency signals with bursts, while the high frequency signals are relayed with single spikes. This thesis describes how a pyramidal neuron's response patterns can be tuned to specific frequencies by the expression of distinct classes of potassium channels. I have cloned 3 small conductance (SK) calcium activated potassium channels from cDNA libraries created from the brain of Apteronotus. I have subsequently localized the AptSK channels throughout the brain using both in situ hybridization (AptSK1, 2 &amp; 3) and immunohistochemical (AptSK1 &amp; 2) techniques. The 3 channels showed distinct expression patterns, with the AptSK1 &amp; 2 channels showing a partially overlapping expression pattern, while AptSK3 appears to be expressed in unique areas of the brain. In the ELL AptSK1 &amp; 2 show a partially overlapping expression pattern, appearing in similar pyramidal neurons. However, their distribution within individual cell is unique, with AptSK1 showing a dendritic localization, while AptSK2 is primarily somatic. We have demonstrated that the unique expression pattern of the somatic AptSK2 channel in the ELL coincides with the functional SK currents evaluated through in vitro electrophysiology. Further we have shown that neurons that encode low frequencies do not possess functional SK channels. It thus appears that the presence of the AptSK2 channel subtype can predispose a neuron to respond to specific types of sensory signals. In an attempt to evaluate if second messengers could modify the AptSK control of frequency tuning I investigated the consequences of muscarinic acetylcholine receptor (mAChR) activation on a pyramidal neurons response patterns. While it had been shown in vivo that mAChR activation increased a pyramidal neuron's response to low frequencies, I have found that this was not due to a decrease in AptSK current, but rather appears to be the result of a down-regulation of an A-type potassium channel. Taken together the studies that comprise this thesis show how the selective expression of a single potassium channel subtype can control a sensory neurons response to specific environmental cues. The secondary modulation of the A-type current highlights the potential for a second messenger to control a neuron's sensory response through the down-regulation of constitutively expressed potassium current.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dr28q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000004234</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Brown ghost knifefish -- Nervous system</dc:subject><dc:subject>Potassium channels</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042z315"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimized Schwarz methods for the advection-diffusion equation and for problems with discontinuous coefficients</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dubois, Olivier, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Optimized Schwarz methods are iterative domain decomposition procedures with greatly improved convergence properties, for solving second order elliptic boundary value problems. The enhanced convergence is obtained by replacing the Dirichlet transmission conditions in the classical Schwarz iteration with more general conditions that are optimized for performance. The convergence is optimized through the solution of a min-max problem. The theoretical study of the min-max problems gives explicit formulas or characterizations for the optimized transmission conditions for practical use, and it permits the analysis of the asymptotic behavior of the convergence. In the first part of this work, we continue the study of optimized transmission conditions for advection-diffusion problems with smooth coefficients. We derive asymptotic formulas for the optimized parameters for small mesh sizes, in the overlapping and non-overlapping cases, and show that these formulas are accurate when the component of the advection tangential to the interface is not too large. In a second part, we consider a diffusion problem with a discontinuous coefficient and non-overlapping domain decompositions. We derive several choices of optimized transmission conditions by thoroughly solving the associated min-max problems. We show in particular that the convergence of optimized Schwarz methods improves as the jump in the coefficient increases, if an appropriate scaling of the transmission conditions is used. Moreover, we prove that optimized two-sided Robin conditions lead to mesh-independent convergence. Numerical experiments with two subdomains are presented to verify the analysis. We also report the results of experiments using the decomposition of a rectangle into many vertical strips; some additional analysis is carried out to improve the optimized transmission conditions in that case. On a third topic, we experiment with different coarse space corrections for the Schwarz method in a simple one-dimensional setting, for both overlapping and non-overlapping subdomains. The goal is to obtain a convergence that does not deteriorate as we increase the number of subdomains. We design a coarse space correction for the Schwarz method with Robin transmission conditions by considering an augmented linear system, which avoids merging the local approximations in overlapping regions. With numerical experiments, we demonstrate that the best Robin conditions are very different for the Schwarz iteration with, and without coarse correction.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sj00s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042z315</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Boundary value problems -- Numerical solutions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schwarz function</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xq818"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Occupational Health</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The association between rhinitis and asthma of occupational origin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Castaño, Roberto</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis explores the relationship between occupational rhinitis and occupational asthma under the postulates of the "united airways disease" concept that refers to the multiple links observed between rhinitis and asthma. Accordingly, the main objective of this thesis is to demonstrate the concomitant expression of significant changes in nasal patency and bronchial calibre following exposure to occupational agents during specific inhalation challenges, complementing the assessment with the investigation of changes in markers of airways inflammation in nasal lavage. To achieve the objectives, we set up a protocol to diagnose occupational rhinitis and conducted a study from January 2005 to January 2007 at Hopital du Sacre-Coeur de Montreal in subjects undergoing investigation for occupational asthma. The reliability of the main research tools---acoustic rhinometry and nasal lavage---used to investigate occupational rhinitis was tested by analyzing the reproducibility of the methods. Both methods proved sufficiently reproducible to be included in our investigative protocol. The results presented in this thesis demonstrate a joint reaction of the nose and the lungs in a group of study subjects after performing specific inhalation challenge. This supports the concept of a "united airways disease" and its applicability to rhinitis and asthma of occupational origin. However, the results also show that although occupational rhinitis frequently coexists with occupational asthma it can also be present without occupational asthma. The assessment of upper airways inflammation in a subgroup of study subjects by the nasal lavage method allows us to observe significant changes in eosinophils counts after the challenge that correlates with the decrease in nasal patency observed in the same subjects.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35698388.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xq818</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Occupational Diseases -- immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Asthma -- immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nasal Lavage -- methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inhalation Exposure -- adverse effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rhinitis -- immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fn31k"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The chemistry of novel cyclic diesters : dialkoxy disulfide, thionosulfite and carbonate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eghbali, Nicolas Dara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The synthesis and chemistry of some new cyclic diesters were investigated. The first part of the thesis is concerned with the study of new cyclic diesters derived from thiosulfurous acid, namely cyclic dialkoxy disulfides and their structural thionosulfite isomers. The second part focuses on the development of a new methodology for the synthesis of cyclic carbonates (carbonic acid diesters). The synthesis of new cyclic dialkoxy-disulfides is described in Chapter 3. Five new molecules have been synthesized and fully characterized. An X-ray structure was obtained for the 2,3-furandimethylene dialkoxy disulfide. The substrates were prepared in an attempt to rationalize some of the existing limitations of the synthetic methodology. The relationship and possible interconversion between the newly prepared cyclic dialkoxy disulfides and their structural thionosulfite isomers were investigated. Benzene dimethanoate disulfide was successfully converted to its structural thionosulfite isomer under acidic conditions. Further investigations show the existence of a reversible sulfur extrusion process between thionosulfite and sulfoxylate. This sequential transformation brings the first chemical demonstration that branched bond sulfur can indeed be involved in sulfur extrusion as was first predicted by Foss in 1950. Finally, a highly efficient method to convert alkenes and CO2 into cyclic carbonates directly in water is presented in the second part of the thesis. Using N-bromosuccinimide (NBS) together with 1,8-diazabicyclo [5,4,0] undec-7-ene (DBU) in water, alkenes were converted into cyclic carbonates nearly quantitatively. Cyclic carbonates were also formed efficiently by using a catalytic amount of bromide ion together with aqueous hydrogen peroxide.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988q001.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fn31k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sulfides</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sm39v"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hookers, hustlers and gringos in global Brazil : the transnational political economy and cultural politics of violence, desire and suffering in the streets of Salvador da Bahia ; also including, The ghosts of empire, an ethnographic novel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Veissière, Samuel P. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This doctoral dissertation is an experimental ethnographic investigation of the political consciousness and radical modes of livelihoods of marginalized "street" populations in a postconial Latin-American city, and of their connections with the transnational flows of capital, goods, peoples, and symbols of Global Capitalism. Beginning in the streets of Salvador da Bahia in this place I call "Global Brazil", this inquiry presents a focal lens through which to examine how the structural and cultural forces of Late-Capitalism (Jameson, 1994) in a globalized world and the legacy of colonialism play out at the level of local and transnational actors' lived experiences (that is, for example, how these forces define, 'value', shape, hurt, confine, and displace bodies; but also how bodies dodge these forces, use these forces, reinvent themselves, or strategically perform their colonizer/colonized identities in a search for agency) and focuses, among other salient aspects, on the connections, dependencies, exploitation, violence, and desire between "street children", subaltern women, transnational prostitutes, (sex)tourists, sexpatriates (Seabrook, 1996) and other foreign men and women constructed as "gringo/as" in the context of Global Brazil. Written as a collage between contemporary social, cultural, and political theory and an experimental ethnographic novel (Hecht, 2006), this project explores, or at best poses certain questions about contemporary forms of domination, survival, and resistance while hoping to shed light on undertheorized aspects of our globalized late-capitalist era by investigating the perspectives of local social actors on the structural, cultural and transnational forces in which their radical livelihoods are embedded. Finally, as a work of political pedagogy, this investigation is also fundamentally preoccupied with the role of grassroots politics, research, ethnography, and global social actors---such as the author and other 'academics'--- who occupy positions of social, economic, political, and symbolic power, in collaborating with other segments of civil societies to work toward equitable alternatives to contemporary social suffering. Intertwined with the many faces, voices and stories of this ethnography, thus, readers will encounter the voice, eyes, body, experience, reflections, interrogations, doubts, pains, fears, desire, violence, hopes, defeats, desperations, and resistance of the author, who, as an individual 'articulated' (Nelson, 1999) as white, male, gringo, intellectual, transcultural, geopolitically mobile, ethnographer, and flaneur in the context of this story, constitutes a character deeply implicated in the global flows and forces that are the object of this study.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397d48w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sm39v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Salvador (Brazil) -- Social conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sex tourism -- Brazil -- Salvador</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prostitution -- Brazil -- Salvador</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ethnic groups -- Brazil -- Salvador</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hf002"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanisms of action of transforming growth factor beta and activin in haematopoietic cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Valderrama-Carvajal, Hector F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this work was to investigate the role of TGFbeta family members in the induction of cell growth arrest and apoptosis in immune cell types. The TGFbeta superfamily is a large group of evolutionary conserved polypeptide growth factors, involved in different physiological processes. Any deregulation of the different components of the TGFbeta signaling pathway, has been largely implicated in multiple human critical disorders including cancer. Activin, originally isolated from gonadal fluid, and more recently described as an antiproliferative and proapoptotic factor in different cell types has been implicated in different immune functions. In particular, activin and TGFbeta play an important role in the haematopoietic tissue. They are critical death inducers in the immune system contributing to the elimination of different activated immune cell types. Control of immune cell proliferation, activation and subsequent elimination of activated cell populations by cell growth arrest and apoptosis are critical events for controlling infections and preventing autoimmune disease. However, very limited information about the downstream target genes and their signaling mechanism that relay on the inhibitory effects on cell growth by activin and TGFbeta ligands. Using a screen for genes that are differentially regulated by activin and TGFbeta in haematopoietic cells, we found that the phospholipids phosphatase SHIP-1 was strongly upregulated by activin and TGFbeta. Thus, we hypothesized that TGFbeta and activin induce cell growth arrest in immune cells through up-regulation of SHIP-1 with a significant and subsequent decrease in PtdIns 3,4,5-P3 levels affecting cell survival. Furthermore, we attempted to characterize the different intracellular signalling pathways downstream of these serine/threonine kinase receptors that lead to SHIP-1 overexpression as well as the transcription factors involved in the mediation of transcriptional regulation of the SHIP-1 gene promoter. Chapter 1 provides a broad introduction to the field of TGFbeta signaling focusing on TGFbeta-induced apoptosis in immune cell types and the biology of inositol phosphatases involved in phospholipide metabolism, mainly focused on SHIP-1. Chapter 2 contains data demonstrating that the activin/TGFbeta-induced cell growth arrests and apoptosis through expression of SHIP-1. Data in chapter 3 proved evidences about the cross-talk between the Smad and JNK MAP kinase signalling pathways and their role in the transcriptional regulation of the SHIP-1 gene promoter. Finally, chapter 4, is focused on the discussion and the propose model of how activin/TGFbeta-induced SHIP-1 expression blocks induction of cell survival signals. As a dynamic cellular and molecular process the induction of SHIP-1 by TGFbeta ligands might be in co-association with other apoptosis molecules leading to cell growth arrest and apoptosis in different cell populations of the immune system.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jw28b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hf002</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>SHP1 Protein Tyrosine Phosphatase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Activins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transforming Growth Factor beta</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mh21p"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of the role and regulation of the RNA binding protein HuR in muscle cell differentiation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Van der Giessen, Kate</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Differentiation is the process of regulated gene expression that gives rise to different phenotypes from a common genotype. Skeletal muscle differentiation, myogenesis, is a good example of this process. Skeletal muscle is susceptible to injury due to direct or indirect causes. If left unrepaired, these injuries may lead to a loss of muscle mass, locomotive deficiency, and even lethality. Thus, understanding the molecular mechanisms behind this process is an important first step in the design of treatment for muscle-related diseases. Once myogenesis is induced, the expression of MRF proteins, such as MyoD and myogenin, is maintained at high levels in myofibers without the need to increase their rates of transcription, suggesting a role for post-transcriptional regulatory mechanisms. HuR is a ubiquitously expressed member of the embryonic lethal, abnormal vision (ELAV) family of RNA binding proteins that is known to post-transcriptionally regulate its target messages. Here, I demonstrate that, in the C2C12 muscle cell line, HuR is a required factor for both the initiation and maintenance of the myogenic process. First in vitro RNA Electro-Mobility Shift Assays (REMSA) and immunoprecipitation experiments demonstrated that HuR specifically binds to the AU-rich elements (AREs) that are present in the 3' untranslated regions (3'UTRs) of the MyoD and myogenin mRNAs. In the absence of HuR at the time of differentiation induction, accomplished using the siRNA technology, the expression of the MyoD and myogenin messages is significantly reduced, leading to inhibition of myogenesis. At this early stage in the differentiation process, HuR, a shuttling protein, is predominantly nuclear; localization that is mediated by the import receptor Transportin2 (Trn2). Nuclear HuR was determined to be required for the negative regulation of nucleophosmin (NPM) translation. Forced overexpression of NPM, resulting in differentiation inhibition, shows that its downregulation is a requirement for induction of the differentiation process. Late in myogenesis, however, NPM RNA is no longer expressed, and HuR is seen to accumulate in the cytoplasm of myotubes. This cytoplasmic accumulation results from dissociation of HuR from Trn2 due to caspase-dependent cleavage within its HNS region. Specifically blocking HuR import through the use of cell-permeable peptides, as well as RNAi-mediated depletion of Trn2, leads to an increase in cytoplasmic HuR, as well as increased cytoplasmic localization and stabilization of the MyoD and myogenin messages, and a corresponding enhancement of differentiation. Overall, we conclude that HuR is required for myogenesis due to its ability to post-transcriptionally regulate genes required for the process, and that HuR itself is regulated at the level of its subcellular localization, mediated by the import receptor TRN2.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x333c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mh21p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muscle Development -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>RNA-Binding Proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muscle Fibers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tw68f"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Marginal modelling of capture-recapture data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turner, Elizabeth L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The central theme of this dissertation is the development of a new approach to conceptualize and quantify dependence structures of capture-recapture data for closed populations, with specific emphasis on epidemiological applications. We introduce a measure of source dependence: the Coefficient of Incremental Dependence (CID). Properties of this and the related Coefficient of Source Dependence (CSD) of Vandal, Walker, and Pearson (2005) are presented, in particular their relationships to the conditional independence structures that can be modelled by hierarchical joint log-linear models (HJLLM). From these measures, we develop a new class of marginal log-linear models (MLLM), which we compare and contrast to HJLLMs. We demonstrate that MLLMs serve to extend the universe of dependence structures of capture-recapture data that can be modelled and easily interpreted. Furthermore, the CIDs and CSDs enable us to meaningfully interpret the parameters of joint log-linear models previously excluded from the analysis of capture-recapture data for reasons of non-interpretability of model parameters. In order to explore the challenges and features of MLLMs, we show how to produce inference from them under both a maximum likelihood and a Bayesian paradigm. The proposed modelling approach performs well and provides new insight into the fundamental nature of epidemiological capture-recapture data.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66347684.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tw68f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epidemiology -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Epidemiology -- Statistical methods</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78th37t"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Production et caractérisation de la prohormone convertase 13</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rabah, Nadia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Biopeptides are synthesised as large pro-protein precursors that have to undergo proteolytic cleavage at positively charged amino acids (Lys and Arg) in order to become active. This cleavage is mediated by a family of subtilin/kexin related calcium dependent serine endoproteinases named prohormone convertases. The present thesis focuses on the endocrine member of the family named PC1/3. PC1/3 is expressed in the regulated secretory pathway of endocrine and neuroendocrine cells, where it was shown to activate various peptide hormones such as proopiomelanocortin (POMC), pro-insulin and pro-glucagon. PC1/3 is synthesized as a large precursor containing a signal peptide, a propeptide, a catalytic domain, a P domain and a C-terminal domain. The activation of the enzyme requires the sequential removal of the signal peptide, the propeptide and ultimately the C-terminal domain. The structural characterisation of the enzyme is compromised by the difficulty in producing a sufficient amount of recombinant PC1/3. In this thesis it is clearly demonstrated that the production of PC1/3 using Baculovirus technology can be greatly improved by modifying the expression vector in insect cells (Spodoptera frugiperda). In addition, the intracoelemic injection of insect larvae (Tricoplusia ni) with the Baculovirus encoding the recombinant PC1/3 is shown to be a very efficient method for the production of a large amount of prohormone convertases. It was previously demonstrated that the propeptide is essential for the folding of the enzyme and act as a tight binding inhibitor of the enzyme until the latter reaches the appropriate compartment for substrate cleavage. To assess the role of certain residues within the propeptide in the inhibition of the cognate enzyme, a mutational analysis by alanine scan was conducted. The results demonstrate that the substitution of a single amino acid can affect markedly the inhibition behavior, potency and selectivity of the propeptide towards the enzyme. Moreover, this mutational analysis allowed the first experimental mapping of the sequence involved in propeptide degradation once its function is achieved. However, PC1/3 also possesses a C-terminal domain which must also be cleaved to allow the full activation of the enzyme. Previous studies showed that this domain is implicated in the sorting of the enzyme to secretory granules. In addition, over expression experiments showed that the C-terminal domain can inhibit the cleavage of certain substrates by PC1/3. The results, presented here, suggest that the CT-peptide acts as a non-essential activator of PC1/3, in vitro, which adds a supplementary level of complexity to the activation process of the enzyme. Finally, based upon our results, it can be proposed that PC1/3 is a very complex enzyme capable of controlling its enzymatic activity through the coordinate action of its various domains. This exceptional mode of self-regulation is unique among all protease families.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w6467.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78th37t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Proprotein Convertase 1 -- chemical synthesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354k48b"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anselm's Cur Deus homo for a peace theology : on the compatibility of non-violence and sacrificial atonement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reesor, Rachel H. (Rachel Helen), 1959-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although the interpretation of Anselm's Cur Deus Homo in the tradition of Albrecht Ritschl, Adolf von Harnack and Gustaf Aulen has led to a suspicion about its usefulness for a Peace Theology, a reading through the lens of more recent scholarship, which assumes its original Catholic, sacramental and sacrificial framework, reveals a beautiful understanding of the cross in this medieval classic that is perfectly compatible with a commitment to nonviolence. Three Mennonite scholars writing in pursuit of an Anabaptist Peace Theology, John Howard Yoder, John Driver and J. Denny Weaver display varying degrees of dissatisfaction with the explanation that Anselm provided in Cur Deus Homo, and none held out many prospects for its usefulness. Yoder highlighted the weaknesses, Driver essentially repeated them, and Weaver went a step further to charge that Cur Deus Homo depicted divinely sanctioned violence and ought to be rejected. They did not demonstrate much awareness of or reliance on the contributions of scholars who have focused on Anselm's theology and context. Reading Cur Deus Homo through the lens of more recent anselmian scholarship reveals that the honour and justice of God are one with the mercy and love of God. Humanity is restored not through punishment, but through the means of satisfaction and reward, while the whole explanation is seen in a sacrificial framework. Anselm's insistence upon human participation, and on satisfaction are very congenial to certain emphases of a Peace Theology, namely, discipleship and restorative justice. The real death understood metaphorically as a sacrifice does not violate the commitment to nonviolence, but strengthens it. A rejection of Anselm's metaphysic, ontology and sacrificial framework, a failure to distinguish between punishment and satisfaction, a failure to reflect from the perspective of the guilty, and a neglect of or ambivalence about the doctrines of the two natures and the trinity all lead to a distorted impression of Cur Deus Homo, concealing the contribution Cur Deus Homo might make to a Peace Theology.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150p259.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354k48b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Peace -- Religious aspects -- Christianity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anselm, Saint, Archbishop of Canterbury, 1033-1109. Cur Deus homo</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d8267"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation into the influence of sodium silicate on the physical and mechanical properties of minefill : by Seyed Mehdi Razavi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Razavi, Seyed Mehdi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Returning waste material underground, as backfill, has been practiced for many years so as to improve the economical and environmental performance of underground mining operations. A specific type of backfill, which is used to fill mined areas that will not be exposed to further mining, is called hydraulic backfill. Cemented backfill has also been used to provide mechanical support for underground mining. Such backfill has allowed mining companies to extract more ore, while simultaneously improving working and environmental conditions. Cemented backfill, however, represents 50 to 85 percent of operating costs compared with the 5 to 10 percent that hydraulic backfill consumes. The objective of this thesis is to investigate use of sodium silicate as a partial or total replacement for cement in stabilised backfill. Sodium silicate is a viscous material that is usually used to activate pozzolanic materials such as slag and fly ash. The chemical compound has many applications, namely, in waste treatment, cement and other construction materials. In order to determine the influence of sodium silicate on backfill performance, a series of laboratory experiments were carried out on samples with different binder compositions, such as: cement; slag and cement; slag, cement and sodium silicate; and slag and sodium silicate. Additionally, the effects of mixing time and addition order on the backfill samples' performance were studied. The subsequent thesis focuses mainly on the strength of paste and slurry backfill samples containing sodium silicate in addition to the observation of a number of experimental variables, which include: pulp density (relative amount of water), curing time, and binder dosage. In order to investigate the overall suitability of sodium silicate for use in stabilised backfill, other properties such as porosity, elastic modulus, and trends of water release are also studied. The results of the research endeavour demonstrate that sodium silicate-fortified backfill materials behave favourably compared with cemented backfills. Sodium silicate, thus, has potential as a backfill binder or additive.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z224s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d8267</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mine filling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silicates</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j9460"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sieve bootstrap unit root tests</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Richard, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We consider the use of a sieve bootstrap based on moving average (MA) and autoregressive moving average (ARMA) approximations to test the unit root hypothesis when the true Data Generating Process (DGP) is a general linear process. We provide invariance principles for these bootstrap DGPs and we prove that the resulting ADF tests are asymptotically valid. Our simulations indicate that these tests sometimes outperform those based on the usual autoregressive (AR) sieve bootstrap. We study the reasons for the failure of the AR sieve bootstrap tests and propose some solutions, including a modified version of the fast double bootstrap. We also argue that using biased estimators to build bootstrap DGPs may result in less accurate inference. Some simulations confirm this in the case of ADF tests. We show that one can use the GLS transformation matrix to obtain equations that can be used to estimate bias in general ARMA(p,q) models. We compare the resulting bias reduced estimator to a widely used bootstrap based bias corrected estimator. Our simulations indicate that the former has better finite sample properties then the latter in the case of MA models. Finally, our simulations show that using bias corrected or bias reduced estimators to build bootstrap DGP sometimes provides accuracy gains.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g4273.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j9460</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bootstrap (Statistics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Econometrics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics -- Statistical methods</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajw827h15c"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigations into the design and dissection of genetic networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Libby, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The sequencing of the human genome revealed that the number of genes does not explain why humans are different from other organisms like mice and dogs. Instead, it is how genes interact with each other and the environment that separates us from other organisms. This motivates the study of genetic networks and, consequently, my research. My work delves into the roles that simple genetic networks play in a cell and explores the biotechnological aspects of how to uncover such genes and their interactions in experimental models. Cells must respond to the extracellular environment to contract, migrate, and live. Cells, however, are subject to stochastic fluctuations in protein concentrations. I investigate how cells make important decisions such as gene transcription based on noisy measurements of the extracellular environment. I propose that genetic networks perform Bayesian inference as a way to consider the probabilistic nature of these measurements and make the best decision. With mathematical models, I show that allosteric repressors and activators can correctly infer the state of the environment despite fluctuating concentrations of molecules. Viewing transcriptional networks as inference modules explains previous experimental data. I also discover that the particular inference problem determines whether repressors or activators are better. Next, I explore the genetic underpinnings of two canine models of atrial fibrillation: atrial tachypacing and ventricular tachypacing. Using Affymetrix microarrays, I find that the genetic signatures of these two models are significantly different both in magnitude and in class of genes expressed. The ventricular tachypacing model has thousands of transcripts differentially expressed with little overlap between 24 hours and 2 weeks, suggesting independent mechanisms. The atrial tachypacing model demonstrates an adaptation as the number of genes found changed decreases with increasing time to the point that no genes are changed at 6 weeks. I use higher level analysis to find that extracellular matrix components are among the most changed in ventricular tachypacing and that genes like connective tissue growth factor may be responsible. Finally, I generalize the main problem of microarray analysis into an evaluation problem of choosing between two competing options based on the scores of many independent judges. In this context, I rediscover the voting paradox and compare two different solutions to this problem: the sum rule and the majority rule. I find that the accuracy of a decision depends on the distribution of the judges' scores. Narrow distributions are better solved with a sum rule, while broad distributions prefer a majority rule. This finding motivates a new algorithm for microarray analysis which outperforms popular existing algorithms on a sample data set and the canine data set examined earlier. A cost analysis reveals that the optimal number of judges depends on the ratio of the cost of a wrong decision to the cost of a judge.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq978018m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827h15c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bayes Theorem</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atrial Fibrillation -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gene Expression -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oligonucleotide Array Sequence Analysis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dk929"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Practical issues in modern Monte Carlo integration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lefebvre, Geneviève, 1978-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Computing marginal likelihoods to perform Bayesian model selection is a challenging task, particularly when the models considered involve a large number of parameters. In this thesis, we propose the use of an adaptive quadrature algorithm to automate the selection of the grid in path sampling, an integration technique recognized as one of the most powerful Monte Carlo integration statistical methods for marginal likelihood estimation. We begin by examining the impact of two tuning parameters of path sampling, the choice of the importance density and the specification of the grid, which are both shown to be potentially very influential. We then present, in detail, the Grid Selection by Adaptive Quadrature (GSAQ) algorithm for selecting the grid. We perform a comparison between the GSAQ and standard grid implementation of path sampling using two well-studied data sets; the GSAQ approach is found to yield superior results. GSAQ is then successfully applied to a longitudinal hierarchical regression model selection problem in Multiple Sclerosis research. Using an identity arising in path sampling, we then derive general expressions for the Kullback-Leibler (KL) and Jeffrey (J) divergences between two distributions with common support but from possibly different parametric families. These expressions naturally stem from path sampling when the popular geometric path is used to link the extreme densities. Expressions for the KL and J-divergences are also given for any two intermediate densities lying on the path. Estimates for the KL divergence (up to a constant) and for the J-divergence, between a posterior distribution and a selected importance density, can be obtained directly, prior to path sampling implementation. The J-divergence is shown to be helpful for choosing importance densities that minimize the error of the path sampling estimates. Finally we present the results of a simulation study devised to investigate whether improvement in performance can be achieved by using the KL and J-divergences to select sequences of distributions in parallel (population-based) simulations, such as in the Sequential Monte Carlo Sampling and the Annealed Importance Sampling algorithms. We compare these choices of sequences to more conventional choices in the context of a mixture example. Unexpected results are obtained, and those for the KL and J-divergences are mixed. More fundamentally, we uncover the need to select the sequence of tempered distributions in accordance with the resampling scheme.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d827h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk929</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Monte Carlo method</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sv180"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis, characterization and stability of arsenate-bearing materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Le Berre, Jean-François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The scope of this thesis is the study (synthesis, characterization and stability evaluation) of poorly-crystalline iron arsenate (Fe/As = 1) and several crystalline metal (Fe, Al, Ga, In, La) arsenates. Scorodite is used as reference materials in both cases. The study of the crystalline materials is approached from the standpoint of determining the relationship between their structure and chemical stability and their potential as arsenic immobilizing carriers. On the other hand the study of the poorly-crystalline iron (III)---arsenate (Fe/As = 1) phases seeks to elucidate their structural development as a function of pH and the mechanism of their crystallization. The synthesis of the crystalline metal arsenates (mansfieldite (A1AsO 4·2H2O), scorodite-mansfieldite solid solution series, gallium arsenate dihydrate, indium arsenate dihydrate and lanthanum arsenate) involves hydrothermal precipitation from equimolar metal---arsenic (V) nitrate solutions at 160°C. Several techniques, among which XRD, TGA, FEG-SEM, VP-SEM and FEG-TEM, are used to characterize the synthesized materials. A1AsO4·2H2O and InAsO4·2H 2O are found to crystallize as single crystal particles as opposed to the other arsenates that crystallize as aggregates of polycrystalline particles. In terms of stability, all synthesized metal arsenates are determined to be less stable than scorodite. Iron (III) arsenate precipitated from equimolar Fe (III---As (V) (nitrate or sulfate) solutions by fast neutralization in the temperature range 22 to 80°C is found to consist predominantly of a poorly-crystalline FeAsO 4·(2+x)H2O phase and to lesser extent of two-line ferrihydrite. The fraction of ferrihydrite (or better arsenate-adsorbed ferrihydrite) increases with pH and temperature elevation. FEG-TEM observation combined with microanalysis revealed a nanosize-domain structure with uniform chemical composition (Fe/As) at pH 2 but widely variable chemical composition at pH 8 consistent with its postulated heterogeneous nature. The poorly-crystalline iron arsenate is found to transform to crystalline scorodite following "auto catalytic" (sigmoidal) kinetic behavior. The rate of transformation is accelerated by temperature elevation and pH reduction. The transformation is explained by a mechanism which involves heterogeneous nucleation within the amorphous precursor phase nanoparticle aggregates and self-catalyzed crystal growth sustained by short-range dissolution.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mh22z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sv180</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Arsenates</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h382j"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of variable evolutionary rates on phylogenetic inference : a Bayesian approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lepage, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this dissertation, we explore the effect of variable evolutionary rates on phylogenetic inference. In the first half of the thesis are introduced the biological fundamentals and the statistical framework that will be used throughout the thesis. The basic concepts in phylogenetics and an overview of Bayesian inference are presented in Chapter 1. In Chapter 2, we survey the models that are already used for rate variation. We argue that the CIR process---a diffusion process widely used in finance---is the best suited for applications in phylogenetics, for both mathematical and computational reasons. Chapter 3 shows how evolutionary rate models are incorporated to DNA substitution models. We derive the general formulae for transition probabilities of substitutions when the rate is a continuous-time Markov chain, a diffusion process or a jump process (a diffusion process with discrete jumps). The second half of the thesis is dedicated to applications of variable evolutionary rate models in two different contexts. In Chapter 4, we use the CIR process to model heterotachy, an evolutionary hypothesis according to which positions of an alignment may evolve at rates that vary with time differently from site to site. A comparison the CIR process with the covarion---a widely-used heterotachous model---on two different data sets allows us to conclude that the CIR provides a significantly better fit. Our approach, based on a Bayesian mixture model, enables us to determine the level of heterotachy at each site. Finally, the impact of variable evolutionary rates on divergence time estimation is explored in Chapter 5. Several models, including the CIR process are compared on three data sets. We find that autocorrelated models (including the CIR) provide the best fits.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vz08q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h382j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Evolution (Biology) -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bayesian statistical decision theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phylogeny -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m826f"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification and characterization of the Icsbp1R294C mutation in BXH-2 mice responsible for their unique susceptibility to intracellular pathogens and their chronic myeloid leukemia-like syndrome</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Turcotte, Karine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While studying the unique Nramp1 (Slcl1a1)-independent susceptibility of BXH-2 mice to Mycobacterium bovis (BCG) infection, we noted that these mice develop splenomegaly associated with important infiltration of Mac-1+/GR-1+ (macrophage antigen-1 +/granulocyte differentiation antigen 1+) granulocyte precursors in spleen, lymph nodes and bone marrow resembling a myeloproliferative syndrome. This syndrome was subsequently found to be independent of the BCG infection. Segregation analyses revealed that the myeloproliferative syndrome was controlled by a single recessive locus (Myls) mapping to a 9 megabases (Mb) region of chromosome 8. Myls contained one of the two replication-defective proviruses (Emv2) integrated into BXH-2 genome, and thought to play a role in generating the replication competent B-tropic ecotropic munne leukemia virus (MuLV) known to cause clonal tumours in BXH-2 mice. By narrowing down the Myls interval to 2 Mb, we could exclude Emv2 as a potential candidate for Myls. However, several other candidates remained, among which the interferon consensus sequence binding protein 1 (Icsbp1) gene. We showed that BXH-2 mice carry a mutation (915 C to T) resulting in an arginine-to-cysteine substitution at position 294 within the transactivation domain of the Icsbp1 protein. We found that Icsbp1C294 behaves as a hypomorphic allele which appears to have a threshold effect on maturation of the myeloid lineage, as well as pleiotropic consequences on resistance to different types of infectious agents including Mycobacterium bovis (BCG). Our results suggest a two-step mutagenic model in which first, inactivation of Icsbp1 predisposes to myeloproliferation and immunodeficiency and favours the production of retroviruses. Then, subsequent insertional mutagenesis of oncogenes or tumour suppressors by the retrovirus results in clonal expansion of leukemic cells characteristic of BXH-2 mice.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1073248.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m826f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f544d"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>What is the nature of university professors' discipline-specific pedagogical knowledge? : a descriptive multicase study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Berthiaume, Denis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research project investigates the nature of university professors' discipline-specific pedagogical knowledge (DPK). Traditionally, DPK has been examined with the help of constructs from two distinct lines of research: the knowledge base for teaching and disciplinary specificity in university teaching. Yet, the two lines of research have seldom been combined to explore DPK. Furthermore, linkages between those two lines of research point to the potential contribution of research on personal epistemologies. Therefore, the aim of this research is to describe empirically the phenomenon of DPK using constructs from these three lines of research. The research project takes the form of an instrumental multicase study of four university professors from four different disciplines. Each professor was interviewed five times, thus providing insight into their thinking about teaching, their discipline and their knowledge in general. Transcripts were analysed using a mixed a priori/emerging coding scheme. The data analysis led to the identification of components and dimensions of DPK corresponding to constructs from each line of research. Simultaneously, relationships between those components and dimensions were identified. Furthermore, the analysis singled out components, dimensions, and relationships common to the four professors, thus providing information about elements of DPK university professors share, regardless of their discipline of instruction. Overall, the findings provide an empirical framework of university professors' DPK that captures the phenomenon more accurately than has been the case with previous approaches. Therefore, from a theoretical standpoint, the DPK framework furthers our understanding of the difficulties faced by university professors when attempting to relate their pedagogical knowledge to the specific characteristics of their discipline of instruction. From an educational standpoint, the DPK framework points to specific aspects of the learning experience of university professors that need to be supported by academic development efforts.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js98q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f544d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Knowledge, Theory of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Educational psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>College teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290f75w"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A predictive model of rectal tumour response to pre-operative high-dose rate endorectal brachytherapy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zlobec, Inti</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pre-operative radiotherapy for patients with locally advanced rectal carcinoma has been shown to improve survival rates and local tumour control. The ability to identify tumours most likely to undergo a complete or partial response would improve the selection of patients for radiotherapy and potentially modify post-treatment planning. The aim of this study was to develop a multi-marker model of tumour response to pre-operative high-dose rate endorectal brachytherapy (HDREB). Immunohistochemistry (IHC) for p53, Bcl-2, VEGF, APAF-1 and EGFR was carried out on 104 pre-treatment rectal tumour biopsies from patients undergoing a pre-operative HDREB protocol. Immunoreactivity was scored by at least three pathologists using a semi-quantitative scoring method. The reproducibility of the scoring system was evaluated. Receiver operating characteristic curve (ROC) analysis was performed for each protein to determine clinically relevant cutoff scores for defining tumour positivity. Multivariate logistic regression analysis was carried out to identify independent predictive factors of tumour response. Both the semi-quantitative scoring system and ROC curve analysis were found to be reproducible. In addition, the combined analysis of VEGF and EGFR was highly predictive of complete pathologic response to radiotherapy. EGFR was found to independently predict complete or partial tumour regression but only with low sensitivity and specificity. A large-scale prospective study is necessary to confirm these findings. Moreover, the novel methodology proposed and validated in this study to assess immunoreactivity could significantly enhance the value of IHC findings in colorectal cancer as well as other tumour types.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494d56t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290f75w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580r78g"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Using multiple representation systems to deepen understanding of functional relationships in mathematics</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Balyta, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes an experiment using technology to develop conceptual understanding of functions through graphical representations. It examines the effects of including dynamic representations in a conceptual approach to the teaching of functions. The study was implemented over a 5-day period in a Grade 9 class in a small, generally working class, rural school in Eastern Massachusetts. Participating students were observed during class discussions and video analysis, and their written responses and created functions were analyzed. The procedure used in the experiment was based on the Theory of Didactic Situations and used the Didactic Engineering methodology. The structure and sequencing of the thesis is also based on these concepts. Conclusions are drawn regarding the effects of using multiple representations systems to deepen understanding of functional relationships and suggested improvements to the introduction of the function concept in high school instructional programs are given.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z709189t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580r78g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Functions -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Educational technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021k31p"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pharmacological induction of Islet Neogenesis and subsequent beta-cell mass expansion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lipsett, Mark Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current therapies for diabetes mellitus are insufficient to prevent the devastating complications associated with this disease. A novel approach for the treatment of diabetes is the restoration of an insulin-producing beta-cell mass through the stimulation of endogenous progenitor cells. Thus, the aim of this thesis was to determine if pharmacological initiation of islet neogenesis and subsequent beta-cell mass expansion will lead to the reversal of hyperglycaemia in a response that is under homeostatic regulation and has efficacy in humans. A pentadecapeptide fragment of Islet Neogenesis Associated Protein (INGAP 104-108), was administered to normoglycaemic hamsters and was found to result in an expanded beta-cell mass as measured by immunohistochemical morphometric analysis. This expansion was shown to occur through the transformation of duct- and acinar-associated progenitors. In order to determine if this therapeutic approach would be effective in mammals other than hamsters, INGAP 104-108 was administered to normoglycaemic mice, dogs and monkeys, hyperglycaemic mice, and to human pancreatic tissue cultures. INGAP104-108 administration led to a dose-dependent increase of beta-cell mass in mice, with similar trends observed in dogs. Similarly, administration of INGAP104-108 to normoglycaemic monkeys for 90 days resulted in profound areas of islet neogenesis. Administration of INGAP104-108 to diabetic mice resulted in restoration of euglycaemia and a dramatic increase in beta-cell mass. Furthermore, INGAP104-108 administration to cultured human acinar tissue, led to the formation of insulin-producing islet-like structures. These results suggest that INGAP 104-108 therapy has the ability to reverse a diabetic state and could be effective in humans. However, it was necessary to determine whether the continual stimulation of islet neogenesis through INGAP 104-108 administration is a safe therapeutic approach. The beta-cell mass dynamics of euglycaemic mice administered INGAP 104-108 at various doses for 31 or 90 days were determined. beta-cell mass was greatly increased at 31 days of therapy, though by 90 days of therapy there was no difference in total beta cell mass between all treatment groups. However, there were marked instances of islet neogenesis in mice treated with INGAP104-108 for 90 days. This elevation in islet neogenesis was tempered by decreased beta-cell replication and increased beta-cell apoptosis, resulting in no overall difference in total beta-cell mass. These results suggest that inherent homeostatic regulation persisted to maintain a net beta-cell mass that matched the physiological need, even in the setting of continual induction of islet neogenesis. INGAP104-108 therapy has been shown to expand the insulin-producing beta-cell mass in a safe homeostatic manner and reverse diabetic hyperglycaemia. These findings suggest that a novel pharmacological agent for the successful stimulation of beta-cell mass expansion is within reach, enabling new therapeutic modalities for the treatment of diabetes.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nd11p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021k31p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>