<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bk116"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The migration, survival and movements of Atlantic salmon (salmo salar) kelts originating from the Miramichi river system, NB</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jacobs, Keelan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the migration and survival of Miramichi River Atlantic salmon kelts within the Miramichi estuary and Atlantic Ocean, with the goals of documenting their migratory characteristics, survival and possible long term effects of catch-and-release angling. A total of 100 kelts were tagged with acoustic telemetry tags in 2008 and 2009 (50 per year) and were passively tracked through the Miramichi estuary system and Atlantic Ocean. Kelt survival to the estuary exit was high; 96 % in 2008, 92 % in 2009 and 94 % combined. Of the kelts that survived, 11 returned as repeat spawners (seven consecutives, four alternates). They did not use the estuary as an overwintering ground after spawning. Kelts spent significantly different amounts of time in the upper, middle and lower reaches of the estuary during their exit and return. Once released, the majority of kelts spent more time between their release site and the first receiver downstream then in the remaining downstream sections of the estuary. Average speeds of travel were variable, differing between years, but speed increased as kelts progressed towards the estuary exit. Kelts entered the sea a short time after release (&lt; 20 d). Once out of the Miramichi system, kelts were occasionally detected along the coast when leaving from and returning to the river system. Some kelts exited the Gulf of St. Lawrence via the Strait of Belle Isle (22 in 2008, 9 in 2009), over a period of 20 d in 2008 and 35 d in 2009. Speeds of travel for kelts within the Gulf of St. Lawrence varied from 10.4 km/d to 69.9 km/d. Repeat spawners that returned as consecutives in 2008 and 2009 did so between 44 and 64.8 d post sea entry. Alternates returned an average of 394.7 d post sea entry. Early stages of estuarine migration are important for early marine survival and the return of repeat spawners. Consecutive spawners may exit the Gulf to recondition. This research gives insight into the role that the early stage of estuary migration has upon the early survival and return of repeat spawners as well as into the migratory routes used and possible destinations for ocean bound kelts.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse couvre la migration et la survie des saumons noir de l'Atlantique provenant de la Rivière Miramichi dans l'estuaire et dans l'océan Atlantique. Le but de cette thèse est de documenté leurs caractéristiques migratoire, leur survie et les effets possible de la graciation. Un total de 100 saumons noir ont été bagués en 2008 et en 2009 (50 par année) à l'aide de bagues de télémétrie acoustiques. Ceux-ci ont été suivis dans l'estuaire de la  Rivière Miramichi et dans l'océan Atlantique. Leur survie jusqu'à la sortie de l'estuaire fut élevée (96 % en 2008, 92 % en 2009 et 94 % combiné). Des saumons qui ont survécut, 11 sont revenus afin de frayer de nouveau (sept consécutivement, quatre alternativement). Ils ne sont pas restés dans l'estuaire durant l'hiver après la fraie. Les saumons noir sont restés pour une période de temps différente dans les trois sections de l'estuaire (début, milieu, fin) durant la sortie et l'entrée. Après leur remise à l'eau, la plupart des saumons noir sont restés entre leur site de relâche et le premier receveur en aval. La vitesse de déplacement a augmenté dans chaque section, de l'endroit de  relâche à la sortie de l'estuaire. La sortie de l'estuaire et l'entrée dans l'océan s'est faite en peu de temps (&lt;20 jours). Dans le Golfe du St. Laurent, les saumons noir ont été documentés près des côtes. Ils sont sortis du Golfe du St. Laurent via le Détroit de Belle Isle (22 en 2008, 9 en 2009) se concentrant durant une période de 20 jours en 2008 et 35 jours en 2009. Dans le Golfe du St. Laurent la vitesse de déplacement se situait entre 10.4 km/jour et 69.9 km/jour. Les saumons sont retournés dans l'estuaire la même année entre 44 et 64.8 jours après leur sortie de l'estuaire, ou l'année suivante dans une moyenne de 394.7 jours après leur sortie de l'estuaire. Le début de leur migration dans l'estuaire peut être important pour leur survie dans l'océan et leur retour pour une autre fraie. Il est aussi possible que les saumons qui frayent chaque année sortent du Golfe afin d'acquérir l'énergie requise pour frayer. Cette recherche nous donne un aperçu du rôle que leur migration dans l'estuaire à sur leur survie immédiate et sur le retour des frayeurs. Cette recherche nous donne aussi un aperçu des routes de migration utilisées et des destinations possible des saumons dans l'océan Atlantique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frederick G. Whoriskey</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mark A. Curtis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322j85c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bk116</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q851j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Capacity allocation in service overlay networks</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lam, Ngok</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Because of its decentralized nature and the lack of the required cooperations among the Internet autonomous systems, the current Internet is unable to provide end-to-end QoS guarantees to the application layer. The Service Overlay Network (SON) is a proposed solution to this end-to-end QoS provisioning problem. With its special overlay structure,the Service Overlay Network is able to provide reliable end-to-end QoS support on top of the Internet infrastructure. By considering the SON as a network with virtual connections and bandwidth allocations, we derive a series of new results for the SON. First, by referring to the reliability theory, we obtain a general form for the end-to-end blocking function. With the general blocking function, we investigate the two optimization approaches for designing a SON, namely the Maximum Profit (MP) approach that maximizes the prot and the Minimum Cost (MC) approach that minimizes the investment. Our study reveals that though the two approaches have been shown to be equivalent in many other settings, they are different in the SON environment. Our result indicates that the MP approach is a more appropriate approach for designing a SON, and the result is independent of the routing algorithm employed. Second, we develop a novel event dependent routing scheme that is efficient enough to be incorporated into the optimal capacity allocation problem. This allows the SON design problem to be formulated and solved as a MP optimization problem. Then we improve the optimization methodology by decomposing the main SON design problem into a number of sub-problems and we solve the main design problem by solving the sub-problems which involve finding the link shadow prices of the network links. It is exactly because we are using the maximum profit approach, the idea of link shadow price could be incorporatedto solve the design problem. A fast macro-state convolution scheme based on the link shadow price is developed to provide a traffic differentiation module to the optimization formulation. This additional module allows the optimization framework consider traffic connections based on the (monetary) contributions they offer to the network. Like many other telecommunications services, SON is believed to exhibit positive net-work externalities - once the network reaches a "critical mass", it will continue to grow in a self-reinforcing manner. The optimal pricing of the SON services is therefore another crucial piece of information for the SON to achieve success. We study a set of Lagrange i imultipliers and show that the SON service charges are closely related to the set of multipliers. When the service levels are not hard requirements, by using the multipliers as the service charges, the resulting network will be on the Pareto frontier of a multi-criteria optimization problem that maximizes both the operator utility and the user utility. This piece of work provides information from the problem formulation, to the actual design process, to the simplication and enhancement of the design process, and finally to the set of optimal prices which the operator could charge. It essentially provides comprehensive information for deploying the SON network.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En raison de son caractere decentralise et le manque de cooperations necessaires entre les l'Internet des systemes autonomes, l'Internet actuel est incapable de fournir de bout en bout QoS garantit a la couche application. L'Overlay Service Network (SON) est une solution proposee a ce QoS de bout-en-bout probleme. Grace a sa structure speciale de recouvrement, l'Overlay Service Network est en mesure de fournir des informations ables de bout en bout la qualite de service support au-dessus de l'infrastructure Internet. En considerant la SON en reseau avec des connexions virtuelles et la bande passante allocations, nous obtenons une serie de nouveaux resultats pour le SON. Tout d'abord, en se referant a la theorie de la abilite, nous obtenons une forme generale pour la fin-en-bout fonction de blocage. Avec l'general fonction de blocage, nous examinons les deux approches d'optimisation pour la conception une SON, soit le maximum Profit (MP) approche qui maximise le profit et le Cout minimum (MC) approche qui minimise l'investissement. Notre etude revele que si les deux approches se sont revelees etre l'equivalent dans de nombreux autres parametres, ils sont differents dans l'environnement SON. Nos resultats montrent que l'approche MP est une approche plus appropriee pour la conception d'un SON, et le resultat est independant de l'algorithme de routage utilise. Deuxiemement, nous developpons un nouvel evenement depend regime de routage qui est assez efficace pour etre incorpores dans le probleme d'allocation de la capacite optimale. Cela permet au probleme de conception Fils pour etre formule et resolu comme un probleme d'optimisation MP. Ensuite, nous avons d'ameliorer la methodologie d'optimisation en decomposant le probleme de conception principale fils dans un certain nombre de sous problemes et nous resolvons le probleme de conception principale en resolvant les problemes sous-qui impliquent la constatation du prix fictifs lien des liens du reseau. C'est justement parce que nous utilisons la recherche du profit maximum, l'idee de prix fictif lien pourrait etre constituee pour resoudre le probleme de conception. Un schema de convolution rapide macro-etat base sur le prix fictif lien est developpe pour fournir une differenciation du trafic module d'optimisation de la formulation. Ce module additionnel permet l'optimisation examiner le cadre des connexions de trafic sur la base des contributions (monetaires), ils offrent au reseau. Comme beaucoup d'autres services de telecommunications, SON est estime a exposer nette positive externalites de travail - une fois que le reseau atteint une "masse critique", il va continuer a croitre dans un auto-renforcement maniere. La tarification optimale des services de SON est donc un autre element crucial de l'information pour le SON pour reussir. Nous etudions une serie de multiplicateurs Lagrange et montrent que les frais de service SON sont etroitement liees a l'ensemble des multiplicateurs. Lorsque les niveaux de service ne sont pas des exigences dur, en utilisant les multiplicateurs que les frais de service, le reseau qui en resulte sera sur la frontiere de Pareto d'un probleme d'optimisation multi-criteres qui maximise la fois l'utilite operateur et l'utilite de l'utilisateur. Ce travail fournit des informations a partir de la formulation du probleme, a l'actuel la conception de processus, de la simplification et l'amelioration du processus de conception, et enfin a l'ensemble des prix optimal o l'operateur peut charger. Il fournit essentiellement des informations completes pour le deploiement du reseau SON. Ce travail fournit des informations a partir de la formulation du probleme, a l'actuel la conception de processus, de la simplification et l'amelioration du processus de conception, et enfn a l'ensemble des prix optimal o l'operateur peut charger. Il fournit essentiellement des informations completes pour le deploiement du reseau SON.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zbigniew Dziong</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lorne Mason</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw80t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q851j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z931t"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Delineating the role of caspase-mediated cleavage of HuR during muscle fiber information</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nassif, Christina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the formation of skeletal muscle, muscle cell differentiation is induced by endogenous and exogenous stimuli which cause mononucleated cells committed to myogenic lineage called myoblasts to fuse into multinucleated myotubes. The molecular mechanisms underlying this process involve myogenic regulatory factors (MRFs) which are under tight regulation. Although transcriptional regulation plays an important role, it alone can not account for the high expression levels of MRFs. In this thesis, a facet of the post-trancriptional regulation of promyogenic factors, namely MyoD and Myogenin, through the RNA-Binding Protein HuR is investigated. The presented studies show that HuR, which specifically binds to the AU-rich elements (AREs) in the 3’UTR of the aforementioned messages and stabilizes them, is cleaved during myogenesis by caspases at the site D226 which is in the HNS region. This domain normally mediates the shuttling of HuR via the import receptor Transportin 2 (Trn2); however, during myogenesis HuR is translocated to the cytoplasm where it is cleaved to generate HuR-CP1. This cleavage product then competes with HuR for binding to Trn2 which in turn prevents HuR from relocating to the nucleus and results in its cytoplasmic accumulation where it can further stabilize of the promyogenic factors and allow for muscle differentiation to proceed. Since HuR-CP1 competes with HuR for Trn2, it was interesting to examine other ligands that HuR-CP1 and HuR-CP2, the complementary cleavage product, could bind to. To this end a pull-down experiment was performed with these isoforms and extensive lists of partner proteins obtained were then compared. A biotinylation experiment was also performed with MyoD and myogenin 3’UTRs to search for RNA-Binding Proteins that could be partners of HuR or its cleavage products. Due to the time restraint, the associations from these preliminary data have not yet been validated; however an analysis of the data, shows hnRNPK, which associates with Hu proteins and antagonizes their role in neurogenesis, to bind all three isoforms as well as MyoD and myogenin 3'UTR. It would therefore be interesting to investigate some of the proteins identified in these experiments, validate the associations, and assess the roles they play, if any, during myogenesis.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Durant la formation des muscles, des stimulis endogènes et exogènes induisent la différentiation de cellules mononuclées en cellules de la lignée myogénique qui vont ensuite fusionner pour former des fibres musculaires multinuclées. Les mécanismes moléculaires entourant ce processus mettent en jeu des facteurs régulateurs de la myogenèse, les MRFs, qui sont eux-mêmes très finement contrôlés. Bien que la transcription joue un rôle très important dans ce processus, seule, elle ne peut pas maintenir le niveau élevé d'expression des MRFs. Dans ce mémoire j'étudie un aspect de la régulation post-transcriptionnelle, notamment le rôle de HuR, une protéine qui se lie spécifiquement aux éléments riches en AU (ARE) dans les régions 3’non traduites (3’UTRs) des ARN messagers comme MyoD et myogenin. Mes expériences démontrent que durant la différentiation musculaire, HuR est clivée par les caspases au niveau de l'acide aminé aspartate (D) 226 qui se situe dans un domaine important pour le mouvement de HuR du noyau au cytoplasme et l'inverse, avec l'aide de l'importine Transportin 2 (Trn2). Le déclenchement de la différentiation suscite le mouvement de HuR vers le cytoplasme, un évènement suivi par son clivage qui génère deux produits HuR CP2 et HuR-CP1. Ce dernier ayant une affinité pour Trn2, rentre en compétition avec HuR et prévient ainsi son mouvement vers le noyau. L'accumulation de HuR dans le cytoplasme permet donc de stabiliser les ARNm pro-myogéniques plus longtemps et de favoriser la différentiation. L'association de HuR-CP1 avec Trn2 m'a aussi menée à étudier les partenaires potentiels des produits de clivage par rapport à HuR. Mes expériences de Pull down ont généré de longues listes que j'ai pu comparer. Dans le but de voir si les protéines qui s'associent aux messages MyoD et myogenin se lient à HuR ou aux produits de clivage j'ai fait une expérience de biotinylation du 3’UTR des messages mentionnés. Malgrès le fait de ne pas avoir eu le temps de vérifier ces associations, j'ai pu repérer une protéine hnRNPK qui a était étudiée dans la neurogenèse et qui antagonise l'effet de protéines Hu dans ce processus. Cette protéine semble s'associer à HuR, les produits de clivages et les messages. Cela étant donné, je pense que ce serait intéressant de valider cette association en plus des autres mentionnées dans mon mémoire et d'étudier leurs importances dans la myogenèse.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Imed Eddine Gallouzi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128g19w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z931t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rq44h"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nebula-CDN: An Unstructured P2P Content Distribution Network</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Soyen, Arin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Current load-balancing and content distribution systems can efficiently handle high amounts of traffic a website encounters. However, when websites do not have the financial means of deploying multiple web-servers or acquiring services of proprietary content distribution networks such as Akamai, service interruptions are unavoidable. Recently, P2P-based approaches to content distribution have been proposed to support websites facing sporadic load. Inherent characteristics of content dissemination and scalability together with adaptation of locality-awareness allow these systems to perform on par with costly content distribution networks. Thus, implicit dissemination of key parts of a website becomes vital for load-balancing at the web-server, avoiding bottlenecks for visitors. Prevailing P2P-based caching systems, however, are either unavailable to leverage locality-awareness of participating peers or enforce structural topologies to do so. Enforcing a structural topology with such systems leads to scalability issues when participating peers exhibit dynamic behaviour, which is common with P2P systems. Hence, the system undergoes constant maintenance to achieve stability, which might not even be possible. In this thesis we outline two contributions. First, we modify Flower-CDN, a P2P content distribution network that exploits both structured and unstructured P2P features, to evaluate it with real rather than synthetic data. Second, we introduce Nebula-CDN, a locality-aware, P2P content distribution network which is completely unstructured. With Nebula-CDN, we leverage locality-awareness and efficient information dissemination by clustering geographically close peers that communicate with purely epidemic algorithms. In this thesis, the design and implementation of Nebula-CDN is assessed. Due to its design and the implemented algorithms, Nebula-CDN is better suited to handle churn without support of any underlying mechanism. Moreover, we conclude that it is able to match other content distribution networks in terms of hit-ratio and accesslatency, while keeping background bandwidth usage to a minimum.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les systèmes actuels de balancement de la charge et de distribution de contenu peuvent gérer eficacement le haut volume de requêtes reçues par les sites web. Cependant, lorsque les sites web qui n'ont pas assez de ressources ﬁnancières pour déployer plusieurs serveurs ou bien acquérir des services de réseaux propriétaires de distribution de contenu tel que Akamai, les services d'interruptions sont inévitables. Récemment des approches basées sur P2P pour la distribution de contenu ont été proposées pour supporter les sites web qui reçoivent des charges sporadiques. Les caractéristiques inhérentes de la diffusion de contenu et d'extensibilité ainsi que l'adaptation de la conscience de localité permettent à ces systèmes de fonctionner d'une façon rentable avec des réseaux de distribution de contenu. Ainsi, la diffusion implicite des éléments clés d'un site web est devenu essentielle pour le balancement de la charge d'un serveur web, évitant la congestion de visiteurs. En effet, les systèmes de cache basés sur P2P, sont soit non-disponible pour as-surer une conscience de localité des noeuds participants ou pour enforcer des topologies structurelles. Enforcer une topologie strcturelle avec ces systèmes mène à des problèmes d'extension lorsque les noeuds existants manifestent un comportement dynamique, ce qui est commun pour les systèmes P2P. D'où, le système subit une maintenance constante aﬁn d'atteindre la stabilité, ce qui ne peut même pas être possible. Dans cette thèse, nous décrivons deux contributions. Premièrement, nous modiﬁons Flower-CDN, un réseau de distribution de contenu P2P qui exploite à la fois les caractéristiques P2P structurées et non structurées, aﬁn de l'évaluer avec des données réelles et non-synthétiques. Deuxièmement, nous introduisons Nebula-CDN, un système conscient de la localité et un réseau de distribution de contenu P2P qui est complètement non structuré. Avec Nebula-CDN, nous exploitons la conscience de localité et la diffusion eficace d'information en distribuant géographiquement les noeuds adjacents qui communiquent avec des algorithmes purement épidémiques. Dans cette thèse, la conception et l'implémentation de Nebula-CDN est évaluée. Grâce à sa conception et ses algorithmes implémentés, Nebula-CDN est mieux adapté pour gérer la baratte sans support d'aucun sous mécanisme. De plus, nous concluons que c'est possible de correspondre autres réseaux de distribution de contenu en termes de taux et de latence d'accès, tout en maintenant l'usage de la bande passante à son minimum. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bettina Kemme</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3659252.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rq44h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593v054m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Albert Schweitzer's reverence for life ethic in relation to Arthur Schopenhauer and Friedrich Nietzsche</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Goodin, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'ouvrage présent se penche sur l'éthique du « Respect de la vie » d'Albert Schweitzer, en termes de ses fondements philosophiques puisés aux œuvres d'Arthur Schopenhauer et de Friedrich Nietzsche. Le rôle de ces penseurs n'a pas bien été compris dans les travaux académiques existants sur Schweitzer. Il a été présumé que les emprunts à ces deux philosophes créaient de sérieuses failles dans le système éthique développé par Schweitzer en le rendant excessivement métaphysique. Cette enquête procède à l'analyse des sources historiques employées par Schweitzer pour développer son éthique. Il est proposé que Schweitzer se soit servi du concept de la « Volonté de vivre » de Schopenhauer et de la théorie naturaliste de la « Volonté de puissance » de Nietzsche pour créer une philosophie élémentaire de la nature, elle-même compatible avec la science empirique. Ces éléments ont été utilisés par Schweitzer pour appuyer une nouvelle compréhension ontologique de la personne humaine, projet qu'il a nommé « Nouveau rationalisme ». Ce fondement éthique naturaliste situe les gens à l'intérieur du monde en tant qu'agents moraux. Après avoir démontré la cohérence de l'éthique du « Respect pour la vie » de Schweitzer, son système sera examiné en relation à son applicabilité dans l'éthique environnementale contemporaine, à travers les observations de Schweitzer sur la vie économique et sur son éthique en tant qu'individu.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present work examines the Reverence for Life ethic of Albert Schweitzer in terms of its philosophical grounding through the works of Arthur Schopenhauer and Friedrich Nietzsche.  The role of these thinkers has not been well understood in prior scholarship on Schweitzer, and it had been presumed that his reliance on these figures created serious flaws with his ethical system by making it excessively metaphysical.  This investigation proceeds through an analysis of the historical sources used by Schweitzer for the development of his ethic.  It is argued that Schweitzer drew upon the will-to-live concept from Schopenhauer and the naturalistic Will to Power theory of Nietzsche to create an elemental nature philosophy compatible with empirical science.  These elements were used by Schweitzer to support a new ontological understanding of the human person, a project termed by him as the New Rationalism.  This naturalistic ethical foundation placed people in the world as moral agents.  After demonstrating the coherence of Schweitzer's Reverence for Life ethic, his system is then examined in relation to its applicability in contemporary environmental ethics through Schweitzer's commentary on economic life and ethical personhood.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gregory Matthew Mikkelson</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>W. J. Torrance Kirby</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n267m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593v054m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion, Philosophy of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v838467j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of aging, metabolism and the age-dependent disease atherosclerosis in mouse mutants with altered mitochondrial function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hughes, Bryan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'inactivation des gènes clk-1 et isp-1, codant tous deux pour des protéines mitochondriales impliquées dans le processus de phosphorylation oxydative, a été démontrée comme augmentant la durée de vie du nématode Caenorhabditis elegans. La présente étude décrit les effets résultants de l'inactivation des homologues de ces gènes chez les mammifères sur le processus du vieillissement ainsi que sur une des principales pathologies reliées au vieillissement, l'artériosclérose. Les souris ne possédant qu'une seule copie fonctionnelle du gène Mclk1, l'homologue du gène clk1 qui code pour une enzyme impliquée dans la formation de l'ubiquinone, ont été montrées comme vivant plus longtemps que des souris de type sauvage. Cette prolongation de la durée de vie implique certainement une diminution de la mortalité reliée à diverses pathologies communément associées au vieillissement. Chez l'humain, l'artériosclérose est une des principales pathologies que l'on retrouve dans cette catégorie. Toutefois, cette étude n'a pas été en mesure de démontrer qu'une perte de fonction du gène Mclk1 confère une quelconque protection contre l'artériosclérose, la dyslipidémie ou le stress oxydatif chez deux lignées de souris modèles pour cette pathologie. Ces résultats démontrent que l'extension de la durée de vie observée chez les mutants Mclk1 +/- n'implique donc pas une augmentation de la protection contre l'artériosclérose. De plus, cette étude révèle qu'une diminution de l'expression du gène Mclk1 ne résulte pas en une prolongation de la durée de vie en présence d'hyperlipidémie ou d'inflammation chronique. Isp-1, de même que son homologue Risp (UQCRFS1) chez les mammifères, code pour la protéine fer-soufre Rieske, une composante de la ubiquinol : cytochrome c – oxydoréductase principalement reconnue comme étant le complexe III de la chaîne de respiration mitochondriale. Dans l'objectif de déterminer les effets de la perte de fonction Risp sur la durée de vie, des souris mutantes contenant exactement la même mutation faux-sens présente chez les vers mutants pour ce gène ont été générées. Ces souris homozygotes mutantes présentent un phénotype de mortalité embryonnaire alors que les souris hétérozygotes sont viables et sont notamment caractérisées par une baisse des niveaux d'expression de la protéine RISP et de l'activité du complexe I.  La fonction mitochondriale est également diminuée chez les souris Risp+/- et elle est jumelée à une diminution significative de l'activité métabolique globale. Les niveaux d'activité spontanée sont élevés chez les souris mâles Risp+/- mais sont inchangés chez les femelles. Bien que la durée de vie des mâles Risp+/- soit plus courte, la durée de vie maximale se trouve augmentée chez les femelles. Une diminution du taux de mortalité en fonction de l'âge a de plus été observée chez les souris hétérozygotes mâles et femelles. Cette étude démontre donc qu'une diminution de la fonction mitochondriale ne résultant en aucune pathologies observables peut néanmoins avoir le potentiel d'exercer des effets bénéfiques sur le vieillissement des individus affectés.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mutational disruption of the genes clk-1 and isp-1, the products of which are involved in mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation, has been shown to extend lifespan in the nematode worm Caenorhabditis elegans. Here, we describe efforts to characterize the effects of disrupting the mammalian homologues of these genes on the aging process and on the age-dependent disease atherosclerosis. Mice with a single copy of Mclk1 (the mammalian homologue of clk-1), a gene that encodes a mitochondrial enzyme required for the biosynthesis of ubiquinone, have been shown to live longer than wild-type mice. The prolonged survival implies a decreased mortality from age-dependent lethal pathologies. Atherosclerosis is one of the main age-dependent pathologies in humans. However, we found that Mclk1 heterozygosity did not protect against atherosclerosis, dyslipidemia or oxidative stress in two mouse models of the disease. Furthermore, an atherosclerosis-susceptible genetic background suppressed the lifespan-promoting effects of Mclk1 heterozygosity. These findings indicate that although Mclk1 heterozygosity can extend lifespan of mice, it does not necessarily protect against atherosclerosis. Moreover, in the presence of hyperlipidemia and chronic inflammation, Mclk1 heterozygosity is incapable of extending lifespan. isp-1, and its mammalian homologue Risp (aka UQCRFS1), encode the Rieske iron-sulfur protein, a core component of the ubiquinol:cytochrome c – oxidoreductase (complex III of the mitochondrial electron transport chain). In order to determine if the effect of Risp disruption on lifespan is conserved in mammals, we obtained "knock-in" mice with the same missense mutation as in isp-1 mutant worms. Homozygous mutant mice were non-viable, whereas heterozygotes (Risp+/-) were healthy with decreased RISP protein and a small but clearly significant deficit in the enzymatic activity of complex III. Risp+/- mice exhibited a mild mitochondrial dysfunction sufficient to decrease overall metabolic rate. Risp heterozygosity also increased spontaneous activity of male, but not female mice. Although lifespan of Risp+/- males was shortened, the maximum (but not median) lifespan of Risp+/- females was increased. In both sexes, Risp heterozygosity slowed the age-related increase in mortality rate. This study demonstrates that mitochondrial impairments not sufficient to cause overt mitochondrial disease nonetheless have the potential to exert significant positive or negative effects on lifespan.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Siegfried Hekimi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430888g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838467j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719r35c"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cortical participation in learning and memory tasks in a novel Alzheimer's disease transgenic rat model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>León, Wanda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La détérioration des fonctions cognitives incluant des pertes de mémoire est un des premiers symptômes cliniques observés dans la maladie d'Alzheimer (AD). Pour des fins de recherche, un modèle de rats transgéniques de la pathologie amyloïde similaire à AD a été généré et caractérisé afin de mieux comprendre les mécanismes pathologiques impliqués dans les troubles de la mémoire. Ce modèle transgénique exprime une seule copie de la version mutée de la protéine humaine APP et une seule copie par allèle est suffisante pour déclencher la pathologie amyloïde Aβ. Ces rats transgéniques accumulent l'Aβ intracellulaire, des plaques extracellulaires ainsi que des troubles cognitifs au fil de l'avancement pathologique. Dans ce modèle, les troubles cognitifs corrélaient avec les niveaux d'Aβ soluble oligomérique, soulignant le rôle d'Aβ dans ces altérations cognitives. En plus de la mémoire, le comportement émotif est aussi affecté par l'AD. Afin de déterminer si ces troubles émotifs sont aussi présents dans ce nouveau modèle de rats transgéniques, nous avons calibré et utilisé un protocole de conditionnement de la peur. Ces études préliminaires ont démontré un trouble de conditionnement de la peur au son chez les jeunes animaux transgéniques qui coïncidait avec de l'accumulation intraneuronale d'Aβ dans l'amygdale. Ces résultats ont confirmé la participation de cette région du SNC dans la partie émotive de la pathologie de l'Aβ. Finalement, nous avons élaboré des stratégies pour étudier les mécanismes d'apprentissage et de la mémoire chez les rats normaux et transgéniques. Nous avons ainsi trouvé une augmentation des niveaux de phosphorylation de ERK dans le mPFC lors de la consolidation et le rappel de la mémoire, supportant le rôle de l'activation de ERK dans le développement de la mémoire spatiale. De plus, nous avons cherché à savoir si les troubles du rappel de la mémoire chez les rats transgéniques étaient causés par un dérèglement de ERK/MAPK dans le mPFC. Nos résultats démontrent que la phosphorylation d'ERK est déréglée dans le mPFC des animaux transgéniques après le rappel de la mémoire. En conclusion, nos études ont mené à la caractérisation d'un nouveau modèle de rats transgéniques, une espèce avec des aptitudes cognitives supérieures aux modèles plus communs de souris transgéniques. De plus, nous avons développé une méthodologie pour étudier le signalement d'ERK dans l'hippocampe et le mPFC et démontré l'implication de ces régions dans la consolidation et le rappel des mémoires spatiales. Finalement, nous avons obtenu de l'information préliminaire sur la participation de l'Aβ dans l'amygdale causant des troubles émotifs reliés à la pathologie.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Deterioration of cognitive functions including a profound loss of memory is one of the early clinical symptoms observed in Alzheimer disease (AD). In light of this, a transgenic rat of AD-like amyloid pathology was generated and characterized to better comprehend the pathological mechanisms involved in the memory loss process. The resulting transgenic model expressing a single human mutated form of APP and only one transgene copy per allele was sufficient to trigger the full Aβ amyloid pathology in this rat model. These AD tg rats developed intracellular Aβ accumulation and plaque deposition along with age-pathology-dependent cognitive impairments. In this model the cognitive deficits were found to correlate with the levels of soluble Aβ oligomers; reinforcing the role for Aβ in driving these impairments. A compromise of the emotional behavior is also present early in AD. To determine whether emotional disturbances are also present in this novel rat transgenic model, a fear conditioning protocol was established and applied. These preliminary studies revealed auditory fear memory impairments in young AD transgenic rats which were coincidental with intracellular Aβ accumulation in the amygdala. These findings confirmed the participation of this CNS region in the emotional component of the Aβ-amyloid driven pathology. Finally, strategies were designed to investigate the complete learning and memory mechanisms in naïve and AD tg rats. Thus, we found an increase of ERK phosphorylation in mPFC during spatial memory consolidation and retrieval, supporting the role for ERK activation in the development of spatial memory. In addition we investigated whether the cognitive deficits during spatial memory recall in AD transgenic rats were due to an ERK/MAPK dysregulation in the mPFC. We have found that ERK phosphorylation was markedly deregulated in the mPFC of tg animals following spatial memory recall. In conclusion our studies have resulted in the characterization of a novel transgenic rat, a species with superior cognitive functions as compared with the traditional mouse transgenic models. In addition we have developed methodologies for the investigation of the ERK-regulated cell signalling in the hippocampus and mPFC showing a participation of this region in memory consolidation and recall and lastly we have obtained solid preliminary information on the participation of amygdala in the emotional involvement provided by the Aβ amyloid pathology. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Claudio Cuello</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246x18r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719r35c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29bb070"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Convergence acceleration for detached-eddy simulation via vorticity preserving limiters</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mohamed, Kaveh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A slope limiting algorithm for second-order Monotone Upstream-centered Schemes for Conservation Laws (MUSCL) is introduced in order to reduce the dissipation of vortices in flow simulations. The algorithm is based on the reconstruction of velocity components along the principle axes of the vortex and the augmentation of the central gradients' weight for the interpolation of velocity components on the swirl plane of the vortex. The performance of the scheme in different vortical flow problems is investigated. The proposed limiting algorithm has been able to considerably reduce the dissipation of vortices provided that the spatial and temporal discretization of the problem have been fine enough to resolve the length and time scales of the corresponding vortical motion. In particular, the scheme has significantly outperformed the conventional van Albada limiter to resolve the the second peak in the lift coefficient spectra in the case of a NACA0021 airfoil at post a stall condition. The eddy preserving scheme results in, on average, a two fold faster convergence rate as compared to the baseline DES scheme.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>On propose une nouvelle stratégie pour limiter les pentes des schémas du second ordre type MUSCL afin de réduire la dissipation des tourbillons pour des cas tests comportant des couches limites. L'algorithme est basé sur la reconstruction des composantes du vecteur vitesse le long des axes principaux du tourbillon et l'accroissement du gradient central des composantes de la vitesse sur le plan du tourbillon. Le schéma a bien performé dans différents problèmes d'écoulement tourbillonnaire. L'algorithme proposé a pu réduire considérablement la dissipation des tourbillons lorsque les discrétisations spaciale et temporelle sont suffisament fines pour résoudre les échelles de temps et d'espace du mouvement tourbillonnaire. En particulier le schéma est nettement moins precis en utilisant le limiteur de pentes Van Albada pour résoudre le deuxième pic du spectre du coefficient de la portance dans le cas de la simulation d'écoulement autour du profil NACA0021 avec décrochage. Les résultats du schéma préservant les tourbillons sont en moyenne deux fois plus rapides par rapport au schéma de référence DES.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sivakumaran Nadarajah</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Marius Paraschivoiu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010v08v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29bb070</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881r24r"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Birch and Swinnerton-Dyer conjecture for Q-curves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhao, Yu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The main result of this thesis is the proof of a Kolyvagin-like result for Q-curves defined over Q=(square root N) of perfect square conductor (including trivial conductor) over that field. Such a setting lies beyond the scope of the general results of Zhang [Zh1] because of the absence of a Shimura curve parameterization for E. This thesis also describes an explicit construction of Heegner points on E in a setting which so far has not yet studied in the literature and provides numerical examples. In turn, these computations yield numerical evidence for a conjectural connection, which we propose in this thesis, between the Heegner points we construct and the ATR points obtained by Darmon-Logan in [DL].</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Victor Rotger</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Henri Darmon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/736668997.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881r24r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m823m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Improving breast reconstruction outcomes: an evidence-based analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tahiri Hassani, Youssef</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Contexte: Avec l'évolution de la chirurgie reconstructive du sein, les chirurgiens plasticiens continuent de trouver des moyens d'améliorer leurs reconstructions. Le but de notre étude est de démontrer, à travers trois études cliniques, comment la recherche en chirurgie plastique peut améliorer les pratiques chirurgicales courantes, durant les périodes pré-, intra- et postopératoires. Méthodes: Lors de notre première étude, nous avons effectué une méta-analyse afin d'évaluer la sécurité d'utilisation et l'efficacité des Blocs Thoraciques Para-Vertébraux (BTPV) pour la chirurgie du sein, en comparaison à l'Anesthésie Générale (AG). Pour cela, nous avons effectué une recherche électronique et manuelle d'articles écrits en anglais et français sur les BTPV en chirurgie du sein (publiés jusqu'en Juin 2010). Deux niveaux de sélection d'articles ont été utilisés. La méthode de Mantel-Haenszel (effets fixes) a été utilisée pour effectuer la méta-analyse. Lors de notre seconde étude, nous avons effectué une revue systématique afin d'évaluer la littérature existante qui compare l'utilisation de drains ou non lors des réductions mammaires. Pour cela, nous avons cherché Pub Med, EMBASE, le "Cochrane Central Database of Clinical Trials (CENTRAL) on the Cochrane Library" et le "Science Citation Index Expanded" pour les articles et revues de Janvier 1980 à Juin 2009. Finalement, lors de notre troisième étude, nous présentons notre expérience sur l'utilisation d'expanseurs sous cutanés de seins avant une reconstruction avec un lambeau basé sur la perforante de l'artère inferieure épigastrique profonde (lambeau DIEP). Nous démontrons comment notre nouvelle technique élimine l'apparence de patch du lambeau DIEP sur le sein. Nous avons développé cette technique; technique chirurgicale qui n'a jamais été décrite ou présentée auparavant. Au courant des deux dernières années (Janvier 2008 – Janvier 2010), cinq patients ont bénéficié de cette approche à trois étapes. Une analyse rétrospective des caractéristiques médicales des patients, de leur pathologie mammaire, de leurs hospitalisations, des complications et de leurs résultats, a été effectuée. Résultats: Notre première étude a démontré que les BTPV en préopératoire permettent une anesthésie effective pour les cas-de-jour de chirurgie du sein et démontrent des bénéfices supérieurs à l'AG. Cependant, plus d'études sont à faire afin de déterminer si ces avantages perdurent si une technique optimale pour une AG pour patients non-hospitalises est employée. L'échographie pourrait contribuer à améliorer la morbidité possible associée avec les BTPV en chirurgie du sein et devrait être étudiée en profondeur. Notre seconde étude a démontré que même si le placement routinier de drains en intra-opératoire après réduction mammaire est une pratique très populaire, cela ne devrait pas être utilisé de manière routinière après les réductions mammaires. Plus d'études randomisées contrôlées ne sont pas requises. Finalement, notre troisième étude a démontré comment l'innovation en recherche en chirurgie plastique peut améliorer le résultat final, postopératoire. L'expansion mammaire sous-cutanée suivie par reconstruction avec lambeau DIEP peut être effectuée en toute sécurité et offre aux patients une reconstruction mammaire totalement autologue, avec une faible morbidité, tout en éliminant l'apparence en forme de patch des reconstructions mammaires autologues classiques. Conclusion: Ces trois différentes études illustrent bien comment la recherche en chirurgie plastique peut affecter les résultats en reconstruction mammaire. Nos deux premières études démontrent avec un niveau d'évidence très élevé (méta-analyse puis revue systématique) que des pratiques préopératoires et intra-opératoires établies peuvent être modifiées au bénéfice des patients. Finalement, nous avons démontré comment une technique chirurgicale innovatrice peut améliorer les résultats postopératoires. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Background: As breast reconstruction evolves, plastic surgeons continue to find ways to improve their reconstruction' outcomes. The aim of our study is to demonstrate how plastic surgery research impacts and improves current surgical practices. For instance, we designed three clinical studies which illustrate how research can affect current popular surgical practices, not only during the pre-operative period, but also intra-operative and post-operative periods. Methods: In the first study, we performed a meta-analysis to evaluate first the safety and efficacy of Thoracic ParaVertebral Block (TPVB) for breast surgery, and then to compare TPVB to General Anesthesia (GA) with regards to postoperative pain, nausea and vomiting, opioid consumption and length of hospital stay. To do so, an electronic and manual search of English- and French- language articles on TPVB in breast surgery (published up to June 2010) was performed. Two levels of screening were used to identify relevant articles. The Mantel-Haenszel method (fixed effect) was used to perform the meta-analysis.In the second study, we performed a systematic review to evaluate the existing literature, comparing the use of drains or not in reduction mammaplasty. We assessed first, if there is enough evidence to reach a conclusion regarding the routine use of drains after reduction mammaplasty, and then, if there is a need for more randomized control trials. To do so, we searched PubMed, EMBASE, the Cochrane Central Database of Clinical Trials (CENTRAL) on the Cochrane Library and Science Citation Index Expanded for original articles and reviews from January 1980 to June 2009. Finally, in the third study, we are presenting our clinical experience of using subcutaneous breast tissue expansion prior to reconstruction with Deep Inferior Epigastric Perforator (DIEP) flaps, and we are showing how our new technique eliminates the patch-like appearance of the skin paddle. We developed this technique; surgical technique that was never described or presented before. Over the past 2 years (January 2008 – January 2010), five patients underwent breast reconstruction using this three-stage approach. Retrospective analysis of patients' characteristics, breast history, surgical stay, complications and outcomes were performed. Results: Our first study demonstrated that pre-operative TPVB provides effective anesthesia for ambulatory / same-day breast surgery and can result in significant benefits over GA. However further studies are required to determine if these advantages would still persist if an optimal technique for outpatient GA is employed. Adjunctive ultrasonography may contribute to improve the safety of TPVB in breast surgery and requires further investigation.Our second study, we demonstrated that although placement of intra-operative drains after reduction mammaplasty is common practice, it should not be used routinely in reduction mammaplasty.  Further randomized controlled trials are not warranted. Finally, our third study demonstrated how innovation in plastic surgery research can improve the final, post-operative aesthetic outcome. Subcutaneous breast tissue expansion followed by DIEP flap reconstruction can be performed safely, offering patients a completely autologous breast reconstruction with low morbidity, as well as eliminating the classical patch-like appearance of flap reconstructions.Conclusion:These three different studies illustrate how plastic surgery research can have an impact on breast reconstruction outcomes. The first two studies demonstrate with a strong level of evidence (meta-analysis and systematic review, respectively) that established pre-operative and post-operative factors can be changed for the benefit of the patient. Finally, we demonstrated how surgical technique innovation can improve the post-operative outcome.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>M. Lucie Lessard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dx62j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m823m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117t00j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A multi-paradigm foundation for model transformation language engineering</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Syriani, Eugene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les systèmes développés aujourd'hui sont de plus en plus complexes. Pour résoudre les problèmes liés à la complexité, l'Ingénierie Dirigée par les Modèles (IDM) utilise des modèles qui décrivent les systèmes à différents niveaux d'abstraction. La Modélisation à Paradigmes Multiples (MPM) renchérie cette approche en modélisant toutes les composantes du système, aux niveaux d'abstraction les plus appropriés, tout en utilisant les formalismes les plus adéquats, afin de réduire toute complexité accidentelle. Les principes MPM stipulent que les transformations doivent aussi être modélisées explicitement. Les transformations de modèles sont au coeur de l'IDM. Elles permettent d'exécuter, d'analyser, de générer le code, d'optimiser, de composer, de synchroniser et de faire évoluer les modèles. Bien que la transformation de modèles soit basée sur de solides théories, les problèmes de mise à l'échelle et de validité restent néanmoins encore à résoudre. Vu l'intérêt suscité par la transformation de modèles, on observe de nos jours une vaste sélection de langages de transformation de modèles. Bien qu'ils apportent une énorme plus-value au développeur, l'implémentation de ces langages de transformation demeure cependant codée en dur. Cette thèse contribue aux fondements de l'ingénierie de langages de transformation de modèles, tout en suivant les principes MPM. Elle propose un système qui permet la conception de langages de transformation adaptés au problème à résoudre. Ces langages de transformation restreignent au maximum le modélisateur à n'utiliser que les concepts nécessaires. Le but est d'accroître la productivité du modélisateur, en élevant le niveau d'abstraction auquel les transformations sont spécifiées, tout en réduisant l'inadéquation du langage de transformation de modèles avec son domaine d'application. Après avoir analysé les différents usages des transformations de modèles et de leurs langages, nous avons identifié et extrait la partie commune à toutes les approches. Ceci permet alors de définir les transformations de modèles à partir des concepts essentiels qui les composent. Nous présentons alors T-Core, une collection d'opérateurs primitifs pour la transformation de modèles. T-Core est implémentée en Python, offrant ainsi une API disponible aux opérations primitives de transformation de modèles qui agissent sur des modèles représentés sous forme de graphes. Ceci permet à des programmeurs de « proprement » interagir avec des modèles et de les manipuler, faisant ainsi le lien entre le monde de la programmation et celui de la modélisation. Le système établi dans cette thèse modélise de manière explicite les langages de transformation de modèles et permet alors de créer des langages de transformation personnalisés. L'approche génère semi-automatiquement des langages de transformation adaptés au domaine d'application. MoTif est un autre langage de transformation de modèles construit à partir de ce système. Sa syntaxe, sa sémantique et son moteur d'exécution sont entièrement modélisés. MoTif est le résultat de la fusion entre T-Core et DEVS, un formalisme de simulation à événements discrets. MoTif permet alors d'introduire la notion de temps dans les transformations de modèles, ce qui permet de facilement modéliser des systèmes réactifs et, par conséquent, les optimiser et les calibrer. Finalement, nous explorons la notion de gestion d'exception au sein des transformations de modèles, afin de renforcer la fiabilité des logiciels bâtis à l'aide de cette technologie.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Systems developed today are increasing in complexity. Model-Driven Engineering (MDE) attempts to solve the issues related to complexity through the use of models to describe systems at different levels of abstraction. Multi-Paradigm Modelling (MPM) promotes modelling all parts of the system, at the most appropriate level(s) of abstraction, using the most appropriate formalism(s), to reduce accidental complexity. MPM principles state that transformations too should be modelled explicitly. Model transformations are at the very heart of MDE. Transformations allow one to execute, analyse, synthesize code, optimize, compose, synchronize, and evolve models. Despite a robust theoretical foundation, model transformation still suffers from scaling and correctness problems. The growing interest in model transformation has lead to a plethora of model transformation languages. They provide tremendous value for developers, but in all existing implementations, the transformation language is hard-coded. This thesis contributes to the engineering of model transformation languages at the foundation level, following MPM principles. It proposes a framework for designing transformation languages tailored to the problem to be solved. As a result, model transformation languages engineered in this framework maximally constrain the modeller to only use the constructs needed. The aim is to increase the modeller's productivity, by raising the level of abstraction at which transformations can be specified and by lowering the mismatch between model transformation languages and their application domain.After thoroughly analyzing the uses of model transformation and their supporting languages, we extract what is common to approaches and express model transformation at the level of their primitive building blocks. We introduce T-Core, a collection of transformation language primitives for model transformation. A Python implementation of T-Core is developed. It offers an API of primitive transformation operations that act on models represented as graphs. This opens the door for non-MDE developers to "properly" interact and manipulate models, making the link between the programming world and the modelling world. In the framework developed, model transformation languages are modelled explicitly. This supports developers in creating custom-built transformation languages. The approach semi-automatically generates model transformation languages adapted to the application domain. MoTif is another model transformation language engineered with this framework. Its syntax and semantics are completely modelled, as well as its execution engine. MoTif is the result of merging T-Core with DEVS, a discrete-event simulation formalism. It thus introduces the notion of time in model transformation. This allows one to easily model reactive systems and consequently optimize and calibrate them. Finally, the notion of exception handling in model transformation is explored to strengthen the robustness and dependability of the software built using this technology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hans Louis Vangheluwe</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881r269.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117t00j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dk911"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Walking on virtual ground: physics, perception, and interface design</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Visell, Yon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The sensorimotor capacities of the foot are crucial to human locomotion in diverse environments, to gathering information about walking surfaces, and to interacting with objects on the ground. Locomotion is increasingly employed to allow users to control and navigate within immersive virtual environments, but, in contrast to the hand, little attention has been given to the rendering of haptic sensations for the feet. This thesis addresses several challenges motivated by the problem of realizing haptic experiences of walking on virtual ground surfaces.  First, a novel family of interfaces is introduced, based on a vibrotactile display integrated in a rigid floor plate.  Its structural dynamics and controller have been optimized to ensure its ability to accurately reproduce mechanical vibrations over a wide frequency band, which was instrumental to realizing the perceptual study presented in the second part of the thesis. Distributed arrays of these devices are used to simulate virtual ground surfaces and floor-based multi-touch surfaces, whose usability for human-computer interaction is empirically demonstrated. The second component of this thesis is an experimental study of the contribution of vibrotactile sensory information to the perception of ground surface compliance.  A novel haptic perceptual illusion is demonstrated, in which the apparent compliance of a floor surface is increased by vibrations felt via the plantar sole of the foot.  This investigation also revealed the surprising ability of the vibrotactile floor interface to overcome, in part, a core limitation: its inability to display kinesthetic force-displacement information. The third part of the thesis analyzes texture-like mechanical signals produced through inelastic physical processes in complex, disordered materials like those encountered during walking in many natural terrains.  Patterns of fluctuations accompanying sliding friction and fracture processes in quasi-brittle, heterogeneous materials subjected to time-varying loads are characterized using methods from statistical physics.  This analysis was used to formulate novel algorithms for the haptic synthesis of high-frequency signatures of fracture processes in fiber composites and compressed granular media. In conclusion, this thesis presents an innovative hardware interface and techniques for interacting with virtual ground surfaces.  It also demonstrates a new haptic perceptual effect that lends justification to the display paradigm adopted here.  Finally, it analyzes and models transient, texture-like physical phenomena associated with stepping onto complex, natural ground materials.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les capacités sensori-motrices du pied sont essentielles à la locomotion humaine, à la collecte d'informations sur les surfaces de marche, et à l'interaction avec des objets au sol. La locomotion est de plus en plus utilisée pour interagir et naviguer dans les environnements virtuels immersifs, mais, contrairement à la main, peu d'attention a été accordée au rendu des sensations haptiques pour les pieds. Cette thèse aborde plusieurs problèmes liés à la réalisation d'expériences haptiques de marche sur des terrains virtuels. Tout d'abord, une nouvelle famille d'interfaces est présentée, fondée sur un dispositif vibrotactile intégré dans un carreau rigide. Sa dynamique structurelle et son contrôleur ont été optimisés pour assurer sa capacité à reproduire fidèlement les vibrations mécaniques dans une large bande de fréquence, ce qui était nécessaire à la réalisation de l'étude de perception présentée en deuxième partie de la thèse. Un pavage de ces dispositifs est utilisé pour simuler des terrains virtuels et des planchers tactiles multi-points, dont l'ergonomie est démontrée de manière empirique. Le deuxième volet de cette thèse est une étude expérimentale sur la contribution de l'information vibrotactile à la perception de la compliance du sol. Une nouvelle illusion perceptuelle haptique est démontrée, dans laquelle la compliance apparente du sol est augmentée par les vibrations ressenties par la plante du pied. Cette étude a également révélé l'étonnante capacité de l'interface vibrotactile à surmonter, en partie, une limitation intrinsèque : son incapacité à transmettre des informations kinesthésiques force-déplacement. La troisième partie de la thèse analyse les signaux mécaniques complexes produits par les processus physiques inélastiques dans les matériaux désordonnés tels que ceux rencontrés lors de la marche en terrain naturel. Les modèles de fluctuations accompagnant le frottement de glissement et les processus de fracture dans les matériaux hétérogènes quasi-fragiles soumis aux charges variables sont caractérisés par des méthodes de physique statistique. Cette analyse est utilisée pour formuler de nouveaux algorithmes pour la synthèse haptique des signatures à hautes fréquences des processus de fracture dans les composites de fibres et les materiaux granulaires compressés. En conclusion, cette thèse présente un dispositif vibrotactile et des techniques novateurs pour interagir avec des terrains virtuels. Elle démontre un nouvel effet perceptuel qui justifie le paradigme d'interaction haptique adopté ici. Enfin, elle analyse et modélise certains phénomènes physiques associés à la marche sur des terrains naturels complexes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jeremy Cooperstock</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042z294.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk911</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Robotics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698c89h"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reconceptualizing international law after 9/11: what role for state responsibility in the prevention and suppression of transnational terrorism?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Proulx, Vincent-Joël</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is clear that every state has an obligation to prevent terrorist attacks emanating from its territory and injurious to another state.  This proposition stems from various multilateral agreements on the suppression of terrorism and Security Council resolutions.  It also originates from the fundamental principle of sovereignty, which entails both rights and obligations.  However, the current state of knowledge does not exhaustively address the scope of this obligation of prevention and the legal consequences flowing from its violation.  The present study attempts to define the contents and contours of such obligation whilst placing particular critical emphasis on the mechanics of state responsibility. Whether obscured by new technologies like the Internet, the sophisticated cellular structure of terrorist organizations or convoluted political realities, the level of governmental involvement in terrorist activities is no longer readily discernible in all instances.  Furthermore, the prospect of governments waging surrogate warfare through proxies also poses intractable challenges to the mechanism of attribution under state responsibility.  Therefore, it is argued that new rules are required or, alternatively, that a critical reassessment of the role of the law of state responsibility in the prevention and suppression of transnational terrorism should be engaged. In so doing, the dissertation sets out the shortcomings of the extant scheme of international responsibility whilst concurrently identifying a paradigm shift towards more indirect modes of responsibility under international law, a trend corroborated by recent state and institutional practice.  This leads to the controversial question of the possible institutionalization of the implementation of state responsibility.  In assessing the potential roles of United Nations organs in this setting, the study carves out a specific – but limited – role for the Security Council in ascertaining the commission of internationally wrongful acts.  These considerations pave the way for the policy-oriented, context-sensitive reform of secondary rules of responsibility that follows.  After drawing heavily on varied legal and theoretical influences, the study devises and prescriptively argues for the implementation of a strict liability-inspired model grounded in the logic of indirect responsibility with a view to enhancing state compliance with counterterrorism obligations, shifting the focus on prevention and promoting multilateralism and transnational cooperation.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Il est clair que le droit international oblige chaque État à prévenir les attentats terroristes provenant de son territoire et portant atteinte aux intérêts d'un autre État.  Ce postulat découle de plusieurs conventions multilatérales et résolutions du Conseil de sécurité.  Il se fonde également sur le principe de la souveraineté qui entraîne droits et obligations.  Or, l'état actuel du savoir n'élucide pas la portée de cette obligation et n'apporte pas plus de précisions au sujet des conséquences juridiques résultant de sa violation.  La présente étude vise à cerner le contenu et la portée de cette obligation tout en mettant un accent particulier – et critique – sur les mécanismes du droit de la responsabilité internationale.  Possiblement obnubilé par l'avènement de nouvelles technologies comme Internet, la structure cellulaire de groupes terroristes ou des réalités politiques complexes, l'apport fourni par l'État originaire dans le cadre d'activités terroristes peut s'avérer imperceptible. La perspective qu'un État puisse procéder à des agressions indirectes par le biais de personnes ou groupes interposés soulève également d'importants défis au niveau de l'attribution.  Par conséquent, ces situations requièrent de nouvelles règles ou, du moins, justifient un réexamen critique du rôle que le droit de la responsabilité peut jouer au niveau de la prévention et de la suppression du terrorisme.  Dans cette optique, l'étude expose l'inadéquation du système actuel de responsabilité en identifiant toutefois un changement de paradigme vers des modes indirects de responsabilité en droit international, un phénomène étayé par la pratique étatique et institutionnelle récente.  Voilà donc les bases jetées avant d'aborder l'épineuse question de la mise en œuvre de la responsabilité de l'État par le truchement d'institutions internationales.  En évaluant le rôle des organes de l'ONU, l'étude taille un rôle spécifique – quoique modeste – pour le Conseil de sécurité au niveau du constat de l'illicite.  Ces observations préparent le terrain pour le projet de réforme des règles secondaires qui suit.  S'inspirant d'influences juridiques et théoriques variées dans une perspective de responsabilité indirecte, l'étude propose l'instauration d'un modèle informé par la responsabilité stricte afin d'augmenter la conformité étatique au droit international, d'encourager la prévention et de promouvoir le multilatéralisme et la coopération transnationale.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rene Provost</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jc979.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698c89h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afq978017b"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of animal models to study effects of maternal infection during pregnancy on offspring behavior</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fortier, Marie-Eve</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>On considère les infections maternelles durant la grossesse comme étant un facteur de risque environnemental important des maladies psychiatriques d'origine neurodéveloppementale telles la schizophrénie et l'autisme. On a attribué de telles altérations sur le développement neurologique de la progéniture à la réponse immunitaire de la mère. Dans ce projet de thèse, nous envisagions de créer un modèle animal nous permettant d'observer les effets de l'activation de l'immunitaire maternelle (AIM) sur le comportement de la progéniture. Au cours d'une première expérience, les rates étaient injectées d'une endotoxine bactérienne (lipopolysaccharide, LPS) aux jours (E) 18 et 19 de la gestation. La progéniture soumise à ce traitement exhibait une élévation dans la locomotion liée aux amphétamines, un indicateur comportemental de l'activité du système dopaminergique mésolimbique. La deuxième expérience consistait à administrer la LPS de manière chronique à l'aide de pompes osmotiques, depuis E18 jusqu'à la naissance. À l'âge adulte, la progéniture présentait une baisse de l'inhibition du réflexe de sursaut acoustique (PPI), indiquant un dérèglement du filtrage sensori-moteur. Préalablement à l'étude des effets de l'AIM provoquée par la mimique virale acide polyinosinique:polycytidylique (poly I:C), nous avons analysé la réponse immunitaire qu'elle provoquait chez le rat adulte mâle. Nous avons démontré que l'injection du poly I:C entraînait une réponse fébrile considérable, une diminution de l'appétit et du poids des animaux et une élévation du taux de cytokines pro-inflammatoires dans le sang. Au cours d'une autre étude, nous avons comparé les effets perturbateurs de l'AIM causée par les immunogènes poly I:C ou LPS, et celle causée par l'inflammation locale par injection intramusculaire de térébenthine. Dans cette même étude, nous avons analysé la présence de périodes de susceptibilité aux conséquences de l'AIM durant la gestation sur le PPI de la progéniture. L'AIM provoquée par l'injection de LPS ou de térébenthine diminuait de façon significative le PPI uniquement lorsqu'administré à des moments précis durant la gestion. Le poly I:C n'a eu aucun effet à la dose administré. Ainsi, nos résultats démontrent que l'agent immunitaire sélectionné et le moment durant la gestation où il sera utilisé sont des facteurs cruciaux dans la création de modèles d'AIM. Finalement, nous avons examiné la relation entre l'AIM durant la gestation et la fonction immunitaire de la progéniture. Nos résultats n'indiquent aucune altération de la réponse pyrogénique ou celle des cytokines suite à l'injection d'un immunogène chez les rats adultes exposés à une AIM in utero. En conclusion, les travaux effectués durant ce projet de thèse démontre que l'AIM durant la gestation peut causer des modifications permanentes sur le comportement de la progéniture. Ce constat vient supporter la notion selon laquelle le lien établi entre l'infection prénatale et le risque élevé de schizophrénie relève d'une relation causale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Maternal infections during pregnancy are thought to be an important environmental risk factor for psychiatric illnesses of neurodevelopmental origin such as schizophrenia and autism.  It has been suggested that the mother's immune response may be affecting the offspring's neurodevelopment and later behavior.  In this thesis, we aimed to develop animal models to study the effects of maternal immune activation (MIA) on offspring behavior.  In a first experiment, pregnant rats were injected with bacterial endotoxin (lipopolysaccharide, LPS) on gestational day (E) 18 and 19. The exposed offspring displayed increased amphetamine-induced locomotion, a behavioral indicator of mesolimbic dopamine activity.  In a second experiment, LPS was administered in a chronic manner by using osmotic pumps from E18 to birth.  Adult offspring displayed decreased prepulse inhibition (PPI), indicating disrupted sensorimotor gating.  Prior to studying the effects of MIA elicited by the viral mimic polyinosinic:polycytidylic acid (poly I:C), we characterized the immune reaction it triggered in adult male rats.  We demonstrated that poly I:C injection induced a robust febrile response, decreased food intake and body weight, and increased pro-inflammatory cytokines in the circulation.  In another study, we compared the disruptive effects of MIA induced by the immunogens poly I:C or LPS to that induced by local inflammation, elicited by intramuscular injection of turpentine.  In the same study, we also investigated the existence of gestational windows of susceptibility to the disruptive effects of MIA on offspring PPI.   MIA induced by LPS or turpentine significantly decreased offspring PPI only when administered at certain times during gestation.  Poly I:C had no effect at the dose administered.  Thus our results demonstrated that selection of the immune agent and gestational time of administration are both critical factors in MIA models.  Finally, we investigated if gestational MIA affected offspring immune function.  Our results indicated no change in pyrogenic and cytokine responses to an immune challenge in adult MIA-exposed rats. In conclusion, the work in this thesis provides evidence that gestational MIA can cause lasting alterations in offspring behavior.  This lends support to the idea that the association between prenatal infection and increased schizophrenia in human epidemiological studies reflects a causal relationship.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Giamal Luheshi</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Patricia J. Boksa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bk13r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq978017b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r7373"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Using "assessment for learning" practices with pre-university level students of English as a Second Language: a mixed methods study of teacher and student performance and beliefs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Colby, D Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of assessment to foster learning has become established in classroom settings in recent years, where it has drawn considerable research interest, as learners have come to take more responsibility for their learning. The Language Testing (LT) community has recently called for more research into advances in alternative assessment practices (Brookhart, 2005; Fox 2009; Harlen &amp; Winter, 2004; McNamara 2001a, 2001b; Pellegrino et al., 2001; Poehner and Lantolf 2005; Rea-Dickins 2004; Shohamy, 2004; Turner, 2009). The present research reports on an exploratory study incorporating treatment and control groups, in which assessment for learning (AFL) principles were applied in two pre-university English for academic purposes (EAP) classes. The study focussed on student learning of a grammatical feature (the use of would and will in contingent use contexts) as a vehicle for investigating AFL. The study has sought to (a) interpret AFL by developing AFL procedures appropriate to a second language (L2) classroom, (b) apply these AFL procedures in an L2 classroom setting, and (c) investigate their effect on learning, and in addition, to investigate for evidence of the assessment bridge (AB), the area of classroom practice linking assessment, teaching, and learning. An AFL methodology for L2 settings was developed for the study in the form of teacher training. The AFL pedagogical materials included computer-assisted language learning (CALL), an online individual, group and teacher-class concept mapping exercises. The data collection instruments included the concept maps produced, classroom observation field notes, transcribed group and class discourse, teacher and student survey questionnaires, and pre- and post-treatment tests to indicate trends. The data were analyzed by mixed methods and the results triangulated. The results found evidence of several instances of the AB and suggest that the application of AFL procedures may have enhanced student learning of the modal usage in question. This study reporting concludes with a call for a research agenda in the LT community for further study of applications of an AFL approach in EAP classroom settings. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans les dernières années, le recours à l'évaluation pour favoriser l'apprentissage est devenu une pratique courante dans les salles de classe. Cela a eu pour effet de créer un intérêt grandissant pour la recherche, puisque les apprenants prennent davantage leur apprentissage en main. La communauté des chercheurs en évaluation des langues a récemment demandé que plus de recherches soient faites sur les progrès dans le domaine des pratiques d'évaluation alternatives. (Brookhart, 2005; Fox 2009; Harlen &amp; Winter, 2004; McNamara 2001a, 2001b; Pellegrino et al., 2001; Poehner et Lantolf 2005; Rea-Dickins 2004; Shohamy, 2004; Turner, 2009). La présente recherche fait état d'une étude exploratoire qui incorpore des groupes expérimentaux et contrôles, dans lesquels les principes de l'évaluation pour l'apprentissage (EPA) ont été appliqués et ce, dans deux cours d'anglais pour des études au niveau préuniversitaire. L'étude s'est appuyée sur l'apprentissage par les étudiants d'un trait grammatical (l'utilisation de would et will dans un contexte hypothétique) comme véhicule pour étudier l'EPA. Cette étude a cherché à (a) interpréter l'EPA en développant des procédures d'EPA appropriées pour une classe de langue seconde, (b) appliquer ces procédures dans une classe de langue seconde, et (c) étudier leur effet sur l'apprentissage, en plus de chercher des cas de pont évaluatif (PE), cette zone de la pratique pédagogique faisant le lien entre l'évaluation, l'enseignement et l'apprentissage. Dans le cadre de cette étude, une méthodologie de l'EPA dans un contexte de langue seconde a été développée sous la forme d'une formation des enseignants et le matériel pédagogique qui a été utilisé, incluait l'enseignement assisté par ordinateur (EAO), ainsi que 3 exercices de schématisation conceptuelle: individuel en-ligne, en petits groupes et en classe avec la participation de l'enseignant. Les instruments de collecte de données incluaient les schémas conceptuels produits, les notes d'observation prises en classe, la transcription des discussions de groupe et de classe, les questionnaires de sondages menés auprès des étudiants et des enseignants, ainsi que les prétests et les post-tests afin de démontrer certaines tendances. Les données ont été analysées utilisant une méthodologie mixte et les résultats triangulés. Ces derniers ont mis en évidence plusieurs occurrences du PE et ont suggéré que l'application des procédures d'EPA aurait aidé les étudiants dans leur apprentissage de cette forme grammaticale. Ce rapport d'étude recommande donc à la communauté des chercheurs en évaluation des langues de mener des recherches plus exhaustives au sujet des applications d'une approche de l'EPA dans le domaine des cours d'anglais.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carolyn E. Turner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qr27f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r7373</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Language and Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c668r"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An empirical study of scientists' reasoning in the Canadian regulatory evaluation of traditional, homeopathic, herbal and other "natural" medicines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cuffe, Jennifer Lynn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Comment les scientifiques arrivent-ils à raisonner de façon si uniforme dans leur travail d'évaluation de l'innocuité et de l'efficacité des médicaments? Cette ethnographie du raisonnement des scientifiques est basée sur treize mois de recherches en 2006 et 2007 parmi une centaine de scientifiques au sein de la Direction des produits de santé naturels de Santé Canada. Les scientifiques qui y travaillent ont des origines et des trajectoires variées : ils sont nés dans le monde entier, se sont formés dans différentes disciplines scientifiques, pratiquent une gamme de traditions médicales en dehors de leur travail et ont des opinions diverses quant à l'utilité des médecines traditionnelles et autres médecines « naturelles ». Plusieurs scientifiques attribuent l'uniformité de leur raisonnement à l'utilisation de normes et à leur empressement à consulter leurs pairs. La thèse décrit la façon dont les scientifiques raisonnent à l'aide de normes textuelles et numériques ainsi que de consultations ciblées avec leurs collègues. Toutefois, ces activités n'expliquent pas les caractéristiques les plus frappantes du style de raisonnement des scientifiques, telles que leur « perception dirigée »; la répétition de phrases telles que « nous devons être flexibles » dans des situations de doutes; une sensibilité aiguë à l'équité; des dispositions affectives communes envers certains dossiers; un point de vue agnostique envers la relation entre normes textuelles et « réalité »; et la prise en considération du retard dans l'octroi de licences. Ces caractéristiques sont inséparables de certains outils clés du gestionnariat tels que les quotas pour le nombre d'évaluations hebdomadaires. Ce style de raisonnement a très peu, sinon rien à voir avec les « croyances » et les convictions préexistantes des scientifiques. Je soutiens que les scientifiques sont amenés à ce style de raisonnement à travers leur participation à l'organisation matérielle et sociale des activités de la Direction. La thèse s'ouvre et s'achève sur l'observation de Ludwik Fleck selon laquelle « toute théorie épistémologique est triviale si elle ne prend pas en considération la dépendance sociologique de toute connaissance de façon fondamentale et détaillée ».</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>How do one hundred scientists reason in a uniform manner during the regulatory review of proposed medicines? This ethnographic account of scientists' reasoning is based on thirteen months of anthropological fieldwork among the hundred scientists in a Canadian government directorate mandated to assess the safety and efficacy of proposed medicines while "respecting philosophical and cultural diversity." The scientists themselves cannot be considered uniform. They were born in numerous countries around the world and educated in many scientific disciplines. Many scientists were also health practitioners, in a variety of traditions. The scientists expressed a wide range of opinions about the usefulness of traditional medicines and other "natural health products." This dissertation describes the ways in which scientists reasoned in their assessment work. Many scientists attributed the uniformity in their reasoning to their use of standards and to their frequent consultation of expert peers. I argue that these activities do not account for the most striking features of scientists' uniform style of reasoning, including scientists': directed perception; repetition of phrases like "we have to be flexible" in situations of uncertainty; acute sensitivity to fairness; common affective dispositions towards certain file traits; agnostic perspective towards the relation of textual standards to "reality"; and consideration of the licensing backlog. These features were inseparable from the omnipresent tools of managerialism such as quotas for the number of evaluations to be completed weekly. Certain of these striking features appeared to be further entrenched by the temporary, rather than permanent, appointment of half the scientific staff to their positions. This uniform style of reasoning had very little, if anything, to do with scientists' pre-existing "beliefs" and convictions. I argue that scientists were interpellated into this style of reasoning (including common directed perception and affective dispositions) through participation in the material and social structuring of activities in the Directorate, even though the pre-structuring of reasoning activities was never fully determined. The dissertation begins and ends with Ludwik Fleck's observation that "every epistemological theory is trivial that does not take th[e] sociological dependence of all cognition into account in a fundamental and detailed manner" (1979:43).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Allan Young</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397d47m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c668r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Cultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524js97f"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Making a case: validating criterion-referenced guidelines for virtual patient case authoring</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Posel, Nancy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Virtual patient cases are a valuable component of medical education informatics.  The supporting literature is largely theoretical; there is a dearth of empirical research on (a) measurable outcomes and (b) components of effective virtual patient cases.  Author guidelines, based on principles of pedagogy, cognition, and identification of technically relevant specifications, do not exist.  This qualitative, multiple-case study developed and validated research-based, comprehensive, theory-grounded, and educationally relevant authoring guidelines.  Nine faculty members at six medical schools, chosen for their expertise and leadership in medical education informatics, and experience in virtual patient case authoring, provided their own criteria for case design and reviewed the criterion-referenced guidelines generated for this study.  Five of their cases were examined in relation to these guidelines.  Access to the guidelines increased the number of design criteria cited as important.  The validated guidelines can now be used to further research and development in medical education informatics and virtual patient cases.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les patients virtuels sont un volet très utile de l'informatique appliquée à l'enseignement médical.  Or, la documentation disponible est en grande partie théorique.  Il existe peu de recherche empirique sur (a) des résultats mesurables et (b) des éléments de cas efficaces de patients virtuels.  On ne trouve pas de principes directeurs de conception, basés sur des principes de pédagogie, de cognition et d'identification de spécifications intéressantes sur le plan technique.  La présente étude qualitative de cas multiples a développé et validé des principes directeurs pour la conception qui sont fondés sur la recherche et la théorie, qui englobent tous les aspects et qui sont valables sur le plan pédagogique.  Neuf membres du corps professoral de six écoles de médecine, choisis pour leur expertise et leur influence en informatique de l'enseignement médical, et leur expérience en création de cas de patients virtuels, ont proposé leurs propres critères pour la conception de cas et ont étudié les principes directeurs à référence critérielle mis au point pour cette étude.  Cinq de leurs cas ont été examinés par rapport à ces principes directeurs.  L'accès aux principes directeurs a augmenté le nombre de critères de conception cités comme étant importants.  Les principes directeurs validés peuvent désormais servir à l'avancement de la recherche et développement concernant l'informatique de l'enseignement médical et les cas de patients virtuels.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lynn Butler Kisber</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Bruce M. Shore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150p22g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524js97f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128g20n"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compulsion and control: prefrontal and mesolimbic systems in human addiction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Venugopalan, Viswanath</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: Addiction to drugs is a chronic disorder characterized by loss of control over substance use despite adverse personal consequences. Addiction can be conceived as the point where drug use is no longer under volitional control and, becomes characterized by compulsive seeking and taking. Drugs of abuse are believed to target two systems thought to be critical for adaptive behaviour, 1) a goal-oriented system relying on prefrontal cortex activity to exert control over behaviour and 2) a motivation system supported by mesocorticolimbic dopamine transmission. These systems are thought to be subverted in addiction.  Interestingly, there is a subset of long-term drug users, 'chippers', who, despite considerable exposure to drug, do not manifest the hallmark loss of control or exaggerated drive for drugs that typifies addicted users. To better understand whether prefrontal function, motivation or both distinguish 'chippers' from addicted individuals, we conducted the follwing experiments. Methods: We first examined the effects of lowering dopamine synthesis on motivation to smoke both nicotine-containing and denicotinized cigarettes in three groups of smokers: (i) low-frequency smokers who have smoked for no more than a year, (ii) low-frequency smokers who have stabilized at this level for at least 3 years, and (iii) high-frequency smokers. Next we used a neurocognitive battery testing regional aspects of prefrontal function in low- vs. high-frequency smokers while sated and following an 18 h abstinence period.  Finally we examined the effects of lowering dopamine synthesis on regional prefrontal function. Results:  1) All smokers worked for more nicotine-containing cigarettes than de-nicotinized ones. 2) High-frequency smokers worked for more nicotine-containing cigarettes compared to low-frequency smokers. 3) Lowering dopamine synthesis reduced the self-administration of nicotine-containing cigarettes in all three smoker groups and did so without influencing conscious craving or pleasure. 4) Low-frequency smokers were better than high-frequency smokers at inhibiting an on-going motor response indicated by lower stop signal reaction time, consistent with dysfunction in lateral or dorsomedial prefrontal cortex. 5) Overall, lowering dopamine synthesis did not affect executive function. However, post-hoc analyses revealed that the personality trait of novelty seeking, a hypothesized proxy for baseline dopamine function, predicted changes in executive function subsequent to lowered dopamine synthesis. Using this approach, we discovered that lowering dopamine synthesis altered attentional biases to smoking cues as measured by the smoking Stroop in a pattern consistent with an inverted 'U' relationship between dopamine and performance. Conclusion: These data suggest the following. i) Dopamine transmission is involved in the motivation to smoke nicotine-containing cigarettes, and this role persists across stages of tobacco use and addiction. ii) Response inhibition mediated by dorso-medial prefrontal cortex and right inferior frontal gyrus distinguishes low- from high-frequency smokers. This group difference might influence the ability to restrict smoking, and protect low-frequency smokers from addiction. iii) No group-wise differences in  prefrontal function were observed following  reduction of dopamine synthesis. However, post-hoc analyses revealed that the personality trait of novelty-seeking, used as a proxy for baseline dopamine reactivity, predicted the effect of reduced dopamine synthesis on a task measuring attention to smoking cues according to an inverted 'U' function. Together, these studies add to our understanding of the role of dopamine in maintaining motivation to obtain nicotine-containing cigarettes, the neurobiological differences between low- and high-frequency smokers and the role of individual differences in personality traits in predicting the effects of dopamine manipulation on task performance. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Introduction : La toxicomanie est un trouble complexe, chronique et qui revient, caractérisée par une perte de contrôle sur la consommation de drogues malgré la menace très réelle de se faire du mal. C'est le point où l'utilisation de drogues n'est plus volontaire mais caractérisée par la recherche et prise de drogues compulsives. La transition à la toxicomanie serait le résultat de changements à des circuits neuronaux induits par la drogue. Le système de la dopamine (DA) méso-cortico-limbique est impliqué dans le motivation, le renforcement et la modulation du contrôle exécutif et le cortex préfrontral (CPF) est impliqué dans le contrôle exécutif. Durant la progression à la toxicomanie, des adaptations à ces systèmes 1) érodent la capacité de résister à la prise de drogues, et 2) exagèrent la saillance encourageante de la drogue et des stimuli associés aux drogues. Ce qui est intéressant c'est que l'exposition à la drogue ne mène pas nécessairement à la toxicomanie. Un sous-ensemble de consommateurs de drogues, les « chippers », ne manifestent pas la perte de contrôle typifiant les toxicomanes. Qu'est-ce qui protège ces gens contre la toxicomanie? Ce qui est remarquable c'est que les différences neurobiologiques des circuits neuraux de la motivation et du contrôle qui distinguent les toxicomanes des chippers n'ont pas encore été étudiées de manière systématique. Méthodes : Nous avons mesuré l'effet d'une manipulation de la DA sur la motivation de fumer et le biais de l'attention vers les stimuli associés à l'action de fumer et sur les tâches qui jaugent la fonction exécutive, contrôlée par le CPF, chez (i) les fumeurs à basse fréquence qui fument depuis un maximum de un an (FBF), (ii) les fumeurs à basse fréquence qui se sont stabilisés à ce niveau pour au moins trois ans (FBFS), et (iii) les fumeurs à haute fréquence stables (FHF). Les résultats principaux sont les suivants. Résultats: 1) Baisser la synthèse de la DA a diminué la consommation de cigarettes contenant de la nicotine chez les 3 groupes de fumeurs mais n'a pas eu d'effet sur le goût conscient ou le plaisir de fumer. 2) Tous les fumeurs ont travaillé plus pour des cigarettes contenant de la nicotine que pour celles qui n'en contenaient pas. 3) Les FHF ont aussi plus travaillé pour les cigarettes avec nicotine que les FBF et FBFS. 4) Les FBF/FBFS étaient meilleurs que les FHF à une tâche consistant d'empêcher une réponse motrice en cours, jaugée par le temps de réaction suivant un signal d'arrêt, un modèle de déficience déjà observé chez les patients avec des lésions focales au CPF latéral et dorso-médial. 5) En général, la déplétion aigue de phénylalanine et tyrosine (DAPT) n'a pas eu d'effet sur la fonction exécutive (FE). Par contre, des analyses post-hoc ont démontré que la recherche de la nouveauté (RN), un index que l'on croit représenter la fonction DA de base, prédisait les changements à la FE induite par la DAPT. En utilisant cette approche, nous avons découvert qu'en accordance avec une fonction « U » inversée, la DAPT modifie les biais de l'attention vers les stimuli associés à l'action de fumer, mesurés par le Stroop de la cigarette. Conclusion: En résumé, l'inhibition de réponses contrôlées par un réseau du CPF dorso-médial/gyrus inférieur droit, distingue les chippers de tabac des FHF. Ceci peut être perçu comme étant un facteur clé contribuant à la capacité de restreindre son habitude de fumer, protégeant ainsi les chippers de tabac contre la progression à la dépendance aux drogues. Nous présentons donc de nouvelles données qui ajoutent à notre compréhension des différences neurobiologiques qui séparent les fumeurs à basse et haute fréquence, et du rôle de la DA dans le maintien de la motivation d'obtenir des cigarettes avec nicotine. Ces données pourraient être utiles pour concevoir des interventions mieux ciblées pour les fumeurs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marco Leyton</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lesley K. Fellows</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68km30d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128g20n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nj951"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Predicting language and literacy outcomes of typically-developing and at-risk English-speaking elementary students in French immersion programs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Erdos, Caroline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des études ont démontré l'efficacité des programmes d'immersion dans une langue seconde, tant pour les élèves qui se développent normalement que pour ceux qui sont désavantagés au plan académique soit à cause d'un rendement académique faible, soit en raison de l'appartenance à un milieu socio-économique défavorisé ou encore à un groupe ethnique minoritaire (voir Genesee, 2006, pour un résumé). Par contre, bien qu'il y ait une tendance à croire que la nature de la première langue (L1) ainsi que le niveau  de développement dans cette langue avant l'entrée à l'école soient  un prédicteur important du rendement académique surtout dans le domaine de la littératie, il y a peu d'études au sujet des différences individuelles notées au plan de la littératie et du langage oral dans une deuxième langue (L2) chez les élèves en immersion et surtout chez les élèves qui sont à risque de présenter des difficultés au plan de la littératie ou du langage oral (Genesee, 2006). Quatre-vingt-six (86) élèves scolarisés dans un programme d'immersion française (IF) précoce et ayant l'anglais comme langue dominante ont été évalués à trois moments distincts, soit à l'automne de la maternelle, au printemps de la maternelle et au printemps de la première année. Notre échantillon comprenait des enfants qui se développaient normalement ainsi que des enfants à risque de présenter des difficultés au plan du langage écrit ou du langage oral. Notre batterie de tests était formée d'un grand éventail d'épreuves de langage oral et de langage écrit. En accord avec la vaste littérature existant déjà au sujet de L1 (e.g. NICHD, 2000), les résultats de notre première étude ont démontré que les meilleurs prédicteurs à la maternelle pour le décodage en L2 étaient la connaissance du principe alphabétique en anglais et la conscience phonologique en anglais. Contrairement à ce que d'autres chercheurs ont trouvé (Jared, Cormier, Levy, &amp; Wade-Woolley, 2006), la connaissance du français lors de l'entrée à la maternelle est apparue comme un troisième prédicteur significatif. Les mêmes variables ont été des prédicteurs significatifs de la compréhension en lecture, avec la contribution additionnelle des scores reliés au langage oral en L1, ce qui suggérait que les habiletés de langage oral jouent un rôle important en ce qui a trait à la compréhension en lecture. De plus, nous avons pu évaluer une théorie populaire qui porte sur la lecture, la théorie 'Simple View of Reading' (Gough &amp; Tunmer, 1986). Nos résultats indiquaient que cette théorie était applicable de façon intralinguistique, mais pas de façon interlinguistique. Dans une deuxième étude, nous avons examiné le développement du langage oral et de la littératie chez des élèves se développant normalement ou à risque de présenter des difficultés au plan du langage oral ou du langage écrit. Cette étude a mis en évidence le caractère distinct des déficits notés soit au plan du langage oral, soit au plan du langage écrit, et ce, à trois niveaux. Même si les épreuves ont été administrées à un moment où les élèves n'avaient pas encore reçu d'enseignement en langage écrit, leur performance en anglais, langue maternelle, au début de la maternelle ainsi que celle observée à la fin de la maternelle étaient toutes les deux un prédicteur significatif de leur performance en première année. Toutefois, la performance à la fin de la maternelle est apparue comme un prédicteur plus précis. Globalement, nos résultats suggèrent l'existence de profils de risque distincts pour les difficultés au plan du langage écrit et pour celles notées au plan du langage oral. Ces résultats indiquent également qu'il est possible d'identifier très tôt les enfants qui ont de fortes chances d'avoir des difficultés de langage oral ou de langage écrit, et ce, même s'ils sont scolarisés dans une L2. Finalement, nos résultats suggèrent qu'il est possible de prédire le domaine spécifique qui pourrait être une source de difficulté pour ces enfants.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Many children around the world are educated in a second language, be they speakers of the majority language of the community in which they are educated or speakers of a minority language. Research has demonstrated the effectiveness of second language immersion for typically-developing students and students who are disadvantaged in the academic environment of schooling due to low levels of academic ability, disadvantaged socio-economic background, or minority ethnic group status (for a review see Genesee, 2006). In contrast, although it is generally thought that the level and kind of first language (L1) ability that children acquire prior to coming to school, and especially in domains related to literacy, are important predictors of success in school, there is little research on individual differences in second language (L2) reading and oral language development of immersion students and, in particular, on students who might be at risk for reading or oral language difficulties (Genesee, 2006). We studied 86 English-dominant children in early French Immersion (FI) programs from Fall of Kindergarten (K) to Spring of Grade 1 and tested them at three time points: Fall K, Spring K, Spring Grade 1. Our sample included both typically-developing and at-risk children and our test battery included a broad range of oral language and literacy related predictor and control measures. Consistent with extensive L1 research (e.g., NICHD, 2000), the best K predictors of L2 decoding in Study 1 were knowledge of the alphabetic principle in English and phonological awareness in English. Contrary to what others have found (Jared, Cormier, Levy, &amp; Wade-Woolley, 2006), knowledge of French at K entry was a third significant predictor. The same variables were significant predictors of French reading comprehension, with the added contribution of scores related to oral language skills in L1, suggesting that oral language abilities play an important role in reading comprehension. Furthermore, we were able to test a popular theory of reading, the Simple View of Reading (Gough &amp; Tunmer, 1986), and provided support for its intra- but not cross-linguistic applicability. Study 2 involved an investigation of both oral language and literacy outcomes of children who were either typically developing or at risk for difficulties in the area of oral language or literacy. This study provides three-pronged evidence for the distinctiveness of oral language impairment and reading impairment, namely that 1) performance on oral language predictor measures was largely independent of performance on literacy predictor measures, suggesting that each domain constitutes a distinct underlying construct; 2) the most significant predictors of oral language and of literacy difficulties were different -- that is, phonological awareness (PA), phonological recoding, and letter-sound knowledge in L1 in K were significant predictors of risk for reading difficulties in L2 while performance on L1 sentence repetition, PA, and tense marking tests in K were the best predictors of risk for L1 and L2 oral language difficulties; and 3) three distinct subgroups were found in our sample and included children with oral language difficulties, children with literacy difficulties, and children presenting with difficulties in both domains. English L1 measures taken at the earliest time point (Fall K) and at the end of that academic year (Spring K) both predicted Grade 1 outcomes to a significant extent, although the latter predictors were more accurate. Overall, our results suggest that risk for oral language and reading development are distinct; and it is possible to identify, early on, children who are likely to struggle in the domains of oral language or literacy, even if they are schooled in an L2. Our findings further suggest that it is possible to predict the specific domain that is likely to be difficult for them. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fred H. Genesee</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579x586.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj951</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Experimental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r953b"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Public diplomacy: a conceptual framework</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chahine, Joumane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La notion de "diplomatie publique" a inspiré un nombre considérable d'études critiques, aussi bien professionnelles qu'académiques, suite à sa mise en pratique particulièrement publicisée durant la "guerre contre le terrorisme" déclarée par l'administration Bush. Ces analyses, cependant, semblent s'être principalement cantonnées à des considérations empiriques et prescriptives, cherchant surtout à identifier les faiblesses et mésinterprétations qui marqueraient l'application actuelle de la "diplomatie publique", et à proposer certaines mesures correctives. Les recherches substantielles quant aux origines conceptuelles de la pratique, en revanche, ont été, d'une manière générale, rares ou du moins limitées. Cette thèse tente de remédier à cette lacune en cherchant à placer l'idée de "diplomatie publique" dans un contexte conceptuel plus étendu et approfondi. Si la diplomatie traditionnelle exprime l'effort d'un état pour rallier à sa cause un ou plusieurs autres états, la "diplomatie publique", elle, consiste pour un état à faire passer son point de vue, non parmi ses homologues sur la scène internationale, mais au sein de la population de ces derniers. Bien que l'essence de la pratique ne soit pas nécessairement récente, l'appellation "diplomatie publique" (qui manque à ce jour d'équivalent exact en français) est relativement jeune, ayant fait son entrée dans le lexique de la politique internationale aux Etats-Unis dans les années soixante, en pleine Guerre Froide. L'objectif principal de cette thèse est de démontrer que la "diplomatie publique," comme forme singulièrement contemporaine de communication entre un gouvernement et un public étranger, est le produit distinct du développement et des entrecroisements de plusieurs concepts fondamentaux de la pensée politique et sociale. Afin de justifier cette proposition, nous identifierons trois concepts essentiels à l'idée de "diplomatie publique" –l'opinion publique, la société civile, et "l'âge de l'information"-- et soumettrons chacune de ses notions à une étude généalogique détaillée. Au fur et à mesure que la thèse avancera, ces différents cheminements conceptuels seront corrélés, leurs points de convergence mis en évidence, de manière à progressivement situer la genèse de la "diplomatie publique" à l'intersection de leurs trajectoires. S'appuyant sur ces observations, la conclusion ouvrira un nouveau champ de réflexion en examinant leurs retombées possibles sur le futur de la pratique.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Since its much publicized deployment in the wake of the September 11th attacks and during the subsequent so-called "War on Terror," public diplomacy has generated a substantial body of critical discourse emanating from both the professional and academic spheres. These analyses, however, have been for the most part empirical studies, aimed at strengthening the efficiency of the practice by identifying potential flaws or weaknesses in its current conception or application and offering possible correctives. Significant enquiries into the conceptual origins and evolution of the practice, on the other hand, have generally been rare and limited. This thesis proposes to remedy, in part, this lack by situating public diplomacy within a broader and deeper conceptual context.  The term "public diplomacy" only entered the lexicon of political and international affairs in the Cold War environment of the mid-1960s. It could however be argued that the essence of the practice –government communication with foreign publics— is as old as history itself. The primary purpose of this dissertation is to argue that public diplomacy, as the specific form taken by the practice of government communication with a foreign audience in the latter half of the twentieth century, is a distinctive product of the development and ultimate intersection of several discrete though somehow connected concepts in social and political thought. We shall seek to substantiate this claim by identifying three fundamental concepts that lie at the heart of the idea of public diplomacy –public opinion, civil society and the information age-- and charting their historical trajectory and various points of interaction. The main body of the dissertation will therefore be divided into three genealogical chapters, one for each of the elected concepts cited above. Throughout, and increasingly as the thesis progresses, these various evolutional paths will be correlated, their points of convergence highlighted, so as to gradually situate the birth of public diplomacy at the intersection of their trajectories. The conclusion will offer further reflections on the continued influence of this collection of notions on the more recent development of public diplomacy, and the implications these might entail for its future.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>William O. Straw</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214t37f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r953b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hd97z"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Participation in recreational activities in school age children with high functioning autism and their peers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Potvin, Marie-Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The patterns of recreational engagement and health related quality of life (HRQL) of school-aged children with High Functioning Autism (HFA) are not well understood. The objectives of this study of children with HFA and their typically developing peers were to: compare their recreational profiles; identify child-based factors related to recreational participation; and, estimate their HRQL in relation to recreational engagement. Additionally, the psychometric properties of the Children's Assessment of Participation and Enjoyment/ Preference for Activities of Children (CAPE/PAC) for this population were estimated. A cross sectional study of a volunteer sample of children with HFA (n=30) and peers (n=31) recruited through multiple Vermont sources was conducted. Data collection took place during 2-3 home visits. Standardized and psychometrically sound tools were used to independently confirm diagnosis and ascertain children's characteristics. The CAPE/PAC and Pediatric Quality of Life 4.0 were the primary outcome measures. The groups were similar on key characteristics except those related to the HFA attributes. Children with HFA differed from peers in terms of diversity (p=.002), social aspects (p=.006) and locations (p&lt;.001) of recreational participation. The two groups were not statistically different in personal intensity (p=.684), enjoyment (p=.239) or preferences (p=.788) of recreation. Children with HFA had significantly poorer HRQL whether reported by themselves (p&lt;.001) or their parents (p&lt;.001), although disagreement (ICC=-.075) between children and parental scores suggested that they had different viewpoints about children's HRQL. The study results have value for parents, clinicians, teachers and administrators in understanding and supporting the recreational engagement of children with HFA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Nous avons une compréhension limitée des habitudes de loisir et de la qualité de vie liées à la santé (QVLS) des enfants d'âge scolaire ayant un trouble envahissant du développement (TED) de haut niveau. Cette étude avait pour objectifs: de comparer les habitudes de loisir; d'identifier des facteurs chez l'enfant qui sont associés aux habitudes de loisir; et, d'estimer la QVLS et la relation de celle-ci avec les habitudes de loisir des enfants ayant un TED de haut niveau et de leurs pairs présentant un développement typique. De plus, la validité et la fiabilité du Children's Assessment of Participation and Enjoyment/ Preference for Activities of Children (CAPE/PAC) chez les enfants ayant un TED de haut niveau furent estimées. Au Vermont, un échantillonnage volontaire d'enfants ayant un TED de haut niveau (n=30) et de leurs pairs (n=31) a été établi à partir de diverses sources afin de procéder à cette étude transversale. La collecte de données s'est faite lors de 2 ou 3 visites. Des outils d'évaluation standardisés, valides et fiables furent utilisés pour confirmer les critères d'inclusion. Le CAPE/PAC et le Paediatric Quality of Life 4.0 étaient les deux outils d'évaluation des principaux concepts étudiés. Les participants dans les deux groupes présentaient des caractéristiques similaires sauf celles reliées au diagnostic de TED. Les enfants ayant un TED de haut niveau participaient dans un nombre plus restreint d'activités de loisir (p=.002), avec un nombre plus limité d'autres personnes (p=.006) et généralement plus près de chez eux (p&lt;.001). Cependant, les deux groupes n'étaient pas statistiquement différents en ce qui a trait à la fréquence de participation moyenne dans les activités de loisir (p=.684), leur plaisir à participer à ces activités (p=.239) ou leur désir d'y participer (p=.788). Les enfants ainsi que leurs parents (p&lt;.001) jugeaient que les enfants ayant un TED de haut niveau avaient une QVLS significativement moindre que leurs pairs. Malgré ce fait, l'accord entre la QVLS jugé par les enfants et leurs parents étaient presqu'absent (ICC=-.075) indiquant qu'ils évaluaient des aspects différents de la qualité de vie. Les résultats de cette étude pourront aider les parents, les cliniciens, les enseignants et les administrateurs à comprendre les habitudes de loisir des enfants ayant un TED et leur permettront de mieux soutenir les enfants dans cette participation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurie M. Snider</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cz447.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hd97z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Occupational Health and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aks65hh46s"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parent support groups: impact on parental adjustment and perceptions of children's behaviour difficulties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Madden, Lisa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les parents d'enfants présentant des problèmes de comportement vivent un stress important pouvant affecter leur santé mentale et influencer leurs pratiques parentales, leurs perceptions de leur enfant, leur relation avec leur enfant, et les comportements de leur enfant.  La présence de support social est un facteur à considérer en ce qui a trait au stress et à la capacité d'ajustement, et l'offre de  groupes de support peut être une façon efficace d'offrir un support social aux parents.  L'objectif des groupes de support pour parents est généralement d'améliorer le fonctionnement et la capacité d'ajustement des parents, et ainsi contribuer au développement de l'enfant et au fonctionnement de la famille entière.  Des recherches antérieures ont observé des résultats positifs chez les parents suite à leur participation à un groupe de support.  Certains des effets obtenus peuvent être particulièrement importants pour les parents d'enfants présentant des problèmes de comportement, notamment une diminution du stress et une amélioration de l'adaptation, des capacités d'ajustement, et de la perception des comportements de l'enfant.  Toutefois, la littérature portant sur l'efficacité des groupes de support pour parents, en particulier les groupes pour parents d'enfants présentant des problèmes de comportement, est extrêmement limitée et caractérisée par d'importantes faiblesses méthodologiques.  Le but de la présente étude était d'examiner l'impact de la participation à un groupe de support sur l'adaptation et les perceptions de parents d'enfants présentant des problèmes de comportement, tout en considérant et corrigeant certaines limites méthodologiques présentes dans littérature.  Spécifiquement, les variables dépendantes incluent étaient le stress parental, la symptomatologie dépressive, le sentiment d'isolement, le sentiment de compétence, la satisfaction parentale, ainsi que la perception des comportements de l'enfant.  Les participants étaient 35 parents ayant au moins un enfant présentant des problèmes de comportement. Vingt-deux parents ont participé au groupe d'intervention et 13 parents ont participé au groupe contrôle.  Un schème pretest posttest avec groupe contrôle, ainsi que des mesures validées et standardisées, ont été utilisés.  Les scores pretest ont servi de variables contrôles lors des analyses statistiques.  Les résultats ont démontré que la participation au groupe de support, comparativement au groupe contrôle, était associée à une diminution du stress parental, à une augmentation du sentiment de compétence parental, et à des perceptions plus positives des problèmes de comportement chez l'enfant.  Les parents ont également rapporté des niveaux très élevés de satisfaction suite à leur participation au groupe de support.  Les implications théoriques et cliniques sont discutées, et des avenues de recherche futures sont proposées.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Parents of children with behaviour problems experience significant stress that may affect their mental health, and may influence their parenting skills, their perceptions of their children, their relationship with their children, and their children's behaviour.  Social support is an important factor in the context of stress and coping, and support groups may be an effective way of providing social support to parents.  The overall goal of parent support groups is to improve parent adjustment and coping, thereby enhancing child development and improving family functioning as a whole.  Support group participation has been associated with a number of positive outcomes for parents, including outcomes particularly important for parents of children with behaviour problems, such as reductions in stress and improvements in adjustment, coping, and perceptions of children's behaviours.  However, the efficacy research on parent support groups, and in particular on support groups for parents of children with behaviour problems, is extremely limited and fraught with methodological weaknesses.  The purpose of the present study was to examine the impact of support group participation on parental adjustment and perceptions for parents of children with behaviour problems, while addressing some of the methodological limitations that presently exist in the parent support group literature.  Specifically, outcome variables included parenting stress, depressive symptomatology, feelings of isolation, sense of competence and satisfaction in the parenting role, as well as parents' perceptions of their children's problem behaviours.  Participants included thirty five parents who had at least one child between the ages of four and twelve with behaviour problems.  Twenty-two parents participated in the intervention group and thirteen parents participated in the control group.  A pretest posttest control group design and standardized, well-validated measures were used.  Pretest scores were controlled for in the statistical analyses.  Results indicated that support group participation was associated with decreased parenting stress, increased sense of parenting competence, and more favourable perceptions of children's behaviour problems relative to control group parents.  Parents also reported very high satisfaction with the group experience.  Theoretical and clinical implications are discussed and future directions for research are suggested. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ingrid Sladeczek</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537531t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hh46s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zz300"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Common good and the concept of expropriation in international law on foreign investment: Determinacy of substance in legitimacy of structure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Falsafi, Alireza</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse, en explorant l'état de droit pour les règles internationales, présente un lien de la déterminabilité de la substance et la légitimité de la structure des règles en vue de bien commun des êtres humains afin d'évaluer les obligations internationales des États en droit international concernant les investissements étrangers. Dans un exposé profond des fondements théoriques et des pratiques qui sous-tendent la structure normative des règles internationales, cette thèse conteste le raisonnement  juridique et l'autorité des règles qui sont fondés sur principes et les precedents, ou des évaluations morales et politiques par les arbitres, dans l'interprétation des obligations contractuelles, conventionnelles, et coutumières des États en arbitrages d'investissement. Étant donné les ramifications morales, politiques, sociales et économiques pour les fonctions constitutionnelles des Etats et leurs peuples impliquées dans la notion d'expropriation en droit international, cette thèse  fournit un cadre de légitimité dans une approche de bien commun avec les critères structurels de la reconnaissance et la cohérence pour l'interprétation des obligations des États en arbitrages entre les États et d'investissement les investisseur étrangers. La cohérence concerne des exigences de la justice pour une évaluation nouvelle d'une règle générale, et la reconnaissance concerne la validation de le pouvoir pour exercer une évaluation morale et politique. Ces critères structurels offrent une approche de la légitimité en vue de bien commun pour tester l'autorité des obligations des États et le pouvoir des arbitres dans les cas difficiles. Avec ces critères la thèse caractérise la nature des droits de propriété des entreprises et des obligations correspondantes des Etats dans le domaine d'investissement étranger comme contingente et consensuelle distingué de droits absolus et constitutionnel des êtres humains dans le domaine de droits de l'homme. Grâce à la cohérence et la reconnaissance, la thèse décrit aussi un statut suprême du droit international coutumier pour la structure et substance normative des obligations des États dans l'interprétation des cas difficiles dans le droit international concernant les investissements étrangers. La thèse adopte un nouvel horizon qui rejette la prétention de lex lata pour les propositions de lex ferenda fabriqués par des précédents et des principles, d'un côté, et la prétention de loi pour la conception de la justice des arbitres en arbitrages d'investissement, de l'autre côté, dans l'interprétation des cas difficiles de la  confrontation entre les exigences de la justice.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis, exploring the rule of law for international rules, offers a human bond of common good between determinacy of substance and legitimacy of structure of rules in order to evaluate international obligations of States in international law on foreign investment. In an in-depth exposition of the theoretical underpinnings and practices underlying the normative structure of rules in international law, the thesis critically questions the legal reasoning embedded in—and the authority of rules borrowed from—principles and precedents or  moral and political evaluations by arbitrators in interpretation of States' contractual, customary, and treaty obligations in investment arbitrations. With crucial moral, political, social and economic ramifications for the constitutional functions of States and concomitant interests of their human members implicated in the concept of expropriation in international law, the thesis provides a framework of legitimacy in a common good approach with structural criteria of recognition and coherence for the interpretation of States' obligations in investment arbitration. Coherence brings to the fore conflicting demands of justice requiring fresh evaluation divesting a general rule of its authoritative force, and recognition brings to the fore the validation of the power to engage in moral and political evaluation. Together, these structural criteria offer a common good approach of legitimacy to test the authority of States' obligations and the power of arbitrators in hard cases. By virtue of these criteria, the thesis characterizes the nature of substantive property rights of corporations and corresponding obligations of States in foreign investment as contingent and consensual in contrast with the absolute and constitutional rights of human beings in human rights. Through coherence and recognition, the thesis also portrays a supreme status for customary international law for the normative structure and substance of States' contractual or treaty obligations in the interpretation of hard cases in international law on foreign investment. The thesis espouses a new horizon for legal reasoning in foreign investment arbitration that eschews the lex lata veneer for lex ferenda propositions manufactured from precedents and principles, on the one hand, and the sheen of law for the conception of justice of investor-State arbitrators, on the other, in cases of hard confrontation between the demands of justice. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Armand De Mestral</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9677750.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zz300</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c473f"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Visual filtering in children with fetal alcohol spectrum disorder</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lane, Kimberly Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'ensemble des troubles causés par l'alcoolisation foetale (ETCAF) fait référence à un éventail d'effets résultant de l'exposition prénatale à l'alcool (EPA).  Les problèmes d'attention sont considérés communs chez les enfants avec une EPA.  Dans cette étude, le filtrage visuel a été examiné chez les enfants atteints de l'ETCAF avec une tâche expérimentale conçue pour mesurer l'efficacité de filtrage et des sous-tests cliniques.  À la tâche expérimentale, les participants ont répondu aux flèches présentées de manière centralisée tout en ignorant les stimuli de distraction (SD) apparaissant parfois à gauche ou à droite de la cible.  Ces SD étaient conciliables ou inconciliables avec la cible. Les exigences attentionnelles de la tâche ont été manipulées dans cette étude, car une augmentation de la demande attentionnelle diminuait les différences de développement dans le filtrage, selon des études antérieures.  Un contrôle cognitif immature, étant une explication potentielle pour le filtrage inefficace, a aussi été exploré chez les enfants atteints de l'ETCAF.  Les questions méthodologiques de niveaux différents d'EPA et de développement de niveau inférieur ont été examinées.  Les 14 enfants atteints de l'ETCAF ont été diagnostiqués selon les lignes directrices canadiennes concernant le diagnostic (Chudley et coll., 2005) et correspondant à l'âge mental avec des enfants ayant un développement typique (DT).  Le groupe d'enfants atteints de l'ETCAF démontre des symptômes de comportements THADA, mais ne démontre pas de difficultés de filtrage visuel en général.  Les conclusions préliminaires suggèrent que les difficultés de filtrage peuvent être évidentes chez les enfants atteints de l'ETCAF plus tard dans leur développement.  Une augmentation dans les exigences de la tâche et de la distance des SD semblait être utile.  Les enfants atteints de l'ETCAF ont démontré des difficultés avec le contrôle cognitif, spécialement avec la commutation de l'attention et la mémoire de travail.  Le temps de réaction (TR) aux écrans avec la cible était beaucoup plus lent que ceux présentés dans un bloc d'essais avec et sans SD.  Le TR à ces écrans était semblable au TR aux écrans avec SD inconciliables.  Ces conclusions peuvent refléter un déficit dans les mécanismes de contrôle cognitif.  La possibilité que des informations visuelles inattendues soient particulièrement dérangeantes pour les enfants atteints de l'ETCAF est également discutée.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Fetal alcohol spectrum disorder (FASD) refers to a spectrum of effects resulting from prenatal exposure to alcohol (PEA).  Attention problems are considered common among children with PEA.  In this study, a specific aspect of visual attending, filtering, was examined among children with FASD with both an experimental flanker task and clinical subtests.  On the flanker task, the participants responded to centrally presented arrows while ignoring distracter arrows that sometimes appeared to the left and right of the target.  These distracters were either congruent or incongruent with the target.  The attentional demands of the task were manipulated in this study, as an increase in attentional demand decreased developmental differences in filtering efficiency in previous studies.  Immature cognitive control, as a potential explanation for inefficient filtering, was also explored among children with FASD.  The methodological issues of differing levels of prenatal alcohol exposure and lower developmental level were considered.  The 14 children with FASD were diagnosed with an alcohol-related disorder based on the Canadian Diagnostic Guidelines (Chudley et al., 2005), and matched on mental age, as assessed with the Leiter International Performance Scale – Revised, with typically developing (TD) children.  The group of children with FASD displayed behavioural symptoms of attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder, but did not demonstrate visual filtering difficulties in general.  The findings suggest that difficulties in filtering may be evident for children with FASD later in development.  An increase in both the attentional demands of the task and the flanker distance appeared to be helpful.  The children with FASD demonstrated difficulties with cognitive control, specifically with attention switching and working memory.  They demonstrated a larger increase in reaction time (RT) to target-only displays when they were presented within a block of trials with flanker and no-flanker displays.  The RT to these target-only displays was similar to the RT to incongruent distracter displays.  These findings support cognitive control deficits.  The possibility that unexpected visual displays are particularly disruptive for children with FASD is also discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacob A. Burack</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278z568.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c473f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Developmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bn59h"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Information Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Information ethics: an applied study of United States foreign intelligence surveillance under President George W. Bush</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Atkin, Michelle Louise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation examines the philosophical foundations of information ethics and their potential for application to contemporary problems in U.S. foreign intelligence surveillance. Questions concerning the limits of government intrusion on protected Fourth Amendment rights are addressed by analyzing the post-9/11 changes to the U.S. foreign intelligence surveillance law and policy in terms of the traditional ethical theories commonly used to support or discount these changes, namely utilitarian and contractarian ethical theories.  This research combines both theoretical elements, through its use of analytic philosophy, and qualitative research methods, through its use of legislation, court cases, news media, and scholarship surrounding U.S. foreign intelligence surveillance.   Using the U.S.A. PATRIOT Act, the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) and the Terrorist Surveillance Program as case examples, the author develops and applies a normative ethical framework based on a legal proportionality test that can be applied to future cases involving U.S. foreign intelligence surveillance.  The proportionality test developed in this research, which is based on a modified version of the Canadian Oakes Test, seeks to balance legitimate concerns about collective security against the rights of the individual.  As a new synthesis of utilitarian and contractarian ethical principles, the proportionality test laid out in this dissertation has potential for application beyond U.S. foreign intelligence surveillance.  It could act as a guide to future research in other applied areas in information policy research where there is a clear tension between individual civil liberties and the collective good of society.  Problems such as passenger screening, racial and ethnic profiling, data mining, and access to information could be examined using the framework developed in this study.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse  porte sur les fondements philosophiques de l'éthique de l'information et sur leur potentiel d'application aux problèmes contemporains en matière de surveillance du renseignement étranger aux États-Unis. On aborde des questions relatives aux limites de l'intrusion du gouvernement sur les droits protégés par le quatrième amendement en analysant les changements post-9/11 aux lois et aux politiques en matière de surveillance du renseignement étranger en termes de théories éthiques traditionnelles couramment utilisées pour discuter de ces changements, à savoir l'utilitarianisme et les théories de contractualisme. Cette étude combine à la fois des éléments théoriques, par son utilisation de la philosophie analytique, et les méthodes de recherche qualitative, à travers son utilisation de la législation, la jurisprudence, les médias et les recherches au sujet de la surveillance du renseignement étranger.  Utilisant comme exemples la U.S.A.  PATRIOT Act, la Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) et le Programme de surveillance des terroristes, l'auteur élabore et applique un cadre d'éthique normative fondé sur un test de proportionnalité, un cadre que l'on peut appliquer à d'autres cas impliquant la surveillance du renseignement étranger. Le test de proportionnalité développé dans cette recherche, qui est basé sur une version modifiée du célèbre Oakes test de la Cour suprême du Canada, cherche à contrebalancer les préoccupations légitimes concernant la sécurité collective et les droits individuels. Comme synthèse des principes utilitairistes et contractualistes, le test de proportionnalité énoncé dans la présente thèse a un potentiel d'application au-delà de la surveillance du renseignement étranger aux États-Unis. Il pourrait servir de guide pour des recherches dans d'autres domaines appliqués où il y a une tension évidente entre les libertés individuelles et le bien collectif de la société. Des problèmes tels que le contrôle des passagers, le profilage racial et ethnique, l'exploration de données, et l'accès à l'information pourrait être examiné en utilisant le cadre élaboré dans cette étude.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>J. Andrew Large</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p26770823.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bn59h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Information Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>