<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290b031"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High-level control of singing voice timbre transformations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thibault, François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The sustained increase in computing performance over the last  decades has brought enough computing power to perform significant audio processing  in affordable personal computers. Following this revolution, we have witnessed a  series of improvements in sound transformation techniques and the introduction of  numerous digital audio effects to modify effectively the time, pitch, and loudness  dimensions of audio signals. Due to the complex and multi-dimensional nature of  timbre however, it is significantly more difficult to achieve meaningful and  convincing qualitative transformations. The tools currently available for timbre  modifications (e.g. equalizers) do not operate along perceptually meaningful axes of  singing voice timbre (e.g. breathiness, roughness, etc.) resulting in a  transformation control problem. One of the goals of this work is to examine more  intuitive procedures to achieve high-fidelity qualitative transformations explicitly  controlling certain dimensions of singing voice timbre. Quantitative measurements  (i.e. voice timbre descriptors) are introduced and used as high-level controls in an  adaptive processing system dependent on the characteristics observed in the input  signal. The transformation methods use a harmonic plus noise  representation from which voice timbre descriptors are derived. This higher-level  representation, closer to our perception of voice timbre, offers more intuitive  controls over timbre transformations. The topics of parametric voice modeling and  timbre descriptor computation are first introduced, followed by a study of the  acoustical impacts of voice breathiness variations. A timbre transformation system  operating specifically on the singing voice quality is then introduced with  accompanying software implementations, including an example digital audio effect for  the control and modification of the breathiness quality on normal  voices.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg96x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b031</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music -- Acoustics and physics -- Data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tone color (Music)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer sound processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sound -- Recording and reproducing -- Digital techniques</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612p16p"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Philosophy of religion as hermeneutics of contemplation according to Dewi Z. Phillips</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Siwiec, John Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dewi Z. Phillips maintains that philosophy must have a  contemplative character. Applied to religion, it takes the form of a hermeneutics of  contemplation that emphasizes the role concepts play in human life. While some  philosophers try to bring philosophy to bear on to religion, others try to bring  religion to bear on to philosophy; seeing their task as being for or against  religion. According to Phillips, both these views are confused. Instead, the  philosophy of religion must strive to understand religion on its own terms: showing  that a sensibility should be possible that does justice to both belief and atheism.  In order to appreciate Phillips' philosophy of religion, it is essential to  recognize the three authors that have contributed to his thinking: Ludwig  Wittgenstein, Soren Kierkegaard, and Simone Weil. From Wittgenstein, Phillips learns  the philosophical method, Kierkegaard teaches Phillips what it means to be a  religious author, and Simone Weil imparts Phillips with an authentic sense of  religious belief and understanding. Throughout his career Phillips has been poorly  understood because he refuses to be pinned down to the categories and frameworks  within which philosophers of religion and theologians traditionally define  themselves. For Phillips, a contemplative conception of the philosophy of religion  endeavours to show just how far philosophy can bring one in a religious dimension:  trying to enable a person to be conceptually clear about the matters at hand and to  realize when a personal judgment must be made.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fm06f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p16p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Religion -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phillips, D. Z. (Dewi Zephaniah)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nm05f"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The nature of community in the Newfoundland rock underground</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guy, Stephen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Twenty-five years of independent, underground, or punk rock  music-making in St. John's, Newfoundland, have been defined by geographic isolation.  In tracing a historical record of the small city's punk/indie scene, this project  seeks to evaluate recent academic discussion surrounding the role of collectivity in  artistic 'independence' and examine the impact of prevailing international  aesthetics and changing communication technologies on local practice. The  self-containment and self-sufficiency of the St. John's music community, largely the  product of the city's isolated position on the extreme eastern tip of a large island  off the east coast of North America, provide a unique backdrop against which to  foreground a discussion of the distance between indie/punk rhetoric and reality. I  contend that 'scene' in popular and academic use refers to the casual aggregation  occasioned by similar interest and shared location, while 'community' hints at  effort, co-operation and productive support.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc57g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm05f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Punk rock music -- Newfoundland -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Music -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alternative rock music -- Newfoundland -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alternative rock musicians -- Newfoundland</dc:subject><dc:subject>Punk rock musicians -- Newfoundland</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w286c"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Between conflict and accommodation : PLO strategies toward Israel 1991-2000</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hamdy, Karim, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the initiation and dynamics of  accommodation in protracted conflicts in the developing world characterized by  important stakes and major asymmetries. The case study is the Palestinian-Israeli  conflict and in particular Palestinian strategy from 1991--2000. This thesis argues  that external politico-military concerns are the main explanatory factors affecting  the pursuit of accommodation in this type of case. Powerful third parties play a  significant role in initiating/mediating processes of accommodation and in providing  assurances/incentives to encourage its pursuit. Bilateral conditions, especially  perceptions of irreversible decline by the weaker party and solid expectations of  reciprocity from its opponent, are the key factors in generating meaningful  accommodative moves. Difficult economic conditions serve as an additional spur for  the pursuit of accommodation while difficult political conditions act as a  constraint. However, established leaders with strong nationalist credentials have  greater room for manoeuvre on foreign policy issues.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719m968.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w286c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Arab-Israeli conflict</dc:subject><dc:subject>Munaẓẓamat al-Taḥrīr al-Filasṭīnīyah</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88ch07g"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Religion and science in the philosophy of David Ray Griffin : a process approach to integration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blakeslee, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>David Ray Griffin claims that the commonly perceived conflict  between religion and science, or between religious and scientific assertions is  primarily that of worldview, or philosophical stance. Science is predominantly  associated with the philosophy of materialistic naturalism, whereas religion is  predominantly associated with supernaturalism. Griffin believes that the conflict  between these worldviews can be overcome by a mutual modification based upon the  tenets of process philosophy, thus allowing for one integrated worldview. In science  this modification involves the adoption of a minimal as opposed to a maximal form of  naturalism. In religion, this modification involves the adoption of naturalistic as  opposed to supernaturalistic theism. Griffin argues that each respective domain  would be more coherent and fruitful if these modifications were to be made. This  study examines the details of this argument, and considers whether Griffin's process  offering is religiously and scientifically compelling, or whether it is simply  potentially philosophically satisfying.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f1749.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch07g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Griffin, David Ray, 1939-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion and science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s078r"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Attitudes d'enfants allophones et de leurs enseignants envers différens accents du français</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaudoin, Sophie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following thesis reports on an investigation of the  attitudes of allophone children and their teachers towards different French accents.  Using the matched guise technique, a total of 108 children in grades 4, 5 and 6 (5  groups) evaluated samples of French spoken with a standard accent, a standard Quebec  accent, an informal Quebec accent and a foreign accent. The pupils evaluated the  accents based on eight criteria related to linguistic, professional and personal  characteristics. Secondly, sub-groups from each class participated in a  post-experimental discussion about the accents they had heard. The children's  teachers were also interviewed privately, in order to give their opinions about the  accents, and share their vision of an oral model for these allophone children  attending French language schools in Montreal. Findings suggest a strong preference  for standard accents, which is confirmed by the analysis of the post-experimental  discussions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv754.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s078r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French language -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Variation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m4730"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of ethnic identity on nursing home placement among Polish older adults</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kromer, Anna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An exploratory, qualitative study on the experiences of Polish  older adults who made a transition from independent living to an ethno-specific  residential care facility in Toronto is presented. Using the framework of Continuity  Theory of Aging, the impact of ethnic/cultural identity on the process of relocation  and subsequent adjustment to a nursing home environment was investigated. A  purposive sampling strategy was used to select 2 male and 4 female participants. The  data was collected using long interviews that were tape recorded and transcribed  verbatim. The findings of this study indicate that the subjects employed specific  coping strategies that stem from traditional value orientation and life experiences  hence suggesting that ethnic/cultural identity may have played a role in their  successful adaptation to residential care setting. Although this research study is  limited to one group of older adults and cannot be generalized to other ethnic  groups, it has a potential to contribute to increasing the body of knowledge about  the dynamics of residential care placement among ethnic minority seniors.  Implications for social work policy, research and practice are  discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935358m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m4730</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Polish Canadians -- Ontario -- Toronto</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older people -- Nursing home care -- Ontario -- Toronto</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418n82k"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Critical analysis of the resurgence of attachment theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Piano, Linda Maria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Over the past few years, attachment theory has taken on  increased significance in academic and professional discourse, particularly in the  field of child welfare. While this appears to be a relatively new area of interest  in social work, the history of attachment theory dates back over five decades. This  thesis aims to identify some of the reasons behind the resurgence of attachment  theory, in particular, in child welfare practice. This renewed interest in  attachment theory is tied to the current social climate and context for social work  practice. This context, it is argued, contributes to the tendency for attachment  theory to become a tool of social control. The thesis concludes by exploring how  attachment theory might be used instead as a means to empower families in  relationship-based social work.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj66n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418n82k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Child welfare</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attachment behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attachment behavior in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741s35n"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Dentistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparison of psychosocial outcomes in head and neck cancer patients receiving a coping strategies intervention and control subjects receiving no intervention</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vilela, Larissa Durão Duarte</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Objective. To compare psychosocial outcomes in head and neck  (H&amp;N) cancer patients receiving the Nucare program with a group of matched  control subjects who received no intervention. Methods. A prospective, non-randomized study design was used.  Subjects were H&amp;N cancer patients. The Nucare program, a psycho-educational  coping strategies intervention, was the test intervention. Control subjects were  matched to test subjects by disease stage and time since cancer therapy. Outcomes  were quality of life (QL) and depressive symptoms (DS) evaluated at baseline and 3-4  months later. Results. 138 subjects were recruited and outcome data was  available on 101. At outcome evaluation, compared to their baseline scores, the test  group had improved physical and social functioning, global QL, fatigue, sleep  disturbance and DS, while the control group showed no changes in QL or  DS. Conclusion. The results suggest the Nucare may improve QL and  reduce DS in H&amp;N cancer patients.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773w223.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s35n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Social</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag732d958w"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Recoil effect of the ice hockey stick during a slap shot</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Villaseñor-Herrera, Alejandro</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examined the 'recoil' effect of the ice hockey stick  shaft during a stationary slap shot. Nine subjects were tested. Four were classified  as 'elite' and the remaining five as the 'recreational' group. Their performances  were evaluated by simultaneously recording stick movement and bending from  high-speed video capture (1000 Hz) and puck acceleration from a triaxial  accelerometer positioned inside the puck. Data were analyzed with a one-way ANOVA  for several dependant variables including final puck velocity, stick shaft bending,  blade-puck contact time and stick kinetic energy. The results indicated that: (1)  the puck velocity was influenced by skill level, blade-puck contact time and stick  bending energy but not puck acceleration. Further studies are needed to address the  influence of events before and after blade-puck contact as well as the strength of  the player on the mechanical energy and impulse given to the puck.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s0791.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d958w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hockey -- Equipment and supplies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vr50r"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Polymorphisms in the major histocompatibility complex and cervical human papillomavirus infection in a cohort of Montreal university students</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robinson, Keira</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Only a minority of women with a human papillomavirus (HPV)  infection eventually develop cervical cancer. This suggests a role for immune  mechanisms in viral acquisition and clearance, most notably presentation of HPV  antigens as mediated by gene products of the human leukocyte antigen (HLA)  complex. A longitudinal cohort investigation of cervical HPV infections  was utilized to examine the role of selected HLA class I and II alleles in  determining risk of HPV positivity and persistence for students attending McGill and  Concordia universities in Montreal. HPV positivity was measured at baseline and then  once every six months for a period of two years. Five hundred and fifty-nine women  were identified for analysis. Five HLA alleles: B*07, DQB1*03, DQB1*0602, DRB1*13,  and DRB1*1501 were typed using DNA extracted from cervical specimens sampled at  enrollment. In multivariate logistic regression analyses DRB1*13 (odds ratio  [OR]: 2.0; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 1.0-4.0) and DRB1*1501 (OR: 2.1; CI:  1.1-4.1) were associated with HPV 16 positivity. Women with DRB1*13 were also more  likely to be positive for high-risk (HR) HPV infections (OR: 1.7; CI: 1.0-2.9), or H  PV infection of any type (OR: 1.7; CI: 1.0-2.8). Most associations became stronger  in the subset of women restricted on the basis of high likelihood to prior HPV  exposure. These results support the hypothesis that certain HLA class II  polymorphisms mediate genetic susceptibility to HPV infection in young  women.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2362581.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vr50r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vr511"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>BIAS : bioinformatics integrated application software and discovering relationships between transcription factors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rajabi, Zeyad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the first part of this thesis, we present a new development  platform especially tailored to Bioinformatics research and software development  called Bias (Bioinformatics Integrated Application Software) designed to provide the  tools necessary for carrying out integrative Bioinformatics research. Bias follows  an object-relational strategy for providing persistent objects, allows third-party  tools to be easily incorporated within the system, and it supports standards and  data-exchange protocols common to Bioinformatics. The second part of this thesis is  on the design and implementation of modules and libraries within Bias related to  transcription factors. We present a module in Bias that focuses on discovering  competitive relationships between mouse and yeast transcription factors. By  competitive relationships we mean the competitive binding of two transcription  factors for a given binding site. We also present a method that divides a  transcription factor's set of binding sites into two or more different sets when  constructing PSSMs.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t915t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vr511</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Biostatistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b183h"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of geriatric trauma care in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Longo, Nadia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this prospective cohort study was to describe the  profile and outcomes of geriatric trauma care patients treated in level I trauma  centers in Quebec. The study also evaluated the quality of care provided to  geriatric trauma patients and identified predictors of outcomes which focused on  mortality. A total of 4934 trauma patients over the age of 65 were admitted  for the treatment of injuries in three level I trauma centers in Quebec. The  majority of the patients were injured in falls and had a low injury severity score.  Male gender, older age, thoracic and abdominal injuries, burns, and delayed  emergency room stays were identified as significant predictors of mortality.  Inferior quality of care was observed with increased age and fall-related  injuries. The observed association between longer emergency room stay and  falls with increased risk of mortality along with inferior care for patients injured  in falls would suggest that level I trauma centers are inefficient and potentially  harmful in treating elderly trauma patients. Further studies would be helpful in  confirming these conclusions.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz273.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b183h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gerontology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mv76d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploration and extensions of detail maps</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mathur, Moses</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we explore "detail maps", a technique  that is a combination of texture compression and texture synthesis. We decompose a  given input texture into its high and low frequency components and, at runtime,  recombine these components to generate a visually acceptable reconstruction of the  original texture. Detail maps use less memory than the original texture, and they  can be implemented in either software or graphics hardware. Our specific  contributions are: the elimination of seam artifacts; showing how detail maps can be  used for texture transfer and volume textures; and demonstrating how to texture very  large spatial areas without visible tile repetition, loss of resolution, or large  texture memory overhead. Finally, we present preliminary investigations into the  quantitative determination of the textures and the corresponding input parameters  that are ideal for this technique.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b664s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv76d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053g64h"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Random generation of Bayesian Networks and Markov Decision Processes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grobys, Sebastian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Markov Decision Processes (MDPs) and Bayesian Networks (BNs) are  two very different but equally prominent frameworks for modeling stochastic  environments. As empirical testing and the use of randomized search algorithms gain  increasing importance in machine learning and artificial intelligence, there exists  a growing need for random models; in particular MDPs and BNs. This thesis aims at  providing a focused review of the field of random model generation. We begin by  motivating in detail the need for rigorous random MDP and BN generation and survey  relevant past research efforts. We outline the different problems involved in  generating the models and then present our main contribution, a random graph  algorithm specifically designed for the uniform generation of graph structures  underlying random MDPs and BNs.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v46s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053g64h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am900nv17v"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Heegner points on elliptic curves of conductor less than 3000</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gournay, Antoine, 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Elliptic curves are one of the important class of problems in  diophantine equations. In this thesis, we describe how to obtain algebraic points  (called Heegner points) on elliptic curves. We first go over the necessary  definitions and theorems in order to properly study these points and their  properties. We pay a particular attention to the property of these point to have  integral coordinates or not. We also explain how to make explicit computations of  these points and discuss the result of extensive computations made on the elliptic  curves of conductor less than 3000, and give a list of the curves that, were found  to always have Heegner points with integral coordinates.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd531.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nv17v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257f72b"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Distribution patterns of sedges in subarctic fens : ecological and phylogenetic perspectives</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dabros, Anna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this study is to assess current distributional  patterns of species within a community, while taking into account species'  evolutionary histories, as reflected in their phylogenetic relationships. The  hypothesis is that closely related species segregate along environmental gradients,  either due to historic evolutionary divergence of their niches, or to ecological  processes presently occurring within a community. Distribution along environmental  gradients was compared to phylogenetic structure of the 27 sedge species  (Cyperaceae) growing in the subarctic fen communities of Schefferville, northern  Quebec. Field data suggest that within these fens, sedges mostly differentiate along  gradients of rooting depth and pH. Species growing in similar (micro)habitats often  belong to different taxonomic sedge clades, and species belonging to the same clade  usually differentiate on at least one environmental gradient. Further comparison of  natural distribution to responses under greenhouse experimental conditions for four  selected Carex species suggests that the two relatives in section Limosae differ in  their tolerance ranges to environmental conditions due to past evolutionary events,  while the two members of section Paniceae differentiate along environmental  gradients in nature due to ongoing ecological processes.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st12k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257f72b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cyperaceae -- Québec (Province) -- Schefferville Region -- Geographical distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cyperaceae -- Québec (Province) -- Schefferville Region -- Phylogeny</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fens -- Québec (Province) -- Schefferville Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2227mq30j"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Symplectic integration of simple collisions : a backward error analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cottrell, David, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Molecular Dynamics simulations often involve the numerical  integration of pair-wise particle interactions with a constant, step size method. Of  primary concern in these simulations is the introduction of error in velocity  statistics. We consider the simple example of the symplectic Euler method applied to  two-particle collisions in one dimension governed by linear restoring force and use  backward error analysis to predict, these errors. For nearly all choices of system  and method parameters, the post-collision energy is not conserved and depends upon  the initial conditions of the particles and the step size of the method. The  analysis of individual collisions is extended to predict energy growth in systems of  particles in one dimension.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw650.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mq30j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tm59n"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The bullying spectrum in grade schools : parents, teachers, child bullies and their victims</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zaklama, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to examine the perceptions and  practices of children, their parents, and their teachers with regards to bullying at  the grade school level. Eight children were interviewed; three that were identified  by their teachers as victims, two identified as bullies and three identified as  regular peers. Three parents, each taken from the victim, bully, peer groups were  also interviewed, as was four teachers taken from the fifth and sixth grade, within  the English and French language stream program. The subjects were interviewed using  a semi-structured qualitative interview format. Victim children were generally perceived negatively by the  bullies, their peers and by some teachers. The school used in this study did not  adopt a formal bullying program and teachers received no bullying training. Parents  of victims and bullies were seen to have had similar childhood experiences. Victims  felt they did not receive enough support by their teachers. The purpose of this study was to examine the perceptions and practices of children, their parents, and their teachers with regards to bullying at the grade school level. Eight children were interviewed; three that were identified by their teachers as victims, two identified as bullies and three identified as regular peers. Three parents, each taken from the victim, bully, peer groups were also interviewed, as was four teachers taken from the fifth and sixth grade, within the English and French language stream program. The subjects were interviewed using a semi-structured qualitative interview format. Victim children were generally perceived negatively by the bullies, their peers and by some teachers. The school used in this study did not adopt a formal bullying program and teachers received no bullying training. Parents of victims and bullies were seen to have had similar childhood experiences. Victims felt they did not receive enough support by their teachers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wright, Robin</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s77b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm59n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bullying in schools -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct523"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A hint of pink : the realities of being queer from the perspective of a mother and a son</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Van Somer, William Jared</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper explores the reality of a queer individuals life and  the reality of a mother of a queer individual, where the author himself and his  mother are the subjects. The paper seeks to explore these person's  experiences/realities using both an autoethnographic approach and a life history  approach. Coming from a postmodern and feminist position the author delves into such  issues as power, oppression, social construction, personal voice, and identity.  Personal narratives and academic literature within this paper are going to display  queer realities and the broad range of oppression (such as heterosexism, homophobia  and gendering) that they face (in educational, familial, and religious settings) and  the experiences of a mother who has a queer child (such as emotional reactions, lack  of resources/information). The methodologies used within this paper also seek to explore  and expand the use of alternative forms of academic research, focusing on the  autoethnographic approach. Personal narratives, emotions and experiences take center  stage within the body of this paper and seek to represent the realities of queer  youth and their families to the reader, and hopefully, expose the need for more  queer awareness, education, and advocacy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brotman, Shari</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415p993w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct523</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gay men</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gay youth -- Family relationships</dc:subject><dc:subject>Parents of gays</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gay men -- Social conditions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vh33r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The new role of open registries as flag states : the battle for a better image in an increasing competitive shipping industry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Valdés Mora, María Isabel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Under international law, every state has the sovereign right to  establish the conditions under which it will grant its nationality to a vessel. By  consequence, different schemes for ship registration have been developed,  traditionally the nationalist and open system. While the nationalist system imposes  strict requirements regarding national ownership and manning, along with burdensome  fiscal regimes for the shipping industry, the open system offered flexible  requirements and a friendly taxation environment, that help shipowners to minimize  their operation costs. Open registries have been criticized for not complying with  international accepted shipping standards in safety, environmental, and labour  aspects. However, some of them have made great efforts to raise these standards,  mainly obliged by the new demands of the shipping industry. Nonetheless, the shift  to a new culture of quality shipping is not only a responsibility of flag states,  but of all the actors of a maritime scenario.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tetley, William</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb42m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh33r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ship registers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ships -- Registration and transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Merchant marine -- Safety measures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flags of convenience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shipping</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289j57r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The legal status of military aircraft in international law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tremblay, Michel, 1955 Feb. 27-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the beginning of the history of aviation, the use of  aircraft for military purposes revealed an efficient and dangerous weapon in the  arsenal of a State. First it was used as observatory post, and then the aircraft  took a more active role in combat until it became a destructive and deadly weapon.  The definition of military aircraft in international law is not clear as States only  wish to regulate international civil air navigation and not state aircraft. On the  other hand, the Law of armed conflict defines the status of every aircraft with  their respective duties and rights in the conduct of hostilities. The interception  of civil aircraft by military aircraft shall be done in accordance with the  international standards adopted by the International Civil Aviation Organization in  virtue of the Chicago Convention and it's limited to determine the identity of the  aircraft. The use of deadly force against civilian aircraft in flight is equivalent  of pronouncing the death sentence of its occupants without the hearing of a trial.  Respecting the international standards of interception of civil aircraft is a  necessity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milde, Michael</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3332791.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289j57r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Airplanes, Military -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aeronautics -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687j01q"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les limites de la notion d'"orientation sexuelle" dans la protection des communautés LGBT contre la discrimination</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Papy, Jacques</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>"Sexual orientation" is increasingly used as a  prohibited ground for discrimination. The aim of this thesis is to show that this  notion is being challenged both at the theoretical and implementation level. As a  ground, "sexual orientation" ought to be replaced by "sex", as  meaning the social construction of biological sex, in other words,  "gender". First, this thesis exposes the history of "sexual  orientation", and then the problems faced by Canadian and international courts  when trying to implement it. "Sexual orientation" is then analysed within  the broader perspective of the traditional liberal discourse on minorities. That  perspective shows that LGBT communities are submitted to criteria established by the  majority, therefore regulating their existence. Finally, the thesis draws on the analysis of scholars who think  that those criteria are, in fact, part of a broader discourse aiming at perpetuating  the domination of "male" over "female" and that discrimination  of LGBT communities is in fact motivated by "gender".</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leuprecht, Peter</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p48w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j01q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Homophobia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sexual orientation -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gay rights</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xj23m"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Keeping the peacekeepers away from the court : the United States of America, the International Criminal Court and UN Security Council Resolution 1422</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dovey, Kathryn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diplomatic stalemate at the seat of the UN Security Council is  by no means a recent problem. Nevertheless, it may be argued that 'American  unilateralism' reached its apex in July 2002, when the United States stood its  ground and demanded immunity from prosecution before the International Criminal  Court ("ICC") for US peacekeepers. This request was accompanied by the  heavy-handed and deadly serious threat to veto the renewal of the UN peacekeeping  mission in Bosnia, a threat which was realised over the course of the debates. This  political brinkmanship, which pitted the United States against friends and foes  alike, finally ceased when the US agreed to accept a Security Council Resolution  offering a twelve-month deferral of prosecution for peacekeepers before the ICC. It  is the legality of this Resolution which is the focus of this thesis. This thesis  will expose the Resolution to the limits of international law and question the  legitimacy of the tactics employed by the US. It will argue that in order to appease  the recalcitrant superpower, the Security Council passed a Resolution contrary to  both the Rome Statute of the ICC and the UN Charter. With the ICC still in its  embryonic stage, this thesis will suggest the responses available to the Court when  faced with a Resolution of such dubious legality which affects its jurisdiction to  try the most heinous crimes known to humanity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ellis, Jaye</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf56q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xj23m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>War crimes</dc:subject><dc:subject>International Criminal Court</dc:subject><dc:subject>United Nations. Security Council</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peacekeeping forces</dc:subject><dc:subject>United States -- Foreign relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axw42n8591"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Etude critique et théorique de l'application des mécanismes du droit de la concurrence du Canada et de l'Union européenne aux brevets technologiques : théorie des organisations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Demoures, Gaël</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The relationship between patent and competition is rather  complex. Whereas both sets of rules contribute to the same objective, i.e. consumer  welfare and economic growth, their means collide. Patent laws create and protect  monopolies while competition laws seek to limit their influence or even oppose their  occurrence. However, since technological development is a financially risky process,  it needs to be secured through a strong rewarding monopoly. Neo-classical theory has  been so far the cornerstone of competition law. It is driven by a view of the market  where price equilibrium and market atomicity constitute the main elements of  allocative efficiency. But it promotes a rather static view of the market which  neglects the fundamental aspects of technology-driven markets in the modern economy.  Therefore we need to curb the role of the mainstream economic postulates by taking  into account adequate theories in order to reflect modern innovation and  technological diffusion onto the markets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gold, Richard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j624b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n8591</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Patent laws and legislation -- Europe</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competition -- Europe</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competition -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Patent laws and legislation -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>