<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xt802"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soviet anti-religious policies and the Muslims of Central Asia, 1917-1938</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rofi'i, Imam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the impact of Soviet anti-religious policies on the Muslims of Central Asia from 1917 to 1938. The long struggle of the Bolsheviks to come to the power, their attempts to perpetuate the Russian hegemony in Central Asia, and the reactions of the Central Asian people towards the new regime will all form part of this thesis. Having successfully brought about the revolution, the Bolsheviks faced many challenges. One the famous slogans of the revolution, recognition of each nationality's right of self determination, boomeranged on the Bolsheviks, with the European proletariat deserting from the path of the revolution and proclaiming their own independence. In this situation, the Bolsheviks endeavored to gain the support of the Muslims. The government made many promises to the Muslims but, at the same time, dissolved the Kokand government established by the Muslims, causing Muslium revolts throughout the Central Asian region. The Muslim threat was met with measures of appeasement. The government's promises succeeded in attracting the modernist Muslims to cooperate with the regime. A strategy of "divide and rule" and of indirect attacks on Islam was employed, aiming at the annihilation of Islam. Conservative Muslims continued to vehemently oppose the Soviet regime and its policies. But, given the success of the regime in the civil war, and the lack of unity and the strength among Muslims, the Soviet anti-religious policies in Central Asia succeeded at the institutional level, to do great damage to Islam. However, these policies proved ineffectual in destroying the influence of Islamic teachings on the Muslims of Central Asia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, Uner A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t4000.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt802</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islam -- Asia, Central</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soviet Union -- Politics and government -- 1917-1936</dc:subject><dc:subject>Persecution -- Asia, Central</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axp68kj28z"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some Qurʾānic legal texts in the context of Fazlur Rahman's hermeneutical method</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rasyid, Amhar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an attempt to analyze Fazlur Rahman's hermeneutical method: his theory of the divine revelation of the Qur'an and its application to the case of zakat (alms) and riba (usury) in particular. Rahman's theory is firmly in touch with reality and he proposes a well-argued system of Qur'anic methodology. Theoretically, he seeks to determine the general principles behind the Qur'anic legal texts, since the latter were contextualized by time and place while the former are universal and eternal. Practically, Rahman calls Muslims to an intellectual jihad in the effort to reformulate the Qur'anic legal injunctions on social matters in order to solve the problems of the present. Rahman sees the long-standing ad hoc solutions, such as those of the traditionalist Muslims, as unworkable due to their piecemeal treatment of the Qur'anic teachings. The thesis then explores Rahman's proposal for hermeneutical philosophy particularly of Gadamer and Emilio Betti. It attempts to show that Rahman's use of the notion of 'effective history' to understand the 'mind' of the Prophet in formulating the Qur'anic laws leads him to subjectivism. For one thing, he judges the Prophet's mind from the present century when rationality and technology play a dominant role. Besides, laws in the Qur'an are explained in terms of their socio-economic background. Consequently, the thesis comes to the conclusion that Rahman's hermeneutics are lacking in theological considerations and the legal intentions of the Qur'an are secularized.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hallaq, Wael B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333436n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj28z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islamic law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rahman, Fazlur, 1919-</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870x927"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Minangkabau traditionalists' response to the modernist movement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rais, Zaʾim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis studies the response of the traditionalist Muslim groups of Minangkabau, Indonesia, to the modernist movement of the early decades of this century. In their effort to lay the foundations of a rational and progressive Muslim society and rediscovery the true ethics of Islam, the modernists had called for fresh ijtihad. The traditionalists rejected the possibility, or necessity, of new ijtihad and insisted that Islam had been perfectly articulated in the authoritative works of the scholars, especially those of the four schools of law, and that every Muslim must simply adhere to them. The traditionalists argued that the methods of the modernists' not only endangered the authority of the four schools, they threatened to undermine the age-old notion of a harmonious balance between Islam and adat, the two ideological foundations of Minangkabau society. To the traditionalists, therefore, the struggle against the modernists was at once a defense of the classical schools of law and of the harmony of Islam and adat in Minangkabau.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. Uner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602287d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x927</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islam -- Indonesia -- Sumatera Barat</dc:subject><dc:subject>Minangkabau (Indonesian people)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988n07j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Al-Ghazālī's theory of Munāsaba in the context of the adaptability of Islamic law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Qomariyah, Siti</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis studies an aspect of Islamic legal reasoning in terms of the method for determining the ruling on cases for which the Shari'a has no textual basis. Al-Ghazali (d. 550/1111), a great Muslim theologian, philosopher and sufi as well as a remarkable jurist, made an important contribution to this methodological problem. His theory of munasaba proposes a technique for making a ruling on the basis of an understanding and interpretation of the meaning behind the Shari'a. With this theory, a new case can be decided through a rational analysis without direct support in the textual sources. This theory is related to the legal doctrine of maslaha according to which legal reasoning ought to be mainly guided by considerations of public interest. Al-Ghazali argues that the absence of textual basis does not mean the absence of guidance and principles in the Shari'a concerning undefined human interests. This theory rests on the theological premise that God's rulings embody a meaning and purpose which can be perceived; such meaning, arrived at through an inductive survey of the Shari'a rulings, is taken to indicate the Shari'a customary orientation which is to be followed in understanding new cases. The theory is thus neither independent reasoning nor justification for arbitrary decision, because it is the Shari'a meaning which determines the ruling on new cases. While al-Ghazali justifies the extension of the Shari'a's meaning to new eventualities so that the law is not restricted by the limited scope of the revelation, he disclaims any influence of the Mu'tazilis. This thesis analyses not only al-Ghazali's theory of munasaba but also his many examples which serve as a practiced guide to an understanding of the adaptability of Islamic law to social change.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hallaq, Wael B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9354992.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n07j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Islamic law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ghazzālī, 1058-1111</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2v23vw09k"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Teaching intellectually disabled students addition through a multisensory approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pupo, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study was designed to see if children with intellectual disabilities could be taught to add pairs of single-digit numbers using the Touch Math method. Three intellectually disabled students who could add only by using physical representations of numbers were selected for the study. A multiple-probe design across the 3 students was used to evaluate the effectiveness of the intervention. The intervention consisted of a three-step addition program that was planned to teach students to add by counting the faded touch points of the smaller addend starting from the larger addend. The data show that the 3 children were able to master the program and to retain the Touch Math method from 1 to 5.5 months following completion of the program. Suggestions for future research and for teachers are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hanrahan, James P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt000.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vw09k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>People with mental disabilities -- Education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arithmetic -- Study and teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xd718"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The restructuring of the Montreal tourism industry : a sectoral analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pohlmann, Corinne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite its growing importance in industrialized nations, the service sector has received relatively little attention from economic geographers in recent debates over the nature and significance of the current processes of change affecting contemporary capitalism. This lack of attention means that we have little detailed knowledge about how the various industries that comprise the service sector are restructuring their operations and how these processes, in turn, influence broader economic change. This thesis goes some way toward redressing this imbalance by studying the evolving structure of two key sectors of the Montreal tourism industry--hotels and travel agencies. I begin with an overview of past attempts to understand the changing role of the service sector in developed economies. Despite their weaknesses new political economy frameworks are shown to perhaps provide the best starting point for the development of a more 'services informed' approach to understanding current economic change. In an attempt to highlight the strengths and weaknesses of applying such approaches to the study of services I first review their ability to explain and predict changes currently taking place in the tourism industry as a whole. This is followed by a discussion of the empirical findings of the thesis based on 103 interviews with managers and owners of Montreal hotels and travel agencies. I focus on the following key areas: the evolving competitive environment, changes in corporate organization, the adoption of new technologies and shifts in labour use. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milne, Simon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df55k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd718</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tourism -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hotels -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Travel agents -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z903192m"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Loft conversions in a local context : the case of inner city Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Podmore, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Montreal serves as an illustration of how loft landscapes outside of Manhattan draw from the landscape discourse of SoHo, but are inscribed with local economic, political and cultural attributes. Two aspects of the reconstruction of loft landscapes are highlighted: the imagery of the loft in the mass media and the role of local residents in interpreting and reconstructing the loft concept in the Montreal rental market. A description of the local impact of economic restructuring on the built environment of the inner city sets the stage for an examination of two groups of residents. The industrial built environment in Montreal suffers from disinvestment and lack of regulation making the rental sector loft a readily available housing choice in the inner city. Undefined and outside of municipal regulations, lofts are domestic spaces in which tenants can construct identities. Artists, who use industrial spaces to combine home and work (Loft Artists) and non-artists, who use appropriate industrial spaces as rental housing (Loft Dwellers) are the two primary groups to occupy these spaces. A comparison between these two groups, their use of space and their identification with the loft concept, makes up the empirical component of the research. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kobayashi, Audrey</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935500m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903192m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lofts -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Housing -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vq47s"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Computerized system for time-motion analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pochobradsky, Pavel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Regular participation in sports is a common practice among the general population. For cardiovascular fitness, the frequency, duration, intensity and mode of the activity must be appropriate for the individual to benefit from the activity. The benefits for cardiovascular fitness are questionable in sports involving high intensity intermittent exercise of short duration. In the past, the procedures for determination of the heart rate and the time-motion characteristics of an activity were cumbersome and time consuming, thus making application to sports an inconvenience. The purpose of this project was to develop a computer based system for matching heart rate data with time-motion characteristics. The system was tested using ice hockey and squash. Subjects were observed during activity. The heart rate data during the activity were collected using a Polar Vantage XL Heart Rate monitor set to record heart rate values in 5-second intervals. The duration and type of activity were entered in the computer in real time using a coding system. Program combined the time-motion analysis with the heart rates that were downloaded from the Polar heart rate monitor. The results were summarized as follows: (1) total time at each intensity level, (2) mean duration at each intensity level, and (3) mean heart rate at each intensity level. Output from the computer program was similar to manual calculations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Montgomery, David L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx87r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq47s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical fitness -- Measurement -- Computer programs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Exercise -- Physiological aspects -- Measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical fitness -- Testing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f329w"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Music in the poetry of Robert Browning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Plamondon, Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis attempts to characterize the musicality of Robert Browning's poetry. There has been much debate about whether or not Browning may be said to be a musical poet, but neither side has effectively characterized the musicality or lack thereof in his poetry. This study does not concentrate on Browning's "philosophy" of music, nor on the musical allusions in his poetry. Instead it attempts to identify aspects of Browning's art that share an affinity with music. First, the state of music in nineteenth-century England is briefly discussed, followed by a discussion of Browning's musical background and an attempt to identify some general characteristics of musical poetry. The balance of the study is devoted to a discussion of the musicality of ten poems, among them "A Toccata of Galuppi's" and "Master Hugues of Saxe-Gotha". Emphasis is placed on these last two poems' ability to approximate a musical form: the toccata and fugue in the first, and the fugue in the second. The study concludes with a more general discussion of music in Browning's poetry.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McSweeney, Kerry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf03t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f329w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music and literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Browning, Robert, 1812-1889 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687k22p"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A.S. Byatt : writing feminist issues</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pearce, Margaret</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A. S. Byatt attempts to recover lost voices in Possession and Angels and Insects (a collection of two novellas) by examining the limiting roles of women in literature and society. Chapter one examines Possession in which the characters search for their connections to the literary past, ultimately locating them through a lesser-known, female, Victorian poet. In chapter two I consider "Morpho Eugenia," the first novella in Angels and Insects. Byatt illustrates how the male gaze names women and defines their roles. In the second novella, "The Conjugial Angel," analyzed in chapter three, Byatt (re)tells Emily Jesse's story, one formerly appropriated by Alfred Tennyson in In Memoriam. I conclude that Byatt attempts to relocate her heroines from the margins to the center by deconstructing hierarchical patterns of storytelling. Rather than replacing male-monopolized narratives with female ones, Byatt undermines the dominating viewpoint by demonstrating the way in which it obscures all other perspectives.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Westphal, Sarah</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37639019.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k22p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Byatt, A. S. (Antonia Susan), 1936- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w941m"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A developmental study of visual filtering : can windows facilitate filtering efficiency?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pasto, Luigi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A forced-choice reaction time (RT) task was used to examine the development of visual filtering. Specifically, this study examined whether visual filtering is more efficient in smaller spatial ranges, and the extent to which age-related changes in filtering efficiency could be attributed to improvements in the ability to expand and contract an attentional focus. Participants included 20 children in each of four age groups (4, 5, 7, and 9 years), as well as 20 adults aged between 20 and 29 years. Conditions varied with regard to the location or presence of distracters, and the presence of a window within which target stimuli were presented. RT's were slower in the presence of distracters located within one 1 degree of visual angle from target stimuli than when distracters were presented 5.7 degree of visual angle away. In addition, young children were less capable than either older children or adults to filter task-irrelevant stimuli. With regard to the window, RT's were faster in the presence of a window than in its absence. Finally, the window was most effective in improving the filtering efficiency of 4 year old children. These results are discussed in terms of the zoom-lens metaphor of visual attention, and the development of the ability to vary the size of an attentive zoom-lens in response to task requirements.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burack, Jacob A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p018t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w941m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Visual perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dp424"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effectiveness of a multisensory approach for teaching addition to children with Down Syndrome</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Newman, Tina Michelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effectiveness of the Touch Math method of instruction was examined in count-all addition procedures with Down Syndrome children. Four children with Down Syndrome were selected for a multiple probe design study. The participants, two male and two female, are students at a school for intellectually handicapped children and adolescents. They were ascertained to have the minimum required skills in rote counting, one-to-one correspondence, and recognition and identification of numbers. In a multiple pretest procedure with 15 simple addition problems, they demonstrated ineffective addition strategies such as guessing and averaged less than 35% correct. The Touch Math program was then implemented during the regularly scheduled math period four days a week for 40 minutes each day. Students progressed through an incrementally more difficult series of simple addition worksheets. During each session the student received training on the problems and then was administered the worksheet. Results indicate that the Touch Math method has been successful for the teaching of simple addition with these students. Scores on the worksheets progressed from 0% to 100% correct and probe results improved from less than 35% correct to greater than 86% correct following completion of the program. Subjects completed the program in 5 to 16 days.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hanrahan, James</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx86q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp424</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Down syndrome</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arithmetic -- Study and teaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children with mental disabilities -- Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j094b"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Charles Taylor on art and moral sources : a pragmatist re-evaluation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matuk, Nyla Jean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis examines Charles Taylor's theory of agency and the moral sources that he believes inform our modern notion of the self. Taylor's concept of the strong evaluator is outlined and brought to bear on post-structuralist and postmodernist literary-theoretical positions that attempt to reconcile amoral positions and nonagency with multicultural political demands and the demands of what Taylor calls a "culture of authenticity". In order to do full justice to a theory of art that would incorporate Taylor's concept of agency, however, it becomes necessary to critique the philosopher's account of art, which he derives from widely held doctrines of Romanticism and aesthetic autonomy found in the Western tradition. The concept of a pragmatist approach to art serves as the main argument against Taylor's views, which exclude certain agents and their social experiences. Those agents who do not subscribe to Romantic and high Modernist ideas about art's function can often be said to adopt a pragmatic critique, which takes into account the uses of art in defining modern identities, and exposes the social privilege that has typically accompanied the autonomy that art has been awarded.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hjort, A. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t99b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j094b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Art -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Agent (Philosophy)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taylor, Charles, 1931-</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010s164"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L' interférence syntaxique de l'allemand sur le français mosellan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mather, Patrick André</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject of my Thesis is the syntactic interference of German in the French of the Moselle region. The geographical location of this Department, situated close to the German border, leads me to believe that French and German are in contact in this region given their geographic proximity and the history of the area. My Thesis is divided into two main sections. First, through a detailed analysis of relevant syntactic structures in French and German, I put forth several hypotheses concerning the syntactic interference of German in the French spoken in the Moselle Department. Then, I tested these hypotheses through extensive fieldwork by interviewing two different groups of speakers, young and old, and by analyzing those data produced which indicated some degree of German interference in French. I then submitted these data to the same speakers to obtain their grammaticality judgments. My analysis has led me to establish an important typological distinction between the sentences produced by the younger speakers and those produced by the elderly, and to uncover a hierarchy in the acceptability of the sentences submitted to these speakers, which I discuss and attempt to explain.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Domingue, Nicole</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3150.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s164</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French language -- France -- Moselle -- Foreign elements -- German</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interference (Linguistics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Dialects -- France -- Moselle -- Syntax</dc:subject><dc:subject>German language -- Influence on French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dp43d"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between the self-perception of psychological empowerment and perceived control in a university population</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Markow, Jody R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explored the self-perception of psychological empowerment in a classroom setting. Specifically, the purpose of this research was to determine if the self-perception of psychological empowerment was related to perceived control and academic achievement in a population of university students. Subjects consisted of 24 students between the ages of 22 and 37. The majority of the subjects were enrolled in a diploma program in the Faculty of Education at McGill University. These students had all completed a previous university degree and were working towards teacher certification. The primary methods of data collection consisted of an empowerment survey, a locus of control measure specific to achievement goals, and an interview with two key informants from the sample. Results indicated that those students who perceived themselves to be empowered (Y Emp) reported a significantly more external locus of control than those students who did not perceive themselves to be empowered (N Emp). Descriptive data from the empowerment survey and the interview suggested that there were mitigating circumstances which were of direct concern to the sample and which might account for the results. The findings offer tentative support for the context specific nature of empowerment as predicted by empowerment theory. Consideration is given to the diverse ways that empowerment can be conceptualized and the implications of this for a student population. Some suggestions for further research are offered.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mager, George C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng70r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp43d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Self-perception</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acz30pv64s"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La banqueroute au Bas-Canada : une étude des années 1840-1849</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Launay, Dominique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is a study about bankruptcy, a procedure incorporated into Lower Canada's legal institutions in 1839. The object is to analyze from both a social and a legal perspectives the relations between insolvent traders and their creditors during the first half of the nineteenth century. This research is based on a source almost unexploited by historians up to now, the bankruptcy records located in the judicial archives in the district of Montreal. The economic difficulties of the 1820's and the inefficiency of the existing legal means for debt recovery were among the main arguments invoqued by the traders of Montreal in their demands for the implementation of a bankruptcy procedure. The result of our research indicate that these demands were not mainly expressed by the wealthiest creditors. The bankruptcy procedure responded more to the needs of ordinary creditors such as artisans, tavernkeepers and bakers whose credit was central to the production and trade of goods. The bankruptcy procedure allowed ordinary creditors to audit and control debtor's transactions, and to constrain other creditors to accept re-payment compromise.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Young, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pf95z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv64s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bankruptcy -- Québec (Province) -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580p54g"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study on China Management Training Centre at Chengdu and its impact on the trainees</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lai, Zong Fang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1978, the Chinese government embarked on an economic reform and adopted an open-door policy for its economic development. The goal of the economic reform was to transform its central planning economy into a market economy. This reform has since led to significant changes in the macro and micro economic system which, and in turn, have challenged the management system based on central planning economy in China. Therefore, the Chinese government faced an important task to train managers with management knowledge based on a market economy. In order to meet this need, since 1978, the Chinese government has set up a number of management training centres with the help of several foreign countries. One of them was the China Management Training Centre at Chengdu (CMTCC) , which was under the sponsorship of the Chinese government and the Canadian International Development Agency (CIDA). This Centre's mission was " to serve the management education needs of state-enterprise management personnel, government personnel involved in management of economic affairs, and township and village enterprise managers, in Sichuan and throughout Southwest and Northwest China" (Proposal for CMTCC, Ph III, 1990, p.1). According to the joint agreement between the two sides, the Association of Canadian Community Colleges (ACCC), on behalf of the Canadian government, was responsible for sending Canadian instructors to teach at China Management Training Centre on a temporary basis. The selected instructors would design the courses, recommend the textbooks and reading materials, and deliver the courses in English at the Centre. The Chinese side would take responsibility for enroling trainees, providing logistical services, translating the reading materials into Chinese versions and offering interpretation services for the Canadian instructors in the classes. The first training program began in the fall of 1984. Since then, the China Management Training Centre at Chengdu has offered 26 management training programs. The success of these training programs could have an important effect on the economic reform in China. Therefore, it was important to study the CMTCC and assess the impacts of the training programs. The purpose of this research is to study the nature and operation, and examine the impacts of the CMTCC training programs on the trainees.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lin, Jing</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150m07z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p54g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Executives -- Training of -- China</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt62c"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Classics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Women's songs and their cultic background in archaic Greece</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Klinck, Anne L. (Anne Lingard)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis applies to Archaic Greek literature the medievalist's concept of "women's songs," that is, love-poems given to a female persona and composed in a popular register. In the Greek context a distinct type can be recognised in poems of women's affections (not necessarily love-poems as such) composed in an ingenuous register and created for performance, choral or solo, within a women's thiasos. The poems studied are those of Sappho, along with the few surviving partheneia of Alcman and Pindar. The feminine is constructed, rather mechanically by Pindar, more subtly by the other two, from a combination of tender feeling, personal and natural beauty, and an artful artlessness. It is not possible to reconstruct a paradigmatic thiasos which lies behind the women's songs, but certain characteristic features merge, especially the pervasiveness of homoerotic attachments and the combination of a personal, affective, with a social, religious function. In general, women's groups in ancient Greece must have served as a counterbalance to the prevailing male order. However, while some of the women's thiasoi provide a vehicle for the release of female aggression, the function of the present group is essentially harmonious and integrative.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schachter, Albert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps57h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt62c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Greek poetry -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Greece -- Songs and music</dc:subject><dc:subject>Greece -- Civilization -- To 146 B.C</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw9505236p"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parcours de la mémoire : l'Islam et ses traces dans l'imaginaire d'Abdelwahab Meddeb</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kazi, Ania</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In nationalist or Islamist ideology, Islam defines itself through an identity which is homogeneous and self-enclosed. The goal of this study is to examine how the Tunisian writer Abdelwahab Meddeb draws from the margins of Islam to imagine instead an identity open to the Other and to possibilities of transformation. Meddeb replaces the traditional search for identity with what we shall call the search for hybridity. This new search, which he develops in his fiction (Talismano (1979), Phantasia (1986), and Tombeau d'Ibn Arabi (1987) and his essays, necessitates an examination of memory in order to extricate the forgotten traces of Arab-Islamic tradition (in particular sufism) and those suppressed remnants of European culture. Meddeb's project is carried out in two aspects: the look at the Self, and the look at the Other. in this way, the little-studied topic of Islam in Maghreb literature here reveals an audacious vision, an alternative imagination that dismantles the categories authentic/inauthentic and resists "the culture of resentment" which, according to Meddeb, is choking Islam today.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boullata, Issa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf98k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505236p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meddeb, Abdelwahab -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579v282"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The shelter experience : a case study of street kid residents at Toronto's Covenant House</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Karabanow, Jeffrey M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This case study of Covenant House, an emergency shelter for street kids in downtown Toronto, focuses on the experiences that draw kids into youth shelters and that drive them out. The analysis stresses the importance to street kids of feeling "cared for". Street kids were drawn to Covenant House because they felt cared for there by its open intake policy, appealing facilities (clean surroundings and good food), and staff who listened to and were interested in their problems. But residents were rather swiftly turned off by its rigidly enforced, elaborate and "uncaring' rule structure, and either walked out or got kicked out. Given the limited alternatives in Toronto's "shelter world", however, Covenant House has become the preferred choice for street kids who find themselves in a cycle of entering, leaving and returning.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rains, Prue</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb36m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v282</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Covenant House (Toronto, Ont.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shelters for the homeless -- Ontario -- Toronto</dc:subject><dc:subject>Homeless youth -- Services for -- Ontario -- Toronto</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qt980"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Drogue et expérience littéraire dans l'oeuvre de Henri Michaux</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jackson, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Henri Michaux first discovered mescaline in 1956. This encounter proved a lasting influence on the work of the writer who, for at least ten years, struggled to circumscribe, then tried to explain the nature of the terrible shock he had received from the mind-altering chemical. The event was so important for the poet that in due time, it brought about a veritable conversion, a total and uncompromising revision of his most fundamental relationships towards the function of language and thought, and towards the basic premises of existence in general. Signs had hinted, previously, at this sudden transfiguration of his vision. His relationships with other drugs (ether, opium) betrayed his hidden desire to go beyond the limits ordained by his tragically caustic and defiant mind. Yet mescaline alone, as a weapon, proved strong enough to overcome Michaux's chronic insubordination, and clear the prolific way that led him toward the realisation and acceptance of that obscure other whose presence he had hitherto only felt, and which had been asleep within him forever.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b535c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt980</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Authors, French -- Drug use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Michaux, Henri, 1899-1984 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1831cm94x"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Visual filtering and covert orienting in developmentally disabled persons with and without autism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iarocci, Grace</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A forced choice reaction time (RT) task was used to examine the relations between covert orienting (shifts in attention independent of eye movement) and filtering (the inhibition of processing of irrelevant stimuli) components of attention in persons with autism (n = 12) and developmentally disabled persons without autism (n = 20). Conditions varied with regard to the validity of the cue (related to covert orienting) and presence of distractors (related to filtering). ?'he RT/p(correct) scores of both groups were longer in the distractor-present conditions and in conditions when a cue provided incorrect information regarding the location of the subsequent target (invalid cue). The RT/p(correct) scores of persons with autism as compared to developmentally disabled persons without autism were slower overall. However the pattern of performance of persons with autism was not significantly different from that of the developmentally disabled persons without autism. These results are inconsistent with the notions of specific deficits in covert orienting and filtering among persons with autism and indicate that certain attentional difficulties may not be unique to autism. Alternatively, they may also reflect differences in the specific mechanisms assessed in different studies. Findings are discussed in terms of the specificity of visual filtering and covert orienting impairments in autism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burack, Jacob A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt20q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm94x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Visual perception</dc:subject><dc:subject>Autism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Developmentally disabled</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tb461"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rhetorical use of the Great Law of Peace at Kahnawake : a measure of political legitimacy in a Mohawk community</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harrison, Regina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The past is often used by political figures in the present in order to achieve political goals by manipulating a feeling of identity, based upon a shared history, among their followers. The extent to which a political leader may alter narratives of the past to meet his or her own needs is governed by certain constraints and laws of structure, as Appadurai and Sahlins have argued (Appadurai 1981; Sahlins 1985). However, the credibility of a leader is affected by such factors as how well that leader fills the cultural construct of a leader's role and adheres to the community's expectations. At Kahnawake, a Mohawk community near Montreal, I found that the amount of authority granted to individual factional leaders in their interpretation of the Iroquois Confederacy's Great Law of Peace reflected the degree to which each leader behaved as a Confederacy chief or orator should, and also reflected the degree to which the leader obeyed social norms, particularly that of not advocating violence against fellow Mohawks. My findings add to the growing body of anthropological literature on the uses of the past by demonstrating in a specific case study how interpersonal relationships between leaders and a community affect the leaders' credibility and authority over the past.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morantz, Toby</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh514.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb461</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kahnawake Indian Reserve (Québec) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mohawk Indians -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kahnawake Indian Reserve (Québec) -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iroquois Indians -- Politics and government</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591b40r"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between video game playing and gambling behavior in children and adolescents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gupta, Rina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is suggested that commercial video games and gambling activities make use of similar types of intermittent reinforcement schedules. This research seeks to examine the nature of this relationship amongst children and adolescents. One hundred and four children from grades 4, 6, and 8 participated. A questionnaire exploring issues related to video game playing and gambling behavior was completed and a computerized blackjack game was individually administered. High frequency video game players are compared to low frequency video game players with respect to their gambling performance on the blackjack gambling task as well as on information gathered from the questionnaire. Findings suggest that high frequency video game players nor only gamble more than low frequency video game players but report that gambling makes them feel more important. Furthermore, they appear to be taking greater risks on the blackjack gambling task. Males exhibited greater risk-taking tendencies on the blackjack task than did females.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Derevensky, Jeffrey L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v00w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b40r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Adolescent psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gambling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Video games</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g218q"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The cross : a long poem using the techniques of numerical composition</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Groves, T. C. (Thomas Cameron)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Cross is a long poem with a numerologically determined structure. In my introduction I examine some of the ideas behind the tradition of literary numerological composition, particularly those presented in the Timaeus of Plato and in Augustine's De musica. I then scrutinize number's aptness as a unifying principle in the poem, briefly elucidating the Golden Proportion and showing its centrality to the poem's structure, concluding with a look at my use of number metaphor. The Cross, partly and wholly the embodiment of these theories, follows. Its subject matter is the history of Montreal. Each book has a unifying focus: Book I centres on Jacques Cartier's explorations in 1535; Book II on the activities of the fictional character Mrs. Chau, in the recent past; and Book III on the visit of the Prince of Wales in 1860 for the inauguration of the Victoria Bridge.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Conway, C. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq73n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g218q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Golden section</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mathematics and literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>