<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r744z"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Occupational Health</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Surgery versus collagen to treat female stress urinary incontinence : physician beliefs and requirements for treatment &amp; a modeled cost-effectiveness analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oremus, Mark, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Surgery Collagen Incontinence Trial (SCIT) is a randomized controlled trial evaluating the comparative efficacy of surgery versus collagen injection to treat female stress urinary incontinence (SUI). This thesis investigated two issues from SCIT: (1) the trial investigators' use of a consensus estimate that assumed collagen would be preferred as a first line treatment if it was at most 20% less efficacious than surgery; and (2) the cost-effectiveness of surgery and collagen. A physician survey was conducted to help verify the SCIT investigators' consensus estimate. Respondents on average believed surgery was more efficacious than collagen, and they generally had stronger beliefs in the ability of surgery to meet their requirements for remaining the first line treatment for SUI. However, on average, respondents indicated a willingness to use collagen if it was at most approximately 23% less efficacious than surgery. The survey also provided baseline data for future research into how SCIT's results may or may not play a role in changing the views of clinicians. The cost-effectiveness analysis was based on a risk-benefit model (decision-tree) that delineated the success rates, side-effects and complication rates of both surgery and collagen. Probabilities from the physician survey and the published literature were used in the model. Collagen was found to be less costly than surgery, but also less efficacious. Until more is known about collagen's long-term durability, the injection material will probably not gain coverage under Canada's provincial health insurance plans.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Collet, Jean-Paul</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Shapiro, Stan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr44v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r744z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am900nw49b"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular analysis of normal and mutant forms of the androgen receptor and their interactive properties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Panet-Raymond, Valerie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The androgen receptor (AR) is a ligand-activated transcription factor and a member of the nuclear receptor superfamily. Mutations in the androgen receptor are associated with androgen insensitivity syndrome (AIS), and a neurodegenerative disease, spinal bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA). Most of the mutations causing AIS are loss-of-function missense mutations whereas SBMA is caused by a gain-of-function polyglutamine expansion in the N-terminal domain of the protein. Characterization of AR mutations has led to a better understanding of structure-function relationships of the AR and serves as a prototype for steroid receptors mechanisms of action. In the first paper, we examine the role of an AR mutation in causing mild androgen insensitivity syndrome. We found that this mutation conferred reduced transactivation by AR through impaired interactions with the AR coactivator, TIF2, and impaired homodimerization. In the second paper, we investigate the role of the AR polyGln expansion mutation in SBMA pathogenesis. Recent evidence has implicated proteolytic degradation of polyGln-expanded proteins and their subsequent intracellular aggregation in polyGn-expanded disease pathogenesis. We examined the role and composition of aggregates using fluorescently-tagged AR and found that proteolysis need not be a prerequisite for aggregation and that aggregation is not necessary for poly-Gln-induced cellular toxicity. Finally, we characterize the novel heterodimerization of AR and ERalpha. We determined that this direct interaction has functional implications for the transactivational properties of both receptors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pinsky, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z68g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw49b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Androgens -- Receptors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spinal muscular atrophy -- Pathogenesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021h076"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Antioxidant activity of Tibetan plant remedies used for cardiovascular disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Owen, Patrick L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Antioxidant activity was measured in 14 plant species incorporated in more than 30% of Tibetan medicines used for cardiovascular disease and related symptoms according to indigenous pharmacopoeias. The study was undertaken in order to explore possible dietary/medicinal elements which may contribute to the reportedly low incidence of cardiovascular disease among Tibetan highlanders despite high hematocrit levels and a high saturated fat/low fruit and vegetable diet. Extracts of Terminalia chebula, Syzygium aromaticum, Aquilaria agallocha, Santalum album, Amomum subulatum, Justicia adhatoda and Myristica fragrans were strong scavengers of the 1,1 diphenyl-2-picryl-hydrazyl (DPPH) radical (P &lt; 0.05). Cu2+-catalyzed low-density lipoprotein (LDL) oxidation was measured in vitro using thiobarbituric acid reactive substances (TBARS) formation and monitoring change in absorbency at 234 rim from conjugated dienes. The hexane fraction of S. aromaticum significantly reduced LDL susceptibility to oxidation (1339.96 +/- 7.01 min. lag time, P &lt; 0.05), more than three times longer than TroloxRTM (431.02 +/- 21.19 min). Results of TBARS (90 min.: r = 0.71, P &lt; 0.005; 180 min.: r = 0.74, P &lt; 0.005) and DPPH (r = 0.69, P &lt; 0.05) assays positively correlated to conjugated dienes formation. Our results suggest that these plants are likely to contribute to the therapeutic effects of traditional drugs used to treat cardiovascular disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Johns, Timothy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064767k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h076</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Herbs -- Therapeutic use</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cardiovascular system -- Diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antioxidants</dc:subject><dc:subject>Medicine, Chinese -- Tibet</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mh35r"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional characterization of the E-4031 sensitive repolarization current, Ikr in rabbit ventricular myocytes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paquette, Tyna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The delayed rectifier potassium current IKr (hERG) participates in repolarization of the cardiac action potential and is implicated in one form of inherited Long QT Syndrome. The goal of this study was to characterize the biophysical properties of IKr in isolated rabbit ventricular myocytes and hERG expressed in a mammalian cell line using mathematical, electrophysiological and molecular biological techniques. Incorporation of results into a mathematical gating model of IKr revealed that the current did not follow the typical Hodgkin-Huxley type gating formulation and therefore comprised a gating model paradox. Furthermore, it was found that different groups of divalent cations selectively affected specific kinetic properties of I Kr, with the relief of rectification of the current by the Cd 2+-like class of divalent cations (Cd2+, Ni 2+, Co2+ and Mn2+; mM range) and the block of the current by Zn2+ (0.1--1 mM) being the most prominent effects. The biophysical properties of hERG were found to be more sensitive to Cd2+ compared to rabbit IKr (muM as opposed to mM concentrations). The relief of rectification of native rabbit IKr and expressed human hERG by the Cd2+-like group of divalent cations and block of rabbit IKr by Zn2+ may be attributed to specific interactions with distinct sites associated with different regions of the channel.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shrier, Alvin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p2218.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh35r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asf268701t"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>SHP-1-dependent, caspase-8-mediated, acidification precedes mitochondrial dysfunction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martino, Giovanni</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The cardinal feature of apoptosis is the activation of a family of proteases termed caspases, and in some forms, loss of mitochondrial integrity and release of cytochrome c into the cytoplasm are viewed as necessary components of cell death. In receptor-mediated apoptosis, more specifically Somatostatin (SST) receptor (SSTR)- and Fas-signaled apoptosis, an additional feature is intracellular acidification (pHi) and Protein Tyrosine Phosphatase (PTP) activity. Increased translocation and activity of PTP, more specifically SHP-1 at the cell membrane as well as the functional activation of caspase-8 are required to reduce pHi. Also, a decrease in mitochondria) membrane potential (Deltapsim) and release of cytochrome c (cyt c) are concomitant with a decrease in pHi suggesting that mitochondrial dysfunction is a consequence and not a cause of acidification. Inhibition of caspase-8 activation and prevention of SHP-1 translocation abrogates the ability of SST to induce acidification and mitochondrial disruption, whereas inhibition of other caspases such as caspase-9, or -3/7 are ineffective. Protection from cell death can also be accomplished by Bcl-2. In this model, Bcl-2 elevates resting pHi and attenuates acidification and apoptosis only when the overexpressed Bcl-2 is targeted to the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) but not the mitochondria. In conclusion, we established that mitochondrial breakdown follows acidification and that acidification is dependent on caspase-8 and SHP-1 activation. Additionally, effector caspases are induced only when there is concomitant acidification. Bcl-2 cannot prevent acidification-dependent apoptosis at the level of the mitochondria despite protecting it revealing that mitochondrial disruption is a potentiating, but not essential event in the apoptotic pathway.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Srikant, C. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1393929.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268701t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A73666642p"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Catalysis of homoaldol reactions by titanium (IV) triflates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martins, Evelyn O.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The introduction of enantioselectivity into zinc catalyzed homoaldol reactions is described. Coordinating ligands such as bis-oxazolines and beta-amino alcohols inhibit the addition of zinc homoenolates to aldehydes while Lewis acids such as titanium (IV) isopropoxide and boron trifluoroetherate promote this reaction. Notably, the addition of zinc homoenolates to benzaldehyde mediated by chiral titanium (IV) alkoxides yields homoaldol adducts with moderate enantioselectivity. The development of titanium catalysis of the homoaldol addition of silyloxyalkoxycyclopropanes to aldehydes is also described. The methodology features alkoxytitanium (IV) triflates as catalysts, which mediate homoenolate addition to a range of carbonyl substrates. The preparation of such titanium triflates by a new procedure, namely the treatment of titanium (IV) alkoxides with trimethylsilyltriflate, affords more reactive catalysts than those prepared by conventional methods. In addition, the catalyst system is stable at elevated temperatures for an extended period of time. Titanium (IV) triflates derived from a variety of alkoxide ligands as well as ligands with sulfide linkages are effective catalysts for this reaction. Efforts directed towards extending this catalytic process to a highly enantioselective protocol are detailed. Moderate enantioselectivity is obtained in homoaldol reactions mediated by a tridentate alkoxide derived titanium tiflate.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gleason, Janet L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gx96z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666642p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk439"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isolation of a Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAOI gene involved in 3-hydroxybutyrate catabolism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcangione, Luigi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work was undertaken with the objective of isolating and characterising the bdh gene of P. aeruginosa PAOI. Isolation of the bdh gene was initially attempted by PCR amplification and then by heterologous complementation of E. coli (LS5218) and S. meliloti (Rm11107) strains unable to catabolise 3-hydroxybutyrate. Three classes of plasmids were isolated. Class I comprised two plasmids, p5218-02 and p5218-07, isolated via complementation of LS5218, which were capable of complementing both LS5218 and Rm11107 for growth on 3-hydroxybutyrate. 3-hydroxybutyrate dehydrogenase (BDH) activity was not detected in an extract of LS5218 (p5218-02). The sole 3.6-kb EcoRI fist was partially sequenced and found to have three putative open reading frames (ORF). ORF 1 is homologous to the fusE gene of E. coli. We hypothesised that p5218-02 encodes an enzyme capable of degrading 3 hydroxybutyrate, but does not encode the bdh gene. Plasmids of class II (p30065) and class III (p30066) were isolated via complementation of Rm11107. Significant BDH activity was detected in an extract of Rm11107 (p30066), but not in Rm11107, leading to the hypothesis that p30066 carries the bdh gene.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>iscoll, Brian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h08g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk439</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pseudomonas aeruginosa -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microbial metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pseudomonas aeruginosa -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poly-beta-hydroxybutyrate -- Metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386m23k"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Treatment seeking for obsessive-compulsive disorder : role of ocd symptons and comorbid psychiatric diagnoses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mayerovitch, Jamie Isaac</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Previous research has indicated that although obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) is associated with immense suffering, and social and economic costs, individuals afflicted with the disorder have a very low rate of seeking help from mental health professionals. Methods. From standardized psychiatric interviews of 7214 Edmonton residents we identified 172 subjects with a lifetime diagnosis of OCD; 37% (63/172) had consulted a doctor about their symptoms. Results. Total number of symptoms (odds ratio, OR = 3.44) and severe obsessions of violence and other unpleasant thoughts (OR = 2.62) were significantly associated with treatment seeking in the multivariate analysis. Conclusion. This study was an important step in examining which specific symptoms and comorbid conditions are associated with treatment seeking. It was somewhat surprising that neither comorbid disorders nor any compulsive symptoms were related to treatment seeking behaviour. This study may be of benefit to future public education programs especially by teaching the public about compulsions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>du Fort, Galbaud</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv71f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m23k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kc53k"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic characterization and molecular evolution of the CAG pathogenicity island of Helicobacter pylori</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kouri, Kimberly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The perinuclear theca (PT) is a cytoskeletal structure that covers the nucleus of mammalian spermatozoa and is believed to have a membrane binding role. The objectives of this study were to analyze the protein composition of the mouse PT, to identify its major protein component, and to characterize this protein's transcriptional and translational origins during spermatogenesis. The PT was extracted from demembranated and acrosome-depleted mouse sperm heads by alkaline treatment. The protein profile of the PT extract was composed of several polypeptides of which a 15 kDa subacrosomal protein predominated and was found to be immunocross-reactive with a previously cloned 15 kDa PT protein of the rat (PERF 15) that belongs to a family of lipid binding proteins. A primer pair designed from rat PERF 15 cDNA was then used to screen a mouse testicular cDNA library by polymerase chain reaction (PCR). The deduced amino acid sequence obtained from the PCR product was almost identical to the testicular-specific rat PERF 15. Developmental Northern blots and in situ hybridization studies performed with riboprobes encoding the mouse PERF 15 cDNA revealed that mRNA levels were highest in round and early elongating mouse spermatids. Immunohistochemistry indicated that PERF 15 began to be expressed in the cytoplasm of mid-pachytene spermatocytes and appeared to reach maximum expression in the distal cytoplasm of late elongating mouse spermatids, long after transcriptional arrest. During the development of round and early elongating spermatids, the immunolabel became progressively concentrated over the anterior half of the spermatid nucleus suggesting a subacrosomal deposition of PERF 15 during this phase of mouse spermatogenesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beech, Robin N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj947.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc53k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Helicobacter pylori -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440v524"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of a major protein of the mouse perinuclear Theca</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Korley, Robert E. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The perinuclear theca (PT) is a cytoskeletal structure that covers the nucleus of mammalian spermatozoa and is believed to have a membrane binding role. The objectives of this study were to analyze the protein composition of the mouse PT, to identify its major protein component, and to characterize this protein's transcriptional and translational origins during spermatogenesis. The PT was extracted from demembranated and acrosome-depleted mouse sperm heads by alkaline treatment. The protein profile of the PT extract was composed of several polypeptides of which a 15 kDa subacrosomal protein predominated and was found to be immunocross-reactive with a previously cloned 15 kDa PT protein of the rat (PERF 15) that belongs to a family of lipid binding proteins. A primer pair designed from rat PERF 15 cDNA was then used to screen a mouse testicular cDNA library by polymerase chain reaction (PCR). The deduced amino acid sequence obtained from the PCR product was almost identical to the testicular-specific rat PERF 15. Developmental Northern blots and in situ hybridization studies performed with riboprobes encoding the mouse PERF 15 cDNA revealed that mRNA levels were highest in round and early elongating mouse spermatids. Immunohistochemistry indicated that PERF 15 began to be expressed in the cytoplasm of mid-pachytene spermatocytes and appeared to reach maximum expression in the distal cytoplasm of late elongating mouse spermatids, long after transcriptional arrest. During the development of round and early elongating spermatids, the immunolabel became progressively concentrated over the anterior half of the spermatid nucleus suggesting a subacrosomal deposition of PERF 15 during this phase of mouse spermatogenesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Oko, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx68j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v524</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860878z"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transcription regulation of murine parathyroid hormoneparathyroid hormone related peptide receptor (PTH1R)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kwan, Mei Yee, 1971-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Our first aim was to generate transgenic mice to express beta-galactosidase reporter gene under the control of the two promoters. The model would allow us to study the temporal and spatial expression of PTH1R during the onset of embryonic endochondral ossification, and in the adult. Our transgenic animals would allow us to identify regulatory elements that are essential for tissue specific PTH1R expression. We have cloned 11 kilobases of mouse PTH1R gene promoter sequence containing four untranslated exons U1, U2, U3 and SS, and fused this to a Lac Z reporter gene, which was in turn fused to a 250 by fragment containing the A-rich polyadenylylation signal. Three additional constructs were made with deletion of transcription start sites in exon U1 (DeltaU1), U3 (DeltaU3) and both (DeltaU1DeltaU3). Both the control and transgenic adult littermates showed high levels of beta-galactosidase-like activity in epiphyseal growth plate and kidney medulla. However, beta-galactosidase activity was not observed for fetuses aged post coital 14.5 and 15.5 days. We were unable to show tissue specific reporter activity in our transgenic animals. In other study, we found that P2 is the predominant promoter controlling PTH1R gene expression in both bone and cartilage. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>White, John H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r9639.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860878z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579v125"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Graph embeddings and approximate graph coloring</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Labelle, François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We describe how to embed a graph into a small n-dimensional hypersphere such that the endpoints of any edge are placed exactly one unit of distance apart. As an application, we show how such an embedding can be used to find large independent sets in sparse 3-colorable graphs. By combining this algorithm with another which is specialized in dense graphs, we obtain a randomized, polynomial time algorithm that can color any 3-colorable graph using at most O(n1/4 log 1/2n) colors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Whitesides, Sue</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z7258.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v125</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429c136"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dynamic load balancing issues in the earth runtime system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kakulavarapu, Kamala Prasad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Multithreading is a promising approach to address the problems inherent in multiprocessor systems, such as network and synchronization latencies. Moreover, the benefits of multithreading are not limited to loop-based algorithms but apply also to irregular parallelism. EARTH - Efficient Architecture for Running THreads, is a multithreaded model supporting fine-grain, non-preemptive threads. This model is supported by a C-based runtime system which provides the multithreaded environment for the execution of concurrent programs. This thesis describes the design and implementation of a set of dynamic load balancing algorithms, and an in-depth study of their behavior with divide-and-conquer, regular, and irregular classes of applications. The results described in this thesis are based on EARTH-SP2, an implementation of the EARTH program execution model on the IBM SP-2, a distributed memory multiprocessor system. The main results of this study are as follows: (1) A randomizing load balancer with both sender and receiver components using global load state information provides scalable, robust performance for recursive and irregular applications. Furthermore, a randomizing algorithm performs the best as long as the cost of computing the random number does not dominate the overall time of thread execution. (2) Load state information outperforms history information for irregular and recursive applications. However for regular applications, history information is more preferable. (3) A purely sender-initiated algorithm is the best choice in two scenarios: barrier-synchronized applications, and very fine-grain applications at low input workloads. (4) A simple, work-stealing load balancer is preferable for applications with modest thread granularities, and very low workloads. Other major contributions include: (1) Description of a runtime system for a non-blocking, non-preemptive multithreaded programming model. (2) A detailed analysis of costs associated with EARTH operations, and a comparative study of EARTH performance on three different platforms. (3) Proposal of a new classification scheme for multithreaded systems. This is supplemented by an extensive literature survey.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gao, Guang R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f782p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c136</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75r964k"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of dietary change among Kahnawake Schools Diabetes Prevention Project participating children (grades 4-6)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jimenez, M. Michelle (Maria Michelle)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study assessed change in the dietary intake and weight, height and body mass index (BMI. kg/ml) measurements of children (grades 4--6) who have participated in the Kahnawake Schools Diabetes Prevention Program (KSDPP). Children from two independent cross sectional samples were assessed at baseline in 1994 (n = 156) and in 1998 (n = 146). Diet was assessed using a single 24-hour recall. Results showed no overall change in energy, fat and sucrose intake. Food groups were created as indicators of diet quality. Results showed a decrease in the frequency of consumption of foods in the high fat food group (p &lt; 0.05) and an increase in the average amount of white sugar consumed (p &lt; 0.05). A decrease in the number of servings of fruit was shown, but also a trend towards their increased frequency of consumption. No significant changes were found in weight, height or BMI. Dietary and anthropometric data were combined but results showed no significant changes in diet by BMI category. Changes in diet are challenging to both measure and implement. These results could be used to identify more specific future interventions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Receveur, Olivier</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kuhnlein, Harriet V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq60c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r964k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>School children -- Québec (Province) -- Kahnawake Indian Reserve -- Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diabetes in children -- Québec (Province) -- Kahnawake Indian Reserve</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x579k"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Insulin-like growth factor-I and its receptor in normal human and Alzheimer's disease brains</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jafferali, Shelina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Evidence indicates that levels of insulin-like growth factor-I (IGF-I) are elevated in the serum of Alzheimer's disease patients. In the present study, using membrane binding assays, we have shown that [125I]IGF-I receptor binding sites are not significantly altered in the frontal cortex, hippocampus and cerebellum of the AD brain. However, in vitro receptor autoradiography revealed significant increases in the density of [125I]IGF-I receptor binding sites in layer IV of the frontal cortex, the stratum oriens of the hippocampus and the putamen nucleus of the striatum but not in other regions of the AD brain. IGF-I immunoreactivity was evident in the pyramidal neurons of the frontal cortex, pyramidal layer of CA1--CA4 subfields and the hilar neurons of the hippocampus, as well as the Purkinje cells of the cerebellum in control and AD brains. Additionally, in the AD brain, IGF-I immunoreacitivity was also observed to be localized with Abeta-containing diffuse and neuritic plaques as well as in astrocytes in the gray matter of the cortex and the hippocampus. These findings, taken together, indicate that although no striking alterations have been found in the number of IGF-I receptors or the peptide itself in the AD brain, the presence of immunoreactive IGF-I in the neuritic plaques suggests a putative role for the growth factor in AD pathology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kar, Satyabrata</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666643z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x579k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k9125"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mental health issues in an urban aboriginal population : focus on substance abuse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jacobs, Kahá:wi Joslyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aims of the study were to examine substance abuse and physical and mental health in an urban Aboriginal population. Data was collected through structured interviews (n = 202) with Aboriginals in the greater Montreal area. The majority were single, unemployed, and lived in the urban area for a long time (mean of 9.96 +/- .76 years). One third reported having a current substance abuse problem. Results indicated high levels of psychological distress augmented by substance abuse. Substance abusers were also more likely to have been the victims of abuse. Ethnographic interviews with urban Aboriginals and community workers were also conducted (n = 30). One third were victims of abuse and 6 reported having a current substance abuse problem. Psychological and biological understructures were used in defining addiction and explaining substance use among Aboriginal peoples. Cultural traditions were viewed as integral components of substance abuse treatment and the need for outpatient treatment facilities and aftercare programs were indicated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, Kathryn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q604r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k9125</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw37638900"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of time domain reflectometry to monitor water content and electrical conductivity of saline soil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Entus, Jonathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Effective management of saline soils requires rapid, reliable methods of monitoring both soil water content (theta) and salt concentration, the latter measured in terms of electrical conductivity (sigma). This thesis examines estimation of theta, and bulk soil sigma (sigmaa) and soil water sigma (sigmaw), using time domain reflectometry (TDR). Calibration experiments were conducted in soil columns and in a vineyard that were irrigated with saline water. Within a theta range of 0.025--0.490 m3/m3, the correlation between TDR theta (thetaTDR) and gravimetrically determined theta (theta g) was high (r2 = 0.979 in soil columns, r2 = 0.836 in the field). The error of estimate of thetaTDR was 0.020 m3/m3 or less. Field thetaTDR estimates were sensitive to high salinity (sigmaw &gt; 10 dS/m). Using a dual pathway parallel conductance (DPPC) model, sigma a was derived from sigmaw of saturated paste extracts and theta g. The correlation of TDR sigmaa to DPPC sigmaa was good in the laboratory (r2 = 0.915), and moderate in the field (r2 = 0.791), indicating a functional relationship between sigmaw and theta and TDR sigmaa. Models, to estimate sigmaw, were built by regression between paste extract sigma w and TDR sigmaa and thetaTDR. In a sigma w range of 3.0--23.4 dS/m in the columns, error of estimate of sigma w was small at 1.50 dS/m (+/-12.4% relative error range). In a sigma w range of 2.2--25.2 dS/m in the field, error of estimate of sigma w was 3.37 dS/m (+/-37% relative error range), which was significantly higher than the acceptable error range of +/-10%. ANOVA tests indicated that both TDR sigmaa and sigmaw·theta changed significantly with respect to the same sources of variance. Error in field estimates of sigmaw was associated with effects of salinity on thetaTDR and variability of soil conditions, particularly with respect to depth and time of sampling.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bonnell, Robert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db81w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37638900</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soils, Salts in -- Measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil moisture -- Measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Time-domain reflectometry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tr17q"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behavioral charqacterization of apolipoprotein e-knockout mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dupuy, Jean-Bernard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Apolipoprotein E-knockout (apoEKO) mice were characterized behaviorally to evaluate the impact of apolipoprotein E deficiency on spatial learning and memory function at different ages. Wild type and knockout mice were tested in two tasks assessing spatial memory function, Morris water maze (MWM) and Radial arm maze (RAM). Both young and aged apoEKO mice backcrossed six generations displayed deficits in the MWM. However, young and aged 10th generation apoEKO mice did not display any deficits in the MWM or the RAM when spatial cues that could be used to solve these tasks were provided. Removal of spatial cues after training had occurred also did not result in an impairment. In contrast, apoEKO mice were impaired when spatial cues were removed from the beginning of training. This result suggests that these mice are less able to utilize non-spatial cues to solve these tasks. The impairments observed in the MWM and RAM were not the result of impaired reference memory function, but rather appeared to arise from a dysfunction in working memory. Additional tests assessing sensorimotor gating function (Prepulse inhibition), and emotionality (the Open field, the Elevated plus maze) suggested that these cognitive deficits did not arise from alterations in sensorimotor gating function or emotionality, as both young and aged apoEKO mice performed at levels similar to those observed in their aged C57BL/6J control groups.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Poirier, Judes</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rochford, Joseph</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx36v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr17q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Experimental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, Behavioral</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z278t"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shelf-life and safety studies on rainbow trout fillets packaged under modified atmospheres</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dufresne, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The combined effect of various gas packaging atmospheres (air, vacuum and gas packaging), films of different oxygen transmission rate (OTR) and storage temperature (4 and 12°C) were investigated on the shelf-life and safety of flesh rainbow trout fillets. Preliminary studies were done to determine the optimum packaging atmospheres to maintain the bright pink color of trout packaged in a high gas barrier film. Both vacuum and gas packaging (85% CO2:15%N2) resulted in the longest shelf-life (~28 days) in terms of color at 4°C. Based on these optimum gas atmospheres for color, shelf-life studies were performed at both refrigerated and temperature abuse conditions (12°C). Challenges studies were also done with Listeria monocytogenes and Clostridium botulinum type E, two psychrotrophic pathogens of concern in modified atmosphere packaged (MAP) fish. Subsequent studies were done to determine the effect of various levels of headspace oxygen (0--100%, balance CO2) or film OTR on the time to toxicity in trout stored at 12°C. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, James P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c71j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z278t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fish fillets -- Packaging</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fish fillets -- Preservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protective atmospheres</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z277j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Craig-Sakamoto Theorem</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dumais, Mylène Fanny</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis reviews the works that most influenced the progress and the development of the Craig-Sakamoto Theorem. This important theorem characterizes the independence of two quadratic forms in normal variables. We begin with a detailed and possibly complete outline of the history of this theorem, as well as several (correct) proofs published over the years. Furthermore, some misleading (or incorrect) proofs are reviewed and their lacunae explained. We conclude with a comprehensive bibliography on the Craig-Sakamoto Theorem; some associated references are also included.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Styan, George P. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v042j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z277j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw9505227q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of proinflammatory agents on oxygen species production by bovine mammary epithelial and immune cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boulanger, Véronique</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate which type(s) of somatic cells release nitric oxide (NO) in response to Escherichia coli lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and cytokines in vitro and how NO affects superoxide anion (O2-) production by bovine neutrophils and blood monocytes. Mammary epithelial cell line (FbE) released NO after stimulation with recombinant bovine interleukin-1beta (rBoIL-1beta). Moreover, monocytes produced NO in response to recombinant bovine interferon gamma (rBoIFN-gamma) alone or in combination with LPS in a dose- and time-dependent manner. Nitric oxide production was diminished by addition of inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) inhibitors L-N 6-(1-Iminiethyl)lysine or aminoguanidine. However, NO release could not be induced in freshly isolated bovine neutrophils under the experimental conditions used, even after 96 h of incubation. Interestingly, when reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) with specific primers for iNOS was performed to study mRNA expression, iNOS expression was observed in both monocytes and neutrophils in response to LPS and rBoIFN-gamma. Unlike neutrophils, monocytes were poor producers of superoxide anion under the experimental conditions. A neutrophil-monocyte co-culture system was set up to study the effect of monocyte derived-NO and iNOS inhibitors on superoxide anion production by neutrophils. Neither NO derived from activated monocytes nor iNOS inhibitors seemed to have an effect on bovine neutrophil ability to release O2-. These results suggest that mammary epithelial cells and mononuclear phagocytes are among the cell types responsible for the important quantities of NO released by somatic cells recovered from LPS-infused mammary quarters during endotoxin-induced bovine mastitis. In addition, NO or iNOS inhibitors have no effect on the ability of activated bovine neutrophils to produce superoxide anions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zhao, Xin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c14g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505227q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Endotoxins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neutrophils -- Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitric oxide -- Pathophysiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interferon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mastitis -- Immunological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97ks34f"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of a BAP31 complex</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyer, Lee Christian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Apoptosis is a genetically predetermined cell death program common to multicellular organisms. Bcl-2/BclXL function to suppress apoptosis and promote survival by inhibiting the death pathway at key points. One key point of the death pathway involves the activation of the caspases which are proteolytic enzymes that systematically degrade the cell. Recently, studies have shown that Bap31 is a polytopic integral membrane protein of the ER which forms a complex with Bcl-2/BclXL, a CED-4-like-adaptor-molecule, and initiator procaspase-8. This suggests that the Bap31 complex may regulate apoptosis by bridging core components of the cell death machinery at the ER. In order to further our understanding of the Bap31 complex in vivo we have isolated it from human KB cells that stably express recombinant forms of Bap31. Bap31 localized to the ER fraction of rat liver cells, and analysis by cryo-immuno-cytochemistry using electron microscope confirmed that Bap31 primarily resides in the ER. Following an adenovirus E1A death signal, the Bap31 complex does not change in size as judged by size exclusion chromatography. Immunoprecipitation of the chromatography isolated complex showed that it consisted primarily of a Bap31 oligomer.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Shove, Gordon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb447.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks34f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26z028g"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Group processes and the perception of discrimination</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bougie, Evelyne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis describes a group-oriented program of research designed to investigate the experience of victims of discrimination. Ninety female college students were tested in small groups and confronted with the possibility of their having been discriminated against by a male student on a test. Women assessed the extent to which the received feedback was due to discrimination or their answers on the test, prior to and following a group discussion. Results indicated that contrary to previous research in which women consistently minimised discrimination as a reason for group-based negative feedback, women in the present experiment were willing to acknowledge discrimination. Results are interpreted in terms of the influence of social sharing of emotional and informational support with ingroup members after receiving feedback where discrimination might be implied. The thesis emphasizes the importance of social networks for disadvantaged group members who need to cope with the possibility of being targets for discrimination.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Taylor, Donald M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k16j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z028g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sex discrimination against women</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hb60w"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Polymorphisms in the promoter region of the dopamine transporter : a candidate locus for alcohol abuse</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bradley, Shannon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The dopamine transporter, the principle binding site for such drugs of abuse as cocaine and amphetamines, has a critical role in limiting dopamine availability. Several lines of evidence, including variation of DAT density in human alcoholics and in vervet monkeys with a preference for alcohol, have implicated this locus as a candidate gene, which might increase vulnerability to alcoholism. The objective of this study was to identify polymorphisms in the regulatory region of the dopamine transporter and determine whether there was an association between any of the alleles and alcoholism. Five polymorphisms were identified: three in humans and two in vervet monkey subjects. Mutation analysis of this locus may be a critical step in identifying alleles which increase susceptibility to alcohol abuse in humans and vervet monkeys.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Palmour, Roberta M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333426d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb60w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Carrier proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dopamine -- Physiological transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alcoholism -- Genetic aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f783z"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The gifts of the chip? : the regulation of occupational health and safety in the post-industrial age</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Savarese, Josephine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the face of the extensive changes resulting from the Post-Industrial Age, many are questioning "the gifts of the chip," or, more specifically, the ability of computer technologies to deliver the comfort predicted. The objective of this thesis is to examine the law's response to computer technology concerning occupational health and safety. This inquiry is necessary due to the dramatic changes that have occurred in the workforce, altering the profile of workplace health. The thesis begins with a reference to The Gift of Stones, a fictional account of the difficulties that stone workers experienced when the Bronze Age arrived. Modern labourers face parallel struggles due to the arrival of the Post-Industrial Age characterized by technological innovation and restructuring. The legitimacy and effectiveness of occupational health and safety law is challenged by changes to social institutions and by computer related work injuries. In many jurisdictions, the state has responded to these changes by enacting ergonomic standards that seek to minimize the harmful effects of computer use. The thesis examines the trend towards ergonomic standards with particular focus on Canadian initiatives. In conclusion, it argues that ergonomic regulations are an important means of promoting safer computer practices. Additionally, ergonomic standards provide a mechanism for continued state regulation of occupational health and safety. The challenge for rule makers is ensuring that the standards are a component of comprehensive legal reforms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sheppard, Colleen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db825.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f783z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Industrial safety -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Employees -- Effect of technological innovations on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Technology -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Human engineering -- Government policy</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>