<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp64r"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of an artificially intuitive reasoner</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sun, Yung Chien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude se penche sur le phénomène de "l'intuition" dans le contexte de l'intelligence artificielle (IA). Dans cette étude, l'intuition fut considérée comme la capacité de l'être humain à en venir à une décision lorsqu'une situation se présente où les informations disponibles sont majoritairement de pauvre qualité: irrégulières et d'un niveau de certitude variable. Cette étude visa la caractérisation de certains aspects de la pensée intuitive de l'être humain et la modélisation de ces aspects par une démarche computationnelle. Cette étude nécessita le développement d'un cadre conceptuel, et, basé sur celui-ci un système informatisé à trois volets: (1) un module fonctionnant par induction de règles servant à établir le base de connaissances du raisonneur; (2) le raisonneur intuitif, moteur essentiel d'un système d'inférences basé sur des règles; (3) deux démarches d'apprentissage permettant une mise à jour continuelle de la base de connaissances, permettant au raisonneur d'en venir à de meilleures prédictions. Afin de servir comme point de référence dans l'évaluation du raisonneur intuitif, un raisonneur de référence employant des méthodes d'analyse de données conventionnelles fut bâti. Nous permîmes aux données d'entrée et aux règles formulées par le raisonneur d'être floues, multivaluées et de différents niveaux de certitude. Un barème du niveau de certitude, le Niveau de Confiance, fut attribué à chaque donnée d'entrée, ainsi qu'à chaque règle. Les règles induites par le raisonneur intuitif ne furent basées que sur le dixième des données disponibles au raisonneur de référence. Les solutions furent formulées à travers plusieurs itérations de consolidation des résultats de raisonnements intermédiaires, durant lesquels le Niveau de Confiance de résultats intermédiaires corroborants furent combinés. Le raisonneur intuitif et le raisonneur de référence furent éprouvés en leur demandant de prédire la valeur (classe) de 12 variables-cibles choisies par l'auteur, dont six continues et six discrètes. Le raisonneur intuitif développé dans cette étude égala la performance du raisonneur de référence pour deux des six variables-cibles continues, et atteigna au moins 70% de la précision du raisonneur de référence pour les six variables-cibles discrètes. Ces résultats indiquent que le raisonneur intuitif fut capable d'induire des règles à partir d'une base de données plutôt limitée, et de fournir des prédictions raisonnablement précises grâce à ces règles. Cela indique qu'en consolidant plusieurs résultats de règles de basse certitude, un raisonneur "intuitif" peut devenir un outil de prédiction efficace ou servir adéquatement à compléter d'autres tâches computationnelles,  à partir de données incomplètes de qualité variable.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This research is an exploration of the phenomenon of "intuition" in the context of artificial intelligence (AI). In this work, intuition was considered as the human capacity to make decisions under situations in which the available knowledge was usually low in quality: inconsistent and of varying levels of certainty. The objectives of this study were to characterize some of the aspects of human intuitive thought and to model these aspects in a computational approach. This project entailed the development of a conceptual framework and a conceptual model, and, based on these, a computer system with three general parts: (1) a rule induction module for establishing the knowledge base for the reasoner; (2) the intuitive reasoner that was essentially a rule-based inference engine; (3) two learning approaches that could update the knowledge base over time for the reasoner to make better predictions. A reference reasoner based on established data analysis methods was also constructed, as a bench-mark for evaluating the intuitive reasoner. The input and the rules drawn by the reasoner were allowed to be fuzzy, multi-valued, and of varying levels of certainty. A measure of the certainty level, Strength of Belief, was attached to each input as well as each rule. Rules for the intuitive reasoner were induced from only about 10% of the data available for the reference reasoner. Solutions were formulated through iterations of consolidating intermediate reasoning results, during which the Strength of Belief of corroborating intermediate results was combined. The intuitive and the reference reasoners were tested to predict the value (class) of 12 target variables chosen by the author, of which six were continuous variables and the other six were discrete variables. The intuitive reasoner developed in this study matched the performance of the reference reasoner for three of six continuous target variables and achieved at least 70% of the accuracy of the reference reasoner for all six discrete target variables. The results showed that the intuitive reasoner was able to induce rules from a sparse database and use those rules to make accurate predictions. This suggested that by consolidating numerous outputs from low-certainty rules, an "intuitive" reasoner can effectively perform prediction, or other computational tasks, on the basis of incomplete information of varying quality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grant Clark</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w275v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp64r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Artificial Intelligence</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nb66k"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Cyberscript Project: a mixed method study of pre-service ESL teachers' corrective feedback beliefs and practices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Guenette, Daniele</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Inspirée par la controverse sur les effets de la rétroaction corrective sur l'acquisition de la langue seconde, ainsi que le rôle des croyances dans le développement de la cognition des enseignants, cette étude fondée sur des méthodes mixtes examine les pratiques de rétroaction corrective de futurs enseignants d'anglais langue seconde (i.e., les mentors), jumelés avec des élèves du secondaire.  L'objectif principal était de recenser les stratégies et techniques de rétroaction corrective à l'écrit utilisées par les futurs enseignants, et d'établir une corrélation entre ces stratégies et les catégories d'erreurs commises par les apprenants.  Dans ce but, la correspondance par courriel échangée par les mentors et les apprenants durant tout un trimestre a été analysée. Le second objectif était d'examiner dans quelle mesure les pratiques de rétroaction corrective des mentors correspondaient à leurs croyances à cet égard.  Afin d'obtenir une interprétation plus poussée des résultats des analyses quantitatives, des données qualitatives ont été recueillies (questionnaires sur les croyances, journaux de bord, entrevues semi-dirigées), afin de mesurer la congruence des pratiques des mentors et leurs perceptions de ces pratiques, en lien avec leurs croyances au sujet de la rétroaction corrective. Des statistiques descriptives et inférentielles ont révélé une prépondérance significative de corrections directes de la part de tous les mentors,  ainsi qu'une constance dans ces pratiques, indépendamment des catégories d'erreurs commises par les apprenants.  Par contre, les analyses ont également mis au jour une grande variance dans le processus de prise de décision des mentors, ainsi que des contradictions entre leurs pratiques et les croyances exprimées.  Conformément aux résultats des recherches en cognition des enseignants, cette étude a révélé des tensions qui proviennent d'un écart entre la théorie et la pratique, et a démontré que la conscience des croyances n'a pas nécessairement de répercussion sur les pratiques, particulièrement lorsque ces croyances sont en contradiction avec les impératifs pédagogiques de la classe de langue seconde.  Cette étude illustre les nombreux facteurs qui influent sur les pratiques de rétroaction corrective des enseignants et, en conclusion, propose des avenues pour la recherche future et pour la formation des enseignants de langue seconde.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Prompted by the controversy regarding the effects of corrective feedback (CF) on second language (L2) acquisition, as well as the role of beliefs in teacher cognition, this mixed method study examines the CF practices of a group of pre-service ESL teachers (i.e., mentors) paired with high school learners.  The primary objectives were to investigate which strategies and techniques pre-service ESL teachers use when providing CF on writing, as well as the correlation between the strategies adopted by the pre-service ESL teachers and the categories of error made by the learners.  To this end, the email correspondence exchanged between the mentors and learners over a school semester was examined. The secondary goal of this study was to investigate whether the CF practices of mentors corroborated their beliefs in this regard.  To explore these issues, data in the form of questionnaires on beliefs, journals and semi-structured guided interviews were collected throughout the project to establish the congruence of mentors' actions and perceptions of their actions with their beliefs about CF, and provide a finer-grained interpretation of the quantitative data collected through the correspondence. Descriptive and inferential statistics revealed that, similar to the findings of research on teacher feedback, the mentors, as a group, used direct corrections significantly more than other feedback strategies and that this correction pattern was constant irrespective of the error categories.  However, great variability in the mentors' decision-making process regarding CF, as well as discrepancies between expressed beliefs and practices, were also apparent.  Consistent with research on teacher cognition, this study revealed tensions resulting from a clash between theory and practice, and showed that an awareness of beliefs does not necessarily have an impact on CF practices, especially when beliefs cannot be reconciled with the pedagogical imperatives of the classroom. The study discusses the myriad of factors that influence the teachers' CF practices, and concludes with implications for future research and suggestions for second language L2 teacher training programs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roy Lyster</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257f56z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nb66k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Language and Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741s25d"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessing the relationship between propagule pressure and probability of establishment for the aquatic invader «Bythotrephes longimanus» using two complementary approaches</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gertzen, Erin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'estimation de la probabilité d'établissement d'espèces invasives est un élément important pour la gestion de leur dispersion. Dans cette thèse, je présente deux approches pour estimer la probabilité d'établissement de Bythotrephes longimanus, un cladocère prédateur qui se disperse à travers des lacs en Ontario et des états Américains avoisinants. D'abord, je développe un modèle basé sur les procédés pour évaluer la probabilité d'établissement de B. longimanus au fil du temps dans un bassin versant. J'emploie des métriques de pression de propagules en provenance de disséminations anthropiques et naturelles afin d'estimer leur dispersion, et j'étends le modèle pour incorporer le manque de certaines informations spatiales et temporelles concernant l'état d'invasion des lacs. Mes résultats indiquent que la circulation de bateaux de plaisance est le vecteur dominant de dispersion et que la majorité du risque d'invasion des lacs est dû à plusieurs points statiques d'invasion - les cinq lacs les plus grands du système. J'étudie ensuite la probabilité d'établissement empiriquement. Je mène une expérience contrôlée afin de suivre des populations récemment introduites de B. longimanus au cours de leur cycle de vie et je cherche des facteurs liées a la dynamique du début d'invasion qui pourraient affecter la façon dont laquelle les pressions de propagules et le succès d'établissement sont reliés. Ceci inclut la stochasticité démographique et environnementale, des opportunités saisonnières où l'établissement est possible, ainsi que la diminution des opportunités et les effets Allee pendant la reproduction sexuelle. Mes résultats suggèrent que l'établissement de B. longimanus est limité aux effets Allee ou aux diminutions d'opportunités pendant reproduction sexuelle pour les populations introduites en doses bases et que les effets Allee se renforcent pendant l'automne. De plus, la probabilité d'établissement est re</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Estimating the probability of establishment of non-indigenous species is a crucial element in managing their spread. In this thesis, I use two approaches to estimate the probability of establishment of Bythotrephes longimanus, a predatory cladoceran that is invading lakes in Ontario and the surrounding American states. At a watershed level, I develop a vector based model to predict the probability of establishment of B. longimanus over time. I use metrics of propagule pressure from anthropogenic and natural dispersal to estimate spread, and extend the model to incorporate spatial and temporal gaps in knowledge of the invasion status of lakes. I found that recreational boating traffic is the dominant vector of spread and that most risk to lakes is due to static hubs of invasion - the five largest lakes in the watershed. Next, at the scale of a local population introduction, I investigate probability of establishment empirically. I follow B. longimanus populations over their entire life cycle and look for evidence of early invasion dynamics that may affect establishment, including Allee effects, demographic and environmental stochasticity, windows of opportunity and bottlenecks during sexual reproduction. I found that populations introduced at low doses exhibit weak Allee effects during sexual reproduction and that these effects strengthen over the season. Further, probability of establishment is positively related to propagule pressure; however, the relation is highly stochastic. The insights obtained on the characteristics of the relation between propagule pressure and probability of establishment at population and watershed scales can be linked in management plans aimed at slowing the spread of B. longimanus in inland lakes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brian Leung</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d266.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s25d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azp38wd16m"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Economic and environmental impacts of trade liberalization: the case of Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gumilang, Howard Putra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Au cours des dernières années, la pression publique a attisé l'intérêt concernant l'impact environnemental découlant de la libéralisation des marchés. Malheureusement, les études se penchant sur ce sujet ne sont pas encore arrivé à un consensus. Cette recherche a pour objectif d'augmenter la compréhension dans ce domaine de recherche par l'utilisation d'une étude de cas basée sur l'Indonésie et de sa participation dans le traité de libre échange avec le Japon (IJEPA) et celui de l'Association des Nations du Sud-Est Asiatique (AFTA). L'étude de cas utilise un modèle monétaire d'équilibre général, multisectoriel et intertemporel, connu sous le nom anglais de Global Trade Analysis Project (GTAP), pour évaluer l'impact environnemental de la croissance et de la libéralisation des marchés. Les prévisions pour l'économie Indonésienne jusqu'en 2022 indique une croissance importante pendant cette période. Cependant, en comparant le scénario d'ouverture des marchés avec celui sans ouverture des marchés, la participation de l'Indonésie dans cet accord de libre échange indique un faible impact sur la production  industrielle de l'Indonésie. Malgré peu d'effet sur la production, une augmentation significative des échanges et une modification du type d'échanges se produit. En 2022, le modèle prédit une détérioration de l'environnement du pays causée par une croissance de la production. Une comparaison avec le statu quo indique que la libéralisation des marchés n'a qu'un effet négligeable sur l'environnement. En général, la pollution atmosphérique augmente alors que la pollution de l'eau diminue suite à la réforme des tarifs douaniers. En conclusion, l'étude suggère que la participation de l'Indonésie dans les accords de l'AFTA et l'IJEPA ne génère pas de changements drastiques dans les performances économiques et environnementales du pays.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>In recent years, there has been a growing interest in the environmental impacts of trade liberalization given the rising environmental awareness of the general public. Unfortunately, existing studies have yet to arrive at a consensus in this area. This thesis provides further discourse in this area with a case study of Indonesia and its participation in free trade agreement with Japan (IJEPA) and ASEAN (AFTA). A static global CGE model, known as Global Trade Analysis Project (GTAP) was used to assess the economic and environmental impacts of growth and trade liberalization. Projection of the Indonesian economy to the year 2022 suggested that it will grow rapidly over this period. Comparison of trade liberalization scenarios with a counterfactual base, however, indicates that Indonesia's participation in these trade agreements will only have a marginal positive impact on Indonesia's industrial output. Nevertheless, it did result in a noticeable increase in trade flows and there were signs of trade diversion occurring. In 2022, it was projected that Indonesia will see a large deterioration in its environment due to the growth in output. Counter factual analysis of trade liberalizations indicated that it has only a marginal environmental impact. Generally, air pollution emissions increased while water pollution decreased following tariff reforms. In conclusion, the study suggests that Indonesia's participation in the AFTA and IJEPA agreements are not likely to bring drastic changes to her economic and environmental performance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Thomassin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc313.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wd16m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82k770n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Skeletal distribution of bisphosphonate after elution from porous implants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McKenzie, Kimberly</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'attachement squelettique à un implant peut être amélioré en apportant de l'acide zoledronique de bisphosphonate de façon locale depuis l'implant. Le but de la présente étude était d'évaluer la distribution squelettique de l'acide zoledronique localement généré. Un implant poreux de tantale enduit d'hydroxyapatite et d'acide 14C zoledronique a été implanté dans le fémur gauche de trois chiens. Après un an, plusieurs échantillons d'os, proches et éloignés de l'implant, ont été prélevés. La quantité de médicament dans chaque échantillon a ensuite été déterminée en utilisant un comptage par scintillation liquide; la distribution dans l'os autour de l'implant a aussi été demontré par autoradiographie. Tous les échantillons prélevés loin de l'implant contenaient 11.8 ng/g d'acide zoledronique ou moins alors que ceux prélevés immédiatement à côté de l'implant  contenaient 388 ng/g. Une diminution de 10 à 100 fois dans la teneur en acide zoledronique a été notée dans l'os situé seulement à 1 ou 2 cm de l'implant.  Les autoradiographies des sections minces d'os-implant et des sections d'os ont indiqué que la concentration la plus élevée en acide zoledronique se situait dans l'implant et immédiatement à côté. Ces données démontrent, pour la première fois, que l'acide zoledronique élué d'un implant reste principalement local, avec une distribution systémique minimale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Skeletal attachment to an implant can be enhanced by locally delivering the bisphosphonate zoledronic acid from an implant. The purpose of this study was to map the skeletal distribution of locally delivered zoledronic acid. A porous tantalum implant coated with hydroxyapatite and 14C-labelled zoledronic acid was implanted into the left femur of three dogs. After one year bone samples were taken from sites near to and distant from the implant. The amount of drug in each sample was determined using liquid scintillation counting and its distribution in peri-implant bone was additionally demonstrated using autoradiography. All distant skeletal bone samples contained 11.8 ng/g zoledronic acid or less whereas bone immediately adjacent to the implant contained 388 ng/g. There was a 10-fold to 100-fold decrease in zoledronic acid content in bone just 1 or 2 cm away from the implant. Autoradiographs of thin bone-implant sections and bone sections revealed the highest concentration of zoledronic acid within and immediately adjacent to the implant. These data demonstrated for the first time that zoledronic acid eluted from an implant remained mainly local, with minimal systemic distribution.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>John Dennis Bobyn</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032353h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k770n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g798k"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Emergency department conditions associated with the number of patients who leave a pediatric emergency department prior to physician assessment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stang, Antonia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Avec l'augmentation du débit et du temps d'attente dans les services des urgences, un nombre élevé de patients ayant rempli les formulaires d'accueil quittent avant d'avoir été vus par un médecin. Cette étude avait pour but de déterminer les conditions du service des urgences reflétant l'inscription, le temps de prise en charge ainsi que le débit de patients, et ayant un lien avec le nombre de personnes qui, dans un milieu pédiatrique, quittent avant d'avoir vu un médecin. Une analyse multivariée a été utilisée afin d'examiner l'effet de variables décrivant le moment de l'arrivée du patient et les conditions qui prévalent au service des urgences (y compris l'acuité des patients, le volume de patients et le délai d'attente), sur le nombre de personnes qui quittent sans avoir été examinés.  Un total de 138,361 patients se sont présentés à l'urgence au cours de l'étude et 11,055 (7,99%) ont quitté avant d'avoir vu un médecin.  Les résultats de l'étude révèlent que les variables liées au temps de prise en charge, soit le délai entre le moment du triage et l'examen du médecin (ratio des taux = 2,11; intervalle de confiance [IC] de 95% : 2,01 - 2,21) et le délai entre l'inscription et le triage (ratio des taux = 1,55; IC de 95% : 1,25 - 1,90) exercent la plus grande influence sur le nombre de patients quittant avant d'avoir été vus par un médecin.  Les interventions visant à réduire le nombre de départs prématurés devraient être orientées en vue d'améliorer le temps de prise en charge dans les services d'urgence.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>As emergency department (ED) waiting times and volumes increase, substantial numbers of patients LWBS (leave after registration but prior to physician assessment). The objective of this study was to identify ED conditions reflecting patient input, throughput and output associated with the number of patients who LWBS in a pediatric setting. Multivariate analysis was used to examine the impact of variables describing the timing of patient arrival and ED conditions including patient acuity, volume and waiting times on the number of patients who LWBS.  During the study period there were 138,361 patient visits; 11,055 (7.99%) of patients LWBS.  The throughput variables, time from triage to physician assessment (rate ratio 2.11 (95% CI 2.01-2.21)) and time from registration to triage (rate ratio 1.55 (95% CI 1.25 - 1.90)) had the largest impact on the number of patients who LWBS.  Interventions designed to decrease the number of patients who LWBS should focus on improving ED throughput.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Antonio Ciampi</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jane McCusker</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx40r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g798k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r3602"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Risk, compensatory, protective, and vulnerability processes influencing youth gambling problems and other high-risk behaviours</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lussier, Isabelle D</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores the impact of individual attributes and environmental risk on youth gambling, substance, and deviant behaviour problems. With a cross-sectional design, regression analyses indicated that among a sample of mostly first-generation immigrant adolescents from low-income homes, social bonding was associated with a decrease in severity for all three problem behaviours, while peer and neighbourhood risk were associated with an increase in severity for all three behaviours. As well, personal competence was associated with a decrease in deviant behaviour only, while family risk was associated with an increase in both substance problem and deviant behaviour severity. Interestingly, social competence was associated with an increase in substance problems and deviant behaviour. In terms of protective processes, a putative moderating effect was found for composite individual attributes on the relationship between composite environmental risk and deviant behaviour. Findings are discussed with respect to the roles of compensatory, risk, and protective processes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse examine l'impact des attributs individuels et des facteurs de risque environnementaux sur les problèmes de jeux de hasard et d'argent, de consommation et de délinquance chez les jeunes.  Dans le cadre de cette étude transversale, des analyses de régression, effectuées sur un échantillon composé en majorité d'adolescents immigrants de première génération et provenant de milieux défavorisés, ont démontré que les liens sociaux étaient associés à une diminution de la sévérité des problèmes; alors que les facteurs de risque reliés aux pairs et à la communauté étaient associés à une augmentation de la sévérité des problèmes.  De plus, les aptitudes personnelles étaient associées à une diminution de la délinquance seulement, alors que les facteurs de risque familiaux étaient associés à une augmentation des problèmes de consommation et de délinquance.  Il fut intéressant d'observer que les aptitudes sociales étaient associées à une augmentation des problèmes de consommation et de délinquance.  En ce qui concerne les facteurs de protection, il a été démontré que les attributs individuels ont un effet de modération putatif sur la relation entre les facteurs de risque environnementaux et la délinquance.  Les résultats sont interprétés en termes du rôle des facteurs compensatoires, de risque et de protection.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jeffrey L. Derevensky</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rina Gupta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zn88c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r3602</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Developmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579s70n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Un chapitre retrouvé des mémoires de l'abbé de Choisy l'écriture autobiographique : étude stylistique des trois manuscrits du «Temps qui m'a manqué» de Gabrielle Roy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Markovic, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le texte de création présenté ici propose un pastiche de François Timoléon de Choisy, mémorialiste et historien de l'Église du XVIIe siècle, qui a laissé le récit de ses intrigues en travesti, sous le titre de Mémoires de l'abbé de Choisy habillé en femme. Notre pastiche constitue un épisode «retrouvé» de ses aventures, auquel il se réfère dans ses Mémoires. La réflexion critique porte sur les trois versions du manuscrit du Temps qui m'a manqué de Gabrielle Roy. Cet ultime fragment autobiographique de la romancière canadienne fait l'objet d'une étude stylistique et génétique à partir de l'analyse des variations et des passages restés intacts d'un manuscrit à l'autre. Dans un cas comme dans l'autre, l'exploration des styles de ces deux auteurs constitue une tentative de répondre à une question que nous pose notre propre pratique d'écrivain : comment convertir en fiction vraisemblable une réalité qui ne l'est pas toujours ?</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The creative writing portion of this thesis is a pastiche of the writings of 17th century memorialist and historian François Timoléon de Choisy. The cross-dressing adventures he lived as a young man were published as the Mémoires de l'abbé de Choisy habillé en femme and the pastiche presented here constitutes a "lost" chapter that recounts an episode referred to in the Mémoires. The critical aspect of this thesis concerns the three versions of Gabrielle Roy's last manuscript: Le temps qui m'a manqué. The Canadian novelist's last autobiographic text is analysed from both a stylistic and a genetic perspective and considers the variations from one manuscript to the next as well as those passages left unchanged. In both cases, the exploration of the authors' individual styles is an attempt to answer a question integral to our own writing practice: how does one create credible fiction from realities that are not always believable?</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frederic Charbonneau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Francois Ricard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j65p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579s70n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tm42g"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Motif discovery algorithms incorporating nucleosome positioning information</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sayad-Rahim, Azin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Transcription factor binding sites are essential components of the machinery that controls gene expression. In the absence of experimental data, computational approaches are used to predict binding sites based on promoter DNA sequence. However transcription factor binding depends not just on sequence but also the packaging of the DNA molecule. Nucleosomes, as the smallest unit of DNA packaging, affect transcription factor binding by obstructing protein-DNA interactions. We use an empirically-derived relationship between binding sites and nucleosome positioning to augment an existing computational approach to predicting transcription factor binding sites. We demonstrate that the inclusion of experimentally-derived nucleosome positioning data improves the prediction capabilities of the basic computational approach using a large dataset of experimentally confirmed transcription factor binding sites.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les sites de liaison de facteurs de transcription sont des composants essentiels du méchanisme de contrôle de l'expression génique. En l'absence de données expérimentales, les approches informatiques sont utilisées pour prédire les sites de liaison basée sur la séquence d'ADN promoteur. Toutefois la liaison de facteurs de transcription dépend non seulement de la séquence mais également de l'emballage biologique de la molécule d'ADN. Les nucléosomes, en tant qu'unité d'emballage de base de l'ADN, ont un effet marqué sur le positionnement des sites de liaison de facteurs de transcription. Nous dérivons une relation empirique entre les sites de liaison et le positionnement des nucléosomes pour améliorer un algorithme de prédiction de sites de liaison. Nous démontrons que l'inclusion de données de positionnement de nucléosome améliore la performance de l'algorithme de base en utilisant un ensemble de données de sites de liaison confirmé expérimentalement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mathieu Blanchette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763729k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm42g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rp173"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shared values, different paths : first-generation Iranian men's and women's perceptions of the cultural production of an "educated person"</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sadeghi, Shiva</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this dissertation, I examined the lived experiences of eight  first-generation Iranian immigrants (six women and two men) enrolled as full-time  undergraduate students in predominantly English institutions of higher education in  Montreal. Using the key principles of phenomenology and critical ethnography, and  through a series of open-ended, in-depth interviews, I explored the situated  meanings of education in the lives of these men and women. The findings of my study  show that the participants' perceptions of higher education seemed to be greatly  influenced by their cultural values and beliefs. They perceived "education'' as  social and cultural capital which secures their status and prestige within their  families and communities. They also identified economic advancement, upward social  mobility, personal fulfillment and easier access to Canadian higher education as  factors that significantly influenced their decisions to pursue their undergraduate  degrees. The study revealed that the women emphasized the crucial role of education  in securing their financial and intellectual independence from the men in the  household. They held the belief that being an "educated woman" contributed  to having a stronger voice and a more authoritative space within the  family. The results of my study suggest that the voices of these men and  women were linked to the issues of "agency", "critical  thinking", and "belonging". The participants talked about their lives  as "immigrants" and members of a marginalized minority group. While some  openly talked about the existence of "covert" or "hidden" racism  in Canadian society, they all expressed contentment with their lives in Canada when  compared to Iran. They articulated their awareness of the conflicting concepts of  gender roles existent in the traditional Iranian culture and the culture of the host  country, and viewed western values of women's education and career development as a  positive factor in pursuing their academic aspirations. Highlighting the significance of individual narratives and lived  experiences of first-generation immigrant students, this study may contribute to  broadening our understanding of issues faced by immigrant students in institutions  of higher education. Furthermore, the insights from the lives of these men and women  may have important implications for educators, administrators, and faculty staff in  order to create more accepting and culturally sensitive campuses.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb313.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp173</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Immigrants -- Education -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iranian Canadians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education -- Iran</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246s54s"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Plasticity of the basal forebrain cholinergic system in rats with neonatal lesions of the ventral hippocampus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laplante, François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Excitotoxic neonatal lesion of the ventral hippocampus (NVH) in  rats has been proposed as a putative neurodevelopmental animal model of  schizophrenia, with characteristic post-pubertal behavioral and neurochemical  abnormalities comparable to those observed in this disease including alterations in  dopaminergic (DA) neurotransmission and prefrontal cortical functions. Dysfunctions  in the mesocorticolimbic DA system are believed to contribute to some of the  behavioural manifestations of schizophrenia. Accumulating evidence also suggests  that alterations in the activity of cortical cholinergic neurotransmission may be  involved in the cognitive abnormalities seen in major neuropsychiatric disorders.  These two neurotransmitter systems are functionally interlinked as the  mesocorticolimbic dopaminergic system stimulates acetylcholine (ACh) release in the  prefrontal cortex (PFC) mainly through the activation of D 1-like receptors. Given  the involvement of the PFC and DA abnormalities in NVH lesioned animals and evidence  of cholinergic abnormalities in schizophrenia, the purpose of the present thesis was  to investigate the status of cholinergic system in pre and post-pubertal NVH  lesioned animals, and its regulation by DA. In vivo microdialysis studies revealed that PFC ACh release was  increased to a greater extent in response to the systemic injection of the D1-like  agonist SKF 81297 in post-pubertal NVH lesioned rats compared to sham control rats.  Furthermore, intra-cortical administration of SKF 81297 increased PFC ACh release in  post-pubertal NVH lesioned rats but not in sham animals. Interestingly, tail pinch  stress, which activates mesocorticolimbic DA neurotransmission, also increased PFC  ACh release to a greater extent in post-pubertal NVH lesioned rats. This increase  was normalised by D1 or D2-like antagonists. Quantitative receptor autoradiographic  studies revealed increases in M1 and M2-like muscarinic receptor levels in some  limbic and PFC regions in post-pubertal NVH lesioned rats. These increases were  associated with enhanced physiological responses to the muscarinic receptor agonist,  oxotremorine. Finally, the muscarinic receptor antagonist biperiden normalized  deficits in prepulse inhibition of the acoustic startle in post-pubertal NVH  lesioned rats. Taken together, these data reveal the developmental alterations of  cholinergic neurotransmission and its regulation by DA with functional changes seen  only in post-pubertal NVH lesioned animals. While being relevant to the behavioural  characteristics of the NVH lesioned animal model, these data also support the  possible role of cholinergic neurotransmission in schizophrenia.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/474299630.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246s54s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arj4305231"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of the chitinase3-like protein HC-gp39 in connective tissue physiology and pathology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ling, Hua, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We report that the chitinase-like protein, human cartilage  glycoprotein 39 (HC-gp39) is a growth and survival factor. It promotes connective  tissue cell survival and growth, and counteracts catabolic processes. Dose-dependent  growth stimulation was observed when human synoviocytes and fibroblasts were exposed  to HC-gp39. Both the ERK1/2 MAP kinase and the PI3 kinase pathways were activated by  HC-gp39. Thus HC-gp39 elicits a signaling cascade leading to increased connective  tissue cell proliferation, suggesting that HC-gp39 may play a major role in the  pathological conditions leading to tissue fibrosis. In addition to acting as a  mitogen, HC-gp39 also reduces stress-induced apoptosis in human connective tissue  cells. HC-gp39 significantly inhibited H2 O2 activation of SAPK/JNK and p38 in  chondrocytes. A reduction of caspase-3 activation, poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase  (PARP) cleavage and apoptotic cell number was also seen. These results suggest that  HC-gp39 plays an important role in the survival of connective tissue cells. The  protective effect is further illustrated by the ability of HC-gp39 to reduce  cellular responses to inflammatory cytokines. IL-1 or TNF-alpha stimulated  phosphorylation of SAPK/JNK and p38 were greatly reduced by HC-gp39. Signalling  through the NF-kappab pathway was unaffected. These actions resulted in a  significant reduction of MMP1, MMP3, MMP13 and IL-8 production, suggesting that  HC-gp39 can participate in the catabolic aspects of tissue remodelling as a repair  or protecting factor counteracting the catabolic processes. Although HC-gp39  affected the response to IL-1 and TNF-alpha, these cytokines had no effect on the  high expression level of HC-gp39 in chondrocytes cultures. However, inhibition of  the NF-B signalling pathway, which has been implicated as a major effectory  mechanism for TNF-alpha, significantly decreased HC-gp39 protein and mRNA levels in  a concentration and time dependent manner. Increased NF-kappaB Therefore, this work demonstrated that expression of HC-gp39 at  inflammation sites is part of the reaction chain in the pathogenesis of joint  degeneration and/or inflammation. The activity of the elements regulating the  expression of HC-gp39 suggests that it could serve as a negative feedback regulator  for the inflammatory cytokines.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zt82x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj4305231</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bp67k"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>P53 regulatory mechanisms by human papillomavirus (HPV) E6 and alternative splicing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stewart, Deborah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In normal cells, the p53 tumour suppressor induces cell cycle  arrest or apoptosis in response to a variety of stresses, including DNA damage and  ectopic oncogene expression. However, cellular pathways controlled by p53 are  compromised in virtually all cancers. Defining the mechanisms regulating p53  activity in normal and tumour cells has therefore been a major priority in cell  biology and cancer research. In this study, we characterized two important regulatory  mechanims of p53 activity: (i) Human papillomavirus (HPV) E6 interaction and (ii)  alternative splicing. Recognized as the major etiological agents for cervical  cancer, the oncogenic potential of HPVs correlates with their ability to target p53  for degradation. This study demonstrates that both p53 and HPV-18 E6 are exported  from the nucleus when co-expressed, via a process that involves the C-terminal  nuclear export signal (NES) of p53. However, neither nuclear export nor the p53  C-terminal NES is required for HPV-18 E6-mediated ubiquitination or degradation of  p53. This study also demonstrates that both low- and high-risk HPV E6  proteins are degraded by the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway, and thus provides an  explanation for the low levels of E6 detected in cervical cancer  cells. Also reported in this study is a novel mechanism of p53  regulation arising through alternative splicing. This novel mRNA encodes a  N-terminal deleted isoform of p53, termed p47. As demonstrated within, p47 does not  supress cell viability but impairs both p53-mediated transcriptional activity and  growth suppression. Interestingly, p47 increases both p53 monoubiquitination and  nuclear export. We propose that p47 induces nuclear export of p53 by a mechanism  involving monoubiquitination, as supported by recent findings from Li and colleagues  (2003). The p47 protein also protects p53 from both Mdm2- and HPV-18 E6-mediated  degradation. A number of cancers display abnormal localization of wildtype p53, and  it will be important to examine the role of p47 in these tumours. Taken together, the regulation of p53 activity by both HPV E6  and the alternative splice variant p47 involves alterations in p53 ubiquitination  status, protein stability, and cell localization. Insight gained into these negative  regulatory mechanisms may aid in the design of therapeutic strategies for  reactivating wild-type p53 in HPV-associated and non-associated  cancers.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b409.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp67k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>p53 protein</dc:subject><dc:subject>Papillomaviruses</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j333269s"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social creativity, values and shared expertise : the synergistic confluence of social creativity, values and the development of shared expertise</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Reilly, Rosemary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following is a report of a qualitative inquiry regarding a  team of novices and their journey in developing shared expertise and social  creativity in the domain of group facilitation and process consultation. Using the  format of public reflection, the participants engaged in an intensive collaborative  process of meaning making, along with the university instructor as expert, while  being teaching assistants in a course about group dynamics. Using the framework of  evolving systems, the methodology employed an instrumental case study approach, with  the case defined as the group. Data sets included videotaped debriefing and planning  sessions, individual and group interviews, and written reflection diaries, covering  the entire lifespan of the team. These sets were transcribed and subjected to an  examination of the unfolding cognitive and metacognitive, creative, value, and  social processes embedded within the team interactions. The process patterns do  demonstrate that under the conditions created within this context, novices can pool  together expert thinking skills that can collectively compare favorably to those of  an expert. Social creativity also emerged as a property of the system, and these  processes seemed to piggyback onto the socially shared expert thinking skills.  Values acted as tacit rules governing and shaping the social interactions. Ones that  showed a strong association to the development of shared expertise were:  supportiveness, care, listening/questioning for clarity, helpfulness, openness to  disagreement/feedback, and plurality. Values that showed a strong association to the  development of social creativity were: supportiveness, listening/questioning for  clarity, helpfulness, and openness to disagreement/feedback. Humor was an ever  present element to the system and acted as a lubricant producing social ease. The  patterns that emanated from this inquiry were placed into two larger theoretical  frameworks, socially shared cogni</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967415x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333269s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Expertise</dc:subject><dc:subject>Creative ability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Creative ability -- Social aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m4595"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Learning invariant neuronal representations for objects across visual-related self-actions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li, Muhua, 1973-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work is aimed at understanding and modelling the perceptual  stability mechanisms of human visual systems, regardless of large changes in the  visual sensory input resulting from some visual-related motions. Invariant neuronal  representation plays an important role for memory systems to associate and recognize  objects. In contrast to the bulk of previous research work on the  learning of invariance that focuses on the pure bottom-up visual information, we  incorporate visual-related self-action signals such as commands for eye, head or  body movements, to actively collect the changing visual information and gate the  learning process. This helps neural networks learn certain degrees of invariance in  an efficient way. We describe a method that can produce a network with invariance to  changes in visual input caused by eye movements and covert attention shifts.  Training of the network is controlled by signals associated with eye movements and  covert attention shifting. A temporal perceptual stability constraint is used to  drive the output of the network towards remaining constant across temporal sequences  of saccadic motions and covert attention shifts. We use a four-layer neural network  model to perform the position-invariant extraction of local features and temporal  integration of invariant presentations of local features. The model is further  extended to handle viewpoint invariance over eye, head, and/or body movements. We  also study cases of multiple features instead of single features in the retinal  images, which need a self-organized system to learn over a set of feature classes. A  modified saliency map mechanism with spatial constraint is employed to assure that  attention stays as much as possible on the same targeted object in a multiple-object  scene during the first few shifts. We present results on both simulated data and real images, to  demonstrate that our network can acquire invariant neuronal representations, such as  position and attention shift invariance. We also demonstrate that our method  performs well in realistic situations in which the temporal sequence of input data  is not smooth, situations in which earlier approaches have  difficulty.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074v615.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m4595</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515n89r"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Competitive goal orientations, friendship quality, and friendship stability in gifted and nongifted adolescent friendships</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schapiro, Michelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examined the friendships between gifted and regular  adolescents to determine if competition was related to the quality and stability of  their friendship. Sullivan (1953) had predicted that competition harmed friendship,  but this has not been tested empirically. Thirty-eight gifted and 38 regular  friendship dyads from grades seven and eight were recruited from two high schools in  Quebec and one in Ontario. Competition was defined in terms of competitive goal  orientation. Students who competed in order to improve their performance on a task  were rated as more task-oriented. Those who competed in order to show superiority  over others were rated as more other-referenced. Competitive goal orientation  differed for gifted and regular students. Classroom teachers, physical education  teachers, and peers rated gifted students as being more task-oriented and regular  students as being more other-referenced in their competitive styles across both  scholastic and athletic domains. Being more task-oriented was related to having less  negative friendship quality (i.e., fewer conflicts), more friendly competition, and  for gifted students only, more friendship stability. Conversely, being more  other-referenced was related to more negative friendship qualities and, for gifted  students only, unstable friendships. Additionally, friends who reported positive  friendship qualities at the end of the school year remained friends over the summer  more so than friends who reported negative friendship qualities. However, during the  school year, when friends saw each other regularly, the quality of their friendship  was not related to whether or not they remained friends. Surprisingly, the  friendships of regular adolescents had more positive qualities (companionship, help,  security, closeness) than the friendships of gifted adolescents. No difference in  friendship stability was found between the groups. Practical implications for  teachers include avoiding forms</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jb92f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n89r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gifted teenagers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Friendship in adolescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competition (Psychology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418n70s"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional magnetic resonance imaging of cerebral blood volume</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stefanovic, Bojana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation describes a novel method for quantifying  venous cerebral blood volume (CBVv) changes accompanying normal functional  activation and employs quantitative functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI)  methods to study the hemodynamic and metabolic changes accompanying neuronal  inhibition. An in vivo occipital lobe relaxometry study was performed first to  investigate the dependence of the spin-spin relaxation time constant of tissue,  T2tissue , on the refocusing interval over the range of interest and thus test the  basis of the proposed CBVv method. The small decrease of the apparent T2tissue with  refocusing interval elongation is consistent with blood being the only significant  source of refocusing interval dependence of apparent T2 in grey and white matter of  the occipital lobe. In ensuing in vitro blood relaxometry studies, ensemble fitting  of the entire set of T2blood estimates, obtained over an extensive range of blood  oxygenation levels and refocusing intervals, was performed using both the fast  chemical exchange model and the model of diffusion in weak magnetic field  inhomogeneities. The results support the application of a diffusion model in  describing the deoxyhemoglobin-induced enhancement in blood transverse relaxation  rate at 1.5 T. Given the uniqueness of T2blood dependence on the refocusing rates  over the range of interest, the novel CBVv method - venous refocusing for volume  estimation (VERVE) - successfully isolates the blood signal by refocusing rate  variation. A model of functional brain activation was developed and in vitro blood  relaxometry data used to assess the effect of the intravascular spin-echo blood  oxygenation level dependent (BOLD) contrast on the activation-induced VERVE signal  change, allowing robust estimation of venous CBV changes. The method was  demonstrated in a visual stimulation study of healthy young adults, where an average  venous blood volume in the visual cortex increase was estimated</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rp16t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418n70s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f6328"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Block copolymer micelles and vesicles : loading, release and cellular internalization with applications to drug delivery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lim Soo, Patrick, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes the preparation, physico-chemical  characterization and pharmacological studies of block copolymer micelles and  vesicles for drug delivery applications. The incorporation and partition  coefficients of model hydrophobic compounds (benzo[a]pyrene and Cell Tracker-DiI)  are investigated in polycaprolactone-block-poly(ethylene oxide) copolymer micelles  (PCL-b-PEO). The release of the probes is also studied from PCL-b-PEO micelles under  perfect sink conditions. To investigate the usefulness of PCL-b-PEO micelles as a  delivery vehicle for hydrophobic drugs, 17beta-estradiol (E2) is incorporated and  released from the micelles. The biological activity of E2 is retained after micelle  preparation and delivery to C57BL female mice. To investigate the cellular  internalization of block copolymer micelles, gold labeled poly (4-vinylpyridine)-  block-poly(ethylene oxide) micelles are internalized into A549 lung cells and HEK  293 kidney cells. The gold labeled P4VP-b-PEO micelles are visualized by  transmission electron microscopy inside of endosomes and lysozomes of these cells.  The incorporation and release of a hydrophilic drug, doxorubicin hydrochloride  (DXR), into polystyrene-block-poly(acrylic acid) vesicles are investigated. An  active pH loading method is used to incorporate DXR into the aqueous center of the  vesicle. A plasticizer, dioxane is used to control the loading and release of DXR by  tuning the permeability of the vesicle walls.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jr69r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f6328</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fh62r"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A contingency approach to service reliability and service customization : their relationship and role in customer evaluations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gupta, Kunal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The presence as well as the nature of the relationship between  customer perceptions of service customization and reliability is investigated in the  first of three studies of the dissertation by applying an exploratory analytical  approach---"probabilistic scaling analysis." Results suggest the existence  of a positive and ordinal relationship between customer perceptions of customization  and reliable quality. The second study of the dissertation applies a more  confirmatory, 'contingency theory' approach to validate, and further develop the  findings of the first study. Results are consistent in that a positive and ordinal  relationship is observed between customer perceptions of service customization and  reliability. Further, findings suggest that customization quality moderates the  affect of reliable quality on overall service evaluations. Some support is also  found for the moderating role of reliable quality. Together, these findings help  unravel the relationship between customer perceptions of service customization and  reliability, and demonstrate how each of them affects the marketplace efficacy of  the other. Overall, results of the probabilistic scaling analysis, as well  as contingency theory demonstrate that among customers at the lower end of the  latent scale, it is primarily the 'things gone wrong,' i.e. lack of reliability that  governs the unfavorability of their overall perceptions. Among customers on the  higher end, it is 'things gone right,' i.e. favorable customization quality  perceptions that govern the favorability of their overall perceptions. Together,  these results suggest that a service provider must minimize 'things gone wrong' and  then focus on 'things gone right' to elicit favorable overall  evaluations. In a service environment however, 'doing things right' requires  an immediate understanding of individual needs that a customer brings forth during  every service transaction, and that must be met to create value for the customer.  Qualitative data are analyzed using a conceptual framework to provide a systematic  understanding of these issues. Such understanding also provides diagnostic  information towards exploring key segment level differences observed in the second  study of the dissertation. Overall, the analyses of the third study extend current  subject understanding by providing a contextual development of value-creating  individual customer needs as they relate to service customization and reliability,  and their implications on service design. Overall, the dissertation develops current subject understanding  of service customization and reliability, and therefore of service quality in  general. Customers evaluate service offerings on both elements of  quality---customization and reliability, and thus one of them cannot be studied  without understanding its affects on the other component of quality. The research,  we believe, would develop the understanding of the subject, and would also aid  service providers in more scientific service design as well as decision-making.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dube, Laurette</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257f666.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh62r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Customer services</dc:subject><dc:subject>Consumer satisfaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Service industries -- Quality control</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tv565"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Peace building : the role of social work and law in the promotion of social capital and political integration</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oberlander Moshe, Marla</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study suggests that two domestic conditions are critical to  foster opportunities for sustainable peace between formerly conflicting societies.  The conditions are defined as social capital and political integration. These are  explored in the context of Israeli and Palestinian societies following the signing  of the Oslo Peace Accords in 1993 and through 1999, just one year prior to the  outbreak of the al-Aqsa Intifada. Social capital refers to networks of association. Strong  networks of relationship are important because they are positively associated with a  community and/or society's ability to foster social cohesion, to problem-solve and  cope with growing uncertainty such as that exemplifying the period of transition  from conflict to peace. Income inequality is inversely related to social capital.  Communities and societies characterized by growing income inequality are typified by  diminishing social capital, hence receding capacity to weather the impact of major  societal change. The term political integration refers to the relationship  between a government and its citizens. In politically integrated societies citizens  share a sense that government is concerned with their welfare and hence their  loyalty is expressed through support of the government, its programs and policies.  Growing political fragmentation, a lack of abidance, and the breakdown of  relationships between civil society and government mark politically disintegrated  societies. Political integration is particularly relevant in the aftermath of the  signing of a peace agreement when domestic sectarian divides threaten to undermine  the national entity that must maintain the delicate balance attained by formerly  conflicting societies. Social capital and political integration are the outcome of  greater or lesser human rights: social and economic, civil and political. The  persistence of inequality, social and economic, civil and political, wears down the  relationships between members of a society and between citizens and their  government. Analysis of standard social and economic indicators in  Palestinian and Israeli societies suggests that despite the promised peace dividend  social and economic inequality persisted and in some instances worsened between 1993  and 1999. Analysis of civil and political conditions in both societies suggests that  political disintegration as opposed to growing integration characterized the  six-year period.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Torczyner, J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bh71z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv565</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Arab-Israeli conflict</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reconciliation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social service -- Political aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct370"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Masculinidades de moda : machos del Siglo de Oro</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gagnon, Julie E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Among the diverse fabric of masculinities that prestigious  authors such as Pedro Calderon de la Barca, Tirso de Molina and Agustin Moreto weave  into their plots, fashion proves to be a common thread and a particularly useful  tool. Thus, as I approach the idea of "Fashionable Masculinities" and  investigate a few "macho" and/or not so "macho men" in Early  Modern drama I hope to go beyond the traditional interpretations, stereotypes and  icons often associated with men---in particular, Spanish men in Golden Age drama.  This will be achieved by revisiting typical cases and compared through research and  documentation of atypical representations of maleness that could be considered  displacements and/or subversions of the social matrix. In effect, this study  explores how the male ideal is shaped and judged both by the essence of his  personality, as well as his physical appearance (i.e.: clothing, hairstyle,  mannerisms, discourse and voice). As such, it becomes evident that masculinity is  moulded, influenced, enhanced, exaggerated and even muted as it is subject to the  whim of different fashions prevalent at a specific moment in time. Moreover, a  multitude of social, cultural, racial and historical factors determine the always  changing image of the so called "macho man". Therefore, in order to explore distinct representations of  masculinity I approach three different comedias by three different playwrights while  comparing how the main character's masculinity fared in three very important spaces:  physical, social and sexual. I focus my attention on Saber del mal y del bien by  Calderon. Secondly, Don Gil de las calzas verdes by Tirso and explored El lindo don  Diego by Moreto. Each one the these represents a different degree of palatable male  identities given this particular social construct.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Perez-Magallon, Jesus</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p38n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct370</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Molina, Tirso de, 1571?-1648. Don Gil de las calzas verdes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Masculinity in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calderón de la Barca, Pedro, 1600-1681. Saber del mal y del bien</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spanish drama (Comedy) -- Classical period, 1500-1700 -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Moreto, Agustín, 1618-1669. Lindo don Diego</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881m45p"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The historical past as a tool for nation-building in new order Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wood, Michael John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study describes how the New Order regime created and used a  particular version of the Indonesian past. This official past drew on the work of  "the history industry" (archaeological and historical research) and is  reflected in approved works of history writing. The New Order past can also be seen  in textbooks and in what monuments the regime erected. The New Order chose to  emphasize fourteenth century Majapahit empire; this hierarchical, Java-centred,  Hindu empire was identified as the true ancestor of the present nation. Although  Indonesia is overwhelmingly Muslim in population, subsequent Muslim advances were  not stressed, except as part of the "palace culture" of Central Java,  which was seen as an extension of Majapahit. Islam also provided its share of  "national heroes" who fought against the Dutch colonialists. Dutch  control, was looked upon with some ambiguity; the colonial regime was oppressive but  it also provided stability. The Dutch were driven out during the 1945--1949  Revolution. The New Order gave credit for the Indonesian victory in this struggle to  the military rather than to civilians such as Sukarno. The Revolution later took on  a more radical character that culminated in an attempt on the part of the Indonesian  Communist Party to seize power. The suppression of the September 30 Movement in 1965  was seen as a righting of the nation's proper path of development, a course that  could in fact be traced back to Gajah Mada's Majapahit. Not all were impressed with  this official history. A more Islamic "history in waiting," which differed  significantly from that of the regime, was created by historians and archaeologists  working within the New Order. This "ummat-oriented" past stressed long  connections between Indonesia and the rest of the Muslim world. The New Order's past  was used to foster national integration and the legitimacy of the regime itself. The  fate of the Suharto Presidency might indicate that the past was utiliz</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Little, D.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. U.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh606.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m45p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nationalism -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indonesia -- History -- 1945-</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indonesia -- Politics and government -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab8515n90h"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A conserved determinant of Ion channel trafficking localized to the cyclic nucleotide binding domain : implication for disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Akhavan, Armin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Cyclic Nucleotide Binding Domain (CNBD) is conserved in a  number of ion channels that belong to three distinct families, the Ether-A-Go-go  (EAG); the Cyclic Nucleotide Gated (CNG) and the Hyperpolarization activated Cyclic  Nucleotide modulated (HCN) channel families. Extensive biophysical characterizations  have established that the function of these channels is directly modulated by cyclic  nucleotides in a manner independent of kinase activity and channel phosphorylation.  However, the role for this domain in the EAG family is unclear. In addition,  although the biophysical properties of CNBD-containing channels are well understood,  little is known about the biogenesis of these channels. The original goal of this  thesis was to identify trafficking signals in the C-terminus of the Human  Ether-a-go-go Related Gene (HERG) potassium channel with the aim of understanding  the underlying mechanisms associated with mutations in this gene that cause the Long  Q-T Syndrome (LQTS) and associated cardiac arrhythmia. By exploiting the unique  biochemical properties of HERG, we identify a discrete C-terminal segment between  residues 860-899 that is critical for the exit of the ion channel from the  Endoplasmic Reticulum (ER). To substantiate the role of residues 860-899 in  trafficking of HERG, we show defective biogenesis associated with a number of  LQTS-causing mutations that interfere with this segment. Subsequent functional,  biochemical and immunolocalization experiments identify the CNBD of HERG as the  trafficking critical segment. Deletions of any of the structural motifs of the CNBD  cause retention of the ion channel inside the ER. Likewise, removal of the entire  CNBD prevents Golgi transit and cell surface localization of tetrameric channels. We  show that all known arrhythmogenic mutations in this domain render HERG channel  nonfunctional as a result of ER retention. Subsequent analyses indicate that the  CNBD is indispensable for ER exit of a relat</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg45x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n90h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bc027"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Micromechanical modeling of dual phase steels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alabbasi, Fawzi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Material characterization is a very important tool needed to  describe and enhance material mechanical properties and to develop optimum material  chemistries and microstructures. The usual approach of achieving the above using  extensive experimental methods has been shown to be expensive and time consuming.  This led to the development of the micro mechanical modeling, which can be used to  predict the material behavior without the need for the extensive experimental  investigation and is based on microstructural characteristics of the  material. In this work, a micro mechanical model is developed to predict  the mechanical properties of dual phase steels consisting of martensite in a matrix  of ferrite. This micro model is also used to elucidate the mechanics and mechanisms  of deformation, which take place in such materials. DP-steels consisting of several  volume fractions of martensite (Vm) representing low, intermediate and high Vm are  developed and tested mechanically to obtain their mechanical properties.  Metallographical examinations are carried out using image analysis to quantify  microstructural material properties of each level of Vm considered. As a validation  of the current work, comparison between the model predictions, which include all the  significant material behavior investigated in this work and the experimental  results, is presented. The comparison demonstrates the ability of the model to  capture the behavior of DP-steels up to the instability point. The Gurson-Tvergaard model, which is the most widely known  damage model to describe ductile failure, is coupled with the results of the micro  mechanical model, presented in this work to form a complete material model of  deformation and fracture of DP-steels. A procedure is developed to determine the  parameters in the Gurson-Tvergaard model utilizing the micromechanical model. The  results are then implemented to simulate the deformation and failure of tensile bars  of DP-steels with different Vm, which shows good agreement with the experimental  results at failure.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s070j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc027</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw66344189"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language/><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Alrededor de una música auscente</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Budón, Osvaldo, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Alrededor de una musica ausente is an 18-minutes long  composition, written for three Instrumental Groups (Group I: two trombones; Group  II: four flutes; Group III: strings [6 0 3 2 1]) and three computer-based Digital  Signal Processing Stations, positioned in the performance space so as to form a  circle around the audience. Instrumental Groups and DSP Stations establish a relationship of  outputs to inputs with respect to each other. Throughout the composition, sound  material is gradually transformed as it flows from one Instrumental Group or Digital  Signal Processing Station to another. Transformation of the sound material is  accomplished by means of digital signal processing and, in the instrumental parts,  by way of compositional techniques modeled after specific electroacoustic sound  processing techniques. The organization of musical structures and formal processes was  informed by certain characteristics associated with devices that handle information  represented digitally, by techniques of electroacoustic sound production and  transformation, and by particular extended instrumental techniques. Volume 1 of this dissertation is a written text articulated in  two parts. The first part gives a historical and aesthetical context for my  composition. The second part is an analysis of materials and formal processes used  in the piece. Volume 2 is the music score of the composition. A CD containing the  patches and soundfiles utilized in the electronic part supplements both  volumes.* *This dissertation is a compound document (contains both a paper  copy and a CD as part of the dissertation). The CD requires the following system  requirements: Windows MediaPlayer or RealPlayer.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rea, John</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k405.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66344189</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electronic music</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orchestral music -- Analysis, appreciation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Budón, Osvaldo, 1965- Alrededor de una música auscente</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orchestral music -- Scores</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electronic music -- Analysis, appreciation</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>