<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fp573"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The linguistic system of a deaf language learner : examining the effects of delayed language exposure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hargraves, Lisa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This investigation reports on the linguistic and communicative  abilities of a deaf child whose initial exposure to conventional linguistic input  occurred at the age of 10. At the time of data collection, the participant had been  exposed to American Sign Language (ASL) for three years. Information concerning the  participant's background, language and communication abilities was collected through  caregiver interviews. Language samples were gathered through storybook and video  retelling tasks and spontaneous conversations. Samples were videotaped, and later  transcribed by a native deaf signer of ASL. Analyses of the participant's lexical,  morphological, syntactic, and pragmatic skills were performed. Results showed  deficits across linguistic subsystems. Comparisons to native language learners of  ASL and late first-language learners of spoken and signed languages revealed both  typical and unique characteristics of late language acquisition. The results  contradict past theoretical claims concerning the selective impact of language  deprivation on the faculty of grammar. Clinical implications and directions for  future research are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mayberry, Rachel I.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g337w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fp573</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Developmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6d56zx13v"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of lymphocyte specific protein tyrosine kinase, Lck, by tyrosine phosphorylation : evaluation of the tail-bite model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hatahet, Laith</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several studies show that the catalytic function of the  Src-family protein kinase Lck is repressed by phosphorylation of a conserved  carboxyl-terminal residue (Y505). This phosphorylation allows the molecule to bind  to its SH2 domain rendering the protein in an inactive state, a proposed model  called the tail-bite mechanism. However, previous findings demonstrated that the  activity of Lck from several T cell lines lacking CD45, which is the phosphatase  known to dephosphorylate Y505, was significantly elevated. Herein, we are evaluating  the tail bite mechanism model by examining the major regulatory sites of Lck, Y394  and Y505, in several T cell lines and assessing the catalytic function of Lck tail  mutants on its substrates in JCaM1 cells in vivo . Utilizing phospho-specific  antibodies, we provide evidence that Lck from activated T cells is phosphorylated  both at Y394 and Y505.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Couture, C.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w540s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx13v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aks65hc86x"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A genetic study of longevity in swine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fortin, Frédéric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Data from the Quebec swine breeding program (1980 to 2001) were  used to estimate genetic parameters for longevity and to evaluate the contribution  of non-genetic factors. After data verifications, there were 28,377 Yorkshire,  30,123 Landrace and 7,830 Duroc sows with records of herd life. The program 'The  Survival Kit V3.12' (Ducrocq and Solkner, 2001) was used to estimate heritability  separately within each breed, using a Cox proportional hazard model. The  time-independent fixed effects of age at first service and of the combinations of  herd with year of birth, estimated breeding value (EBV) backfat, EBV age to 100  kilograms and EBV litter size were included. The effects of number of piglets born,  number of piglets weaned, crossbreeding at insemination, stage of sow (farrowing,  weaning or heat) and their combination with parity were treated as fixed  time-dependent variables whereas herd by year was treated as random time-dependent  variable. The random effect of sire using sire relationships back two generations  was considered as the source of genetic variation. Length of productive life  (longevity) was defined as the number of days from first service until culling.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cue, Roger I.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xx94g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hc86x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Swine -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Swine -- Longevity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8336h256g"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Diversity of Brachycera (Diptera) in a Quebec old growth forest</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fast, Eleanor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The diversity of Brachycera (Diptera) was studied in an old  growth beech-sugar maple forest at Mont St. Hilaire, Quebec. Sampling was carried  out weekly from early May to late September 2001 using a malaise trap, pan traps, a  newly designed trunk trap and sweep netting. Almost 10,000 specimens from 45  families and over 334 species were collected. The most diverse families were  Empididae (43 species), Tachinidae (39 species), Syrphidae (35 species) and  Dolichopodidae (24 species). Collecting techniques were compared, with particular  reference to the trunk trap designed for this study. NMDS ordination showed that a  different Diptera assemblage was collected by each method. The greatest number of  species was collected using the malaise trap; however, 21 species were collected  only in trunk traps. Some of the most abundant species from trunk traps were  collected rarely, or not at all, using other methods. These are species which are  often considered rare in forests because they are infrequently collected using  traditional techniques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wheeler, T. A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm04n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h256g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diptera -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire</dc:subject><dc:subject>Species diversity -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q208b"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cycles on the moduli space of hyperelliptic curves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fortin Boisvert, Mélisande</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Oort gave a complete description of symplectic commutative group  schemes killed by p and of rank p2g . Each such group appears as the p-torsion group  scheme of some principally polarized abelian variety and this classification can be  given in terms of final sequences. In this thesis, we focus on the particular  situation where the abelian variety is the Jacobian of a hyperelliptic curve. We  concentrate on describing the subspace of the moduli space of hyperelliptic curves,  or rather the cycle, corresponding to a given final sequence. Especially, we  concentrate on describing the subspace corresponding to the non-ordinary locus,  which is a union of final sequences.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Goren, Eyal Z.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t918n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q208b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sg97x"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Renal calcification in Npt2 knockout mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chau, Hien Nguyet, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mice homozygous for the disrupted renal type 11a  sodium/phosphate (Na/Pi) cotransporter gene, Npt2, (Npt2 KO) exhibit renal Pi  wasting and hypercalciuria, predisposing factors for renal stone formation. We  observed that Npt2 KO mice, but not wild-type littermates form renal stones. The  renal stones were evident in newborn, weanling and adult mice and composed of  calcium (Ca) and Pi. The presence of renal calcification correlated with the absence  of Npt2 gene expression and the presence of genes responsible for the synthesis  (1alpha-hydroxylase) and catabolism (24-hydroxylase) of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D,  whose elevated levels contribute to the hypercalciuria and renal calcification in  Npt2 KO mice. The renal calcification was associated with increased osteopontin  (OPN) mRNA expression and colocalized with OPN, the latter associates with renal  stones in vivo and inhibits Ca mineralization in vitro). These data demonstrate that  hyperphosphaturia and hypercalciuria, secondary to Npt2 gene disruption, are  sufficient for the development of renal calcification.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tenenhouse, Harriet S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f411b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg97x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hypercalciurea -- Genetic aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice -- Molecular genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sodium cotransport systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Osteopontin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kidneys -- Calculi -- Genetic aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cd830"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spontaneous errors of imprinting in mouse embryos</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Charron, Marie-Claude</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Genomic imprinting is a mechanism of fine regulation of gene  expression. Imprinted genes are expressed from only one parental allele and many of  them have critical roles in growth and development. Imprinting marks that  distinguish the parental origin must be erased and re-established in germ cells  according to the sex of the individual to ensure proper embryonic development. We  investigated occurrence of imprinting errors in mouse embryos. Firstly, we tested  the hypothesis that errors in resetting of imprints occur and lead to  grandparental-origin effects on embryonic growth. Although we did not find  statistically significant effects, we observed trends that should be confirmed by  replication. Secondly, we examined expression of 5 genes located on the distal part  of chromosome 12 in order to establish the incidence of spontaneous imprinting  errors. We report a strain and parental-origin specific imprinting relaxation of  Dlk1 and Dio3 genes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Naumova, A. K.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h951q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cd830</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m2346"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Amphibian recruitment success at a landscape scale</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bol, Leslie D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Size fluctuations in amphibian populations at single breeding  sites are related to variations in recruitment from the larval stage. However,  overall patterns of abundance should be related to the pattern of recruitment  success at the many sites where breeding occurs over a landscape. Recruitment  patterns for six amphibian species, Ambystoma laterale, A. maculatum, Bufo  americanus, Hyla versicolor, Pseudacris crucifer and Rana sylvatica, were  investigated at multiple sites within the 10 km 2 Mont St. Hilaire nature reserve  during 2001 and 2002. Amphibians bred at eighteen sites but recruitment occurred at  only 8 and 11 sites in each year, respectively. Hydroperiod and predation were the  most important determinants of recruitment. Four species suffered multiple  recruitment failures both years. However, when sites were considered collectively,  recruitment was successful for all species because of asynchronous recruitment  patterns across heterogeneous sites. Amphibian population dynamics may be stochastic  at any single site but recruitment success at multiple sites is a plausible  predictor of abundance and trends in regional population  persistence.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Green, David M.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz08d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m2346</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Amphibian populations -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dm979"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Altering electrolyte balance of diets for lactating dairy cows to reduce phosphorus excretion to the environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Borucki Castro, Sylvia Irene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study was designed to test the hypothesis that P excretion  in manure of dairy cattle could be reduced by manipulating electrolyte balance of  the diet. Feces was the main route of P excretion, but fecal P was not affected by  dietary cation-anion (DCAB) (P &gt; 0.05). Plasma concentration of P tended (P  &lt; 0.10) to be higher at lower DCAB levels, implying that DCAB may have  influenced P homeostasis. The overall P balance was not affected by the different  DCAB levels. The range of DCAB where both P excretion and animal performance could  be optimised is very narrow (+250 to +350 mEq/kg DM), so using DCAB to control P  excretion in dairy cattle requires caution. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Phillip, Leroy E.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w056g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dm979</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phosphorus -- Environmental aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electrolytes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Feeding and feeds</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gk50d"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic epidemiology of tuberculosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ahmadipour, Nooshin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Susceptibility to a complex disease such as  tuberculosis generally involves interactions among several genes and environmental  factors. Several association studies have been conducted to examine the association  between candidate genes and tuberculosis. However, the genetic risk factors are not  fully understood. Objective. To examine the effect of several candidate genes,  including natural resistance associated macrophage protein 1 (NRAMP1), vitamin D  receptor (VDR), surfactant proteins (SFTPA1), and mannose-binding lectin (MBL), and  also to assess the effect of several risk factors on their association with  tuberculosis. The other objectives were to test for mode of inheritance and also to  estimate the relative risks of disease for different genotypes. Methods. A prospective case-parental control study was  conducted. Ninety-five nuclear families were selected from an existing database of  families with tuberculosis in Ethiopia. Each family consisted of one affected child  and two parents. The primary outcome was transmission/nontransmission of alleles  from parents to affected offspring. Results. The transmission disequilibrium test showed that marker  SFTPA1-294 was significantly associated with the outcome (chi 2 = 4.297; p = 0.038).  When other risk factors such as age, sex, ethnicity, certain symptoms or other genes  were allowed to modify the transmission probabilities in a logistic regression  model, several other markers were found to be significantly associated with the  outcome. Conclusions. Despite the limitations of this study, this thesis  provided evidence for inheritance of susceptibility to tuberculosis in Hadiayan  families in Ethiopia. To confirm the findings in this thesis, it would be useful to  conduct similar research in populations with different ethnic origins, where genetic  and environmental exposures can be examined and compared.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gyorkos, Theresa W.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Greenwood, Celia</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v605t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk50d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qs682"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimized waveform relaxation methods for RC type circuits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Khaleel, Mohammad D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The waveform relaxation method is a very efficient and reliable  method, it has been widely used in several fields including circuit theory, for  solving large systems of ordinary differential equations as well as partial  differential equations. The convergence rate of the classical waveform relaxation  approach is not uniform over the time interval for which the equations are  integrated. A new approach called the optimized waveform relaxation approach was  proposed with a remarkable and great improvement in the convergence behavior by  introducing new transmission conditions. Here, we continue the work done on the  optimized waveform relaxation by extending previous results and trying to get a  better performance as well as a more general optimized waveform relaxation approach.  We use two RC circuits to illustrate the theory and the performance obtained by  improving the convergence behavior of the new algorithm.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gander, Martin</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd35t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs682</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azg64tm64h"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Public access to information : reaching the right balance between public and private</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Larsen, Irene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the change towards a property-based view of  information in the fields of copyright, database protection and data privacy. Focus  will be placed on the United States and the European Union, as those territories  together are responsible for more than half of the world's Internet population. The  thesis will attempt to show that a view of information as personal property is not  actually benefiting society in general and is dangerous for future progress:  economic, scientific and social. The thesis suggests balancing the restrictions on  access to information as a whole, meaning viewing the restrictions in copyright,  database protection and privacy laws to see how they together affect access to  information. It argues that these fields of law should supplement each other in  maximizing social welfare through a baseline of public access as opposed to a  baseline of monopoly.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gold, Richard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dd080.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm64h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Privacy, Right of -- Europe</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copyright -- Europe</dc:subject><dc:subject>Freedom of information (International law)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Privacy, Right of -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copyright -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Freedom of information</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c347c"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The protection of indigenous medicinal knowledge in international intellectual property law</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lassonde, Marie-Claire</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>For 20 years, and more intensively during the last decade,  indigenous knowledge has challenged the regime of intellectual property. If this  field of law has been, in the past, challenged by new technology, it is now, with  the problematic of indigenous medicinal knowledge, put to the test by "old  invention". The present thesis examines the status of indigenous medicinal  knowledge in international intellectual property law. Thus, we will proceed to the  study of the main international conventions and the common regime of intellectual  property law in order to determine the treatment accorded to medicinal indigenous  knowledge within the actual system. The role that intellectual property could play  in the future will also be examined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gold, Richard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx64k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c347c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Traditional medicine</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intellectual property (International law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w543m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Intellectual property rights in outer space</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bhattacharya, Raja</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Private entities, investing billions of dollars, as a matter of  reasonable commercial corporate expectations, want to be protected against undue  use, exploitation and copying of their technology and inventions which they have put  into their space ventures (often termed as 'theft') by any third party. States, to  secure an environment friendly to such generation, use and transfer of intellectual  property rights (IPRs) in outer space, have initiated applying and/or extending  their national IP laws into outer space either in form of a statute or a  multilateral agreement. This may have both commercial and political  significance. This thesis deals with IP issues in international perspective  (with reference, however, to some leading national IP legislation when and where it  is necessary) with special reference to the contemporary legal regime governing  outer space. While emphasizing the existing legal regime relating to IPRs in outer  space, it explores the possibility of commercial exploitation of IPRs made in space  and on ground through the existing international trade system. The increasing  importance of cooperation between the World Intellectual Property Organization and  World Trade Organization in this regard is also examined, against the back drop of  space activities and the outer space legal regime relating to IPRs. (Abstract  shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jakhu, Ram S.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s083m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w543m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intellectual property</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intellectual property (International law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kn76d"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Our tangled web : international relations theory, international environmental law, and global biodiversity protection in a post-modern epoch of interdependence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bowman, Megan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The global crisis of biodiversity depletion sets the stage for a  necessary re-definition of State self-interest in the international milieu. That  re-definition is effected by a changing perception of 'self'; one that occurs  through the mental lens of interdependence and long-term vision. This thesis  attempts to challenge conventional precepts and present a submission for change by  drawing upon constructivist thought, which asserts that current perceptions are  socially constructed and rooted in "collective intentionality", such that  what has been human-made can be altered by the same processes through which it came  into existence. In so doing, the author employs the notions of international ethics  as a shared belief and international law as an ideational instrument to facilitate  that change in favor of international cooperation toward the necessary amelioration  of global biodiversity diminution in order to assure our future.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ellis, Jaye</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k54h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn76d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Environmental law, International</dc:subject><dc:subject>International cooperation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biodiversity conservation -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biodiversity conservation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tp98h"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A critical analysis of the child welfare system and attempts to reclaim clinical practice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>St. Hillaire, Kim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Stress and burnout have received a great deal of attention in  the child welfare field. This has been due to such issues as the high workload, the  complexity of the cases, working with resistant and at times violent clients and the  negative work environment of the youth protection agency. These factors have a  detrimental effect on the worker's personal and professional resources and undermine  the healthy functioning of the agency, all of which ultimately affects best practice  with clients. One way in which child welfare organizations could make an effort  towards reclaiming clinical practice is to engage in training for its workforce.  Training can benefit practitioners by improving their skills and knowledge and this  can lead to greater job satisfaction. Agency functioning is improved by having a  trained workforce as well as social workers who are knowledgeable regarding agency  policies, values and models of intervention. Children and families ultimately  benefit by working with practitioners who are equipped with the appropriate skills.  These benefits for workers, clients and the agency cannot materialize unless  barriers are removed and changes within the agency take place in order to support  the effective transfer of knowledge and training.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Davies, Linda</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt46w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp98h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Child welfare workers -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Child welfare -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Burn out (Psychology)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q210c"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Street outreach programs for homeless and underhoused people : a grounded theory study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tanner, Alan Gordon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As extreme poverty and homelessness continue to increase and  become more visible in urban centres throughout Canada, it is increasingly more  important to develop and critique interventions within the field. This grounded  theory study provides and overview of one type of intervention---street outreach  programs. It is informed by interviews with front line street outreach workers in  Vancouver, Toronto and Montreal. It includes an outline of the academic literature  on homelessness and street outreach programs and stresses the importance of viewing  this social phenomenon through a structural lens. It describes in detail the main  aspects of street outreach work, as well as evaluates the greater the political  significance of this type of work. Conclusions demonstrate the importance of  establishing trusting relationships with clients and working from a structural  approach that satisfy peoples immediate needs while addressing the root causes of  extreme poverty and oppression.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brotman, Shari</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8434.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q210c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social work with the homeless -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Homeless persons -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bm28r"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Churching the shawms in Renaissance Spain : Lerma, archivo de San Pedro ms. mus. 1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kirk, Douglas Karl</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Numerous studies have shown that in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries Spanish churches (both metropolitan and monastic) employed bands of wind instrumentalists to play frequently in liturgies and processions throughout the church year. Exactly what this music was, though, beyond colla parte participation in masses and motets has remained conjectural because not a note of it has been found. This dissertation is a study and edition of a major, newly-discovered manuscript which contained part of the repertory of the minstrels who served the Duke of Lerma, c. 1607, in the collegial church of San Pedro in Lerma. By comparing the repertory in the manuscript with sixteenth- and seventeenth-century instructions to minstrels in Le6n and Palencia, it has been possible to establish typical ecclesiastical performance responsibilities of minstrels and deduce how such a collection of instrumental music would have been used. Furthermore, after study of the surviving inventories of San Pedro, it has been possible to reconstruct the entire polyphonic musical repertory of the church. This enables us to see the sort of musical library available to the typical succentor or chapelmaster of the time, and the place that minstrel repertory occupied. Finally, a significant number of the original Lerma manuscripts and prints have been traced into modern collections, allowing us to know much more about their origins and history than heretofore.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Plusieurs etudes ont demontre qu'au seizieme et au dix-septieme siecle, les eglises espagnoles (metropolitaines et monacales) employaient des ensembles de musiciens utilisant des instruments "hauts" pour jouer dans de nombreuses liturgies et processions tout au long de l'annee. Ce que cette musique etait precisement, au-dela de la participation dans l'accompagnement des choeurs des messes et motets, ne reste que conjectures puisqu' au aucune note n'a ete trouvee. Cette dissertation est une etude et une edition d'un manusmt d'une importance majeure et nouvellement decouvert, identifie comme ayant fait partie du repertoire des menestrels servant le duc de Lerma, c. 1607, qui etaient engages pour jouer a l' eglise collegiale de San Pedro a Lerma. En comparant le repertoire dans le manuscrit avec les instructions des menestrels du seizieme et du dix-septieme siecle a Le6n et Palencia, il a ete possible d' etablir les responsabilites musicales liturgique des menestrels et de deduire comment toute cette collection de musique instrumentale avait pu ~e utilisee. De plus, apres l' etude des inventaires subsistants de San Pedro, on a pu reconstruire le repertoire musical polyphonique dans son entier. Ceci nous permet de voir la collection musicale disponible du chantre ou maitre de chapelle typique du temps, ainsi que la place qu' occupait le repertoire des menestrels. Finalement un nombre significatif de manuscrits et imprimes a ete retrace dans les collections modemes, nous permettant d' en connaitre. fr</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x927c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bm28r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Church music -- Catholic Church -- 17th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church music -- Spain -- 17th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iglesia Colegial de San Pedro (Lerma, Spain). Archivio. Manuscript. Mus. 1</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church music -- Spain -- 16th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church music -- Catholic Church -- 16th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sacred vocal music -- 16th century -- Scores</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sacred vocal music -- 17th century -- Scores</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v372m"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geology, geochemistry and genesis of Montauban lead-zinc deposits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prabhu, Mohan Keshav</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lithogeochemical investigations were carried out in and around the Montauban polymetallic deposits of the Grenville Province, Quebec. A number of chemical criteria used to distinguish sedimentary and igneous protoliths for the ore host rocks were tested and found to be weak in their discriminating capabilities. Critically evaluated chemical criteria show that the protoliths for quartzofeldspathic gneisses, quartz-rich rocks, and host rocks were mainly siliceous sediments and intercalated carbonate lenses. Hornblende gneisses of the Montauban area are orthogneisses. They and other orthoamphibolite rocks in the study area have a tholeitic affinity. Incompatible element chemistry suggests that they were formed in an island-arc (including back-arc) environment. Alteration associated with the Montauban Pb-Zn deposits is weak and has a narrow lateral extension with erractic chemical halos close to the ore-bearing zones. A CaO-rich zone extends up to 140 m laterally to the east from the calc-silicate ore zone, and an anomalous MgO zone extends on both sides of the cordierite-anthophyllite ore zone into the quartzofeldspathic gneisses. The cordierite-anthophyllite gneiss host rock is more anomalous in Zn, Pb, Cu and Au than the calc-silicate host rock. Erractic high concentrations of Zn and Au occur within the quartzofeldspathic gneisses close to both ore-bearing zones. Copper and Au occur at slightly greater depths than Zn and Pb within the deposits. The Montauban Pb-Zn deposits were formed in a mainly sedimentary environment, probably by exhalative processes, and were metamorphosed to the almandine-amphibolite facies with the enclosing sediments.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p53r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v372m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mineralogy -- Québec (Province) -- Montauban Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lead ores -- Québec (Province) -- Montauban Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geochemistry -- Québec (Province) -- Montauban Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zinc ores -- Québec (Province) -- Montauban Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s543v"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>No more than simple justice : the Royal Commission on the status of women and social change in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morris, Cerise</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study documents a process of planned social change. In 1967, the Canadian government appointed the Royal Commission on the Status of Women (RCSW) following a campaign mounted by a coalition of women's groups to promote women's rights. The Commission helped to define the status of women as a legitimate social problem, recommended changes in social policy, and helped to mobilize a constituency which pressed the government to implement the recommendations. The existence of an organized and vocal women's movement strengthened the Commission's demand for "simple justice." The Report of the Commission was tabled in 1970, and the government responded to it by creating a federal policy system for promoting women's rights. The study assesses the different outcomes of the 167 RCSW recommendations over a ten-year period and it discusses the relationships between the women's movement, a governmental commission of inquiry (RCSW), and public policy on the status of women in Canada.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx15d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s543v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Royal Commission on the Status of Women in Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women's rights -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526c966"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure and viscoelastic properties of telechelic polymers and dynamic and dielectric properties of ethyl acrylate-based ionomers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Polatajko, Elsa S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes an investigation of the structure and viscoelastic properties of telechelic polymers as well as the dynamic and dielectric properties of ethyl acrylate-based ionomers, a material of medium dielectric constant. Stress relaxation studies of low molecular weight sodium carboxylate-terminated polystyrene and polybutadiene will show that time-temperature superposition does not hold for samples with greater than 6 mole % ion content. It is shown that two mechanisms are operative, the first proceeding with an activation energy of circa 600 kJ/mole and the second proceeding with an activation energy of circa 142 kJ/mole at T(,g) and at a rate of 2.9 x 10('-6) sec('-1). The dynamic mechanical and dielectric properties of a series of ethyl acrylate-based ionomers are described in the second part of this thesis. The results are consistent with the hypothesis that below 12 mole % the ions form simple multiplets which act as transient cross-links, while above that concentration cluster formation is encountered.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nf40t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526c966</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ionomers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36tz19c"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enzymatic studies on GM1 ganglioside biosynthesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rabinowitz-Kaplan, Fëıge</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An enzyme that catalyzed the terminal step in GM(,1) ganglioside biosynthesis was demonstrated in rat brain and rat liver microsomal preparations. This galactosyltransferase enzyme could be solubilized from the Golgi fraction of rat liver homogenates. Anion exchange chromatography resolved two distinct enzymes with activity toward GM(,2) ganglioside. These two activities could be distinguished by such properties as pH optima, detergent requirements, and isoelectric points. The two enzymes had similar molecular weights and cation requirements. Extensive characterization of the acceptor specificities of galactosyltransferase enzymes present in solubilized Golgi preparations led to the identification of five enzyme reactions. Two activities were identified which had a requirement for acceptors within the glycoprotein family. A single activity supported the biosynthesis of GM(,1) ganglioside only. The fourth galactosyltransferase activity catalyzed the incorporation of galactose into both ganglioside and glycoprotein.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kr08m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tz19c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Enzymes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gangliosides -- Synthesis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m0049"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Messianisme littéraire au Canada français, 1850-1890</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaudoin, Réjean, 1945-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject of this study is French-Canadian literature of the middle nineteenth century. This study effectuates an analysis starting with the very idea which constitutes the genesis of this national literature, that is, Messianism. This research consists of applying on a vast corpus of writing the principle concepts developed by the sociology of religions in the study of historical and contemporary Millenarist movements. The first chapters consolidate the sources of the providencial mission of the French-Canadian people within the greater Catholic tradition of French literature. Bossuet, de Maistre, Chateaubriand, Rameau de Saint-Pere were the thinkers who aroused interest among the writers of French Canada, and are thus subject of consideration. The second part of this study attempts to acknowledge the ripening of a local intellectual tradition, by considering diverse ideological writings which started by denying the specificity of literature, before eventually manifesting and incorporating literary qualities. Finally, a study based on same concepts examines works of the period by Frechette, Casgrain, Tache, de Gaspe, Gerin-Lajoie and Buies; works that are clearly literary in nature. The results of this study clarify within a global perspective the set of questions which have always been posed about French-Canadian literature while at the same time connect literature to the development problems of this society.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306sz83v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m0049</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French-Canadian literature -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741s40h"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Yves Bonnefoy et la phénoménologie du dire poétique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chatterjee, Usasi (Usasi Goswami)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La these se propose d'analyser la specificite du dire poetique d'Yves Bonnefoy, tant sur le plan du rapport entre theorie et pratique, que comme rapport organique entre la "parole" et la "phenomenologie". La negativite servira comme principe methodologique, permettant de distinguer entre la phenomenologie husserlienne de la conscience, fondee sur une theorie apodictique de la connaissance, et une phenomenologie du dire, ayant comme visee le sens, ou la presence de l'etre, et se proferant dans l'existence sensible. La these delimitera l'homologie structurelle et thematique entre la parole de Bonnefoy et de Heidegger, a partir de la finitude dans sa double dimension de dereliction et de transcendance, ce qui permettra de deboucher sur la valeur redemptrice du sacre. La phenomenologie du dire se dissociera egalement d'une analyse linguistique, opposant au "textualisme", la presence vivante d'une parole ouverte, soucieuse d'instaurer, au sein de l'existence hic et nunc, le sens destinal de l'homme.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t655.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s40h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phenomenology and literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bonnefoy, Yves -- Language</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heidegger, Martin, 1889-1976</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bonnefoy, Yves -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Husserl, Edmund, 1859-1938</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pq947"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Thymus and bone marrow immune functional defects associated with histopathological alterations in the thymus induced by a graft-versus-host reaction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Seddik, Mona</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Graft-versus-host reactions induced thymic epithelial cell injury, which was associated with a block in T cell maturation. No suppressor cells were detected in these thymuses. Thymic epithelial cell injury neither affected the acquisition of theta alloantigen nor interfered with homing of haemopoietic stem cells to the thymus, however, it impeded the ability of GVH thymuses to process the normal haemopoietic cells into mature T cells. GVHBM cells repopulated the lymphoid organs of irradiated normal mice, and restored cell mediated humoral and splenic PHA, and ConA responses when transferred into T cell deprived mice. The GVH reaction also induced B cell functional deficiencies. No suppressor cells were detected in the GVHBM. However, the colony forming ability of GVHBM cells was significantly decreased. Thus, the GVH reaction resulted in a block of both T and B cell maturation which explained, at least in part, why GVH mice remained permanently immunosuppressed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149q52k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pq947</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>