<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816q42t"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agronomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of some commercial fertilizers on the botanical composition and yield of permanent pastures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nowosad, Frank S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pastures occupy a large part of the total land area of the world. According to the 1931 International Year Book, 24.4 per cent of the total land area in twenty-six countries of the world, were classed as pasture in 1930 (Table I, Appendix). This area in pasture was 1.6 times the area of the total arable land. Great Britain had the highest and Australia the lowest percentage of the total area in pasture, having 56.8 and 0.3 per cent respectively. Canada had 4,002,000 hectares or 9,888,942 acres, which represented 15.8 per cent of the arable land and only 0.4 per cent of the total area. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McKibbin, R. R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806296p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q42t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fm02x"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>English domestic tragedy from 1731 to 1800</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Montgomery, Harriet Rose</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tragedy is an inheritance from Greece and Rome, which was not accepted by Western Europe until the Renaissance. The mediaeval religious drama and the few plays which had precededthe classical plays were not definitely classified as tragedy. Renaissance and pseudo-classical theorists turned to Aristotle's "Poetics" for rules governing tragedy. The "Poetics" may be the fragmentary notes of one of Aristotle's pupils, jotted down as he listened to his master in the shady walks of the Lyceum. Aristotle's method was analytical; he studied plays and gave his opinion as to their principal characteristics. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Files, H. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf72r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm02x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xm605"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Action of sulphurous acid on cellulose</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moore, Leonard Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A knowledge of the action of sulphurous acid on cellulose is important not only from a technical, but also from a purely scientific viewpoint. Thus, on the one hand it is likely that the action of small amounts of sulphurous aoid play an important role with respect to the permanence of "paper" (lA), while on the other hand, the behavior of cellulose (in the form of sulphite pulp) towards sulphurous aoid, under varying conditions of temperature, time and concentration are as yet unknown, although such knowledge is of very great importance to the manufacture of sulphite pulp. In the preparation of the latter material, the wood chips are heated with solutions of sulphurous acid, containing calcium and magnesium bisulphites to remove the lignin. Little or no attention has been paid, hitherto, to the changes brought about in the cellulose itself by the sulphurous acid. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hibbert, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r4003.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm605</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dq19j"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The specific viscosity of acetaldehyde and of acetaldehydeparaldehyde mixtures and a study of the oxidation of allyl alcohol by permanganate in an acid medium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mason, Clarence Tyler</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acetaldehyde spontaneously undercges two reactions ; oxidation in the presence of air or oxygen, and polymerization to more complex polymers. Through former researches done in thislaboratory , end the work of Bowan and Tietzi, we know that acetaldehyde and oxygen react when they come into contact in the gaseous state to give rise to a per oxygen compound. This reaction is one where by the carbonyl group of the aldehyde is oxidized by the oxygen to a peroxy group. As a result of this reaction, acetaldehyde, when distilled in air or even when allowed to stand in contact with air, is always contaminate with small quantities of the peroxide compound. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hatcher, W. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z115m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dq19j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar781wk08d"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The industrial quality of the unemployed : with particular reference to occupational classification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morton, Nelson W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Among the essential characteristics of the industrial system which has constituted the core of our economic life for the past century and a half are two phenomena which form the theoretical starting-point for this study: unemployment, and the specialization of labor. The former might be termed a pathological symptom of the malfunctioning of our economic machmnery, owing its existence perhaps to several etiological factors, and exhibiting itself in accordingly different phases; while the latter is probably to be regarded as a necessary adjunct to a constantly increasing complexity of societal organization. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kellogg, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cd84j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk08d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q7057"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Botany</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The physiology of cold resistance in plants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levitt, Jacob</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Winter injury is a serious problem to agriculture in temperate climates the world over. Macoun (1908) states, "If one could make an accurate estimate of the number of fruit trees which have been Winter killed in the colder parts of Ontario and the Province of Quebec, the figures would be astounding, they would be so large. This has been the chief cause of the slow development of the fruit indnstry in the colder parts of Canada." Summing up the importance of injury in Michigan during eighty winters, Bradford and Cardinell (1926) maintain that "To countless individuals and numerons commities it has been a calamity and has entailed distress and bankruptcy." [...] </dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225f031.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q7057</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plants -- Frost resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plants -- Effect of cold on</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adz010t063"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of appreciation through creative self-expression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Binmore, Mary Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Any treatment of the theme of education for appreciation should be welcome to the growing company of thinking people who are casting about for means of restoring some measure of harmony and dignity to a world gone awry. For some time a crust of sanity has held the social structure more or less intact; but the gathering pressure underneath is now breaking loose into tremors and disruptions that leave us aghast at the possibilities of an overwhelming catastrophe to our civilization. There can be little doubt, however, that knowledge of society's present position, well seasoned by contemplative awareness to all life and thought, is essential for its reorganization. Many believe that this attitude can only be brought about by a widespread education designed to promote appreciation. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clarke</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569730v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t063</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Creation (Literary, artistic, etc.)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Creation (Literary, artistic, etc.) -- Appreciation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kd68d"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>New England in America literature since 1900</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Calder, Alice Delphine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>"I found two sortes of people, the one Christians, the other Infidels, these I found the most full of humanity and more friendly than the other." l So said Thomas Morton of MerryMount, one of the first of a long line of critics of New England Puritanism. Since then both the sins and the virtues of America have been laid at the door of Puritanism and the Pilgrim Fathers have been made the recipients of paeans of praise in commemoration speeches and of equally enthusiastic abuse from reactionaries. The one point upon which both parties meet is that Puritanism was a tremendous factor in the formation of American life and character: where they disagree is whether this force was for good or ill. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg85x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd68d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>New England -- In literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>English</dc:subject><dc:subject>American literature -- History and criticism -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752k816"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The action of sulfuric acid on cyclopropane ketones</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boyer, Raymond</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ever since the recognition of cyclopropane by Freund (l) there has been considerable experimentation and speculation upon the mode and ease of opening of the ring in the hydrocarbon and its substitution products by acidic and basic reagents. Perkin (2) first drew attention to the fact that the stability of the ring depended on the substituent groups present and that in many respects the rings resembled ethylenic compounds e.g. some take up water in the presence of dilute sulfuric acid whereas others do not. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Allen, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x219b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752k816</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans0648860"><ual:graduationDate>1933</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Unemployment Among Dock Labourers in Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bowker, E. Elwyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>"Unnemployment is still a problem of industry, not an act of God", wrote Sir William Beveridge in 1930, twenty years after the publication of the first edition of his classic,Unemployment: a Problem of Industry. The truth in this statement might be practically self-evident, but unfortunately its significance is not generally appreciated by lawmakers orlaymen, many of whom apparently consider unemployment a fortuitous and inevitable evil of our industrial order - a malady, the victims of which may be assisted through the crisesby the use of palliatives, but for which there is no specific treatment. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117r94d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0648860</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz8062987"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cyclic acetal formation, the Hibbert-Michael partition principle, and its relation to polysaccharide chemistry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trister, Saul Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Propionaldehyde, isobutyraldehyde, trimethylacetaldehyde, and dibromacetaldehyde have been condensed with glycerol, the isomeric five and six membered glycerol acetals isolated in each case, and their structure and physical properties determined and compared with those of related compounds. The ratio in which the two isomers are formed from the different aldehydes has been carefully determined in each case and shown to depend to a marked degree, on the polarity of the aldehyde in question. The ease of glycerol cyclic acetal formation {total mixed glycerol acetal formation) is shown to decrease, with increase in the negative polarity of the aldehyde group, while the proportion of the five to six membered acetal actually increases. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hibbert, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xz04s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8062987</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042w88w"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The structure of beech-wood lignin : an investigation into the isolation of lignin by the direct acetylation of beech-wood meal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>White, Elwood Vernon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The direct acetylation of a prepared beechwood meal has been carried out with a view to the separation of an acetylated lignin. The maximum solution by acetylation uas 76.7% of the lignin present in beech-wood. A separation of the acetylated lignin in high yield by preferential solvent extraction was not obtained. The soluble acetylated product was subjected to methylation followed by hydrolysis and a lignin fraction separated. The maximurn yield was 24.7% of the lignin present in beech-wood. The hydrolysed product was partially solublein dioxane. The dioxane soluble fraction was separated into an ether soluble and ether insoluble fraction. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hibbert, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gk338.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w88w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524jr81b"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agronomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of some commercial fertilizers on the chemical composition of pasture herbage in the eastern townships of Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stobbe, P. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper reports the results of chemical analyses made on samp1es of mixed pasture herbage collected from fertillized and unfertillized plots 1n 1931 and 1932 and of distinct species in 1932 only. The % nitrogen in the mixed herbage was significantly increased by an application of superphosphate, by lime and during the first year of the experiment by potash. The calcium and phosphorus contents in the mixed herbage were significantly increased only by superphosphate. The calcium: phosphorus ratio was decreased by superphosphate in 1931 and inoreased by lime in 1932. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raymond, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q444m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jr81b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mq51j"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quelques interieurs dans les romans d’Honoré de Balzac</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weston, Grace Edson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette these est une étude de quelques intérieurs dansles romans d'Honoré de Balzac; elle oomprend une analyse des impressions générales qui s'en dégagent pour voir si elles etablissent un rapport entre la psychologie du personnage et son milieu. Pour faciliter cette étude j'ai fait de ces intérieurs deux grandes divisions; les intérieurs de Paris et ceux de Province avec les subdivisions suivantes; les intérieurs de luxe, les intérieurs bourgeois et les intérieurs du peuple. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Furness, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm24n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq51j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623g46v"><ual:graduationDate>1935</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies in organic oxidation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Horwood, James Francis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The supply of hydrocarbons from natural gas and from petroleum oils alone is almost unlimited. The commercial significance of such a potential wealth of aldehydes and alcohols is as obvious as the technical importance of the nature of the combustion of hydrocarbon fuels, and both these considerations have prompted a great deal of research. To those who, perforce or perchance, are financially disinterested, the phenomenon of combustion is more attractive from a theoretical than from a practical point of view, and for this reason a multitude of catalytic reactions, which have been reviewed by Marek and Hahn (1), will find no further reference here. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hatcher, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nf06r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g46v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8s45qc71t"><ual:graduationDate>1935</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A photoelectric methods of measuring the surface of small particles with particular regard to its application to the problems of ore-dressing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hicks, H. Brodie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A review of modern progress in mining and metallurgical operations reveals no factor more significant than the steady reduction in the cost of concentrating and milling ores. New processes have succeeded one another with bewildering rapidity, and today the gradual perfection of flotation concentration is revealing possibilities of low costs and high recoveries undreamed of a few years ago. In the treatment of ores, the operations of crushing and grinding have ever been of prime importance. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McBride, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qq12m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qc71t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591c16w"><ual:graduationDate>1935</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Metallurgy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The recovery of copper, silver, and gold from sulfide ores and concentrates by processes including roasting, leaching and electrolysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Herzer, Richard Wilfrid</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Metals are found in nature occasionally native or elemental, but most often in a combined state, as simple or complex oxides, sulfldas, carbonates, or silicates. The metal in these compounds has a positive valenoe, that is each atom is oxidized by the removal of one or two valency electrons. In order to remove these and reduce the metal to the elemental state energy must be supplied. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stansfield, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nx56z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c16w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zk666"><ual:graduationDate>1935</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reactions of gold and silver in cyanide solutions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Holmes, Edward Lawson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The chemistry, of the cyanides in general, dates from the early eighteenth century, but the action of aqueous solutions of cyanide on gold was not noted until 1840. At that time the  Elkingtons (20) obtained a patent for gold plating electrolytically, using for the electrolyte a solution made by dissolving gold in potassium cyanide with the aid of an electrio current. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mennie, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc87r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk666</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn107201r"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The structure and properties of alkali lignin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marshall, Harry Borden</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Alkali lignin was prepared oy heating thoroughly extracted spruce wood-meal in an autoclave with 4% NaOH for 1 hour at 172 °. The crude product, on purification by precipitation from dioxan into ether was separated into two homogeneous fractions, Alkali Lignin A, insoluble in dioxan-ether, and Alkali Lignin B, soluble in dioxan-ether. Alkali Lignin A condensed with both 0- and p-bromphenol to form the corresponding substituted phenyl ethers, which gave identical analyses. On the basis of the bromine content of these condensation products, Alkali Lignin A corresponds to the empirical formula C67H7l023 (m.w.= 1244), and contains, as shown from the analyses of its acetylated and methylated derivatives, 6 methoxyl groups, 3 phenolic, and 4 aliphatic hydroxyl groups. Alkali Lignin A also condensed with two molecules of phenol, one in ether condensation, the other in nuclear condensation. This Phenol Alkali Lignin A has an empirical formula C79HSI024, and contains 6 methoxyl groups, 6 phenolic and 3 aliphatic hydroxyl groups, as likewise shown from its derivatives. The absence of carbonyl groups in both Alkali Lignin A and Phenol Alkali Lignin A was shown by the inability of the fully meLhylated derivatives to form methyl esters with diazomethane. On treatment with MeOH-HC1, tne methoxyl content of Alkali Lignin A increased by an amount corresponding to the introduction of two methoxyl groups. The smallest building unit for Alkali Lignin B corresponds to the formula CIOgHl07037, with a m.w. of 1996 and containing 9 methoxyl groups, g phenolic, and 3 aliphatic hydroxyl groups. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hibbert, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j220.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107201r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s5493"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Botany</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A karyosystematic investigation in the Gramineae</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hunter, A. W. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The history and present state of the classification of the Gramineae is briefly reviewed. Some of the different characteristics on which phylogenetic systems have been based are considered. The subject of chromosome morphology is discussed in detail, and the application of idiograms and karyetypes to taxonomic studies is explained. The main purpose of the present study was to scrutinize and extend the findings of Avdulov who has recently published a monograph in which extensive changes, based on karyological studies, have been made in the classification of the Gramineae. Taking the grasses in order by tribes, Avdulov's results are summarized, to them are added the results of an original investigation of thirty-three species belonging to twenty-nine genera from ten tribes, and also new results from other workers. The evolution of different forms within the family is touched upon. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Huskins, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4307560.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s5493</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grasses</dc:subject><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d052q"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L’évolution des idées de R. Rolland sur la vie internationale</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Howie, Ruth Joyce</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dès son enfance Romain Rolland manifesta un goût spontané et précose pour les écrivains et musiciens étrangers à la France. Des relations personnelles avec Tolstoi, au oours de sa jeunesse l'orientèrent définitivement vers un idéal d'union et de fraternité internationales. La musique qui, pour lui oomme pour son héros Jean Christophe, se révéla comme "la lumière qui devait illuminer sa vie ft lui apparait alors comme un des plus grands liens mystiques entre les peuples. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lemaitre, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cx05b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d052q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rolland, Romain, 1866-1944 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vf41m"><ual:graduationDate>1934</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The geology and mineral deposits of the Beattie-Galatea area, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Halet, Robert Alfred Frans</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Beattie-Galatea area is in Duparquet and Destor townships, northwestern Quebec. The main points of interest are: recent gold discoveries, and a longstanding controversy over the age of some porphyry intrusions. The geological features of the area include an east-west band of Timiskaming sedimentary rocks, with Keewatin volcanic rocks to the north and south of it. It is believed that these formations are closely folded into a synclinorium. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>O'Neill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p3231.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf41m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zf11m"><ual:graduationDate>1936</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of bond between a steel beam and a superimposed concrete slab</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kirk, William Douglas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Reinforced concrete slabs supported by structural steel beams are frequently used in structures to carry superimposed loads. Unless the steel beams are haunched the bond between the steel and the concrete has a low, uncertain value. In designing steel beams where a concrete slab merely rests upon them, the beams have to carry the dead load due to their own weight and the weight of the slab, plus the live load and impact without any assistance from the slab. If the bond between the slab and the supporting beams had a high, dependable value, the slab and beams could be assumed to be a structural unit capable of supporting greater loads than if acting independently. The concrete slab would provide an excellent compression flange and the bottom flange of the beam would be more effective due to the increased distance to the top flange. The object to this research is to test the degree of structural unity between a concrete slab and a steel beam with four different types of plates welded to the top flange of the beam and from the data obtained evolve a rational method of designing composite structures.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jamieson, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zf12w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zf11m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil engineering and applied mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4j03d292v"><ual:graduationDate>1936</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Classics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sincerity of the Roman satirists</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brown, Margaret Frances</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>THE SINCERITY OF THE ROMAN SATIRISTS. "Facit indignatio versum."l "Difficile est saturam non scribere. n2 "Sum petulanti splene cachinno. n3 "Hie stilus haud petet ultro, ~uemquam animantem et me veluti custodiet ensis Vagina tectus.,,4 Very noble sentiments are expressed in' these statements of the three great Roman satirists in justifying their choice of this field of literature. We might accept them in their entirety without suspicion or caution, or again we might assume an attitude of incredulity. Did Juvenal really rage within his heart at the vices of the world, or was he an embittered poet with singular rhetorical powers? Was Persius actually downcast at man's apparent lack of reason and morality, or was he simply voicing his preceptor's axioms? And finally, could Horace possibly justify his attacks on the grounds of self-defense, or was he laughing at man 9nly to cut and wound all the more deeply? To clarify these pertinent questions, we must inquireinto what innate rights these Romans possessed to criticize their fellow-men. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thompson, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j85d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d292v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>LATIN LITERATURE -- HISTORY AND CRITICISM</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z3799"><ual:graduationDate>1936</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A new adiabatic calorimeter and some thermal properties of deuterium oxide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brown, Robert Stewart</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with the determination of some of the thermal properties of deuterium oxide. Precision measurements of the specific heats and latent heat of fusion of deuterium oxide are not only interesting in themselves but they may give some clue as to the degree of association of the molecules in the liquid state both of deuterium oxide and of ordinary water. For convenience of presentation this thesis is divided into two main sections each complete in itself with its own disoussion, index, and bibliography. A brief discussion of adiabatic calorimetry is given in the introduction. Section I deals with the determination of some thermal properties of deuterium oxide and is divided into two parts. Part I deals with the specific heats of the solid and the latent heat of fusion. Part II contains the determination of the specific heat of the liquid in a smaller calorimeter. In Section II a full description of the design and method of operation of the new calorimeter is given. This section also presents further results on the specific heats of the liquid deuterium oxide. A general discussion and summary conclude the thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barnes, W.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Maas, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt512.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z3799</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Deuterium oxide -- Thermal properties</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>