<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795b99s"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Zoology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The growth, morphology and relationship of the species of Pacific Salmon and the Steelhead trout</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Milne, Donald Johnston, 1916-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study of the Pacific salmon, sockeye (Oncorhynchus nerka, (Walbaum), pink (0. gorbuscha. (Walbaum), spring (0. tshawytscha, (Walbaum)), coho (0. kisutch. (Walbaum)), chum (0. keta, (Walbaum)), and the steelhead trout (Salmo galrdnerlii, Richardson), was carried out during the summers of 1946 and 1947 in conjunction with the general programme of the Skeena River Salmon Investigation which has been conducted by the Fisheries Research Board of Canada since 1944. During the winter of 1946-47, while at McGill University, Montreal, Que., the morphometric data and systematic counts collected during the first summer were analysed and a male and female of each species were dissected. In the following winter at the Pacific Biological Station, Nanaimo, B. C , the analyses were completed by determining the growth from the scales and by incorporating such data collected during the second summer as was necessary for a sound interpretation of the results already obtained.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Berrill, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q27c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b99s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fishes -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salmon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fishes -- Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trout</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042x31z"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Word recognition as a function of retinal locus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mishkin, Mortimer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>No contemporary psychologist would deny that the problems of learning and perception are intimately related. But how they are related and the degree to which they are interdependent has never been considered systematically. Hilgard (6, p. 181) has pointed to what is in all probability the major stumbling block. Leading theorists have been too long preoccupied with either one or the other of the two fields of investigation, and it can be fairly said that they have neglected the relationship between them. Kohler (9, p. 192), for example, would have us believe that if past experience does exert an influence upon perceptual organization, “it must be restricted to particular situations”. Furthermore, those who believe otherwise “will have to support their theory by experiments of their own”. Certainly the evidence gathered in support of the Gestalt view (8), (10), (18) is voluminous and persuasive.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ferguson, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63t013s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x31z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Word recognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Retina -- Psychophysiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95053706"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The climate of Labrador and its effect on settlement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Montgomery, Margaret Robinson</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although Labrador is the oldest discovered portion of the North American mainland it has remained isolated from the general development of the continent and, even today, knowledge of its climate and geography is still far from complete. The establishment of weather stations throughout the Ungava Peninsula during the war has recently made available more material from which to deduce the atmospheric conditions of the region. The purpose of the present study is to examine the results shown by this slowly growing mass of meteorological data and from it and other existing records make some evaluation of climatic conditions and their influence on life and activity.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hare, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd90x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95053706</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Labrador (N.L.) -- Climate</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f462855t"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Families in debt : a study of the cases of a family agency from 1942-1948</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murphy, Viva</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Relief giving is a major function of most family Weifare Agencies. Even where governments provide social security measures through Public Welfare, relief from such sources is seldom adequate, if we define adequate relief as “That which Covers the deficit existing between the budget and the family earnings and what relatives give.” Where relief is given through private agencies it is rarely adequate to meet the full needs of a family or individual. This inadequacy is associated with a large problem which clients bring to the attention of the agency, that of indebtedness. They only ask for help with indebtedness when the situation is beyond their ability to cope with it, or when it has become acute, usually through threatened action on the part of a creditor.[...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333562g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462855t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr172138t"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies in 'suppression'.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sloan, Norman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Factors influencing and effecting a decrease or an increase in function have been the subject of much inquiry. Experimental investigations into the functions of the nervous system brought early rewards along the lines of increase in function resulting from its excitation. However, as Ferrier stated in 1876: “There is no reason to suppose that one part of the brain is excitable and another not. The question is, how the stimulation manifests itself”.[...] This thesis will be presented in three parts, with a final general discussion and summary. Part I will deal mainly with the electrical characteristics of “suppression”; Part II with the motor aspects of “suppression”, as well as other somato-motor effects excited from the anterior limbic cortex; and Part III with the autonomic aspects of the anterior limbic regions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jasper, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9033166.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172138t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b6616"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Negative resistance loading of transmission lines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nachfolger, Nathan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...] A search through the literature has revealed that except for the proposals and claims contained in the patents of Bullington and Edwards, no investigations of either a theoretical or experimental nature have been undertaken to show how negative resistance elements might be employed to improve the transmission characteristics of wire lines. The writer has therefore decided to undertake a theoretical investigation of this new “Negative Resistance Loading Process” with the objectives listed below: Synopsis of Research to be Undertaken (1) To review the causes of distortion in transmission lines with the object of showing the extent to which they could be eliminated through a reduction in the line resistance. (2) To determine the nature of negative resistance elements and the manner in which they may be introduced into a transmission line such that they cancel a portion of the positive resistance of the latter. (3) To establish the criteria for stability of transmission lines embodying negative resistance elements. (4) To determine the required spacing interval between negative resistance units. (5) To determine the factors governing the design of negative resistance loading elements to give specific transmission characteristics. [...] (9) To determine the adaptability of this new process into the existing telephone plant. In this connection, the writer feels that a number of his proposed applications might be of a patentable nature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg85h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b6616</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1544bs68g"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Introduction to hyperbolic number theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Smith, Norman E.</ual:dissertant><ual:supervisor>Williams, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q67p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bs68g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At148fm371"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The action of liquid ammonia on maple wood</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Neubauer, Lewis Gregory</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1947 M.M. Yan carried out an investigation in this laboratory on the solvent effects of liquid ammonia on woody materials, chiefly concerning himself with sugar maple wood. He found that liquid ammonia at 25° extracted nearly 6% by weight of maple wood, and the extract was separated into three fractions, acetamide 4%, “liquid ammonia lignin” 0.7%, and a polyuronide material 0.8%. The “liquid ammonia lignin” was investigated by Yan, and a possible formula was suggested. The nearly quantitative production of acetamide from the acetyl groups of the wood showed that the liquid ammonia cleaved any ester links that were present. This Inference suggested that the wood residue after liquid ammonia extraction might be chemically changed, and that components previously insoluble might then be capable of extraction. The present thesis is devoted to investigating this possibility. It was found that hot water could extract about 2% of polysaccharide material, not previously water-soluble, from the ammonia-extracted wood residue. This polysaccharide was a xylan - methoxyglucuronic acid complex, contaminated with pectic material, and the greater part of the work was concerned with attempts to purify it and to determine its structure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b920b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm371</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085p402"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An experimental study of collateral coronary circulation produced by transplanting the left mammary artery to the left ventricular myocardium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Niloff, Paul H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Considerable investigation has been carried out in an effort to develop a satisfactory procedure to augment the blood supply to the heart. The stimulus in this work has been great due to the high mortality and morbidity resulting from diseases of the coronary arteries. [...] Since medical therapy does not alter or diminish the progress of the underlying changes in the vessels, there is a need for surgical therapeutic measures. In eighty percent of cases coronary artery disease is not immediately fatal when first diagnosed; thus, surgical therapy may be employed to modify or prevent further progression of the disease which almost invariably follows. The present investigations were carried out to study the development of anastomoses between a transplanted left internal mammary artery and the vessels of the left ventricular myocardium. Previous work by Vineberg et al. [...] showed that in a dog a left internal mammary artery transplanted into the left ventricular myocardium could form anastomoses with the coronary circulation. In one series anastomoses occurred in forty-four percent of cases. The object of the present work was (1) to determine and clarify the factors responsible for the development of functioning anastomoses and (2) to determine whether such anastomoses would protect the myocardium against coronary occlusion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacKenzie, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g485.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085p402</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j860m"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The estimation of aldehydes in rancid fats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Novick, Seymour</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>[...]The investigation described in the present thesis represents an attempt to develop a satisfactory, simple method of estimating aldehydes in fats and oils. Attention has been largely concentrated on the Schiff reaction, and the objective has been the development of a modification of the Schiff test which will be at once more effective and more adaptable to routine use than existing modifications of the Schiff test.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chapman, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt822.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j860m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultrual Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36v164s"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bacteriology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The evaluation and comparison of the immune response in guinea pigs to infection with pneumococcis type I when treated with sulphonamides and when treated with penicillin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nunes, Doris S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has long been known that infection by pneumococci resulted in the development of a type specific immunity to the organism. Until recently, specific serum therapy has been the only means of effectively combatting pneumococcal infections. The advent of antibiotics, however, has now given us another potent therapeutic weapon, and has thus greatly modified the therapy of diseases of pneumococcic etiology. It has thus become of considerable interest and importance to determine whether the presence of various antibiotic drugs in the body modified or influenced the natural immunity response on the part of the host. It was in an attempt to elucidate this question that this study was undertaken.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murray, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752m09p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v164s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bacteriology &amp; Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azw12z8378"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Phase measurement in microwave fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ornstein, William</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Methods of evaluating the relative phase of energy samples taken in a microwave field are considered. It is shown that all such methods in present use involve comparison with some standard of phase shift, using a null method. Two circuits considered in detail are the conventional wave interference method and the Robertson “Homodyne” method. In the Robertson method signal energy is split into two paths. In the carrier path the original signal frequency traverses a calibrated phase shifter. In the sideband path the signal is converted into double sideband suppressed carrier energy and traverses a path into which are introduced unknown increments of phase shift. A null at a junction of the two paths is obtained when the carrier is in quadrature phase with the sidebands. A description of a laboratory setup of the Robertson circuit and its adjustment procedure are given. Experimental results are adduced to show the superiority of the Robertson method over wave interference for microwave phase measurement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woonton, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd224.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z8378</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r8623"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The artistic principles of Gerard Manley Hopkins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Orr, Paul Anthony</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gerard Manley Hopkins has long been accorded an honorable place among the English Poets of the last century. But until recently his value as a critic went unrecognized. With the full publication of his writings, however, there has been an increasing respect for his pungently expressed comments on his contemporaries. One critic has advisedly pointed out that from his letters “one could extract a handbook of critical aphorisms worth more to those who are now writing, than imitative study of what was peculiar in Hopkin’s verse,”. W. H. Gardner, perhaps the most balanced and thorough of Hopkins’s critics, after a careful consideration of the poet’s critical analyses, maintains: “To sum up, Hopkins’s critical remarks with their vigorous style and constant preoccupation with definite ethical and aesthetic standards, frequently reminds us of the honest and trenchant manner of Dr. Johnson ... Though he could at times be harsh and hypercritical, Hopkins’s taste was more catholic, his perception more versatile than that of Johnson, who had not enjoyed the advantage of early enlightenment at the feet of Wordsworth, Coleridge, and Keats. With Hopkins as with Johnson, however, it is usually difficult if not dangerous to disagree; in either case, disagreement always entails an exhilarating mental exercise, a salutary revision and reaffirmation of our own principles.”</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anderson, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf656.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r8623</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hopkins, Gerard Manley, 1844-1889</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77st192"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bacteriology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The kinds and distribution of bacteria in the air over northern Canada at altitudes over 5,000 feet</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pawlikowska, Anna M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ever since the middle ages, when the miasmatic theory gave a convenient explanation of plaques, people suspected the air of being a medium in which particles invisible to the naked eye are suspended and dispersed. In the 19th century the controversy over the question of spontaneous generation and the establishement of the science of bacteriology caused a great interest in the micro-flora of the air and thus originates a branch of science known now as aerobiology. Aerobiology as defined by the late F. C. Meier in 1938, is the study of aerial carriage of microscopic particles. Durham (1941) when quoting Meier’s definition suggested a slight modification of the above mentioned term to aeromicrobiology thus defining more clearly the actual field of investigation. At the present time the study of aerobiology as specified by The Committee on Apparatus in Aerobiology of the National Research Council (1941) is carried on by workers in several fields having a rather wide range of objectives. [...] 1. Sanitary air analysis and disinfection; 2. air borne pollen dissemination; 3. microorganisms in the upper air; 4. epidemiology of plant diseases; 5. insect population and migration in the air. In approaching the study of aerobiology we have to bear in mind the characteristics of the outer atmosphere that provides an infinite source of dilution, as compared with semi-enclosed atmosphere in which the dilution is restricted, thus facilitating the spread of infection.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kelly, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xw25d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77st192</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514np58w"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the carbonyl groups of oxidized celluloses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perlin, Arthur S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The technical importance of cellulose oxidations, which play an undesirable part in such processes as bleaching and dyeing, and in the slow degradation that occurs during use, has served to promote research on the nature of the basic reactions involved. Many oxidations have been investigated[...] Most oxidations appear to be greatly dependent on the physical state of the cellulose and yield complex materials having varying proportions of carboxyl and carbonyl groups. With a few notable exceptions, methods available for estimating these groups are not entirely trustworthy and there is need for dependable methods of a general nature which could be applied throughout the field of cellulose oxidations. This Thesis was undertaken to develop a method of differentiating between carbonyl groups located in the second, third and sixth positions of the glucose units in cellulose. The procedure adopted consisted of adding the elements of hydrogen cyanide to the carbonyl units and reducing the adducts with hydriodic acid to the corresponding hydrocarbon units. It was necessary to repeat Kiliani’s parallel work with glucose and fructose, carried out in 1885-1887, most carefully in order to establish the best experimental conditions. A cellulose modified by diverse treatments and oxidized with chromium trioxide, was chosen for the research, and advantage was taken of the opportunity to compare the relative merits of various published estimations for carbonyl groups in oxidized celluloses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xz26t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np58w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h277g"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the nicotinic acid oxidase of pseudomonas fluorescens</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pinsky, Alex</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The past twenty years have witnessed remarkable advances in the problems associated with the assay of accessory food substances by means other than biological assays. Chemical, spectrographic and microbiological methods have been applied with varying degrees of success; and the problems involved have exerted an appreciable influence over the entire field of biochemical analysis. More strictly physiological work has made it possible to assign specific biochemical functions to certain of the substances involved. A classic instance is the role of thiamine as a constituent of co-carboxylase. Research on the possible parts played by these substances in cell metabolism has, in fact, become a major subdivision of biochemical research. [...] The action of the organism is believed to be due to the presence of an enzyme system which is highly specific for the destructive oxidation of nicotinic acid and which has been provisionally named nicotinic acid oxidase. The specificity and activity of the enzyme are such that it can be applied to the determination of nicotinic acid. The research described in the present thesis is an extension of this work. It has centered round three main issues: (a) the elucidation of the mode of action of nicotinic acid oxidase by experiments involving the use of various analogues and inhibitors, (b) the isolation of nicotinic acid oxidase from the bacterial cell and (c) the identification of intermediate and end products of the nicotinic acid oxidation.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Common, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw001.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h277g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rm51j"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of German</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Franz Kafka und sein Vater : das Verhältnis der Beiden und dessen Einwirkung auf Kafkas Werk</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pratt, Audrey Eleanor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>So unterstreicht Kafka die Wichtigkeit seines lebenslanglichen Ringens mit seinem Vater.Es war ein Kampf um Anerkennung,voller Irrtum, Angst, Verachtung,und Schmerz, den der Dichter mit Willen und beinahe mit lust hinnahm. Franz Kafka wurde am 3«Juli 1883 in Prag geboren. Die eigentumliche Atmosphere Prags.besonders die der alten Stadt,machte einen tiefen Eindruck auf den empfindsamen Knaben.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Graff, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n20q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm51j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kafka, Franz, 1883-1924 -- Family</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tz37k"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A northern pastoral : a novel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Purcell, Donald</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gilles Dupuis, a day laborer, is unhappy in St. Joachim. He does not feel that the community accepts him. He marries and becomes a colonist in the new colony of Lac Epinette, a colony opened by the new Duplessis government. At Lac epinette Gilles learns to depend on others, and he learns that others depend on him. He returns to a practice of the faith and he attains a modus vivendi with society. A Northern Pastoral is a study in fictional form of Franco-Canadian rural life. The novel is an attempt to present to English speaking people a picture unfalsified by language differences, cultural strangeness, and national prejudice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Files, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp234.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz37k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hv792"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Standardization of a closed field intelligence tests for rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rabinovitch, Mortimer Sam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Some fifty years ago, Thorndike, (11), Small, (10), KLine, (5), and others, began systematically to study psychological aspects of animal behaviour. These early investigators used various kinds of mazes and problem boxes to describe the variables under examination. Since these pioneer attempts, new mazes and problem boxes have been designed, and a great deal of the research carried on in the field of comparative psychology has involved mazes of one type or another. A different “type of maze, designed by Hebb and Williams, (3), to evaluate rat intelligence, has provided the most recent improvement in animal testing apparatus. This thesis reports the development of an improvement of the Hebb and Williams intelligence test, and presents measures of reliability and validity for the use of this procedure and apparatus. The traditional procedure in the evaluation of rat intelligence is to test the animal’s learning ability in a maze and infer from this behaviour the animal’s level of intelligence. “While the mazes and problem boxes used in this procedure vary greatly in design, they all have certain characteristic disadvantages.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rosvold, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q471h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hv792</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>PSYCHOLOGY, COMPARATIVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RATS</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88ck86j"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An exploratory investigation of the relationship between kinesthesis and certain industrial motor skills</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rankin, Winston Bertram</ual:dissertant><ual:supervisor>Webster, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr05t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ck86j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Motor ability -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Motor ability -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j333563r"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Properties of the higher benzene-polycarboxylic acids and their isolation from wood lignins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Read, Donald Earle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Numerous studies of the degradation of spruce lignin, both isolated and in the wood, using the techniques of fusion, hydrolysis, mild oxidation and hydrogenation, have shown that the greater part of this complex material is composed of guaiacyl radicals joined to a substituted propyl side chain. Quantitative studies of these degradations have, however, failed to account for more than approximately 70% of the lignin complex. [...] Since phenolic compounds are thought to yield no benzenepolycarboxylic acids when similarly oxidized, the production of the latter from lignin suggests that not all of the lignin molecule is based on guaiacyl or similar phenolic units. A thorough investigation of such oxidations of various lignins therefore appeared highly desirable. The procedures employed by the earlier workers were repeated, but it was soon found that the methods reported in the literature for isolating and separating the benzenepolycarboxylic acids from the debris of an oxidation of lignin were quite inadequate. New methods of isolation and identification were required [...] Various lignins isolated from spruce wood, spruce wood itself, and a commercial alkali lignin from poplar wood were then oxidized and the products examined with the help of the procedures for isolation and separation devised from the study of the individual acids.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k1277.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333563r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qq391"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La paysannerie dans les romans d’Honoré de Balzac</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Richard, Oneil Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>En France on se sert du mot paysannerie pour désigner la partie du peuple français qui cultive la terre et qui retire de son travail agricole la somme totale ou partielle de ses ressources, soit comme propriétaires soit comme ouvriers. Cette classe, bien entendu, est loin d’être uniforme. Comme toutes autres classes sociales, elle a son aristocratie et elle a ses pauvres. II y a, par exemple, une grande différence entre le laboureur. descendant du franc tenancier, qui possède un petit lopin de terre, qui vit exclusivement de la culture de son champ et qui est fier de son indépendance, et le domestique. qui, loué a l’année, dépend de son employeur pour sa nourriture et son logement. Aussi les caractères et les moeurs diffèrent-ils largement dans les diverses régions de la France. Cependant, il y a un trait commun a toute cette partie du peuple français: c’est que les paysans sont tous près de la nature. Aisés ou pauvres, ils sont tous en contact direct avec la terre. Quand un paysan enrichi met de cote ses outils pour vivre dans une aisance complète, il cesse d’être paysan dans le vrai sens du mot. Seul celui qui manie les outils du champ peut se reconnaître vrai paysan. Le vrai paysan est celui qui laboure la terre et qui sème les champs, qui houe et qui pioche et qui bêche les récoltes qui poussent, qui récolte les fruits de ses longs et durs travaux. C’est lui qui taille les vignes dans les pays vignobles. C’est lui qui fait paître les bestiaux dans les montagnes.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Launay, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r428s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq391</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75rc13h"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of vertical motion in radar patterns of rain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rigby, Elizabeth Caroline Grey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In a study of the measurement of rainfall by radar Marshall, Xangille and Palmer ( l ) have derived formulae relating the intensity of the power received at the radar from rain to the size of the drops, and so to the intensity of the rainfall. [...] It is the purpose of the present paper to analyse some films similar to those used by Langille and Gunn with a view to studying particularly the vertical motion of the showers, and to compare the film observations and the experimental drop-size distributions with the results arrived at through various theoretical considerations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marshall, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw927.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc13h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g820g"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The design of discriminators for subminiature frequency modulated transceivers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rioux, Philip Gregory</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to investigate the design of discriminators suitable for use in portable frequency modulated transceivers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Howes, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f19q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g820g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085p41b"><ual:graduationDate>1949</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of electroconvulsive shocks on the performance of the rat in the closed field test</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rishikof, Jack Richard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the introduction of electroconvulsive shock therapy into Psychiatric practice, extensive research has been carried out to discover any deleterious effects of the shock. Learning and retention have received particular attention. Although the majority of the studies report no decrement in learning and retention in the rat after a series of electroconvulsive shocks, a few studies do indicate some impairment of these functions. In view of the conflicting results reported, it was feit that a more sensitive instrument was needed; the ‘closed-field’ test (10) appeared to be such an instrument. Accordingly, the basic studies on the effects of electroconvulsive shock—that is, the effects on learning and retention in both infants and adults—were repeated using this apparatus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rosvold, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg06c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085p41b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>PSYCHOLOGY, COMPARATIVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RATS</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>