<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g4551"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of pulsed electric fields on structural modification and rheological properties for selected food proteins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xiang, Bob</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RÉSUMÉ L'utilisation de champs électriques pulsés (CEP)                dans la transformation d'aliments est une technique de pointe qui nécessite des                études approfondies. Une meilleure compréhension de l'effet de traitements CEP sur                les modifications structurales, l'hydrophobicité en surface et les propriétés                rhéologiques de protéines alimentaires est nécessaire à l'application de cette                méthode pour l'amélioration des propriétés fonctionnelles de protéines alimentaires                dans les systèmes alimentaires. Deux principaux paramètres CEP furent étudiés:                l'intensité du champ électrique, variant de 12 à 25 kV cm-1, et le nombre de                pulsions, variant de 10 to 120. L'effet de traitements CEP sur les modifications                structurales, l'hydrophobicité en surface et les propriétés rhéologiques de certaines                protéines alimentaires furent étudiés par spectroscopie fluorescente et analyse                calorimétrique à compensation de puissance (ACCP) et diverses techniques rhéologiques                Un isolat de protéine lactosérique (IPL), un isolat de protéine de fève soja (IPFS),                du lait de soja et du lait écrémé reconstitué servirent dans cette étude. La                modification structurale, l'hydrophobicité en surface et les propriétés thermiques de                l'IPL et de l'IPFS furent modifiées par les traitements CEP. L'enthalpie Un isolat de                protéine lactosérique (IPL) a diminué avec les traitements CEP. L'enthalpie apparente                et les températures de dénaturations des échantillons de IPL ont été modifié après                les traitements. La lactalbumine indigène restante était environ de 56% après un                traitement de PEF de 20 kV cm-1 et 30 pulsions. Ces traitements augmentèrent à la                fois la fluorescen</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>ABSTRACT The application of pulsed electric fields (PEF) in food                processing is a novel technique that requires careful study. An improved                understanding of the effects of PEF treatments on structural modification, surface                hydrophobicity, thermal properties and rheological properties of food proteins is                needed for the application of this method to the improvement of functional properties                of food proteins in food systems. Two main PEF parameters were studied: electric                field intensity ranging from 12 to 25 kV cm-1, and number of pulses ranging from 10                to 120. PEF effects on the structural modification, surface hydrophobicity, thermal                properties and rheological properties for selected food proteins were investigated                using fluorescence spectroscopy and differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) along                with rheological measurements. Whey protein isolate (WPI), soy protein isolate (SPI),                soy milk and reconstituted skim milk were used in this study. The structural                modification, surface hydrophobicity and thermal properties of WPI and SPI all                changed with PEF treatments. The enthalpy of whey protein isolate decreased with PEF                treatments. The apparent enthalpy and denaturation temperatures of WPI samples were                modified by PEF treatments. The remaining native whey protein was about 56% by a PEF                treatment of 20 kV cm-1 and 30 pulses. The intrinsic tryptophan fluorescence                intensity and the extrinsic fluorescence intensity of whey protein and soy protein                all increased with PEF treatments. The intrinsic tryptophan fluorescence of whey                protein and soy protein appeared as a red shift of 2-6 nm. The extrinsic fluorescence                of whey protein and soy protein appeared as a blue shift of 2-6 nm with</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michael O. Ngadi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km50c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g4551</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698932z"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hope development in psychotherapy: a grounded theory analysis of client experiences</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chamodraka, Martha</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'espoir du client est depuis longtemps considéré comme                l'un des facteurs couramment observé ayant le plus d'impact sur les résultats                positifs en psychothérapie. La recherche sur la relation entre l'espoir et l'issue                favorable de la thérapie a produit des résultats prometteurs indiquant le besoin de                mieux comprendre les processus et les conditions selon lesquels l'espoir peut se                développer pendant la thérapie. La présente étude a examiné la trajectoire du                développement de l'espoir en fonction d'entrevues approfondies et semi-structurées                auprès de 17 clients demandant une consultation relativement à diverses                préoccupations dans un centre de counselling universitaire. Les clients ont complété                une évaluation de leur degré d'espoir avant le premier et après chaque entretien,                puis ont été interviewés lorsque leurs réponses indiquaient un niveau d'espoir                significativement plus élevé. Le récit des clients a été analysé selon la méthode de                théorie ancrée. Une synthèse des résultats fut effectuée de façon à produire une                théorie dynamique à multiples facettes, la théorie de l'espoir redonnant le pouvoir                (Hope as Empowerment Theory - HET), qui propose une vision intégrative de l'espoir                comme étant à la fois cognitive et affective et conceptualise l'espoir accru en un                plus grand contrôle du client sur le problème ainsi qu'une mise en direction vers le                changement positif. La compatibilité des préférences du client avec les interventions                du thérapeute fut observée comme augmentant la confiance du client dans le processus                de « counselling », et dans certains cas fut le tremplin menant à la manifestation de                l'espoir envers le ré</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Client hope has long been considered one of the most potent common                factors accounting for positive psychotherapy outcomes. Research on the relationship                of hope to successful outcome has produced promising results indicating the need to                discover the processes and conditions under which hope flourishes during therapy. The                present study examined the trajectory of hope development in psychotherapy based on                in-depth, semi-structured interviews with 17 counselling clients presenting at a                university counselling center with various concerns. Clients completed a measure of                state hope before the first and after every session, and were interviewed once their                responses indicated significantly higher levels of hope. Client narratives were                analyzed using grounded theory methodology. Findings were synthesized into a dynamic                and multifaceted theory, the Hope as Empowerment Theory (HET), which adopts an                integrative view of hope as both cognitive and affective, and conceptualizes                increased client hopefulness as a higher sense of control over the problem and as an                increased sense of direction toward positive change. The compatibility of client                preferences with therapist input was observed to raise clients' faith in the process                of counselling, which was in some cases the stepping-stone for gaining hope in the                outcome. A number of conditions, including the adaptability of client role                preferences and the directiveness of hope-inspiring therapeutic strategies, were                found to produce different types and varying degrees of strength of client hope.                Findings are discussed in terms of the need for therapists to inquire about and                consider client wishes and expectations, as well as to promote client</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marilyn R. Fitzpatrick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w03t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698932z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Guidance and Counseling</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322g158"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular and neurological effects of fenretinide on Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Skinner, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La Sclérose latérale amyotrophique (SLA) est la maladie                affectant les neurones moteurs adultes la plus commune. Il n'existe qu'un seul                traitement pharmacologique approuvé par la FDA ayant certains effets bénéfiques, soit                le Riluzole. Il est par ailleurs documenté que des concentrations d'acides gras                polyinsaturés (PUFA) peuvent affecter la progression d'un état neurodégénératif.                Cependant, la plupart des interventions s'appuient sur des suppléments nutritifs et                ont une efficacité à long terme plutôt limitée. Cette thèse décrit une série de                traitements utilisant le fenretinide, un rétinoïde synthétique capable d'altérer la                concentration de PUFA dans les membranes, dans un modèle de souris de SLA (souris                SOD1(G93A)). Les traitements ont entrainé un retardement du déclenchement de la                maladie avec une meilleure coordination motrice ainsi qu'une espérance de vie                améliorée. Le fenretinide a également accrue les niveaux plasmatiques de l'acide                docosahexaenoique tout en diminuant les niveaux d'arachidonate ainsi que les produits                de peroxydation lipidiques tel que malonyldialdehye et nitrotyrosine. L'analyse                immunohistochimique de la moelle épinière a révélé une réduction significative de                l'inflammation déterminé par la quantité d'astrocytes et de microglies activés                présentes. Ces résultats indiquent que le fenretinide représente un traitement                prometteur contre la SLA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) is the most common adult motor                neuron disease. Currently there is only one modestly beneficial pharmacological                treatment, Riluzole, approved by the FDA. It has been documented that polyunsaturated                fatty acid (PUFA) concentrations can affect the progression of neurodegenerative                conditions however most interventions rely on nutritional supplementation and have                limited long-term effectiveness. This thesis describes experiments using fenretinide,                a synthetic retinoid capable of altering membrane PUFA concentrations, in a mouse                model of ALS (SOD1(G93A)mice). Our treatment resulted in delayed onset, improved                motor coordination, and increased life expectancy. Fenretinide also increased plasma                levels of the ω-3 PUFA docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) while decreasing ω-6 PUFA                arachidonic acid (AA) and products of lipid peroxidation malonyldialdehyde (MDA) and                nitrotyrosine (NT). Spinal cord immunohistochemistry revealed a significant reduction                in inflammation as assessed by the quantity of activated microglia and astrocytes.                These results indicate that fenretinide represents a promising treatment strategy for                ALS.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Danuta Radzioch</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw43x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g158</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn860"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of the boron nitrogen interaction and its influence on the catalysis of amide formation reactions by aromatic boronic acids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Li San Cheung, Ken</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The synthesis of two nitrogen containing aromatic boronic acids was                accomplished in the premise that the interaction between B and N would grant                hydrolytic resistance to a boronic ester intermediate in the catalysis of an amide                formation reaction. One of these catalysts, 2-(dimethylamino)methyl- phenylboronic                acid, gave comparable yields to known boronic acids catalysts, despite lacking                electron withdrawing groups and furthermore, without the need to remove water.                Following NMR investigations of the boronic ester intermediate formed during the                reaction, it was found that less of this intermediate was formed due to the presence                of the B-N interaction when compared to other boronic acids. It is postulated that                this interaction lowers the Lewis acidity of the boron atom, effectively causing                lower levels of formation of the desired intermediate. Higher than expected yields                are obtained, as a result of the molecule being a bifunctional catalyst and not as a                result of increased hydrolytic stability.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La synthèse de deux acides boroniques aryles, qui                contiennent une interaction B-N fut accompli; étant donné que cette interaction                puisse rendre l'ester de cette acide boronique, produite durant la formation d'un                amide, resistant à l'hydrolyse. Une de ces catalyseurs, l'acide boronique                2-(dimethyleamino)methylephenyle, produit un bon rendement dans une de ces réactions                sans que l'eau ne soit enlevée. Le rendement est comparable à ceux qui sont obtenus                par des acides boroniques connus qui contiennent un groupe qui retire des électrons                du système aromatique. Des analyses NMR ont déterminé que l'ester de l'acide                boronique se forme moins bien lorsque la molécule contient une interaction B-N. On                croit que c'est parce que cette interaction a comme résultat de réduire la capacité                de l'atome de bore d'accepter des électrons, devenant ainsi un acide de Lewis moins                fort. Le bon rendement lors des réactions de formation est attribué au fait que la                molécule est en elle-même, un catalyseur bi fonctionnel.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ulf Marcus Lindstrom</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r956w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn860</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s196w"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Distortion correction for diffusion weighted magnetic resonance images</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stinson, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diffusion magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is useful for studying the                diseased, dysfunctional, and healthy human brain. Unfortunately, this technique is                susceptible to geometric distortions that decrease the accuracy and value of the                data. A distortion correction algorithm must be used to remedy these issues during                post-processing. The purpose of this thesis is to develop, implement, and test a                distortion correction method for diffusion weighted MRI. A distortion correction                algorithm was designed and implemented and then tested on simulated and real human                brain datasets. The algorithm was found to work well for simulated datasets with                b-values up to and including b=2000 s/(mm*mm). Furthermore, the cause of distortion                correction failures were investigated. Failures are believed to be due to a                combination of reduced signal to noise ratio (SNR) and increased contrast differences                in datasets with higher b-values.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM) de diffusion est                utile dans l'étude du cerveau humain, tant en santé que dysfonctionnel ou atteint de                maladie. Malheureusement, cette technique est susceptible à des distortions                géometriques qui diminuent la précision et la valeur des données. Un algorithme de                correction de ces distortions doit être utilisé pendant le traitement des données. Le                but de ce mémoire est de développer, d'implementer et de tester une méthode de                correction des distortions pour l'IRM de diffusion. Un algorithme de correction des                distortions fut developé et implémenté, puis évalué sur des ensembles de données                cérébrales humaines simulées et réelles. L'algorithme fonctionne bien pour des                données simulées avec des valeurs b jusqu'à b=2000 s/(mm*mm). La cause des échecs de                la correction de distortion fut également étudiée. Les échecs sont attribués à une                combinaison de la réduction du rapport signal sur bruit (SNR, pour signal-to-noise                ratio) et de l'augmentation des différences de contraste, dans les ensembles de                données avec des valeurs-b plus élevées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gilbert Bruce Pike</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t815w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s196w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b065n"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Maximizing carbon uptake and performance gain in slag-containing concretes through early carbonation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Monkman, George Sean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions have been identified as a major                contributor to climate change. Current CO2 mitigation efforts focus on the removal,                recovery and disposal of CO2 at point sources. Finding beneficial uses of as-captured                or recovered CO2 is a critical challenge in greenhouse gas mitigation. This thesis                investigates the possibility of the beneficial use of carbon dioxide in precast                concrete production and the performance, both short-term and long-term, of the                concretes so produced. The calcium compounds in cementitious materials react readily                with carbon dioxide to convert CO2 to thermodynamically stable carbonates. The                reaction accelerates strength development and makes the technology appropriate for                early age curing. Paste, mortar and concrete samples were examined to quantify such                aspects as the carbon dioxide uptake, strength development, and durability of                carbonated concrete. It was found that the uptake by the cementitious binders was                significant. Compared to their theoretical capacity, cement could reach a carbonation                degree of over 25% when treated as pastes and about 20% when used as a part of                concrete. The study compared carbonation-cured and hydrated Portland cement concrete                and slag cement concretes in terms of their early strength, late strength, weathering                carbonation shrinkage, freeze/thaw durability, water absorption, and pH. The                carbonated concrete was generally comparable, or superior, to the hydrated concrete                except for the case of a 50% GGBF slag blend which had a slower strength development                due to reduced secondary cementitious reaction. A second method of binding carbon                into concrete was considered by carbonating ladle slag fines and us</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les émissions de dioxyde de carbone (CO2) contribuent de                façon importante aux changements climatiques. Les efforts actuels de mitigation du                CO2 se concentrent principalement sur la saisie, la récupération et le débarras du                CO2 aux sources ponctuelles. Trouver des usages bénéfiques au CO2 tel que la capturé                ou récupération représente un défi critique pour la mitigation des gaz à effet de                serre. Cette thèse examine la possibilité d'utiliser le CO2 de façon bénéfique dans                la production du béton préfabriqué, ainsi que la performance à court et à long termes                du béton ainsi produit. Les composés calcaires dans le ciment réagissent avec le                dioxyde de carbone pour convertir le CO2 en carbonates qui sont stables du point de                vue thermodynamique. Cette réaction accélère le développement de la résistance du                béton, ce qui rend la technologie appropriée pour des bétons à cure rapide. Des                échantillons de pâte, de mortier et de béton ont été examinés pour tenter de                quantifier certains aspects tels l'absorption du dioxyde de carbone, le développement                de la résistance et la durabilité du béton carbonaté. L'absorption du CO2 par les                liants dans le ciment fut importante. Comparé à leur capacité théorique, le ciment                pourrait atteindre un degré de carbonation de plus de 25% quand il est préparé sous                forme de pâte et de 20% quand il est utilisé dans le béton. L'étude a considéré des                bétons composés de ciment Portland et de ciment de scories, curés de façon                traditionnelle (hydratation) et curés par carbonatation, et a comparé leurs                résistance après 7 jours, résistance après 56 jours, résistance à la contraction lors                de la$</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yixin Shao</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc32k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b065n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rw31m"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of LASU1-mediated Mcl-1 degradation and its roles in apoptosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Warr, Matthew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'apoptose est une forme de mort cellulaire programmée                ayant été conservée évolutivement et qui demeure essentielle pour le développement                normal, pour le maintien de l'homéostasie tissulaire et l'élimination des cellules                endommagées et de celles infectées par des virus. Mcl-1, une protéine membre de la                famille Bcl-2, joue un rôle de survie déterminant dans le développement et le                maintien des tissus tant sains que malins. En réponse aux facteurs de survie,                l'expression de Mcl-1 peut-être rapidement induite par induction de la transcription                de Mcl-1. Toutefois, son niveau demeure également régulé de façon étroite par                l'activité protéolytique du système ubiquitine-protéasome 26S. Un renouvellement                protéique rapide de la sorte joue un rôle essentiel dans l'initiation de l'apoptose                suite à l'inhibition de synthèse de protéine induite par le stress. J'identifie ici                une nouvelle ligase, LASU1, une E3 ligase de la famille HECT dite à BH3 seulement                (BH3-only) (maintenant aussi appelée Ureb-1, E3histone, ARF-BP1, Mule et HectH9).                LASU1 interagit de façon spécifique avec Mcl-1 par son domaine BH3 et Mcl-1                ubiquitinée in vitro. De plus, dans les cellules HeLa la dégradation de Mcl-1 par                protéasome nécessita LASU1, son absence conduisant à l'augmentation des niveaux de                Mcl-1 tel que cela fut observé dans nos expériences de knock-down de LASU1 par ARN                interférents. Un ligand compétitif à BH3 dérivé de Bim interagit avec Mcl-1 et                empêcha son interaction avec LASU1, augmentant ainsi les niveaux d'état stationnaire                de Mcl-1. Ceci suggèrait que la forme non ligandé de Mcl-1 puisse être                particulièrement sensible à la dégradation par l</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Apoptosis is an evolutionarily conserved form of programmed cell death                that is essential for normal development, the maintenance of tissue homeostasis and                the elimination of virus-infected and damaged cells. Mcl-1, a Bcl-2 family member,                plays a critical pro-survival role in the development and maintenance of both normal                and malignant tissues. Mcl-1 expression can be rapidly induced in response to                survival factors through induction of Mcl-1 transcription. However, its levels are                also tightly controlled by ubiquitin-dependent protein degradation by the 26S                proteasome. This rapid protein turnover plays an essential role in the initiation of                apoptosis following conditions of stress induced protein synthesis inhibition. Here I                present the identification of a novel BH3-only Hect E3-ligase, LASU1 (now also known                as Ureb-1, E3histone, ARF-BP1, Mule and HectH9). LASU1 interacted specifically with                Mcl-1 via its BH3 domain, and ubiquitinated Mcl-1 in vitro. Furthermore, LASU1 was                required for the proteasome-dependent degradation of Mcl-1 in HeLa cells as knock                down of LASU1 by siRNA increased Mcl-1 levels. A competing BH3-ligand derived from                Bim interacted with Mcl-1 and prevented its interaction with LASU1, causing elevation                of the steady state levels of Mcl-1. This suggests that the unliganded form of Mcl-1                is particularly sensitive to LASU1-mediated degradation. Following SDS-PAGE, Mcl-1                resolves into two isoforms, with the small isoform being less sensitive to                ubiquitin-mediated protein turnover. I found that this small isoform was the result                of alternative translational initiation at Mcl-1 codon 38 (human) or 34 (mouse). This                generated an N-terminally truncated Mcl-1 protei</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gordon C. Shore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p33q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw31m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cg19c"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of the «proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin 5» gene in high-density lipoprotein metabolism: potential implications for atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Iatan, Iulia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Low plasma high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) is a                well-established risk factor for coronary artery disease (CAD). The proprotein                convertase subtilisin/kexin 5 (PC5/PCSK5) is known to inactivate endothelial lipase,                enzyme critical in modulating HDL-C levels. In this study, we investigated the role                of human PCSK5 genetic variants on HDL-C. We examined haplotypes at the PCSK5 locus                in 9 multigenerational families with HDL-C&lt;10th percentile and discovered                segregation with low HDL-C in one family. We genotyped novel single nucleotide                polymorphisms (SNPs) found through sequencing and tagSNPs from the HapMap Project                (n=182 total) in 457 individuals with CAD and identified 9 SNPs associated with HDL-C                (P&lt;0.05), the strongest being rs11144782 (minor allele frequency 0.164,                p=0.002). This SNP decreased HDL-C by 0.076 mmol/L in a gene dosage-effect and was                also associated with very low-density lipoprotein (P=0.039), triglycerides (P=0.049)                and apolipoprotein B (P=0.022) levels. We conclude that variability at PCSK5                influences HDL-C levels and consequently, CAD risk.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le rôle protecteur des lipoprotéines de haute densité                (HDL) envers les maladies cardiovasculaires est documenté par un grand nombre                d'études épidémiologiques. Il est bien établi qu'un niveau bas de HDL-cholestérol                (HDL-C) représente un facteur de risque des maladies coronariennes. Des études                récentes ont démontré que la proprotéine convertase subtilisin/kexin 5 (PC5/PCSK5)                est impliquée dans l'inactivation de la lipase endothéliale, enzyme clé dans la                modulation des niveaux plasmatiques de HDL-C. Dans cette étude, nous avons examiné la                relation entre les variantes génétiques de PCSK5 et les niveaux du HDL-C chez                l'humain. L'analyse des haplotypes PCSK5 dans 9 familles multigénérationnelles                caractérisées par un HDL-C&lt;10e centile a montré une ségrégation avec des                niveaux faibles de HDL-C chez une famille. D'autre part, l'analyse génotypique des                polymorphismes de nucléotide simple (SNP) trouvés par séquençage et des tagSNPs du                projet HapMap (n=182 en total) dans 457 personnes coronariennes, a permis                l'identification de 9 variantes dans PCSK5 associées à une déficience en HDL-C                (P&lt;0.05), la plus forte représentant le rs11144782 (fréquence d'allèle mineure                0.164, P=0.002) et causant une diminution de HDL-C par 0.076 mmol/L dans une relation                gène dose-effet. Celui-ci à également été associé à des niveaux faibles de                lipoprotéines de très basse densité (P=0.039), des triglycérides (P=0.049) et de                l'apolipoproteine B (P=0.022). En conclusion, nos travaux indiquent que la                variabilité du gène PCSK5 influence les niveaux du HDL-C et conséquemment, le risque                des maladies coronariennes. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacques Jean Genest</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj200.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg19c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5138jg67p"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soil carbon in a grazed and ungrazed tidal marsh in the St. Lawrence Estuary</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yu, Olivia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le stockage de carbone dans les sols est un service                important dans l'écosystème des marais salants, mais ce service est-il maintenu lors                de l'utilisation agricole? Des moutons broutant sur l'Île Verte, dans l'estuaire                supérieur du fleuve du Saint Laurent, nous donnent l'occasion de mesurer si sept étés                de broutage ont négativement affecté le stockage de carbone de sol des marais salants                de latitude élevée. J'ai comparé des biomasses et des propriétés de sol dans les                sections broutés et intactes. La production à la surface et souterraine de la litière                végétale sont évaluées par la récolte à la fin de la saison, et les racines et                rhizomes dans des mesures d'échantillons de sols. Des propriétés édaphiques ont été                mesurées à partir d'échantillons de sol de 10 cm. Le marais brouté avait une densité                plus élevée de carbone de sol et de biomasse souterraine, mais une baisse de biomasse                en surface. Une plus grande densité de carbone de sol était attribuable au pâturage,                comme à cette latitude, le sol de marais reste gelé jusqu'en avril. Pendant le                printemps et l'été, une plus grande exposition solaire des sols réchauffe les sols et                apporte une plus longue période de croissance végétale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Soil carbon storage is an important ecosystem service of tidal salt                marshes, but is this service maintained under an agricultural use? Sheep grazing on                Quebec's Île Verte, in the upper estuary of the St. Lawrence River, provided an                opportunity to examine whether seven summers of grazing negatively affected soil                carbon storage in high latitude tidal salt marshes. I compared plant biomass and soil                properties in grazed and ungrazed sections. Above- and below-ground production was                assessed through plant litter, end-of-season standing crop, and roots and rhizomes in                ingrowth core measurements. Edaphic properties were measured from 10 cm soil cores.                The grazed marsh had higher soil carbon density and belowground biomass, yet lower                aboveground biomass. Greater soil carbon density was attributable to grazing, as at                this latitude, marsh soil remained frozen through April. Greater solar exposure of                grazed soils during spring and summer allowed for warmer soils and thus a longer                growing season for belowground growth.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gail L. Chmura</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr454.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jg67p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m1194"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Persistence and prevalence of the enzootic chytrid fungus, «Batrachochytrium dendrobatidis», in relation to amphibian population decline in Panama</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kilburn, Vanessa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The pathogenic chytrid fungus, Batrachochytrium dendrobatidis, causes                population decline and extinction of numerous species of tropical, principally                montane, amphibians. Is B. dendrobatidis an enzootic pathogen emerging as a disease,                or rather a novel invasive pathogen infecting naïve amphibians? Are only                high-elevation amphibians susceptible to the pathogen? If the chytrid is enzootic,                then it may be in the environment before or after epidemic decline and may infect                both montane and lowland amphibians as well as other organisms. To determine                distribution of the pathogen and corresponding anuran abundance, I established eight                research sites of varying elevations and stages of epidemic infection from west to                east, ranging from 45 m to 1215 m elevation throughout Panama west of the Canal.                Differential infection susceptibility among anurans was addressed in relation to                three ecological factors: anuran body size, season and habitat. Prevalence and                infection intensity of the chytrid were determined at all sites and for all factors                using sensitive DNA-based RT-qPCR amplification. Amphibian populations at all                elevations and stages of decline showed at least some degree of chytrid infection,                and the chytrid was found on reptiles. In addition to presence of the pathogen,                effects of the disease chytridiomycosis were variably seen at all elevations. Habitat                and season did not seem to have a strong effect on infection prevalence and/or                intensity, but frogs did appear to show greater infection at smaller anuran body                sizes. All of the above results are suggestive of an enzootic pathogen and perhaps                only the current epidemic of chytridiomycosis disease is novel. Since the infection</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le champignon pathogène chytrid, Batrachochytrium                dendrobatidis, cause la diminution et l'extinction de nombreuses populations                d'amphibiens tropicaux, principalement dans les regions à haute altitude. Si le                champignon est endémique, il peut rester dans l'environnement après le passage d'une                épidémie, contaminant les amphibiens des hautes et basses terres, ainsi que les                autres organismes. Les sites de recherche étaient établis à diverses élévations et à                différents stades de l'épidémie, à l'ouest du canal de Panama, où l'état des                populations d'amphibiens pouvait être examiné. L'hypersensibilité différentielle des                grenouilles à la maladie était adressée pour trois facteurs: la taille des                grenouilles, la saison et l'habitat. La prévalence et l'intensité de l'infection                étaient déterminées pour chaque facteur à tous les sites en utilisant la technique du                RT-qPCR. Les amphibiens de toutes les élévations et de tous les stades de l'épidémie                ont montré au moins un niveau d'infection, indiquant la présence d'un pathogène                endémique. Le chytrid a aussi été trouvé sur les reptiles. En plus de la présense du                champignon, les symptômes de la maladie chytridiomycosis ont même été remarqués sur                les grenouilles des terres basses. La prévalence de l'infection est restée similaire                pour les forêts et les ruisseaux, et aussi pour les deux saisons, et plus élevée pour                les petites grenouilles que pour les plus grosses. Puisque l'infection peut rester                dans les communautés amphibiennes à toutes altitudes, habitats et saisons, qu'elle                peut persister pour longtemps (jusqu'à 11 ans), et qu'elle peut survivre sur d'autres                organismes, la réintro</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roberto Ibanaez</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>David M. Green</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf636.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m1194</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Ecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mp13x"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>How neural activity underlies visual motion perception</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Masse, Nicolas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Over the last several decades, much progress has been made in                understanding how neurons in visual cortex encode various stimuli. However, it is                still unclear how their neural response underlies visual perception. The aim of this                thesis is to build upon our current understanding of how visual motion perception is                generated by sensory neural activity. Many interpretations on how sensory neural                activity is combined to form perceptual decisions rely upon the often-observed                correlation between neural activity and behavior. Due to its importance, it is                critical that we understand whether this correlation is an inherent feature in                forming perceptual decisions, or whether it is the result of factors outside the                brain. We found that microsaccades, which are small, involuntary eye movements,                contribute a small but significant amount to this correlation. This result reinforces                the view that the correlation is inherent in forming percepts, but its value has been                overestimated in several studies. Given that this correlation between neural activity                and behavior is genuine, on what timescales can it operate? We found that the                correlation between neural activity and behavior can exist on a timescale of about                ten milliseconds. Although our results do not say anything about how visual cortex                encodes motion in general, it does suggest that the brain is capable of extracting                information from neural responses on fast timescales. If neural activity can be                correlated with behavior on fast timescales, can electrical microstimulation be used                to demonstrate causality on this temporal regime? By comparing the temporal effects                of microstimulation on behavior to an equivalent visual stimulus, we f</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Pendant les quelques dernières décades, beaucoup de                progrès a été fait dans notre compréhension à savoir comment les neurones, dans les                cortices visuelles, encodent différents stimulus. Toutefois, il n'est toujours pas                clair comment les réponses neurales forment la base de la perception visuelle. Le but                de cette thèse est d'ajouter à notre compréhension concernant comment la perception                de mouvement visuel est générée par l'activité neurale sesnsorielle. Plusieurs                interprétations, concernant comment l`activité neurale sensorielle est jointe pour                former des décisions perceptuelles, comptent sur la corrélation souvent observée                entre l'activité neurale et le comportement. À cause de son importance, il est                crucial de comprendre si cette corrélation est un trait inhérant dans la formation                des décisions perpceptuelles ou si c'est le résultat de facteurs non reliés au                cerveau. Nous avons trouvé que les microsaccades, qui sont de petits mouvements                involontaires des yeux, font une petite, mais significante, contribution à cette                corrélation. Ce résultat renforce l'opinion que la corrélation est inhérente dans la                formation des perceptions, mais sa valeur a été surestimée dans plusieurs études.                Étant donné que cette corrélation entre l'activité neurale et le comportement est                authentique, sur quelle période de temps peut-elle opérer? Nous avons trouvé que la                corrélation entre l'activité neurale et le comportement peut exister dans une période                de temps d'environ 10 millisecondes. Bien que nos résultats ne disent rien concernant                commnet le mouvement visuel est encodé en général, ils suggèrent que le cerveau est                capable d'extraire de</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Erik Cook</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q73f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp13x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hm017"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Price and resource-related risk of the wind power business in electricity markets</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gomez Quiles, Catalina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A generalized mathematical model is developed that allows the                quantification of the economic risk of the investment in a wind farm under the two                most common revenue options defined by how the output of the wind farm is paid to the                owner: a) at a pre-established fixed-rate or, b) at the hourly electricity market                prices. Sensitivities are also characterized in order to determine the influence of                various market and resource-related parameters on the variability of the annual                revenue and the corresponding economic risk. Particular to the fixed-rate revenue                option, the developed model allows the owner of the wind farm to determine the                minimum necessary rate to meet a pre-established risk-return requirement. The model                is validated using actual wind power output and electricity market datasets.                Understanding the sources of risk in any investment is crucial for the development of                proper hedging strategies.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans ce travail, un modèle mathématique généralisée est                développé qui permet la quantification du risque économique de l'investissement dans                un parc éolien dans le cadre des deux options de rémunération les plus communes,                définies par la manière dont la production du parc éolien est rémunérée au                propriétaire : a) à un tarif fixe pré-établi ou, b) au prix horaire du marché                d'électricité. Des sensibilités sont aussi caractérisées afin de déterminer                l'influence de divers paramètres reliés au marché d'électricité et à la ressource                éolienne sur la variabilité des recettes annuelles et ses risques économiques. Dans                l'option de recette à tarif fixe, le modèle développé permet au propriétaire du parc                éolien de déterminer le tarif minimal nécessaire pour répondre à une exigence de                risque pré-établie. Le modèle est validé en utilisant des données réelles de                production d'énergie éolienne et du marché d'électricité. La connaissance des sources                de risque dans un investissement est cruciale pour la conception des stratégies de                couverture propres.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Francisco D. Galiana</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr46d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm017</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50gx909"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Functional dependency detection: an information theoretic algorithm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ophir, Adi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Il existe de nombreuses mesures statistiques de                corrélation, tels que le Pearson coefficient de corrélation des variables aléatoires,                le chi-carré pour les variables aléatoires discrètes et, finalement, l'information                mutuelle. La plupart de ces mesures sont symétriques et ne pas permettre la détection                d'influence. Nous proposons une nouvelle mesure de l'information-théorique dont la                valeur indique la direction de le dépendence fonctionnelle. La mesure algorithme de                calcul est effectué sur la valeur réelle de données quantifiées en bacs. Cette                quantification est une fondation de l'algorithme proposé, car elle informe à la fois                la signification statistique entre les variables et la force de la dépendance.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>There are many statistical measures of correlation, such as Pearson's                correlation coefficient for real random variables, the chi-square statistic for                discrete random variables, and mutual information. Most such measures are symmetric                and do not allow detection of influence direction. We propose a novel information                theory measure whose value indicates direction of functional dependency. The measure                calculation algorithm is performed on real-valued data being quantized into bins.                This quantization is a corner stone of the algorithm suggested, as it affects both                the statistical significance between the variables being tested for dependency and                the numeric strength of dependency.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Theodore J. Perkins</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967547d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gx909</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h1425"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Digital rotoscoping using Markov random fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Drouin, Simon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire présente un modèle statistique ainsi que son                implantation dans un programme de rotoscopie qui peut être utilisé pour la production                de films d'animation. Le problème de la segmentation assistée de scènes video                contenant un avant-plan et un arrière-plan distincts, un sous-ensemble du problème                plus général que constitue la rotoscopie, est utilisé pour analyser les propriétés du                modèle statistique et de son implantation. Le modèle statistique utilisé est                construit à partir d'un découpage de paires d'images d'entraînement composées d'un                cadre de la séquence video à segmenter et d'une image binaire qui défini la                segmentation associée. La segmentation de chaque cadre de la sequence est obtenue en                collant, pour chaque portion d'image, la portion d'image la plus similaire de                l'ensemble d'entraînement. Un mécanisme inspiré de la "propagation de                conviction"(belief propagation) est utilisé pour assurer la cohérence entre les                portions de l'image de sortie qui sont voisines. L'algorithme est appliqué à                plusieurs niveaux d'échelle afin de considérer la dépendance statistique de plus                longue portée qui existe entre les pixels d'une image. Une métrique est définie pour                mesurer la performance de la segmentation automatique. Les résultats de la                segmentation sont analysés à l'aide d'une série de séquences vidéo qui ont                préalablement été segmentées manuellement. Une nouvelle technique est également                présentée pour permettre au logiciel de segmentation de choisir automatiquement                l'ensemble d'entraînement optimal. Une segmentation grossière est d'abord obtenue en                ulitisant le plus petit ensemble d'entraînement possible (1 cadre)</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a statistical framework and its implementation in a                user-assisted rotoscoping program intended for the production of animation movies.                User-assisted video segmentation of scenes with well-defined foreground and                background, a special case of the general problem of rotoscoping, is used to analyze                the properties of the framework and its implementation. The statistical model used in                the framework is built from pairs of training images composed of a frame from the                sequence to segment and of a binary image representing the associated user-specified                segmentation. The segmentation for a new frame is generated by pasting in, for each                image patch, the nearest neighbor from the training set. A mechanism inspired by                belief propagation is used to insure consistency between neighboring patches. The                algorithm is applied at different scale levels of the input images to take into                account longer range interactions. A performance metric is defined for the automatic                segmentation and the segmentation results are compared with a set of video sequences                that have been entirely traced by hand. A new technique is also presented to                automatically choose the optimal training data for the statistical model. A crude                segmentation is computed from the smallest possible training set (one frame). A                statistical analysis of this segmentation is then used to determine which other                frames should be added to the training set in order to get the best possible                segmentation. Finally, it is shown how the technique used for segmentation can be                extended to perform example-based filtering of video and thus allow the creation of                general-purpose rotoscoping systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gregory L. Dudek</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc09j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h1425</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237ht56j"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating the genetic basis of germline quiescence in «C. elegans» dauers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Colella, Eileen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>When faced with unsatisfactory environmental conditions, young C.                elegans larvae can enter a diapause-like stage called dauer. The decision to form                dauer is controlled by three parallel signalling pathways (TGF-β, cGMP and                insulin/IGF-like signalling) that converge on DAF-12, a nuclear hormone receptor that                prompts either dauer formation or reproductive growth depending on the environmental                cues presented to C. elegans during its development. DAF-12 is related to the Vitamin                D, Liver-X, and Androstane receptors, and similar to these human NHRs, responds to                cholesterol-derived hormones. Ligand-bound DAF-12 has transcriptional activity                directing reproductive development, while unliganded DAF-12 forms a dauer-specifying                complex that regulates the transcription of genes required for dauer development with                its interacting protein DIN-1S. I report here that din-1S is required in the germ                cells upstream of insulin-like signalling (IlS) and in parallel to LKB1/par-4                signalling to establish dauer germline quiescence. I also observed that din-1S is                important for post-dauer reproductive fitness when IlS is impaired. Moreover, I                demonstrate that din-1S is necessary for long dauer life span in response to reduced                insulin signalling, either downstream of, or in parallel to, AMPK/aak-2. Finally, I                show that din-1S acts upstream of IlS pathway components to restrict somatic gonad                precursor cell proliferation during dauer development, and uncover a conditional role                for LKB1/par-4 signalling in this process.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Chez C. elegans, des conditions de croissance inadéquates                promeuvent l'entrée dans un stade de dormance appelé dauer. La décision d'entrer en                dauer est contrôlée par trois cascades de signalisation parallèles qui convergent sur                DAF-12, un récepteur d'hormone nucléaire qui, dépendamment des signaux                environnementaux qui se présentent à l'animal pendant son développement, l'incite à                entrer en dauer ou à croître reproductivement. DAF-12 est apparenté aux récepteurs de                la Vitamine D, des oxystérols et des androstanes et, comme ces récepteurs nucléaires                humains, réagit à des hormones dérivées du cholestérol. En présence de son ligand,                DAF-12 possède une activité transcriptionnelle qui dirige le développement                reproductif, tandis qu'en l'absence de cette hormone, DAF-12 forme un complexe                spécifique au stade dauer avec son partenaire DIN-1S et régule la transcription de                gènes requis pour le développement de ce stade. Mes analyses génétiques suggèrent que                din-1S est requis dans la lignée germinale en amont de la cascade de signalisation                par l'insuline et en parallèle de LKB1/par-4, afin d'établir la dormance des cellules                germinales pendant le développement du stade dauer. Je démontre que din-1S est                nécessaire pour le succès reproductif après ce stade lorsque la cascade de                signalisation par l'insuline est perturbée. Je révèle aussi que din-1S est essentiel                pour la longue vie des larves dauer en réponse à une réduction de signalisation par                l'insuline, en aval ou bien en parallèle de AMPK/aak-2. Finalement, je montre que                din-1S fonctionne en aval des composantes de la voie de signalisation par l'insuline                afin d'empêcher la prolif</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Richard D. W. Roy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hr510.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht56j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xw81g"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Democracy, participation, and empowerment: poverty alleviation programs in Sleman, Yogyakarta, Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khuluq, Lathiful</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Abstract Keywords: poverty; micro credit; good governance; international social work; Indonesia. Indonesia has experienced a shift from authoritarianism to  democracy since the late 1990s. After the severe economic crisis of 1997, which ultimately forced Soeharto to relinquish power, Indonesia embarked on a more liberal and participatory form of democracy. To overcome the economic and social crisis that caused many to fall into poverty, the new government administration launched a number of poverty alleviation programs. This dissertation explores one such effort, namely, the Program Penanggulangan Kemiskinan di Perkotaan (P2KP), an extensive scheme that                utilized democratic, participatory, and empowerment approaches to help the poor deal with unemployment and other problems of poverty. Using qualitative methodology, this study has explored and examined the process and outcomes of poverty alleviation programs in several villages in the southern parts of Sleman District, Yogyakarta  Special Province, Indonesia, from February-May 2006. The thesis begins with a review of the literature on the factors leading to poverty, development and participation, globalization and its negative impacts, and various strategies for ending the problems of poverty, such as multiple occupations, empowerment, and human capital improvement. Findings were based on interviews, observation, and reviews of written  documents concerning the P2KP poverty alleviation programs. Over 30 individuals were interviewed, ranging from government officials to facilitators and organizers of the programs, non-government activists, and the poor who benefitted or were excluded from the programs. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Résumé Mots clefs : pauvreté, micro-crédit, bonne gouvernance, travail social international, Indonésie L'Indonésie a subi un décalage                de l'autoritarisme à la démocratie depuis la fin des années 90. Après la crise économique sévère de 1997, ce qui a enfin poussé Soeharto de renoncer au pouvoir, l'Indonésie s'est embarque dans une forme de démocratie plus libérale et participative. Pour surmonter la crise économique et sociale qui a jeté plusieurs dans la pauvreté, la nouvelle administration gouvernementale a lancé nombre de  programmes destinés à atténuer la pauvreté. Cette dissertation vise à explorer un de ces efforts, c'est-à-dire, le Program Penanggulangan Kemiskinan di Perkotaan (P2KP), un vaste projet qui a employé des approches démocratiques, participatives et autonomisantes pour aider les démuni s à affronter la chômage et d'autres problèmes liés à la pauvreté. En employant une méthodologie qualitative, cette étude a enquêté                et examiné le processus et les résultats des programmes d'atténuation de la pauvreté dans plusieurs villages du secteur sud du district de Sleman, province spéciale de Yogyakarta, Indonésie, en février-mai 2006. La dissertation commence avec une revue de la littérature sur les facteurs qui mènent à la pauvreté, le développement et la participation, la mondialisation et ses impacts négatifs, et les stratégies multiples pour mettre fin aux problèmes de la pauvreté, tels que des emplois multiples, l'autonomisation et l'amélioration de capital humain. Les résultats sont fondés sur des entrevues, [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hanley, Jill</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. Uner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd294.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw81g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qk63j"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implementation of a bioherbicide strategy for golf course environments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gagné, Geneviève</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> The local pathogen Sclerotinia minor has been formulated to be used as                a bioherbicide for broadleaf weed control in turfgrass. Prostrate knotweed (Polygonum                aviculare L.), a major golf course weed, is difficult to control with chemical                herbicides, but prostrate knotweed is susceptible to the bioherbicide. However, a                golf course is a challenging environment for the bioherbicide due to the close and                frequent mowing and concomitant reduced competitiveness of the grass. This research                demonstrates that prostrate knotweed control in golf course is dose response                sensitive. Studies have shown that when the bioherbicide is combined with a                protective cover, the bioherbicide performance is enhanced. This research also                demonstrates that the bioherbicide can be used with Daconil fungicide, but Banner                fungicide adversely affects bioherbicide efficiency. This research involved                collaboration with Beaconsfield Golf Club Inc., Ile Perrot Golf and Country Club Inc.                and The Royal Montreal Golf Club.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Sclerotinia minor est utilisé dans une stratégie de                contrôle biologique par inondation pour les terrains gazonnés. La renouée des oiseaux                (Polygonum aviculare L) est une des principales mauvaises herbes infestant les                terrains de golf. Cette mauvaise herbe est difficile à contrôler avec des herbicides                chimiques et elle est susceptible au bioherbicide. Les terrains de golf sont des                environnements spécifiques qui sont susceptibles d'affecter le potentiel du                bioherbicide. Cette recherche démontre que le contrôle de la renouée des oiseaux est                positivement relié à l'augmentation de la dose de bioherbicide appliquée. Cette étude                établit que l'utilisation d'un tissu protecteur augmente la performance du                bioherbicide. Également, elle prouve que la performance du bioherbicide est affectée                par le fongicide Banner. En revanche, le fongicide Daconil peut être utilisé avec le                bioherbicide. Cette recherche a été effectuée en collaboration avec: Club de golf                Beaconsfield Inc., Club de Golf Ile Perrot Inc. et le Royal Montréal.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Alan K. Watson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp920.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk63j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77ft217"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The use of computed tomography images in Monte Carlo treatment planning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bazalova, Magdalena</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Monte Carlo (MC) dose calculations cannot accurately assess the dose                delivered to the patient during radiotherapy unless the patient anatomy is well                known. This thesis focuses on the conversion of patient computed tomography (CT)                images into MC geometry files. Metal streaking artifacts and their effect on MC dose                calculations are first studied. A correction algorithm is applied to                artifact-corrupted images and dose errors due to density and tissue mis-assignment                are quantified in a phantom and a patient study. The correction algorithm and MC dose                calculations for various treatment beams are also investigated using phantoms with                real hip prostheses. As a result of this study, we suggest that a metal artifact                correction algorithm should be a part of any MC treatment planning. By means of MC                simulations, scatter is proven to be a major cause of metal artifacts. The use of                dual-energy CT (DECT) for a novel tissue segmentation scheme is thoroughly                investigated. First, MC simulations are used to determine the optimal beam filtration                for an accurate DECT material extraction. DECT is then tested on a CT scanner with a                phantom and a good agreement in the extraction of two material properties, the                relative electron density rho_e and the effective atomic number Z is found. Compared                to the conventional tissue segmentation based on rho_e-differences, the novel tissue                segmentation scheme uses differences in both rho_e and Z. The phantom study                demonstrates that the novel method based on rho_e and Z information works well and                makes MC dose calculations more accurate. This thesis demonstrates that DECT                suppresses streaking artifacts from brachytherapy seeds. Brachytherapy MC dose</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les calculs de dose Monte Carlo (MC) ne peuvent                précisément déterminer la dose délivrée au patient, à moins de bien connaître son                anatomie. Cette thèse se concentre sur la conversion des images tomographiques du                patient en fichier de géométrie Monte Carlo. Les artefacts métalliques et leur effet                sur les calculs de dose MC sont étudiés. Un algorithme de correction est appliqué sur                les images avec artefacts et les erreurs de dose dues au mauvais assignement des                densités et tissus sont quantifiées dans un fantôme et une étude de patient.                L'algorithme de correction est aussi testé sur des fantômes avec de réelles prothèses                de hanches et l'effet de correction sur les calculs de dose MC est étudié. En tant                que résultat de cette étude, nous suggérons qu'un algorithme de correction des                artefacts métalliques soit intégré à tout plan de traitement MC. Par le biais de                simulations MC, le diffusé est prouvé être une cause majeure des artefacts                métalliques. L'utilisation d'un scanner double énergie pour une méthode novatrice de                segmentation de tissu est minutieusement étudiée. Tout d'abord, les simulations MC                sont utilisées pour déterminer la filtration optimale de faisceau pour une extraction                précise du matériau en scanner double énergie. La méthode à double énergie est                ensuite testée sur un scanner avec un fantôme et un bon accord dans l'extraction des                propriétés des deux matériaux, la densité électronique relative rho_e et le nombre                effectif atomique Z est trouvé. Comparé à la segmentation conventionnelle des tissus                réalisée sur la base des différents rho_e, la méthode novatrice de segmentation de                tissu utilise les diff</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frans Verhaegen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236393t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft217</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Radiation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b518q"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Jumping behaviour for a wheeled quadruped robot: analysis and experiments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harmat, Adam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes a new jumping behaviour developed for the                quadruped robot PAW. The robot has very few degrees of freedom, employing springy                legs and wheels at the distal ends of the legs to achieve its various modes of                locomotion. This simple construction allows PAW to exploit the dynamics of a                mass-spring system to achieve gaits such as bounding, galloping, and presently                jumping. An MSC.ADAMS / Simulink co-simulation is used to develop and optimize the                jumping process, which consists of four stages: acceleration to jumping speed, front                hip thrusting, rear hip thrusting, and flight. Due to the strong coupling between the                parameters describing the jump, manual tuning is not possible and thus a genetic                algorithm is used for the optimization process. The data generated by the genetic                algorithm is then used for the fitting of a quadratic response surface, which                identifies those parameters that contribute most to a successful jump. The simulation                is then generalized to allow robots of various geometries to be analyzed, and it is                found that leg length and body length are important factors in the jumping behaviour.                Finally, the possibility of extending this approach to simulate the jumping of                virtually any wheeled-leg quadruped is discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse décrit un nouveau comportement sautant                développé pour le robot quadrupède PAW. Le robot a très peu de degrés de liberté,                employant des ressorts dans les jambes et des roues aux bouts pour atteindre ses                divers modes de locomotion. Cette construction simple permet à PAW d'exploiter la                dynamique d'un système de masse-ressort pour atteindre l'allure du galop, du rebond,                et le sujet de cette recherche: le saut. Une co-simulation de MSC.ADAMS et Simulink                est utilisée pour développer et optimiser le processus sautant, qui consiste de                quatre étapes : l'accélération pour atteindre la vitesse necessaire pour sauter, la                poussée des jambes de devant, la poussée des jambes postérieur, et le vol. En raison                du fort accouplement entre les paramètres décrivant le saut, l'accordement manuel de                ces paramètres n'est pas possible. Alors, un algorithme génétique est utilisé pour le                processus d'optimisation. Les données produites par l'algorithme génétique sont alors                utilisées pour l'adjustement d'une surface de réponse quadratique, qui identifie les                paramètres qui contribuent le plus à un saut réussi. La simulation est alors                généralisée pour permettre aux robots de diverses géométries à être analysé, et il                est trouvé que la longueur des jambes et la longueur du corps sont des facteurs                importantes dans le comportement sautant. Enfin, la possibilité d'étendre cette                approche pour simuler le saut de quasiment n'importe quel quadrupède avec des roues                aux bouts des jambes est discuté. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Inna Sharf</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p214v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b518q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Robotics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sj121"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Medical Physics Unit</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Whole Brain Isotropic Arterial Spin Labeling Magnetic Resonance Imaging in a transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer's Disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Curtis, James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents the design, implementation, and validation of a                novel, arterial spin labeling (ASL) perfusion magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) pulse                sequence to generate three-dimensional quantitative maps of cerebral blood flow (CBF)                in mice at 7 Tesla with an isotropic 281μm resolution. ASL and anatomical scans were                registered to a common template using an automated non-linear registration pipeline                to allow for voxel-wise inter-scan and inter-subject comparisons of CBF. The                technique was applied to the study of a transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer's Disease                (AD) which demonstrates many of the characteristic features of cerebrovascular                dysfunction present in AD. The technique resolved regions of significant difference                between transgenic and wild-type mouse populations using voxel-wise- and                region-of-interest-based analyses. These findings are the first to demonstrate the                utility of perfusion MRI for population-based analysis of cerebrovascular                pathophysiology in transgenic AD mice.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse présente la conception et la validation d'un                nouveau séquence d'acquisition d'imagerie par resonance magnetique (IRM) pour la                marquage des spins des arteres (ASL) pour créer des cartes parametrique en                trois-dimensions de debit de sanguin cérébral (CBF) dans les souris à 7 Tesla. avec                un résolution isotrope de 281 μm. Les volumes d'IRM anatomique et ASL ont été                enregistrées avec un procedure non linéaire pour effectuer des comparaisons de CBF                par-voxel entre les scans seriale et entre les animaux. La technique a été appliquée                à l'étude d'un modèle de souris transgénique de la maladie d'Alzheimer (MA), qui                démontre beaucoup de traits caractéristiques de dysfonctionnement cérébral qui sont                présents dans la maladie d'Alzheimer. La technique résolu régions de différence                significative entre les populations transgéniques et de type sauvage par les methodes                d'analyse par-voxel et par-regions-d'intérêt. Ces résultats sont les premiers à                démontrer l'utilité de l'IRM de perfusion au niveau de la population sur l'analyse de                physiopathologie vasculaire cérébral dans les souris transgéniques MA.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gilbert Bruce Pike</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Barry Joseph Bedell</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s4259.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj121</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics - Medical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vm80g"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimization algorithms for minor-closed classes of graphs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kapadia, Rohan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A class of graphs is minor closed if it contains all the minors of its                elements. In this thesis, we discuss optimization algorithms for the graphs in                certain minor-closed classes that exploit their structural properties. The algorithms                use special tree- decompositions of these graphs as well as some other structural                theorems. We present new results on finding odd cycle covers of bounded size. We                present a new algorithm to do so in arbitrary graphs, and show that a variant of this                algorithm runs in linear time on the class of graphs obtained by excluding any fixed                graph H as a minor.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une classe de graphes est dite close par mineur si elle                contient tous les mineurs de ses éléments. Dans cette thèse, nous discutons des                algorithmes d'optimisation pour certaines classes closes par mineur qui exploitent                leur structure. Ces algorithmes sont basés sur des décompositions arborescentes                spéciales de ces graphes et quelques autres théorèmes structurels. Nous présentons de                nouveaux résultats sur la recherche de couvertures de cycles impairs de taille                limitée. Nous présentons un nouvel algorithme pour résoudre ce problème dans un                graphe arbitraire, et montrons qu'une variante de cet algorithme prend un temps                linéaire sur la classe de graphes obtenus en excluant n'importe quel graphe fixe H                comme mineur.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruce Alan Reed</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r287j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm80g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3j3334211"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Scorodite stabilization with aluminum hydroxy-gels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leetmaa, Karl</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Au sein des procédés d'industrie minière, la                neutralisation de l'arsenic sous forme de scorodite est aujourd'hui un sujet                d'attrait majeur. Cependant, même la scorodite s'avère parfois instable dans                certaines conditions de pH et d'oxydoréduction, pouvant mener au rejet d'arsenic dans                l'environnement. L'une des nouvelles méthodes développées en vue de neutraliser                l'arsenic consiste à encapsuler/stabiliser les particules de scorodite à l'aide de                revêtements/matrices caractérisés par une forte résistance à la décomposition en                milieu d'enfouissement. Dans ce travail, des gels amorphes d'hydroxyle d'aluminium                ont été identifiés et étudiés comme potentiels matériaux d'encapsulation. Une                procédure correspondante d'encapsulation a également été développée en fin de projet.                Le travail de recherche présenté ici inclut (1) la synthèse de particules de                scorodite ; (2) la production et la caractérisation des gels d'aluminium ; (3) le                vieillissement de particules de scorodite au sein de gels d'aluminium; (4)                l'évaluation de la stabilité de ce système en terme de rejet d'arsenic pour des pH                variant de 6.5 à 8 et à une température de 22ºC. La production des gels a été                réalisée par neutralisation rapide et partielle (fraction molaire OH/Al = 2.5), à                22ºC, de solutions de chlorure d'aluminium (AlCl3) et de sulfate d'aluminium                (Al(SO4)1.5) chacune d'une concentration de 2 mol/L. La composition des gels, en                pourcentage massique, a été déterminée après vieillissement et rinçage à l'eau de ces                derniers: 60-70% d'hydroxyde d'aluminium (Al(OH3)), 5% de chlore ou respectivement                18% de sulfates et environ 20% d'eau ont été mesurés. Des ana</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The disposal of arsenic in the form of scorodite presently attracts a                lot of interest. However, even scorodite under certain pH and redox conditions may                decompose potentially releasing arsenic to the environment. A novel way of arsenic                fixation is to encapsulate/stabilize scorodite particles with mineral                coatings/matrices that are not prone to decomposition. In this work, amorphous                aluminum hydroxyl-gels were identified and investigated as a potential encapsulating                material and a procedure was developed towards this end. The research work presented                in this thesis included (1) synthesis of scorodite particles; (2) production and                characterization of aluminum gels; (3) ageing of aluminum gel/scorodite blends; and                (4) stability evaluation in terms of arsenic release in the pH range 6.5 to 8 at                22˚C. The gels were produced by partial (molar ratio OH/Al = 2.5) quick                neutralization of 2M AlCl3 or Al(SO4)1.5 solutions at 22˚C. The gels were determined,                following ageing and water washing, to consist of 60 – 70 wt.% Al(OH)3, 5 – 18 wt.%                Cl or SO4 and ~20 wt.% water. ATR-IR and Raman spectra revealed the aluminum                sulphate-derived gel to be different than the corresponding aluminum chloride-derived                gel in its molecular make-up, most likely having the Keggin type structure. Ageing                aluminum sulphate gel and scorodite for at least one day at 22˚C was shown via BSE                images and x-ray maps of cross sections to lead to development of an aluminum                hydroxide matrix around the scorodite particles. Arsenic release from the aged                gel/scorodite blends was found to be drastically reduced with respect to gel-free                scorodite. Thus a 0.1 Al/As sulphate gel/scorodite mixture reached an equilibri</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>George Demopoulos</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq72d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3334211</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1j92g9246"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of German Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ellen Olestjerne: Franziska zu Reventlow et le projet de soi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Garcia Hernandez, Paula</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>SOMMAIRE Il est communément admis que le genre                Bildungsroman, soit, en raison de la notion d'éducation, exclusivement masculin. Par                contre, il s'agit ici de démontrer le pendant féminin de ce genre en étudiant le                cheminement intellectuel, affectif et éducationnel de l'héroïne éponyme dans Ellen                Olestjerne de Franziska zu Reventlow. Le premier chapitre de cette analyse met en                place le cadre théorique où sera définit le Bildungsroman féminin. Le deuxième aborde                le Selsbtbefreiung, la libération de l'héroïne, élément indissociable du pendant                féminin du genre. Enfin, le troisième chapitre traite sur le Selbsterfindung de                l'héroïne, qui doit se réinventer une définition en dehors des normes patriarcales                pour atteindre l'harmonie avec soi-même et avec son milieu. L'étude d'Ellen                Olestjerne mène à la conclusion qu'il existe en effet le Bildungsroman féminin,                l'héroïne atteint son Selbsterfindung d'une manière extrêmement radicale, elle refuse                toute conception préconçue de sa féminité par le patriarcat, et se crée de toutes                pièces une identité conforme à ses valeurs. Mots clés Bildungsroman féminin,                Lebensrecht, Selbstbefreiung, parthénogenèse féminine, Selbsterfindung, Paradiesstufe </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>ABSTRACT This thesis examines Franziska zu Reventlow's novel Ellen                Olestjerne in which Reventlow creates a heroine who reaches intellectual, emotional,                and educational maturity exclusively outside of the established constructs and                definitions of patriarchal Wilhelmine society. Given that the Bildunsgroman was a                hitherto almost exclusively male genre, this thesis aims to prove, based on                Reventlow's novel, the existence of a possible alternative and "female"                Bildunsgroman, and all that this entails. The first chapter of this study establishes                the theoretical framework for the possibilities and problematic of female                Bildunsgroman by examing the overall historic, thematic, and formal context of the                genre. The second approaches the Selsbtbefreiung, or the difficult process of the                liberation of the heroine from all external constraint and definition, an                indispensable element of a female Bildunsgroman. Lastly, the third chapter treats of                Selbsterfindung or, self-reinvention of the heroine. Her path, it is argued, is, as                woman, more one painful self-reinvention than of simple self-discovery, since she                must radically reshape herself and her image of an autonomous female identity against                all prevailing definitions in order to ultimately reach harmony with herself and her                environment, a harmony she paradoxically achieves by flouting all societal                convention. The study of Ellen Olestjerne leads to the conclusion that there is                indeed a female Bildungsroman: for the heroine achieves both her Selbsterfindung and                reconciliation with life and the human collectivity, but in an unprecedentedly                radical fashion, which shows the deep originality of both the author and her novel.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul Peters</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35696262.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g9246</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature - Germanic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p892n"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Hardware acceleration on IBM cell broadband engine for simulation of coupled interconnects using waveform relaxation and transverse partitioning</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Zikai</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Résumé Au cours des dernières années, la tendance dans la                conception des microprocesseurs est passée de l'augmentation de la fréquence                d'horloge à des modèles multi-core qui intègrent de multiples noyaux de traitement                sur la même puce. Cela signifie que nous ne pouvons plus compter sur l'augmentation                des fréquences d'horloge dans le but d'améliorer les performances des outils                d'automatisation de conception électronique (EDA). En fait, pour prendre avantage des                progrès réalisés dans la conception de microprocesseurs, ces outils doivent être                adaptés afin d'utiliser des architectures de calcul parallèle. Dans cette thèse nous                avons paralléliser et de mis en oeuvre un algorithme d'IBM sur le Cell Broadband                Engine (Cell BE), qui est basée sur les techniques de relaxation d'onde et de                partition transversale pour simuler de manière efficace des circuits                d'interconnection couplés à haute vitesse. Plusieurs stratégies sont utilisées dans                le Cell BE programs pour atteindre la haute performance. Le processeur Cell BE                réalise la meilleure performance avec une vitesse de 10x lorsque le nombre de lignes                de transmission est un multiple du nombre maximum d'éléments synergiques du                processeur (SPEs) qui sont en cours d'exécution simultanément.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Abstract Over the past few years, the trend in microprocessor design has                shifted from increasing the clock frequencies to multi-core designs that embed                multiple processing cores on the same chip. This has meant that we can no longer rely                on increasing clock frequencies in order to improve the performance of electronic                design automation (EDA) tools. In fact, for these tools to take advantage of modern                advances in microprocessor design they must be adapted to take advantage of parallel                computing architectures. In this thesis we parallelize and implement an algorithm on                the IBM Cell Broadband Engine (Cell BE), which is based on the techniques of waveform                relaxation and transverse partitioning to efficiently simulate large coupled                interconnect circuits at high speed. Several strategies are used in the Cell BE                programs to achieve high performance. The Cell BE processor achieves the best                performance with a speed-up of 10x when the number of transmission lines is a                multiple of the maximum number of Synergistic Processor Elements (SPEs) that are                running concurrently.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roni Khazaka</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Warren Gross</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg204.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p892n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r967549z"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lepton pair production at the CERN SPS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Winkels, Adam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nous interprétons les données expérimentales sur les                paires de leptons mesurées dans les collisions Pb-Au à 158 AGeV, au SPS du CERN. Nous                traitons l'évolution du système hadronique en considérant une modélisation                thermodynamique ajustée aux observables asymptotiques. La production de leptons dans                la phase du plasma quark-gluon est obtenue avec les techniques reconnues de la                théorie des champs à température finie, où les quarks ont des masses thermiques                non-nulles. Après la transition de phase, les contributions des désintégrations des                mésons rho et omega sont évaluées en partant des amplitudes de diffusion vers                l'avant, ce qui tient compte des effets de milieu. Tous nos résultats sont filtrés                par l'acceptance du détecteur CERES. Nos calculs sont en accord avec les données                mesurées sur la production de dileptons de petite et moyenne masses invariantes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>We interpret theoretically electron pair data observed in Pb(158                AGeV)-Au collisions at the CERN SPS by considering the system as an evolving fireball                with parameters fit to experimental observables. Dilepton production in the QGP phase                is found via standard finite temperature field theory techniques where annihilating                quarks have thermally generated effective masses. After the phase transition,                contributions from rho and omega meson decays are found via from experimentally                determined forward scattering amplitudes which account for the effects of emission                from a medium with finite temperature and density. All results are folded with a                model which considers bias created by the CERES detector's acceptance. Our                calculations agree well with existing data dilepton production at low and                intermediate invariant masses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Charles Gale</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408003g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967549z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Nuclear</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>