<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04ds18f"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electoral practices in Quebec, 1867-1882</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shea, Philip E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first two chapters consider the social conditions in the province, the evolution of political parties, and the effect they had upon the attitude of Quebeeers towards politics during the years 1867-1882. The body of the thesis describes the preparations for elections and the methods used to attract party followers and to win over the electorate. The role played by the clergy in the politics of this period is also considered. Finally, there is a study of the laws and regulations governing elections and Dew they affected electoral practices in Quebec. A short conclusion considers some possible explanations for the attitude of Quebecers towards politics in later years of the province's history in the light of conditions prevailing in the period 1867-1882.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lapierre, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j1475.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds18f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Elections -- Québec (Province) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Québec (Province) -- Politics and government -- 1867-1897</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aff365770g"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology and Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social aspects of multilingualism in New Guinea</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sankoff, Gillian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the nature and extent of multilingualism among the Buang of northeastern New Guinea, treating both the history and present status of multilingualism in Buang society in an analysis which is also relevant to other New Guinea groups. A careful examination of the relationships among Buang dialects, and between them and other Huon coast area languages forms the linguistic background to this study. Acquisition, knowledge, use and attitudes about other languages are closely related to the kinds of social relationships existing between Buang and other groups. The extent of multilingualism among the population is described in terms of the results of comprehension tests which, show the Buang to be multilingual both in foreign and in related languages. Usage and code choice are discussed in connection with the former, and non-determinate aspects of code-switching are seen as crucial both to linguistic change (especially code repertoires) and to individual speech strategies. With respect to related languages, the tests, in conjunction with lexical comparisons, throw light on the distinction between mutual intelligibility and bilingualism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Salisbury, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb03d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365770g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>New Guinea -- Languages</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociolinguistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f389b"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L’art de Félix-Antoine Savard dans Menaud, maitre-draveur</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ricard, François, 1947-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> Menaud maitre-draveur marque un tournant de la littérature canadienne-fran9aise. Ce roman, dont l'exaltation nationaliste a surtout", jusqu'à présent, retenu la critique. S’impose cependant, au premier chef, par l'étonnante qualité de son style. Le but de notre étude a été de dégager, par une analyse serrée du texte, l'originalité de cette écriture et ses principaux caractères. Après une présentation sommaire de l’auteur, nous consacrons notre première partie à la comparaison des différentes versions de Menaud (1937, 1938, 1944, 1960 et 1964), ce qui nous permet de constater l'extrême application que met l’abbé Savard a tous les détails de son expression. La deuxième partie est l'analyse proprement dite, que nous divisons selon les différents aspects du style: vocabulaire, grammaire, ordre des mots, liaisons, phrase et rythme. Dans chacune de ces rubriques, deux faits s'imposent à l’attention: d'abord, la grande connaissance que possède Savard des ressources du fran9ais, et surtout, l'impressionnisme de ce style emporte et vif, pliant ses modulations a tous les méandres de la sensibilité et de l'émotion. Un dernier chapitre nous fait retrouver, dans la construction même de l'œuvre, ce même souci de perfection qui caractérisé l'expression. Enfin, la psychologie des personnages, de Menaud en particulier, nous fournit une explication de l'impressionnisme précédemment constate.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm76g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f389b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Savard, Félix Antoine. Menaud, maître-draveur</dc:subject><dc:subject>Savard, Félix Antoine -- Literary style</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698b040"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Matthew Arnold in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Opala, Beatrice Barbara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>After touring America, Matthew Arnold arrived in Toronto on February 12, 1884, for a ten-day stay in Canada. Arnoldt s success as: a lecturer in America-was: moderate, his matter and manner being unpopular. Canadians, too~, found Arnold's ideas unsuitable: for the North-American life-style, but differed significantly in how they called them in question. Canadian editorials we-re generally courteous in tone and well-informed. Canadians were also more sympathetic to Arnold himself. He was cordially received everywhere, achieving a personal triumph in Quebec City. In Montreal, however, an "incident," which occurred as a result of Arnold's expressed opinion on the city's religious: problem, left an unpleasant after-math. Nevertheless', this "incident in its way, as much as other events of the visit in theirs, pointed to the quality of Canadian intellectual life and conditions at the time, and indicated the impact this great critic had upon Canada ...</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lucas, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jp106.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b040</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canada -- Social conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Intellectual life</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arnold, Matthew, 1822-1888</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1g05ff44p"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An assessment of the ice masses of Axel Heiberg Island, N.W.T. : a study of glacier inventory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ommanney, C. Simon L., 1942-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The measurements proposed for' a glacier inventory, including the form of a basic data sheet suitable for computer analysis, are discussed in Part I. The importance ofstandardizing glacier identification, the quantitative data (elevation, linear, area volume mC'H:U3Ur'cments and their accuracy) and the qualitative information (glacier description and classification) is stressed. Elevation of the snow line and of the mean accumulation &amp; ablation areas is included in the inventory. The feasibility of the inventory proposals was successfully tested in a pilot study on the 1101 glaciers of Axel Heiberg Island (BOON) 900 W) , Canadian Arctic Archipelago. The great variety of glaciers; covering 31.5 per cent of the island, permitted evaluation of many critical problems. Basic data for each glacier is presented as a computer printout, accompanied by an index map, and the physiography and climate of the area and a list of source material included. Part 11 can be considered the first completed example of an International Hydrological decade world glacier inventory.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q81q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff44p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Glaciology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glaciers -- Nunavut -- Axel Heiberg Island</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahx11xh35g"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ceylon’s foreign policy (1953-59) : an elite image analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mukerjee, R. J. (Roman John)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The foreign policy of Ceylon (1953-59) has been examined on the basis of a model for foreign policy analysis developed by Professors Michael Brecher, Blema Steinberg and Janice Stein (McGill University).  An attempt was made to delineate and compare the 'world views' of Prime Ministers J.L. Kotelawala and S.W.R.D.  Bandaranaike, followed by an analysis of the way in which their 'images' were reflected in selected foreign policy decisions. The data collated from this study of Ceylonts foreign policy was then tested against a number of hypotheses that emerged from a macro-study of the decision-making behavior of eight middle-powers. A major conclusion of this study was that despite the dramatic change in regimes in Ceylon after the 1956 General Elections, the country's foreign policy continued to be marked by a process of both continuity and change.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steinberg, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz54n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh35g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sri Lanka -- Foreign relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vr046"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology and Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Status politics in English Canada, 1900-1930</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Longstaff, Stephen Alan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> This study applies a conceptual distinction --first suggested in analyses of McCarthyism --between class politics (where the aim is access to greater wealth and power) and status politics (where the aim is the maintenance or advancement of social honour and prestige) to the English speaking Canada of 1900 to 1930. The focus is on the major mass movements and political currents of that era, viz., woman suffrage, the labour movement, the Progressives and the United Farmers parties, temperance and sabbatarianism, and nationalist and racist extremism. On the 'basis of data gathered by content analysis, the year-by-year development of these movements has been charted. Examination of the impact of economic conditions on each movement's growth indicates that, with the exception of a brief wartime and postwar period (1918-1921), class movements received their greatest support during periods of recession and status movements their greatest support during prosperity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pinard, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zk267.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vr046</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Canada -- Politics and government -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x639t"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of the civil service in the implementation of the basic democracies scheme of Pakistan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leghari, M. I. (M. Iqbal)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> The thesis deals with the leadership role of a law and order oriented bureaucracy in the implementation of a comprehensive programme of rural development in Pakistan.. The findings lead to the conclusion that the district bureaucracy is a long way from becoming a development administration, as envisaged in the Basic Democracies Order, 1959. However, as a result of pressures from the political system and the formation of a new strategy, district administration is undergoing changes, and finally being enlisted behind the task of rural development.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sayeed, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b8646.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x639t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil service -- Pakistan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pakistan -- Politics and government</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3197xp25q"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Federal aid to higher education : with particular reference to universities in the period 1951 to 1967</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hyman, Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this paper is to make an historical analysis of the relationship between the federal government and the universities over a definite period of time. The study examines the development of precedents leading to federal aid, the economic form that the government-university relationship assumes from 1951 to 1967, the quantitative and qualitative aspects of this relationship and the growth of mediating agencies at federal, provincial and university levels.  The paper deals with certain agencies of involvement" that are seen as important institutions in helping to clarify the nature and form of the relationship. These include various agencies of both federal and provincial governments, the Association of Universities and Colleges of Canada and its predecessors, the Canadian Association of University Teachers and relevant investigating bodies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Horowitz, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pz66p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xp25q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Federal aid to higher education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Universities and colleges -- Canada -- Finance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5712m9396"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The iron mining communities of Quebec-Labrador : a study of a resource frontier</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hilton, Keith David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> Iron mining in Quebec-Labrador developed in response to the needs of the U. S. steel industry. The timing, organization and markets for the developments on this resource frontier reflect this. The communities needed' to house the workers were constructed along southern lines and administered as company towns. The experiences of Schefferville, Gagnon, Labrador City and Wabush in physical planning 'and administration are reviewed. General principals' which may be applicable in the establishment of new northern mining towns are put forward. Analysis of the labour force from SchefferviUe and Gagnon showed the majority of workers to come from Quebec. Long service hourly paid men came primarily from the Gaspe -South Shore. the skilled and supervisory men have more diverse geographical origins. The size of the formative community, the socio-economic character of the source area together with the age and marital status of the worker affect the migrant1s perception and adaption to the northern town. Schefferville has evolved into a stable subarctic mining community through a combination of the character of its labour force, company policy and town amenities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gilmour, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bp17n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m9396</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Iron mines and mining -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x179k"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pressure group politics : the case of the Federation of Classical Colleges</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gershberg, Sidney M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract> The-study examines the activities of a particular interest group in Quebec -the Federation of Classical Colleges. It attempts to determine the political influence of this group. The framework of analysis is essentially empirical. The thesis is divided into three sections. The first describes the internal structures and the decision making centers within the group. The second analyzes the attitudes and the policy positions of the Federation and the government. The final section provides a study in depth of a specific case where the Federation acted as a pressure group -the financial crisis of summer 1965. The case study suggests that the Federation had a decisive influence on the final outcome of the crisis..</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frankel, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010s68w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x179k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pressure groups -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fédération des collèges classiques</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adr26z087n"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Themes et style dans l’oeuvre de Marie-Claire Blais</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fréchette, Jean-Marc, 1943-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse de ma1trise constitue la première étude d'ensemble de l'œuvre de Marie-Claire J31ais; aussi l’auteur a-t-il préféré s'en tenir à une analyse d'ordre très général. Dans 1'introduction, il est indiqué que la méthode suivie par l'auteur sera quelque peu pointilliste, les limites prescrites pour cette thèse et l'abondance de la matière ne permettant pas de veritab1es développements. Cependant, de l'œuvre de Marie-Claire B1ais, ressort avec évidence une dualité que cette étude tentera surtout de cerner. L'Introduction est précédée d'Une biographie. La première partie traite des thèmes psychologiques, 80oiologiques et phi10aophiques (l’enfance, l'adolescence, l’amour, la cruauté, le père, la mère, la famille, la société, le monde contemporain, Dieu, la souffrance, la culpabilité, la liberté, le temps, la mort.) La seconde partie est consacrée à déterminer les principaux éléments oniriques de l'œuvre. Une brève étude de l'art et du style constitue la troisième partie. Enfin, la conclusion tente de définir la valeur de L’œuvre de 11arie-Claire Blais</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ethler-Blais, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v537f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z087n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Blais, Marie-Claire, 1939- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10wt01t"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some attempts at reform of the civil service of Pakistan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cabatoff, K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study traces the history of some attempted reforms of the Pakistan bureaucracy with a view to determining the extent of its reorientation to development goals. The study deals with four main subjects. Firstly, it tries to portray the precedent-oriented process of decision-making in the Secretariat, and its effect on the internal organization off, the Secretariat. Secondly, it outlines the history of the attem9ts by executive heads to gain autonomy from the Secretariat. Thirdly, it deals with the attempts to give administrative ministries autonomy from the Ministry of Finance, while preserving financial responsibility. Lastly, it deals with the attempted replacement of ad hoc decision-making by planned decision-making. The study shows that much reform 11as been thwarted by vested interests and inadequate capabilities. Notable reforms have nevertheless occurred, and there is thus some basis for optimism in assessing the prospects of administrative reform in developing countries.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sayeed, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp891.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt01t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil service -- Pakistan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Civil service reform -- Pakistan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv935548s"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Journal geographique du voyage de Chateaubriand en Orient</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Andreani, Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La relation du voyage en Orient de Chateaubriand nous apparait comme une œuvre Littéraire dans laquelle nous trouve une réalité géographique sous-jacente. En effet, la pensée de l'auteur n'est pas celle d'un spectateur. Il participe aux différents rythmes de la nature avec l'évident désir de dresser un inventaire du monde dans lequel il vit. Sous sa plume magique la nature prend une dimension nouvelle, matérielle.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ethler-Blais, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h4329.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935548s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chateaubriand, François-René, vicomte de, 1768-1848</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811kn29b"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The evolution of an English-speaking community in rural French Canada, 1820-1867</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thompson, John B. (John Beswarick)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The social development of a small Eng1ish-speak~ng community surrounded by French-Canadian settlements is described between 1820 and 1867. The district studied comprises today the villages of Como, Hudson and Hudson Heights in the County of Vaudreuil. The origins of the British immigrants’ and their motives in choosing to settle among French Canadians are probed. A picture of the community it was in the 1830 is presented and the changes brought about by the Rebellion of 1837-38 are described.  Following the conflict the community consolidates itself, and special attention is paid to local leadership 1n this period. Other factors studied include seigneurialism, politics, agriculture and education. The study concludes at Confederation and the contrast between the frontier settlement af 1820 and the established village of 1867 is drawn.[…]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lapierre, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sd008.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn29b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Vaudreuil (Québec) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vaudreuil (Québec) -- Foreign population</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2f75rb406"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Germaine Guèvremont, portrait de la femme dans le roman canadien français</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rubinger, Catherine, 1936-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chez Germaine Guevremont on trouve le point culminant de la peinture de la paysanne canadienne francaise et aussi les premieres esquisses d'une femme moderne, citadine, internationale.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ethler-Blais, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb86t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rb406</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Guèvremont, Germaine -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian fiction -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537371c"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology and Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The attitudes of the Montreal Jewish community toward French Canadian nationalism and separatism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Romalis, Coleman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This is a study of the attitudes of a socio-religious minority group living in a large~ multi-ethnic metropoliS, toward the nationalist grievances and demands and the separatist tendencies of the numerically dominant minority. At the more particular level~ it examines the attitudes of the Montreal Jewish community toward French Canadian nationalism and separatism; and at the more general level, it seeks to explore the reactions of a minority group toward a social movement by which they may potentially be strongly affected, but of which they are not a part.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pinard, Maurice</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hall, Oswald</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66346211.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537371c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Jews -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nationalism -- Québec (Province) -- Public opinion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848t056"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le thème des passions dans les romans d’André Langevin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Plante-Charron, Cécile</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Aucun thème n'a autant obsédé les écrivains que celui des passions. Alors qu'au théâtre, la tragédie s'inspire de sombres passions, le roman se construit grâce a l'analyse des sentiments profonds du cœur humain, poussant parfois ceux-ci jusqu'au démonisme. Ainsi, la littérature semble même dépasser la psychologie dans l'intérêt qu'elle accorde aux passions. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ethler-Blais, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt51g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t056</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Langevin, André, 1927- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514np04k"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Organization of memory in bilinguals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nott, C. Ruth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Bilinguals' free recall of unilingual lists in each of their two languages and of bilingual lists was investigated. Previous research had suggested that differences between the stronger and weaker language of a bilingual are revealed when he has to process words that form logical categories but not when he is presented non-category lists of words to recall. The results of this study confirmed this hypothesis. The recall of category lists was further investigated by isolating the steps bilinguals take in detecting the nature of the categories and in reshuffling the words into their categories. Aid in detecting the categories did not improve performance significantly whereas presenting the words grouped by eategories did. However blocking the lists in this fashion improved recall in all three language conditions by the same amount. Therefore, it was argued that the inferior recall of category lists in a weaker language was not due to greater difficulty in reshuffling the words during list presentation, but rather to problems involved in decoding the words.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lambert, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk74n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np04k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bilingualism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k5168"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The solvent extraction of some metal (II) pyridine and picoline thiocyanates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacKay, John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The pyridine and picoline thiocyanates.of the metals cobalt, nickel, zinc and cadmium were studied, at 25.00 C, in equilibrated solvent-extraction systems. The distribution ratio, D, defined as D equals the "Total metal concentration in organic phase" divided by "Total metal concentration in aqueous phase" was determined for each metal as a function of the equilibrium concentration of pyridine or picoline. For an individual metal it was found that r~placement of the pyridine molecule in the complex by a picoline resulted in a change in the distribution ratio for that metal with respect to other metals. For each of the extracted metal pyridine and picoline thiocyanate complexes, the product of the partition coefficient and the overall fo~~tion constant in the aqueous phase was found.. The effects of temperature~ pH, metal concentration, different solvents and steric hindrance were also studied. A method of separating these metals by means of this solvent extraction system is suggested.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cave, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795b250.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k5168</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Extraction (Chemistry)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Picoline</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thiocyanates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pyridine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cd45v"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Political Development in Peru</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carrière, Jean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study deals with the political system of Peru in terms of categories of analysis that have not previously been used explicitly in relation to that country. The analysis focuses on a selected number of processes that have been found by contemporary political theorists to be highly relevant for politics in the context of modernization. Although there is no attempt, here, to give a total picture of the determinants of the political process in Peru, the perspective that has been selected should add a new dimension to our understanding of political change in that country. It should help us to establish whether the political system in Peru is becoming more or less viable, more or less able to cope with the increasingly complex problems with which it is confronted, more or less ftdeveloped" •[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nayar, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sw37v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cd45v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Peru -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social mobility -- Peru</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w719z"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A description and analysis of Trade Union growth theory and the Canadian aggregate model, 1936-1965</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brody, Bernard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Theorists differ as to the effects of the business cycle on changes in union membership levels. The "Plurallistic" school attributes to non-economic factors the primary influence. In an analysis of Canadian annual statistics, an attempt is made to show the extent to which key economic variables "explain" changes iin membership growth. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woods, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx20t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w719z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Labor movement -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Labor unions -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jp11g"><ual:graduationDate>1967</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Control of villus size in the small intestine of adult rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Altmann, Gabriel G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Villus size was estimated by counting the mean number of epithelial cells per villus in control and transplanted intestinal segments. In controls, Villus size decreased progressively from duodenum to terminal ileum, thus causing a"villus size gradient". After jejunal segments had been transplanted into ileum or ileal segments into jejunum, the gradient was restored within two months. When duodenal segments (with or without duodenal papilla and Brunner's gland) were transplanted into ileum, the gradient was not restored; duodenal vlli remained large and distal ileal villi increased in size. Following duodeno-ileal (or gastro-ileal) side connection, distal ileal villi were again enlarged; and, therefore, duodenal (and gastric) secretions have a promoting effect on villus size. Furthermore, some duodenal villi near the ileal. connection were decreased; perhaps, passage of ileal products caused a decrease in villus size. Thus, gastric, duodenal and lleal factors may intervene in villus size control.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacIntosh, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd29q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jp11g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Villus size</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v838318d"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of motivation and the amygdala in the association of stimuli</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Adamec, Robert Edward</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effect of hunger on sensory preconditioning was explored. An appetitive task was used to test for sensory preconditioning effects in order to avoid complications arising from differences of drive state during preconditioning and testing for preconditioning. It was found that hunger facilitated the association between paired auditory and visual stimuli, but not between stimuli presented separately and in random order. It was also found that bilateral lateral amygdaloid lesions disrupted the facilitating effect of hunger on sensory preconditioning, but not on preconditioning per se. Examination of the orientation responses of animals during preconditioning, indicated that the auditory stimulus becomes an arousing cue that signals the onset of the visual stimulus. It is suggested that the orientation responses produced as a consequence of this cue function are responsible for the association of the auditory and visual stimuil. Furthermore, differences in the orientation response patterns of the lesioned and normal animals suggest that the lesion disrupts these orientation-attentional responses. Such a disruption may account for the lack of hunger facilitation of sensory preconditioning in lesioned animals. These results implicate the amygdala in orientation-attentional processes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Melzack, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf44k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838318d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Motivation (Psychology)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mesencephalon</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p7344"><ual:graduationDate>1952</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Hudson Bay lowland : a geographical study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Coombs, Donald Brackinreed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There are few areas in Canada which have not, at one time or another during the past few decades, been drawn to the attention or the public by the movement into them of people and industry as the result of some local characteristic. At the turn of the century it was the wheat fields of the West and the gold discoveries of northern British Columbia and the Yukon. In recent years it has been the iron ore deposits of northern Quebec, the development of extensive mineral finds in the Great Slave Lake area and the valuable oil discoveries of the Prairie regions. Through the medium of the newspaper, motion picture and radio, the average Canadian citizen today has a reasonable geographic knowledge of much of the country and the associated cultural development. […] During the summers of 1947, 1949 and 1950 the writer visited much of the Hud8on Bay Lowland as a field man with the Geodetic Survey) of Canada. This provided an opportunity' to study and evaluate at first hand many of the region's problems. Further research was conducted at the Photo Library, Department of Mines and Technical Surveys, and the Public Archives, Ottawa, while considerable source material was provided b7 Federal and Provincial agencies such as the Indian Affairs Branch and Canadian Wildlife Service, Ottawa, and the Department of Lands and Forests, and Department of Mines, Toronto.    </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n120h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p7344</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hudson Bay</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada--geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>