<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azc77sv22k"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Support vector machines for classification and regression</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shah, Rohan Shiloh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the last decade Support Vector Machines (SVMs) have emerged as an important learning technique for solving classification and regression problems in various fields, most notably in computational biology, finance and text categorization. This is due in part to built-in mechanisms to ensure good generalization which leads to accurate prediction, the use of kernel functions to model non-linear distributions, the ability to train relatively quickly on large data sets using novel mathematical optimization techniques and most significantly the possibility of theoretical analysis using computational learning theory. In this thesis, we discuss the theoretical basis and computational approaches to Support Vector Machines.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k949d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sv22k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biologically-inspired computing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computational learning theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computational biology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289p23r"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Endotoxins detection and control in drinking water systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Parent Uribe, Santiago</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Endotoxins are a constituent of the lipopolysaccharide (LPS) complexes present in the outer layer of the cell wall of most Gram-negative bacteria and some cyanobacteria. The ingestion by a typical adult of amounts exceeding 1,000 endotoxin units (EUs) can cause fever, diarrhoea, vomiting, acute respiratory illnesses, and lung inflammation. In contrast, much smaller doses may lead to protective immunity against allergic diseases. Endotoxins can be released in the air as well as in the water; previous studies have mainly focused on airborne endotoxins. Although many studies on endotoxins in raw and treated drinking waters have been performed, few have assessed seasonal variations and none have been conducted in Eastern Canada. Furthermore, a clear understanding of removal of endotoxins by various water treatment processes is still required. Two methods to measure the concentrations of endotoxin were used and compared, the Limulus Amebocyte Lysate test (LAL) and the recombinant Factor C test (rFC). Raw water samples were taken from various drinking water sources around the Island of Montreal. The effects of free chlorine, UV radiation, and ozone were studied in batch experiments on filtered water samples via typical dosages and fluences used in drinking water treatment facilities. Residual concentrations for free chlorine were 0.8 and 1.6 mg/L; ozone doses were 0.5 and 1 mg/L; UV fluences were 40 and 100 mWs/cm2. Detention times of 20 and 60 minutes were tested for chlorine and 5 and 20 minutes for ozone. Grab sampling from three drinking water treatment plants in the Montreal area was performed during the months of June and late August/September 2006 and January 2007. Processes at these plants include coagulation and flocculation, sand filtration, ozonation and disinfection by chlorine. To test the variation in endotoxin concentrations during a sand filter cycle, samples were withdrawn directly from a filter in one of the treatment plants studied. The filtration cycle, from one backwash to the next one, lasts 72 h. Samples were collected immediately before the backwash, at the beginning and at the end of the ripening period, at the beginning of the filtration cycle and 48 h later, which corresponds to a half cycle period. Of the two endotoxin detection methods used, LAL consistently gave slightly higher values compared to rFC; rFC also required more expensive hardware, but the method was less tedious and reagent costs were lower. Results presented, unless otherwise stated, were obtained with the rFC method. Endotoxin levels decreased in raw water samples between June and September. Concentrations ranged from 20 to 30 EU/mL in June, and decreased to 10 to 14 EU/mL in August and beyond. For the disinfection processes, the UV and free chlorine doses tested had little or no effect on the endotoxin concentrations, but ozone reduced the concentrations by up to 75%. Sand filtration and flocculation showed significant endotoxin removal efficiencies (50--60%). Levels remained around 5 EU/mL throughout the remaining treatment processes regardless of the influent concentration. Hence, endotoxin inactivation by free chlorine and UV does not occur with typical doses used in drinking water treatment plants; in contrast, flocculation and sand filtration, as well as ozonation, are much more effective.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692tb558.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289p23r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Drinking water -- Purification -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drinking water -- Microbiology -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endotoxins -- Analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endotoxins -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88cm846"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of early age carbonation on strength and pH of concrete</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Xiaolu, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Carbonation curing of concrete products has shown potentials for CO2 capture and storage with environmental, technical and economical benefits in global greenhouse gas mitigation exercise. The primary objective of this study is to investigate the effect of early age carbonation on mechanical performance and pH of concrete in an attempt to understand the process and promote large scale applications. It was found that significant early strength was developed in cement and concrete through early age carbonation curing. The early strength could be maintained and improved due to subsequent hydration. Twenty-eight-day strength of carbonated cement and concrete was comparable to that of hydrated reference if subsequently cured in the air in a sealed bag, but was lower if subsequently cured in water. Treatment with either internal curing using lightweight aggregates or chemical admixture can effectively enhance late strength development in carbonated concrete. For three typical cement-based products including cement paste compacts, concrete compacts and precast concrete, two-hour carbonation reduced pH value from 12.8 to 11.8 as the lowest and subsequent 28-day hydration could slightly increase pH by 2% as maximum. At any time pH of early age carbonated concrete was always higher than 11.5, a threshold value under which the corrosion of reinforcing steel is likely to occur in concrete. The high pH in early-age carbonated concrete was likely attributed to the fact that early age carbonation was an accelerated hydration process, which was totally different from weathering carbonation in which pH of concrete could be neutralized due to the decomposition of calcium hydroxide and calcium silicate hydrates gel. Therefore, early age carbonation technology is applicable not only to concrete products such as masonry units and paving stones, but possibly to precast concrete with steel reinforcement as well.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526h45j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm846</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Carbon dioxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cement composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Concrete -- Curing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Concrete products</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cf958"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of particle size and natural organic matter on the transport and fate of latex nanoparticles in saturated porous media</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pelley, Andrew John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Colloid filtration experiments were performed using latex particles (50 nm, 110 nm and 1500 nm) in both the presence and absence of 5.0 mg/L humic acid (HAs). At low ionic strengths (1 -- 10 mM KCl), an increase in attachment efficiency (alpha) with increasing particle size was observed, which contrasts with predictions based on DLVO theory. The presence of HAs generally resulted in a decrease in alpha. Characterization experiments to better understand this behaviour included particle sizing using dynamic light scattering (DLS) and zeta potential using laser Doppler velocimetry (LDV). The particles' hydrodynamic diameters were unchanged in the presence of HAs. HAs lead to an increase in absolute zeta potential for the 50 nm and 110 nm colloids and a decrease in zeta potential for the 1500 nm particles. A discussion of the apparent deviations from Derjaguin-Landau-Verwey-Overbeek (DLVO) theory and explanations for the observed behaviour are provided.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fh133.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf958</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colloids</dc:subject><dc:subject>Groundwater -- Purification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transport theory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r967780v"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experiments in object tracking in image sequences</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Law, Albert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis explores three object tracking algorithms for image sequences. These algorithms include the ensemble tracker, the EM-like mean-shift colour-histogram tracker, and the wandering-stable-lost scale-invariant feature transform (WSL-SIFT) tracker. The algorithms are radically different from one another. Despite their differences, they are evaluated on the same publicly available, moderately sized, research data sets which include 129 test cases in 13 different scenes. The results aid in fostering an understanding of their respective behaviours and in highlighting their flaws and failures. Lastly, an implementation setup is described that is suited to large-scale, grid computing, batch testing of these algorithms. Results clearly indicate that none of the evaluated trackers are suited to general purpose use. However, one may intelligently choose a tracker for a well-defined application by analysing the known scene characteristics.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs576.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967780v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer vision</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860c13r"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the differences between in-vivo and in-vitro matured mouse oocytes priming with or without gonadotropins</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Yue, 1973 Aug. 1-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Acquisition of full developmental competence of oocytes not only occurs during growth stage, and the final preparation during oocyte maturation is also critical. Previous studies have shown that nuclear maturation can occur spontaneously following culture in vitro; however, there may be some insufficiency in cytoplasmic maturation of the in vitro matured oocytes. But till now, the differences of the events of cytoplasmic maturation between in vitro and in vivo matured oocytes are still not clear. Ovarian stimulation by gonadotrophins is used to permits the growth and development of follicles, to time the initiation of pre-ovulatory oocyte maturation, and to increase the numbers of oocytes ovulated. It is one of the foundations of current treatments of human infertility. The success of clinical IVF has been depending on generation of matured oocytes at high frequency. However, ovarian stimulation with gonadotropins is associated with side effects and complications. In order to illuminate mechanisms which affect the developmental competence of oocytes produced in vitro, in the present study, we have compared the difference of the quality of oocytes produced in vitro with that of the oocytes produced in vivo using mouse model. In order to understand the relationship between oocyte competence and ovarian responses to stimulation in the mouse, we also have compared difference of the quality of oocytes produced in vitro or in vivo from gonadotrophns stimulated ovaries with that of from natural cycling ovaries. In-vitro matured oocytes were collected from (1) naturally ovulated mice and (2) superovulated (PMSG + hCG) mice. Immature oocytes were retrieved from (3) naturally cycling mice, and (4) from mice primed with PMSG. The results indicate that the percentages of cleavage and blastocyst formation are significantly different (P&lt;0.05) between in-vivo and in-vitro matured oocytes. Blastocyst formation rate is significantly higher (P&lt;0.05) in immature oocytes derived from PMSG primed mice compared to immature oocytes derived from naturally cycling mice. The percentages of oocytes with comet tails and the length of comet tails are significantly higher and longer respectively in in-vitro matured oocytes compared to in-vivo matured oocytes. Total cell numbers of blastocyst are also significantly different (P&lt;0.05) between in-vivo and in-vitro matured oocytes. However, there are no differences in ratio of trophectoderm (TE)/inner cell mass (ICM) between in-vivo and in-vitro matured oocytes. In conclusion, in-vivo matured mouse oocytes are more competent than those of matured in-vitro, suggesting that it may be due to its less damage of DNA. Embryonic development capacity of in-vivo matured oocytes is not promoted by ovarian stimulation. Gonadotropin priming prior to immature mouse oocyte retrieval is beneficial to subsequent embryonic development.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b950.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860c13r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gonadotropins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fertilization in Vitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oocytes -- growth &amp; development</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wp465"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of mother care on the relationship between self-esteem and neural subtrates in young men and women : a neuroimaging study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wadiwalla, Mehereen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction. Numerous studies have suggested that maternal care can influence the development and expansion of an individual's self-esteem. Yet the neural mechanisms of this relationship remain unexplored. Incidentally, it has already been demonstrated that a brain region, namely the Hippocampus (HC) is associated with both self-esteem and maternal care. Thus suggesting that there may be a three-way relationship. This also provided the impetus to speculate that a similar interaction could be observed in other brain regions like for example, the Dorsolateral Prefrontal cortex (DLPFC) and the Medial Prefrontal Cortex (MPFC). Therefore, the aim of this study is to scrutinize the possible relationship between mother care, self-esteem and neural correlates including the DLPFC, MPFC and HC, with emphasis on how normal variations in mother care could have consequences for the relationship between self-esteem and particularly the prefrontal cortices. Methods . Fifty-one subjects were recruited on the basis of their maternal scores, as assessed by the Parental Bonding Index and were consequently assigned to either a high mother care (MOCA) or low MOCA group. Their self-esteem was measured through various self-esteem scales including the Rosenberg self-esteem scale. The structural integrity of the regions was ascertained through the use of both manual and semi automated segmenting procedures. Results . Initial Bivariate correlations reported a negative association between DLPFC volumes and self-esteem in the high MOCA group while HC was positively associated with self-esteem in both high and low MOCA groups. There were no associations to report for the MPFC. Additional analysis revealed that the Biregional association was sex specific. Discussion. For the first time, we were successful in associating DLPFC volume with self-esteem. In addition, we successfully replicated the association between self-esteem and HC volume. This study could provide an indication how of maternal care could have a sex specific affect not only on the evolution of self-esteem, but also on the regions they may be targeting.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k9505.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wp465</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Hippocampus -- anatomy &amp; histology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mother-Child Relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self Concept</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prefrontal Cortex -- anatomy &amp; histology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gm679"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Association of second trimester amniotic fluid constitutents with emergence of gestational diabetes mellitus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tisi, Daniel Kevin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Our objectives were to measure concentrations of glucose, insulin, insulin-like-growth-factor-binding-protein-1 (IGF BP1) and beta-hydroxybutyrate (BOHB) in amniotic fluid (AF), and establish if these concentrations were associated with emergence of maternal gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM). AF samples (n=408) were collected following routine amniocentesis (12-22 weeks gestation). Glucose and insulin concentrations were elevated in our GDM mother-infant pairs, where GDM was associated with a 176g increase in birth weight. Logistic regression showed that AF glucose but not insulin was associated with developing GDM. Non-linear Bayesian probability plots showed that when 2nd trimester glucose was plotted against insulin increases in both were predictive of the subsequent emergence of GDM. In conclusion, our findings show that: (1) AF glucose but not insulin predicts subsequent emergence of GDM and (2) these observed elevations provide evidence that the fetus of GDM mothers is being exposed early in-utero to metabolic perturbations (i.e. elevated glucose) that may have important long-term metabolic consequences for their future development.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rj72g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gm679</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diabetes in pregnancy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amniotic liquid -- Analysis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zz39g"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of the Plant Breeders' Rights Act on wheat productivity : evidence from western Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ye, Xiangxiang, 1983-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Plant Breeders' Rights (PBR) are a form of intellectual property rights enabling breeders of new plant varieties to have the exclusive right to produce and sell propagating material of their new plant varieties. The existence of effective property rights has been pointed to as a stimulus of increased R&amp;D and productivity. Canada has had legislation to provide PBR protection for about two decades, and is considering further strengthening of the regulatory framework. However, there are few studies that have examined the effectiveness of the legislation on crop productivity. This thesis investigates the hypothesis that the adoption of wheat varieties qualifying for Plant Breeders' Rights has increased overall wheat yields and rate of yield increase. The yield response function models are applied to industry data for western Canada and Alberta, respectively. The empirical results show that the PBR Act had a relatively small impact on wheat yields. Among wheat classes, it had a positive impact for Durum wheat in Alberta.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92gc486.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zz39g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant breeding -- Law and legislation -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada. Plant Breeders' Rights Act</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant breeders -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wheat -- Yields -- Canada, Western</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kv56w"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Treatment and recovery in first-episode psychosis : a qualitative analysis of client experiences</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Windell, Deborah L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: There is currently very little research on recovery from the perspective ofindividuals with recent-onset of psychotic disorders. Forming a better understanding ofthesubjective meaning ofrecovery and recovery experiences during this early phase ofrecovery caninform effective and meaningful service design and practices.Method: Thirty individuals recovering from psychosis and receiving specialized earlyinterventiontreatment were interviewed regarding the meaning and experience of recovery frompsychosis during the early phase (2-5 years) ofthe illness course.Results: Recovery was described as a multidimensional experience that included aspects of"illness recovery," "psychological recovery," and "social recovery." Seven common earlyrecovery experiences were identified. Individual variations in the magnitude ofdescribeddisruption of self and social functioning, duration ofthe illness-acceptance process and theprocess treatment negotiation greatly influenced the experience ofrecovery.Conclusion: Differences in illness acceptance and social recovery trajectories have importantimplications for understanding individual responses to the experience ofpsychosis, its diagnosisand treatment. These differences emphasize the importance of assisting individuals with theconstruction of meaning and the reengagement in social roles following the initial illnessexperience.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte: Il y a actuellement peu de recherche sur la rétablissement du point de vue d'individusaprès un premier épisode de psychose. La formation d'une meilleure compréhension de senssubjectif des expériences de rétablissement pendant cette première phase de rétablissement peutinformer le design efficace et expressif des services et des pratiques.Méthode: Trente individus se rétablissement de la psychose et recevant un traitement depremière intervention spécialisé ont été interviewés à propos du sens et de l'expérience derétablissement de la psychose pendant la première phase (2-5 ans) du cours de maladie.Résultats: La rétablissement a été décrite comme une expérience multidimensionnelle qui ainclus des aspects de "la rétablissement de maladie," "la rétablissement psychologique," et "larétablissement sociale." Identifiées ont été sept premières expériences de rétablissementcommunes. Les variations individuelles dans l'étendue de perturbation décrite de soi et defonctionnement social, la durée du processus d'acceptation de maladie et de la négociation duprocessus de traitement ont beaucoup influencé l'expérience de rétablissement.Conclusions : Les différences dans les trajectoires d'acceptation de maladie et de rétablissementsociale ont des implications importantes pour comprendre les réponses individuelles àl'expérience de psychose, sa diagnose et traitement. Ces différences accentuent l'importanced'assister les individus avec la construction de sens et avec le réengagement dans les rôlessociaux après l'expérience de maladie initiale.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malla, Ashok</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547w68b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kv56w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Quality of Life -- psychology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schizophrenia -- rehabilitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychology, General</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychotic Disorders -- rehabilitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schizophrenic Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ang451n88z"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Leishmania donovani peroxin 14 N-terminal region is important for glycosomal localization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nyisztor, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Glycosomes are subcellular organelles that are evolutionarily related to the peroxisomes of higher eukaryotes. The Leishmania glycosome performs various metabolic processes that are essential for the survival of these parasites, such as the glycolytic process. Proteins that are destined for import into the glycosome interact selectively with specific cytosolic receptors peroxin 5(PEX5) or PEX7. The PEX5-protein complex migrates toward the glycosomal membrane where it interacts with PEX14, a vital step for protein important into the glycosome. This project investigated the interaction mechanism of Leishmania donovani PEX14 with the glycosomal membrane. The regions responsible for PEX14 interaction with the glycosomal membrane are established in higher eukaryotes. LdPEX14 is poorly conserved with respect to the other PEX14 homologues. In Leishmania the interaction of LdPEX14 with the glycsomal membrane has been shown to be unique in terms of its lack of insertion in the glycosomal membrane. Using LdPEX14 mutants it was determined that the first 63 amino acids are important for the interaction of LdPEX14 with the glycosomal membrane. Results further suggest that LdPEX14 is a homopolymer forming a complex of 20S in size which is vital for the proper functioning of the glycosome.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les glycosomes sont des organelles subcellulaires reliés aux peroxysomes des eucaryotes supérieures. Les glycosomes de Leishmania sont impliqués dans d'important processus pour le parasite, notamment la voie glycolytique. Les protéines qui sont destinées au glycosome sont attachées sélectivement au Peroxine 5 (PEX5) ou PEX7, des récepteurs cytosoliques. Le complexe PEX5-protéine est importé à la membrane du glycosome où il interagi avec la protéine PEX14 attachée à la membrane. Dans ce projet le mécanisme d'interaction de PEX14 de Leishmania donovani avec la membrane du glycosome a été examiné. Les régions responsables de l'interaction entre PEX14 et la membrane du glycosome ont été établies chez les eucaryotes supérieurs. LdPEX14 est peu conservé par rapport aux PEX14 des autres espèces, de plus LdPEX14 est une protéine attaché en périphérie de la membrane. L'interaction de LdPEX14 avec lamembrane du glycosome semble être unique due à son absence d'insertion dans la membrane du glycosome. Avec des protéines mutantes de LdPEX14 nous avons déterminé que les premiers 63 acides aminés sont importants pour l'interaction avec la membrane du glycosome. Finalement, les résultats suggèrent que LdPEX14 est un homopolymère d'une taille de 20S qui est crucial pour le bon fonctionnement du glycosome.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pf81x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451n88z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Leishmania</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microbodies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591d384"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Recent contributions to the phenomenology of musical time : a critical survey</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaudreau, Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un dévelopment récent dans le domaine de la théorie musicale est l’application des méthodologies phénomenologiques de l’analyse du temps musical. Une analyse phénomenologique de la musique prend, comme point de départ, la musique comme phénomene “auditif.” Cette thèse fournit une étude critique des diverses façons par lesquelles les théoriciens de lp musique ont appliqué la phénomenologie à l’analyse du temps musicale. Je commence mon étude par une présentation générale de la discipline philosophique de la phénomenologie.et ensuite je considère le travail de trois théoriciens, Judy Lochhead, Thomas Clifton, et David Lewin, qui ont adopté une démarche phénomenologique aux questions du temps dans la musique. Dans le dernier chapitre, je considère certaines études du temps musicale faites par deux autres théoriciens, Christopher F. Hasty et Jonathan D. Kramer. Malgré le fait que ces derniers ne sont pas d’abords des phénomenologistes, certains aspects de leur travail peuvent néanmoins être considérés comme implicitement phénomenologique en caractère.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The application of phenomenological methods to the analysis of musical time is a recent development in the field of music theory. Phenomenological analyses of music take as their point of departure music as a "heard" phenomenon. This thesis provides a critical survey of the differing ways music theorists have applied phenomenology to the investigation of musical time. After presenting a general overview of the philosophical discipline of phenomenology itself, the thesis considers the work of three theorists, Judy Lochhead, Thomas Clifton, and David Lewin, who adopt a phenomenological approach to issues of time in music. The final chapter considers some approaches to issues of musical time by two theorists, Christopher F. Hasty and Jonathan D. Kramer, who are not explicitly phenomenologists, but whose works are implicitly phenomenological in orientation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Caplin, William</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44ps069.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591d384</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phenomenology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Communications and the Arts, Music</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tempo (Music)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558j36p"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geology of the Mutton Bay Intrusion and surrounding area, North Shore, Gulf of St. Lawrence, Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Davies, Raymond</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Geology and structure of 1,000 square miles of granulite-upper amphibolite facies gneisses cut by syn- and late-kinematic intrusions are described. The circular post-kinematic Mutton Bay alkaline syenite (631 m.y.) is divided into three main intrusive groups on the basis of chemistry, mineralogy, and field relations. Differentiation includes gravity settling and flow differentiation, while intrusion involved early stoping and assimilation with late faulting. Depth of the present level below the roof of the intrusion is estimated at 6-8 miles and temperature of crystallization of felspars in the early magmas at greater than 1015°C at less than 500 bars water pressure. Orthoclase inverted to microcline in foliated rocks that intruded as crystal mushes. A giant gabbro dyke with syenite differentiate (470 m.y.) is intruded by diabase and trachyte dykes. Carbonate enrichment in the trachytes is accompanied by high potash felspar content. Sandstone dykes are the only Paleozoic sediments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kranck, E. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913v08k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558j36p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology -- Québec (Province) -- Mutton Bay Area</dc:subject><dc:subject>Earth Sciences, Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483p46j"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dipolar interactions in selected paramagnetic crystals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vanier, Jacques</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dipole-dipole interactions in various paramagnetic crystals have been studied. Line broadening, an effect caused by dipolar interactions, has been investigated in KJ {Cr Co} (CN)6 and Rb {Cr Al} (SO4). 12H2O as a function of the concentration of Cr3+. In the alum, the theory of line widths based on dipolar interactions agrees well with experimental results. In chromicyanide, the measured widths are greater than the widths calculated from dipolar interactions alone; inhomogeneous broadening is known to take place. Spin lattice relaxation rates in the two mentioned crystals were measured at 4.2°K; the rates are dependent on the concentration of the paramagnetic ions. Relaxation rates measurements made in K3 {Fe Co} (CN)6 showed that the relaxation takes place through a two phonons process at 4.2°K; the rates are independent of concentrations. An experiment is described in which fast relaxing canters (Fe3+) are inserted in a Kr {Cr Co} (CN)6 crystal. A strong cross relaxation between the chrome and the iron ions is detected and is dependent on the concentration of the ions. This partly explains the concentration dependence of the measured spin lattice relaxation rates in the chromium salts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woonton, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193f092.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483p46j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236663q"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Lifetimes of excited nuclear levels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Weaver, Ralph. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new method of analysis of delayed coincidence experiments, the third moment method, is reported. A description of electronic and experimental techniques used to obtain beat time resolution is given; the resolution obtained was 2.33 X 10^-10 s. A number of measurements of mean lives of excited states is given; the values obtained were: 80 keV level in I131, (7 .15 +/- 0.30) X 10^-10 s; 3.2 meV level in Pb208, (4.41 +/- 0.20) X 10^-10 s; 2.62 meV level in Pb208, (4.7 +/-1.5) X 10^-11 s; 323 keV level in V51, (2.5 +/- 0.6) x 10^-10 s; 374 keV level in Ca53, less than 8 X 10^-11 s; 993 keV level in Ca43, (1.3+0.2/-0.4) X 10^-10 s; 288 keV level in Gd156, (2.08+/- 0.20) The expected mean lives of the second excited states in the even-even rare earths and heavy nuclei are calculated using the rotational model; these are compared with known experimental results, and future work in the rare earths is proposed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bell, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mc169.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236663q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72pc465"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Proton emission from neutron deficient light nuclides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McPherson, Ross</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Delayed proton emission has been observed following bombardment of stable isotopes among the elements between nitrogen and silicon using both the external and internal proton beams of the McGill 100 Mev synchrocyclotron. The protons are emitted from virtual states excited by the beta decay of highly neutron deficient nuclides. Charged particle spectroscopy, cross bombardment and reaction Q values have allowed the identification of several new radioactive neutron deficient nuclides as the precursors of the proton emission. The delayed proton precursors (and their half-lives in msec where measured) are O¹³, Ne¹⁷ (103 ± 7), Mg²¹ (118 ± 4), and Si²⁵ (225 ± 6), all having A = 4n + 1 and Tz = -3/2. The lowest energy T = 3/2 state bas been located in the Tz = -1/2 daughter nuclides Na²¹, and A1²⁵. These states are excited by superallowed beta decay of the respective precursor and their de-excitation is by isotopic spin forbidden proton emission. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bell, R. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193f10t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pc465</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xd85w"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Relative acceptor powers of group III and IV halides</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Miller, Jack Martin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Molecular addition compounds have been known for over one hundred and fifty years. Ammonia-boron trifluoride (BF₃ .NH₃) was first prepared by Gay-Lussac (1) and studied by Davy (2). Lewis (3,4) attempted to explain the bonding in this complex in terms of the donor-acceptor principle which he first used to define the terms acid and base. He stated that "A base is any species that is capable of donating a pair of electrons to the formation of a covalent bond, and an acid is any species that is capable of accepting a pair of electrons to form a covalent bond." [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stammer, C.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Taurins, A.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Onyszchuk, M.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Whitehead, M. A.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xd85w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kv575"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rethinking International Bankruptcy Law: A Critical Study of the Substantive and Procedural Approaches to its Current Status</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Al-Bashir, Salah-eddin M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is essentially a critical examination of the traditional and reformatory approaches of international bankruptcy law in Canada, England, and the United States. It highlights the shortcomings of the traditional law and the inherent limitations, contradictions, and inconsistencies of its applicable mechanism; the doctrines of private international law. The dissertation further argues that the reform schemes thus far advanced suffer from jurisdictional problems and fall short of ensuring optimal outcomes for international bankruptcy cases. Although some of these reform schemes achieve the desired equality of distribution, they unnecessarily entail a reduction in the value of distributable assets by carrying out piecemeal liquidations of local assets in order to satisfy some local claims. […]</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse contient principalement une étude critique des conceptions traditionnelles et réformatrices de la loi sur la faillite internationale au Canada, en Angleterre et États-Unis. Elle éclaire les insuffisances de la loi traditionnelle ausi qua les limitations, contradictions et incohérences des mécanismes qui lui sont inhérents: les principes du droit international privé. Cette thèse soutient en outre que les plans de la reforme formulés jusque-là sont affectés par des problèmes d'organisation judiciaire et n'aboutissent pas à assurer les meilleurs résultats pour les procédures de faillite internationale. Quoique certains de ces projets de réforme réalisent l’égalité de distribution recherchée, ils entrainent une diminution inutile de la valeur des biens distribuables en provoquant des liquidations fragmentaires de biens situés sur place, en vue de satisfaire certaines réclamations locales. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Groffier, Ethel</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q575t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kv575</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bankruptcy (International law)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap8418s42f"><ual:graduationDate>1965</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The glacial geomorphology of the Cambrian Lake area, Labrador-Ungava</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Drummond, Robert Norman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Field work by the author in 1951 in the Kaniapiskau-Koksoak area laid the foundation for the air photo interpretation of the vegetation and physiography of northern Labrador-Ungava. This was elaborated by two teams of photo interpreters, and, together with data from field investigations elsewhere, was extended to cover all of Labrador-Ungava. The maps of vegetation and physiography that resulted showed new and unexpected distribution patterns and helped pinpoint areas where more detailed-ground study might reveal significant information on particular aspects of the vegetation and glacial history of the peninsula. Many such etudies have been made, partly as a result of the initial mapping. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418s42f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geomorphology -- Québec (Province) -- Cambrien, Lac, Area</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lac Cambrien Area (Québec)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glacial landforms -- Québec (Province) -- Cambrien Lake Area</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f789v"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Magnetoresistance at medium and high fields in indium antimonide and indium arsenide</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Champness, Clifford. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Measurements have been made of the angular dependence of magnetoresistance and Hall effect of indium antimonide at room and liquid air temperatures in fields less than 7,000 oersted, and of the transverse magnetoresistance at room temperature of indium antimonide and indium arsenide in transient fields up to 3 x 10^5 oersted. The lower field results confirm the existence of a small positive longitudinal magnetoresistance not due to sample and field misalignment but due to either a cubical anisotropy of conduction properties or to sample inhomogeneity. Some structure in the angular variation is apparent at 77°K.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stevenson, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h1636.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f789v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acj82kc65m"><ual:graduationDate>1912</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Contributions to the knowledge of the Monteregian petrographical province</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Stansfield, John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A study of the geology of a portion of the township of Outrement was made by the author. The area under consideration is included in the sheet of Montreal and vicinity published by the Geological Survey of Canada to accompany the report of Adams and Leroy on The Artesian and other Deep Wells on the Island of Montreal. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Adams, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tk76c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kc65m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9w0327191"><ual:graduationDate>2013</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The design of an integrated system for rapid prototyping with ice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Barnett, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ice construction has been used for practical and artistic purposes for thousands of years. In the past few decades, computer numerical control (CNC) ice sculpting has become a well-established industry, with many companies producing ice sculptures for corporate events. This thesis presents a novel form of ice construction, namely, 3D ice printing, also known as rapid freeze prototyping. Rapid prototyping is an interesting alternative technique for ice construction, since it can be used to produce many objects that would be difficult or impossible to build with manual or CNC techniques.  A robot-assisted rapid prototyping system has been produced by retrofitting an Adept Cobra 600 robot. This thesis first provides an overview of the system; then, several of the innovative control algorithms that have been implemented are reported. The Cobra 600 system is capable of constructing any 3D model, up to a size of approximately 300 × 300 × 200 mm; the system accuracy is approximately 0.5 mm, with the rate of construction about one litre per day. Most of the retrofitting work has been on the software side; several innovative algorithms have been produced, which represent the main contributions to knowledge of this thesis. A part-slicing algorithm produces deposition paths from CAD parts; compared to the established algorithms on which it is based, computational efficiency has been greatly improved. A trajectory control algorithm produces data for controlling the Cobra 600 system during part construction. This algorithm is unique because of its simple, robust approach to the time-optimal trajectory planning problem, and its independence of a dynamic model of the robotic system. A geometric feedback system has been developed that detects and corrects geometry errors during part construction. An integral component of this system is a three-dimensional spatial PID controller, produced by transforming the traditional PID controller, which is one-dimensional in time. Time-varying flow control has also been developed and implemented, as both a necessary feature to complement variable-speed deposition paths and a means to correct part errors detected with the geometric feedback algorithm. All of the algorithms described above have been integrated to produce the Cobra 600 software implementation. Many of the innovative techniques developed are applicable to other rapid prototyping systems; additionally, some are applicable to other fields of research, including mapping, manufacturing, and signal processing.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La construction en glace est utilisée à des fins pratiques et artistiques depuis des milliers d'années. Au cours des dernières décennies, l'usinage de glace par CNO (commande numérique par ordinateur) est devenu un secteur bien établi, où également diverses sociétés produisent des sculptures pour des événements corporatifs. Cette thèse porte sur une nouvelle technique de construction en glace par impression 3 D. Cette technique, aussi appelée le prototypage rapide, peut être utilisé pour produire des objets qu'il serait difficile ou même impossible de produire avec les techniques traditionnelles d'enlèvement de matière. Un système de prototypage rapide en glace a été conçu et mis au point au moyen d'un robot Cobra 600 d'Adept Technology. Cette thèse donne un aperçu du système d'impression 3 D et des divers algorithmes novateurs mis au point. Le système Cobra 600 est capable de construire n'importe quel objet, de dimensions maximales de 300 × 300 × 200 mm, avec une précision d'environ 0,5 mm, et une cadence de construction d'environ un litre par jour. La plupart des contributions à l'avancement des connaissances porte sur les logiciels. Un algorithme de tranchage de l'objet produit les trajectoires de déposition ; comparé aux algorithmes bien établis, sur lesquels il est basé, l'efficacité de calcul est nettement meilleur. Un deuxième algorithme génère l'information de commande nécessaire pour construire un objet avec le système Cobra 600. Son approche simple et robuste minimise le temps requis pour suivre une trajectoire, et le rend indépendant du modèle dynamique du robot. Un système d'asservissement géométrique détecte et corrige les erreurs géométriques durant la construction de l'objet. Un régulateur OIT (odométrique, intégral, tachymétrique) spatiale 3 D remplace le régulateur OIT traditionel, unidimensionnel et temporel. La commande variable de l'écoulement du liquide complète les trajectoires de déposition à vitesse variable, et corrige les erreurs détectées au moyen du système d'asservissement géométrique. Tous les algorithmes décrits ci-dessus sont intégrés afin de permettre l'utilisation du logiciel du système Cobra 600. De nombreuses techniques novatrices mises au point dans le cadre de cette recherche sont susceptibles d'application aux autres systèmes de prototypage rapide ; en outre, certaines peuvent être appliquées à d'autres domaines, comme la cartographie, le traitement de signaux, et la fabrication.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Damiano Pasini</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jorge Angeles</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pf826.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0327191</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah415pf83g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Impermanent structure of communitarian thought</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blattberg, Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le dévbat actuel entre les liberaux et le communautarires a été des le commencement un dialogue d'incompréhension. Ce dont je vous propose de discuter à la source , c'est qu'au dénbat les liberaux et les communautaires sont en désaccord au sujet de la relation entre la théorie et la pratique alors que c'est la nature de la théorie politique elle même. Pour aider a trouver une solution plus productive dans ce débat, je propose que ce sujet placé bien évidence dans le discours des protagonistes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Since its inception, the contemporary debate between liberals and communitarians has been a dispute mired in misunderstanding. The source of this, I want to argue, is that liberals and communitarians disagree about the appropriate relationship between theory and practice and hence the nature of the political theory itself. To help bring about a more productive debate, then, I suggest that this theme be placed front an centre in the writings of its protaganists.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376194h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pf83g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Conservative literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liberalism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A794082398"><ual:graduationDate>1969</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Music and the arts in Calvin's Geneva : a study of the relation between Calvinistic theology and music and the arts, with special reference to the Cent Cinquante pseaumes (1583) of Pascal de l"Estocart</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leslie, Robert Homer</ual:dissertant><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021k43g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/794082398</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music -- Geneva -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psalms (Music)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calvinism</dc:subject><dc:subject>L'Estocart, Paschal de, b. 1540? Pseaumes de David</dc:subject><dc:subject>Part songs, Sacred</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajq085q298"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design of a VLSI convolution system for image processing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Haule, Damian Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L'une des techniques les plus connues dans traitement de l'image est évidemment la convolution en deux dimensions (2-D). Elle est aussi utilisée fréquemment dans graphique par ordinateur, techniques de filtrage, filtres linéaires et "invariant a la translation", clans le but de détecter des contours, réduire les bruits, etc ... Un problème majeur de ces opérations en 2-D est la consommation énorme du temps de calcul, même pour des petites fenêtres. Le temps de calcul dans les filtres croit très rapidement avec la grandeur de noyau de convolution. Une solution pour ce problème est de concevoir un système qui peut accomplir des calculs de convolution d'une manière précise et parallèle. L'approche optimale est de concevoir un circuit-intégré spécialisé : il s'agit de fabriquer un processeur pour la convolution, celui-ci peut accomplir une partie de l'opération entière. Ce processeur est utilisé clans un système de vision robotique, dans lequel les nouvelles caractéristiques sont nécessaire pour détecter des erreurs de convolution et en minimiser, particulièrement les "dépassement de capacité". </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>One of the most commonly used algorithms in image processing is certainly the two dimensional (2-D) convolution. It is also widely used in graphics, filtering applications, linear, shift-invariant filters, like in edge detection, noise reduction, etc. The main problem with 2-D operations is that they require intensive computations even for small image windows. This large computational requirements takes minutes or hours if implemented in software and it grows very rapidly with the convolution kernel size. One solution to this problem is to build a dedicated hardware system that can perform the convolution calculation in a highly regular and parallel fashion. This hardware approach is followed and a specialized VLSI convolution chip is designed and fabricated to perform a part of the entire convolution operation. The chip is to be used in an autonomous robot vision system, hence novel features are included for the detection and minimization of convolution errors especially overflows. […]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malowany, A. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hk91s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085q298</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aviation insurance -- Law and legislation -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aviation insurance -- Law and legislation -- New York (State)</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>