<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mh70b"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>From Gutenberg's Galaxy to Cyberspace: The Transforming Power of Electronic Hypertext</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mason, Jean S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Literacy, as we have come to understand and teach it, is currently in a situation of critical change. New and increasingly complex technologies are creating new literacies; however, our present concepts of literacy are heavily grounded in Gutenbergian print. This traditional understanding is inadequate for the new and complex literacy of digital discourse. This dissertation foregrounds the issue of how literacy, as manifest in the writing process, is affected when composing in hypertext, particularly in the context of the World Wide Web. This qualitative study addresses the question: How are writers' perceptions of the new rhetorical situations presented by hypertext affecting the decisions they make and the consequent heuristics they employ in response to these perceptions?</dc:abstract><dc:abstract> fr</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq78j.zip</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh70b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education -- Language and Literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x358z"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Combinatorial auctions: allocation and communication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wu, Christopher</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une enchère est une procédure bien-connue pour redistribution de biens matériaux entre des vendeurs et des acheteurs. Une extension de l’enchère où plusieurs acheteurs sont en compétition pour un seul itème est l’enchère combinatoire, où plusieurs itèmes sont redistribués simultanément. Ce mémoir a pour but d’adresser le problème de l’allocation de biens dans le contexte d’une enchère combinatoire. Nous considérons les résultats déjà obtenus dans la théorie computationnel des enchères combinatoires. Un problème primordial dans la théorie des enchères est la représentation des enchérisseurs et leurs préférences. Une autre question concerne le coût des communications entre les enchérisseurs et le commissaire-priseur. L’outil principal à ces fins est la structure de la fonction sousmodulaire, qui représente du point de vu économique les valeurs marginales décroissantes. Nous donnons quelques résultats d’inapproximabilité pour les allocations sur des fonctions sousmodulaires. Finalement, nous donnons des nouvelles garanties d’approximation pour des fonctions sur des ensembles restreints et sur des fonctions qui drivent de propriétées de graphes. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>An auction is a well-known mechanism for reallocating items between buyers and sellers. An extension of the standard single-item auction is the combinatorial auction where multiple items are handled simultaneously. The focus of this thesis is to address the problem of allocating items in the setting of a combinatorial auction. We consider some of the computational work that has been done in recent years for combinatorial auctions. A fundamental problem in auction theory is how one represents the bidders and their preferences. Another issue is to address the cost of communications between bidders and the auctioneer. The main tool of interest is the structure of the submodular function which has the economic interpretation of decreasing marginal values and has been well-studied since the early 60s. We show some inapproximability results for allocations on submodular functions. Finally, we present some new approximation guarantees for restricted set functions and functions stemming from graph properties.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Adrian Roshan Vetta</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn74j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x358z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences -- Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5t34sm64x"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Performance evaluation of a picture archiving and communications system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rioux, Alexandre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The DICOM-conformant PACS of the MGH was subjected to a performance study. The goal was to develop the tools needed to extract meaningful, quantitative measures related to performance with a view towards establishing reliable indicators that can help identify design weaknesses and performance changes over time. Efforts focused on operational scenarios such as moving images from servers to workstations, automatic routing and prefetching tasks. The performance of each process underlying these scenarios was studied using residency timing combined with a web-based monitoring system to yield quantitative data from various low-level resources on each server. While the critical processes and hardware on the PACS were already monitored to identify faults, the tools developed in this study now provide the means to assess overall performance issues. The results have yielded insights that have helped to identify faulty and inefficient logic in certain program constructs, and suggestions for design improvement and software enhancement.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le PACS du HGM a été soumis à des études de performance. Le but était de développer des outils qui permettent d’obtenir des mesures quantitatives reliées aux performances, afin d’établir des indicateurs fiables permettant d’identifier des points faibles du design et des variations des performances. Les efforts ont été concentrés sur des scénarios opérationnels tels que le transfer d’images des serveurs aux stations de travail, et les services automatisés de distribution d’images. La performance de chacun des procédés utilisés pour ces scénarios a été étudié en utilisant le temps de résidence combiné avec un outils de surveillance du système qui permet ainsi l’acquisition de données quantitatives pour plusieurs ressources de base de chacun des serveurs. Bien que les principaux programmes, ainsi que les équipements du PACS, soient déjà sous surveillance, les outils developpés dans cette étude permettent d’évaluer les problèmes de performance global. Les résultats ont aidé à identifier des erreurs et des inneficacités dans les algorithmes de certains programmes, et ont permis de suggérer des améliorations au design ainsi qu’aux programmes. fr</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq24t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm64x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences -- Radiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8g84mp588"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kahnawake Iroquois and the Lower-Canadian Rebellions, 1837-1838</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sossoyan, Matthieu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Drawing on archival data and theoretical reflections on interest groups and collective identity, this thesis aims to understand why the Kahnawake Iroquois cooperated with the British Crown during the Lower-Canadian Rebellions of 1837-1838. It is suggested that the Iroquois' decision to intervene was prompted by their own interpretations of the events and of their complex relationships with the British, neighboring settlers, and the Patriotes. It is argued that the resulting collective action was intended to defend interests such as government annuities, land, and livelihood. An analysis of the cultural, social, economic and political contexts further reveals that by intervening in the crisis, the Iroquois intended to protect land and presents because they were powerful symbols around which they collectively defined themselves as "Indians", despite the presence of internal factions. To conclude, it is argued that Kahnawake Iroquois did not intervene in the Rebellions only to defend economic interests, but, more fundamentally, to express and protect their collective identity.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>S'inspirant de sources archivistiques ainsi que de concepts théoriques tels que le groupe d'intérêt et l'identité collective, ce mémoire de maîtrise A pour objectif de mieux comprendre les raisons qui ont amené les Iroquois de Kahnawake A collaborer avec les autorités britanniques au cours des Rébellions de 1837-1838. La prise de décision des Iroquois semble avoir été basée sur leur propres interprétations des événements et de leurs relations avec les autorités coloniales, les villages voisins et les Patriotes. Une analyse des contextes culturels, sociaux, économiques et politiques suggère que l'intervention des Iroquois avait pour but de défendre des intérêts collectifs tels que les cadeaux annuels et le territoire. De tels intérêts avaient une valeur symbolique importante comme représentant une identité "indienne" et "de Kahnawake", et ce, malgré la présence de factions internes dans la communauté. Enfin, nous proposons que les Iroquois de Kahnawake ont décidé d'intervenir au cours des Rébellions non seulement afin de protéger des intérêts d'ordre économiques mais, aussi, afin d'exprimer et de défendre une identité collective. fr</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk39m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp588</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology -- Cultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870z17w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geochemical investigation of perennial spring activity and associated mineral precipitates at Expedition Fiord, Axel Heiberg Island, Canadian high arctic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Omelon, Christopher R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two groups of perennial springs are observed in the Canadian High Arctic at Expedition Fiord on Axel Heiberg Island. Saline discharge (~1.3-2.5 molal) produces a variety of calcite (travertine) and gypsum-rich precipitates. Field observations, laboratory experiments, and geochemical modeling of the waters reveal that calcite precipitation is controlled primarily by CO2 degassing, but alternating light (sparite calcite crystals) and dark (amorphous micritic calcite spheres coated by organic material and trace metals) laminae are present. Evaluation of the geochemical environment in conjunction with field observations suggest that micrite layer formation may be influenced by microbial activity, although their presence has yet to be confirmed.      In addition, discharge from two springs at Colour Peak leads to the precipitation of metastable calcium carbonate crystals (0.25-0.5 cm long) on terraced and steep mound slopes that form during winter months. Background literature and field observations suggest that this mineral may be ikaite (CaCO3•6H2O). The precipitation of this mineral may provide information regarding its environmental growth constraints and opportunities.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Deux groupes des sources pérennes sont observés dans le Haut-Arctique au fjord Expedition sur l'île Axel Heiberg. Les eaux minéralisées (~1.3-2.5 molal) qui sortent des sources produisent une précipitation de dépôts variés et riches en calcite (travertine) et gypse. Les observations de terrain, les expériences en laboratoire et les modèles geochimiques des eaux montrent que la précipitation de calcite est contrôlée principalmente par la perte de gaz CO2 mais il y a des couches pâles (crystaux calcite sparite) et foncées (sphères de calcite micritique amorphe emrobées par materiaux organique et metaux trace). L'évaluation de l'environnement geochimique et les observations de terrain suggèrent que la production de la couche micritique pourrait être influencée par l'activité microbienne, mais la présence de microbes reste à confirmer.      Les sources pérennes à Colour Peak produisent également des cristaux calcium carbonate "métastable" (0.25-0.5 cm) sur les pentes raides et en terrasses pendant l'hiver. La litérature et les observations de terrain suggèrent que ce minéral peut fournir de l'information sur les conditions environnementales de la croissance. fr</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838269p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z17w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences -- Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mx684"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Program in Communications</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Literature at lightspeed: a community of writers on the world wide web and its relationship to the print publishing industry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nayman, Ira</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>L’Internet offre aux écrivains de nouvelles possibilités de réalisation et de distribution de la littérature contemporaine. Cette dissertation commence par examiné en profondeur l’identité de ces écrivains, ce que font ces écrivains et les avantages et les désavantages du Web en comparaison avec les méthodes d’édition traditionnelles. Etant donné les réseaux qui se produisent et l’existence d’objectifs communs parmi les écrivains, on s’aperçoit qu’une véritable communauté d’auteurs s’est développé sur le Web. Ceci dit, aucune communauté n’existe indépendement d’autres facteurs sociaux qui l’influencent. Les sociétés de divertissement multinationales, par exemple, essaient de changer la structure fondatrice de ces technologies pour en tirer des profits potentiels qui seraient extraordinaires; leurs efforts pourraient effectivement diminuer la capacité des auteurs indépendents à se servir du Web pour distribuer leurs œuvres de manière efficace. Les gouvernenments, pour citer un autre exemple, peuvent transformer les pratiques des utilisateurs du Web en imposant des lois contraignantes. Ces lois peuvent délimiter le contenu en ligne tout comme elles peuvent favoriser les intérêts des grandes sociétés de production. Pour terminer, les auteurs qui se publient sur le Web pourraient avoir un effet de désintermédiation sur l’édition traditionnelle. Cet effet aurait des répercussions importantes pour, entre autres, les maisons d’édition et les librairies. Cette dissertation dresse le portrait d’un réseau de liens complexes entre les auteurs indépendents et les développeurs institutionnels qui se servent de cette nouvelle technologie toujours en évolution. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The World Wide Web offers individual writers new possibilities for producing and distributing fiction. This dissertation begins with an in-depth look at who these writers are, what they are doing and the advantages and disadvantages the Web has compared to traditional publishing venues. The common goals of these writers and the various ties which bind them suggests that a community of writers has developed on the Web. No community exists in isolation, however, so the dissertation also looks at some of the other forces at work in society which may have an effect on this community. Transnational entertainment conglomerates, for instance, are attempting to change the underlying structure of the technology in order to reap potentially great profits from it; their efforts may result in diminishing the ability of individual writers to use the Web to effectively distribute their work. Governments, to use another example, can affect the way individuals use the medium by enacting laws restricting certain categories of content online or developing copyright laws which favour the interests of large entertainment producing corporations. Finally, writers publishing on the Web may have a disintermediating effect on traditional print publishing, with ramifications for, among others, publishing houses and bookstores. What emerges in this dissertation is a portrait of the complex web of relationships between individual and institutional stakeholders in this developing technology.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx573.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx684</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications and the Arts -- Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97ks602"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation and retraining of driving skills in clients with stroke / Évaluation et réentraînement des habiletés à la conduite automobile de clients ayant subi un accident vasculaire cérébral</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mazer, Barbara Lee</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une composante importante du processus de réadaptation des clients ayant subi un accident vasculaire cérébral (AVC) est la référence à un service d’évaluation de conduite automobile, dans le but de déterminer la capacité à conduire du client. Toutefois, la validité de la procédure d’évaluation actuellement utilisée n’a pas encore été déterminée. De plus, même si les cliniciens offrent des thérapies visant à optimiser le niveau de fonctionnement dans plusieurs domaines d’activités de la vie quotidienne, peu de centres de réadaptation ont jusqu'à maintenant tenté d’aider leurs clients à réapprendre à conduire de façon autonome. La présente thèse est constituée de trois articles portant sur les méthodes d’évaluation des performances de conduite ainsi que sur l’efficacité d’un nouveau programme d’entraînement à la conduite automobile pour les clients ayant subi un AVC. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>An important component of the rehabilitation of clients with stroke is a referral by treating clinicians to a driving evaluation service in order to determine fitness to drive. However, the validity of the evaluation procedure has not been well established. In addition, while clinicians offer therapy to help improve the level of function in many areas of daily life, few rehabilitation centres have attempted to assist clients to return to independent driving. This thesis is comprised of three manuscripts examining both the methods used to evaluate driving performance as well as the effectiveness of a novel training program on the driving success of clients with stroke.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f8151.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks602</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences -- Occupational Health and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gg20w"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Then play on: listening to the Shakespearean soundscape</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Folkerth, Wes</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Shakespeare’s plays articulate their author’s understanding of sound at various registers of theatrical and linguistic representation. I have tried to make listening my own critical practice by attending to the ways Shakespeare is attuned to, and rebroadcasts throughout his work, the many interrelated valences sound has in the early modern period. “Shakespearience” is the term I use for a re-invigorated phenomenological approach to the study of Shakespeare’s works, one which considers them the products of an embodied consciousness that is itself informed by cultural beliefs and attitudes. Shakespearience allows us to inquire not only into what Shakespeare thought about sound, but what he may have thought through it as well. Religious, philosophical, and anatomical discourses on sound and hearing in the early modern period all associate this perceptual domain with notions of obedience, receptivity, transformation, reproduction, and cognitive nourishment. In Coriolanus and other plays, he investigates the subjective and political consequences, as well as the ultimate impossibility, of refusing to hear. In A Midsummer Night’s Dream he associates sound and hearing with notions of metamorphosis and grotesque continuity. Throughout his works, he represents sound as a privileged mode of access to the deep subjectivity of others. These ideas resonate strongly in our own culture, where references to sound and hearing increasingly figure in our estimations of his genius.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les pièces de Shakespeare articulent sa compréhension du son à registres divers de représentation théâtrale et linguistique. J’ai essayé moi-même d’employer l’écoute comme méthode critique en prêtant attention à la façon dont Shakespeare se met à l’écoute des maintes sens corrélatifs qu’avait le son à l’époque moderne, et les (re)transmet partout dans son œuvre. J’utilise le terme «Shakespearience» pour signaler une méthode phénoménologique revigorée à l’étude de l’œuvre de Shakespeare, une méthode qui considère ces textes comme produits d’une conscience incarnée qui est elle-même informée par les croyances et attitudes culturelles. La Shakespearience nous permet d’examiner non seulement ce que pensait Shakespeare au sujet du son, mais aussi ce qu’il aurait pu penser par le son. Les discours religieux, philosophique, et anatomique sur le son et l’ouïe à l’époque moderne associent ce domaine de perception aux idées d’obéissance, réceptivité, transformation, reproduction, et nourriture cognitif. Dans Coriolan et autres pièces Shakespeare examine les conséquences subjectives et politiques de refuser d’entendre…aussi bien que l’impossibilité fondamentale d’un tel refus. Dans La Nuit d’une songe d’été il associe le son et l’ouïe à la métamorphose et la continuité grotesque. Souvent dans ses pièces il représente le son comme un mode d’accès à la subjectivité insondable d’autrui. Ces idées résonnent profondément dans notre culture, où des reférences au son et à l’ouïe figurent de plus en plus dans nos estimations du génie de Shakespeare. fr</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh793.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg20w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature -- English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128ng94b"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High pressure processing of fresh tuna fish and its effects on shelf life</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zare, Zahra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le thon est fortement périssable et a été impliqué dans l’empoisonnement de l’histamine à cause de niveau très élevé d’histidine dans la chair du poisson. Il y a un forte demande pour le filet de thon frais et de steaks de type japonais de même que les grillades. La demande pour les produits frais de mer, sans additifs et sûrs a stimulé le milieu scientifique afin de découvrir de nouvelles méthodes pour prolonger la durée de vie des produits frais avec la perte minimale de qualité. Le traitement à haute pression a été évalué pour ses effets sur la qualité et la durée de vie du thon frais. Le thon frais a été soumis aux divers traitements de pression (220 MPa, 200 MPa, 150 MPa), avec les temps de rétention de 30 minutes et 15 minutes, et une température sous 20ºC. Les échantillons pressurisés et non pressurisés ont été analysés pour leurs propriétés physicochimiques initiales ainsi que les changements associés au stockage. Les paramètres de couleur (CIE L*, a* et b*), la texture, l’exsudat, pH, les attributs sensoriels, l'activité endo-protéase, TBA, TVB et le niveau d’histamine ont été évalués. Tous les échantillons pressurisés ont perdu leur lustre, et leur rougeur a diminué avec la pression et le temps de rétention. La pressurisation a augmenté le jaune des échantillons et les valeurs de ‘b’ ont augmentés au cours du stockage. Le traitement à haute pression au-dessus de 150 MPa a augmenté la fermeté des muscles ainsi qu’une élasticité plus élevée. Par le fait même, le traitement à haute pression a causé l'augmentation de l’exsudat de tous les échantillons pressurisés. Cependant, l’exsudat était significativement plus rapide sur les échantillons non traités que sur les échantillons pressurisés. L'activité protéolytique n'a pas changé significativement durant le stockage, à la différence des niveaux de TVB qui ont augmenté durant le stockage. La pressurisation à 220 MPa/</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Tuna is highly perishable and has been implicated in histamine poisoning because of high histidine levels in the muscle.  There is high demand for fresh tuna fillet and steaks for Japanese type foods, and as a grilled item in restaurants.  Demand for fresh, additive-free and safe seafood products has stimulated efforts to discover novel methods to prolong the shelf life of fresh products with minimum loss of quality.  High pressure processing was investigated for its effects on quality and useful shelf life of fresh tuna.  Fresh tuna was subjected to various pressure treatments (220 MPa, 200 MPa, 150 MPa), holding times (30 min, 15 min) and temperature (below 20oC). The pressure treated and control (untreated) samples were analyzed for initial physicochemical properties and subsequent changes during chilled storage. Color parameters (L*, a* and b* values), texture, drip loss, pH, sensory attributes, endoprotease activity, TBA, TVB and histamine levels were all evaluated. All the pressure-treated samples lost their glossiness, and their redness decreased with pressure and holding time.  Pressure treatment increased yellowness of the samples, and the ‘b’ values increased throughout storage.  High pressure processing above 150 MPa resulted in firmer muscles with higher springiness. High pressure also resulted in increased drip loss for all pressure treated samples. However during chilled storage increase in drip loss was significantly faster in untreated samples than in pressure treated samples. Proteolytic activity did not change significantly during storage, unlike the TVB levels that increased during storage. Pressure treatments at 220 MPa/30 or 15 min, and 200 MPa/30 min reduced TVB values the most.  None of applied pressure conditions induced major changes in initial pH values. Also no consistent pattern was observed for TBA levels, although the levels were low and indicative of high quality products.  Histamine formation was inhibited by pressure treatment</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Benjamin K. Simpson</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z59k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng94b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture -- Food Science and Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r7767"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Simple scaling anisotropy in the atmosphere, an exploratory study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Addor, Jean-Bernard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Motivation : l'anisotropie invariante d'échelle est mise en évidence dans des images de nuage. Même si ces images paraissent les mêmes dans toutes les directions, des structures anisotropes peuvent s'observer à différentes échelles. Méthode de mesure de l'anisotropie invariante d échelle : une méthode simple de visualisation et de mesure des exposants de base de l'anisotropie invariante d'échelle dans toutes les directions est proposée pour le cas d'anisotropie légère. Des images des satellites MODIS sont utilisées pour mesurer l'anisotropie invariante d'échelle sur des champs de nuages. Principaux résultats : une variation douce de l'exposant de la fonction de structure avec la direction géographique a été observée et le comportement de la fonction correspond à ce à quoi on s'attend, d'un point de vue mathématique. Il y a aussi une nette différence entre les exposants dans les directions nord-sud et est-ouest. La variation de la valeur de l'exposant entre les deux axes est du quart de leur valeur ; l'exposant le plus grand est celui de l'axe est-ouest. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Motivation: we investigate scaling anisotropy in cloud images. Even if these images look much the same in all directions, we can observe anisotropic structure at different scales. Scaling anisotropy measurement method: we propose a simple method to visualize and measure basic exponents of scaling anisotropy in all directions, assuming weak anisotropy. MODIS satellite images are used to measure scaling anisotropy on cloud fields. Main results: a smooth variation of the structure function exponent with the geographic direction has been observed and the behaviour of the function corresponds to what is mathematically expected. There is also a clear difference between the exponents in the North-South and East-West directions. The variation in the value of the exponent between the two axes is one quarter of the exponent, with a higher exponent in the East-West axis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Martin Grant</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hc03g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r7767</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics -- Fluid and Plasma</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nk36g"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Unit commitment with primary frequency regulation constraints in electric power systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Restrepo, José</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le problème de la planification de l’opération des unités de production d’électricité comprenant des spécifications des niveaux de régulation secondaire et tertiaire (celles-ci agissant sur un horizon de temps compris entre deux et trente minutes) a été amplement étudié. Le problème de planification de la production comprenant les aspects relatifs à la régulation primaire, agissant en fonction des variations de fréquence du réseau dans un horizon de temps de quelques secondes, n’a cependant reçu que peu d’attention jusqu’à maintenant. Dans ce mémoire, nous développons et solutionnons le problème de la planification de la production d’électricité en incluant la notion de la régulation primaire. On démontre que celle-ci est gouvernée explicitement et uniquement par la variation de la fréquence du réseau. Ensuite, la planification simultanée de la production d’énergie et de la fourniture des services de régulation primaire et tertiaire est étudiée via des études de cas sur des systèmes types possédant jusqu’à 34 unités de production.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The unit commitment problem with secondary and tertiary reserve requirements with time constants ranging from two to thirty minutes has been broadly studied in electric power systems. In contrast, the scheduling of units offering primary frequency regulation reserve deployable within seconds of a contingency has received relatively little attention. In this dissertation we formulate and solve a unit commitment problem explicitly accounting for the characteristic that primary frequency regulation has a single common degree of freedom, namely, the system frequency deviation. The simultaneous scheduling of energy, primary and tertiary reserves is then studied through a number of cases of up to 34 generating units.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Francisco D. Galiana</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666689k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk36g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering -- Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rg61j"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sujet des médias alternatifs: un citoyen néolibéral modèle?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vigneault, Karine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Beyond their actual content, the alternative media that have appeared in the last decade also constitute a concrete social practice that presumes and, thus, contributes to the normalisation of a particular view of reality. More precisely, as a practice possessing its own rationality, these media have to promote a specific conception of the political subject. It is this ideal of the subject that we have sought to qualify by interviewing volunteers from different Quebec alternative media. Three main characteristics of this subject have been identified: conceived of in (1) expressivist terms, the individual is an (2) “enterprising self”, but an “enterprising self” that is simultaneously a member of (3) communities of interests. Yet, in promoting this definition of the political subject over others, the alternative media are in fact privileging a form of subjectivity very similar to that of the neo-liberal rationality to which they are openly opposed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Par-delà leur contenu, les médias alternatifs apparus au cours de la dernière décennie constituent aussi une pratique sociale concrète qui présuppose et, donc, contribue à normaliser une définition de la réalité donnée. Plus particulièrement, ces médias doivent faire appel à une conception du sujet politique déterminée afin de se présenter comme pratique rationnelle. À partir d’entrevues réalisées auprès de bénévoles de médias alternatifs du Québec, c’est cet idéal du sujet que nous avons cherché à caractériser. S’est ainsi vu dressé un portrait en trois temps : conçu sous l’angle (1) expressiviste, l’individu apparaît comme (2) « soi entreprise », mais un « soi entreprise » s’insérant dans des (3) communautés d’intérêts. Or, en s’articulant autour de cette définition du sujet politique plutôt qu’une autre, les médias alternatifs s’appuient sur une subjectivité très près de celle que présuppose une rationalité néolibérale de gouvernement à laquelle, pourtant, ils s’opposent ouvertement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>William O. Straw</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x133z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg61j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications and the Arts - Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kq306"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design of novel gas velocity sensors for flotation systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Torrealba Vargas, Jorge Agustin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gas dispersion properties of flotation systems, such as: bubble size (db), gas holdup (epsilong) and gas velocity (Jg) are became increasingly relevant in the past 10 years for optimization of flotation systems. Flotation system kinetics have been related to the bubble surface area flux (Sb), which is known to be derived from gas dispersion properties (Jg, db). Modeling of flotation systems and in particular flotation kinetics requires reliable measurements of Jg and to do this, two novel sensors were developed. The sensors collect bubbles by natural buoyancy, and relate gas flow to either accumulation of the gas bubbles (discontinuous technique) or the pressure drop across an orifice (continuous technique). Fundamental flow equations were derived to relate those properties to Jg. Experiments range from laboratory scale (column of 15.24 cm diameter and 4 m high) to industrial flotation systems (up to 130 m3 flotation cells) were performed to validate the sensing principles and reliability of the sensor measurements. Over the range of Jg from 0.20 to 3.00 (cm/s) the continuous sensor accuracy ranges from –2.40 to –4.20 % and –0.90 to –1.93 % for tubes of 7.62 and 10.16 (cm) diameter respectively. Sampling tests indicate that tubes of 7.62 and 10.16 (cm) diameter gave same results for discontinuous and continuous techniques. In contrast, for tubes smaller than 7.62 (cm) a bias occurs between the two techniques, being the continuous always higher than the discontinuous, for example the difference between the on-off Jg sensor with a 0.5 (inch) diameter tube (1.27 cm) and the continuous 4 (inch) (10.16 cm) diameter tube is as high as 45 %. Analysis of the sensitivity of the relationship between sensors measurements and process parameters, for example bulk density, were performed. Both sensors were used in industrial applications to set the gas profiles across banks of flotation cells and, along with metallurgical analysis, allowed the industrial operators, to</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les propriétés des systèmes de flottation ayant rapport à la dispersion de gaz, par exemple: la taille des bulles (db), la charge gazeuse (epsilong), et la vélocité de gaz (Jg), sont devenues de plus en plus importantes les vingt dernières années dans l’optimisation de ces systèmes. Une relation a été établie entre la cinétique des systèmes de flottation et le flux superficiel des bulles (Sb), dérivée des propriétés de la dispersion de gaz Jg et db. La modélisation des systèmes de flottation et particulièrment de la cinétique requiert des mesures exactes de Jg et pour cette raison, deux nouvelles sondes ont été développées.  Ces sondes recueillent les bulles par flottabilité naturelle et font le lien entre la circulation gazeuse et ou l’accumulation des bulles (technique en discontinu) ou le changement de pression à travers un orifice (technique en continu). Des équations de bases pour la circulation ont été dérivées afin de relier ces propriétés à Jg. Des expériences en laboratoire (colonne de 15.24 cm de diamètre et 4 m de hauteur) et en industrie (volumes cellulaires jusqu’à 130m3) ont été complétées afin de valider les principes de précision et de fiabilité des mesures des sondes. Pour des valeurs de Jg entre 0.20 et 3.00 (cm/s) la précision de la sonde a été variée entre –2.40 et 4.20 % et entre –0.90 et –1.93 % pour des diamètres de tubes de 7.62 et 10.16 (cm) respectivement. Des tests par prélèvement ont indiqué que les tubes avec un diamètre entre 7.62 et 10.16 (cm) ont donné les mêmes résultats pour les techniques en continu et en discontinu. Par contraste, pour les tubes de diamètre de moins de 7.62 (cm), la tendance de la sonde  en continu était de donner une mesure plus élevée que celui en discontinu.  Par exemple, la différence entre une sonde en discontinu avec un diamètre de 1.27 (cm) et celui en continu avec un diamètre de 10.16 (cm) peut atteindre 45%. L’analyse de la p</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>James A. Finch</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d874k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kq306</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering -- Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0p096940g"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interpretation of dairy data using interactive visualization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>St-Onge, Annie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The agricultural domain is faced with the challenge of increasing amounts of collected data, multiple sources of external information and various summary reports, all tending to exist in a non-structured fashion. The formats and locations of these various data sources almost certainly differ, but profitable decision-making often depends on using and interpreting all of these inputs accurately. Based on the hypothesis that the interpretation of dairy-herd data can be aided using interactive visualization, the main goal of this research was to improve the understanding of the data-interpretation process, using such techniques, and by taking full advantage of them in the context of the Quebec dairy farm. The challenge was one of designing a system that would integrate interactive visualization techniques while also accounting for the diversity of information involved, the clientele of the dairy industry, and the technologies available. A methodological framework was developed to support the design of such an interactive visualization system, and a software prototype – HerdLine – subsequently developed. This prototype focused on the planning of a dairy-herd composition, based on the evolution of its performance over time via genetic and economic profiles. The framework helped the prototype development by better matching the characteristics of the targeted users with the data involved in the software. The result was a tool that provides an overall picture of the dairy-herd, as well as rapid, incremental, and reversible views of information contained within. An informal evaluation process was performed in order to assess the appropriateness of the prototype from a user’s point of view. Four participants, representing diverse sections of the dairy industry, downloaded, installed and tested the prototype. They subsequently completed a survey regarding their impressions to such an approach, as well as their actual experience with the prototype. Both quantitative and</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le domaine agricole fait face au défi d’un nombre croissant de données collectées, de rapports et de sources d’information. De plus, ils tendent tous à exister de manière non structurée. Le format et l’emplacement de ces multiples sources de données diffèrent, mais les prises de décision importantes à la ferme dépendent souvent d’une interprétation juste de toutes celles-ci. L’objectif principal de cette recherche était de présenter une approche qui améliorait l’interprétation des données par l’emploi de la visualisation interactive comme support technique en maximisant leur potentiel dans le contexte des fermes laitières québécoises.  Le défi était d’effectuer le design d’un système qui intégrerait ces techniques de visualisation interactive tout en tenant compte du caractère diversifié de l’information qui serait à l’étude par ce système, ainsi que des utilisateurs potentiels et des technologies disponibles. Un cadre méthodologique a d’abord été conçu dans le but de supporter le développement d’un système de visualisation interactive et un prototype informatique - HerdLine - a ensuite été développé. Ce prototype avait pour domaine d’application la planification de la composition d’un troupeau laitier, se basant sur l’évolution de ses performances et son rendement, en plus de ses profils génétique et économique. Le cadre méthodologique a aidé au processus de développement en rejoignant mieux les caractéristiques des utilisateurs visés et des données impliquées aux caractéristiques que le logiciel devait posséder. Il en a résulté un outil capable de fournir une image globale d’une ferme laitière, en plus d’offrir des vues rapides, cumulatives et réversibles de l’information. Un processus d'évaluation auprès d’utilisateurs potentiels a été créé et exécuté dans le but d’évaluer si le prototype et l’approche utilisée pour son développement étaient appropri</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kevin Wade</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d875v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096940g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture -- Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vd714"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>IGF-IR targeted cancer gene therapy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Samani, Amir Abbas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Depuis la “déclaration de la guerre contre le cancer” en 1971 et grâce aux avancées en génétique humaine et technologie moléculaire, le domaine de la biologie du cancer s’est rapidement étendu, fournissant l’espoir qu’un traitement pour cette maladie léthale sera trouvé. Une des contributions majeures du domaine de la biologie cellulaire pour la compréhension des maladies malignes a été la mise en évidence du rôle des facteurs de croissance et de leurs récepteurs dans la transformation et la progression maligne. En particulier, le rôle central que jouent les récepteurs à tyrosine kinase (RTK) dans différents cancers a abouti au développement d’agents thérapeutiques efficaces. Un des RTK impliqué dans la progression maligne est IGF-IR, le récepteur de type 1 du facteur de croissance de l’insuline qui a été identifié comme étant une cible pour des traitements anti-cancéreux. La thérapie génique est en pleine voie de développement pour la thérapie du cancer. De manière générale, de nombreuses stratégies de thérapie ont été développées en ciblant les gènes et protéines impliqués dans l’initiation et la progression du cancer. L’élaboration d’une stratégie de thérapie génique efficace nécessite la compréhension des bases moléculaires de la progression du cancer ainsi que la connaissance de la génétique et la physiologie humaine et animale Dans ce travail, j’ai introduis deux stratégies différentes pour inhiber la formation de métastases du foie en utilisant des lignées cellulaires cancéreuses humaines et murines. La première stratégie est basée sur le ciblage de IGF-IR dans des cellules tumorales en utilisant une stratégie antisens (chapitre 2). Cette stratégie s’est également avérée être appliquable à la thérapie génique du cancer de glioblastome dans le cerveau (chapitre 3). De facon intéressante et ce, pour la première fois, nous avons montré que la diminution de l’exp</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Since the declaration of “War on cancer” in 1971, and with the insight provided by recent advances in human genetics and in molecular  technology , the field of cancer biology has been expanded rapidly providing  hope that a cure for this lethal disease will be found. One of the major contributions of the field of cell biology to the understanding of malignant diseases has been the identification of growth factors and their receptors as major promoters of transformation and malignant progression. In particular, the appreciation of the central role that receptor tyrosine kinases (RTK) play in different cancers has led to development of effective therapeutic reagents. One of the RTK implicated in malignant progression is the receptor for the type 1 insulin like growth factor (IGF-IR) that has been identified as a target for anti-cancer treatments. Cancer gene therapy is a rapidly developing modality for cancer therapy. Many gene therapy strategies have been developed generally targeting the genes and proteins involved in cancer initiation and progression. To design a successful gene therapy strategy requires an understanding of the molecular basis of cancer progression and knowledge of human and animal genetics and physiology. In the present work, I have introduced two different strategies to inhibit liver metastases formation using established human and murine cancer cell lines. The first strategy is based on targeting the IGF-IR in tumor cells using an antisense technology (chapter 2). This strategy was also shown to be applicable in cancer gene therapy of glioblastoma growing in the brain  (chapter 3). Very interestingly and for the first time, we showed that reduction of IGF-IR   expression levels in glioma cells can induce a state of dormancy, providing a unique model to study this clinically important phenomenon. As the second strategy, I designed a novel soluble IGF-IR molecule. I showed that expression of this molecule in tumor cells caused an inhibitio</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Penina Brodt</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tp13f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd714</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1831cn13x"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identités et loyautés des auteurs et peintres russes de l'Estonie post-soviétique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rouillard, Remy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lorsqu’elle mit fin à cinq décennies d’occupation soviétique, l’Estonie comprenait une importante minorité russe. Dans le but de se distancier de la Russie et de « corriger » les torts causés aux Estoniens par le régime soviétique, l’État estonien mit en place des politiques nationalistes qui affectèrent ces Russes ainsi que les autres non-Estoniens. Les membres de la minorité russe durent donc redéfinir leur position en Estonie alors que leur présence et leurs liens à la Russie étaient perçus comme problématiques par le peuple estonien et par l’État. Depuis que l’Estonie est devenue candidate à l’accession à l’Union européenne, on fit pression auprès de l’État estonien afin qu’il améliore ses relations avec ses minorités nationales, ce qui mena à l’adoption d’une vaste politique d’intégration des non-Estoniens. Menée suite à la mise en application de cette politique, cette recherche examine diverses facettes de l’identité ethnique de peintres et d’auteurs russes qui vivent en Estonie. Dans ce mémoire, nous verrons que ceux-ci ont de forts liens d’appartenance à l’Estonie, tout en étant profondément attachés à la langue et à la culture russes, en plus d’entretenir certains liens avec l’Europe. Ceci remet en question certaines politiques de l’État estonien, en particulier celles qui concernent les conditions de citoyenneté. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>After five decades of Soviet occupation, Estonia’s population included a large Russian minority. In order to distance itself from Russia, and to “correct” the harm done to the Estonian people by the Soviet regime, the Estonian state implemented nationalistic policies that affected Russians and other non-Estonians. Thus, the members of the Russian minority needed to redefine their position within Estonia at a time when their presence and their links to Russia were perceived to be problematic by both the Estonian people and the state. When Estonia became a candidate to enter the European Union, the Estonian state was pressured to improve its relations with its national minorities, which led to the adoption of the Integration of non-Estonians policy. Conducted after implementation of the policy, this research examines the multifaceted aspect of the ethnic identity of Russian painters and authors living in Estonia. This thesis shows that they demonstrate a strong sense of belonging to Estonia, yet they manifest a deep attachment to the Russian language and culture, while also feeling related to Europe. This calls into question certain policies of the Estonian state, in particular those concerning the conditions of citizenship.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carmen Lambert</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn21c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cn13x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology -- Cultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am900nw74p"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Risk perceptions, importance ranking and a contingency valuation analysis: results from a survey of Quebec producers on farm environmental management</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Quan, Yongxin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research studied Quebec producers’ environmental attitudes and perceptions on environmentally friendly practices on farm, such as an environmental management system (EMS), using a survey. The contingency valuation method (CVM) was applied to elicit producers’ mean willingness to accept compensation (WTA) of adopting an EMS on farm, in terms of the percentage of direct costs of implementation. Factors affecting the mean WTA were studied to examine their influences. The results show that Quebec producers adopt environmental practices extensively and face many challenges in agro-environmental management. The results also show that producers have mixed perceptions in the benefits and difficulties of environmentally friendly practices and a negative attitude towards environmental regulations. The mean WTA of Quebec producers is estimated at 79.73%. French speaking and English speaking farmers have the mean WTA of 79.91% and 71.75%, respectively. The regression analysis identifies that producers’ knowledge level on EMS, their attitudes towards the benefits and difficulties, internet access and the use of a computer in farm management are significant variables with respect to the mean WTA.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette recherche a pour but l’étude de la perception et l’attitude des producteurs agricoles du Québec sur les pratiques culturales respectueuses de l’environnement tel que le système de la gestion environnementale (SGE) à partir d’un sondage. La méthode l’evaluation contingente est utilisée afin de mesurer la volonté d’accepté la compensation (VAC) d’adopter le systeme de gestion environnementale au sein de l’entreprise en terme de pourcentage de coûts directs d’adoption comme compensation. Dans cette recherche, les facteurs influençant la moyenne de la VAC seront étudiés. Les résultats de l’analyse montrent que bon nombre de producteurs québécois adoptent déjà les pratiques respectueuses de l’environnement et font face à de nombreux défis en gestion agro-environnementale. Ces résultats montrent également que les producteurs confondent leur perception concernant les avantages et les difficultés des pratiques culturales respectueuses de l’environnement et une attitude peu négative envers les lois environnementales. La moyenne de la VAC des agriculteurs québécois est estimé à 79,73%. Les agriculteurs francophones démontre une VAC de 79,91% alors que celui des agriculteurs anglophones est de 71,75%, respectivement. D’après cette étude, le niveau de connaissance des agriculteurs sur le SGE, leurs attitudes envers les avantages et difficultés, l’accès à l’internet et l’usage d’un ordinateur dans la gestion de l’entreprise  sont des facteurs significatifs qui influencent la moyenne de la VAC. fr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurence B. B. Baker</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj63s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw74p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics -- Agricultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773x89p"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Words that carry meaning: issue definition and affirmative action</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pylkkänen, Elisa Maaria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le présent mémoire est une étude comparée de politiques d’action positive en vigueur dans sept pays : l’Australie, le Canada, l’Inde, les Pays-Bas, l’Afrique du Sud, le Royaume-Uni, et les États-Unis. Se basant sur une variété d’études universitaires, le mémoire aborde trois approches analytiques qui ajoutent à notre compréhension des différences entre les politiques : la distinction entre les mesures antidiscriminatoires dites douces et dures, les différences idéologiques, et les acteurs sociaux dont le comportement est visé par la législation. L’argument principal s’appuie sur la perspective théorique de définition de problèmes et soutient que la langue associée avec les politiques d’action positive nous aide à comprendre les différences observées entre ces politiques. Enfin, une typologie de programmes d’action positive est développée à partir des cadres analytiques présentés tout au long de l’étude. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This paper presents a comparative study of affirmative action policies in effect in seven countries: Australia, Canada, India, the Netherlands, South Africa, United Kingdom, and the United States. Drawing on a wide range of literature, the paper discusses several analytical frameworks that help in describing and accounting for differences between the policies, including the distinction between soft and hard affirmative action, ideological differences, and the social actors expected to adapt to affirmative action legislation. Ultimately, however, it is argued that the greatest insights can be gained by applying the issue definition perspective into the study of affirmative action, in particular by examining the language associated with these policies. Based on the analysis, a typology of affirmative action policies is developed, bringing together the findings of the different analytical perspectives presented in the paper.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stuart Neil Soroka</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v88h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x89p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Political Science - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qp32w"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Structure-function analysis of the prosegment and the cysteine-rich domain of the proprotein convertase PC5A: its interaction with TIMP-2</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nour, Nadia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mammalian proprotein convertases (PCs) of the secretory pathway are calcium-dependent serine proteinases related to bacterial subtilisin and yeast Kexin. As Kexin and subtilisin, all basic aa-specific convertases contain a comparable N-terminal structure starting with a signal peptide followed by a prosegment and a conserved catalytic domain. The convertases possess additional domains at their C-terminus following the catalytic domain. All PCs exhibit a P-domain prior to the C-terminal architecture, which is specific to each convertase. Three of the basic-aa-specific convertases, furin, PACE4 and PC5 display the presence of a Cysteine-rich domain (CRD). The function of the CRD has not been studied extensively and remains unclear whereas the inhibitory function of the prosegments has been investigated previously. In this manuscript, both the function of the prosegment and the CRD of PC5A were investigated as very little was known about the zymogen activation of PC5A, the inhibitory role of its prosegment and the characterisation of the function of its CRD. Previous subtilisin- and furin-based studies demonstrated that the prosegment acts as an intramolecular chaperone and as a potent inhibitor of its cognate enzyme. From these results, the inhibitory function of the prosegment of PC5A was investigated. The data revealed that the prosegment of PC5 is a potent inhibitor in vitro and ex vivo of its parent enzyme, but is not selective. Introduction of single point mutations within the prosegment did not increase the potency or the selectivity of the inhibitor. We next characterised the relevance of the CRD of PC5A as it implication in the cell surface localisation of the enzyme. The plasma membrane retention was demonstrated to be via the interaction of the CRD of PC5A with TIMP-2, an endogenous MMP inhibitor. This study also showed that PC5A may have an anti-proliferative role as its overexpression diminishes cell proliferation while its inactivation by siRNA cau</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les convertases des proprotéines qui résident dans la voie de sécrétion sont des serine protéases de mammifères, apparentées par leur structure aux subtilisines bactériennes et à l’enzyme de la levure kexine. Comme ceux-ci, les convertases possèdent un peptide signal, un segment pro et une région catalytique conservée. De plus, ces protéases possèdent deux domaines supplémentaires, appelés domaines P et C-terminal qui sont absents chez les subtilisines mais présents chez la kexine. Le domaine C-terminal est unique à chaque convertase. Trois membres de la famille des convertases, furine, PACE4 et PC5 démontrent la présence d’un domaine riche en cysteine (CRD). La fonction de ce domaine ne fut jamais sérieusement étudiée et demeure inconnue, toutefois, l’activité inhibitrice du segment pro de la subtilisine ainsi que de certaines convertases furent étudiées extensivement auparavant. Dans ce mémoire, la fonction du segment pro ainsi que du domaine riche en cysteine de PC5A furent étudiées. Des études précédentes sur la subtilisine et la furine ont demontrées que le segment pro agit à la fois de chaperone et d’inhibiteur de l’enzyme parental. Inspirée de ces études, la fonction inhibitrice du segment pro de PC5 fut investiguée et révéla que ce domaine est un inhibiteur puissant de PC5 in vitro et ex vivo, cependant l’inhibition n’est pas spécifique à une seule convertase. De plus, des mutations ponctuelles introduites dans la région pro n’ont augmenté ni la puissance, ni la spécificité de l’inhibiteur. Auncune fonction du CRD n’avait été définie chez les PCs. Ce domaine joue un rôle important dans la localisation de l’enzyme puisqu’il permet à PC5A d’être retenu à la surface cellulaire. Sans ce domain riche en cysteine, PC5A n’est plus retrouvée à la surface car c’est au niveau de ce domaine que PC5A interragit avec TIMP-2 qui se trouve à la surface cellulaire. De plus, la surexpress</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nabil G. Seidah</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn70z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp32w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry -- Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nd325"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fractionally total colouring most graphs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Meagher, Conor John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une coloration totale d’un graphe est le coloration des arêtes et des sommets telle que deux sommets adjacents ont des couleurs différentes, deux arêtes incidentes ont des couleurs différentes, et une arête a une couleur différente de celles des ses extrémités. Si nous formulons le problème de trouver le nombre chromatique total comme un programme linéaire entier, nous pouvons considérer la relaxation connue comme la coloration totale fractionnaire. Dans cette thèse nous présentons un algorithme pour calculer le nombre chromatique total d’un graphe en temps polynomial en moyenne. Nous présentons aussi un algorithme qui calcule asymptotiquement presque sûrement le nombre chromatique total de $G_{n,p}$ pour toute valeur de $p$. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A total colouring is the assignment of a colour to each vertex and edge of a graph such that no adjacent vertices or incident edges receive the same colour and no edge receives the same colour as one of its endpoints. If we formulate the problem of finding the total chromatic number as an integer program, we can consider the fractional relaxation known as fractional total colouring. In this thesis we present an algorithm for computing the fractional total chromatic number of a graph, which runs in polynomial time on average. We also present an algorithm that asymptotically almost surely computes the fractional total chromatic number of $G_{n,p}$ for all values of $p$.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruce Alan Reed</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w461x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd325</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences -- Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xt95p"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Network software architectures for real-time massively multiplayer online games</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McFarlane, Roger D P</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A real-time massively multiplayer online game (MMOG) is a networked computer or video game in which tens of thousands to hundreds of thousands of consumers may interact with one another in real-time in a shared environment, even though these users may be separated by vast geographic distances.  Game industry analysis highlights trends indicating that online game usage and market penetration will grow significantly over the next five to ten years.  As such, game developers and entertainment companies seek to offer subscription based mass-market online games.  However, the risks, costs and complexity involved in the successful development and operation of a scalable online game service are high, in part due to lack of well established and understood models for the network software architecture of such a product.  This thesis explores the literature and research regarding distributed military simulation, academic networked virtual environments, and commercial online gaming in search of patterns for network software architectures which are applicable to massively multiplayer online games.  It is the hope of the author to contribute to this cross pollination of ideas by providing a thorough review of the techniques and approaches for the design and implementation of large scale distributed systems having properties similar to those found in a massively multiplayer online game system.  In this way, perhaps the cost, complexity, and risk involved in building a massively multiplayer online game service can be reduced.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Un jeu en ligne massivement multi joueurs en temps réel est un jeu vidéo ou d'ordinateur géré en réseau dans lequel des dizaines à des centaines de milliers de consommateurs peuvent interagir entre eux en temps réel dans un environnement partagé, et ce même s’ils sont répartis dans des régions géographiques très distantes. Les analyses de l’industrie du jeu démontrent que l'utilisation et la pénétration de marché du jeu en ligne se développeront de manière significative au cours des cinq à dix prochaines années. Ceci explique que les développeurs de jeu et les compagnies de divertissement cherchent à offrir à un marché grand public des jeux en ligne basés sur un abonnement. Cependant, les risques, les coûts et la complexité impliqués dans le développement et l'opération d’un service de jeu en ligne sont élevés, dû en partie au manque de modèles bien établis et compris pour l'architecture de logiciels de réseau de tels produits. Cette thèse explore la littérature et la recherche concernant la simulation militaire distribuée, les environnements académiques virtuels gérés en réseau, et le jeu en ligne commercial à la recherche de modèles pour les architectures de logiciels de réseau qui sont applicables aux jeux en ligne massivement multi joueurs. C'est l'espoir de l'auteur de contribuer à cette pollinisation d’idées en fournissant un examen complet des techniques et des approches utilisés dans la conception et l'implémentation de systèmes répartis à grande échelle ayant des propriétés semblables à celles que l’on retrouve dans les systèmes de jeu en ligne massivement multi joueurs. De cette façon, peut-être, le coût, la complexité et le risque impliqués dans la réalisation d’un service de jeu en ligne massivement multi joueur pourront être réduits. fr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jorg Andreas Kienzle</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d223f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt95p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences -- Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ast74cs72m"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Competitiveness of Canada's poultry processing industry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Hao</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The economic research on competitiveness has become popular in recent years. Free-trade agreements and open-market policies provide new challenges for food processors competing in domestic and international markets. The Canadian poultry processing industry is one sector in which the competitive status needs to be investigated.  The purpose of this thesis is to compare the poultry processing sectors of Canada and the United States. The study measures the competitiveness, both at the industrial level and at a firm’s level, and identifies the internal and external drivers of competitiveness. Comparisons were conducted in terms of price, value added ratios, and productivity growth. Results show that Canada’s poultry industry was less competitive than that of U.S.  Lack of economies of scale, rigid supply system and high input prices in Canada are the main reasons for being less competitive.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le concept de compétitivité a gagné en popularité  dans le milieude la recherche au cours des dernières années. L’accord de libre-échange ainsi que la politique libérale ont apporté  de nouveau défis pour les entreprises de transformation alimentaire qui œuvrent dans les marchés domestiques et internationaux. L’industrie de transformation avicole est un des secteurs ou le niveau de la compétitivité se doit d’être étudié. Cette thèse a pour but de faire la comparaison entre les industries de transformation avicole  canadiennes et américaines.  La compétitivité de ces industries est donc étudiée au niveau des industries ainsi qu’au niveau des firmes, et les facteurs tant internes qu’externes déterminant la compétitivité sont présentés.  La comparaison est faite au niveau des prix, du ratio de valeur ajoutée, et du taux de croissance de production.  Les résultats démontrent que l’industrie canadienne de transformation avicole est moins compétitive que sa voisine américaine. Le niveau peu élevé des économies d’échelle réalisées, la rigidité du système d’offre, ainsi que le prix élevé des intrants canadiens sont les  principales raisons expliquant cette différence. fr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Laurence B. B. Baker</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494b490.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs72m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics -- Agricultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m175g"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Prediction in a biomimetic controller for binocular target pursuit on a free head</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Wei-Jen Jessica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Physiological evidence suggests that a single symmetric controller in the brainstem is involved in the oculomotor system (OCS) for all types of eye movements. Focusing on ocular tracking with slow pursuit (slow phase) and saccades (fast phase), a previously developed bilateral controller by Galiana is the first to adopt this unified philosophy which allows it to be free of instability during switching between modes. We upgrade this model by incorporating additional sensory signals observed in nature. 1. During slow phases, retinal slip from the flocculus and temporal integration via superior colliculi compensate for large visual delays and provide near perfect ramp tracking. 2. For fast phase control, the saccade goal, which initially only considers retinal discrepancy, now also corrects for the disparity caused by non-zero retinal slip values during saccades. The resulting OCS achieves both slow phase velocity tracking and fast phase position matching better than its precursor, coordinating two eyes on a moving head in two dimensions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les rapports physiologiques  sur le système oculomoteur (OCS) suggèrent qu’un seul système dans le tronc cérébral est partagé par tous les types de  mouvements oculaires. En se concentrant sur la poursuite oculaire basée sur les mouvements lents et les saccades, un modèle bilatéral déjà proposé par Galiana est le seul à adopter cette philosophie intégrée, ce qui permet une opération stable en dépits d’une alternation aléatoire entre les modalités  poursuite lente et saccade. Ce modèle est ici amélioré en incorporant des signaux sensoriels additionnels, qui sont connus en physiologie comme participant dans le contrôle de la poursuite. 1. Pendant la poursuite lente, la vitesse de l’erreur rétinienne venant du floculus et l’intégration temporelle de cette erreur via les collicules supérieurs sont employés pour compenser l’effet des délais visuels et produire une réponse presque parfaite aux cibles en rampe. 2. Pour les saccades, le but visuel qui antérieurement considérait seulement l’erreur rétinienne, maintenant inclut aussi sa vitesse pour prédire la position future d’une cible. Le résultat est un contrôleur du OCS qui obtient une poursuite améliorée et pendant les phases lentes, et pendant les saccades vers des cibles en mouvement; ceci est démontré avec la coordination de deux yeux sur une tête mobile pendant la poursuite de cibles se déplaçant en deux dimensions. fr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henrietta L. Galiana</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw802.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m175g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering -- Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913s03s"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Road to Turkish language reform and the rise of Turkish nationalism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Johnson, Aaron Scott</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire traite des changements qui ont eu lieu en même temps dans l’identité turque et dans la langue turque à partir de la période de réforme et de modernisation du Tanzimat jusqu’au nationalisme turc anatolien et à la réforme de l’alphabet et de la langue dans la période républicaine. Ce travail étudie spécifiquement le grand rôle que le thème du langage a joué dans le développement de l’identité nationale turque vers la fin de la période ottomane, et aussi s’occupe du développement de l’ottomanisme et de l’Islamisme. Finalement, on examine comment le désir de propager le nationalisme turc laïc en place de l’ancienne identité ottomane-Islamique a motivé les réformes kémalistes de l’alphabet et de la langue, et on termine avec une discussion de quelques conséquences de ces changements planifiés par rapport à la langue et à la base de l’identité turque. fr</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the concurrent changes in Turkish identity and in the Turkish language from the early developments in the period of the modernizing Tanzimat reforms to the Anatolian Turkish nationalism and the alphabet and language reform of the Republican era. It looks specifically at how language issues played a large role in the development of Turkish national identity towards the end of the Ottoman period, and also examines the development of Ottomanism and Islamism. Finally it looks at how the desire to promote secular Turkish nationalism in place of the old Ottoman-Islamic identity was the driving force behind the Kemalist script and language reforms and discusses some of the consequences of these planned changes to the Turkish language and to the basis of Turkish identity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. Uner</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v89s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s03s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History -- Middle Eastern</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An296x1347"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Toward excellence as the standard for medical practice variation in documentation and surgeons' opinion in the breast clinic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghaderi, Iman</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Recently, there has been a growing movement toward an Electronic Health Record (EHR) to improve quality of care. The paper-based medical record is still the primary source of information in today’s medical practice. In order to design the EHR, knowledge with regard to the current medium of documentation is required. In the MUHC Cedars Breast Clinic, 112 medical records for 7 surgeons were audited to determine what was recorded in the initial visits between year 2002 and 2003. A Likert scale questionnaire was developed and included 46 questions derived from the chart review. It was introduced to assess their opinions on important variables in managing breast patients. The correlation between the medical records and surgeons’ opinions was then sought. The majority of data points had a low rate of documentation with wide variation; breast cancer risk factors were recorded in less than one third of charts. Family history and physical examinations had relatively high rates of documentation. The survey showed a considerable variation among surgeons’ opinions. Surgeons reported that they addressed 63% of all data points (29 of 46 questions) very often/always. There was weak correlation between what each surgeon records and what he/she thinks is important.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Récemment, il y a eu un mouvement grandissant vers le dossier électronique de santé (EHR) pour améliorer la qualité du soin.  Le dossier médical sur papier est toujours la source primaire d'information dans la pratique en matière, aujourd'hui.  Afin de concevoir EHR, la connaissance en ce qui concerne le milieu courant de la documentation est exigée. Dans la Clinique du sein de l'Institut des cèdres du CUSM, 112 disques médicaux pour 7 chirurgiens ont été apurés pour déterminer ce qui est enregistré dans les visites initiales en l'année 2002 et l'année 2003.  Un questionnaire de balance de Likert comprenant 46 questions dérivées des dossiers a été présenté pour évaluer leur avis sur des variables importantes dans les patients de gestion de sein.  La corrélation entre ces deux a été cherchée. La majorité de points de repères a eu un bas taux de documentation avec une grande variation;  des facteurs de risque de cancer de sein ont été enregistrés dans moins d'un tiers de dossiers. Les antécédents familiaux et les examens physiques ont eu des taux relativement élevés de documentation. L'aperçu a montré une variation considérable parmi l'opinion des chirurgiens.  Les chirurgiens ont rapporté qu'ils ont adressé 63% de points de repères (29 de 46 questions) très souvent/toujours.  Il y avait corrélation faible entre ce que chaque chirurgien enregistre et quel il/elle pense est important. fr</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David M. Fleiszer</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp581.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x1347</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences -- Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>