<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajd472w90n"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Expression of histone modifying proteins and chromatin remodelling factors in swine oocytes and developing embryos</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wachter, Audrey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Currently, the quality of oocytes matured in vitro is still not satisfactory. In fact, only 5-10% of oocytes were evaluated to be intrinsically capable to produce in vitro embryos with full developmental competence. Recent studies have highlighted the importance of epigenetics, a mechanism controlling activation and repression of gene expression, in embryonic development. Indeed, several proteins involved in histone modifications including histone deacetylase 1 (HDAC-1), lysine specific demethylase 1 (LSD-1), and brahma related gene 1 (BRG-1) were shown vital to early development. We described the presence of these proteins during porcine oocyte maturation and embryo development and investigated whether these proteins were also involved in the regulation of developmental competence. We detected the three proteins in all stages of development, but nuclear localization was not always confirmed. We noticed that these three proteins followed the same general trend before activation but while the fluorescence signal of HDAC-1 increased after activation those of LSD-1 and BRG-1 decreased. Moreover, oocytes and embryos of lower developmental competence were observed to have differences in the fluorescence signal of HDAC-1, LSD-1, and BRG-1. The occurrence of targeted LSD-1 histone modifications, histone 3 lysine 4 mono- (H3K4me1) and di- (H3K4me2) methylation, were also found to be different in embryos of different developmental competence. This study suggests that HDAC-1, LSD-1 and BRG-1 are developmentally regulated during early development of swine embryos and are potentially involved in the acquisition of the embryonic developmental competence.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Aujourd'hui, la qualité des ovocytes maturés in vitro n'est toujours pas satisfaisante. En effet, seulement 5 à 10% des ovocytes peuvent intrinsèquement engendrer in vitro des embryons avec entière compétence développementale. Récemment, des études ont montré l'importance qu'a l'épigénome, mécanisme qui active ou inhibe l'expression des gènes, dans le développement embryonnaire. Effectivement, plusieurs protéines reconnues capables de modifier les histones telles que l'histone déacétylase 1 (HDAC-1), la déméthylase spécifique aux lysines 1 (LSD-1), ainsi que le gène brahma related 1 (BRG-1), ont été démontrées vitales aux premiers stades développementaux. Nos expériences ont pour buts de décrire par immuno-détection la présence des ces protéines pendant la maturation méiotique et le développement d'ovocytes et d'embryons porcins et de savoir si ces protéines sont aussi impliquées dans la régulation de la compétence développementale de ces-derniers. Nous avons décelé la présence des trois protéines à tous les stades de développement bien que leurs localisations nucléiques n'aient pas été toujours confirmées. De plus, nous avons observé que l'intensité du signal de fluorescence des trois protéines fluctue similairement au cours de la maturation des ovocytes. Cependant, après l'activation, la fluorescence de HDAC-1 augmente alors que celles de LSD-1 et BRG-1 diminuent. D'autre part, nous avons pu constater que les ovocytes et embryons de moindre compétence développementale présentent des différences de fluorescence pour les trois protéines étudiées. En outre, nous avons également détecté des différences dans la présence de mono- (H3K4me1) et di- (H3K4me2) méthylations sur la 4e lysine de l'histone 3, cibles de LSD-1, dans des embryons de différentes compétences développementales. Cette étude suggère que les protéines HDAC-1, LSD-1 et BRG-1 sont régulées aux premiers stades de développement po</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vilceu Bordignon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784m267.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472w90n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Animal Culture and Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7m01bm088"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The regulation of STAT1 nuclear content by Mammalian Target of Rapamycin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tan, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) est une kinase sérine/thréonine fortement conservée qui contrôle la croissance des cellules. Chez le Saccharomyces cerevisiae, en plus de son rôle comme régulateur de croissance, TOR abaisse le contenu nucléaire de facteurs de transcription spécifiques et contrôle ainsi l'expression des gènes de réponse au stress. Dans les mammifères, nous avons déjà identifié un complexe macromoléculaire contenant la protéine mTOR, son kinase PKCδ et le facteur de transcription STAT1. Notre hypothèse est que mTOR contrôle le contenu nucléaire de STAT1 par un mécanisme similaire à celui observé chez Saccharomyces. Dans l'étude courante, nous avons démontré que l'inactivation du mTOR par rapamycin cause l'accumulation nucléaire de STAT1 et son kinase PKCδ. Nous avons également démontré que le résidu de STAT1 L407, un site d'interaction avec importin α5, est réquis pour cet effet. L'accumulation nucléaire de STAT1 a été trouvé d'étre dépendante sur le phosphatase PP2A. L'importin α5 a été également trouvé d'étre nécessaire pour l'accumulation nucléaire de STAT1 en réponse de l'inhibition de mTOR. Cependant, la mutation d'une sérine hautement conservée (S111) en alanine a renversé l'effet de l'inhibition de mTOR par rapamycin. Finalement, nous avons déterminé que la localisation nucléaire de STAT1 en réponse au rapamycin n'a pas augmenté l'apoptose, ni les marqueurs de l'arrêt du cycle cellulaire. Ces résultats décrivent un nouveau rôle pour la protéine mTOR dans la régulation des niveaux nucléaires de STAT1 et suggèrent un impact sur la mort des cellules autre que l'apoptose.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) is a highly conserved serine/threonine kinase that controls cell growth. In yeast, in addition to its regulation of cell growth, TOR lowers the nuclear content of specific transcription factors and thereby controls the expression of stress response genes. In mammalian cells, we previously identified a macromolecular protein complex containing mTOR, the kinase PKCδ, and the anti-proliferative transcription factor STAT1. We hypothesized that mTOR suppresses the nuclear content of STAT1 by a mechanism similar to that observed in yeast. Here, we showed that inactivation of mTOR by rapamycin induces nuclear accumulation of STAT1 and its kinase PKCδ. We also demonstrated that the STAT1 L407 residue, an importin α5-binding site, is required for this effect. mTOR-mediated inhibition of nuclear STAT1 levels required its associated phosphatase PP2A. The karyopherin importin α5 was required for the accumulation of STAT1 in the nucleus in response to mTOR blockade. Mutation of a highly conserved serine (S111) to alanine in importin α5 inhibited the effect of rapamycin. Finally, enhanced STAT1 nuclear localization in response to rapamycin did not correlate with apoptosis or markers of cell cycle arrest, despite the ability of rapamycin to reduce cell number in vitro. These results describe a novel role for mTOR in the regulation of STAT1 nuclear levels and suggest an impact on cell death other than apoptosis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Arnold Scott Kristof</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jr65n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bm088</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nh558"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the implementation of long LDPC codes for optical communications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wong, Andrew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les télécommunications optiques ont souvent besoin de codes de correction longues et efficaces tel le standard LDPC du ITU G.975.1 (32643, 30592) [1]. Les réalisations traditionnelles de ce code exigent des millions de fils et ne sont pas économiques. Cette thèse présente l'étude du décodage de l'algorithme différentiel avec un passage de message binaire (DD-BMP) [2] avec décision-dur. Lorsqu'il s'agit d'un algorithme bas-complexité avec des messages binaire, un nombre minimal de fil est exigé. Nos résultats de simulations pour ce code montre que le DD-BMP avec décision-dur a une meilleure exécution que celui du standard, et que la différence entre le DD-BMP avec décision-dur et l'agorithme sum-product (SP) avec décision-dur est petite aux rapports de signal-bruit (SNR) élevés. Cette thèse présente aussi une méthodologie originale pour la réalisation d'un algorithme de décodage avec décision-doux en exploitant leur structure. Une architecture d'exécution-efficient est présentée utilisant une approche partiel-parallèle avec l'agorithme line-passing, une modification de l'agorithme min-sum (MS). Cette architecture permet à l'information de doux-décision d'être employée tout en exigeant un nombre minimal de fils qui serait intéressante pour des systèmes de télécommunication optique de long-courrier.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Very powerful long low-density parity-check (LDPC) codes, such as the ITU G.975.1 Standard (32643, 30592) LDPC Code [1], have been considered for optical communications. Traditional implementations of such long codes result in circuits requiring millions of interconnections, which are not affordable. This thesis investigates the performance of the hard-decision differential decoding with binary message-passing (DD-BMP) algorithm [2], a low-complexity algorithm requiring a minimal number of wires due to its binary messages. Our simulation results for the ITU G.975.1 standard demonstrate that hard-decision DD-BMP algorithm outperforms the results provided in the standard, and that the gap between the decoding performance of hard-decision DD-BMP and hard-decision sum-product is small at high signal-to-noise ratios (SNR). We also present a novel design methodology for implementing a soft-decision decoder by exploiting the code's structure. An implementation-efficient architecture is presented using a partially-parallel adaptation of the min-sum algorithm known as the line-passing algorithm. The line-passing algorithm makes soft-decision decoding available while requiring a minimal number of interconnections, which is attractive for long-haul optical communication systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Warren Gross</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kq86s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh558</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahq37vp00p"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of double-stranded RNA binding proteins, TRBP, ADAR1 and PACT, on PKR activation and HIV-1 production</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gélinas, Jean-François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The interferon-induced protein kinase RNA-activated (PKR) is activated after virus infection but not during human immunodeficiency virus type-1 (HIV-1) infection of lymphocytes. The TAR RNA binding protein (TRBP) counteracts the inhibitory effects of PKR on HIV-1 expression and replication. In U251MG astrocytes, which are low TRBP producers, PKR is activated upon HIV-1 transfection and viral production is low. Astrocytes overexpressing TRBP express more viral proteins. Expression of adenosine deaminase acting on RNA-1 (ADAR1)-p150 and its binding to PKR are increased during high HIV-1 replication. ADAR1 also reverses PKR inhibition of HIV-1 expression and production in HEK 293T and astrocytes. DNA- and RNA-binding domains of ADAR1 are required for PKR inhibition. Surprisingly, the PKR activator protein (PACT) also reversed PKR inhibition of HIV-1 expression in HEK 293T. These results indicate that three double stranded RNA binding proteins, TRBP, ADAR1 and PACT belong to a multiprotein complex that inhibits PKR function during HIV-1 infection.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La protéine kinase induite par l'interféron activée par l'ARN (PKR) est activée après une infection virale, mais pas durant l'infection des lymphocytes par le Virus de l'Immunodéficience Humaine de type-1 (VIH-1).  La protéine de liaison à l'ARN TAR (TRBP) empêche l'effet inhibiteur de PKR sur l'expression et la réplication du VIH-1. Dans les astrocytes U251MG, exprimant faiblement TRBP, PKR est activée par le VIH-1 et la production virale reste basse. Des astrocytes qui surexpriment TRBP produisent plus de protéines virales. L'expression de l'adénosine déaminase agissant sur l'ARN-1 (ADAR1)-p150 et sa liaison à PKR augmentent quand le VIH-1 se réplique activement. ADAR1 inverse l'inhibition de l'expression et de la production du VIH-1 par PKR. L'inhibition de PKR nécessite les domaines de liaison à l'ARN et à l'ADN d'ADAR1. Étonnamment, l'activateur de PKR (PACT) inverse aussi l'inhibition du VIH-1 par PKR dans les HEK 293T. Ces résultats indiquent que trois protéines liant l'ARN double brin, TRBP, ADAR1 et PACT forment un complexe multiprotéique qui inhibe la fonction de PKR pendant l'infection du VIH-1.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anne Gatignol</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r607m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp00p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Virology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tv53b"><ual:graduationDate>2010</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Health impacts and psychological risk factors of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease exacerbations: a one-year follow-up study in China</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xu, Wanning</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les exacerbations de la maladie pulmonaire obstructive chronique (MPOC), caractérisées par la détérioration aiguë des symptômes respiratoires, sont des plus importantes dans la progression de la maladie.Cette thèse aborde deux questions principales de recherches liées aux exacerbations de la MPOC : 1) évaluer les impacts des exacerbations non rapportées de la MPOC sur la qualité de vie relative à la santé; et 2) évaluer les facteurs psychologiques (anxiété et dépression) comme facteur de risques des exacerbations de la MPOC. Comme ces études ont été menées en Chine, une des plus grandes populations de MPOC à l'échelle mondiale, cette thèse aborde également les questions de mesure tel que les traductions, validations et interprétations cliniques de deux principaux instruments de mesure utilisés pour évaluer la qualité de vie relative à la santé et les symptômes psychologiques chez les patients chinois atteints de la MPOC.L'étude a été effectuée dans une cohorte comprenant 491 patients avec une MPOC stable qui ont été suivis durant 12 mois à Beijing (Pékin), Chine. Les patients ont été évalués mensuellement par téléphone pour enregistrer les informations relatives aux exacerbations, hospitalisations et mortalité.La traduction, la validation et l'interprétation du questionnaire St-George en Mandarin-Chinois (SGRQ-MC) et l'échelle de dépression et d'anxiété en Mandarin-Chinois (HADS-MC) sont incluses dans la première et la deuxième étude. Le SGRQ-MC a été employé pour évaluer la qualité de vie relative à la santé spécifique à la MPOC, la mesure principale dépendante de la troisième étude. Le HADS-MC a été employé pour évaluer l'anxiété et la dépression, la mesure principale indépendante de la quatrième étude. Les résultats ont démontré que le SGRQ-MC et le HADS-MC sont des instruments fiables, valides et sensibles au changement chez les patients MPOC chinois. La troisième étude a évalu</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) exacerbations, characterized by acute worsening of respiratory symptoms, are the most important events in the progression of COPD. This thesis focused on two important research topics related to COPD exacerbations: 1) impacts of unreported COPD exacerbations on health-related quality of life (HRQL); and 2) impacts of psychological co-morbidities (anxiety and depression) on the risk of COPD exacerbations and hospitalizations. As the studies were conducted in China, which has one of the largest COPD populations in the world, this thesis also addressed measurement issues of translations, validations and clinical interpretations of two key measurement instruments used to assess HRQL and psychological symptoms in Chinese patients with COPD. A prospective cohort of 491 patients with stable COPD in Beijing, China was monitored for 12 months. Patient characteristics and clinical profiles were assessed at the beginning and the end of the study. Patients were monitored monthly by telephone to record important clinical outcomes (exacerbation, hospitalization and death) and to collect health and clinical data during each exacerbation. The first two studies included the translation, validation and interpretation of the St. George's Respiratory Questionnaire in Mandarin-Chinese (SGRQ-MC) and the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale in Mandarin-Chinese (HADS-MC). The SGRQ-MC was used to assess COPD-specific HRQL, which is the main outcome in the third study. The HADS-MC was used to assess anxiety and depression, which are the main exposures in the fourth study. Results suggested that the SGRQ-MC and the HADS-MC were reliable, valid and responsive instruments in Chinese patients with COPD. They have good levels of cultural and clinical equivalence to those in other populations and diseases.  The third study evaluated the impact of unreported exacerbations on patients' HRQL at one year. Unreported COPD exacerbations are common but the</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean-Paul Collet</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jean Bourbeau</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Stanley H. Shapiro</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c094c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv53b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b651q"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of chemical reaction kinetics on the structure of gaseous detonations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ng, Hoi Dick, 1977-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to elucidate the effect of chemical kinetics on the  dynamic structure of a detonation, an investigation is carried out by means of  high-resolution numerical simulations of the reactive Euler equations. The chemical  description ranges, with increasing complexity, from simplified single-step reaction  kinetics to complex models with detailed chemical reaction rates. To illustrate the unsteady dynamics of the detonation structure  and its dependence on chemical kinetics, a one-dimensional pulsating detonation with  one-step kinetics has been investigated. Different nonlinear dynamics of the  pulsating front are observed by varying the global temperature sensitivity of the  chemical process. Numerical results have suggested that the route to higher  oscillation modes may follow closely the Feigenbaum scenario of a period-doubling  cascade leading to the existence of chaos as observed in many generic nonlinear  systems. The remarkable similarity between a simple nonlinear dynamical system and  the pulsating detonation structure suggests that the use of a nonlinear oscillator  model can be considered to explore the role of chemical kinetics on the instability  spectrum of the oscillatory front. To clarify the importance of chain-branching reactions and to  resolve the drawbacks associated with the single-step Arrhenius model, a thorough  analysis of the pulsating detonation using a two-step reaction mechanism, consisting  of a thermally neutral induction step followed by a main reaction layer, has been  carried out. It is found that the dynamics of detonation structure depend not only  on the temperature sensitivity of the reaction but also the shape of the reaction  zone characterized by the length of induction and main heat release layer. From the  parametric study, a relevant non-dimensional stability parameter chi and its  associated neutral stability curve have been determined. These results are further  generalized to more complicated kinetic models of detonation in real gaseous  mixtures. They provide a tool to elucidate different experimental observations on  the detonation structure such as the cell regularity, the effect of argon dilution  and the propagation mechanism. An improved model for the prediction of the  characteristic cell size of a detonation is also formulated by including the present  stability parameter chi. To deduce a global method to examine the transient reaction  structure of the detonation, the head-on collision problem of a detonation with a  shock wave has been proposed. The present study concerned with the effect of  chemical kinetics on the unsteady dynamics of the head-on collision phenomenon.  Numerical simulations have demonstrated that the unsteady interaction involves a  relaxation process consisting of a quasi-steady period and an overshoot for the  transmitted detonation subsequent to the frontal collision, followed by the  asymptotic decay to a CJ detonation. Due to the change of chemical kinetics as a  result of the increase in the thermodynamic state of the reactive mixture froth  shock compression, the transmitted pulsating detonation can be stabilized with  smaller amplitude and period oscillation. These observations are in agreement with  experimental evidence obtained from smoked foils where significant decrease in  detonation cell size after a region of relaxation is observed when the detonation  collides head-on with a shock wave.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc44d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b651q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afn106z604"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Orthopaedic Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Internal deformation and strain of human lumbar intervertebral discs subjected to multi-axial loads</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tsantrizos, Anthony</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Morphological and clinical signs of lumbar intervertebral disc  disruption are pronounced in the posterior and postero-lateral inner annulus  fibrosus. The regional intervertebral disc predisposition to disruption suggests  that intradiscal stresses and strains may also be region specific and possibly  initiate the disruption. Quantitative data describing intradiscal deformations have  been limited to the mid-sagittal plane using techniques that compromise the  intervertebral disc integrity. No experimental study has quantified intradiscal  strain patterns. The initial objectives of the present work were to use experimental  cadaveric methods and finite element techniques to develop and validate methods of  measuring intradiscal deformations and strains along the complete mid-transversal  plane using a fine wire grid. Subsequently, these methods were used to quantify intradiscal  deformations and strains in healthy and degenerated intervertebral discs during  sub-maximal loads. Eighteen healthy and degenerated intervertebral discs were  subjected with wires placed within and beads glued along their mid-traversal plane  surface, to compression, extension, flexion and lateral bending. Cramo-caudal  radiographs at unloaded and loaded steps documented wire and bead positions.  Intradiscal nucleus pulposus displacements, circumferential, radial and shear  strains in the annulus fibrosus and transitional zone under load were compared among  all anatomical regions and between healthy and degenerated intervertebral  discs. The methods develop to estimate intradiscal strains from  intradiscal wire intersection displacements demonstrated a relative overall accuracy  of 2.9% (i.e. percent error from theoretical estimations). Generally, intradiscal  circumferential and radial strains decreased from the transitional zone to the  annulus fibrosus and increased at the side of bending during all bending conditions.  Circumferential and radial strain peaks were observed in the postero-lateral regions  even in healthy intervertebral discs during extension and lateral bending. Shear  strains were generally uniform within the healthy intervertebral disc. Degeneration  significantly increased intradiscal circumferential, radial and shear strains during  all bending conditions (particularly in the postero-lateral regions). The increased  nucleus pulposus migration in degenerative intervertebral discs appeared to have  caused the increases in circumferential and radial strains and to some extent  perhaps increases in shears strains. The inner postero-lateral annulus fibrosus is predisposed to  excessive normal circumferential and radial strains early on which coincide with  morphological changes observed in the same regions. This observation suggests a  predisposition to failure likely due to an inability of resisting delaminating  normal strains. Furthermore, the increased nucleus pulposus migration observed in  degenerated intervertebral discs appears to shift the pivot point during bending  movements more posterior, which consequently forces the postero-lateral regions to  consistently experience higher circumferential and radial strains. These effects may  contribute to the segmental instability observed in degenerated motion segments  prior to intervertebral disc failure.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw262.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z604</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct32m"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of medications in the Alzheimer's disease population : physician and caregiver perspectives</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oremus, Mark, 1968-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction. Research into medications for Alzheimer's disease  (AD) is primarily conducted in drug trials, were efficacy is assessed by changes in  score on established outcome measurement scales. However, physicians' and  caregivers' perspectives on efficacy, along with their perspectives on other factors  that may influence prescribing (e.g., adverse effects), remain largely unexplored.  The objective of this thesis is to examine these perspectives to gain a broader  understanding of the factors that can influence the use of medications in  AD. Methods. Two studies were conducted. The first involved all of  the Province of Quebec's geriatricians, neurologists, and psychogeriatricians, as  well as a random sample of Quebec's 8,115 general practitioners. The second study  involved 375 caregivers who attended AD-related support groups. Questionnaires were  used to collect data on the proportion of patients prescribed cholinesterase  inhibitors (ChEIs), efficacy requirements for prescribing new medications,  acceptance of adverse effects, physician-caregivers discussions about medications,  and caregiver pressure on physicians to prescribe medications. Results. Response rates were 35.4% (physicians) and 64.4%  (caregivers). More stringent efficacy requirements on the part of physicians were  negatively associated with prescribing ChEIs, although effect sizes were small and  associations were not always statistically significant. More stringent efficacy  requirements on the part of caregivers were negatively associated with prescribing  in some instances (e.g., required improvements to patients' ability to eat, OR=0.74,  95% CI=0.61 to 0.89), but not in others (e.g., required improvements to patients'  speech, OR=1.02, 95% CI=0.81 to 1.19). Caregivers' willingness to accept adverse  effects was positively associated with prescribing ChEIs (odds ratios for 11 adverse  effects ranged from 1.83 to 8.30); however, prescribing was not associated with  physicians being the first to discuss the use of medications to treat AD (OR=2.37;  95% CI=0.90 to 6.24), nor was it associated with caregiver pressure on physicians to  prescribe (OR=1.33; 95% CI=0.49 to 3.58). Conclusion. This research is the first to show how physician and  caregiver perspectives on issues such as efficacy and safety can affect the use of  medications in AD.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kb24x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct32m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290991f"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Layered graph drawing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Suderman, Matthew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A layered graph drawing is a two-dimensional drawing of a  combinatorial graph in which the vertices lie on a given set of horizontal lines.  Such drawings are used in application domains such as software engineering,  bioinformatics, and VLSI design. In addition to being layered, drawings in these  applications may also satisfy other constraints, for example bounds on the number of  edge crossings. The problems related to obtaining these drawings are almost always  NP -hard, so, in this thesis, we investigate restricted versions of these problems  in order to find efficient algorithmic solutions that can be used in  practice. As a first very drastic restriction, we consider layered  drawings that are planar. Even with this restriction, however, the resulting  problems can still be NP -hard. In addition to proving one such hardness result, we  do succeed in deriving efficient algorithms for two problems. In both cases, we  correct previously published results that claimed extremely simple and efficient  algorithmic solutions to these problems. Our solutions, though efficient as well,  show that the truth about these problems is significantly more complex than the  published results would suggest. We also study non-planar layered drawings, particularly drawings  obtained by crossing minimization and minimum planarization. Though the  corresponding problems are NP -hard, they become tractable when the value to be  minimized is upper-bounded by a constant. This approach to obtaining tractable  problems is formalized in a theory called parameterized complexity, and the  resulting tractable problems and algorithmic solutions are said to be  fixed-parameter tractable ( FPT ). Though relatively new, this theory has attracted  a rapidly growing body of theoretical results. Indeed, we derive original FPT  algorithms with the best-known asymptotic running times for planarization in two  layer drawings. Because parameterized complexity is so new, little is known  about its implications to the practice of graph drawing. Consequently, we have  implemented a few FPT algorithms and compared them experimentally with previously  implemented approaches, especially integer linear programming (ILP). Our experiments  show that the performance of our FPT planarization algorithms are competitive with  current ILP algorithms, but that, for crossing minimization, current ILP algorithms  remain the clear winners.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj554.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290991f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719m861"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigations into aspects of nod factor utilization for crop production</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Supanjani</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nod factors, lipo-chitooligosaccharides (LCOs), are rhizobial  signal molecules important in the establishment of nodule formation, leading to  atmospheric dinitrogen fixation in legume-rhizobium symbioses. Recently, LCOs were  also found to regulate other plant processes. We demonstrated that, at 10 -6 M, four  LCOs produced by Bradyrhizobium japonicum enhanced soybean seed germination.  Evaluation of G-protein inhibitors showed that U-73122, a phospholipase C inhibitor,  also increased soybean seed germination, similar to the increase by LCO  NodBj-V(C18:1 MeFuc), indicating different mechanisms for the plant perception to  LCOs for nodule initiation and seed germination. This was confirmed as LCOs were not  able to break dormancy of skotodormant lettuce seeds. Soybean early seedling growth  was also increased by the application of LCOs. Pulse 14Ca2+ experimentation showed  that the increase might also be related to an increase in Ca 2+ uptake by shoots. We  confirmed this with both genistein-induced and non-induced B. japonicum 532C;  however, strain 168 (a mutant unable to produce LCO) and non-host rhizobia  (Rhizobium leguminosarum, Sinorhizobium meliloti), did not increase Ca2+ uptake.  Addition of 1.6 g L-1 casein hydrolysate in yeast extract mannitol broth drastically  increased bacterial growth and increased volume-basis LCO production, but decreased  LCO production per cell. Best conditions for sterilizing and storing LCOs were  determined. LCO should be sterilized by using polyestersulfone filter or autoclaving  for up to 30 minutes. LCO was degraded faster when stored at room temperatures (23  +/- 2°C) than low temperature (4 +/- 1°C) and can be stored more  than one year.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp03h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m861</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant cellular signal transduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mycorrhizas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rhizobium japonicum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soybean -- Preharvest sprouting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oligosaccharides</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0r967414n"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of the legal system on parental alienation syndrome</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vassiliou, Despina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of the present study was to examine Parental  Alienation Syndrome (PAS) and to expand the research based knowledge in the area.  PAS entails both psychological processes and legal dimensions as it occurs primarily  within the context of custody litigation. False allegations of abuse (FA) are  commonly associated with PAS and similarly entail both psychological and legal  issues. The research comprised two separate studies. First, interviews with target  parents were conducted to attain their unique perceptions and experiences of PAS and  on the way their cases were handled within the legal system. Second, a quantitative  comparison between PAS and FA was performed to identify any similarities and  differences and examine a possible relationship between the two. Results highlighted  inherent difficulties for successful joint custody arrangements for PAS families as  communication was difficult and litigation was prominent. In spite of  well-established parent-child relationships before the divorce, these were  negatively impacted with the onset of litigation. Parents and children were  negatively impacted from the PAS, including reported mental illness for both. In FA  cases the children were found to be significantly younger and from one-child  families compared with PAS families. Women were found to more likely be the  alienators or accusers of FA. In spite of having the legal authority to deal with  the PAS, judges reportedly rarely utilized this power. The limitations of the  research are discussed and direction for future study given.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860747r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967414n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Children of divorced parents -- Mental health -- Evaluation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Custody of children -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zh32z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A narrative analysis exploring the effects of long-term caregiving on the female caregiver's sense of self</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nelham, Carolyn May</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research project explores the effect of long-term  caregiving on a female caregiver's sense of self. Participants of this study  consisted of six women: three daughters caring for their mothers and three wives  caring for their husbands. All the women had been caregiving for a minimum of three  years. Seidman's (1991) structure for in-depth phenomenological interviewing was  used which involved conducting a series of three semi-structured interviews. The  data were analyzed and described using the five-step Holistic-Content approach to  narrative analysis described by Lieblich, Tuval-Mashiach, and Zilber (1998). The six  narratives that emerged from the data present six unique stories and provide insight  into the nomothetic aspects of the caregiving experience. These aspects include time  and role captivity, guilt, loss of mutuality, appraisal of the loved one's behavior,  as well as some of the differences between caring for a parent versus a  spouse.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x754.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh32z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Caregivers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af1881m434"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Superspecial abelian varieties, theta series and the Jacquet-Langlands correspondence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nicole, Marc-Hubert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Let Ei, i = 1, ..., n, be all the supersingular elliptic curves  over Fp up to isomorphism. The modules of isogenies Hom(Ei, Ej), equipped with the  degree map, are quadratic modules that give rise to theta series of level p. The  space of modular forms of weight two for Gamma0(p) is thus spanned by the theta  series coming from supersingular elliptic curves in this fashion. We generalize this  classical result to Hilbert modular forms by showing that for totally real fields L  of narrow class number one, the space of Hilbert modular newforms of parallel weight  2 for Gamma0( p), p unramified, is spanned by theta series coming from quadratic  modules HomOL , (Ai, Aj), where Ai, Aj range across all superspecial abelian  varieties with real multiplication by OL . We also provide a version of this theorem  in the more delicate case where p is totally ramified in OL , building on the  classification of superspecial crystals following from the generalization of Manin's  Habilitationschrift that we present in the first Chapter.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591895x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m434</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax059c798d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An imaging technique for sizing bubbles in flotation systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hernandez Aguilar, José Ramon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A sampling-followed-by-imaging technique for sizing bubbles in  flotation systems has been developed and validated. The technique is based on  directing a sample of bubbles into a viewing chamber where they are exposed and  digitally imaged using incoherent backlighting. The images are automatically  analyzed by means of a threshold criterion. The chamber is sloped to spread the  bubbles over the surface of the viewing (glass) window. This configuration reduces  bubble overlap and facilitates the definition of the focus plane. To validate the images, measurements were compared with  standardized bubble sizes obtained with the displaced-volume method. It was observed  that when thresholding at half the intensity level, sizes were systematically  underestimated and the bias was correlated to bubble size, increasing from 0.3% at  ca. 0.7 mm to 2% at ca. 4 mm. Experiments were designed to evaluate the bias due to  system optics (i.e., the contribution of reflected/refracted rays and the defocus  distance to image formation) and due to the sloped window. The results showed that  reflected/refracted rays slightly biased towards underestimated sizes whereas the  inclined window caused a small overestimation. The overestimation was due to the  bubble flattening caused by the gravity force. These two effects were of similar  magnitude and, therefore, tended to cancel. Consequently, the underestimation trend  was attributed to the defocus distance which, in this unique system, is small and  unambiguous (i.e., it is invariably negative since bubbles flow "behind"  the focus plane, the underside of the window). A semi-empirical correction procedure  is suggested which uses the fundamental method of Bongiovanni et al. (1997) to  correct the bias due to system optics along with an empirical approach to compensate  for bubble flattening. To verify whether the computed size distributions were  representative of the actual dispersion, bubble populations with significantly  different size classes were mixed in a bubble column (0.1 m x 2.5 m). The column was  equipped with two independently aerated spargers with nominal porosities of 0.5 mum  (generating bubbles from 0.2 mm to 1 mm) and 100 mum (generating bubbles from 1 mm  to 5 mm), respectively. Various proportions of airflow rates were injected through  each sparger. The results showed bi-modal distributions in which the real and  calculated proportions corresponded with a deviation of less than 15%, considered  good given the severity of the test. However, the deviation was correlated to the  superficial gas velocity (J g) and bias was consistently against smaller bubbles.  The data were not sufficient to reveal the cause of the bias, but several  possibilities were entertained. The technique was demonstrated in an industrial-scale flotation  machine, where it was compared with a capillary technique. It was also used to  determine the bubble surface area flux (Sb) in a micro-flotation cell, setting up a  test of the proposed relationship between the flotation rate constant k and Sb for  the pulp zone.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg00f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c798d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j856f"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Three essays on volatility</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mazzotta, Stefano</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation is in the form of one survey paper and three  essays on the topic of volatility. The unifying feature that permeates the entire  thesis is the focus on the measurement and use of conditional second moment of  equities and currencies as a measure of risk for asset pricing and policy purposes  in the context of international markets. The survey examines selected papers from the international  finance literature and from the volatility literature with a focus on the  theoretical and empirical relationship between first and second unconditional and  conditional moments of domestic and international asset returns. It then  specifically proposes several areas for investigation related to international  finance topics. The first essay investigates the importance of asymmetric volatility  when computing the risk premium of international assets. The results indicate that  conditional second moment asymmetry is significant and time-varying. They also show  that, if the price of risk is time-varying, the world market and foreign exchange  risk premia estimated without allowing for time-varying asymmetry are less  consistent with the data. Furthermore, they imply that asymmetry is more pronounced  when the business condition is such that investors require higher compensation to  bear risk. In the second essay we start from the consideration that  financial decision makers often consider the information in currency option  valuations when making assessments about future exchange rates. The purpose of this  essay is then to systematically assess the quality of option based volatility,  interval and density forecasts. We use a unique dataset consisting of over 10 years  of daily data on over-the-counter currency option prices. We find that the implied  volatilities explain a large share of the variation in realized volatility. Finally,  we find that wide-range interval and density forecasts are often misspecified  whereas narrow-range interval forecasts are well specified. In the third essay we examine whether the information contained  in various measures of correlation among exchange rates can be used to assess future  currency co-movement. We compare option-implied correlation forecasts from a dataset  consisting of over 10 years of daily data on over-the-counter currency option prices  to a set of return-based correlation measures and assess the relative quality of the  correlation forecasts. We find that while the predictive power of implied  correlation is not always superior to that of returns based correlations measures,  it tends to provide the most consistent results across currencies. Predictions that  use both implied and returns-based correlations generate the highest adjusted R2's,  explaining up to 42 per cent of the realized correlations.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g273.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j856f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Stocks -- Prices -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Futures market -- Mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Capital market -- Mathematical models</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asx61dm804"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Photon time-of-flight and spectroscopic characterization of scattering samples using analysis of self-similarity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gributs, Claudia E. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Scattering samples such as tissue or milk are difficult to  analyze using spectroscopy. Due to scattering, the path length of light through  samples varies. However, diffuse scattering is repetitive, and can therefore be  considered to be a self-similar process. This thesis shows that mathematical  techniques which characterize self-similarity can significantly improve  spectroscopic quantification in absorbing/scattering media. Often, quantification in scattering samples relies on  multivariate analysis of near-infrared (NIR) spectra. Using data from wheat samples  and tissue phantoms, it is shown that Haar transform (HT) preprocessing improves  quantification. Wavelet domain calibration reduces the need for trial and error  preprocessing of spectra, and yields more parsimonious models and lower errors than  single wavelength selection. In particular, preprocessing with Haar "son"  wavelets gives simple calibrations which are useful to design future simplified data  acquisition schemes. Time-resolved intensity measurements compliment NM spectroscopy  by providing information on absorption and scattering coefficients (mua and mu s).  Haar wavelets are shown to be useful for constructing simple models to determine  optical properties of tissue phantoms from times-of-flight (TOFs) of transmitted or  diffusely reflected photons. For TOF distributions collected with a research-grade  instrument, three wavelets at frequencies less than 800 MHz accurately quantify mua  and mus (less than 8% and 3% error, respectively). Furthermore, when the light  source is simplified to a portable nanosecond rise-time laser diode, three wavelets  of frequencies less than 400 MHz yield accurate estimates from transmitted photon  data. Based on the above results, simplifications to the light source and  electronics of photon TOF instruments are suggested. Fractal correlation dimension calculations further improve the  analysis of photon TOF distributions. Compared to HT analysis, models based on the  correlation sum use fewer variables to quantify mua and mu s, while maintaining  comparable accuracy. A simple method of analysis that is forgiving to instrumental  drift is obtained. Overall, analysis of self-similarity facilitates quantification  in highly scattering samples. By using wavelets or correlation dimension  calculations to analyze NIR spectra or TOF distributions, simple yet accurate models  are obtained to estimate optical properties. Improvements proposed in this thesis  could serve to make measurements at the bedside of a patient  feasible.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35695053.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dm804</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913q39r"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>How do I, a teacher-researcher, contribute to knowledge of teacher learning and practice in teacher education as I explore my values through self-study?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McBride, Judith B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Stories told of and by teacher-researchers hold the potential to  inform members of both academic and school communities with concerns about teaching  and learning. The author's self-study and an embedded case study constitute this  thesis. The latter is an instrumental, single-case (Stake, 1998), seeking to offer  insight into teacher learning. It is framed by theories of cognition (Sternberg,  1998), adult learning (Mezirow, 1991), narrative (Gudmundsdottir, 1995),  teacher-research (Connelly &amp; Clandinin, 1999), and self-study (Hamilton, 1998).  This thesis presents my experience as a teacher-researcher engaging in self-study,  asking: "What do I care about in education?" (Whitehead,  1993). In conducting my inquiry, I have become interested in knowing  the following: (1) What have I learned? (2) How do I represent my learning? (3) How  shall I take my learning forward? Learning is understood to mean "the process of using a  prior interpretation to construe a new or revised interpretation of the meaning of  one's experience in order to guide future action" (Mezirow, 1998, p. 6), and is  seen in terms of improvement to professional practice. In examining the self-study  report of my colleague, Nancy, the question "How is learning evidenced in the  narrative report of the teacher-researcher engaging in self-study?" is  addressed. A claim is made that, as teachers engage with questions about what they  care about in education, they are learning. Data for my self-study include narrative  accounts, artifacts, and images. Data for the embedded case include a co-constructed  narrative account, photographs, a tape-recorded conversation, and interview and  concept map collected between January 2000 and July 2003. Narrative data in the  embedded case study were subjected to inductive and deductive analyses. Confirmatory  evidence was sought in the conversation and interview, which were analyzed  similarly, and the concept map, which was interrogated deductively. It may be seen  that the stories of teacher-researchers inquiring into practice offer evidence of  transformative learning (Mezirow, 1991), which may initiate and constitute living  educational theory (Whitehead, 1993), and provide insights to those with interests  in teacher education.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s066z.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q39r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>McBride, Judith B</dc:subject><dc:subject>Teaching</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rk80j"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analyses of alternative cell signal transduction pathways</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gong, Yunchen, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Living cells keep sensing the changes in their environments,  mostly, via cell surface receptors for different ligands. Attachment-dependent cells  are sensitive to alterations in extracellular matrix (ECM). ECM is not only required  for cell survival, but also prerequisite for epidermal growth factor (EGF) to  stimulate cell proliferation. The receptors for the majority of ECM components are  integrins and the receptor for EGF is EGF receptor (EGFR). When bound by their  ligands, integrins and EGFR induce signal transduction cascades composed of  alternative pathways. A quantitative assessment of relative contributions of  alternative pathways to one final cell signaling will help understand designing  principles of the network. Unfortunately, a methodology for such assessment is still  not available, partly because of lack of relatively mature mathematical models. On  the other hand, in most biochemical cascades, existence of alternative pathways  increases the complexity and thus the robustness of networks. The relationships  between the topology and robustness of large-scale biochemical networks have been  studied intensively recently. In small-scale networks, while feedback has been  revealed as an important contributor for adaptation and robustness, the quantitative  correlation between the topology/pathway redundancy of small networks and their  robustness remains unknown. In this thesis, apoptosis of bovine mammary gland epithelial  cells was demonstrated to be induced when fibronectin, one of the major components  of ECM, was degraded by overexpressed tPA via two potential ways: deprivation of  attachment and the effects of fibronectin fragments. Secondly, a mathematical model  for EGFR activation of the MAPK cascade, in which alternative pathways exist, was  explored and it was found that the Shc-dependent pathway is both redundant and  dominant. We hypothesize that the Shc-dependent pathway is important for EGFR to  compete with other receptors, which need Shc to transduce cell signals; and this  pathway is not aimed to increase the robustness of the EGFR cascade. Finally, for  the general importance of alternative pathways to the network topology and  robustness, several concepts have been proposed to decompose and quantitatively  characterize the networks. We demonstrate that the pathnet score is a better  assessment for robustness than the molecular connectivity.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw561.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rk80j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Apoptosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cellular signal transduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasminogen activators</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fibronectins</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r138d"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>TGF-[beta] action in skin cells : regulation by oxygen tension and steroids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mortazavi, Roya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this era of modern medicine, impaired wound healing is still  a major medical problem with limited treatment options, especially for the elderly  and for diabetic patients. One of the molecules that are recognized to be critical  in wound healing is transforming growth factor (TGF-beta). Exogenous direct  application of TGF-beta to the wound promotes healing in animal models. Since this  property of TGF-beta is cell context-dependent, the present study investigated the  role of ischemia/reperfusion using a pig-skin flap model (in vivo). In addition, we  studied the effects of: (i) hypoxia/reperfusion, (ii) steroids, and (iii) the  combined effect of both hypoxia and steroids on the TGF-beta signaling pathway  (TGF-beta, its receptors and its downstream mediators, Smad2 and Smad3) in vitro;  all of these were studied using human primary skin fibroblasts and a human  keratinocyte cell line (HaCat cells). Our in vivo results showed that the TGF-beta receptors (RI, RII,  and RIII) and TGF-beta1 are markedly increased under acute ischemic conditions in  dermal blood vessels and fibroblasts. Our in vitro experiments showed that  short-term (2 hours) and long-term (24 hours) exposure to hypoxia differentially  regulates TGF-beta components, namely, active TGF-beta, RII mRNA, phosphorylated (P)  and total Smad2 and Smad3. Our studies have also shown that steroids are able to  strongly modulate TGF-beta signaling and that these effects are critically dependent  on the type of steroid used and on treatment duration. Analysis of the combined  effect of hypoxia and steroids revealed that steroid effects on the TGF-beta  signaling machinery is potentially modulated by oxygen tension, with hypoxia acting  synergistically or antagonistically in a steroid-specific manner. In summary, we  have identified oxygen tension and steroids as regulators of the action of TGF-beta  in skin cells. We demonstrated that their effects are critically dependent on the  duration of treatment and that they may act synergistically or antagonistically on  the components of the TGF-beta pathway, emphasizing the complexity of TGF-beta  signaling. Identification of these agents as modulators of TGF-beta signaling  provides a basis for the development of strategies for the manipulation of TGF-beta  action in the skin. This may contribute towards the development of agents that  promote wound healing.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq59d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r138d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tc477"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Actions of interleukin-8 and extracellular nucleotides on airway smooth muscle from normal and CF subjects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Govindaraju, Vasanthi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cystic fibrosis (CF) patients have airway neutrophilic  inflammation associated with high levels of interleukin-8 (IL-8) and often develop  airway hyperresponsiveness (AHR). Aerosolized uridine triphosphate (UTP) has been  used to improve mucosal clearance by inducing Cl- secretion. However, nucleotides  such as UTP and ATP (adenine triphosphate) also evoke the release of intracellular  Ca2+ ([Ca2+]i), which are enhanced by pro-inflammatory mediators, such as IL-1beta.  Since most of the CF airway epithelium is lost during infection and inflammation,  the underlying airway smooth muscle cells (ASMC) are exposed to IL-8 and  extracellular nucleotides. Thus, we were particularly interested in evaluating the  effects of IL-8, extracellular ATP and UTP on contractile responses of ASMC. For  this study, cultured ASM from normal and CF lung specimens were used. We have found  that human ASM cells (HASMC) express mRNA and protein for IL-8 receptors (CXCR1 and  CXCR2) and IL-8 causes an increase in [Ca2+]; as well as cellular contraction and  migration. Furthermore, changes in the [Ca2+] i were abrogated on blocking IL-8  receptors with specific neutralizing antibodies, and were also decreased following  inhibition of phospholipase C (PLC), indicating that changes in [Ca2+]i were likely  mediated by inositol trisphosphate. The effects of IL-8 on HASMC prompted us to  investigate whether IL-8 induced ASMC contraction in CF was different from normal.  IL-8 caused larger ASM contractions and greater phosphorylation of myosin light  chain (MLC20) compared to normal cells. CF cells expressed more MLC20 compared to  normal cells. However, the expression of CXCR1, CXCR2, IL-8 induced changes in  [Ca2+]i and ASMC migration in CF cells were similar to normal cells. We also found  that normal HASMC express receptors (subtypes of P2Y) for ATP and UTP, which  stimulated the release of intracellular Ca2+. Brief exposure of normal HASMC with  UTP enhanced Ca2+ transients in response t</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx65n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc477</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dq17r"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis of graft copolymers based on poly([R]-3-hydroxybutyrate) for orthopaedic surgery purposes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nguyen, Sophie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Graft copolymers using biodegradable and biocompatible bacterial  poly([ R]-3-hydroxybutyrate) blocks were synthesized and tested as biomaterial  candidates for orthopaedic surgery applications. Low molecular weight poly([  R]-3-hydroxyalkanoates), namely poly([R]-3-hydroxybutyrate),  poly([R]-3-hydroxyvalerate), and their copolymers poly([  R]-3-hydroxybutyrate-co-[R]-3-hydroxyvalerate), were prepared by thermal degradation  in the melt at 190°C. The chemical composition of the oligomers was  well-defined, featuring the same repeat unit as their high molecular weight  analogues, a carboxylic acid end, and an alkenyl end mostly in the trans  configuration (crotonate-type). Increase in the reaction temperature, time, or  [R]-3-hydroxyvalerate content decreased the molecular weight of the products.  Methacrylic macromonomers of PHB were obtained by functionalization of the oligomers  at the carboxyl end, and copolymerized with methyl methacrylate. Two free radical  polymerization methods were employed: conventional free radical and a controlled  free radical polymerization, Atom Transfer Radical Polymerization. Kinetics of the  copolymerizations were studied, and the copolymerization behavior of the comonomers  was shown to change with the comonomer feed composition. This would have resulted in  variable graft copolymer microstructures. Graft copolymers produced by conventional  free radical copolymerization were incorporated in commercial acrylic (poly(methyl  methacrylate)-based) bone cement formulations. Cements with formulations containing  6.6-6.7, and 13.5 wt.-% of PMMA-graft-PHB were prepared. The morphology of the graft  copolymer particles was suggested to influence the processability of the modified  cement. The cements were found rather porous, with average porosities of 13.5 to  16.9%. Nevertheless compression strengths were quite similar to those found for the  reference material, pure Antibiotic SimplexRTM, and met the ASTM requirements on  acrylic b</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322d77v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dq17r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Polymer</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3x816n058"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of telomerase-specific catalytic functions by nucleic acid interactions and human telomerase reverse transcriptase N-terminal domains</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moriarty, Tara J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Telomerase is an unusual reverse transcriptase (RT) that  catalyzes the de novo addition of telomeric DNA repeats to telomeres. Telomerase  activity counteracts the progressive loss of telomeric DNA over successive rounds of  DNA replication, and is important for the immortality of most eukaryotic cells.  Telomerase is distinct from other RTs in that its catalytic subunit (TERT:  telomerase reverse transcriptase) stably associates with a telomerase RNA (TR)  component that contains a short template used to direct synthesis of telomeric  repeats. Telomerase also exhibits a unique, repeat addition form of processivity  that permits the addition of multiple telomeric repeats to a single substrate by  repetitive reverse transcription of the template. The TERT proteins consist of a  central region of RT-conserved motifs, which is flanked by extensive  telomerase-specific N- and C-terminal sequences. The N terminus constitutes nearly  half of the TERT protein, and is an excellent candidate site for telomerase-specific  catalytic functions. Using a mutagenic approach, we investigated the contributions  of human TERT N-terminal sequences to telomerase catalytic function and nucleic acid  interactions. We found that the hTERT N terminus contains two RNA interaction  domains, RID1 and RID2. RID1 was functionally and physically separable from the  remainder of hTERT, and may constitute an hTERT polymerase accessory domain. We  investigated the catalytic function of two RID1- and RID2-interacting regions in the  human TR, the pseudoknot/template domain and the P6.1 helix.  RID1-pseudoknot/template domain interactions were essential for repeat addition  processivity, and RID2-P6.1 interactions mediated telomerase assembly and were  required for basic polymerase function. Repeat addition processivity is thought to  be partly dependent on an anchor site(s) in TERT that stabilizes telomerase-DNA  interactions. We found that RID1 mutations also reduced the affinity of human  telo</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r843m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n058</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qj18h"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Discordant liver xenotransplantation in recipients with liver failure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tector, A. Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Liver xenotransplantation could eliminate the liver donor  shortage, but currently it is not possible because of a lack of understanding of  liver xenograft rejection. Hyperacute xenograft rejection is initiated by the  binding of preformed naturally occurring xenoreactive antibodies (XNA) to the  xenograft endothelium. The XNA bind to the xenograft endothelium, leading to  complement-mediated endothelial injury. Liver xenotransplantation will be initially offered to patients  with severe liver failure as a bridge to a human liver transplantation. The  hypothesis tested in this thesis is that hyperacute rejection of liver xenografts  placed into recipients with liver failure will be diminished because of the  complement deficiency that accompanies liver failure. The experiments described in  this thesis detail the development of an in vitro pig-to-human liver xenotransplant  model incubating cultured pig hepatic endothelial cells (PHEC) and human serum in  culture. We showed that either classical or alternative complement pathways could  initiate endothelial injury. Next we developed the dog-to-pig liver xenograft model  and characterized the lethal coagulopathy that results from hyperacute rejection.  The coagulopathy results from the lack of function of platelets as well as their  disappearance from the circulation. We then used the galactosamine induced liver  injury model in porcine recipients of canine liver xenografts to demonstrate that  hyperacute rejection in the setting of liver failure is diminished. We showed that;  tissue injury, coagulopathy and platelet defect, and endothelial injury were  diminished. Our experiments suggested that the cause of the decreased injury was the  lack of complement in the pigs with galactosamine induced liver injury since the XNA  levels were no different than in control animals. Our final experiments evaluated  serum from patients with liver failure and compared the injury caused by incubation  with PHEC. Serum from the liver failure patients had similar levels of XNA when  compared with normal subjects, but had less complement activity, and less C3 and C4.  Incubation of liver failure serum with PHEC caused much less injury and complement  activation than serum from control subjects. The results in this thesis suggest that  liver failure will have a significant impact on liver xenograft rejection, helping  to diminish hyperacut rejection. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La xénogreffe du foie pourrait éliminer la pénurie d'organes à
transplanter, mais actuellement ce n'est pas possible en raison d'un manque de
compréhension du rejet du xénogreffon du foie Le rejet suraigu du xenogreffon
est lancé en liant les anticorps xénoreactifs préformés (XNA) aux cellules
endothéliales du xénogreffon. Les liens du XNA aux cellules endothéliales du
xénogreffon mène aux dommages endothéliaux assistés par le complément.
Au début la xénogreffe du foie sera offert aux patients en insuffisance aiguë du
foie comme passerelle à une transplantation humaine du foie L'hypothèse
évaluée dans cette thèse est que le rejet suraigu des xénogreffons du foie chez
les patients en insuffisance aiguë sera diminué en raison de l'insuffisance de
complément qui accompagne la phase aiguë du foie. Les expériences décrites
dans cette thèse détaillent le développement d'un modèle de xénogreffe du foie
porc-à-humain in vitro incubant les cellules endothéliales hépatiques cultivées
de porc (PREe) et le sérum humain dans la culture. Nous avons prouvé que la
voie d'accès classique ou alternative de complément pourrait lancer des
dommages endothéliaux. Ensuite nous avons développé le modèle de
xénogreffon du foie de chien-à-porc et avons caractérisé la cascade des
réactions de coagulation mortel du rej et suraigu.
La coagulopathie résulte du manque de fonction des plaquettes aussi bien que
leur disparition de la circulation sanguine. Nous avons alors démontré par un modèle d'insuffisance du foie aiguë précipité par la galactosamine dans les
porcins avec xénogreffons de foie canins que le rejet suraigu est diminué.
Nous avons montré que le dommages des cellules endothéliales, de la
coagulopathie, des défauts de plaquettes et du tissue ont été diminués. Nos
expériences ont suggéré que la cause des dommages diminués ait été le manque
de complément chez les porcs avec l'insuffisance aiguë du foie induit par la
galactosamine puisque les niveaux de XNA n'étaient aucunement différent que
chez les animaux de contrôle. Nos expériences finales ont évalué le sérum des
patients en insuffisance aiguë et ont comparé les dommages provoqués par
incubation à PHEC. Le sérum des patients en insuffisance aiguë du foie a eu
des niveaux semblables de XNA en comparaison avec les sujets normaux, mais
a eu moins d'activité de complément, et moins de C3 et de C4. L'incubation du
sérum d'insuffisance aiguë du foie avec PHEC a causé beaucoup moins de
dommages et de complément que le sérum des sujets de contrôles. Les
résultats de cette thèse suggèrent que l'insuffisance du foie ait un impact
significatif sur le rejet suraigu du xénogreffon du foie, aidant à diminuer le rejet
surmgu. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Tchervenkov, Jean I.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x800.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qj18h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atd96k309f"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Predicting the emotional variables in a clinical population of discordant couples with a history of conjugal violence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blumstein-Bond, Sharon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to examine the relationships among  several demographic and emotional/relational variables, and physical abuse  victimization in conjugal relations. Participants were eighty-two individuals,  involving 41 heterosexual couples in permanent relationships, who were being seen in  marital therapy for discordant relationships. This was a cross-sectional sample,  with participants selected from four community-based couple and family therapy  treatment facilities. Couple participants completed a questionnaire package which  measured their standing on a number of socio-demographic (age, income, duration of  marriage, employment, education), emotional/relationship (attachment,  differentiation, self esteem, marital satisfaction, global distress, problem solving  communication), and violence (aggression, physical and non-physical abuse)  variables. The emotional variables selected for this study drew on principles from  both attachment and Bowen family systems theory. The design of this study  differentiated victims of physical violence from non-victims of violence and  included multiple measures of abuse. The findings revealed significant gender correlations in terms  of level of aggression in relationships. For females, level of global distress and  problem solving communication were positively associated with higher levels of  marital aggression. An association between poor differentiation and marital  aggression was identified for females, while self esteem only approached  significance. For males, a significant correlation was identified between level of  aggression and the dismissing attachment style. For males the anxious attachment  style was negatively correlated with being a victim of physical violence, with  self-differentiation and with having a dismissive attachment style. The central findings were identified through the use of logistic  regression analysis. Attachment style was found to be the more powerful predictor  for both females and males in predicting victimization of physical violence.  Separate gender analysis revealed evidence that women's anxious attachment style is  a significant predictor of physical violence victimization. For males, the  dismissing style was less powerful a predictor of male victimization, however the  combined female-anxious, male-dismissing attachment combination was found to be  highly predictive of relationship violence. Logistic regression has provided  evidence for the combination of female-anxious and male-dismissing attachment  pattern with poor problem solving and communication skill, within the context of a  longer relationship, as significant predictors of relationship violence for the  whole sample. These three variables, anxious-dismissing attachment style, poor  problem solving communication and longer duration of marriage taken together have  provided a predictor model or couple profile for conjugal violence in a sample of  discordant couples. Results of the final couple analysis have contributed to an  emerging hypothesis, with the identification of a particular "toxic"  gender defined couple attachment pattern, that can predispose a couple for  relationship violence. Results have identified that anxious females coupled with  dismissing males significantly increased the odds of relationship violence. Research  findings were discussed in terms of clinical applications and implications for  theory and future research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Trute, Barry</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj48g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k309f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Marital violence -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attachment behavior</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57nr48r"><ual:graduationDate>2004</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>3, 5-Dihydroxybenzyl alcohol based dendrimers and hyperbranched polymers : synthesis, characterization and applications in catalysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bourrier, Olivier E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new divergent methodology to prepare a variety of dendritic  polymers containing dimethylsilyl-linked-3,5-dihydroxybenzyl alcohol units in the  backbone is reported. This simple and versatile synthetic route is based on the  acid-base hydrolytic chemistry of 3,5-dihydroxybenzyl alcohol (DHBA) and  dimethyldiaminosilane Me2Si(NMe2)2. Controlled sequential addition of reactants was  used to prepare dendrimer generations 1--5. The dendritic growth was found to be  dictated by a preferential attack of the benzylic hydroxyl group of DHBA on the  aminosilane, as no traces of residual benzylic OH groups were observed using 1H NMR  spectroscopy. By a continuation of this divergent route, these dendrimers were  functionalized with a variety of terminal units, including trimethylsilyl,  n-octanoate, organic dye disperse red 1, and hydroxypropyldiphenylphosphine.  Uncontrolled reaction protocols using the same reacting partners were also  investigated to prepare the corresponding hyperbranched polymers. Resulting  macromolecules showed structural fragments ranging from that of dendrimer generation  1 to that of dendrimer generation 2 in their MALDI-TOF mass spectra. Addition of  more reactants did not seem to increase the size of these hyperbranched  polymers. Determination of some of the structure-property relationships in  these dendrimers was carried out to obtain a better understanding of their potential  applications. Hydrolytic stability of the dendrimers was examined using dendrimer  generations 1--3 solvated in wet DMSO. Their resistance towards hydrolysis was found  to increase with an increase in generation number. Intrinsic viscosities were  determined for dendrimer generations 1--5. A non-linear relationship was found  between the generation number and the intrinsic viscosity, as it reached a maximum  for dendrimer generation 4, followed by a decrease. 3,5-dihydroxybenzyl alcohol  based dendrimers were found to self-assemble via hydrogen bonding between terminally  situated hydroxyl groups. This phenomenon was found to be dependent on their  concentration in solution, and a critical aggregation concentration was determined  at 3.7 mg mL-1 for dendrimer generations 1--3. Higher generation dendrimers showed  aggregate formation at low concentrations as the number of peripheral OH groups was  significantly increased. By functionalizing dendrimers and hyperbranched polymers with  hydroxypropyldiphenylphosphine ligands, followed by coordination with [Rh(COD)Cl],  we were able to synthesize metallodendrimers and organometallic hyperbranched  polymers, in which active organometallic fragments are present at the periphery.  Their catalytic activity was assessed in hydrogenation of 1-decene. Conversion rates  of decene into decane for metallodendrimers were found to be dependent on the time  of reaction and the generation number. Maximum conversion rates were found after 5 h  reaction time in each case.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kakkar, Ashok K.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m4616.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr48r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>