<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zr677"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The political and social satire of Thomas Love Peacock</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lumsden, Jean Alice Gould</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Thomas Love Peacock was born at Weymouth in October, 1785. His father was Samuel Peacock, a glass-merchant, carrying on his trade in St. Paul’s Churchyard. Nothing of any interest seems to be known of his family or himself. That he was in business in 1768 is certain, for many years later his son, Thomas, wrote the rough copy of a farce, The Three Doctors, on the blank pages of an old account book, whose cover was marked with the words “Day Book: 1768: Saml. Peacock”. One of these pages indicates that Peacock, the author, was one day suffering from an attack of indolence or distraction, or that he had momentarily lost the urge to write. It is covered with scrawls of all sorts, capital letters, curves and other marks which make little or no sense. In the corner of the left margin, however, there is inscribed: “T. L. Peacock - 1811 - 1768 = 45” This not only furnishes evidence that The Three Doctors was written in 1811, but also contains what is probably the second best autograph to be found in the manuscripts. One may presume that Samuel Peacock was still in business in 1785, for at the end of that year his son was baptised in London. About three years later the father died. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mason, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77st167.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zr677</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>PEACOCK, THOMAS LOVE, 1785-1866</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rs023"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the processing of wheat germ</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lusena, Charles Victor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the most important post-war aims is a more adequate diet for all people. To achieve this, the production of each dietary essential will need to be carefully considered and the production of some commodities may have to be greatly increased if more people are to be adequately fed from approximately the same acreage. This investigation has sought to make cereal germs more acceptable as a human food and thereby to make available a rich source of the B-vitamins and a large amount of highest quality protein in addition to fat and vitamin E. The cereal germs have an additional significance in economy of production since they are plant products which do not need to be transformed by animals to give these important dietary essentials. The germs of wheat and corn are the most important from the standpoint of quantity available. Both are by-products of the milling industry and are used as animal feed, generally as components of the bran and in limited amounts as a source of oil. This investigation was confined to studies on wheat germ. The annual production of wheat germ, as such, in the States is estimated to be 30 to 50 million pounds. However, the present milling yield of about 0.5% indicates a potential production of about 150 million pounds of germ (35). The wheat kernel is reported (2) to contain 2.2 - 3.0% of germ and therefore it is possible that, in the future, the milling yield and hence the potential production of wheat germ may be greatly increased. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McFarlane, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn016.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rs023</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn02g"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the chemical determination of plant lignin</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacDougall, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The problem has its origin in the empirical nature of existing methods for the chemical determination of plant lignin. It is generally recognized that the apparent lignin content of plant tissues depends largely on the pretreatments employed, and on the method and conditions of final isolation of the lignin. By using various pretreatments and carefully regulating the conditions of the final determination of lignin, methods have been developed which give reproducible results on any given tissue. However, the apparent lignin content of any particular tissue may vary greatly, depending on the method used for its determination. Consequently, an investigation of more efficient methods for the removal of materials which interfere in the final isolation of lignin was indicated. In this connection, special attention has been paid to obtaining a lignin relatively free from nitrogen, and also, to the prevention of changes in the lignin itself during its isolation. The most commonly used criteria of plant lignin purity have been its nitrogen and methoxyl contents. As an additional criterion of the purity of isolated lignin ultraviolet absorption spectra of lignin solutions have been studied. With the same end in view, high pressure hydrogenation studies have been carried out on pre-extracted materials. These latter studies also throw some light on the chemical composition of lignin from succulent plant tissue as compared with that from mature wood.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xp87q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn02g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Lignin</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn301457h"><ual:graduationDate>1946</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Survey of electromagnetic theories</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mamelak, Joseph S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Electromagnetic Theory of Clerk Maxwell will forever remain outstanding work in theoretical physics. The fundamental equations of this theory are the laws governing electric and magnetic fields perfected and generalized by the concept of displacement current. Singular and unimportant as it may seem at first, it makes a most important advance in our understanding of the universe. The Maxwellian Theory which proves that the velocity of light is the same as that of the ratio of the electric and electrostatic units and the identity of the velocity of light and electricity leads us to the conclusion that light is no more than an electric disturbance. [...] The simple work of Melloni who was first to establish, in spite of his own will, the identity of light and heat waves is now at once generalized to include the whole of the electromagnetic spectrum, which includes all vibrations commencing with the long electric waves and ending in the extremely short cosmic rays. The theory thus marks the final and irrevocable step in severance of physical light waves from physiological perception; a concept which not even the great German poet and philosopher Goethe was willing to admit or able to perceive. The simple concept of the existence of a displacement current made possible the emancipation of the physical notion of light from physiological perception - the human eye. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gillson, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g099t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301457h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acv43p141t"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agronomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relation of pH to base saturation in some Quebec soils</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Menzies, Robert George</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Much of the soil of that part of Eastern Canada lying east of a line between Quebec City and Lake Champlain is acid in reaction and may be improved in productive capacity by an intelligent liming practice. A considerable part of this area has recently been surveyed and the limits of the various soil types indicated (3,16,20). The broader outlines of a liming programme now may be laid down with some degree of precision. It is the object of this investigation to make a preliminary test of the variability of; (a) Virgin soils of six of the major series represented in South-eastern Quebec; (b) Cultivated soils of the Greensboro series which occupies a larger area than any of the other soils under study. It was thought possible that the six soils chosen might be found sufficiently similar to permit making a uniform liming recommendation based on field and laboratory determinations of pH and base saturation. This possibility has been tested by determination and study of pH, base saturation, and lime requirement values. At the same time the nature of the exchange complex in these soils, particularly with reference to the relative contributions of the organic and inorganic colloidal fractions to the total exchange capacity, has been studied. Since cultural practices may modify considerably the liming requirements, the effects of past practices also were studied In the case of the most widely distributed of these soils, the Greensboro loam. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DeLong, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236545k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p141t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gw88n"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of absorbents in refining linseed oil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morrison, Earl Stanley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Wartime shipping restrictions have resulted, during the past two years, in a scarcity of the edible oils ordinarily used in this country. The possibility of utilizing linseed oil for edible purposes is now under investigation. Linseed oil has an objectionable odor and color. The ordinary refining procedures which are applicable to edible oils do not improve the color and odor to any extent. Edible oils must also have a low free fatty acid content and good stability during storage. Deodorization removes the odor completely from raw linseed oil. However, on heating the refined and deodorized oil, off odors develop which are referred to as “reverted odors”. Attention was directed in this laboratory to the refining of linseed oil to produce the desired qualities of an edible oil. A study was also made of the “reverted odor” and stability of linseed oil insofar as they were affected by refining with adsorbents.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McFarlane, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dj76q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw88n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r423d"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Horticulture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nutrient levels as affecting stringiness in celery</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>O’Reilly, H. J. (Henry James), 1916-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Findings are presented indicating the effects of nutrient solutions containing combinations of nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium at different levels, on the tissues causing stringiness in celery petioles. These tissues are the collenchyma strands and the vascular bundles. High applications of nitrogen stimulated succulent growth and hence retarded maturity and development of stringiness in the collenchyma, and to a lesser extent in the vascular bundles. Phosphorus had no direct effect on stringiness. Potassium had a marked effect in increasing stringiness when applied in large amounts. The cell walls of the collenchyma strands became thicker as maturity progressed. This thickening of the cell walls of collenchyma tissue resulted in their increased stringiness. The size of the collenchyma strands was no indication of amount of string present but maturity was an indication since stringiness increased with age. Cell size in the larger collenchyma strands was usually greater than in smaller collenchyma strands.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murray, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j417r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r423d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Horticulture-Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95053642"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of some market diseases of tomatoes with special reference to anthrachose (colletotrichum phomoides (sacc.) chester)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pelletier, Real L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Anthracnose of tomatoes is a fungus disease that manifests itself on ripe fruits. A survey of fruit diseases on the Montreal market showed it to be one of the most important of the tomato diseases. Since it is essentially a rot of ripe fruits, the principal losses occur in the retail stores. Losses caused by anthracnose have also been sustained, however, by field growers picking ripe tomatoes for the local market and for canning (McNew,1943a), A survey of the literature showed that, even though the disease was recorded as early as 1881, comparatively little was known about the life history of the causal organism, the factors affecting the development of the disease, or the control measures that might be employed. This investigation was therefore undertaken in an attempt to gain some information on these points.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Coulson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq690.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95053642</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698b856"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Flotation of chromite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Salman, Mehmet Talat</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Flotation process is undoubtedly the most important development in the recovery of metals from ores that has taken place during the present century. No other method of ore treatment has ever effected such great changes in metallurgical practice in so short a time. The industrial importance can be emphasized best by considering the non-ferrous metal mining industry. At the period under question practically every mining district has witnessed almost complete exhaustion of high grade oxidized ores near the surface and often of the high grade sulphides in the so-called zones of secondary enrichment, leaving only the low grade primary sulphides usually more or less complex in the lower levels. Hence the companies were thus confronted with increased mining costs, lower grade ores and high treatment charges. In many cases it became economically impossible to mine and ship the sulphides at all. The only alternative was to introduce some method of mechanical concentration. Eventually these methods all lead to flotation practice. To-day concentration of sulphide ores of copper, sulphide-lead-sinc ores, copper-zinc, copper-lead, copper-nickel ores, precious and rare metals is successfully accomplished in many plants. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>O'Shaughnessy, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js01m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b856</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mining Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278x51p"><ual:graduationDate>1944</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on tuber rot of potatoes due to phytophthora infestans (mont.) de by.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Simard, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Late blight rot due to the fungus Phythopthora infestans is one of the most destructive diseases of potatoes. Losses occur in the field and in storage. An important feature of the disease is that it is frequently followed by secondary decay organisms which rot the tubers much more rapidly than does P. infestans. Tuber infections arise in several ways. It is a well established fact that spores produced on blighted vines fall to the ground through which they are washed to the surface of the young growing tubers where they germinate and initiate tuber infections. According to Link and Ramsey, 1932, the fungus may gain entrance into the stem end of a tuber by growing along the stolon of a diseased plant but this method of infection seems to occur only rarely. According to Link and Ramsey, 1932, Crosier and Reddick, 1935, and Barrus et al, 1940, the fungus may grow and fruit in and on heavy wet soils during wet seasons and thus spread underground from tuber to tuber. Tubers are almost certain to become infected during harvesting operations if they are dug while the fungus is fruiting on the vines or if the tubers are covered in the field by blighted tops. Rotted tubers in storage are usually due to infections which took place before or during harvesting but if moist air and temperatures above 41°F prevail in the storage room, the fungus may grow out of infected tubers and produce spores which may spread to nearly sound tubers. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Coulson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445ch481.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278x51p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zk85d"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sexual reproduction of Trillium : T. erectum L., T. grandiflorum (Michx) Salisb</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blain, Auray</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since Atkinson (1699), who was the first cytologist to investigate the andromeiosis of Trillium, the species of this Asiatico-American genus have been largely used by cytogeneticists. The large dimensions of their chromosomes (“average 30 microns in length by three microns in width in somatic divisions” Warmke, 1941, 1937) and their low number (the basic haploid number is 5) were good features for the study of mitosis and meiosis mechanisms and chromosomes structure. Due to technical facilities, the root tip cells and androsporogenetic tissue were the basic material mainly employed; the gynohaplogenesis and the embryology were almost neglected though it was tacitly assumed that meiosis was identical in both andro- and gynosporogenesis. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Huskins, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv74p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk85d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Trillium erectum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trillium grandiflorum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plants -- Reproduction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60d074r"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Variations in the composition of forage plants : with special reference to phosphorus and calcium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brogden, Clarence LeRoy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Soil surveys are revealing the location and extent of phosphorus deficient soils in Eastern Canada, and recommendations for fertilizer practice are being made. The primary objective of fertilization is to improve crop yield. It is, however, desirable to have information on the composition of unfertilized crops from such areas, and also on the extent and duration of the effect of fertilization on crop composition. The principal objective of the present investigation has been to study the behaviour of forage crops under such conditions. Studies of this nature usually have been confined to the determination of the total amounts of calcium and phosphorus in the crops. Since it is possible, however, that the form in which phosphorus is present in the plant may have some effect on its utilization by the animal, the distribution of the total phosphorus among various classes of compounds of this element known to occur in plants has been investigated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DeLong, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s15z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d074r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Forage plants</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62fc45s"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The expression and interaction of hereditary factors affecting hair growth in mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fraser, Frank Clarke</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Until about 1925, geneticists were mainly concerned with the demonstration, confirmation, modification and extension of Mendel’s laws, and with their bearing on the problem of evolution. The genes were thought of as discrete units, and interest was focussed mainly on their identification and localization on the chromosomes, and the way in which they were combined, segregated and transmitted through the germ cells. More recently the attention of geneticists has turned more and more from what Goldschmidt (1938) terms the ‘static’ towards the ‘dynamic’ aspects of genetic research; namely, the causal relationships existing between the genotype and the phenotype. It is realized that, in most cases at least, the primary action of the gene is connected with its phenotypic effect by a long series of developmental reactions, and that each series affects and is affected by many similar series stemming from other genes, so that the pattern of development is determined by an intricately branched and interlacing network of gene-initiated reaction chains. Two fundamental questions must be answered: (1) what is the nature of the gene, and (2) what is its mode of action? [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steinberg, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f442n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc45s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mice</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heredity</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqv33s0692"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the mechanism of renal failure associated with the release of haemoglobin or related pigments in the blood plasma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gold, M.M.A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The renal lesion which is seen in certain fatal transfusion reactions, the crush syndrome, blackwater fever, haemolytic sulphonamide reactions, eclampsia, and severe burns, has been found to be of a characteristic type, invariably showing degenerative changes in tubular epithelium along with the presence of pigment casts low in the nephron. These casts were, undoubtedly, derived from the haemoglobin or allied pigments circulating in the blood plasma in all these disorders. For this reason many investigators have sought a common mechanism for the renal failure accompanying this morbid picture; some holding tubular blockage by pigment casts to be the underlying factor; some claiming that the pigments injure tubular epithelium, the casts being merely a sequel; some prefering the concept of a new or newly released substance which causes tubular degeneration, and others stating that the tubules are damaged by anaemia, low blood pressure, or peripheral circulatory collapse.  A group of other workers feel that the renal failure seen in these illnesses is not related to the anatomical alterations but is a physiological uraemia. Thus, all the work resolves itself into three main theories, one of which blames the kidney failure on tubular blockage, another laying stress on tubular degeneration, discrediting the blockage theory altogether, and the third saying that neither of these holds true. The present experimental investigation is the first work in which an attempt is made to evaluate the relative importance of tubular injury and tubular blockage by pigments, being also the first in which a method is devised to readily reproduce the characteristic lesion. [...]</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb66p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s0692</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924f83b"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Physiological studies on the nature of toxemia of pregnancy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gold, Simon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>“Toxemia of pregnancy” defines a syndrome or disease occurring during pregnancy. It includes preeclamsia and eclampsia, and may affect seriously the lives of the mother or foetus during pregnancy. This disease may exert a serious late effect on the renal and cardiovascular systems of the mother. Toxemia of pregnancy is characterized by rapid and excessive gain in weight, usually associated with oedema, elevation of arterial pressure, albuminuria, and symptoms referable to the central nervous system. Various renal, gastrointestinal and visual symptoms may also appear. These changes develop in various combinations during the last trimester of pregnancy, and rapidly disappear after delivery. Preeclampsia and eclampsia are identical, with the exception that convulsions or coma occur in the latter. In some instances the coma and convulsions appear after delivery. Whether the toxemia is manifested by preeclampsia or eclampsia, the difference is one of degree, and eclampsia is reserved for those cases in which convulsions or coma occur. With the appearance of severe toxamia, the immediate prognosis of mother and foetus becomes serious, and in the ultimate prognosis of the mother there is the possibility that persistent hypertension might supervene after delivery. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoff, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945v122.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f83b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Toxemia of pregnancy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gp170"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relation between the odontoblast development in the guinea pig tooth and the intake of vitamin C.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hughes, Muriel I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A total of 308 guinea pigs were used in a series of four experiments designed to determine some of the factors, other than vitamin C, which might affect the odontoblast cell method of assaying vitamin C. Neither the previous diet of the mothers, and young up to weaning time, nor the method of penning during the test, made any difference on the development of the odontoblast cell. The minimum length of feeding period, using this method, was found to be 5 weeks. Chemical, growth and odontoblast methods of assay were compared on an unknown solution, concentrated orange juice, and dehydrated cabbage. In contrast to the erratic results obtained on the growth method, the response of the odontoblast cells to increasing doses of vitamin C was very much less variable. For natural foods, these tests indicated a significant difference between chemical and biological assays.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crampton, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1619392.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp170</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257j03j"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La vie de l’époque dans les lettres de Mme. de Sévigné</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Meyer, Paul Hugo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Il s’agit dans cette thèse de reconstruire, non pas la vie de la société de la deuxième moitié du dix-septième siècle, mais le tableau que Mme. de Sévigné, la plus célèbre épistolière de l’époque, et ses correspondants et amis, nous en présentent. C’est pourquoi je ne me suis pas occupé du grand nombre d’ouvrages savants qui ont été écrits sur cette époque que dans le cas où cela a servi à éclaircir quelque endroit un peu obscur dans les Lettres. La seule source proprement dite de cette thèse est d’une part ce qui jaillit de la plume de Mme. de Sévigné, et d’autre part les lettres écrites de son vivant et peu après sa mort par ses parents et ses amis, et qui se trouvent dans l’édition des Grands Ecrivains de la France, publiée par P. Mesnard, d’après l’édition antérieure de Monmerqué, en 1862, et dans les deux tomes publiés par Charles Câpmas en 1876. A celui qui veut extraire la peinture d’une société d’un recueil de lettres, il se présente immédiatement une difficulté grave, car ce n’est qu’incidemment qu’une telle esquisse peut se dégager. Ce ne sont pas les gens qui écrivent des lettres, mais ceux qui composent leurs mémoires, qui ont l’intention de nous présenter une vue de l’ensemble d’une époque. Mais c’est justement pour cette raison que les auteurs de mémoires ont un parti pris et souvent ils se soucient plutôt de se justifier que d’être tout à fait sincères. Par contre, celui qui écrit une lettre à un ami, bien qu’il ne puisse pas se libérer de ses préjugés, tache de lui rendre compte des faits. Sous ce rapport Mme. de Sévigné est extrêmement scrupuleuse; elle écrit à sa fille: «Je ne sais nulle nouvelle aujourd’hui; je hais tant de dire des faussetés, que j’aime mieux ne vous rien dire. Ce que je vous mande est toujours vrai, et vient de bon lieu.» Une autre fois, elle nomme comme ses sources pour les novelles de la cour les grandes officiers de la couronne, le Premier Ecuyer Henri de Beringhen, le Grand maitre de l'Artillerie le duc du Lude, et le prince de Mersillac, Permier Maitre de la Garderobe. Elle se pique de donner une gazette reguliere a sa fille, une gazette beaucoup plus digne de foi que la gazette officiele parce que, ne s'adressant qu'a des amis intimes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Darbelnet, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt53v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257j03j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>FRANCE -- SOCIAL HISTORY AND LIFE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEVIGNÉ, MARIE (BORN RABUTIN-CHANTAL), MARQUISE DE, 1626-96</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apz50h037c"><ual:graduationDate>1946</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Quebec provincial election of 1944 : an analysis of the role of the election in the democratic process</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Quinn, Herbert F., 1910-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The basic purpose in undertaking the present thesis was to determine to what extent the election as an essential element of the democratic process performs the function which democratic theory assigns to it. In order to test the validity of this theory the election campaign in the Montreal Area in the Quebec Provincial Election of 1944 has been used as a case study. The thesis is divided into three parts. The first part briefly outlines the theory of Representative Democracy. The second part deals with the background of the election, that is the effect of the war on Quebec politics, and the nature of the parties which were to contest the election. I have felt it necessary to go into some detail in discussing the political events leading up to the election, as otherwise it would be impossible for the reader to fully understand the nature of the issues which were to play a part in that election. The third and main part deals with the actual election campaign. The method followed has been to first of all present an analysis of the results of the balloting in the Montreal Area, and then proceed to study the type of appeal each party made to the electorate in an endeavour to ascertain the reasons for the success or failure which met that party’s efforts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Keirstead, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c3762.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h037c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Elections -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Québec (Province) -- Politics and government -- 1936-1960</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tz30n"><ual:graduationDate>1946</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of liver function tests on rabbits</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robertson, Florence E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The term “liver function test” was originated in the days when investigators envisioned discovering a single procedure which would measure accurately the status of all the functions of the liver. Over a period of about fifty years many tests have been developed, some on a sound physiological basis, others quite empirically; few have proved to be of value. Within the last few years research in this field has followed a different trend. There has been an increasing interest in investigation into the physiological principles underlying these tests, with the result that great improvements have been made in some of the procedures, and there has been a sharper delineation of the normal ranges of many tests. Nevertheless, today the view is widely accepted that no single test is adequate to measure all hepatic functions, and the repeated performance of different tests is now advocated in the estimation of hepatic function (1). In recent years there has also been a renewed and widespread interest in the study of liver damage in animals. Investigators have employed various criteria in estimating the condition of the liver: many have made post mortem histological examinations or liver lipid determinations; biopsies have occasionally been used; liver function tests have been performed infrequently, and have been confined almost entirely to the dog. [...] The present investigation is essentially a study of liver function tests on small animals. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc93v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz30n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jp883"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The gold deposits of Fifteen mile stream, Nova Scotia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cameron, Harcourt Leslie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Fifteen Mile Stream gold district, Nova Scotia, is situated on a composite anticlinal dome. The folded rocks are the Goldenville formation of quartzites with interbedded slates, believed to be Pre-Cambrian in age. Interbedded quartz veins of saddle vein type occur in slates, along slate-quartzite contacts and rarely in the quartzites. Sections of these veins contain sufficient gold to constitute ore bodies. The dome has been truncated by erosion. The district has been sheared regionally and shows a well defined fracture pattern consisting of two sets of main shears with their accompanying fractures. The local fold structure did not control the direction of shearing. Both sets of shears acted as channels for quartz-forming solutions later than the interbedded quartz veins. Bodies of commercial ore were formed along the lines of intersection of such channel fractures with interbedded quartz veins, or favourable slate belts. Ore also occurs in the shears at changes of strike and dip. Two good examples of the intersection type are given and a third inferred on the basis of the intersection theory. Similar bodies have been mined elsewhere in Nova Scotia. The small size of the local anticlinal structure makes Fifteen Mile Stream an ideal place to study the effect of shear zones on opposite sides of an anticlinal structure. The conclusions reached on the basis of this study, may prove very important in developing other districts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67317185.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jp883</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gold ores -- Nova Scotia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322h78r"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The fate of intravenously injected colloids</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carlton, Lucille</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study was undertaken to correlate the water-retaining properties of the “plasma substitutes” with the concentrations attained in the blood stream, storage in tissue, and any pathological changes brought about by their presence or excretion. A review of the literature on the use of foreign colloids as plasma substitutes is presented. Experimental work on gum acacia, polyvinyl alcohol, starch, dextrin, isinglass and dextran is given. Gum acacia was found to be stored, mainly in the liver, and to cause marked blood changes. Polyvinyl alcohol produces similar changes but is not stored. Starch and dextrin are very rapidly hydrolyzed in the blood stream and exert little water retaining effect. Isinglass was found to be the most suitable since, though it remained in the blood stream a shorter time than gum acacia, it did not produce pathological changes in the blood or tissues, and was excreted 100% without kidney damage. Dextran remained in the blood stream for many hours but produced no hemodilution whatsoever.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b9189.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322h78r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569745g"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of pulsating air on the rate of drying of porous material</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chadillon, François J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the most convenient methods for improving the rate of drying of certain materials is the use of pulsating air, which causes a breathing action in the cavities of the material where Lewis‘s law for the rate of vaporization in still air can be assumed to hold. A very misleading interpretation of the principle can often come about by confusing the word “pore” in the literature on pulsating air, with its true definition as a micro-dimensional void in the material to be dried. In this investigation, an attempt has been made to clear up this confusion by making experimental measurements on the rate of drying of kaolin, felt and cellulose sponge under the action of pulsating air. An introductory outline of the mechanism of drying is mentioned and an hypothesis correlating the beneficial effects of pulsating air in drying and the porous structure of the material to be dried is suggested. Numerical data are presented which show that the rate of vaporization with the use of pulsating air is in agreement with Lewis’s basic law and the suggested hypothesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Phillips, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm35d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569745g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv9356099"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of storage on the Vitamin A content of mixed rations as determined by the rate of growth of rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chalmers, A. Edith</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper is a report on the stability of vitamin A in feeding fish oil, and the antioxidant effect of wheat germ oil when added to mixed diets before storage. The increase in weight of rats is used as the criterion for vitamin A intake. There was evidence for deterioration in the nutritive value of feeds stored for sixty days. This could not be related to a loss in vitamin A potency and wheat germ oil was not effective in preventing it.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crampton, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x240k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9356099</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Feed additives</dc:subject><dc:subject>Feeds -- Research</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vitamin A</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b919k"><ual:graduationDate>1945</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The chemical determination of free, combined and total choline in biological materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chapman, Douglas Gordon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the discovery and isolation of choline by Strecker in 1849, many workers have devoted much time to the study of this important compound. The importance of choline as a portion of the lecithin molecule, has been known for some time, but it was not until after the discovery of insulin that choline came to be recognized as an essential constituent of the diet. While discussing the physiological aspects of choline, McHenry (31) states that it may function in at least three ways: “to stimulate the formation of phospholipids, to make possible the production of acetylcholine and to supply labile methyl groups”. In addition to the development of fatty livers, various other results of a deficiency of choline have been reported. Rats not receiving sufficient choline lose hair and have red swollen paws. A choline deficiency in young male rats was found to result in the formation of hemorrhagic kidneys and renal lesions. Choline also appears to be essential for normal lactation in the rat. In poultry, the role that choline plays in perosis has been widely studied. A choline deficiency may result in an inadequate formation of acetylcholine at the nerve endings and hence interfere with the transmittance of nerve impulses. The nutritional value of choline in the diet would indicate that a rapid, chemical method for its determination is of the utmost importance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McFarlane, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v160p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b919k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pt776"><ual:graduationDate>1946</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the conversion of PHX to AcAn</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcus, Rudolph Arthur</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the recent conflict, cyclotrimethylene triamine, more familiarly known as RDX, was recognized by both the Allies and the enemy as the most powerful explosive available in large quantities. The production of RDX stemmed from two main processes, (a) the Woolich Reaction (1), and (b) the Bachmann or Combination Method (2). The former essentially consisted in reaction between hexamine and fuming nitric acid, while in the latter hexamine is acted upon by nitric acid, ammonium nitrate and acetic anhydride in the presence of acetic acid. Although recent research on the explosive has been concerned mainly with problems of production, a new field in organic chemistry was simultaneously developed, that of the polymethylene nitramines. The mass of data thus accumulated emphasized the frequency of the reaction involving rupture of a methylene carbon-nitrogen bond by “acetyl nitrate”, the acetate grouping attaching itself to the carbon and the nitro group to the nitrogen atom. Indeed the mechanisms (3, 4) proposed for the formation of RDX and related compounds generally included this as an essential step. Acetyl nitrate was suggested as the active agent, purely for convenience, but without experimental basis. [...] These considerations made it of interest to attempt a detailed study of the reaction leading to the rupture of the methylene carbon-nitrogen bond. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b654s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt776</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>