<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn99k"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Proper orthogonal decomposition (POD): application to finite element analysis of electromagnetic diffusion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Adnan, Farasatul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Proper Orthogonal Decomposition (POD) is a technique which has been used successfully to reduce the computation time in various fields of engineering. Here POD is applied to electromagnetic field computations, specifically to the simulation of electromagnetic diffusion by the time-domain finite element method. The standard method requires a large matrix equation to be solved at every time step. POD is applied to greatly reduce the size of the matrices. Both 1-D and 2-D test cases are considered. Applying POD reduces the matrix dimension for a 2-D problem from 2,535 to just 5, with negligible loss of accuracy. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La Décomposition Orthogonale Nécessaire (POD) est une technique qui a été utilisée avec succès pour réduire le temps de compte dans les champs différents d'ingénierie. Ici la POD est appliqué les comptes électromagnétiques de terrain, spécialement à la simulation de la diffusion électromagnétique par le domaine de temps la méthode d'élément finie. La norme la méthode exige à une grande équation matricielle d'être résolue au pas de chaque fois. La POD est appliquée beaucoup réduire la grandeur du matrices. De 1ème que 2ème cas tant d'essai sont considérés. L'application de la POD réduit la dimension matricielle pour un 2ème problème de 2,535 à juste 5, avec la perte négligeable d'exactitude.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jonathan P. Webb</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s8982.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn99k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>