<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aht24wn89r"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The noise of singing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ram, Abraham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>He awoke in the fuzzy half-dark of his room to muffled little noises. From the kitchen only a passage width away came the clink and the scraping of a pot in the sink, the discreet slushing rise in pitch of the tap water filling the pot, the tempered shuffle and heel click on the linoleum of his mother’s moving about. Up already, he thought. He listened hard for a moment. Her voice, still as young and fresh as a spring, gurgled in an endless flow of Yiddish past his closed door and into his room, punctuated every now and then by an indignant "Ah!" She was talking to herself. He couldn't hear what she was saying, but there was something wrong. He could tell.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Files, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b4656.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wn89r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn440"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of epicardectomy and cardiac neurectomy on the ventricular fibrillation threshold</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ragheb, Samir</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The importance of removing the epicardium for myocardial revascularization was recognized by Beck in 1935. Beek and Tichy (1935) recommended removal of the epicardium irrespective of the graft or material used, be it talc powder, pericardium, pericardial fat, mediastinal tissue, pleura, etc. Beck believed that the epicardium was a barrier to the development of extra-coronary vessels. Further, he stated that a pressure differential was necessary to promote anastomoses between the cardiac and extra-cardiac vascular beds.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Vineberg, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172171v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn440</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azk51vm519"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The church in the novels of George Eliot</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Raff, Anton. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Victorian England George Eliot “must needs occupy a central place. Probably no English writer of the time, and certainly no novelist, more fully epitomizes the century.” Many, including William Hale White and Lord Acton, have considered her the greatest Victorian. G. M. Young makes the reason for such tributes clear. George Eliot was, he says, “a light to thousands who had learnt from her that, in the darkness deepening over all ancient faiths, the star of duty shone clearer than ever. Grave and wise men thought that George Eliot had, single-handed, by her ethical teaching, saved us from the moral catastrophe which might have been expected to follow upon the waning of religious conviction. They were not altogether wrong. George Eliot did give body, and expression… to her time. In doing so she shaped a generation.”</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lucas, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sx42x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm519</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az603r211h"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of electrical stimulation on the ACh-like activity of the cat’s superior cervical ganglion and the isolated frog’s heart</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Proulx, Lucille. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Usually, attempts to demonstrate the physiological function of a substance are made after this substance has been shown to be present in the animal body or tissue. In the case of acetylcholine (ACh), the sequence of events was quite different, for, it will be seen that the physiological role of ACh had been suggested long before its discovery in animal tissue. It is generally believed that two different physiological events occur innerve activity: a) conduction, i.e. propagation of the nerve impulse in the nerve fibers and, b) transmission, a biochemical process that occurs at nerve endings or synapses. The fundamental findings on which these concepts were based can be traced as far back as 1843.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hosein, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515r840.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r211h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246w49j"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Short-term memory in focal cerebral damage</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prisko, Lilli-Heddi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In recent years increasing interest has been aroused in short-term memory processes and their anatomical substrate. There have been numerous reports, some based mainly on clinical observations and others on experimental findings, but these are not all in agreement, and analysis of the results obtained by different investigators is rendered particularly difficult by the lack of uniformity of methods and by the lack of comparable studies in man and experimental animal. In man. bilateral medial temporal-lobe lesions appear to cause a grave, persistent, and generalized defect of recent memory (Scoville and Milner, 1957; Penfield and Milner, 1958; Milner, 1959; Milner, 1962b) but attempts to produce an analogous deficit in the monkey by similarly placed lesions have been largely unsuccessful (Orbach, Milner, and Rasmussen 1960), although loss of recent memory in both auditory and visual modalities has been reported after bilateral medial temporal-lobe removal in one study (Stepien, Cordeau, and Rasmussen, 1960).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milner, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq40c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246w49j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mg44s"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluational reactions to English, Canadian French and European French voices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Preston, Malcolm. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There has been some research in recent years which has attempted to demonstrate the effect of needs, attitudes and stereotyped beliefs on social judgements and perception (see, for instance, Secord, 1959). One type of experimental design that highlights the role that such factors play in perception consists of observing and comparing the reactions of a subject when presented with the same stimulus under different labelling conditions. A technique which employs this sort of design has been developed by Lambert, Hodgson, Gardner, and Fillenbaum (1960). They compared a listener's evaluative reactions to the same individual speaking in two languages. In this case, different labels (languages) are attached to the same stimulus (a person's voice).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lambert, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816r07f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mg44s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b2228"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some nematode parasites of wild rats (Rattus rattus) from Taiwan, Formosa</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prah, Sam. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nematode parasites studied were collected from a large number of wild rats, Rattus rattus, on the island of Formosa by the United States Navy Medical Unit No.2 under the direction of Commander R. E. Kuntz. Rattus rattus belongs to the group of mammals, Rodentia, the members of which are characterized by their gnawing and chewing habits. They are vegetarians and have a world wide distribution. Representatives of all the large groups of parasitic nematodes have been recorded from rodents; the parasitic nematodes of the common rat, for example, have a cosmopolitan distribution.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cameron, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg56t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b2228</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Parasitology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7h149t152"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Survival, as affected by primary excision with grafting and hypothermia, in a lethal experimental scald</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poy, Neville. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The cutaneous burn and the problem of effective therapy, especially in the more extensive ones, is profound and interest in it dates back many decades. In this paper, we are presenting the problem of cellular injury resulting from the application of heat to living tissue, otherwise known as a "thermal burn". There are numerous varieties of thermal burns aptly named according to the physical nature of the heat emitting agent. Amongst these are electrical burns resulting from contact with a “live electric current”, flash burns secondary to intense radiant energy, flame burns produced by contact with flames from any flamable agent, and scald burns resulting from contact with high temperature liquids to mention only a few.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woolhouse, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g847w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t152</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s8426"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Frobenius groups</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poland, John. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The theory of group characters was founded, and developed to a high degree, by G. Frobenius in the period from 1885 to 1910. As an example of its usefulness, he proved (see M. Hall, Jr.[10],p.292) that if G is a transitive permutation group of degree m whose permutations other than the identity leave at most one of the symbols invariant, then those permutations of G which displace all the symbols form together with the identity a normal subgroup of order m.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schwerdtfeger, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt92j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s8426</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s385s"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The co-current vertical downward flow of a turbulent gas stream and a thin liquid film in a rectangular duct</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pike, John. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis was undertaken to at least partially close the enormous gap which exists in the understanding of the behaviour of liquid films flowing co-currently with a gas stream. A review of previous studies is presented. A theoretical model is established which considers the gas stream to be influenced by both the motion of the film and the “non-smooth” nature of the film surface. The subject experimental investigation of a water film flowing on one face of a vertical rectangular duct is described. Liquid Reynolds numbers in the range 150-1500 and mean air velocities up to 55 fps were encountered Values of mean, maximum and minimum film thickness as well as records of the film surface profiles were obtained by use of a photometric measuring technique.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mordell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2688827.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s385s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72pb922"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mesencephalic-thalamic relations in the mechanism of the experimental wave and spike complex in the cat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perot, Phanor. L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It was known from ancient times that some men suffered from a disease that periodically threw them to the ground and caused a convulsion. The earliest mention of epilepsy of which we are now aware occurs in the Code of Hammurabi (2080 B.C.) in which may be found laws regulating the marriage of epileptic persona and the validity of their court testimony. Ancient Hebrew writings (2000 B.C.) found in the Talmud contain references to epilepsy in the precepts of the sanitary laws (Pirkner, 1929). It is understandable that the attention of the earliest observer of epilepsy should have been arrested by the prominent and awesome aspect of the generalized convulsion, and it is to this part or form of the disease that most consideration was given.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jasper, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827g25d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pb922</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qg715"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An electronic sampled-flow integrator for the measurement of the expiratory flow rate</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pengelly, Lionel. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There has been much development in the field of respiratory physiology within the recent past, and this has been accelerated by the availability of better instruments for the purposes of making measurements. Since Hutchinson introduced the spirometer in 1846, the introduction of each new instrument has revealed a new area into which efforts of research, both clinical and purely physiological, have been directed. One of the most powerful, and yet the most simple tests of respiratory dynamic capability is the Forced Expiratory Volume, consisting of a maximal forced expiration following a maximal inspiration. It has been demonstrated that this test is a sensitive indicator of respiratory airway resistance.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christie, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h078m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg715</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tc777"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gastrointestinal absorption of radioactive strontium in rats</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thyvalikakath, Paul. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The man produced radiation had been with us for nearly three-quarters of a century. It represents an element which has significant impact on nearly every phase of human life. In the latter part of last century, the experiments with vaccum dischargers have led to the discovery of X-rays by Roentgen in 1895. This was soon followed by Becherel's (1896) discovery of radiation from radiactive materials. Within months it was recognized that each of these radiation could have injurious effect upon persons exposed to it. The increasing incidence of radiation damage had culminated in the establishment of International Commission of Radiological Protection in 1928.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Skoryna, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924g25n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc777</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jq24r"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>George Berkeley’s theory of notions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Park, Désirée. U.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>More than two hundred and fifty years have elapsed since George Berkeley first published his Principles of Human Knowledge and thereby divided the intelligible world into “notions” and “ideas". In the ensuing period, the more articulate world has shown a marked preference for treating only his theory of “ideas” .The result has been misleading. It is therefore the purpose of this essay to present Berkeley' s theory of “notions”, in so far as it can be gleaned from the pages of his extant works, and to emphasize the importance of "notions" in any fair-minded attempt to view Berkeleyan philosophy as a whole. The vital role of a theory of notions will become evident in due course.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Currie, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j338.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jq24r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v8384073"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of the development of DDT resistant strains of the house fly Musca domestica L. and the laboratory mouse Mus musculus domesticus L.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ozburn, George. W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The growing use of synthetic chemicals to combat insects of economic importance to man has led to the discovery and wide recognition of changes in the nature of insect populations and of subsequent control failures. Changes which result in inadequate control when an insecticide dosage which was formerly effective is employed are termed insecticidal resistance. Major review papers (Brown 1958, Crow 1960, Metcalf 1955) all conclude that resistance is a result of natural selection taking place with such rapidity that the worker is able to observe the evolutionary processes. Smith (1941) was one of the first workers to call attention to the significance of racial segregation in applied biology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morrison, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719q68q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8384073</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cx751"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The difficulties experienced by Luo and Swahili children in learning English</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Owuor, Donald</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Like other countries which have only recently emerged from British colonial rule, for example, India and Ceylon, or are on the verge of attaining self-government, Kenya has had to face the task of choosing an official language. In her case the choice has been complicated by the prominence of two languages, namely, Swahili and English. Swahili, a Bantu-based language, is widely spoken and understood among the country’s population, whose languages belong mainly to the Bantu family of languages. It is estimated that some 7,000,000 people throughout East Africa speak Swahili as their native language.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hall, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w328x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx751</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591c64j"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Control of learned responses by drug states</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Overton, Donald. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is well known that a response learned by an animal in its normal state may be markedly depressed when any one of a number of drugs is administered to the animal. Such drug effects are currently receiving considerable attention. A different type of drug effect is that first noted by Girden and Culler (1937). They observed that, in certain cases, a response learned in a particular drug state would subsequently reoccur only when that drug state was reinstated. Their results draw attention to response decrements produced by a change in the chemical state of the organism, independent of whether it is a change from the nondrug state, to a drug state, from a drug state to the nondrug state, or from one drug state to another drug state. However, until recently, little interest was shown in such control of subsequent response occurrence by the “drug state" or body-chemistry condition present during acquisition of the response.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bindra, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430815z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c64j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awh246w509"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synthesis of methylenedioxy and dimethoxy compounds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Orphanos, Demetrius. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It is a very well-known fact that numerous alkaloids contain as a substituent methylenedioxy and/or methoxy groups. Many of these substances possess a characteristic physiological activity and therefore are extensively used in medicine. The significance of these compounds bas provided an impetus for extensive synthetic research by various schools to prepare new related substances of improved biological activity. The fact that many physiologically active substances are oxazines, led us to believe that the combination of a dialkoxybenzene ring with an oxazine nucleus, might give rise to or increase biological activity. In the present work the object was to study the synthesis of a number of 6,7-dialkoxy-1,4-benzoxazin-2-ones and their dihydro-derivatives 2-phenomorpholones.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Taurins, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591c65t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246w509</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sf00g"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on certain nematopagous fungi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Olthof, Theodorus. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The existence of fungi capable of capturing and consuming microscopic animals has been known for approximately eighty years; however, it is only during the past three decades that this interesting group of fungi has received the critical attention of an increasing number of workers who are studying them from several aspects. During this period, which was inaugurated by Drechsler in the U.S.A., the range of morphological diversity of these fungi has received considerable attention; some work has been done on their distribution and degree of occurrence in various habitats; aspects of their biology have been studied and attempts have been made to utilize these fungi in the biological control of plant and animal diseases, caused by nematodes, or eelworms as they are sometimes called.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Estey, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462876k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sf00g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04ds99n"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Programming and analysis of a barotropic prediction model</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Olson, Marvin. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A quasi-geostrophic barotropic model, incorporating a planetary wave stabilization term, was integrated at the 500-mb level to obtain 12, 24, 36 and 48-hour height forecast charts. To achieve planetary wave stabilization, an approximation based on Phillips’ (1951) two-layer atmospheric model, was made to the horizontal divergence term. The integration was performed on the IBM 1410 computer located at McGill University. The calculations were done on a (49 x 38) rectangular, hemispheric grid network using initial 500-mb height data for February 15, 1959. The resulting forecast, for the particular day, showed a definite improvement over forecasts obtained with other barotropic models which did not include the stabilization term. The comparisons also demonstrated that the use of a large grid can result in an improved forecast.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kwizak, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kp181.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds99n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Meteorology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv9356455"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An experimental investigation of intergrowth phenomena in bornite and chalcopyrite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Newham, Walter. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Samples of bornite and chalcopyrite between the compositions Cu5FeS4 (Bo) and CuFeS (subscript 1.76) were heated in sealed1 evacuated1 silica glass capsules, then chilled in water and studied under a reflecting microseope. The solvus curves delimiting the two phase region,join Bo80 at 500 °C to Bo65 at 800 °C and Bo (subscript 10) at 500 °C to Bo(subscript 25) at 800 °C. Lines extending from Bo (subscript)35 at 800 °C through Bo(subscript)28 and &amp; 45 at 500 °C bound a field of double exsolution. Chalcopyrite exsol ves in borni te as lamellae up to 0.004 mm wide, boundary segregations and possibly rounded blebs; while bornite exsolves in chalcopyrite as irregular hair-like structures generally less than 0.001 mm wide. Chalcopyrite and bornite lamellae seem to be controlled by the low and high temp. erature forms of the respective host minerals. Chalcopyrite lamellae grow more rapidly than bornite1 and exsolution occurs raster in the pure system than in natural minerals (Schwartz, 1931), therefore these data are not directly applicable to geothermometry. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k18h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9356455</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bornite</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021j62g"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A cytogenetic study on interspecific diploid hybrids closely related to lotus corniculatus L. (leguminosae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Nettancourt, Dreux</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A cytogenetic study was carried out on 53 interspecific h;ybrids derived from ten different crosses between six diploid species of Lotus, namely, L.japonicus (Regel) Larsen, L.alpinus Schleich, L.fllicaulis Dur, L. schoelleri Schweint , L.krylovii Schischk and Serg, and tenuis Waldst et Kit, to provide data on crossability, hybrid fertility and the mode of inheritance of phenotypic traits. Red stem colour, presence of cyanogenetic glycoside1 black keel tip, floret striping, pod mottling and seed speckling were inherited as dominant characters• Several of the hybrida expressed p.ronounced heterosis, especially for leaflet and floret size. In spite of cytological irregularities which included cytomixis, desynapsis and multivalent formation, normal chromosome pairing was recorded in at least 60% of the metaphase plates observed for each hybrid. Percentages of stainable pollen ranged from 55 to 99 in the parental species 1 whereas only 2 to 45% of the pollen stained in the hybrids. Seed set per pod was low in all hybrids.[...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grant, W. F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wt996.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021j62g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cell hybridization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lotus corniculatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cytogenetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant hybridization</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rp76k"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A history of physical education in the Protestant schools of Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Neil, Graham. I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to understand the development of physical education in Quebec in its proper historical context, it is first of all necessary to understand the general education development in the province. The divisions that are seen to evolve in the one complete education system may help to explain why physical education has grown as it has in the province, and why the division of chapters is as it is in this thesis. This province is the oldest of the Canadian Confederation, European settlement coming in 1608 when Champlain founded the city of Quebec. It is also the largest province in the Dominion. In population it is second only to Ontario.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b27740171.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp76k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kf19p"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A phenomenological hyperon-nucleon potential</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Needler, George. T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the discovery of the hyperons, that is, the ^ particle and the E particle, and their classification as baryons of strangeness  S = 1 by Gell-Mann (1953), there has been considerable interest in the nature of the interaction of these particles with the nucleons. It has been established that the hyperon-nucleon interaction is of the strong type which arises from the exchange of bosons, that is, which is present in the nucleon-nucleon interaction. At low energies, the effects of the exchange of kaons on the nucleon-nucleon interaction may be neglected and the interaction may be taken as arising from the exchange of only pions. The work of Lichtenberg and Ross (1958) indicates that the effects of the exchange of kaons on the ^-nucleon interaction may also be neglected.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sharp, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903354m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kf19p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agh93h306q"><ual:graduationDate>1963</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evoked response pattern and recovery cycles in human subjects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nazif, Abdel. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>By definition evoked potentials are "the detectable electrical changes in the brain in response to deliberate stimulation of any part of the nervous system” (16). The importance of recording human brain responses to controlled sensory stimuli is well recognized. These responses represent, in fact, the end product of a long series of events in the nervous system from the peripheral receptor organs, through many interneurones and relay stations, up to the cortical neurons which participate in their production. Any change, physiological, chemical or pathological, occurring anywhere along their paths may be reflected in the recorded evoked responses. It is conceivable, therefore, that the study of these electrophysiological data can yield useful information about the functional state of the nervous system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Muller, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x480p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h306q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychiatry</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>