<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ang451k771"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compensation for the gravitational force on the jaw during speech</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shiller, Douglas M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>External loads, such as those due to the orientation of body segments relative to gravity, affect the extent to which control signals result in the achievement of desired goals. The degree to which subjects adjust control signals to compensate for loads provides a measure of what the nervous system knows about forces affecting motion and gives an indication of the complexity of control signals needed for voluntary movement. In the present study, we have explored the hypothesis that subjects take no account of the orientation of the head relative to gravity when making jaw movements during speech. We used a simulation model of the jaw to predict the kinematic effect of using a single set of motor commands (which take no account of the relative direction of the gravitational force) to produce speech-like movements while the body was in three different orientations: upright, prone and supine. The simulations predict a systematic change in jaw pitch angle and horizontal translation resulting from the change in body orientation. Empirical results for five subjects tested under the same conditions as those explored in the simulations are for the most part consistent with the pattern predicted by the model. This suggests that in the case of jaw movements during speech, control signals are not adjusted to account for changes in head and body orientation relative to gravity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ostry, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn63j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k771</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biomechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Speech -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jaws -- Mechanical properties</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt81k"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sanctified lie : form and content in the art of Oscar Wilde</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sheety, Roger</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study seeks to show that in the work of Oscar Wilde, form and content, though manifestly separate, are latently connected. In Wilde's aesthetics, form and content are more than mere critical generalities---they are also metaphors for, respectively, art and nature, order and chaos, two conflicting but interdependent principles. Form in Wilde's work is a metaphor for the artist's defense against the largeness and ambiguity of nature and life. Therefore, to create, Wilde needs to insist on form over content, art over nature. Form in Wilde's work manifests itself in a deliberately artificial style, a style revealed by, for example, epigrammatic dialogue and posing of characters. However, because of this emphasis on form, nature and life will make an uncanny figurative return in Wilde's fiction, a return symbolized, for instance, by emotional ambivalence, intellectual ambiguity, and even acts of murder. In Wilde, form and content are interdependent because the content is latent in the principle of form, which stands for the human struggle against the perceived disorder of nature and life, a struggle which nevertheless is revelatory of that same chaos.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kilgour, Maggie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw62m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt81k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1831cn082"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bridging the gap? : a critical reading of Bhabha, Said and Spivak's postcolonial positions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Selby, Don</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>With the progress of globalization, it is becoming increasingly evident that there lies within it a Westernizing thrust that forms a part of the European colonial legacy. Postcolonial theorists, exemplified by Homi K. Bhabha, Edward W. Said, and Gayatri Chakravorty Spivak, have, over the last twenty years, produced some of the most influential discourse-analysis of colonialism, and critiques of neocolonialism. Their works, committed to various streams of poststructuralism, nonetheless exhibit some debilitating epistemological problems this thesis demonstrates by recourse to Wittgenstein and Kierkegaard. In conclusion it offers an alternative approach to globalization derived from Kierkegaard's dilemma of first principles in Either/Or, and Wittgenstein's discussion of language games in Philosophical Investigations .</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pericard, Alain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c488t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cn082</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Said, Edward W. -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bhabha, Homi K., 1949- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Postcolonialism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spivak, Gayatri Chakravorty -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apc289m14c"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'ennemi chez A. de Saint-Exupéry, suivi de, L'échec de l'idéologie moderne</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Séguin, Benoit, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present master's thesis includes an essay and a fiction based on the theme of the ennemy. The essay relies on Antoine de Saint-Exupery's works: it shows the main three steps leading the warrior to a fall understanding of the meaning of his combat. First, the warrior must recognize and confront the outer ennemy, in order to attain certain virtues which will lead him to a first degree of personal growth. But the warrior who wishes to go beyond that limit must then point towards himself the faults attributed to the outer ennemy: he will thereby discover his own inner ennemy. Finally, the evacuation of hatred will be possible only if he accepts to challenge himself to the limit of his combat, by sacrifying himself for the sake of mankind. The fiction tells the story of a young teacher who decides to declare war on his own principal for having done something absolutely immoral: the plagiarism of a philosophical essay in an editorial sent to the parents. Progressively, the troubling events that this teacher will go through will force him to admit that cowardness and dishonesty, faults first attributed to his boss, are in fact vices that he was never able to recognize in himself until then. The discovery of his inner ennemy will change everything. The teacher won't accept anymore to fight in this war that has degenerated into hatred. Facing his responsibilities towards those who, just like him, challenged the principal and put themselves in a precarious situation, he will surrender to the only fraternal action left: his own sacrifice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945t045.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m14c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Saint-Exupéry, Antoine de, 1900-1944 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aws859h824"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Encountering the uncanny in art and experience : possibilities for a critical pedagogy of transformation in a postmodern time</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Scott Kabwe, Maureen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis considers the ways that critical reflection on normalizations of social meaning and structures can provide sites for learning and transformation in a pluralist, divided, and destructive world. It investigates five recent "uncanny" works of art, in order to illustrate the value of critiquing closed frames of reference and attending to theories of hermeneutics, ideology critique, and aesthetics. The thesis explores the elements of postmodern consciousness which raise questions about self, identity, and agency in an era of fragmentation, difference, and challenges to master narratives. Using a dialogue between theory and text, history and fiction, it outlines part of an interpretive project, in which art provides one site for curriculum and public debate regarding a participatory and inclusionary society, thus contributing to a postmodern pedagogy of transformation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood, Elizabeth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k026r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h824</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Art criticism -- Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Postmodernism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3b591b607"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Race, class, women and the state : the case of domestic labour in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Schecter, Tanya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the history of female immigrant domestic labour in Canada from a socialist feminist perspective. Over the past hundred years, Canadian immigration policy with respect to domestic workers became increasingly regressive with the shift in the racial composition of foreign female domestics. The women's movement contributed to this change as gains in Canadian women's public rights did not effectively challenge the dominant social paradigm of women's roles, and so left intact the public-private divide and the sexual division of labour to which were allied biases of race and class. The women's movement thus became an unwitting participant in the formulation of regressive immigration policies which rebounded on the women's movement itself, reinforcing its internal divisions.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq20q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b607</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women alien labor -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Government policy -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women domestics -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hr863"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The British public school and the imperial mentality : a reflection of empire at U.C.C.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Scarff, Stephen D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The focus of this work is on how the educational elements that made up the institution called the British public school developed to form an "imperial mentality" among its students, and how these elements were transported, albeit with some modification, to the periphery of Empire. The existence of a broad and varied curriculum worked to form an imperial mentality that supported the aims of the British Empire from the mid-eighteenth century through the First World War. The use of a case study featuring Upper Canada College, one of the oldest Canadian "public" schools, further illuminates the influence and legacy of the public school model. Throughout the research, references to Upper Canada College will serve to focus the attention of the reader to the manner in which the British public school shaped the curriculum and the ethos of the College.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wolforth, John</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v988x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr863</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Private schools -- Ontario -- Toronto</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endowed public schools (Great Britain)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Upper Canada College -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p934z"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'oeuvre de Charles Cotin, ou, Pour une esthétique de la galanterie</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roy, Roxanne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This Master's Thesis analyses the work of Charles Cotin an abbot and a poet who, between 1630 and 1665, successfully proved himself in the Literary Salons of France. This thesis will try to determine how his work illustrates well the Gallant esthetics and how his poetical choices reflect but also challenge the great tendencies of the Gallant literature. The analysis of Cotin's Work divides itself into three facets: Lampoons, Religious texts and Gallant poetry. The Gallant esthetics is shown differently as Cotin progressively extricates hermeneutic rules and then try to adapt Theology to the King's entourage. Cotin's work will also be able to show the links between a Gallant literature and the social background of this time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DoiRon, Normand</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881p232.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p934z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cotin, Charles, 1604-1682 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r3172"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La vie à travers un kaléidoscope, suivi de, Le personnage : du théorique vers la pratique</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ross, Vika</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>At first glance, one might perceive fictional characters as straightforward beings. Upon closer examination, however, one discovers what multi-faceted entities they really are. This essay deals with the complexity of the nature of characters by focusing on several theoretical and practical aspects thereof. With the help of several theorists (such as Todorov, Greimas, and Hamon) this paper uses theoretical concepts as a springboard for a discussion of strategies and pitfalls in the creation of fictional characters. Virginia Woolf, Julien Green, Milan Kundera and Gabrielle Roy are some of the writers whose knowledge was tapped for the portion of the essay dealing with the creation of characters. La vie a travers un kaleidoscope (Life as seen through a kaleidoscope) is a collection of seven short stories in which some of the characters were inspired by people encountered by the author. The focus on character in the essay is therefore a natural extension of the creation of these short stories.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Everett, Jane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784n88f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r3172</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Characters and characteristics in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g7208"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of the relationships between learning context, student approach to learning and student learning outcomes in distance education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Price, Nancy, 1966-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of the present study was to explore qualitative differences in student learning outcomes in distance education courses. The following relationships were examined within the context of three McGill Distance Education Program courses that vary widely in content and instructional goals: (1) the relationship between learning context, student approach to learning and student learning outcomes; (2) the relationship between student and instructor perspectives of the learning context; and (3) the relationship between type of course, course learning expectations, course structure and design, and the selected method(s) of assessment. The design of this study employed a mixture of both qualitative and quantitative data collection and analysis procedures. The data set included instructor interviews, a qualitative measure of instructor's student learning expectations for their course, qualitative measures of students' course learning expectations, and quantitative measures of students' general learning approach, students' specific approach to learning in their course, and students' positive and negative impressions of their course. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Amundsen, Cheryl</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw692.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g7208</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Learning, Psychology of</dc:subject><dc:subject>Distance education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4t64gq40p"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The varieties of paranoia in Gravity's rainbow</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pooley, Charles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This paper is an investigation into the way that paranoia is represented in Thomas Pynchon's novel Gravity's Rainbow. Using various definitions of paranoia which are given in the text itself, I outline how each definition is demonstrated, both in narrative events and in the structural principles of the text. As well, I show how each definition may lend a different perspective on the reading process itself, thus implicating the Pynchon's reader in the paranoid dynamic which Gravity's Rainbow depicts. In effect, I attempt to return the pluralism to Pynchon's definition of paranoia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ohlin, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945t05f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq40p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pynchon, Thomas. Gravity's rainbow</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150m21s"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The interplay between exile-in-narration and narrators-in-exile in Salman Rushdie's Midnight's children, The Satanic Verses and The Moor's Last Sigh</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pirbhai, Mariam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an analysis of Salman Rushdie's Midnight's Children, The Satanic Verses and The Moor's Last Sigh. The approach is twofold: (a) it seeks to establish an interplay between the concept of exile-in-narration (theme) and narrators-in-exile (form) as a reflection upon questions of rootlessness; and (b) it seeks to underscore this interplay as a recurring 'double bind' within each novel, such that the novels form a loosely bound trilogy that functions as a developing discourse on individual and national identity from a decentred perspective. The aim is similarly twofold: (a) it proposes that the metaphor of exile as a polarized state manifests itself as either an unreflecting pull of opposites or as a thoughtful acceptance of the inter-connectedness between ideas, people, places and things; and (b) it argues that once this polarization becomes evident, it disturbs all static narratives of selfhood and community to the point at which they can be reconceptualized, and yet remain open-ended.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dorsinville, Max</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999878x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m21s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rushdie, Salman. Moor's last sigh</dc:subject><dc:subject>Exiles in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rushdie, Salman. Satanic verses</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rushdie, Salman. Midnight's children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x603f"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>ita</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Italian</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'insegnamento dell'italiano a Montreal verso il Duemila : insegnamento e apprendimento al livello post-secondario in un contesto plurilingue</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Picciano, Giovanna A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Teaching and learning foreign languages has always been a source of debate. This research begins by tracing the evolution of teaching methods and approaches. It proceeds to describe how the teaching and learning of Standard Italian at the post-secondary level and in adult education in Montreal is affected by the multicultural nature of the community. The analysis of individual textbooks used in post-secondary and adult instruction in Montreal and the surrounding area follows. This study should provide an impetus for further investigation regarding the relationship between foreign language acquisition and the choice of textbooks for classroom use and it could provide solutions for some of the pedagogical problems arising from Montreal's linguistic plurality.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Predelli, Maria Bendinelli</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c4893.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x603f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Methodology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italian language -- Textbooks</dc:subject><dc:subject>Italian language -- Study and teaching -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m6236"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Community learning in Haiti : a case study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paproski, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Life in a bidonville (poor urban slum) is portrayed in this study using the lens of learning. This contribution to the generally sparse literature and knowledge on communities in Haiti, discusses elements of informal and non-formal learning in this difficult context. The process of qualitative observation over the period of six months revealed many "community-based assets." These assets contributed to learning by providing spaces of calm, safety and respect, emerging from strong shared values of mutual assistance. In equal proportion, however, mawonaj (deceit or hiding the truth) and silence, as well as the social and cultural challenges of listening at many levels reinforced traditional hierarchies and prevented or interfered with changing mental models, making these obstacles to learning. In the-heart of this neighbourhood, the focal point of social and economic activity, a community-based development organization served as the vantage point for observation and interviews. Primary information sources included observation and interviews largely involving this organization's personnel, volunteers and the people that frequented it for many different reasons. The unit of analysis for this study is the adult learner, observed within a community development organizational context. Using the adult learner in situe (at a community centre) as the focal point, this study attempts to gain insights on how community learning takes place. It posits that changes in knowledge, skills and attitudes which take place at an individual level---learning---which bring about transformations in the social and interpersonal context, is the basis of community development. Revealing this context, the content and how the behaviour and mental modeling are controlled at a community's epicentre, gives insights into understanding the process of how the community learns more broadly, giving value to phenomena which take place in and around it. Understanding elements of this process, community learning, can usefully inform approaches to community development intervention.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lusthaus, Charles</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107113b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m6236</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education -- Haiti</dc:subject><dc:subject>Community education -- Haiti</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602313t"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Là où le chien aboie, et, La rhétorique de l'idiot</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ouellette, Julie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Up where the dog barks (creation). Sitting around the table of a secret municipal council, a mayor and his aldermen, outraged by the village idiot's stupidity, are planning his death. On a beautiful spring's morning, they kidnap him and throw him in a isolated well, whose opening they carefully seal afterwards. Three days later, however, screams are heard from the bottom of the idiot's pit. Contaminated within their own cadastre by the innocent's cries, the villagers, one after another, will have to tell their story: their rural madness, hidden within their common unawareness. Then, without knowing it, it is with the dispossessed's eloquence that they will be caught inside short narratives with no beginning or end---many frames in movement---that will constitute a sole account since all determined by the same disturbing rumour. The rhetoric of the idiot (criticism). In the shadow of the madman, literary character extremely fascinating lately, the idiot silently cradles himself. Many times portrayed in the works of various authors, its problem seems to differ from the "illuminated"'s. Often aphasic or having a poor vocabulary, the idiot is, in most cases, only described. However, some authors have been able to give him a voice, usually in a strongly poetic prose. Among these writers, William Faulkner ( The Sound and the Fury), Anne Hebert (Les fous de Bassan) and Suzanne Jacob (Laura Laur) distinguish themselves by letting the characters such as the idiot or the simple minded assume control, to a certain extent, of the narration in their fiction. Indeed, it will be the tools of the new rhetoric (rhetoric reconciled of the figures and the argumentation) as apprehended by Michel Meyer in his several works that will be used for the analysis of the three narrations. It will then be possible to investigate the necessary assimilation of the sense and the argumentation within what could be called a project common to the three authors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rivard, Yvon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Chapdelaine, Annick</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg14z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602313t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mental illness in literature</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7p88cj763"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Formalization in a social movement organization : cooptation or survival? :</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nordquist, Karen L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Social movement literature suggests that organizations espousing radical ideologies must develop bureaucratic structures in order to survive, changes which inevitably create an organization more concerned with self-maintenance than social transformation. In the Battered Women's Movement, some radical feminists argue that trends toward increased formalization and centralization in feminist collectives provide evidence that the movement has been coopted, and thus radical organizations seeking to challenge inequitable social structures have been transformed into more traditional social service agencies. This thesis examines one shelter for battered women which, due mainly to severe internal conflict, found it necessary to modify its structure from a collective to a hierarchy led by a coordinator. This change led neither to decreased radical ideology nor to an increased focus on organizational maintenance at the expense of socially transformative goals. However, due to a lack of formalized procedures, this outcome largely reflects the personal inclinations of the coordinator.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Staggenborg, Suzanne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh26d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj763</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Feminist theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nonprofit organizations -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Management -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women's shelters -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Management -- Case studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0c483m332"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Renegotiating home and identity : experiences of Gujarati immigrant women in suburban Montréal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nair, Roopa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the meaning of home for 19 Hindu Gujarati immigrant women living in the Montreal suburban municipality of Dollard-des-Ormeaux. Adopting a qualitative approach, this study redefines home as a multiple and dynamic concept, referring not only to the house but also the homeland, neighbourhood, cultural community and even the abstract feeling of belonging or being 'at home.' While this study concentrates on the women's present homes and neighbourhoods, the idea of the home as being reinvented across a variety of spaces and social relationships is a central theme. Home-making is argued to be an evolving social process that begins in the childhood and marital homes in India and continues with the transition into new homes in Montreal. The house and home spaces (the neighbourhood and cultural community) are sites where multiple dimensions of the women's identities are given a voice and reinvented. The women define the character of the home spaces, and also negotiate culture, ethnicity and identity within them. Through the construction of hybrid cultural identities, the women are able to make themselves and their families 'at home' between cultures. This study points to complex and sometimes paradoxical meanings of home, and emphasizes the significance of the suburban, rather than inner city, quality of home-making and adaptation processes among immigrant women in Montreal.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ray, B. K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj924.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483m332</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Group identity -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Home -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Suburbs -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>South Asian-Canadian women -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region -- Ethnic identity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women immigrants -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region -- Social conditions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rq909"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tanwīr al-Miqbās min Tafsīr Ibn ʹAbbās : its principles of interpretation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Muthmainnah, Inna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigates the principles of interpretation in Tanwir al-Miqbas min Tafsir Ibn `Abbas, focusing on its approach and method, sources and points of view. To accomplish this purpose, both historical and literary analysis are employed. Nevertheless, this study does not attempt to resolve the well-known dispute over its authenticity or ascription. Like other Qur'anic commentaries produced in the classical period, Tanwir al-Miqbas relies heavily on philological analysis in the sense that it provides an interpretation of Qur'anic verses based on their literal meaning and in very simple terms. Similarly, it employs sources that were commonly used in classical tafsir, namely, Qur'anic cross-reference, ḥadith, Arabic poetry and isra'iliyat. However, due to its simplistic approach, it is difficult to extract any guiding principles behind its interpretation. In fact, there is little to indicate that this Qur'anic exegesis represents the views of any particular Islamic sect, let alone of any individual person. Nevertheless, with its simple presentation, Tanwir al-Miqbas brings up many interesting and challenging issues which deserve greater scholarly attention. Further and deeper research into these issues may help us to situate the work within the broader exegetical tradition in Islam.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boullata, Issa J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150m222.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq909</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>ʻAbd Allāh ibn al-ʻAbbās, d. 688? Tafsīr</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fīrūzābādī, Muḥammad ibn Yaʻqūb, 1329-1414 or 15. Tanwīr al-miqbās min Tafsīr Ibn ʻAbbās</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644t749"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of the translation movement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Musaji, Zahra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The development of the translation movement in Islamic history was a long, intricate movement which encompassed a large number of people over a long period of time. It is the objective of this paper to assess the historical setting which gave rise to this movement as well as to evaluate why it was embraced. Moving onward, the paper will then move to a more detailed examination of six translators, in an effort to evaluate their contribution to the movement. While doing this, an inventory will be conducted of the works which were translated in the three disciplines of astrology, philosophy, and medicine by these translators in an attempt to answer the question of why the selection process was so specific and what perhaps were the criteria for these choices.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ormsby, Eric</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j111s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t749</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Translating and interpreting -- Islamic Empire</dc:subject><dc:subject>Civilization, Islamic -- Foreign influences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9k41zg66v"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of East Asian Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Eating disorders in Japanese women : a cross-cultural comparison with Canadian women</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Moriyama, Nancy Yoshie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This cross-cultural study examines eating disorders, Anorexia nervosa, Bulimia, and compulsive overeating in Japanese and Canadian women. Through qualitative interviews with nine Japanese and nine Canadian women with eating disorders, it was found that factors contributing to the onset of eating disorders were similar in the two groups. Similarities included the value placed upon thinness by society which is widely perpetuated by the media, being told they were fat and made to feel they needed to lose weight, wanting attention for their eating disorder, and a history of sexual abuse. The Canadian women interviewed, revealed that their mothers also had eating disorders. On the other hand, the Japanese women reported stress from the education system, which led to abnormal eating behavior. Japanese women also reported gender-role conflicts as a cause. A questionnaire regarding attitudes towards food and weight was given to 100 Japanese and 55 Canadian female university students. It was found that the women's desire to lose weight was strong in both samples. Sixty-six percent of the Japanese women and 38.1 percent of the Canadian women reported that they are "always," "usually," or "often" terrified that their weight will increase. This study postulates that the women with eating disorders want to empower themselves by controlling their food intake and their body weight. The implication is that any factor that creates a sense of ineffectiveness in the woman may trigger an eating disorder if the woman believes the only thing she can control is her food intake. Evidence to support this argument will be shown through discussions of actual experiences of women with eating disorders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Culter, Suzanne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v13z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg66v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Eating disorders -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Mental health -- Sociological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eating disorders -- Japan</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mm08x"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Jewish Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exodus 34:29-35 : Moses' "horns" in early Bible translations and interpretations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Medjuck, Bena Elisha</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Exodus 34:29--35 contains an ambiguous Hebrew phrase that describes the peculiar condition of Moses' face after his encounter with God on Mt. Sinai. The iconographic tradition of Moses in religious art includes many depictions of him as "horned," yet the early exegetes described his condition as some kind of radiance, Divine glory, or as a metaphor for strength. How, then, is this iconography of horns based on the biblical text or early biblical exegesis? The primary sources evaluated for this study encompass more than two thousand years of biblical interpretation, but the subject of this thesis comprises exegetical material from the time of the canonisation of the Bible until Jerome in the fourth century. This material includes selections from the Hebrew Bible and the New Testament, the Old Testament Pseudepigrapha, Jewish and Christian post-biblical narratives, rabbinic midrash, and translations of the Pentateuch into Aramaic, Greek and Latin.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levy, B. Barry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj58x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm08x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Moses (Biblical leader)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz88x"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Voices of Vietnam : a monumental poetry of trauma</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McWha, Matthew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The poetry written by combat veterans and other witnesses to the Vietnam War is a testament to what they saw and felt in Southeast Asia. Through their poetry they build 'monuments' to their traumatic experience, piecing together memories in order to heal themselves and teach future generations about the horrors of Vietnam. These poems function in much the same way as the Vietnam Veterans Memorial in Washington, D.C., both poem and Memorial requiring the effort of the 'reader' in order to propagate the legacy of the Vietnam War. By bearing witness to the Vietnam experience, the poem and the Vietnam Veterans Memorial facilitate questions; questions through which the reader and the visitor are able to construct their own imaginary monuments to the Vietnam War.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lindeman, Yehudi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g478b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz88x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>War poetry, American -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vietnam War, 1961-1975</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t425v"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Perceptions of culture in the nursing student-teacher relationship</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McLaughlin, Veronica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This qualitative study examines the influence of culture on the teaching and learning process in an eastern Canadian college nursing program. The study reveals incongruency between the ideals of multiculturalism and teaching and learning processes. While teachers perceive they have the requisite skills to fulfill the content objectives using various pedagogical methods set out by the curriculum, they are not always able to promote successful achievement of these objectives in a multicultural student population. Moreover, students experience special learning difficulties in their interactions with teachers when the learning environment is unfamiliar to them and their own cultural identity and life values are not well understood. The study concludes that the content of nursing education curricula needs to be broadened to include attention to cultural considerations. Most importantly, teachers practicing within multicultural student populations need training in cultural sensitivity and in developing culturally appropriate pedagogical approaches.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boston, Patricia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr75v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t425v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Multicultural education -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nursing -- Study and teaching -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hr87c"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Socio-political background of the enactment of Kompilasi hukum Islam di Indonesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mawardi, Ahmad Imam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The formulation of the Kompilasi Hukum Islam di Indonesia (KHI), the standard reference on family law---marriage, inheritance and waqf---is the most recent legal milestone throughout the history of Islamic legal development in Indonesia. The change of social perceptions on family law and the practice of living adat or customary law has been the major factor in the compilation of the KHI. The social and adat elements in the KHI are unmistakable and allowed by the concepts of `urf (usage), maṣlaḥah (public interest), sadd al-dhara'i` (blocking the means) and istiḥsan (juristic preference) in Islamic law. The KHI, in turn, is to change and make uniform the social perception of family law throughout Indonesia, which varies from one place to another. From a political perspective, the enactment of the KHI is to strengthen the position of the Islamic courts by putting them on an equal footing with other courts in Indonesia. Since the Islamic courts earlier lacked a codified or compiled material law to be used as the official reference in rendering legal decisions, the emergence of KHI is a positive step in that direction. Finally, the emergence of the KHI is a realization of the accommodative relationship between the government and Islam under Indonesian New Order era, both of which take advantage of the enactment of the KHI. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Federspiel, Howard M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv98c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr87c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Adat law -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marriage (Islamic law) -- Indonesia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inheritance and succession (Islamic law) -- Indonesia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537329c"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Working for family, nation and God : paternalism and the Dupuis Frères department store, Montreal, 1926-1952</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matthews, Mary Catherine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>From 1868 to 1978, the Dupuis Freres department store serviced the French Montreal community from its headquarters on St. Catherine Street, east of Saint Laurent. This thesis looks at the management strategies of Dupuis Freres through its employee newspaper, Le Duprex, from 1926 to 1946, and then at their collapse with the Dupuis Freres strike in 1952. The Dupuis Freres management retained the loyalty of its employees by using a combination of paternalism and welfare capitalism. The company supported a union, organized leisure activities, provided sales incentives and rewarded loyalty financially and socially. In addition, the store integrated its French Canadian and Catholic identity with its employees' understanding of their work to impart cultural meaning to their employment. Dupuis Freres equated support for the company with the success of the French Canadian people, and its connections with the Catholic clergy added a sacred element to its enterprise. Dupuis Freres strike in 1952 divided French Canadians along class lines, and those who supported the workers were seen by neo-nationalists as doing so at the expense of French Canadian survival.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morton, Suzanne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v507q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537329c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Strikes and lockouts -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Paternalism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Department stores -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>