<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x581m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Otolaryngology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Finite-element model of the human eardrum and middle ear</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Daniel, Sam J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Computer-generated models are increasingly being used in otolaryngology for teaching purposes, pre-operative planning and clinical simulations, especially when dealing with small complex areas such as the middle ear. One technique used to analyse the mechanics of complex models is the finite-element method whereby the system of interest is divided into a large number of small simple elements. The mechanical properties and applied forces are represented by functions defined over each element, and the mechanical response of the whole system can then be computed. A unique three-dimensional finite-element model of the human eardrum and middle ear was devised. This model takes advantage of phase-shift moire shape measurements to precisely define the shape of the eardrum. The middle-ear geometry is derived from histological serial sections and from high-resolution magnetic-resonance microscopy of the human ear. The model allows an improved understanding of the mechanics of the human middle ear, can simulate various pathological conditions, and assist in the design of ossicular prostheses.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Funnell, W. Robert J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n261.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x581m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xw89p"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Long term effects of early maternal separation on cocaine self-administration in the adult rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chrétien, Pablo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Epidemiological studies have consistently shown that early life events serve to define populations at high or low risk for drug abuse during adulthood. It has also been shown in rats that repeated episodes of early maternal separation permanently alters their dopamine (DA) and behavioral responses to stress and psychostimulants. In this study, we investigated how early life events alter intravenous cocaine self-administration. Animals were tested on a progressive ratio (PR) schedule of reinforcement which yields a measure (the break-point or BP) of drug-seeking and drug reinforcement efficacy. On post-natal days 2--14, rat pups were exposed daily to either 3 hr of maternal separation (MS) or 15 min of handling (H). 3 months later, animals were initially trained to self-administer cocaine (1.0 mg/kg/inj) on a fixed-ratio schedule. Animals were subsequently allowed to earn cocaine on a PR schedule at doses of 0.125, 0.25, 0.50 or 1.0 mg/kg/inj. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gratton, Alain</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q8198.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw89p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj6731585m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cannabinoid receptors in animal models of acute, tonic and chronic pain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dableh, Liliane J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of the work presented here is to evaluate the effects of cannabinoids in three animal models of pain: acute, tonic and chronic. The tail flick test (acute pain) was used to test the effect of the cannabinoid agonist, WIN 55,212--2, on tail withdrawal latency from a noxious radiant heat source. It was also tested on the allodynia induced by either endogenous release or exogenous administration of substance P. WIN 55,212--2 was antinociceptive in this test, and blocked the substance P-induced allodynia, suggesting a post-synaptic site of action. The formalin test (tonic pain) was used to test the effects of the endogenous cannabinoid agonist, anandamide and the cannabinoid receptor antagonist AM 281. Anandamide was antinociceptive (with a short duration of action), and AM 281 was pronociceptive. When administered concomitantly, AM 281 blocked the effects of anandamide. When given alone and in the absence of a noxious stimulus, AM 281 was without effect. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henry, James L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht70c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731585m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arv042v84k"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>De la cryptographie sur les corps quadratiques reéls</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Desrosiers, Simon Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We describe here a key-exchange protocol over real quadratic fields. This is accompanied by all the pertinent algebraic background needed for the understanding of the protocol. We also present two quantum algorithms that solve the regulator problem over real quadratic fields and the discrete logarithm problem also known as the principal ideal problem.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crepeau, Claude</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935489t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v84k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn94p"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Texts, translators, transmissions : "Ḥayy ibn Yaqẓān" and its reception in Muslim, Judaic and Christian milieux</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hasanali, Parveen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>From its inception in the twelfth century to its current use as a text, Ibn Tufayl's Hayy ibn Yaqzan has a sustained history of translation and transmission. A unique aspect is its early translation into Hebrew around the first quarter of the fourteenth century, whose extensive manuscripts have been traced and established in this study. The Hebrew translation, and its commentary by Moses Narboni, shift the Tufaylian narrative from the Maghribi milieu toward Latin Averroism. They allow us to examine the particular reception in the Judaic milieu and suggest new perceptions of Ibn Rushd and Ibn Tufayl as rational mystics. The extensive printed translations in Europe that begin with the Latin Philosophus Autodidactus (1671) reflect different facets on Individuality, the Natural Man and Inner Revelation as accessible to and sought by the natural theologies of the 17th-18th centuries. The concurrent translations also reflect the differences in their reception by the translators. Through the process of transmission, the notion of self-sufficiency becomes epitomized in the paradigm of "Robinson Crusoe." In its own milieu, the narrative is conceived as an answer to Ibn Sina's 'secret of eastern philosophy' and is expressed as a rational-mystic response from the Maghribi context. The narrative finds its anti-thesis in Ibn al-Nafis' reiteration, that applies the structure and content of the Tufaylian narrative to reverse its philosophical precepts and establish a normative frame of revelation. Its recent reclamation in modern Arabic literature as the proto-type of Robinson Crusoe is indicative of post-Colonial validation. The different receptions of the narrative within each of the three milieux have inspired the application of new methodologies in literary criticism. Using the literary theories of reception and cultural paradigm in Hans Jauss and Edward Said, I further discuss the process of translation, transmission and reception of the narrative. Each milieu in a particular time-frame receives the text within certain sets of expectation and accordingly responds to it. This approach raises vital questions on both structural analyses that study an aesthetic work outside its history, and historical analyses that focus on the "unchanged loyalty" of its sources. The methodology developed in this study can be applied to central issues in Islamic thought, from the predilection toward its Greek sources to its dismissal of Averroism. It also allows for the appreciation of the integrai notion of rational mysticism. The notion of reception validates, resolves and values the different reiterations by recognizing their diverse contexts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Landolt, Hermann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn59b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn94p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ibn Ṭufayl, Muḥammad ibn ʻAbd al-Malik, d. 1185. Ḥayy ibn Yaqẓān</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqj72p9072"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>spa</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Hispanic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La "Respuesta a sor Filotea" : una pública defensa de la "Carta Atengórica"</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Escamilla-Elizalde, Jesús David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The thesis focuses on two letters written by Sor Juana Ines de la Cruz: The "Carta Atenagorica" (1690) and The "Respuesta a sor Filotea" (1691), as well as on the "Carta de sor Filotea de la Cruz a sor Juana Ines de la Cruz" (1690), written by Manuel Fernandez de Santa Cruz, bishop of Puebla. The "Respuesta a sor Filotea," inspired by the "Carta de sor Filotea," presents an elaborated defence of the "Carta Atenagorica" and the right to discuss theological principles that the author claims on her behalf. The thesis was inspired by the main theme of the "Respuesta a sor Filotea" as well as the polemical content of the other two letters. The introduction briefly presents the historical context in which the polemic took place. It also explains the objectives of the thesis and comments some of the critical work related to this theme. Chapters one and two analyse the "Carta Atenagorica," focusing on the theological discussion. Chapters three and four analyse the "Carta de sor Filotea." Chapter three examines the intentions of the bishop of Puebla when he published Sor Juana's letter under the title of "Atenagorica." The analysis of the bishop's letter is in chapter four. Chapter five examines, in the light of the preceding chapters, the "Respuesta a sor Filotea" and presents the conclusion.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boruchoff, David</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd20m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p9072</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Juana Inés de la Cruz, Sister, 1651-1695. Respuesta a sor Filotea de la Cruz</dc:subject><dc:subject>Juana Inés de la Cruz, Sister, 1651-1695. Carta Athenagórica de la madre Ivana Ynes de la Cruz, que imprime y dedica a la misma Sor Phylothea de la Cruz</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fernández de Santa Cruz y Sahagún, Manuel, 1637-1699 Carta de sor Filotea de la Cruz a sor Juan Inés de la Cruz</dc:subject><dc:subject>Juana Inés de la Cruz, Sister, 1651-1695. -- Religion</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sf54g"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Global positioning system receiver autonomous integrity monitoring</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perepetchai, Valeri</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with a theoretical development of Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) algorithms. Integrity characterizes a navigation system ability to provide timely warning to users when the Global Positioning System (GPS) should not be used for navigation. RAIM algorithms detect, identify GPS anomalies and satellite failures and provide the Horizontal Protection Level (HPL). HPL means the smallest detectable horizontal position error with given probabilities of a false alert and missed detection. The developed algorithms use carrier phase measurements, which compared with code measurements can provide precise positioning and an extremely high level of GPS integrity due to setting a very tight fault detection threshold and HPL. First the linear model based on accumulating a few epochs of single difference carrier phase measurements is presented. Then the estimated integer ambiguities available from the positioning solution are used to develop the other single difference linear model. The typical fault detection and identification methods, used for code measurements, are applied to these linear models, leading to various single difference algorithms. The double difference method is also derived. The maximum position separation technique is used to derive the position space based method, implemented through a set of Kalman filters. Finally, computer simulations are performed to compare the developed various algorithms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chang, X. W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb69c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf54g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geodesy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5712m868f"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kurt Gerstein's actions and intentions in light of three post-war legal proceedings</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hébert, Valerie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Kurt Gerstein entered the Waffen-SS in 1941 with the intention of working against the Nazi regime from the inside. Despite being required to participate in some of the criminal activities of the SS, Gerstein believed he could be most effective for the resistance if he remained in the SS. This thesis examines the evidence presented in and the results of three separate legal proceedings (a criminal trial, a Denazification hearing and a rehabilitation and compensation case) which took place in the 24 years following Gerstein's death in 1945. Each of the three proceedings was brought about for a different legal purpose, and therefore involved different laws and standards for judgment. However, all of the proceedings dealt with the problem of balancing the incriminating nature of Gerstein's means of resistance against what he had hoped to accomplish, or did accomplish, from that position.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoffmann, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q339.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m868f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gerstein, Kurt, 1905-1945</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anti-Nazi movement -- Germany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A79408012f"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Magmatic and hydrothermal processes in rare-element granite-pegmatite systems : the Preissac-Lacorne batholith, Quebec, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mulja, Thomas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Geological and mineralogical investigations of four moderately peraluminous monzogranitic plutons (Preissac, Moly Hill, Lamotte, Lacorne) in the Archean Preissac-Lacorne batholith (northwestern Quebec) indicate that each consists of biotite, two-mica and muscovite monzogranite facies, and that these facies are zonally distributed in this order from margin to core or the larger Lamotte and Lacorne plutons. Rare-element-enriched granitic pegmatites are associated with the Lamotte and Lacorne plutons and are also regionally zoned, in this case, with respect to their respective plutons, from beryl-bearing in the plutons to spodumene-bearing in the country rocks. Molybdenite mineralized albitites and stockworks occur beyond the spodumene pegmatites and in the Preissac and Moly Hill plutons. The monzogranites display systematic mineralogical and major- and trace-element trends from biotite to muscovite monzogranite in the four plutons that are best explained by fractional crystallization of a biotite monzogranite-forming liquid. These petrochemical trends in the Lamotte and Lacorne plutons extend to the rare-element pegmatites, indicating that the latter are comagmatic with the monzogranite. A model is proposed in which the liquids of the Lamotte and Lacorne plutons underwent an initial side-wall crystallization to produce the observed zonation of the monzogranite types, followed by extreme differentiation inside the magma chamber, from where batches of pegmatite-forming liquid were sequentially injected into the overlying rocks. Pegmatites are rare and barren from the smaller Preissac and Moly Hill plutons due to early saturation of the residual liquid with aqueous fluid, from which quartz vein molybdenite precipitate to form quartz vein stockworks adjacent to the muscovite-bearing monzogranite. The fractionation of the pegmatite-forming liquid is recorded partly in the crystal-chemistry of columbite-tantalite solid-solutions, by progressively higher Ta/(Ta + Nb) and Mn/(Mn + Fe) values with evolution from beryl- to spodumene-bearing pegmatite. These trends correlate to the greater solubility of Mn- relative to Fe- and of Ta- relative to Nb-columbite-tantalite end-members in the magma. In the Lacorne pagmatites, these trends were modified by contemporaneous crystallization of spessartine garnet, which buffered the Mn and Fe activities of the columbite-tantalite. The pegmatite-forming liquid became saturated with an aqueous fluid at the onset of crystallization as shown by the entrapment of primary fluid inclusions in the paragenetically early beryl and spodumene. The orthomagmatic fluid was NaCl-dominated, had low salinity, contained appreciable dissolved CO$ sb2$, and evolved from Fe-bearing in beryl to Mn-, Li- and Cs-bearing in spodumene pegmatite in concert with the petrochemical evolution of the magma. Subsequent fluid evolution was marked by influx of externally derived Ca-brines of metamorphic origin and eventual unmixing of the orthomagmatic fluid into aqueous and carbonic phases. The study represents the first comprehensive reconstruction of the petrological and fluid evolution in a comagmatic suite of monzogranites and rare-element granitic pegmatites.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Williams-Jones, Anthony E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m08q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408012f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avx021h122"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Language learning and teaching in Zimbabwe : English as the sole language of instruction in schools : a study of students' use of English in Zimbabwe, their indigenous languages (Shona and Ndebele), and the schools' methods of instruction in secondary school classrooms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Masawi Mugore, Maireva Faustina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study focuses on the use of English as the sole medium of instruction in Zimbabwean schools and the effect of such a policy on the educational achievement of students, particularly in secondary schools. The role of Shona and Ndebele, two other Zimbabwean official languages, in schooling is also examined. Some of the findings reveal a learning and teaching environment that prevents strategies from addressing linguistic, social and cultural development with a coherent workable vision in the English classroom. Because English is the working language of government, business, and industry in Zimbabwe, an English-only policy seems to be a practical means to prepare students for higher education and the workforce. The growing status of English as an international lingua franca provides additional support for such a policy. This study reveals the need to rethink the imposition of an English-only policy. The findings indicate that current teaching approaches/methods and materials do not entirely support language development in English, largely because they do not take into account the economic, social, and linguistic situations of the students. The study supports and calls for a multifaceted approach to the way language is currently taught in Zimbabwe, and sees this as one way secondary schools can produce, through the medium of English instruction, students and teachers who can adapt to rapid change, and relate to people from diverse socio-cultural and linguistic backgrounds. The study emphasizes the integration and expectations of people's views on language and education, as heard and expressed by many respondents. This is considered central to any meaningful effort towards linguistic competence, a challenging but stimulating learning environment, and better communication among students and teachers.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw446.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h122</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Zimbabwe</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494b31j"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Employee empowerment : definition, measurement and construct validation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Menon, Sanjay T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The notion of improving employee productivity and satisfaction through increased work autonomy has led to a variety of managerial practices that seek to enhance employees' sense of control over their work and workplace. One such organizational intervention which has gained currency last decade is empowerment. This thesis is an attempt clearly explicate the precise nature of the empowerment construct through theoretical analysis and empirical investigation. An analysis of the construct of power from a psychological perspective yielded three dimensions of power: power as perceived control, power as perceived competence and power as being energized toward valued goals. Based on this analysis and a review of existing literature on empowerment, the empowered state was defined as a cognitive state perceived control, perceived competence and goal internalization. Building on this definition, a number of antecedents and of empowerment were examined leading to theoretical propositions and testable hypotheses. The empirical test of the proposed theoretical framework was carried out in two stages. Phase I was devoted to the development of a psychometrically sound measure of empowerment. Phase II was concerned with construct validation through the testing of hypotheses relating the empowerment construct to other established constructs. The empirical results supported the view that empowerment is a construct conceptually distinct from other constructs such as delegation, self-efficacy and intrinsic task motivation. The proposed multi-dimensional nature of empowerment was also strongly supported. In addition, organizational and job level context factors as well as select managerial behaviors were identified as possibile antecedents of empowerment. Empowerment was also found to be significantly related to a number of outcome variables including job satisfaction, job involvement and organizational commitment. The thesis concludes with implications for managerial practices and suggestions for future research.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kanungo, R. N. .</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks378.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494b31j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Employee empowerment</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7d278w175"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization and functional studies of the mouse biliary glycoprotein (Bgp) genes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nédellec, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Adhesion molecules are present throughout embryonic development and during several physiological and pathological processes. Biliary glycoproteins (Bgp) are cell adhesion molecules that belong to the carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) family, a member of the Ig supergene family. In an attempt to develop a relevant mouse model, we characterized the gene organization, regulation and expression patterns of the mouse Bgp1 gene. The mouse Bgp1 gene is down-regulated upon tumor transformation. This phenomenon has been correlated with a change in the methylation state of the promoter region of the mouse Bgp1 gene. Two other Cea-related genes, called the Bgp2 and Bgp3 genes, that also belong to the mouse Bgp gene family according to their deduced amino acid sequences and phylogenetic analyses, have also been characterized. Thus, three Bgp genes exist in the mouse genome while a unique BGP gene is found in the human genome. We have demonstrated that the Bgp2 gene product can also act in vitro as an alternative receptor for the mouse hepatitis virus. However, the expression pattern of the mouse Bgp2 gene is less abundant in the colon which is the natural route for MHV infection. Interestingly, the mouse Bgp3 gene presents a gene organization that resembles that of the pregancy specific (Psg) genes, another Cea-related gene subgroup. Expression patterns as well as phylogenetic studies suggest that the Bgp3 gene may represent an evolutionary link between the Cea subgroup and the Psg subgroup. The question remains open regarding the role of Bgp either during embryogenesis and during tumor development. Our studies on the different mouse Bgp gene expression and organization will render a gene ablation approach possible.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beauchemin, Nicole</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t407.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w175</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj9602278f"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of analytical techniques and mechanistic studies related to the thermal decomposition of Amadori rearrangement products from secondary amines</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Huyghues-Despointes, Alexis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Standards of Amadori rearrangement products (ARP) were synthesized for the purpose of developing analytical techniques and performing mechanistic studies related to their thermal decomposition. Several synthetic strategies were explored. An HPLC analytical system with a diode array detector was coupled to a fluorometer and an electrochemical detector, in order to detect simultaneously and on-line, a wide variety of degradation products of ARPs and to follow their kinetics. The potential of such a system to analyze complex Maillard mixtures was demonstrated. The kinetics of the reaction of glucose with morpholine (a Strecker inactive analogue of proline was used in order to simplify the kinetics) to produce Amadori morpholine was studied under experimental conditions that minimize side reactions and maximize Amadori product formation. At specific time intervals, the samples were analyzed for the presence of reactants and Amadori product by the multidetector HPLC system. Color and fluorescence were also measured. The data obtained were used to calculate the rate constants for the formation and degradation of Amadori product. A mechanistic model that statistically fitted the kinetic data was proposed. To further understand the details of the decomposition mechanism of Amadori proline, different mass spectrometric experiment were performed. High resolution, linked-field scan and neutral loss experiments have indicated that 1-((2$ sp prime$-carboxyl)pyrrolidinyl)-1-deoxy- scD-fructose (Proline Amadori product) followed two main pathways of fragmentation under electron impact conditions; one initiated by the ring oxygen and the other by the amino acid nitrogen, producing two well stabilized fragment ions; oxonium and imminium ions. In addition, ortho-elimination reactions initiated by O or N-centered radical sites were shown to produce the most intense peaks and diagnostically important ions for the identification of Amadori products. However this approach can only pro</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yaylayan, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/000002062.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602278f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Amino acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>High performance liquid chromatography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Maillard reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fructose</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655j54v"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patterns of interlimb coordination during asymmetrical reaching movements</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hatzitaki, Vassilia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study investigated the patterns of interlimb organization during the concurrent performance of asymmetrical reaching movements. The inherent tendency towards interlimb synchronization often constrains activities requiring the two limbs to move over different distances or at different movement speeds. The study of bimanual coordination has shown that the amount of interlimb interference during bilateral performance of asymmetrical actions, is regulated according to the magnitude characteristics of the variable used to introduce the asymmetry between the limbs. The purpose of the present study was to examine the relationship between the degree of interlimb decoupling and the magnitude of the asymmetry between the limbs. Asymmetry was systematically manipulated by scaling the magnitude of the interlimb difference in final target distance, during bimanual performance of reaching movements. The degree of interlimb decoupling was reflected in the movement time, muscle activity onset and joint torque relationship between the limbs. Decoupling of the asymmetrical limb movements was effected by an earlier onset of the antagonist muscles in the constrained limb which scaled the amount of muscle torque production and therefore the stiffness of the limb during the acceleration phase of the movement. Thus, the movement amplitude differentiation was achieved by an initial accelarative impulse attributed to the differential control of the muscle torque production at each joint. On the other hand, the interactive forces played a secondary role in the degree of decoupling process. Overall, the degree of decoupling scaled according to the magnitude of the interlimb difference in distance; the greater the asymmetry, the greater the differentiation between the limbs. However, systematic variations of the interlimb asymmetry in distance gave rise to a wide variety of individual decoupling trends. Bimanual practice of the asymmetrical reaching tasks did not result in the development of more independent limb movements. The results of the present study have implications to human factor design and ergonomics.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hoshizaki, T. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x582w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j54v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arm -- Movements</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arm -- Muscles</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r511j"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Silyhydrazines : chemistry and pyrolytic conversion to Si-N-C ceramic materials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>He, Jiliang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new synthetic route to silylhydrazine molecules and polymers has been developed by the heterodehydrocoupling of organosilanes with hydrazines. A dimethyltitanocene catalyst has been employed to facilitate the dehydrocoupling reaction. The dehydrocoupling was shown to proceed by stepwise replacement of Si-H with hydrazino groups. The controlled hydrolysis of Ph$ sb2$Si(NHNHMe)$ sb2$ formed a hydrazinodisiloxane. Cyclizations of Ph$ sb2$Si(NHNHMe)$ sb2$ to form cyclic silylhydrazines were achieved by the reaction with n-BuLi/Ph$ sb2$SiCl$ sb2,$ or MeI (or HCl or Ph$ sb2$SiCl$ sb2),$ or thermolysis. Crystal structures of Ph$ sb2$Si(NHNR)(NRNH)SiPh$ sb2$ (R = H, Me) reveal chair (R = H) and twist-boat (R = Me) conformations of the Si$ sb2$N$ sb4$ ring, respectively. Planar and pyramidal nitrogen geometries were found to coexist in a hydrazino unit. A preceramic polymer, synthesized by the polymerization of MeHSiCl$ sb2$ with hydrazine in an appropriate ratio, was pyrolyzed to Si$ sb3$N$ sb4$/SiC$ rm sb{x}$N$ rm sb{y}$ in 67-80% ceramic yields. It is proposed that the structural unit of this polymer is a tetraazadisilacyclohexane bridged by MeHSi groups. This assignment is based on $ sp{1}$H and $ sp{29}$Si NMR measurements, as well as by comparison with the well-defined reaction product of Me$ sb2$Si(NHNH) $ sb2$SiMe$ sb2$ with MeHSiCl$ sb2.$ The pyrolysis was carried out from room temperature to 1500$ sp circ$C under argon and studied by using thermogravimetric analysis, solid-state $ sp{29}$Si NMR spectroscopy, infrared spectroscopy, x-ray powder diffraction, and elemental analysis. Serial structural changes were characterized in the pyrolyzed solid products. The ceramic product of this polymer at 1100$ sp circ$C was found to possess a quasi-metallic electrical conductivity ($ sigma$ = 10$ sp3$ ($ Omega$cm)$ sp{{-}1}),$ and was evaluated as an electrode material.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Harrod, John F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b166.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r511j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ans0647740"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Seismic design and retrofit of coupled walls using structural steel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Harries, Kent A. (Kent Alexander)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The reversed cyclic loading responses of reinforced concrete walls coupled with steel beams are investigated. Four full-scale segments of coupled walls having both "shear critical" and "flexure critical" steel coupling beams with their ends embedded in the walls were tested. The reversed cyclic loading responses of these specimens are compared with those of conventionally reinforced and diagonally reinforced concrete coupling beams. Design and detailing guidelines are proposed for both the steel coupling beams and the reinforced concrete embedment regions. Non-linear dynamic analyses of prototype coupled wall structures, comparing conventional and diagonal reinforcement details with the proposed flexure and shear critical steel coupling beams are presented. Four full-scale reversed cyclic loading tests of shear deficient reinforced concrete coupling beams were conducted to study efficient ways of retrofitting these beams. An unretrofitted control specimen and three specimens with different retrofit details were tested. The retrofit procedure investigated involved applying steel plates to one side of the coupling beams to determine ways of increasing the shear strength of the beams such that the nominal flexural capacity may be attained. Different methods of attaching the retrofit plates using structural epoxy and mechanical anchor bolts are investigated. A method for determining the influence of the steel plate retrofit on the shear capacity of the beam is developed. Non-linear dynamic analyses comparing the structural responses of unretrofitted and retrofitted prototype structures are also presented.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mitchell, Denis</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm82w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647740</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw0892c776"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Social-class gradient in childhood asthma : the nature of the link and issues of measurement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Demissie, Kitaw, 1960-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objectives of this thesis were: (i) to examine the relationship and the nature of the link of socioeconomic status (SES) to an objective indicator of childhood asthma; (ii) to quantify the agreement between area-based SES measures and SES assessed at the level of the individual; and (iii) to compare the test characteristics of asthma as evidenced by questionnaire, exercise and methacholine challenges without assuming a gold standard. We carried out a cross-sectional study of 989 Montreal elementary school children in an area where there is universal access to medical care through state-funded health insurance. A questionnaire was completed by parents, and the children performed spirometry before and after a free-running exercise challenge. Street address information and parental occupation were used to establish neighborhood and individual-level SES indicators respectively. A sub-sample of 332 children underwent allergy skin and methacholine bronchoprovocation tests, and indoor home measurements of NO$ sb2$, PM$ sb{10}$, dust-mites and various types of moulds were performed. Low SES was associated with an increased likelihood of exercise-induced bronchospasm (EIB), lower FEV$ sb1$ and FVC, but not with FEV$ sb1$/FVC, a measure of airway calibre. With lower SES the likelihood of positive allergy skin tests decreased for cat, trees and grasses but increased for cockroach and moulds. Of the host factors examined, birthweight was positively associated with FVC and FEV$ sb1$ while airway responsiveness to methacholine increased as birthweight decreased. Pre-term birth independent of birthweight was associated with a lower FEV$ sb1$/FVC. Of the environmental factors, increasing exposure to household tobacco smoke and smoking during pregnancy were found to be associated with larger FVC and lower FEV$ sb1$/FVC. The current presence of a cat and lower respiratory infection prior to the age of 2 years (LRI) were associated with EIB. Increasing usual dietary salt intake was also found to be associated with higher methacholine responsiveness. Part of the observed relationship between SES and indicators of asthma was mediated by the indoor environmental pollutants. There was poor agreement between the area-based and the individual-level SES measures even when used to classify children into broad SES categories. Using a Bayesian approach, comparison of the three tests for measuring asthma revealed exercise challenge to perform least well compared to a questionnaire or methacholine provocation in terms of the test characteristics when the purpose was to chose a single test for identifying asthma in community based studies. The results provide evidence suggesting that SES is an important risk factor for childhood asthma. This further suggests that excess morbidity and mortality from asthma in inner city areas of large American cities is not only due to differential access to health care but that under-utilization of health care as well as host, dietary and environmental factors associated with social disadvantage are also important.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq42d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c776</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bd571"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Une question de confiance? : le parlement de Paris et Henri IV, 1589-1599</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Waele, Michel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>From 1589 to 1599, the relation between Henri IV and the Parlement of Paris was a tumultuous one. Some parlementaires associated with the Catholic League refused at first to recognize Henri of Navarre as their king. These magistrates met in Paris until April 1594. Meanwhile, their royalist colleagues congregated in Tours where, in March 1589, Henri III had transferred his sovereign court. From there, the royalist councillors helped Henri IV reconquer his realm. This, they did in spite of his religion, although they frequently asked him to convert to Catholicism. After the reunification of the two rival courts in April 1594, the parlementaires seemed to work as one and blocked the verification of numerous edicts presented by the king. Their opposition was so strong that it has led some historians to claim that it was endangering the State's survival. It slowly faded away after the verification of the Edict of Nantes in February 1599. In a pacified France, the conflicts between a king finally in control of his realm and his parlementaires became rare. The magistrates finally had confidence in the government which seemed to take adequate measures to stabilize France after more than thirty years of civil wars. The difficult relationship between Henri IV and the Parlement of Paris between 1589 and 1599 was not created by the egoistic nature of the magistrates or their incompetence as claimed by numerous historians. If some of the Parlementaires--we will call them the "opportunists"--put their own interests before those of the realm, a majority of their colleagues had a very high idea of their political role within France, an idea based on centuries of relation between the kings of France and the Parlement as well as on the political role of the court as defined by theorists of the time. Confronted to a king they hardly knew, these "traditionalists", on whom this work will be centered, tried to make sure that the interests of the kingdom, its king and its inhabitants were protected. They would not give Henri IV's government the leeway it sought but would scrutinize and frequently block the edicts presented to them, and this until Henri IV proved that he could be trusted as the head of the realm.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boulle, P. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k4579.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd571</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Henry IV, King of France, 1553-1610</dc:subject><dc:subject>France. Parlement (Paris)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xb49m"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of the fungal pathogen, Colletotrichum coccodes (Wallr.) Hughes, on growth, reproduction and competitive ability of velvetleaf (Abutilon theophrasti Medik.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>DiTommaso, Antonio</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Field and growth bench experiments were performed to assess the effect of a selective fungal pathogen of Abutilon theophrasti (velvetleaf) on various aspects of intra- and interspecific competition between this vigorous agricultural weed and soybean (Glycine max). In the absence of the foliar pathogen, Colletotrichum coccodes, A. theophrasti and soybean responded differently to the presence of conspecies or to individuals of the other species. In pure stand, the deleterious effects of intraspecific competition on reproductive output were substantially greater for A. theophrasti than for soybean, especially at lower monoculture densities. In mixtures, however, A. theophrasti reproductive performance was markedly higher than at equivalent monoculture densities, particularly at the lower mixture densities. Soybean reproduction at these lower mixture densities (10 to 20 plants m$ sp{-2}$) was severely curtailed compared with reproductive output at equivalent pure stand densities. A. theophrasti reproductive output was limited more by the presence of conspecies than by the presence of soybean, whereas the opposite trend was observed for soybean. In pure stand, application of C. coccodes had limited impact on either A. theophrasti or soybean yield. However, application of the fungal pathogen in A. theophrasti monocultures caused significant (30-44%) aboveground biomass reductions within five weeks of inoculation, in two of the three years in one field study. Eight weeks following C. coccodes inoculation, A. theophrasti biomass within inoculated monoculture plots did not differ significantly from biomass within uninoculated control plots, although height hierarchies were significantly more developed. In mixtures, C. coccodes applications caused reductions in A. theophrasti growth and reproduction when provided with an adequate dew period. Alternatively, soybean yield losses within inoculated mixture plots were generally lower than for uninoculated control plots, althoug</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Watson, Alan K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws26g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb49m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Phytopathogenic fungi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Colletotrichum coccodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weeds -- Biological control</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214r05r"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theory, design, construction and characterzation of confocal scanning laser microscope configurations</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doukoglou, Tilemachos D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objective of this study was the development of the imaging subsystem of an organ mapping system that would be able to acquire sufficient information for building a 3D cellular level map of a small organ. The imaging subsystem that is presented is a confocal scanning laser microscope arrangement that is versatile and offers a number of different imaging modes, with minimal modifications in the optical configuration, and no need for realignment of optical components. The organ mapping system is a part of a larger project involving the building of a teleoperated microsurgical robot capable of operating on small organs, such as the eye. In this context a second imaging system prototype based again on a scanning laser microscope configuration is presented. The development of this second imaging system is for investigating possible integration of such a device into the surgical microrobot for high resolution image acquisition during operations. The main feature of this system is that the scanning is performed in spherical coordinates; making it suitable and advantageous for imaging organs that exhibit some form of spherical shape, such as the eye. Before the two imaging systems are presented an overview of the theory governing the operation of confocal microscope arrangements is given, together with a simple model based on geometric optics with Gaussian beam weighting that describes the depth response of a confocal arrangement as a function of the detector size. Finally, a detailed analysis of the error due to refractive index mismatches, that can lead to significant dimensional miscalculations when volumetric imaging is performed with a confocal microscope, is also presented.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hunter, Ian W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v85v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r05r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644t510"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of 64 kDa antigen(s) and corresponding autoantibodies in patients with thyroid-associated ophthalmopathy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Zhiguang, 1956-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The ophthalmopathy associated with Graves' hyperthyroidism (GH) and Hashimoto's thyroiditis is an autoimmune-mediated inflammation of extraocular muscle and orbital connective tissue. The association of thyroid-associated ophthalmopathy (TAO) with autoimmune thyroid disease (ATD) can be explained by the expression on thyroid and eye muscle of shared or cross-reactive Ag(s) targeted by autoimmunity. The best candidate for such Ag(s), at present, are 64 kDa membrane molecules. When incubated with cultured human eye muscle, thyroid, and skeletal muscle cells in vitro, autoAbs in TAO patient sera immunoprecipitated a 64 kDa Ag from the first two tissues, but not from skeletal muscle. In dot blot experiments using D1 fusion protein, a fragment of a cloned 64 kDa protein, autoAbs were detected in the sera of 47% of patients with TAO and 57% of those with GH without ophthalmopathy but in only 5% of normal subjects. Short random fragments (100 to 200 bp) of 1D cDNA, a cloned 64 kDa protein, were cloned an expressed in E. coli as fusion proteins using the pUEX1 vector. Four antigenic peptides recognized by TAO sera were cloned and sequenced. When a panel of sera was screened for recognition of each peptides, sera from TAO patients reacted to one or more peptides significantly more frequently than sera from normal controls. A quantitative reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) methodology was used to investigate the tissue distribution of 1D mRNA and quantitate the levels of expression of transcripts of this specificity from a variety of human tissues. Expression of 1D was highest in thyroid and eye muscle, consistent with a high level of expression of this protein in these tissues. These studies indicate that 64 kDa proteins are expressed in eye muscle and thyroid, and that autoAbs reactive with the Ag(s) are present in the early stages of thyroid eye disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bernard, Nicole F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp32w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t510</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Ophthalmology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741t674"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Long-distance dependencies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zushi, Mihoko</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis proposes a modification of Chomsky's (1992) theory of locality to deal with restructuring phenomena which allow an apparent violation of the locality condition on certain local processes. Various restructuring phenomena including long-distance NP movement exemplified by long-distance Object Preposing (Chapter 2) and long-distance head movement exemplified by clitic climbing (Chapter 3) are examined cross linguistically. Long-distance anaphora (Chapter 4) are also examined based on the view the locality on various types of anaphor-antecedent relationships follow from the theory of movement. It is argued that the peculiar behavior of restructuring constructions in terms of locality follows from the lexical properties of restructuring verbs that allows a defective Tense to occur in the complement clause. The following effects result: (i) Case checking within the embedded clause becomes impossible; (ii) the defective Tense triggers incorporation of the infinitive verb into the matrix verb. As a result, the embedded element that requires Case is forced to raise into the matrix clause as a last resort operation, hence motivation long-distance movement. In order to reconcile long-distance movement with the economy principle which requires chain links to be minimal, this thesis refines Chomsky's (1992) theory of locality. The proposed hypothesis claims that the locality condition on certain operations such as NP movement and head movement follows from the economy principle in such a way that an element can move to the closest position in which its morphological requirement can be satisfied. This notion of the shortest movement is further clarified in that the domain in which the shortest movement requirement is satisfied can be extended if there is an appropriate linked chain formed by head movement. The proposed system not only provides principled account for the phenomena of restructuring, but also has some important implications for the notion of economy of derivation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, Mark</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t387n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t674</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Syntax</dc:subject><dc:subject>Minimalist theory (Linguistics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anaphora (Linguistics)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amk61rk082"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reform and discontent : the causes of the 1989 Chinese student movement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhao, Dingxin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The central argument of this thesis is that a series of China's state policies, before and during the reform era, were conducive to the rise of the 1989 Chinese Student Movement (CSM). The most important of these were (1) leftist policies during Mao's era which fostered the formation of pro-democratic yet impractical intellectuals and created a university ecology that was remarkably conducive to student movements, and (2) the state-led reform which over produced students on the one hand, and blocked upward mobility channels for intellectuals and students on the other hand. These and other conducive factors to the rise of the 1989 CSM were not simply state mistakes. To a large extent, they were characteristic of the regime. The thesis does not reject non-state centered factors such as anomic feelings toward uncertainties brought by the reform, the conflict between reformers and hardliners within the Chinese Communist Party (CCP), the rise of civil society during the eighties, the impact of Western ideologies following the open door policy or the intrinsic character of Chinese culture, that have all been hitherto proposed to explain the rise of the CSM. Rather, it incorporates these explanations under a state-centered paradigm in light of a general model (the DSSI model) that I am proposing to explain the general causes, and to a lesser extent, the dynamics of large scale social movements.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rytina, Steven</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pinard, Maurice</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m5957.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk082</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>China -- Politics and government -- 1976-2002</dc:subject><dc:subject>Higher education and state -- China -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>China -- History -- Tiananmen Square Incident, 1989</dc:subject><dc:subject>Student movements -- China -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject><dc:subject>Students -- China -- Political activity -- History -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1c18dh67j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dimensions of repetition and negative affect in dreams and their relation to psychological well-being</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zadra, Antonio L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Six studies are presented whose combined goals were to investigate the relationship between the dimensions of repetition and negative affect in dreams, dream content measures, and measures of well-being. Study 1 presents the results of a content analysis of childhood and adult recurrent dreams. Study 2 showed that recurrent dreamers score lower on measures of well-being and report more negative dream content than both past-recurrent dreamers and non-recurrent dreamers. Study 3 showed that people who experience recurrent dream themes report low levels of well-being and negative dream content, but not to the extent shown by people with recurrent dreams. Underlying assumptions of commonly proposed definitions for nightmares were tested in Study 4. Study 5 showed that people with frequent nightmares score lower on indices of well-being than people with frequent bad dreams, who score lower than control subjects. Study 6 presents five cases of recurrent nightmare sufferers who were treated successfully with lucid dreaming.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donderi, D. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r59q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dh67j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nightmares</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lucid dreams</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dreams</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As1784n60r"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The chemistry of cyclopentadienyl ruthenium disulfanes, 2-oxodisulfanes and 2-dioxodisulfanes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trojansek, Darlene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The complexes CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SR(Cp = $ eta sp5$-cyclopentadienyl; R = 4-C$ sb6 rm H sb4$Me, C$ rm sb6H sb5, CH sb2C sb6H sb5$) insert sulfur from S$ sb8$ to give CpRu(CO)$ rm sb2S sb{x}$R (x = 1-3) and undergo ligand exchange with R$ rm sp prime sb2S sb{y}$ (y = 2,3) to give CpRu(CO)$ sb2 rm S sb{x}R sp prime$ (x = 1-3). The mechanisms of these reactions are discussed. Treatment of CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SH with the appropriate phthalimide sulfur transfer reagents REphth (phth = phthalimide; E = SS, SS(O); R = 4-C$ rm sb6H sb4Me, C sb6H sb5, CH sb2C sb6H sb5$) gave CpRu(CO)$ sb2$ER. The complexes CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SSR undergo sulfur redistribution in solution to give CpRu(CO)$ rm sb2S sb{x}$R (x = 1-3) and insert sulfur from S$ sb8$ to give CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SSSR. The complexes CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SS(O)R undergo spontaneous oxygen transfer in solution to form CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SSR and CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SS(O)$ sb2$R. The reaction of CpRu(CO)$ sb2$ER (E = S, SS, SS(O)) with PPh$ sb3$ in ambient light gave CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SR. The complexes CpRu(L)(CO)SS(O)$ sb2$R were prepared by oxidation of CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SS(O)CHMe$ sb2$ with NaIO$ sb4$ (L = PPh$ sb3$) and reaction of CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SH with RS(O)$ sb2$Cl (L = CO; R = 4-C$ rm sb6H sb4Me, C sb6H sb5$). The reaction of CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SS(O)$ sb2$R with PPh$ sb3$ gave CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SS(O)$ sb2$R. The x-ray structures of CpRu(CO)$ sb2$SS(O)C$ rm sb6H sb5 and CpRu(CO) sb2SS(O) sb2C sb6H sb5$ were determined. Oxidation of CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SS(O)-4-C$ rm sb6H sb4$Me by dimethyldioxirane (DMDO) gave CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)S(O)$ sb2$S(O)$ sb2$-4-C$ rm sb6H sb4$Me which was immediately hydrolyzed by trace amounts of H$ sb2$O to give CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)S(O)$ sb3$H. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) studies of CpRu(CO)$ sb2$ER (E = S, SS, SS(O), SS(O)$ sb2$) were performed. All of these complexes undergo irreversible sulfur-based oxidations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sauer, Alan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm20m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784n60r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>