<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tc72v"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Employment experience of a group of seizure patients : a descriptive study of the unemployment/employment experiences of ten unemployed and fifteen employed seizure patients who attend the Out-Patient Neurological Clinics of the Montreal Neurological Institute, Montreal, 1963-64</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcella, Paul</ual:dissertant><ual:dissertant>Rose, Anne</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study delineates circumstances contributing to the employment status of a group or twenty-five seizure patients attending the Out-Patient Neurological Clinics of the Montreal Neurological Institute. Certain aspects of the social and employment experiences of ten unemployed and fifteen employed patients are studied in detail. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McNaughton, Francis</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rasmussen, Theodore</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Verity Ross</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Griffin, Cynthia</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d759k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc72v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dz73p"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Behaviour guthathione in citrated human blood during preservation at 5C.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mathai, Claramma K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1888, de Rey Pailhade for the first time described a substance containing sulfur which he had been able to isolate from yeast in an impure state and he called this substance "Philothion". Hopkins in 1921, iso1ated from yeast cells a low molecular weight sulfur containing substance which he named "glutathione". Finding that the compound gave a positive nitroprusside reaction and contained glutamic acid and cysteine he concluded that it probably was a dipeptide of these amino acids. Eight years later Hunter and Eagles questioned the validity of the dipeptide structure and Hopkins was prompted to reinvestigate the constitution of the compound. With the aid of cuprous oxide as a reagent he was able to isolate glutathione as a copper derivative and from it to isolate glutathione itself in a crystalline form. On further analysis he found the substance to be a tripeptide consisting of glutamic acid, cysteine and glycine. Soon afterward Pirie and Pinhey performed for the first time the electrometric titration of the ionizable groups in glutathione and proposed the correct structure of the compound. This finding was confirmed by degradation studies and by the synthesis of the compound by Harington and Mead. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denstedt, O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b458s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz73p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x4720"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Investigative Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Urinary excretion of testosterone in idiopathic hirsutism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mansuwan, Karoon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is a lack of understanding of simple or idiopathic hirsutism concerning both the etiology and the treatment. Even the nature of normal hair growth itself is not completely clarified. Hirsutism has been reported in a variety of conditions. lt may be associated with defects of the pituitary gland, the adrenal gland, the ovary, and the thyroid gland, with genetic defects, central nervous system defects, and other miscellaneous conditions, e.g. pregnancy, burns, anorexia nervosa, dermatomyositis, treatment vith certain drugs, thymic tumor, mumps, teratomata (Brookbank review, 1961).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Browne, J. S. L.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Saffran, J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Giraud, C. J. P.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kalant, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j751.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x4720</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Investigative Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zx754"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of hypothermia on experimental burns</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Manson, Arthur D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis describes investigations of a purely experimental treatment for severe burns, and seeks to relate the benefits of such treatment to the accepted pathophysiological principles of burn sickness. In particular it dwells on the eftect of hypothermia on the scalded rat in terms of mortality, development of shock, and postburn toxicity. The work was stimulated by certain observations made by Dr. N. G. Foy, reported in his Master of Science thesis of 1963, at McGill University. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacMillan, C. W.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Trank, J. W.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Woolhouse, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g129b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zx754</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440x322"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Transplantability of the tumour of the thyroid gland of Fischer rat induced by a continuous low iodine diet</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mandavia, Mansukhlal G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Removing a tissue from one site and placing it in another in the same animal, or a similar or a different site in another animal is known as grafting or transplanting. The transplanted tissue can be a complete organ like a kidney, or a part of an organ or cells which may be normal or malignant. Bec au se the technique is usually simple and can be applied to any organ or any animal it has a very wide appeal. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nadler, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z874d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440x322</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pr27v"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Irreducibility of polynomials</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mahatabuddin, Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In many mathematical investigations such as determination of degree of a field extension, determination of the Galois group etc. the knowledge of ineducibility of a polynomial f(x),or if reducible the nature of the irreducible factors of f(x)are desired. We wish to give here a brief survey of the polynomial domain, factorisation in such a domain and the criteria by which non factorisability of a polynomial in such a domain can be determined. We shall try to make the contents self supporting and self explanatory as much as possible within the scope of our present work. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schwerdtfeger, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj334.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pr27v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Polynomials</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v838402q"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology and Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Migration and occupational mobility from a Nova Scotia coal mining town</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Magill, Dennis W.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Rapid and continued social change is a predominant feature of modern Canadian society. Indeed, one of the outstanding characteristics of our society is its complex and diversified economic growth since the end of the Second World War. One of the consequences of this growth is the opening of new resources: oil, natural gas,and uranium. However, the development of these natural resources has affected older, more firmly established industries, such as coal mining.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roseborough, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf363.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838402q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Labor mobility -- Nova Scotia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Migration, Internal -- Nova Scotia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mg38n"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Zoology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The annual cycle of certain calanoid species in West Greenland</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maclellan, Delphine C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The West Greenland coast is a typical fjord region with a considerable development of local deepwater basins. The majority of the West Greenland fjords are of the typcial bottom configuration, with a well-developed threshold at the mouth, which normally rises to within 100 or 200 m of the surface. Such a fjord has been named an "Arctic" type fjord by Stephensen (1916), because the bottom water is arctic in character, having a negative temperature and low salinity. Ameralik fjord (Latitude 64o 3' N., Longitude 52o 30' W.) (map) is in this category. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dunbar, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w813h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mg38n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Copepoda -- Greenland</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calanoida</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahd76s376t"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the structure of cytochrome c.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lustgarten, Jack A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Between 1882 and 1886, the Irish physician MacMunn focused attention on myohaematin or histohaematin, a pigment which he identified by spectroscopy in muscle and other tissue of various animal species. He noted the appearance of four bands in the visual spectrum upon simple chemical reduction and their disappearance after reoxidation. In muscle, he regarded this substance as separate and distinct from haemoglobin (myoglobin) and he concluded that it was involved in cellular respiration. Unfortunately, MacMunn's findings were severely criticized by some contemporaries and,therefore, remained forgotten until Keilin rediscovered and named it cytochrome, some forty years later. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J. H.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Scholefield, P. G.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Margoliash, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1072552.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s376t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247dw79h"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the validity of the resonance approximation to three particle states</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Luke, Trevor MacDonald</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This work examines the validity of an approximation commonly used to simplify the study of scattering processes at energies above one or more production thresholds. The approximation consists of replacing three particle states by states containing two particles, one of which is a resonance between two of the original three; the resonance is regarded as an ordinary stable particle. The approximation is tested in a modified form of the Lee model, which is sufficiently simple to admit explicit calculation and comparison of "exact" and "resonance approximation" cross sections. the indication of this model calculation is that the approximation is a reasonably good one. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Margolis, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w814s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw79h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av405sd95t"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Investigative Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biosynthesis of steroids by the rat adrenal using radioactive precursors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lucis, Ruta</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mammalian adrenal cortex morphologically is arranged into three zones: the outer layer, called zona glomerulosa,the middle layer where cells are arranged in more radial fashion called zona faseiculata and the innermost layer bordering the medulla is called zona reticularis. This classification originates with the studies of Arnold in 1866. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Browne, J. S. L.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Venning, E. H.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Carballeira, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074z55n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd95t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Investigative Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386p027"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on brain gangliosides: I. the preparation, isloation and properties of brain gangliosides II. The effect of hypercapnia on gangliosides III. Localization of gangliosides in neurones</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lowden, J. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study of neurochemistry has tended to follow two main pathways. One of these, the isolation and characterization of the constituents of nervous tissue, had its beginnings over eighty years ago in the laboratory of J.L.W. Thudicum, the "Father of Neurochemistry". The other path has led to studies of the metabolism of nervous tissue, both in vitro and in vivo. It is the aim of most neurochemists to bring these two divergent paths into a closer alignment in arder to gain inaight into the unique function of this important tissue. The studies described in this thesis also follow two different paths. It is hoped that these two approaches complement each ether, however, and lead to a better understanding of the chemistry and the functional role of the gangliosides in nervous tissue. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elliott, K. A. C.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Wolfe, L. S.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mathieson, Gordon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Branch, Charles</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pappius, Hanna M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p666.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386p027</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xz57t"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Sacred Theology</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Divinity</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>God and necessity : an evaluation of the concept of necessity as applied to divine essence and existence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lochhead, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis seeks to evaluate the use of the concept "necessity" in the Christian doctrine of God. The concept is used frequently in discussions of God's existence. Traditional theism differentiates between God and the world with specific reference to this notion. God exists necessarily: the world, contingently. Not only is "necessity" used by classical theism in relation to the divine existence, but to God's nature as well. The doctrine of the immutability of God excludes all contingency from his nature. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Evans, D. D.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Gombay, A.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>McLelland, J. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr284.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xz57t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ontology</dc:subject><dc:subject>God</dc:subject><dc:subject>Divinity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap26770203"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Acoustic power measurement in a reverberant room</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leong, Kwok Onn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the most active fields of Applied Acoustics is Noise Control. In this field, the concept of sound power is employed extensively. If the sound power of a noise source is known, then the prediction of the sound pressure level in an area at a distance from the source is made possible. The ability to predict noise levels in a given area is prerequisite to planning for noise control. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thorpe, D.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Howes, F. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042x573.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p26770203</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apk02cf37c"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The influence of strain rate on clay soil strength</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leitch, Hugh Corley</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents the account of an investigation into the effects of the rate of strain used in testing on the measured shear strength characteristics of three types of clay soils. The investigation consisted of undrained triaxial testing of specimens of each type of clay under varying conditions of cell pressure and strain rate. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zv09d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf37c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m292b"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Foster Radiation Laboratory</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A high energy neutron spectrometer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leighton, Henry George</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A proton recoil spectrometer designed to measure neutron spectra in the energy range of 50 MeV to 100 MeV has been built. An attempt was made to improve the energy resolution of this spectrometer as compared to other spectrometers of a similar type by using a scintillator as the converter in which the neutron-proton collisions take place. The spectrometer was used to measure the neutron spectra from aluminum, water, and heavy water targets. Because of the low counting rates, the resolution of the instrument was not tested. Improvements to the experimental arrangement are discussed and a comparison made between this instrument and a time-of-flight spectrometer.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bell, R. E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mb36k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m292b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17cx73g"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regge trajectories from a variational principle</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leibbrandt, George</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new procedure, the variational method, is proposed for the evaluation of Regge trajeotories from the nonrelativistic SchrOdinger equation. The general region of validity in the L-plane is defined. Using a simplified trial wave function, a number of calculations are then performed for various strengths of an attractive Yukawa potential and the results plotted as Regge curves. In order to check the numerical calculations for large and very small energies, a derivation of asymptotic formulae for each trajectory is also included, together with several tables of resulta. It is found that the variational method is useful and relatively simple, but less accurate than other existing techniques. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sharp, R. T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hg58c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx73g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9c67wr26t"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Liability for nuclear damage caused by flight instrumentalities</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Roy Skwang</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Because of the enormous capacity of nuclear energy, this force is beneficially employed in many different ways. Among these applications, power generation for electricity and propulsion is most important. As the uses of these materials increase, so does the number of transactions, especially among nations. To preserve energy and to save time and money, certain radioactive materials are transported by air and as nuclear activity advances, so will the number of air carriages. To provide for economic and distant space travel, experiments have been undertaken to develop nuclear power propulsion in flight instrumentalities, both in spacecraft and aircraft, in order to overcome the difficulties of chemical fuels. Because of the ultrahazardous nature of the materials and the potential catastrophic damage involved, attention has been given to the question of liability. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cohen, Maxwell</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Sand, P.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Vlasic, I.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913t340.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wr26t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air &amp; Space Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sh08s"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of linear process dynamics by means of integral equation models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Howard Chong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A method has been developed for identifying linear processes having one input and one output in the presence of noise, with the assumption that some a priori knowledge of the process dynamics is available. The method fits an integral equation model to the observed input and output of the process using the principle of least squares. The model parameters together with the initial conditions of the output are determined simultaneously without requiring a test signal. This method has been applied to identify various types of process dynamics, including three hand-drawn unit-impulse responses, by simulation on a digital computer. During this study both the a priori knowledge and the output signal-to-noise ratio of the process were varied. A process con be accurately identified within a fraction of its settling time for a reasonable signal-to-noise ratio at the output. For the case of using a model with more parameters than necessary, the estimates of the unwanted parameters are approximately zero, provided that (a) the noise level is low, and (b) all these unwanted parameters are in either the numerator or the denominator of the model transfer function. Also, a relatively fast time-varying process has been successfully identified in the presence of noise. The results indicate that this method is particularly effective when low order models are selected. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milsum, J. H.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>d'Ombrain, G. L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx94m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sh08s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axd07gx206"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On cylindrical detonation waves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Benedict Huk Kun</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A theoretical and experimental investigation of cylindrical detonation waves have been carried out. In the theoretical phase of this investigation, the dynamics of the combustion products behind a cylindrical detonation wave is analysed by extending the Taylor-Zeldovich model of the spherical case. Based on the conservation of mass, it is shown that when the reaction zone thickness is not small compared to the radius, a steady detonation wave cannot exist. A study of the initiation mechanisms of a cylindrical detonation wave shows that it must be initially over-driven and for large radius, the Chapman-Jouguet hypothesis is satisfied. In the experimental phase of this investigation, the detonation velocities in acetylene-oxygen mixtures with different chemical compositions (20% - 60% acetylene by volume) are determined by using ionization probes. The critical energy for spark ignition is also determined. Vertical slit streak photographs and pressure measurements are taken at different radii from the ignition source to verify that the cylindrical detonation wave is initially over-driven. Pressure measurements of the combustion products are also taken and compared with the theoretical values based on the similarity solution. The problem of transition from cylindrical deflagration to detonation, and the phenomena of spinning and pulsations are also investigated. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wu, J. H. T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58ph43m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx206</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zr93v"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics and Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pricing railway freight services in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leclerc, Wilbrod</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the last ten years, the railways generally throughout the world have suffered a decline in their share of the transportation market relatively to other modes of transportation. This has meant a serious loss of business which has led to many financial difficulties. This loss of a share of the market has come about despite the lasting importance of the railways generally in the economy, despite their necessity in economic development and despite their continued progress in technology. Should the railway situation continue to deteriorate, transportation systems could be endangered seriously. In this thesis, a reform of railway pricing policies is proposed as an important contribution to the solution of the present railway problem. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beach, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q9720.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zr93v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Railroads -- Freight -- Rates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Economics &amp; Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac247dw808"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French Language and Literature</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le camp de concentration dans le roman français de 1945 à 1962</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lazar, Judith Nemes</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La seule mention d'un camp de concentration évoque instinctivement Auschwitz, Dachau, Bergen-Belsen, Büchenwald Ravensbrück... Ces noms restent gravés dans l'esprit contemporain. Par définition, toutefois, n'importe quel enclos qui emprisonne ou enferme des réfugiés, des prisonniers, ou même des étrangers hostiles, est un camp de concentration. Mais à cause des évènements historiques ce sont ces camps d'extermination qui nous reviennent à l'esprit. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Launay, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913t358.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw808</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Concentration camps in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w580b"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Soil Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Soluble constituents and ion exchange reactions of Champlain sea sediments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laventure, Reginald S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Champlain Sea sediments are the parent materials of some of the most important agricultural soils of Quebec. They contain a high proportion of clay-size particles which are primary minerals derived from igneous and metamorphic rocks. The mineralogy and mode of deposition give rise to unusual properties. The physical properties of these sediments have stimulated many studies of their geotechnical properties but only limited information is available for chemical properties. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henneberry, G. O.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Warkentin, B. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vm480.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w580b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Soil Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq237hw15q"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Botany</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of cobalt on the response of sections of etiolated pea epicotyls to plant growth regulators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lau, Crystal Suit-Ching</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lowther and Boll in the study of the effect of 2,4,5-TCPAA on etiolated bean leaf discs observed that inhibition of expansion at low concentrations was relieved at high concentrations where growth was equal to that of the light plus Co control. This means that at appropriate concentrations, TCPAA completely replaced Co in the expansion of light-treated leaf discs. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boll, W. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720h35s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw15q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plants -- Effect of cobalt on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject><dc:subject>Growth (Plants)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Etiolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plant regulators</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f462872g"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Investigative Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Corticoid production by the regenerated adrenal of rats with and without hypertension</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Laplante, Charlotte T.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The elusive role of the adrenal cortex in hypertension has recently been depicted in the following analogy: "The adrenal cortex is like a lady who has kept bad company and late hours for so long that, human nature being what it is, she must have sinned. Testimony has been brought against her, however, only by her few suitors who had adrenal hyperplasia or adrenal tumors. Her other friends have refrained from talking. Perhaps this is because they are gentlemen; or perhaps it is only that they do not have much to talk about." [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stachenko, J.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Cleghorn, R. A.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Rose, Alan</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hillman, Donald</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Giroud, C. J. P.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Chappel, C. I.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Browne, J. S. L.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hartroft, S.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Despointes, R.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Hartroft, P. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf64w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462872g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Investigative Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>