<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236272v"><ual:graduationDate>1988</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The characteristics of titanium tetrachloride plasmas in a transferred-arc systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tsantrizos, Panayotis G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A stable transferred arc was produced with plasmagas containing up to 20 percent molar TiCl$ sb4$ in argon, helium and argon/hydrogen mixtures. This was achieved by replacing the commonly-used thoriated tungsten cathode tip with a tantalum carbide tip. Thus, corrosive reactions at the cathode surface, which were shown to be the cause of the observed instability, were prevented. This allowed the characteristics of stable titanium tetrachloride plasmas in a transferred arc reactor to be investigated. Furthermore, an investigation was conducted into the feasibility of collecting titanium metal from the dissociated TiCl$ sb4$ molecule in the plasmagas. The titanium metal was collected in a molten bath, which also served as the anode in the transferred arc system. Three anode bath compositions were used in this study. Two of them, namely titanium and zirconium, were not able to reduce recombined titanium subchlorides in the bath. The third aluminum, was a reducing bath. When aluminum was used, about 60 percent of all titanium fed into the reactor was collected. Finally, phenomena occurring on the surface of a thoriated tungsten cathode were studied in a transferred-arc reactor using argon or helium as the plasmagas. The effect of cathode geometry on the rate and mechanisms of cathode erosion were investigated. It was shown that the surface temperature of flat-tip cathodes operating in argon is near the melting point of tungsten. On the other hand, the surface temperature of flat-tip cathodes operating in helium and pointed-tip cathodes operating in either helium or argon are near the boiling point of tungsten. Some of the material vapourized from the cathode was redeposited on the cathode surface, forming crystals whose morphology and composition depended on their distance from the arc root and the plasmagas composition.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gauvin, W. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j944.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236272v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Metals -- Effect of high temperatures on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Titanium tetrachloride</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasma jets</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612p33b"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of the repressor gene product (c) and the immunity region of Mu-like transposable bacteriophage D108</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levin, David Bernard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Transposable elements are discrete segments of DNA capable of moving, or transposing, from one location to another in host cell DNA. The Escherichia coli, temperate, generalized transducing bacteriophages D108 and Mu are highly homologous, and their linear, double-stranded, 37 Kilobase pair genomes are propagated by multiple rounds of DNA transposition. They are, however, non-homologous in the region of their genomes that regulate transposition. We have cloned both the wild-type $(c sp+)$ and thermo-sensitive (c ts10) D108 repressor genes and the thermo-sensitive (c ts62) Mu repressor gene under the control of the lac UV5 promotor. We localized the functional D108 repressor gene and found that the wild-type and thermo-sensitive D108 repressor gene products have apparent molecular weights that are smaller (19 Kilodaltons (KDa)) than the thermo-sensitive Mu repressor gene product (22.5 KDa). Using gel electrophoresis band-retardation assays, we found that the D108 and Mu thermo-sensitive repressors display different DNA-binding properties. The D108 repressor protects a single 77 bp region from exonuclease III hydrolysis and DNase I cleavage. We mapped the sites of transcription initiation for both the D108 repressor gene and the D108 early region operon. Finally, we determined that the host protein, Integration Host Factor (IHF), is required for D108 lytic growth and that it protects from DNase I cleavage, a sequence that lies within the D108 repressor operator. Our results suggest that the role of the D108 repressor may be to repress early operon expression, and thus lytic growth, by preventing the binding of the transcriptional activator protein IHF.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf46q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p33b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jr900"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Islamization and the Khojah Ismāʻīlī community in Pakistan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rattansi, Diamond</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Muslims of Pakistan and other countries such as Egypt are groping for ways to change their situation. The phenomenon of Islamic Resurgence in Pakistan is one major expression of this frantic desire of the Muslims to improve their lot through the acquisition of the control of the nation's political machinery. This political concern is something new and volatile. It has affected the life of Pakistan as a whole and that of the various Muslim groups within it. The Khojah Isma$ sp{ rm c}$ili response to the process of Islamization in Pakistan is reflected in their re-thinking of many aspects of religious traditions and beliefs, mainly those related to the concept of religious authority. The transition in the community's self-definition is that from the emphasis on its inherited traditional beliefs concerning the authority of the Imam to a posture more accommodating to the ethos of Pakistani Islam. Tensions have been generated as a consequence of this tradition, as well as social and economic mechanisms to cushion these tensions. The nature of Isma$ sp{ rm c}$ili response to the changing situation can be grasped through the understanding of their religious beliefs.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h512q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr900</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Khojahs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ismailites -- Pakistan -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam -- Pakistan -- 20th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acc08hg13s"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Strontium dissolution in liquid aluminum and A356 alloys</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pekgüleryüz, Mihriban Özden</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The dissolution mechanism and kinetics of a number of strontium master alloys in liquid aluminum and A356 alloys have been investigated. The dissolution behaviour of the strontium alloys was found to show marked differences depending on strontium content. Dilute strontium alloys containing less than 63 weight percent Sr were observed to exhibit simple dissolution in both melts. The dissolution rate and the recoveries of these alloys were found to increase with increasing melt temperature. Over the temperature interval of 675-775$ sp circ$C dissolution was determined to be mass-transfer controlled with associated activation energies of 10-20 kcal/mole. Experimental rate constants for dissolution showed good agreement with a mass transfer correlation expressed as k = (0.67(Gr.Sc)$ sp{1/4}$ + 0.58(h/r)) (D/h). The dissolution of high strontium master alloys $(&gt;$63 wt. pct. Sr), unlike the dilute alloys, was accompanied by the formation of various intermetallics. Additions at low melt temperatures yielded the exothermic formation of those intermetallics that have the lowest Sr content as seen in the relevant phase diagram, i.e., SrAl$ sb4$ in liquid Al and SrAl$ sb2$Si$ sb2$ in liquid A356. Due to low reaction rates at these low melt temperatures, these intermetallics formed as dispersed particles that could easily dissolve in the melt yielding high recoveries. At high melt temperatures, the associated chemical reactions yielded, as products, the higher Sr intermetallics which formed with little or no exothermicity. These intermetallics were observed to be scarcely soluble in the melt resulting in low strontium recoveries. The dissolution times of these alloys were found to show good agreement with calculated values based on a two-stage dissolution model comprising an initial exothermic reaction period and a subsequent free dissolution period. The strontium master alloys were classified in two groups; the high Sr alloys that are efficient at low temperatures of 675-7</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh02k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg13s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aluminum alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liquid aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strontium</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117p56k"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation of seismic performance of concrete frame structures in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paultre, Patrick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Three buildings in Montreal and three buildings in Vancouver were designed for different level of "ductility" according to the 1985 National Building Code of Canada and the 1984 Canadian Concrete Code. Three full scale reinforced concrete specimens representing an exterior beam-column-slab subassemblage of the Montreal structure were tested in order to determine the behaviour of these components. The role of the spandrel beam in limiting the effective slab width and its role in transferring shear to the joint region was investigated. Analytical procedures were developed in order to predict the responses of main structural components to the combined loading effects of axial load, moment and shear. In addition a hysteretic behavioural model was developed in order to account for strength and stiffness degradation as well as pinching of the hysteretic response. The analytical procedures were then used to model the responses of the components of these buildings. Non-linear dynamic analyses were carried out on each building for a series of artificially generated accelerograms. The results of the tests as well as the results of the non-linear dynamic analyses enabled an assessment of the performance of different building designs and an assessment of current code requirements.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g823q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p56k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Concrete construction -- Canada -- Earthquake effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Concrete construction -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Earthquake effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Concrete construction -- British Columbia -- Vancouver -- Earthquake effects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rp351"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Premenstrual depression : a distinct entity?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McMillan, Marcia J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The validity of the Premenstrual Assessment Form (PAF) typological category "Major Depressive Syndrome", as a distinct subtype of premenstrual change, was assessed. The nature of the depression associated with the premenstrual phase was investigated with standardized measures of depression and a test of dysphoric attentional bias derived from Beck's cognitive model of depression. Three subject groups were delineated based on prospective daily ratings: PMD (depression only premenstrually), controls (no depression), and INTD (intermittent depression throughout cycle). The control group did not exhibit a dysphoric attentional bias. The INTD group demonstrated a dysphoric attentional bias both pre- and postmenstrually. The PMD group, despite clinically elevated premenstrual depression levels, failed to show an associated dsyphoric attentional bias. These findings suggest that although PMD and clinical depression share an affective component, they may differ with regard to other features of depression (i.e. cognitive/information processing). As well, phenomenological differences between PMD and clinical depression were suggested by subjects' prospective daily ratings. For confirmed PMD subjects, depressive mood was only one facet of a multidimensional symptom picture which included signs of water retention, breast pain, fatigue, irritability, anxiety, and associated dysmenorrhea. These findings raise questions concerning the construct validity of premenstrual depression (specifically PAF Major Depressive Syndrome) as a distinctive subtype of premenstrual change.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c47t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp351</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Premenstrual syndrome</dc:subject><dc:subject>Menstrual cycle -- Psychological aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akd17ct67q"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A morphological and functional investigation of the enamel organ and enamel in the rat incisor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McKee, Marc Douglas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A morphological and functional investigation of the enamel organ and enamel was carried out on the incisor of the rat. Using transmission electron microscopy and other electron optical techniques, the ultrastructure of enamel hydroxyapatite crystallites and the morphology of the cells of the enamel organ related to these crystallites were examined. In the enamel secretion zone, putative cell communication via matched approaches of rough endoplasmic reticulum to the ameloblast cell membrane was not confirmed. Throughout the enamel organ, extracellular permeability was assessed using radiolabeled proteins as tracers. Regional differences were found, especially related to the two types of maturation ameloblasts. Several modified histochemical techniques were successfully applied to the enamel such that the functional contribution of each type of ameloblast was ascertained. In this way it was demonstrated that several functional cell subpopulations exist and that they can be correlated with different calcium and protein distributions within the enamel. In vivo injection of vinblastine, and in vitro treatments with other drugs, all severely modified the enamel maturation staining pattern and $ sp{45}$Ca uptake. In addition, it was found that ruffle-ended maturation zone ameloblasts possess higher levels of specific transferrin receptor sites relative to smooth-ended ameloblasts, a finding that may be directly related to the deposition of iron within the enamel.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt521.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct67q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524jp41z"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The permeability of the outer membrane of Haemophilus influenzae type b</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vachon, Vincent</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Phospholipids and lipopolysaccharide were purified from Haemophilus influenzae type b and combined by sonication to form liposomes which were impermeable to sucrose and to high molecular weight polysaccharides. When outer membrane proteins were incorporated into such liposomes, they became permeable to saccharides up to a molecular weight of about 1,400 daltons. The outer membrane proteins were fractionated on DEAE-Sepharose. Three protein-containing peaks were eluted from the column. Two of these peaks contained mixtures of proteins while the third peak contained only a single species of protein with a molecular weight of 40,000 daltons (40 kDa). When tested in reconstituted vesicles, only the material from this third peak rendered liposomes permeable to sucrose. The molecular weight exclusion limit for the 40 kDa protein matched the estimate of 1,400 daltons determined for the outer membrane. The relative rates of diffusion of small sugars were determined by measuring the rates of swelling of liposomes reconstituted with the 40 kDa protein. From these rates, a pore diameter of 1.8 nm was estimated using the Renkin equation. The properties of the 40 kDa protein were also studied using black lipid membranes. When added to the aqueous phase which was bathing a lipid bilayer, this protein caused the conductance of the membrane to increase rapidly. At low protein concentrations, the conductance of the membrane increased in a stepwise fashion with an average single-channel conductance of 1.1 nS in 1.0 M KCl. Single-channel experiments were performed with a variety of different salts. The conductance of single channels was proportional to the specific conductance of the aqueous solution which was bathing the membrane. Current through the pores was proportional to the applied voltage, indicating that these pores are not voltage-controlled. The 40 kDa porin was only slightly cation-selective: the pores were about 1.6 times more permeable to potassium ions than to chloride ions. These properties of the 40 kDa porin are those of large water-filled channels and are characteristic of most bacterial porins. The single-channel conductance of the porin is, however, much smaller than might be expected from its exclusion limit or from its pore diameter estimated by the liposome swelling assay.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xj319.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jp41z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A02870w55w"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of growth factors for osteoblasts from human prostatic tissue : implications for the pathogenesis of osteoblastic prostatic cancer metastases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Koutsilieris, Michael N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Prostatic adenocarcinoma is virtually unique in its tendency to produce osteoblastic bone lesions. The hypothesis of the present thesis was that the basis of this osteogenic response to skeletal metastases of prostate cancer is mediated by the production of trophic factors from prostatic tissue. I have therefore examined the mitogenic activity of extracts of human prostatic tissue and of some known growth factors in isolated fetal rat osteoblasts, fetal fibroblasts, and osteoblast-derived rat osteosarcoma cells. The results demonstrate that material with characteristics of peptides can be extracted from prostatic tissue and appears distinct from a variety of known growth factors. Employing reverse-phase and gel permeation high performance liquid chromatography, I was able to obtain several homogeneous peaks of UV absorbance with an apparent selective growth factor activity for cells of the osteoblast phenotype. This novel selective mitogenic activity for osteoblast-like cells was not present in the extracts from all normal and malignant tissue tested other than prostate, and it was absent also from extracts of pre-pubertal prostate. These results demonstrate that the prostate gland contains selective mitogens for osteoblast-like cells, a characteristic which appears to be unique among known mitogens. These mitogens appear furthermore to be androgen dependent. The above data may explain the unique ability of metastatic prostatic cancer to produce blastic reaction in the skeleton. Furthermore the data suggest that products of the normal and abnormal prostate gland may play an important role in skeletal physiology and pathophysiology.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999737g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870w55w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5q47rp369"><ual:graduationDate>1986</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Influence of barley, red clover and weeds on timothy stands</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lemieux, Claudel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two experiments were conducted between 1983 and 1985. In each case, timothy was established with or without barley, red clover, broadleaf weeds and grassy weeds. Four and six weeks after seeding, botanical composition, soil water-content, soil nutrient-content, light interception, and plant coverage data were obtained. The plots were then harvested once during establishment year and twice during subsequent years. At harvest, yield, botanical composition, and forage quality were obtained. Companion-cropping precluded forage cut during establishment and decreased forage yield during the first production year. Establishment with barley had little effect on forage quality but it favored the development of perennial broadleaf weeds. Inter-cropping with red clover decreased timothy yield but total forage production was increased and forage quality was improved. Red clover also reduced the development of perennial broadleaf weeds. The absence of broadleaf weed control increased productivity during establishment but timothy contribution was reduced and perennial broadleaf weeds development was accelerated. Perennial broadleaf weeds reduced yields during the first production year. Establishment without grassy weed control increased yield during establishment (but quality was lessened) and reduced it during the first production year. Establishment with grassy weeds had little effect on the weeds growing thereafter. In presence of both types of weeds, the grassy species were suppressed and the results reflected the situation observed in presence of broadleaf weeds. Finally, principal component analyses showed 12 factors that could be used to predict crop yield. The interpretation suggested that early measurements of weed density along with weed and crop coverage data would give good predictions of crop loss.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm694.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp369</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Intercropping</dc:subject><dc:subject>Timothy-grass -- Yields</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hj81r"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies on the immunobiology of infections with the metacestodes of Echinococcus multilocularis in rodents</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kroeze, Wesley Kars</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The relationships among parasite growth, responses to infection and host genetic factors were examined in rodents infected with Echinococcus multilocularis. Mongolian gerbils, cotton rats and C57L/J mice were relatively susceptible to the infection, whereas five other inbred strains of mice, and hybrids and backcrosses between C57L/J and C57BL/6J mice were more resistant. In mice, susceptibility to E. multilocularis was controlled by multiple, non-H-2-linked genes, as were pathological, inflammatory and specific (antibody) responses to the infection. These responses were also affected by the degree of parasite growth in individual hosts. Antibodies, natural killer cells and hematological responsiveness were ruled out as contributing to resistance to E. multilocularis. Studies on peritoneal leukocytes from infected animals suggested that infections with E. multilocularis were controlled by cells in two phases: an acute phase involving neutrophils and mononuclear cells and a chronic phase involving eosinophils and mononuclear cells.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n95n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj81r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Host-parasite relationships</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rodents -- Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tapeworm infections -- Immunological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Echinococcus multilocularis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128b591"><ual:graduationDate>1986</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Performance of an anisotropic clay under variable stresses</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mohamed, Abdel-Mohsen Onsy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the true triaxial test procedure used for testing laboratory-prepared kaolinite clay samples, undrained (with constant mean stress) strength tests were conducted to study the yield and failure of the clays. The principle concern focussed around the influence of orientation of particle bedding plane on the development of yield and failure characteristics of the clay. As the true triaxial cell permits variations of the three principal stresses, it was possible to study the soil response in any chosen quadrant of the principal space. As a consequence to what is mentioned above, two types of consolidated undrained true triaxial tests were conducted in this study. In the first type, specimens were trimmed from the block sample with 90, 60, 30 and 0 degree orientation angles of particle's bedding planes; these angles were measured with respect to the direction of the major principal stress axis. For each degree of inclination, specimens were tested with three confining pressures 207, 276 and 345 kPa, and for each value of confining pressure, the loading path was varied from compression to tension. The degree of dissociation between the stress and strain increment vectors was seen to depend on both initial and stress induced anisotropy. Most important of all, a constitutive relationship for anisotropic kaolinite clay was derived on the basis of the observed experimental behaviour of soil samples under loading. Additionally, anisotropy is characterized by a double transformation technique. The first transformation accounts for the directional dependency whilst the second transformation concerns itself with anisotropy of the base vectors. The relative joint invariant principle is used to calculate the degree of dissociation during the loading process. The variation of the dissociation angle during the loading process can be considered as a measure of the evolution of the resultant anisotropy. The model has shown to provide viable predictions of the stress-strain relationships obtained from true triaxial tests on an anisotropic kaolinite clay for: (a) different inclinations of particle's bedding planes, (b) different stress paths in one sector, (c) different stress paths in other sectors, and (d) the failure surfaces for different inclinations of particle's bedding planes in the octahedral plane. (Abstract shortened with permission of author.)</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc91s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128b591</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Clay</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Clay soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soils -- Plastic properties</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343s869"><ual:graduationDate>1987</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The analysis of latency data using the inverse Gaussian distribution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pashley, Peter J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The inverse Gaussian distribution is investigated as a basis for statistical analyses of skewed and possibly censored response times. This distribution arises from a random walk process, is a member of the exponential family, and admits the sample arithmetic and harmonic means as complete sufficient statistics. In addition, the inverse Gaussian provides a reasonable alternative to the more commonly used lognormal statistical model due to the attractive properties of its parameter estimates. Three modifications were made to the basic distribution definition: adding a shift parameter to account for minimum latencies, allowing for Type I censoring, and convoluting two inverse Gaussian random variables in order to model components of response times. Corresponding parameter estimation and large sample test procedures were also developed. Results from analysing two extensive sets of simple and two-choice reaction times suggest that shifting the origin and accounting for Type I censoring can substantially improve the reliability of inverse Gaussian parameter estimates. The results also indicate that the convolution model provides a convenient medium for probing underlying psychological processes.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139260t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s869</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Distribution (Probability theory)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m244f"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cascade processes and fully developed turbulence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saucier, Antoine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The energy cascade process in turbulent flows is studied. Kolmogorov inertial range theories are critically reviewed and the multifractal characterization is discussed. Multiplicative cascade models are compared to the energy dissipation field (EDF) measured in the atmosphere. Landau's objection to the 1941 Kolmogorov theory is extended to the predictions of statistical fluid mechanics. The hypothesis $ rm Delta v( lambda L) { buildrel{d} over=} lambda sp{1/3} Delta v(L)$ is rejected with a statistical test. The moments $ rm langle( log varepsilon(L)) sp{p} rangle,$ where $ varepsilon$(L) denotes the EDF averaged over a volume of size L, are shown to be gaussian. For the EDF: Convergence tests showed that the exponents $ tau$(q) were not reliable for q $&lt;$ 0; the correlations obey $ rm langle( mu sb{x}( delta)) sp{p}( mu sb{x+ delta}( delta)) sp{q} rangle propto delta sp{ gamma(p,q)}$ but $ gamma$ does not always equal the value obtained with a multinomial measure; a privileged scale ration r $ approx$ 1/2 is suggested by the prefactor oscillations of the correlation function. The implications of these results for the modelling of the EDF are discussed.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx83k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m244f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Fluid and Plasma</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az890rv126"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kings, Brāhmaṇas, and temples in Orissa : an epigraphic study (300-1147 C.E.)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Singh, Upinder</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Royal endowments to Brahmanas have been interpreted either as a factor of political integration or disintegration in Indian history. Through the first thorough presentation and analysis of the epigraphic data from Orissa, this study argues that the period 300-1147 C.E. was one of intensive state formation and political development in which royal grants played an important integrative role. During this period, Brahmanas, many of whom were ritual specialists associated with the Yajur Veda, emerged as land-holders endowed by royal decree with privileged control over land. Despite the consistent appearance of sectarian affiliations in the royal inscriptions, temples did not benefit from royal patronage on a comparable scale. Until the close of the period under review, it was the gift of land to Brahmanas, not the royally-endowed temple establishment, that was a major basis of royal legitimation and political integration in Orissa.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xf91d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv126</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Orissa (India) -- Politics and government</dc:subject><dc:subject>Religion and state -- India -- Orissa</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orissa (India) -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Land grants -- India -- Orissa</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inscriptions, Sanskrit -- India -- Orissa</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j168m"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors influencing product microstructure and the injection molding behavior of liquid crystalline polymers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khennache, Omar</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Liquid Crystal Polymers (LCP) are a new class of polymeric materials with special molecular and solid state structures, flow characteristics and mechanical properties. Injection molded articles of rigid chain liquid crystal copolymers (LCP's) are gaining increasing commercial importance because their dimensional stability, high stiffness and strength per unit weight, make them highly attractive for aerospace structures and automotive parts, where the anisotropic nature of the materials can be exploited to achieve novel design strategies. Considerable technological importance is given to thermotropic LCP's because of their melt phase behavior and ease of processing. Because of their comparatively low viscosity, they can be injection molded with short cycle times into thin and complex shapes. In the present work, broad range of material properties, including specific heat, thermal conductivity, thermal diffusivity, and shear viscosity of a commercial LCP injection molding resin have been determined experimentally. In addition, a detailed experimental study has been made of the crystallization kinetics of this LCP resin. The study showed that the resin undergoes two crystallization mechanisms, a fast and a slow mechanism, depending on the temperature and the cooling rates. Various experimental techniques, to characterize the microstructure of the molded parts, including morphology, orientation, crystallinity and mechanical properties, have been developed and used. An effort is made to explain the results. Furthermore, composite theory is employed to explain the mechanical properties in light of microstructural observations. Overall, the present work represents the most comprehensive effort to date to study and explain the processing-microstructure-property relationships for injection molded LCP's.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0967755.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j168m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182k88v"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An examination and critique of the understanding of the relationship between apocalypticism and gnosticism in Johannine studies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hill, Robert Allan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Johannine studies it is often assumed that apocalyptic eschatology offended the Gnostic and that vertical eschatology was uncharacteristic of the Apocalypticist. The thesis demonstrates that this assumption is unwarranted. First, the assumption is identified and described as it functions in Johannine studies. Second, the assumption is compared to the trend in current apocalyptic studies. Third, the assumption is compared to evidence from recently discovered gnostic tractates. The thesis concludes that this assumption, widely present in scholarship devoted to the Fourth Gospel, is unwarranted in light of contemporary apocalyptic studies, and in light of new evidence from gnostic documents. Consequently, a new understanding of eschatology in Gnosticism, parallel to the new trend in Apocalypticism, is needed. Further, the assumption can no longer function as it has in Johannine scholarship.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm380.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182k88v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gnosticism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eschatology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj38607723"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development, analysis and comparison of models for respirometric biodegradation data</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cailas, Michael D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>When continuous monitoring devices such as the electrolytic respirometer are used for performing biodegradation experiments, cumulative data are acquired. The structure of these observations limits the reliable application of existing methodologies for analyzing cumulative respirometric biodegradation trends, because the resulting error terms are likely to be highly autocorrelated. To overcome these limitations it is proposed that the Oxygen Uptake Rate (OUR) should be used as the data source for further analysis, because the dependence of the error terms is then removed. To model uniform reaction rate respirometric biodegradation OUR data trends, 1st and 2nd-order OUR models are proposed. Theoretical and practical assessment of these models in comparison with their cumulative counterparts indicates that (a) they are likely to have improved nonlinear behaviour, (b) their parameters will have more reliable confidence interval estimates, and (c) the optimal duration of an experiment performed to estimate the OUR model parameters is shorter compared to that required for estimating similar parameters in the case of cumulative biodegradation data. During respirometric biodegradation studies, data trends with distinct microbial growth periods often appear as well. In order to describe such observations a new diphasic OUR model is proposed, which provides valuable information for each phase in the form of 1st-order reaction rate coefficients and the duration of the first phase. Application of this model to a number of data cases indicates that this model can be regarded as a practical alternative for modelling diphasic respirometric data trends. A similar conclusion was drawn for a proposed two-stage respirometric biodegradation model. In the present study an approach is also suggested for performing statistical comparisons between biodegradation curves which have been obtained under different experimental conditions. This approach is based on the proposed OUR models, t</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085k89w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38607723</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anc580n27c"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cardiovascular responses to psychological stress and caffeine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>France, Christopher R. (Christopher Robert)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While considerable information exists regarding the independent effects of caffeine and psychological stress on cardiovascular activity, there is relatively little information on their combined effects. Since caffeine may enhance cardiovascular responsivity to psychological stress, research on hemodynamic responses to caffeine-stress combinations may help elucidate mechanisms of hypertension development. In a series of studies, regular consumers of caffeine were exposed to laboratory and naturalistic stressors with and without prior caffeine intake. Among the findings were (1) caffeine and stress produced additive increases in blood pressure, (2) caffeine appears to potentiate beta-adrenergic responsivity to active coping, but not passive coping, stressors, (3) caffeine enhanced emotional responses to stress, and (4) cardiovascular responses to caffeine and stress in a naturalistic setting were similar to those observed in the laboratory. These results indicate that caffeine may enhance cardiovascular and psychological responses to stress, and that these responses may contribute to risk for essential hypertension.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xj33v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n27c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Caffeine -- Physiological effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stress (Psychology) -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cardiovascular system</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w7972"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>HPLC-AAS interfaces for the determination of ionic alkyllead, arsonium and selenonium compounds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blais, Jean-Simon</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Three direct interfaces for coupling high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC) with atomic absorption spectrometry (AAS) were developed and optimized for the determination of ionic organolead, organoselenium and organoarsenic compounds. The first all-quartz interface consisted of a thermospray nebulizer and a flame microatomizer in which ionic alkyllead analytes (R$ sb{ rm n}$Pb$ sp{ rm (4-n)+};$ R = CH$ sb3,$ C$ sb2$H$ sb5)$ were atomized by a methanol (from HPLC eluent)-oxygen kinetic flame, and channeled in a quartz tube (atom keeper) mounted into the AAS optical beam. Alternately, the classical electrothermal atomization technique for organolead species (quartz furnace under hydrogen atmosphere) was coupled with a post-column derivatization-volatilization apparatus based on the ethylation of ionic alkylleads by sodium tetraethylborate. The limits of detection provided by these two approaches were 1.0-3.4 ng and 0.10-0.15 ng, respectively. Arsonium ((CH$ sb3) sb3$RAs$ sp+;$ R = CH$ sb3,$ CH$ sb2$CH$ sb2$OH, CH$ sb2$COOH) and selenonium ((CH$ sb3) sb2$RSe$ sp+;$ R = CH$ sb3,$ CH$ sb2$CH$ sb2$OH) species were quantified using a novel HPLC-AAS approach based on a direct coupling of three processes: thermospray nebulization, thermochemical hydride generation using hydrogen gas, and diffuse flame atomization. Direct evidences for the thermochemical hydride generation process was obtained by injecting (CH$ sb3) sb3$SeI and SeO$ sb2$ into the interface and capturing the gaseous end products in liquid chemical traps specific for SeH$ sb2$ and Se(IV). Both analytes were derivatized to SeH$ sb2$ only in the presence of hydrogen in the interface. Reverse- and normal-phase high pressure liquid chromatographic methods were also developed and adapted for the HPLC-AAS analyses of alkyllead, arsonium and selenonium compounds in real samples. The limit of detection of the arsonium and selenonium cations were 7.6-13.3 ng and 31.0-43.9 ng, respectively.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j872t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w7972</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atomic absorption spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organoarsenic compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>High performance liquid chromatography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organoselenium compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organolead compounds</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahh63sw58b"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Body image in anorexic, bulimic, and overweight women : selection of references</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mikhail, Carmen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis deals with factors which may be related to faulty body image in anorexic, bulimic, overweight, and non-eating-disordered (ED) women. It was found that anorexic, bulimic, and overweight women overestimated their body sizes whereas non-eating-disordered controls were accurate regardless of assessment method. Additionally, ED women had slimmer notions of average, normal-healthy, ideal and own ideal sizes than did controls. For controls and successful dieters, the larger one perceived oneself to be the larger were one's selection of references sizes; this was not found for anorexic and bulimic women, nor for unsuccessful dieters. Successful dieters in a weight loss program had more accurate body images and selected larger references than did unsuccessful dieters. Body size confrontation resulted in more accurate body image and in more positive attitudes toward dieting in anorexics.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1392613.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sw58b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Eating disorders</dc:subject><dc:subject>Body image</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v381k"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biological control of white mold of bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L.) by Epicoccum purpurascens Ehrenb. ex Schlecht</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhou, Ting</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>After a wild-type isolate of Epicoccum purpurascens was exposed to shortwave ultraviolet light, several new strains were recovered which were improved in sporulation, fungicide tolerance, and performance in suppression of white mold caused by Sclerotinia sclerotiorum. The efficacy of E. purpurascens in controlling white mold of snap bean (Phaseolus vulgaris) was assessed in greenhouse and field trials. White mold was significantly reduced in both greenhouse and field trials when 2-4 sprays of E. purpurascens conidial suspensions (in 1% malt extract) were sprayed onto the plant surface during the flowering period. Germination of E. purpurascens conidia on senescent petals was greater than on younger flowers. Addition of malt extract to conidial suspensions improved germination on flowers and increased colonization of emerging flowers. Application of E. purpurascens did not accelerate senescence of bean leaves or affect pod yield of bean in greenhouse trials. Mycoparasitism of S. sclerotiorum by E. purpurascens was found only rarely in in vitro tests and was not observed on flower disks. Production of inhibitory compounds by E. purpurascens was the most important mechanism in suppression of white mold but competition for nutrients also appeared to play a role in biocontrol. The influence of nutrients on conidial germination, growth, sporulation and production of antifungal compounds by E. purpurascens were also investigated.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n406q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v381k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Epicoccum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kidney bean -- Diseases and pests -- Biological factors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sclerotinia -- Biological control</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak3569521g"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Bacterial asparagine synthetase gene as a dominant and amplifiable marker in mammalian cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cartier, Mireille</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The use of the bacterial asnA gene as a dominant and amplifiable marker for a variety of mammalian cells was demonstrated. This gene, coding for asparagine synthetase (AS), was first shown to complement mammalian cells lacking an endogenous AS enzyme. These transfectants proved highly resistant to the glutamine analog albizziin, which inhibits the mammalian AS enzyme. This finding allowed us to use the bacterial AS gene as a dominant marker in wild type mammalian cells, selecting with asparagine-free medium containing albizziin. Thereafter, amplification of the AS marker in transfectants was achieved through selection of cells in increasing concentrations of the asparagine analog $ beta$-aspartyl hydroxamate (AH). Studies on the use of the AS marker, alone or in conjunction with other markers, to select for stable, amplified transfectants producing one or more co-transfected gene products are also reported.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh79x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569521g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xj35d"><ual:graduationDate>1991</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Autonomic and pharmacologic modulation of the frequency-dependent properties of the atrioventricular node</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nayebpour, Mohsen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The responses of the atrioventricular node (AVN) to changes in activation rate is complex. A variety of approaches have been used to explain the different responds of AVN, but none has been able to describe fully nodal behavior. Three rate-dependent nodal properties referred to as recovery, facilitation, and fatigue contribute to rate-induced changes in nodal conduction time. We developed a model incorporating a quantitative description of these properties that was able to accurately predict AV node conduction during steady state atrial pacing. This model provides a mathematical framework through which interventions such as changes in the autonomic tone may affect AV nodal conduction. This was evaluated by studying effects of vagal stimulation (VS), isoproterenol (IP), and beta blockade (BB) an AVN conduction. Experimental results and mathematical modelling revealed that these interventions alter the ways in which the AVN responds to changes in activation rate. These changes result in enhanced rate-dependent AVN conduction slowing with VS and BB, and reduced rate-dependent slowing with IP. The potential implications of the rate-dependent properties of the AVN were studied by evaluating whether the depressant effects of diltiazem (D) on the AVN are enhanced during arrhythmias which increase AVN activation rate. The relative magnitude of D's effects on the AVN during tachycardia (atrial fibrillation, and circus movement tachycardia) were significantly magnified compared to the effects at races comparable to sinus rhythm in man. Rate-dependent calcium channel-blocking properties of D were an intrinsic property, though their intensity was modulated by autonomic tone. This thesis provides a link between basic theories of rate dependent properties and physiologic and pharmacologic implications.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fs02t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xj35d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t262k"><ual:graduationDate>1990</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Entomology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Determination of key factors affecting the population dynamics of Diopsis longicornis and D. apicalis (Diptera:Diopsidae), pests of rice in the Republic of Guinée, West Africa</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chiasson, Hélène</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Pest status of the rice stem-borers, Diopsis longicornis and D. apicalis was not well known in the Republic of Guinee. In the present study, adult and immature populations of both species were monitored under various local cultural practices, i.e., planting methods (direct and transplanted), different planting dates and seasons (wet and dry). As previously observed in other West African countries, D. apicalis did occasional damage to rice in Guinee. However, contrary to findings elsewhere, D. longicornis was not an important pest of Guinean rice, infesting 4% of stems over the five seasons studied. Regulators affecting population size and behaviour of D. longicornis were determined, focusing on factors controlling the fly's quiescent period in aggregation sites during the dry season, and the insect's movement to and from these refugia. Availability of cultivated and wild rice was found to interrupt or prevent quiescence of D. longicornis. Abiotic factors, (relative humidity, rainfall and photoperiod) influenced time of dispersal of D. longicornis.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk55s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t262k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Rice -- Guinea -- Field experiments</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rice -- Diseases and pests -- Guinea</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diopsis -- Guinea</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>