<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w293s"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On the detection of non-adjoining dependencies in molecular sequences</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dutil, Nicolas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Molecular sequence data contain many evolutionarily conserved  stretches of nucleotides or amino acids that act as signals. This thesis extends a  graph theoretic framework from Agarwal and Bafna that detects and models adjoining  and non-adjoining dependencies in these signals. In their model, each vertex  corresponds to a random variable modeling one position and the weight of each arc  〈u, v〉 is the information content of random variable v given u.  Whereas previous work allows each position in the signal to be dependent on only one  other position (l = 1), we focus on the case where a position may be dependent on a  number of other positions (l ≥ 1). We address two significant obstacles in  this extended framework. Firstly, the computational problems for l &gt; 1 are  intractable. Secondly, a solution S of weight w(S) to their graph theoretic problem  does not necessarily imply the existence of a Markov model with an information  content value of w(S). We offer two new ways to find good Markov models where every  position is dependent on at most l other positions. We give a factor 2 approximation  (under the pairwise information content scores) and a polynomial time algorithm for  bounded treewidth which is guaranteed to produce a Markov model maximizing  information content. We also investigate a heuristic alluded to by Agarwal and Bafna  for extending an l order model to an l + 1 order model. Lastly, we compare the  specificity and sensitivity of various approaches using "synthetic" signal  data generated from a difficult distribution and identify an important  tradeoff.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hallett, Michael T.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x21c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w293s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pn55d"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of the Schwarz algorithms : understanding restricted additive Schwarz</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Efstathiou, Evridiki</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>More than 100 years ago, H. A. Schwarz formulated a method to  prove the existence of harmonic functions on irregular domains. This method, the  alternating Schwarz method, is based on the decomposition of the domain into  subdomains and is the first known domain decomposition method. Modern variants of  the Schwarz algorithm, the additive and multiplicative Schwarz methods are studied  in this work as domain decomposition methods and as preconditioners for the solution  of algebraic equations. Recently, a new variant of the additive Schwarz method was  introduced, the restricted additive Schwarz, which was found to converge faster and  require less communication than additive Schwarz. But, it is not immediately clear  why this happens. This is what motivated this work. It is shown in this thesis that  additive Schwarz is not equivalent to the classical method and that it does not  converge in general when used as an iterative solver. Restricted additive Schwarz on  the other hand, corresponds to the classical method. This work, presents the Schwarz  methods in algorithmic form and studies them step by step. A comparison of each  method with the classical Schwarz is discussed and attention is paid on the  information exchange between subdomains in each method.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gander, Martin</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q68g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn55d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848r22f"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The relationship between upper extremity function and use of the paretic upper extremity at home in stroke survivors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Côté-LeBlanc, Geneviève</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite its relative importance, "use" of the affected  upper extremity (UE) following stroke has obtained very little attention. This can  be explained in part by the fact that effective means of measuring "use"  are not readily available to clinicians. The objective of this cross-sectional study  was to examine whether measures of manual dexterity and UE function, commonly used  by clinicians and researchers, can effectively gauge at-home "use" of the  affected UE by patients who have suffered a stroke. Methods. Gross and fine manual dexterity, UE specific function,  UE related independence, grip strength and endurance were evaluated on 47 chronic  stroke survivors living in the community. "Use" of the affected UE was  measured using the Motor Activity Log. Results. "Use" of the affected UE was found to have a  linear relation with measures of UE capacity, once age and side of paresis were  controlled in the analysis. In fact, up to 80% of the variance in "use"  could be accounted for by some of the models. Both the TEMPA unilateral functional  score and the Box &amp; Block Test on the affected side were associated with an  increase of ~20% in "use" for each increase of one standard  deviation. All of the other measures were associated with substantially lower  increase in "use" per standard deviation change. Conclusion. Measures involving movement of the affected shoulder  and elbow such as the TEMPA or the Box &amp; Block Test are more closely associated  with increased "use" of the affected UE in comparison to other measures  such as the Nine Hole Peg Test or grip strength that can be completed without  incorporating the shoulder and elbow.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood-Dauphinee, Sharon</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k5578.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r22f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tv73t"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Examining synaptic vesicle morphology and function in dopamine neurons of mice lacking vesicular monoamine transporter 2</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Croft, Benjamin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The brain isoform of the vesicular monoamine transporter (VMAT2)  packages monoamines into synaptic vesicles (SVs), an essential step in synaptic  transmission by central dopamine (DA) neurons. While the modulation of VMAT2 levels  influences the amount of DA that can be released, the underlying mechanisms remain  unclear. The objective of the present study is to elucidate these mechanisms by  examining the SVs of VMAT2 knock out (KO) mice. We used transmission electron  microscopy to determine that DA terminals from VMAT2 KO and wild type samples are  morphologically indistinguishable from one another. We then monitored the uptake and  release of the activity dependent fluorescent dye FM1-43 by VMAT2 KO neurons and  found that their SVs cycle, despite being devoid of DA. Our results demonstrate that  SV biogenesis and cycling are independent of SV filling, suggesting that one way by  which changes in VMAT2 levels could influence is DA release by altering the  proportion of SVs that are able to fill.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fon, Edward</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d963r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv73t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mc60j"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The ATP binding cassette transporter A1 gene : expression and role in hypoalphalipoproteinemia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bissonnette, Rachel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study was undertaken primarily to determine the  prevalence of ABCA1 gene defects in a selected population with a HDL-C &lt; 5 th  percentile. The results showed that 30% of the selected patients had a lipid efflux  defect and 16% (10/64) of those patients had a mutation in the ABCA1 gene. The  cholesterol and phospholipid efflux showed a high correlation with HDL-C levels. In  addition, both phospholipid and cholesterol effluxes (r = 0.64 p &lt; 0.001 and  r = 0.48 p &lt; 0.001, respectively) were significantly correlated to HDL-C  levels in selected hypoalphalipoproteinemia subjects. Knowing that ABCA1 is regulated by cholesterol, oxysterols, and  cAMP in peripheral cells, it was also of interest to investigate the regulation in  other cells where cholesterol metabolism is an important function. Therefore the  second objective was to determine the regulation of ABCA1 in hepatocytes. The  results demonstrated that ABCA1 was not regulated in HepG2 cells but strongly  regulated in fibroblasts. Taken together, these studies support the two-step hypothesis  proposed by Fielding et al. These studies also suggest that ABCA1 regulation in the  liver is different than in peripheral cells. We believe that understanding the ABCA1  pathway will lead to a better comprehension of the reverse cholesterol transport  system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Genest, Jacques, Jr.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296wz70h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mc60j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58pd58m"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trait and state aspects of P300 in schizophrenia : a prospective longitudinal study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bicu, Monica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study investigated trait and state aspects of the reduction  of the P300 event-related potential component in schizophrenia in a prospective  longitudinal design. Twelve patients and 12 healthy subjects underwent auditory and  visual P300 tests on consecutive sessions at two month intervals. Patients had also  PANSS symptom quantifications. The comparison between patients and healthy subjects  revealed that the P300 reduction in patients is stable across sessions in the  auditory modality thus representing a trait marker. The analysis of the  relationships between symptoms and P300 showed that the frontal auditory P300 is  negatively related to negative symptoms, whereas the posterior visual P300  positively correlates with positive symptoms. Consistent with clinical and  pathophysiological models of schizophrenia, our study suggests that P300 assessment  taking into account its frontal/posterior topography and visual/auditory modality  could provide a simple tool to understand and follow changes in the brain activity  involved in both trait and state expressions of schizophrenia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Debruille, J. Bruno</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g084w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd58m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311p961"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les impacts du 11 septembre sur l'ordre juridique international : l'exemple du droit spatial</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pereira-Bahia, Liliane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>International law is not insulated from all external influences:  eminently political and conflicting, international relations assume a vertical  vision of the relationship between law and power. Therefore, the terrorist attacks  of September 11, whether fueled by the desire for a new world order or simply the  pursuit of power, necessarily affected the international legal order. To identify  these effects, one must consider the very foundations of international law,  sovereignty and the equality of the States, as well as the emerging international  trends of globalization and unilateralism and the theoretical models, which must be  compared to the immediately measures taken in response to the attacks. Having  defined the situation, as it existed on the 10th of September, one will observe the  acceleration and expansion of the already existing phenomena. The radicalization of  international law and outer space law confirms the statement of Prosper Veil,  "always the same one, and always started again".</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jahku, Ram</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q4627.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311p961</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>International law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space law</dc:subject><dc:subject>September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z708x22n"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Understanding the concept of asset securitization in the Canadian context</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pelletier, Anne-Barbara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis has been written to provide the reader with a  general understanding of a securitization transaction. It should be considered  constructive reading for persons engaged in the practice of Canadian corporate,  banking and securities law, the financial services industry as well as corporate  officers who wish to expand their knowledge on the topic of structured finance. The  following describes the primary participants and basic components involved in a  securitization transaction and discusses how each comes together to result in the  issuance of asset-backed securities. Further, this thesis provides an analysis of  each step and aspect that is necessary to structure a securitization transaction.  Securitization involves a multitude of legal, accounting and tax issues, and this  thesis concentrates on the most central of such issues. Lastly, this thesis  concludes with some insight into what the future holds for the securitization  market.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stevens, David P.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv83t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708x22n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Asset-backed financing -- Law and legislation -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161682q"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Misdiagnoses and wrong prescriptions : R&amp;D divestitures in the pharmaceutical industry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chauhan, Iqbal</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The emergence of biotechnology necessitating change in  traditional pharmacological research, cost cutting by hospitals and health insurers,  and an increasing number of patent expirations have posed a considerable challenge  to the pharmaceutical industry, which hitherto had been considered recession-proof.  Responding to this challenge, the industry has undergone tremendous consolidation  through mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As). These M&amp;As have resulted in high  concentration within the therapeutic classes of drugs, thereby raising  anticompetitive concerns. In order to allow the mergers to proceed, the Federal Trade  Commission in the U.S. had required the merging entities to divest their R&amp;D  assets. The European Commission, on the contrary, had taken more permissive  approach. The thesis has argued that R&amp;D divestitures in  pharmaceutical cases have not been appropriate as anticompetitive concern arises  owing to the acquisition of market power with drug purchasers, rather than the  combination of R&amp;D assets. The innovative nature of the industry, and the costs  and risks involved in drug discovery make it hard to analyze the likely future state  of the market. Ex-post analysis shows that divestiture in these cases proved  counterproductive. It is suggested that ex-post remedies like compulsory licensing  and price regulation are preferable in pharmaceutical mergers, as they do not  disrupt the companies' R&amp;D structure. Moreover, these remedies could be applied  once the anticompetitive concerns become apparent the merger is consummated, thereby  allaying the uncertainty involved in the assessment of the future state of  innovation markets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Janda, Richard</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k558j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161682q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmaceutical industry -- Mergers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antitrust law -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pharmaceutical industry -- United States</dc:subject><dc:subject>Consolidation and merger of corporations -- United States</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440t02q"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Trade and investment disputes : whose business is it anyway ?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Casanova-Jimenez, Richard P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is a discussion on whether every sector of human  activity really is or needs to be 'global'. It discusses the impact that economic  globalization has on the role of the nation-state and on the concept of democracy,  at both local and international levels. Particular emphasis is put on some of the  democratic challenges associated with dispute settlement at the WTO and also under  foreign investment international instruments. It is argued that increased  participation by non-state actors, particularly NGOs, in state-to-state and in  investor-state arbitration threatens to weaken the arbitration process and does  little to remedy alleged democratic deficiencies. The author concludes that many  democratic concerns regarding these types of dispute settlement processes may be  better addressed by strengthening national democracies. Increased public  information, consultation, and participation in the shaping of foreign policy could  reduce much of the criticism concerning both, international dispute settlement and  decision-making.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Toope, Stephen</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999731t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t02q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Globalization -- Political aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anti-globalization movement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Globalization -- Economic aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Globalization -- Social aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>International economic integration</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A47429980n"><ual:graduationDate>2003</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aggression replacement training : evaluation of a program for young offenders</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Torchin, Stephanie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Aggression Replacement  Training Program (ART) is an approach to reduce aggression in Young  Offenders. This program was implemented with a sample of youths on probation and  living in the community (N = 21). The goal was to evaluate the efficacy of the  program, and to measure changes in aggression, skill acquisition and recidivism  rates. A quasi-experimental nonequivalent control group design was used. The  Aggression Questionnaire and Skillstreaming Checklist were the main source of data  and results were compared pre- and posttest. Recidivism rates were determined six  months after the start of the program. An improvement in aggression scores was found  in the ART sample, but this was not statistically significant. Only 5.8% of the  total sample that had recidivated, committed an aggressive crime. Recommendations  are made to maximize the efficacy of the ART program for the future.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Duder, Sydney</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp22q.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429980n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aggressiveness in youth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Juvenile delinquents -- Rehabilitation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anp193969p"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Emotional ramifications of adoption reunion : is there a predictable pattern of response?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Toner-MacLean, Sally</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examines the emotional responses of adoption reunion  participants over time by a cross-sectional survey. A questionnaire was modeled  after an existing reunion guideline, "Relationship Stages in Reunion".  Ontario adoption reunion counselors in the public and private sectors use this  guideline. This questionnaire was circulated by a Parent Finder's organization (22  respondents), and a provincial government organization (27 respondents). The  hypothesis that there is a predictable pattern of emotional response in reunion was  not supported. No significant differences were found between those that experienced  reunion via either organization. There were some differences in the demographics.  Both groups noted a high level of satisfaction with their reunion. This research  would have been better tracked by a longitudinal study.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Duder, Sydney</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n051.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193969p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Birthparents -- Identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adoptees -- Identification</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az316q211n"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>From negotiation to accommodation : cultural relevance in the Asha Gram Mental Health Program, Barwani district, India</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jain, Sumeet</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyzes the degree of cultural relevance in the  Asha Gram Mental Health Program in Barwani, India. The focus is on the role of  community mental health workers as bridges between a professional culture of  psychiatry and the local cultural understandings of mental health. Processes of  cultural interaction are analyzed on a continuum from negotiation, defined as  interaction without fundamental cultural change, to accommodation, defined as  interaction with cultural change. Accommodation at the level of the vision of mental  health disorders was limited while there was an active negotiation that resulted in  some transformation of the social vision. Negotiation with communities at the level  of relationships underpinned this transformation and contributed to a social  accommodation with local forms of relationships. Although, professional and class  power were important obstacles to achieving cultural relevance, the Program also  demonstrates the necessity to subvert this power in order to create social  change.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Piat, Myra</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Corin, Ellen</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k559t.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q211n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Community mental health services -- India</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150j87g"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of child protection employment on the children of the employees : an exploratory study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ingram, David Edward</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An exploratory study was conducted to examine the effects of  parental child protection employment on the children of the employees.  Semi-structured interviews were conducted of eight children, who had one parent  employed in a child protection agency in Eastern Ontario. The analysis of the  interviews demonstrated perceived impacts on identified areas of the participants'  lives: family transactions within the community; internal family functioning; and  the impact on the individual participant. The interview results were also examined  along four variables: gender of the child protection worker parent; gender of the  participant; age of the participant; and position held by the child protection  worker parent. Of these, only the gender of the child protection worker parent  appeared to have a differing trend between groups. Further research is suggested to  generalize these results beyond the participants in the study.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wright, Robin</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b54n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j87g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Child welfare workers -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children -- Attitudes</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As7526c95x"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regional ceramic trade in Early Bronze Age Greece : evidence from neutron activation analysis of early Helladic pottery from Argolis and Korinthia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Attas, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ceramic production and exchange in Early Bronze Age Greece have been studied through provenance determination by neutron activation analysis. The concentrations of Na, K, Rb, Cs, Ca, Al, Sc, La, Ce, Eu, Yb, Th, Ti, Hf, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, and Co were determined, with respect to Perlman-Asaro standard pottery, in 255 objects of the Early Helladic (or EH) II and III periods found at Keramidhaki, Korakou, Phlious, Zygouries, Tiryns, and Asine in Korinthia and Argolis. Multivariate treatment of these data, merged with 162 analyses from the author's earlier work with samples from Lerna (Argolis) and Lake Vouliagmeni (Korinthia), yielded 11 compositional reference groups. Many of these could be attributed to centres of production on distributional or other grounds, thereby allowing the sources of more than half the sampled objects to be determined. The following conclusions were reached: All 8 sites (except possibly Phlious) were sources of common EH II ware (sauceboats and small bowls), which had limited distributions. Many unusual EH II fine wares had other sources and broader distributions. The attribution of coarse wares was complicated by the presence of tempering material. The changes in pottery acquisition patterns which accompanied the beginning of EH III were probably more drastic at Tiryns than at Lerna or Korakou.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795834j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526c95x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pottery dating</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pottery, Greek</dc:subject><dc:subject>Radioactivation analysis in archaeology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bronze age -- Greece</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445cd848"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Graduate Communications Program</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Images of women in National Film Board of Canada films during World War II and the post-war years, 1939-1949</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nash, M. Teresa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present thesis represents the first major Canadian study to examine images of women in film. It concentrates on a body of film which was produced by the National Film Board of Canada (NFB) in its first decade (1939 to 1949). It is postulated here that the images of women in these films will reflect the position of women in the larger socio-economic context. We begin by looking at the status of women in Canada during World War II and the post-war years (1939 to 1949). Since there has been so little research on women during this period of Canadian history, and since the NFB is a government agency, we examine the House of Commons debates of this era as an index to women's status. We then examine the role of women in the NFB itself, with particular emphasis on the influence that women had in film production during the 1940's. Finally, we examine the images of women in the NFB films. We find that there are distinct differences in the films made by men and those made by women. The major difference is characterized by the fact that the images of women in male-produced films clearly reflect the patriarchal values of the society in which the films were produced, while the female-produced films do not.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st233.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cd848</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Women in motion pictures -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>National Film Board of Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Motion pictures and the war</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A474299826"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Theoretical and experimental electron paramagnetic resonance studies : A, The conformation of transition metal-biuret complexes and their interaction with carbohydrates and polyols : B, Radical anions of 9, 10 anthrasemiquinone generated by carbohydrates</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mattar, Saba M. (Saba Mitri)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A detailed review and revision of the theories required to simulate the electron paramagnetic resonance (epr) spectra of S' = 1/2 transition metal monomers and dimers is undertaken. The simulation of the epr spectrum of bis(biuretato)cuprate(II), doped in its isomorphous nickel(II) complex, enables the determination of its effective spin Hamiltonian parameters, independent of PH and solvent effects. An axial bis(biuretato)cuprate(II) dimer is also detected at 110 K and its simulated spectra indicate that it is formed by the axial interaction of two monomers. The nature of copper(II)-biuret complexes in acidic and neutral media is then investigated. Their epr spectra are shown to be deceptively simple and arise from more than one species in solution. Furthermore, in basic media the bis(biuretato)cuprate(II) and di-(mu)-hydroxo-bis(biuretato)dicuprate(II) are the predominant species. However a consideration of the structure and superexchange interactions of the latter complex indicate that it is "epr silent". Electronic absorption and epr investigations demonstrate that polyols and carbohydrates interact axially with bis(biuretato)cuprate(II) in solution without the displacement of the equatorial biuretato ligands. The resonance field positions and general contribution of the g tensor to the epr intensities of a preferentially oriented paramagnetic probe is derived. They are used in simulating the epr spectra of copper(II) complexes adsorbed on cellulose fibres. The results suggest that the complexes interchelate between the cellulosic sheets of the fibre. An empirical parameter describing the degree of order of the sheets, within the fibre, is defined and estimated. Stable 9,10-anthrasemiquinone radicals are generated by carbohydrates in strictly aqueous media for the first time. They are also shown to be the predominant radicals in AQ-Soda and AQ-Kraft-Soda pulping liquors. Monitoring the radical concentrations with temperature via epr strongly suggests that they should not be disregarded as possible catalysts in these processes.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053g71x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/474299826</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electron paramagnetic resonance</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4x51hj74b"><ual:graduationDate>1982</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Action of penicillin G on Neisseria meningitidis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Neirinck, Leonard G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Neisseria meningitidis SD1C exhibited a low tolerance to penicillin G (0.03 (mu)g/ml). Loss of viability was independent of the concentration of antibiotic above the minimum inhibitory concentration, whereas the rate of bacteriolysis was concentration dependent. Penicillin-induced lysis was secondary to cell death. At low but lethal levels of this antibiotic, rapid loss of viability was accompanied by specific ultrastructural changes, yet growth characteristics appeared normal. Subminimal inhibitory concentrations of penicillin G decreased cell numbers and altered the colonial morphology, cellular ultrastructure, as well as the division rate. N. meningitidis SD1C was shown to have six penicillin binding proteins. The binding of penicillin was rapid and for certain proteins was dependent upon concentration and active cell growth. No single penicillin binding protein could be correlated with cell death. Penicillin treatment of cells in the presence of polyvinylpyrrolidone-40 and horse serum resulted in an inhibition of cell division, yet no loss in viability, no ultrastructural changes nor reduction of penicillin binding to the cells occurred. Protection from the antibiotic was shown to be related at least in part to the ability of such collids to eliminate a penicillin G induced increase in intracellular H(,2)O volume. This antibiotic was also shown to cause a concurrent increase in transmembrane potential and intracellular potassium ion level. The relationship of these findings to the lethal events in N. meningitidis is discussed and a model is proposed for the mode of action of penicillin G.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x801.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj74b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s5444"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mutagenesis in Lotus corniculatus L.</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Therrien, Mario C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Some 7,500 seeds of Lotus corniculatus cv. Mirabel were treated with X-rays (3,000-12,000 Rads), ethyl methanesulfonate, 8-ethoxycaffeine, n-hydroxyurea, and 2-aminopurine (0.001 to 1.0% solutions). A total of 93 selfed, partially inbred, and open-pollinated lines, comprising some 22,000 plants, were generated over four generations. Mutagenic effects were assessed on germination, seedling survival, meiotic aberrations, pollen abortion, seed and forage yields, pod dehiscence, winter hardiness, brown floral keel tip color, and cyanoglycoside (HCA) content in the leaves. Dose effects were largely confined to the M(,1) generation. Germination and seedling survival could not be used to predict mutation rates. Higher levels of forage and seed yields and lower levels of HCA content were induced. Pod dehiscence, winter hardiness and brown keel tip frequency were not affected. Three qualitative mutants, chlorotica, vestigial floret, and dwarf, were tetrasomic recessives. Only tetrasomically inherited characters were found. X-rays and EMS were the most effective mutagens.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j87q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s5444</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mutagenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lotus corniculatus</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117p541"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The mechanical properties of the human lumbar spine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tencer, Allan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with the investigation, in vitro, of the mechanical properties of the intact and injured human lumbar spine under general loading conditions, by both experimentation and use of a numerical simulation. For the experimental investigation, a three dimensional loading apparatus and displacement transducer were constructed. In order to standardize the experiment, the influence of several secondary variables was investigated. The load deflection properties of intact and injured joints were then studied. Eight states of injury were considered. As well, the effect of various types of preloading upon joint response was determined. Using the data generated by the experimental study and measurements of the surface geometry of the vertebra, a numerical simulation was devised. This simulation allowed the interpretation of the experimental results in terms of strains in the soft tissue elements and facet interaction. As well, the locations of the instant center of rotation and the foraminal gap dimensions could be determined.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct566.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p541</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Human mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182k826"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Belief among academics in free will and in the veracity of scientific judgement</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doan, Brian D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A review of the philosophical and psychological literature on free will is presented. Three major positions are identified: libertarianism, hard determinism and compatibilism (or soft determinism). The latter enjoys widespread and largely unchallenged support in psychology. Substantive conceptual and empirical grounds are presented which suggest that psychologists may be dismissing free will at their peril. It is argued, first of all, that belief in the reality of free will has profound implications for conceptions of human action, of moral responsibility, of the form and veracity of scientific accounts and of the validity of scientific reduction. Moreover, the results of a multi-disciplinary survey of academics reveal that 80% of those surveyed believe free will is real. Contrary to popular assumptions in psychology, determinism is not endorsed by many scientists outside of psychology, nor does belief in free will reflect naive belief in mind-body dualism. Modern libertarians reject both dualism and reductionism, distinguishing instead between different levels of scientific explanation. The findings are discussed in terms of their theoretical implications for cognitive, social and clinical psychology, and directions for further research are suggested.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580n220.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182k826</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Libertarianism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Free will and determinism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Science -- Moral and ethical aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>McGill University -- Faculty</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623d234"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tax incentives and investment in two Canadian manufacturing industries</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Forde, Penelope</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Canada has pursued during the postwar period a policy of accelerated capital cost allowances to stimulate private investment. Faster write offs increase a firm's cash flows and hence internal funds available for investment. These allowances reduce government revenues since taxes are deferred. These deferred taxes have grown rapidly and now more attention is being paid to the effects of tax incentive devices on investment and on government revenues. In the thesis non-neoclassical models of investment are employed for an analysis of investment in two manufacturing industries. One model emphasizes the interdependence of the investment and financing decisions of firms. Both sales and external finance are significant determinants of investment expenditures. The main conclusion of the thesis is that accelerated write offs have played a limited role in financing investment. Instead, firms relied more on external borrowing and other financing methods which confer larger tax benefits than faster write offs.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579s858.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d234</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Investment tax credit -- Canada -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Manufacturing industries -- Canada -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tax exemption -- Economic aspects -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Capital investments -- Canada -- Case studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fm12k"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulation of protein biosynthesis in L-cells infected with reovirus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Skup, Danial</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The regulation of protein synthesis was examined in L-cells infected with reovirus. To carry out these studies, an in vitro protein synthesizing system was developed from L-cells. Examination of these L-cell extracts showed that the translational apparatus undergoes a transition from cap dependence to cap independence as a function of time post infection. Reovirus progeny subviral particles contain an active RNA polymerase enzyme and inactive or masked guanylyl transferase and methylase enzymes. The 5' terminal structure of the mRNA synthesized by these particles is pGpCp... Examination of the 5' terminal structure of reovirus mRNA associated with polysomes of L-cells infected with reovirus at early, intermediate and late times post infection, revealed a transition from a proportion of capped to uncapped viral mRNA of 3:1 to a predominance of uncapped over capped mRNA of at least 10:1. The uncapped mRNA is monophosphorylated at the 5' terminus. This pG... terminated mRNA is not a substrate for the host capping enzymes, and is not translated in extracts from uninfected cells, but is translated with high efficiency in extracts prepared from infected cells. The host cell mRNA is present in the infected cell but is not expressed in vivo, nor can it be translated in vitro, in extracts from infected cells. We concluded that reovirus induces a gradual modification of the cap dependence of the host translational apparatus. As a result of this modification uncapped reovirus mRNA is translated preferentially over host (capped) mRNA. The data have been drawn together in the form of a revised model of the reovirus replicative cycle.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pq95h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm12k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95051178"><ual:graduationDate>1980</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Selective attention to dysphoric stimuli by depressed and nondepressed individuals</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shenker, Leonard J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The hypothesis that depressed individuals selectively attend to instances of depressive ideational themes (dysphoric stimuli) is derived from Beck's cognitive model of depression and general theories of information processing. A dichotic auditory shadowing task with alternating dysphoric and nondysphoric distraction was employed to assess relative allocations of attention to dysphoric and nondysphoric spoken prose by 88 mildly depressed, moderately and severely depressed, highly test-anxious nondepressed, and low test-anxious nondepressed university students. Only moderately and severely depressed Ss were significantly more distracted by dysphoric than nondysphoric stimuli, with Helplessness the most salient, and Failure the least salient, of ten depressive themes. All groups performed equally well with nondysphoric distraction. No subsequent changes of relative allocations of attention were found to result from experimenter-induced success-reward or failure-loss experiences. It is proposed that the results directly demonstrate depressive information processing disturbances at stimulus selection, which are congruent with Beck's formulations. The potency of descriptions of helplessness for the moderately and severely depressed groups support the Learned Helplessness model of depression. Selective attention to noncontingency may be a mechanism by which the cognitive set to perceive noncontingency produces perceptions of current helplessness.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s41s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95051178</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Depression, Mental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zp038"><ual:graduationDate>1981</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The public sector and economic growth in Nigeria : policy simulation with partial adjustment models</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kwanashie, Michael</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Following the sharp rise in oil prices in late 1973 and early 1974, most oil exporting countries adopted highly expansionary fiscal and monetary policies aimed at rapid development of their economies. In Nigeria the role of the public sector since then has been significantly increased as most of the oil revenue accrues directly to the Federal government rather than to individuals. Given the host of economic problems faced by the country in the 1970s the debate over the role of the public sector in a mixed capitalist economy in the process of economic growth gains more relevance. The essence of this study is to analyze the consequence of alternative patterns of government policy on economic growth in Nigeria. The study provides a general framework that is useful in studying the effects of alternative government policies on the domestic economy and also in analyzing alternative patterns of allocating the sudden increase in domestic resources. Using policy simulation experiments, an alternative policy package is suggested and the relative effectiveness of various policy instruments used by the government are examined.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v3745.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zp038</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economic development -- Simulation methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nigeria -- Economic conditions</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>