<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As1784p375"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of beta2-glycoprotein I-reactive T cells in antiphospholipid syndrome</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tolomeo, Tanya</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Antiphospholipid syndrome (APS) is an autoimmune disorder characterized by             the presence of autoantibodies to phospholipid (PL)-binding proteins, such as             beta2-glycoprotein I (beta2GPI), and clinical manifestations including thrombosis and/or             recurrent pregnancy loss. Beta2GPI-reactive T cells have been shown to be activated in             patients with APS, but the mechanism responsible for this activation remains unclear.             Recent studies have proposed that exposure of a cryptic epitope on beta2GPI, as a             consequence of binding to PL, leads to the activation of beta2GPI-autoreactive T cells             in APS patients. To test this hypothesis, we evaluated the development of             beta2GPI-reactive T cells in a murine model of aPL production. C57BL/6 mice were             immunized repeatedly with human beta2GPI in the presence of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to             induce aPL production. High levels of circulating aPL were observed as early as the             second immunization, but splenic T cell reactivity to beta2GPI was not detectable in             vitro until after the fourth immunization. Splenic T cells from mice producing high             levels of aPL proliferated in response to native human beta2GPI, alone or bound to             anionic PL, but PL-bound beta2GPI appeared to be a more potent antigen.             Beta2GPI-reactive T cells produced IL-2 and IFN-gamma, but not IL-4 or IL-10, suggesting             a TH1 bias of this T cell response. These results demonstrate that T cell reactivity to             beta2GPI can develop in nonautoimmune individuals repeatedly exposed to this antigen in             a proinflammatory context (e.g., LPS). Our data further suggest that the             beta2GPI-reactive T cells induced in this model have a TH1 bias and may be more reactive             to a PL-dependent epitope on beta2GPI than to native beta2GPI.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le syndrome antiphospholipide (SAPL) est une maladie             autoimmune caractérisée par la présence d'auto-anticorps antiphospholipides (aPL)             dirigés contre des protéines liant les phospholipides anioniques dont la             beta2-glycoproteine I (beta2GPI), ainsi que par des manifestations cliniques incluant la             thrombose et la perte foetale récurrente. Il a été démontré que des lymphocytes T             spécifiques à la beta2GPI étaient activés chez les patients atteints du SAPL. Cependant,             le mécanisme responsable de cette activation lymphocytaire reste nébuleux. Des études             récentes ont proposé que l'exposition d'épitopes cryptiques de la beta2GPI, suite à la             liaison de cette glycoprotéine à des phospholipides anioniques, engendre l'activation de             lymphocytes T autoréactifs spécifiques à la beta2GPI chez les patients atteints du SAPL.             Afin de vérifier cette hypothèse, nous avons évalué le développement de lymphocytes T             spécifiques à la beta2GPI dans un modèle murin de production d'aPL. Des souris C57BL/6             ont été immunisées à répétition avec de la beta2GPI humaine en présence de             lipopolysaccharide (LPS) dans le but d'induire la production d'aPL. Des titres élevés             d'aPL circulants ont été observés dès la deuxième immunization, tandis que les             lymphocytes T spécifiques à la beta2GPI n'ont été détectés que suite à la quatrième             immunisation. Ainsi, les lymphocytes T provenant de la rate des souris produisant des             niveaux élevés d'aPL ont proliféré en réponse à la forme native de beta2GPI et encore             plus fortement en réponse au complexe beta2GPI-PL. Ces lymphocytes T réactifs à la             beta2GPI ont démontré une production d'interleukine 2 et d'interféron gamma. Cependant,             aucune interleukine 4 ou 10 n'</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Joyce Ellen Rauch</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn76z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784p375</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag158bm13p"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ice hockey stick and puck biomechanical predictors of wrist shot accuracy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Michaud-Paquette, Yannick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this study was to identify the movement patterns of the ice             hockey stick from a wrist shot that corresponds to the accuracy of puck trajectory. A             total of twenty five subjects participated in this study; each performed 10 successful             wrist shots on four targets. Performances were evaluated by simultaneously recording the             movements of the stick's shaft and blade and of the puck with infra-red based motion             capture (Vicon®) system (240 Hz) Kinematics of the shaft and blade of the hockey stick             were examined using a multiple regression analysis using the accuracy score as the             dependant variable. The results indicate that accurate shooters tended to alter release             parameters (puck release orientation and velocity), loading mechanics and blade             orientation to achieve proper puck trajectory explaining 40% and 76% of the accuracy             variances for the bottom and top corners respectively. Shooters were more accurate             shooting at bottom corners than at the top corners (67% vs 45%). These analyses helped             to identify key stick usage variables that predict accuracy during the execution of             stationary wrist shots. Further studies are needed to identify the whole body kinematic             patterns associated with the hockey stick kinematics.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'objectif premier de cette étude était d'identifier les             mouvements caractéristiques du bâton de hockey correspondant à la précision de tirs du             poignet stationnaire à travers différents niveaux d'habiletés. Un total de vingt-cinq             sujets ont fait parti de l'échantillon. Chacun d'eux ont dû réussir correctement dix             lancers dans chacune des quatre différentes cibles. La performance des sujets a été             évaluée en mesurant le déplacement du bâton et de la rondelle à l'aide de marqueur             réfléchissants qui était filmé à l'aide d'un système d'analyse du mouvement composé de             caméra infrarouge (Vicon®), le tout étant enregistré à 240 Hz. La cinématique du manche             et de la palette du bâton de hockey ont été analysées par le biais d'une analyse de             régression multiple en utilisant le niveau de précision comme étant la variable             dépendante. Les résultats démontrent que les joueurs les plus précis ont tendance à             modifier les paramètres de projection (orientation et vitesse de la rondelle), le             mécanisme de mise en charge du bâton ainsi que l'orientation de la palette pour obtenir             la trajectoire de rondelle désirée avec des modèles de prédiction pouvant expliqué             respectivement 40% et 76% de la variabilité de la précision pour les cibles inférieures             et supérieures. Les sujets étaient plus précis pour les cibles inférieures que pour les             cibles supérieures (67% vs 45%). Cette analyse a permis d'identifier les variables clés             pour effectuer un lancer du poignet stationnaire précis mais d'autres recherches doivent             être effectuées pour identifier les mouvements du corps qui sont associés avec la             cinématique du bâton de hockey.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rene A. Turcotte</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>David J. Pearsall</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x69h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm13p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4q77fv337"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>TCSIM: a top-down approach to mixed-signal circuits and systems design</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alhajj, Tarek</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Design methodologies have evolved over the years, especially due to             shrinking transistors in CMOS technology. This has encouraged the use of behavioural             modelling in Matlab and Simulink over other less accurate or time consuming options for             design and simulation, hence the development of TCSIM (Top-down Circuit Simulation In             Matlab). The following components are modelled for this initial prototype: the output             voltage limitation of operational amplifiers (opamps), the current limitation and             parasitic capacitances of operational transconductance amplifiers (OTAs), the finite and             nonlinear variation of on resistance in switches, and the nonideal behaviour of switched             capacitor (SC) integrators. This is complemented by an analysis of the noise in these             circuits. The models are verified with Cadence simulations and are shown to be both             accurate and easy to map to the circuit level. It is also possible to optimize complete             systems to efficiently meet specifications. The top-down methodology is demonstrated             with the design of a delta-sigma analog-to-digital converter (ADC) to be both accurate             and simple with TCSIM.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les methodologies de conception ont evolue au fil des             annees, notamment en raison de la diminution de la taille des transistors dans la             technologie CMOS. Ceci a favorise l'utilisation de la modelisation comportementale a             l'aide de Matlab et Simulink, en remplacement des anciennes techniques qui etaient moins             precises et demandaient plus de temps, ce qui a mene au developpement de TCSIM (Topdown             Circuit Simulation In Matlab). Dans le cadre de ce prototype initial, les composantes             suivantes ont ete modelisees: la limitation du voltage de sortie des amplificateurs             operationnels (opamps), la limitation du courant et de la capacitance parasitique des             amplificateurs-transconductance operationnels (OTAs), les variations finies et             non-lineaire de la resistance des interrupteurs et le comportement non-ideal des             integrateurs a condensateur commute. A ces modelisations s'ajoute une analyse du bruit             dans ces circuits. Les modeles ont ete valides a l'aide de simulations dans Cadence. Ces             simulations demontrent la precision des modeles mais aussi la facilite avec laquelle ils             peuvent etre transposes au niveau circuit. Les modeles permettent l'optimisation de             systemes complets en vue d'atteindre les specifications. La methodologie "top-down" est             illustree a l'aide du design d'un convertisseur analogue-a-digital (ADC) delta-sigma. Le             travail demontre la facilite avec laquelle ce design peut etre effectue grace a TCSIM.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gordon W. Roberts</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462815v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv337</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6m311s170"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wild edible plant consumption and age-related cataracts in a rural Lebanese elderly population: a case control study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zeitouny, Joelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Mediterranean diet is characterized by considerable diversity and high             consumption of wild leafy greens which are excellent sources of antioxidants, including             lutein and zeaxanthin. The latter are the only carotenoids present in the human lens and             observational and intervention studies suggest they may be protective against             age-related cataracts. To better understand the role of dietary diversity in general             (and lutein and zeaxanthin in particular) in preventing age-related cataracts and the             determinants of wild leafy greens' consumption, dietary and socioeconomic data were             collected from one hundred cases and one hundred controls randomly selected from Hermel,             a poor and fairly traditional Lebanese rural area. Results showed that dietary diversity             and antioxidants (including but not limited to lutein and zeaxanthin) are inversely             related to age-related cataracts and that wild leafy greens seem to contribute             substantially to the protection against age-related cataracts by optimizing nutrient and             antioxidant intake especially in those of low socio-economic status.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le régime Méditerranéen est caractérisé par une diversité             considérable et une consommation élevée de plantes vertes sauvages, qui constituent             d'excellentes sources d'antioxydants, y compris la lutéine et zéaxanthine. Ces-derniers             sont les seuls caroténoïdes présents dans la lentille humaine et des études             observationnelles et interventionnelles suggèrent qu'ils pourraient protéger contre la             cataracte liée à l'âge. Pour mieux comprendre le rôle de la diversité alimentaire en             général (et de la lutéine et zéaxanthine en particulier) dans la prévention de la             cataracte liée à l'âge et les déterminants de la consommation de plantes vertes             sauvages, des données socio-économiques et alimentaires ont été collectées de cent cas             et cent témoins sélectionnés arbitrairement de Hermel, une région rurale pauvre et             traditionnelle libanaise. Les résultats ont montré que la diversité alimentaire et les             antioxydants (y compris mais non limité à la lutéine et zéaxanthine) sont inversement             reliés à la cataracte liée à l'âge et que les plantes vertes sauvages sembleraient             contribuer substantiellement à la protection contre la cataracte liée à l'âge en             optimisant l'apport de nutriments et d'antioxydants, particulièrement chez les personnes             ayant un statut socio-économique peu élevé.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Timothy A. Johns</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Malek Afif El-Batal</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv309.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s170</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zk488"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vivre comme frères: Native-French alliances in the St Lawrence Valley, 1535-1667</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cook, Peter Laurence</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation addresses the question of how the Native peoples of the             St Lawrence River valley and the French colonizers who entered the region in the             sixteenth and seventeenth centuries formed and maintained intercultural alliances. It             explores the political cultures of the French and of the northern Algonquian and             Iroquoian peoples who occupied the region in this period as well as sixteenth-century             patterns of Native-French interaction in the Atlantic world before turning to an             analysis of the symbolic and institutional aspects of the alliance established between             the Innu, Algonquins, Hurons, and French in the early seventeenth century. This study's             attention to the classifications employed in Native and French political discourse and             to Native and French actors' manipulations of symbolic capital—a notion borrowed from             sociologist Pierre Bourdieu—leads to an emphasis on the centrality of the metaphor of             brotherhood in this Native-French alliance. The history of this metaphor and its             transformations are traced through the extensive geopolitical changes of the             mid-seventeenth century, up to the French-Haudenosaunee treaties of 1665–67.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette dissertation se penche sur la question des moyens par             lesquels les peuples autochtones de la vallée du Saint-Laurent et les colonisateurs             Français qui pénètrent dans la région aux XVIe et XVIIe siècles ont formé et entretenu             des alliances interculturelles. Elle examine les cultures politiques des Français et des             peuples algiques et iroquoiennes ainsi que les précédents créés au XVIe siècle par les             relations franco-amérindiennes dans l'espace atlantique, avant d'entreprendre une             analyse des aspects symboliques et institutionnelles de l'alliance établie au début du             XVIIe siècle impliquant les Innus, les Algonquins, les Hurons, et les Français. Cette             étude porte une attention particulière aux classifications qui se manifestent dans les             discours politiques des Amérindiens et des Français et aux façons dont les acteurs             manipulent le capital symbolique (notion empruntée au sociologue Pierre Bourdieu); elle             souligne en conséquence le rôle central de la métaphore de la fraternité dans cette             alliance franco-amérindienne. La thèse suit l'histoire de cette métaphore dans la             rhétorique des diplomates durant les changements géopolitiques du milieu du siècle,             jusqu'aux traités franco-iroquois de 1665–67.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Catherine Desbarats</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612r430.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk488</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History - Canadian</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awd376028q"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compression and security platform for the testing of wireless sensor network nodes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mihajlovic, Bojan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse étudie le test sur le terrain de noeuds de résaux de senseurs sans-fil (RSSF) afin d'obtenir un temps de vie accru. De tels noeuds opeèrent avec des limites strictes en énergie, cot, puissance en travail, et sont sensibles d'être attaqués. Alors que l'auto-test basé en logiciel (ATBL) a ses avantages sur des noeuds RSSF, l'efficacité en énergie peut être améliorée en comprimant les programes ATBL avant de les distribuer. Une parmi plusieurs méthodes de compression étudiées pour la tâche, l'algorithme BSTW avec codage Rice démontre des économies d'énergie, tout en nécessitant une faible quantité de mémoire et de bons ratios de compression. La sécurité du test est assurée à travers une approche à plusieurs niveaux qui utilise une puce émetteur-récepteur sans-fil sur lequel décharger les fonctions cryptographiques AES. Toute l'approche concernant la sécurité ne rajoute qu'un 2.5 pourcent de besoin en énergie pour la distribution du programme ATBL. Finalement, le protocol de test est créé pour combiner des commandes de test de haut niveau avec des méthodes de compression et de sécurité.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis considers the in-field testing of wireless sensor network (WSN) nodes as a means of providing increased network uptime. Such nodes operate with strict limits on energy, cost, computing power, and are prone to attack. While testing through software-based self-test (SBST) programs has advantages on WSN nodes, energy efficiency can be increased by compressing SBST programs before distributing them. Of several compression schemes considered for the task, the BSTW algorithm with Rice coding demonstrates node energy savings while providing a low memory footprint and good compression ratios. Test security is provided through a multi-layer scheme which uses a wireless transceiver chip to offload AES protocol cryptographic functions. The entire security scheme is found to add only approximately 2.5% to the energy needs of SBST program distribution. Finally, a testing protocol is created to combine high-level testing commands with the compression and security schemes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Katarzyna Radecka</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Zeljko Zilic</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s036h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd376028q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agb19f876r"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Music</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>As The Music Leaves No Scar: composing with models based on popular music: distillation and distantiation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Galaty, James G</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis has been written with the aim of integrating the two parallel paths which have characterized my formative years: on the one side an early contact with and practice of popular music, on the other, a more 'classical' training in music in a university context. This suggested a path of investigation within a song cycle for solo baritone and 17 musicians, where a musical space is extended beyond an imagined 'popular' world, through the creation of 'models' – based upon my own popular-music inspired songs – which are then set into 'perspective' through various combinations and transformations. The form of the work, based on an original poetic narrative of artistic self-searching and alienation, charts a path of perspectives that moves from the original popular space to others that are increasingly remote and speculative, which eventually acquire a new autonomy.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse a pour but de faire converger les deux voies jusqu'ici parallèles qui ont caractérisé mes années de formation musicale: d'une part une pratique acquise jeune de la musique populaire et de l'autre une formation plus 'classique' dans un cadre universitaire. Celà m'a suggéré un mode d'investigation particulier exemplifié par la composition d'un cycle de chansons pour baryton solo et dix-sept musiciens. Dans cette oeuvre, j'ai imaginé un espace musical se développant au-delà de l'idiome 'populaire' par la création de 'modèles' – eux-mêmes distillés de mes propres chansons inspirés de l'idiome populaire –  qui sont littéralement 'mis en perspective' par les biais de divers processus de combinaison et de transformation. Issue de la structure poétique de la narration que j'ai écrite pour cette occasion et qui traite de questionnement identitaire et d'aliénation, la forme de l'oeuvre s'articule au fil de différentes perspectives qui s'éloignent graduellement de l'espace artistique populaire vers des régions éloignées plus spéculatives qui acquirèrent leur autonomie propre.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Denys Bouliane</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430746r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f876r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848t29s"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparison of flexible electrogoniometers to a 3D optical tracking system for measurements of ankle angles during level walking and running</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ouckama, Ryan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Accurate measurement of joint motion is highly desirable for human gait analysis. Marker based optical motion capture is currently a gold standard in human gait studies but limited to a small field of view, exclusively in a laboratory setting.  Where quantitative assessment is needed in the unconstrained environments (eg. factory floor, clinical wards), strain-gauge electrogoniometers provide portable operation and simple measurement of joint angles. These modern electrogoniometers have overcome problems associated with prior generations of fixed axis goniometers. The purpose of this study was to examine the kinematics obtained between the optically based 3D system with strain guage based elgons, for the measure of ankle angles. Ten subjects completed 20 barefoot walking and running trials with simultaneous recording from both measurement devices. Data revealed high correlations between devices (r2=0.78-0.97) and relatively small degrees of error (&lt;2.5 degrees) particularly at slower walking speeds.  Electrogoniometers may be considered as reliable and accurate devices for use in gait studies.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Une  mesure juste et fidèle du mouvement des articulations est  extrêmement importante pour les différentes études d'analyse  de la démarche humaine. À ce jour, la capture optique du mouvement  à l'aide de marqueurs est un standard pour les études sur la démarche humaine, mais elle est sujette à des erreurs reliées au mouvement de la peau ou au mauvais placement des marqueurs réfléchissants. Une alternative à cette méthode consiste à utiliser des électrogoniomètres flexibles. Ces derniers sont portables et plus simples d'utilisation, mais ont tendance à provoquer  un niveau indésirable de rétroaction. L'objectif de cette étude est d'examiner les différentes caractéristiques de ces deux techniques durant la mesure des angles de la cheville durant le cycle de marche, ce qui permettra de tester la validité des résultats obtenus avec les deux méthodes dans les études sur la démarche humaine. Dix sujets ont complété vingt essais de marche et de course à pieds nus alors que les résultats étaient enregistrés utilisant les deux techniques. Ces résultats présentent de très forte corrélations (R2=0.78-0.97), particulièrement à vitesse de marche, en plus de démontrer des différences non significatives entre les événements spécifiques à la démarche humaine. Les électrogoniomètres peuvent donc être considérés comme des appareils justes et fidèles pour l'étude de la démarche humaine.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>David J. Pearsall</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x708.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t29s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214r991"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les effets de la politique étrangère américaine sur la démocratisation du Moyen-Orient : le cas du Middle East Partnership Initiative</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Théroux-Samuel, Ariane</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ce mémoire porte sur les effets de la politique étrangère américaine après le 11 septembre 2001 sur la démocratisation du Moyen-Orient. Plus particulièrement, l'auteure y examine le cas du Middle East Partnership Initiative (MEPI), un programme d'assistance à la démocratie mis en œuvre en 2002 dans le cadre de la vaste campagne de promotion démocratique de l'administration Bush, lancée peu après les événements de 2001. Après une analyse théorique des éléments reliés au processus de démocratisation et une rétrospective de la place accordée à la promotion de la démocratie dans l'historique récente des affaires étrangères des États-Unis, l'auteure introduit les différents aspects de la nouvelle rhétorique pro-démocratique de l'administration Bush, communément appelée le Freedom Agenda. En décrivant et en analysant les programmes, l'évolution et les priorités du MEPI, ainsi qu'en examinant les critiques qui lui ont été adressées et les défis que l'initiative devra affronter dans les années à venir, l'auteure réussit à démontrer que les effets positifs de ce genre de programme de démocratisation sont difficiles à prouver, les avancées démocratiques « réelles » étant peu nombreuses au Moyen-Orient à ce jour.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis focuses on the effects of American foreign policy on the “democratization” of the Middle East in the post-September-2001 period. The author examines the case of the Middle East Partnership Initiative, a democracy assistance program created in 2002 within the context of the vast democracy promotion campaign undertaken by the Bush administration in response to the attacks of September 11, 2001. Following a theoretical analysis of the elements related to the process of democratization and a retrospective of democracy promotion in the recent history of the United States, the author introduces the different aspects of President Bush's new pro-democracy rhetoric, known as the Freedom Agenda. In describing and analyzing MEPI's programs, evolution and priorities, as well as its main shortcomings and challenges ahead, the author demonstrates that the positive effects of such democratization programs are difficult to show as there have been few “real” democratic advancements in the Middle East so far.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rex J. Brynen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh592.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r991</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Political Science - International Law and Relations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395wb22m"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Selling youth: how market research at the J. Walter Thompson company framed what it meant to be a child (and an adult) in 20th Century America</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gennaro, Stephen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Selling Youth: How Market Research at the J. Walter Thompson Company Framed What It Meant to Be a Child (and an Adult) in 20th Century America.  This thesis examines the marketing discourse of “perpetual adolescence,” a term, which describes the ways in which the advertising industry trains all people, young and old, to be consumers of “youth” in a marketplace that privileges adolescence over adulthood; with ultimate goal of achieving access to an adult wallet that is controlled by a consumer with child-like sensibilities.  The discourse of perpetual adolescence came to prominence after WWII when drastic changes in population and the emergence of a new middle class were influential factors in shifting ideologies surrounding what it meant to be a child, a teenager, and an adult.  One of the key institutions in the crystallizing of new ideologies about “youth” was the advertising agency, who through advertisements framed and defined the family unit in postwar America to American consumers.  The thesis looks specifically at the interior of one of the largest advertising agencies of the 20th century the J. Walter Thompson Company.  Through an examination of their practices in consumer research with behaviourist John B. Watson, the Consumer Panel, the Personality Profile Project, and a series of advertisements produced for The Seven-Up Company between 1942 and 1968, the J. Walter Thompson Company in the post war period aimed to further expand the youth market into the more profitable age category of 25-44 year olds by selling “youthfulness” to adults.  Consumers were promised the romanticized sensibilities of youth but were only given the destabilized identity of adolescence.  Explicitly, J. Walter Thompson sold images of “youth” to adults who longed to be young again.  In doing so they implicitly “took the lid off” of a time that adults were supposed to have already conquered—adolescence—by drawing them back to a destabilized identity that</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Vendre la jeunesse : comment la recherche de marché au J. Walter Thompson Company a encadré ce qui veut dire être un enfant (et un adulte) en Amérique pendant le 20e siècle.   Cette thèse nous permet d'examiner le discours, issu du marketing, que nous désignons par « adolescence perpétuelle ». Nous avons conçu cette expression pour décrire les différentes formules utilisées par l'industrie publicitaire afin d'apprendre aux gens — tant les jeunes comme les personnes âgées — à devenir des consommateurs de « jouvence » dans un marché qui privilégie l'adolescence à l'âge adulte. Le but étant l'accès au portefeuille du consommateur adulte ayant des sensibilités d'enfant. Le discours de « l'adolescence perpétuelle » a toujours été présent dans la publicité, mais est devenu déterminant après la Deuxième Guerre mondiale. Des changements majeurs en ce qui concerne la population ainsi que l'émergence d'une nouvelle classe moyenne influencent de façon décisive les changements idéologiques de l'époque entourant la conception de ce que veut dire être un enfant, un adolescent et un adulte. Une des industries clefs permettant la cristallisation des nouvelles idéologies concernant l'idée de jeunesse a été l'agence publicitaire. Cette dernière à travers la publicité encadre et définit la cellule familiale des consommateurs de l'Amérique d'après-guerre. Notre thèse se concentre plus spécifiquement sur l'une des plus grandes agences publicitaires du vingtième siècle : la J. Walter Thompson Company. À travers l'examen des pratiques concernant la recherche sur le consommateur avec le behavioriste John B. Watson, le Consumer Panel, le Personality Profile Project et une série d'annonces publicitaires produites pour les compagnies Seven Up et Ford entre 1942 et 1968, nous pouvons dire que la J. Walter Thompson Company, en cette période d'après-guerre, cherche à étendre son marché à une catégorie d'âge ayant un pouvoir</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jonathan Sterne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf58x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb22m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xm48w"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of distinct and conserved features between ciliate and vertebrate telomerases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marie-Egyptienne, Delphine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Telomeres are nucleoprotein structures that protect the ends of chromosomes from recombination and fusion. Telomeres are prefentially maintained by the enzyme telomerase. Telomerase is a reverse transcriptase, minimally composed of two core components, a catalytic subunit, TElomerase Reverse Transcriptase (TERT) and an RNA subunit, Telomerase RNA (TR) that carries the template for the replenishment of the telomeres. Telomerase is present throughout evolution, from ciliates and yeasts to vertebrates. Likely because it performs reverse transcription to maintain telomeres in these organisms, telomerases are remarkably conserved in terms of structure as well as in term of function. Nevertheless, some species-specific differences exist between telomerases from different model organisms. Studying these differences can deepen our knowledge of the telomerase enzyme, critical for human diseases such as cancer.  The conservation and distinction between telomerases was explored by studying the functional conservation of a pseudoknot structure between Tetrahymena and human TRs and the response of mouse and human cells to the mutations of the subunits of telomerase.  The hypothesis that the pseudoknot domains of the Tetrahymena and human TRs (tTR and hTR, respectively) may be functionally interchangeable was tested by constructing a chimeric TR (htTR) where the hTR pseudoknot domain was exchanged for tTR pseudoknot domain. htTR exhibited a weak, non processive telomerase activity in vitro, and was defective in telomere elongation, demonstrating that the Tetrahymena and human pseudoknots are not fully functionally interchangeable.  Then, the importance of telomerase for cellular proliferation in mouse compared to human cells was investigated by studying the cellular consequences of mutating each core subunit of the mouse telomerase. First, the TERT-DN, a dominant-negative catalytically-inactive mutant of mTERT, was stably introduced into a mouse cell line (CB17) whose telomere</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les télomères sont des structures nucléoprotéiques qui protègent les extrémités des chromosomes contre la recombinaison et la fusion.  Les télomères sont maintenus de manière préférentielle par l'enzyme télomérase. La télomérase est une transcriptase inverse, composée minimalement de deux constituants essentiels, la sous-unité catalytique TElomerase Reverse Transcriptase (TERT) et la sous-unité ARN, Telomerase RNA (TR) qui comprend la matrice pour la génération des télomères. La télomérase est présente à travers l'évolution, des ciliés au vertébrés en passant par les levures. Vraisemblablement parce que l'enzyme utilise un mécanisme de transcription inverse pour maintenir les télomères dans ces organismes, l'enzyme est remarquablement conservée, tant en terme de structure qu'en terme de fonction. Néanmoins, quelques différences propres aux espèces existent entre les télomérases d'organismes modèles. Étudier ces différences peut approfondir notre connaissance de la télomérase, une enzyme cruciale pour des maladies humaines tel que le cancer.  La conservation et la distinction entre les télomérases furent explorées en étudiant la conservation fonctionnelle d'une structure de pseudonœud entre les sous-unités TRs de Tétrahyména et de l'humain, et en étudiant la réponse des cellules murines et humaines à des mutations dans les deux sous-unités essentielles de la télomérase.  L'hypothèse que les domaines pseudonoeuds de l'ARN de la télomérase  de Tétrahyména et de l'humain (tTR et hTR, respectivement) soient fonctionnellement interchangeables a été testée en construisant un TR chimérique (htTR) où le domaine pseudonoeud de hTR a été échangé avec le domaine pseudonoeud de tTR. htTR a démontré une faible activité non processive in vitro et était défectif en terme d'élongation des télomères, démontrant que les pseudonoeuds de Tétrahyména et de l'humain ne sont pas complètement fonctionnel</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chantal Autexier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1071831.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm48w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj139480q"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>X-ray observations of young neutron stars</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gonzalez, Marjorie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les propriétés extrêmes des étoiles à neutrons font de ces objets compacts des émetteurs efficaces dans toutes les longueurs d'ondes du spectre électromagnétique. Cependant, elles ont historiquement été étudiées principalement dans les ondes radios. Les étoiles à neutrons ayant un fort champ magnétique (appelées "magnétars") ont des caractéristiques remarquablement différentes du reste de la population: elles n'émettent pas d'ondes radios mais elles présentent de grandes quantités de radiations à haute énergie causées par le champ magnétique. Pour ce projet, nous avons étudié les propriétés des rayons X provenant de différents types de jeunes étoiles à neutrons, découvert des caractéristiques inattendues, contraint le comportement à long terme et enfin trouvé des nébuleuses associés aux étoiles à neutrons.  Tout d'abord, nous avons observé les étoiles à neutrons PSR B0154+61 et PSR J1119-6127. Ces deux objets ont un fort champ magnétique mais ils émettent cependant des ondes radios normales. Pour la seconde, des émissions de rayons X thermiques ont également été découvertes, ce qui suggère les possibles effets du champ magnétique sur la surface. Aussi, cette source est maintenant la plus jeune étoile à neutrons émettant une radiation thermique depuis sa surface. Il n'y a cependant aucune preuve permettant d'associer ces sources aux caractéristiques des magnétars. La raison de cette différence, toujours incomprise et sujette à de nombreux débats, pose un énorme défi à notre compréhension de l'évolution des étoiles à neutrons et de leurs mécanismes d'émission.  Ensuite, nous avons également étudié les propriétés à long terme du "pulsar anormal à Rayons X" 4U 0142+61, que l'on pense être un magnétar. Nous trouvons des changements de presque toutes ces caractéristiques d'émission sur les 7 dernières années. Les variations observées sont en accord avec les prédictions suggérées par$</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The extreme physical properties of neutron stars make them efficient emitters at all wavelengths of the electromagnetic spectrum and, traditionally, they have been extensively studied at radio wavelengths. The neutron stars with the highest estimated magnetic fields (so-called "magnetars") have remarkably different characteristics from the rest of the population: they emit no persistent radio emission but show large amounts of high-energy radiation that is thought to be powered by their large magnetic fields. For this thesis we have studied the X-ray emission properties of various types of young neutron stars, discovering unusual characteristics, constraining long-term behaviour and finding associated nebulae.   We have observed the neutron stars PSR B0154+61 and PSR J1119-6127, which have high magnetic fields but otherwise emit normal radio emission. For the latter, unusual thermal X-ray emission was discovered that points to the possible effects of a magnetic  field on the surface. Also, this source now represents the youngest neutron star from which thermal emission from the surface has been detected. However, we find no evidence for clear magnetar-like characteristics in these sources. The reason for this discrepancy, as yet unclear and a matter of debate, poses a great challenge to our understanding of the evolution of neutron stars and their emission mechanisms.   We have also studied the long-term properties of the "anomalous X-ray pulsar" 4U 0142+61, thought to be a magnetar. We find that changes are present in almost all of its emission characteristics over the last 7 years. The observed changes agree with the general predictions made by the magnetar model of such sources. However, the details of these changes suggest that further work is still needed on the expected emission from these objects.  In addition, neutron stars are seen to power extended structures, called pulsar wind nebulae (PWNe), which can radiate large amounts of high-energy emission. He</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Victoria Kaspi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g288d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139480q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Astronomy and Astrophysics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p7522"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Monitoring and simulating nutrient removal in a constructed wetland</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kroeger, Anne-Caroline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Phosphorus contamination of surface waters is a primary water quality concern in the agricultural watershed of Pike River in southern Québec. Surface waters from Walbridge creek, a tributary of the Pike River, were diverted into a small constructed wetland consisting of three basins laid out in series to evaluate nutrient (nitrogen and phosphorus) retention within the system. Hydraulic and nutrient loading rates to the constructed wetland were highly variable in time, with peak rates of loading occurring during runoff events in the watershed, with a mean hydraulic loading rate of 25 cm/day. The wetland retained 8.47 kg total phosphorus, which corresponded to 44 % of total phosphorus inputs (19.3 kg) and it also retained 132.5 kg nitrates, which represented 13 % of nitrate inputs (995 kg) to the wetland, over 4 years (2003-06) of seasonal (May-Nov) operation. Annual mean nutrient retention rates (1.7 g total P m-2 year-1 and 27.3 g NO3- m-2 year-1) were within the range of values reported in the literature for constructed wetlands treating agricultural runoff. This study therefore provided additional evidence supporting the use of small constructed wetlands as nutrient traps in agricultural watersheds in a moderate Canadian climate. A first generation wetland model was also developed using MATLABTM programming language to simulate phosphorus cycling in the wetland. The model was evaluated as a prediction tool of effluent particulate phosphorus and ortho-phosphate concentrations. Much more work needs to be done to improve the accuracy of the model simulations.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Sur le plan de la qualité de l'eau, la première source de préoccupation dans le bassin agricole de la rivière aux Brochets concerne les teneurs élevées en phosphore.  Une partie des eaux du ruisseau Walbridge, un tributaire de la rivière aux Brochets, a été détourné vers un marais filtrant aménagé en dérivation du ruisseau. Le marais est composé de trois bassins en série et la rétention des éléments nutritifs (azote et phosphore) été évaluée dans ce système. Les apports hydrauliques et nutritifs ont été mesurés de façon continue durant la période de croissance végétale (Mai-Nov) de 4 années (2003-06). En moyenne, l'apport hydraulique au marais filtrant était de 25 cm/jour. La rétention de phosphore total (8.47 kg) dans le système représentait 44% des apports en phosphore total (19.3 kg), tandis que la rétention de nitrates (132.5 kg) représentait 13 % des apports en nitrates (995 kg). Les taux de rétention moyens exprimés par unité de surface du système (1.7 g phosphore total m-2 année-1 et 27.4 g NO3- m-2 année-1) se comparent aux valeurs de la littérature. Cette étude apporte des données additionnelles pour faire la preuve que les marais filtrants en climat tempéré canadien ont la capacité d'assainir les cours d'eau en milieu agricole. Un modèle a aussi été développé, à l'aide du langage de programmation MATLABTM, pour simuler le cycle du phosphore dans le marais. Il reste encore beaucoup de travail à faire pour améliorer les prédictions du modèle.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chandra A. Madramootoo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss713.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p7522</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bx256"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Potential for cold storage of horticultural commodities in tropical countries</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Connolly-Boutin, Liette</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une évaluation d'entreposage de tomates à court terme a été effectuée à Coimbatore, dans l'état du Tamil Nadu en Inde, dans le but d'aider les fermiers à pallier la saturation cyclique du marché des fruits et légumes frais. Des fermiers ont entreposé leur récolte de tomates dans un entrepôt frigorifique commercial situé dans la ville, ainsi que dans un entrepôt frigorifique expérimental situé dans le Tamil Nadu Agricultural University dans la même ville indienne. Le but de l'expérience était d'étudier les caractéristiques d'entreposage du produit, ainsi que d'évaluer les bénéfices économiques liés à l'adoption d'une telle intervention. La température, l'humidité relative et le sort des produits horticoles ont été surveillés. Avec l'augmentation des temps d'entreposage, la proportion des fruits frais ayant une valeur marchande a baissé considérablement; la plupart des pertes était due à des infections microbiennes. Les différences dans les conditions ambiantes des deux entrepôts n'ont pas eu d'effet considérable sur les pertes de fruits frais dues à l'entreposage. Une analyse économique a démontré que l'entreposage à court terme n'aidera pas les fermiers à moins que des mesures supplémentaires soient adoptées afin de réduire les pertes microbiennes durant les manipulations post-récoltes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>An evaluation of the use of short-term cold storage of tomatoes to tide over the cyclical market glut of horticultural products was conducted in Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India. Farmers stored their harvest at a rental commercial cold-storage facility in the city and at an experimental cold store at the Tamil Nadu Agricultural University in Coimbatore. The goal was to study the storage characteristics of the produce as well as to assess the economic benefits of adopting such an intervention. The temperature and relative humidity conditions at both locations and the fate of the produce were monitored. The proportion of marketable produce diminished significantly as the storage period increased, with major losses occurring due to microbial damage. Differences in the air conditions at the locations did not have a significant effect on the storage-related losses of produce. Economic analysis showed that short-term cold storage would not aid farmers unless measures were taken to reduce the microbiological losses during postharvest handling.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>G. S. Vijaya Raghavan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h72r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx256</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Agricultural</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5x21tj21k"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implications of preoperative pulmonary function testing for post liver transplant outcomes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ghali, Maged</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>RÉSUMÉ  Les complications respiratoires sont fréquentes après les greffes et peuvent amener un taux accru de mortalité.  Les tests de fonction pulmonaire sont maintenant obtenus régulièrement en phase pré-opératoire.  Cependant, leur pertinence dans les cas de greffes hépatique est inconnue.  Le but de cette étude est d'évaluer la capacité de prédiction des tests de fonction pulmonaire pré-opératoires sur les complications post-opératoires, la durée de séjour aux soins intensifs et les risques de mortalité post-greffe hépatique.  Cette étude rétrospective fut menée à un site de référence pour les greffes hépatiques, soit l'Hôpital Royal Victoria.  Nous avons révisé toutes les opérations (531) qui furent effectués chez 462 patients jusqu'au 30 juin 2006.  Nous avons considéré les décès, les complications pulmonaires, ainsi que la durée d'intubation et la durée de séjour aux soins intensifs en tant que variables dépendants.  Les facteurs prédictives étaient des tests de fonction pulmonaire, l'âge, le sexe, l'origine ethnique, l'histoire de tabagisme, le type de maladie hépatique sous-jacent, le score MELD et le temps ischémique de la greffe.  Nous avons utilisé des modèles de régression logistique et de Cox afin d'évaluer la capacité prédictive indépendante des tests de fonction pulmonaire ainsi que des autres variables.    205 patients avaient des données complètes de leurs tests de fonction respiratoire en pré-opératoire.   Une réduction dans la capacité pulmonaire totale étant associée de façon significative à la durée de séjour aux soins intensifs, ainsi qu'une durée accrue d'intubation et à un taux accru de mortalité.  Ainsi, une diminution de 10% dans la capacité pulmonaire totale respiratoire en pré-opératoire était associée de façon indépendante à une augmentation de 43% du risque de mortalité.  Une augmentation du volume résiduel, ainsi qu'une augmentation du temps ischémique et</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>ABSTRACT Pulmonary complications are common post-transplant and may lead to increased mortality. Pulmonary function tests (PFTs) are routinely obtained preoperatively, but their usefulness in liver transplantation is unknown. The objective of this study was to assess the impact of preoperative PFTs on postoperative pulmonary complications (PPCs), ICU stay, and death post-liver transplant.  This single site historical cohort study encompassed all 531 liver transplants performed in 462 patients at the Royal Victoria Hospital through June 30, 2006. Outcomes included death, PPCs, and length of intubation and ICU stay. Independent variables  including PFTs, age, gender, race, smoking history, etiology of liver disease, MELD score, and ischemia time were used in logistic regression and Cox proportional hazards models to assess their impact on the outcomes listed above.  205 patients had complete PFT data.  Decreased total lung capacity (TLC) was a predictor of increased length of ICU stay, duration of intubation, and mortality. A 10% decrease in TLC increased the mortality risk by 43%. Increased residual volume (RV), cold ischemia time, and age were predictors of mortality. Predictors of prolonged ICU stay or intubation were TLC, MELD score, male gender and cold ischemia time.  PFTs were not significant predictors of PPCs.    PFTs do not predict pulmonary complications but predict length of ICU stay and intubation, as well as mortality.  PFTs may reflect the severity of underlying liver disease as well as intrinsic lung disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kevin Schwartzman</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v834p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tj21k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av118rh265"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Estimating resilience of Amazonian ecosystems using remote sensing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oswald, David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un modèle de résilience écologique de l'écosystème amazonien a été développé, intégrant des processus tels que le couplage atmosphère-biosphère avec des facteurs de perturbation tels que le feu et les changements climatiques. L'objectif de cette étude était d'évaluer l'état des écosystèmes dans l'état du Mato Grosso. Une possible transition de la forêt à la savane a été examinée en utilisant des données de télédétection.   Il y a eu une réduction de l'EVI pendant la saison sèche dans le Mato Grosso, de mai à août pour chaque année d'étude. La sécheresse de 2005 a provoqué une réduction de l'EVI plus importante que la normale, en plus d'augmenter la fréquence des feux (48, 682) par rapport à 2006 (28, 466). Il y a eu une augmentation des incendies avec la distance par rapport aux principales autoroutes, ce qui est contraire aux résultats des études précédentes. Il a été estimé qu'il y a eu une réduction du nombre d'écosystèmes forestiers entre 2001 et 2006.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A model for ecological resilience of Amazonian ecosystems was developed integrating processes such as atmosphere-biosphere coupling with disturbance factors such as fire and climate change.  The focus of the study was on the status of ecosystems in the state of Mato Grosso and the possibility of forest to savannah transition was examined using remote sensing data.  There was a consistent reduction in EVI during the dry season in Mato Grosso – May through August of each year. The 2005 drought demonstrated a greater dry-season reduction in EVI than normal and there was also a higher frequency of fires (48, 682) than in 2006 (28, 466).  There was an increase in fires with distance from the major highways – which is contrary to the results of previous studies.  It was estimated that there was a reduction in the amount of forest ecosystems from 2001 to 2006.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Garry Peterson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752k663.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh265</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arn3014168"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Methods for measuring the acoustic response of wind instruments</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Buckiewicz-Smith, Alexander</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis studies methods to take acoustical measurements of wind instrument bodies and mouthpieces. Acoustic responses and existing measurement methods are reviewed. Multiple- and single-microphone measurement techniques are compared with a discussion of object-length limitations and frequency response.  Impulse response measurements using a complex input signal are discussed and signals used for measuring room acoustics are reviewed. Construction and deconvolution methods for several types of signals are specified and the effects of signal degradation on measurements are discussed.  A novel pulse reflectometry technique that can use these signals as stimulus is presented. The signals are used in a waveguide model which simulates adverse measurement scenarios and calculated impedances are compared. Model measurements are then compared with actual reflection function measurements of two fabricated test objects to show the limitations of pulse reflectometry when calculating the impedance of long objects.  Viscothermal losses and open-end radiation characteristics measured using a pulse reflectometry setup are then compared with their theoretically predicted values. Finally, the input impedance calculated from several saxophone mouthpieces are presented and a novel method for measuring the reed resonance frequency of a mouthpiece is shown.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse étudie des méthodes pour prendre des mesures acoustiques des corps et embouchures d'instruments à vent.  Les réponses acoustiques et les méthodes existantes de mesure sont passées en revue. Mesures de multiples pressions et pression unique sont contrastées par un discussion des limitations sur la longueur de l'objet et la réponse en fréquences.  Les mesures de réponse d'impulsion employant un signal d'entrée complexe sont discutée et des signaux utilisés pour mesurer l'acoustique de salles sont passés en revue. Les méthodes de construction et de déconvolution pour plusieurs types de signaux sont spécifiés et les façons dont la dégradation des signaux affecte les mesures sont discutées.  Une nouvelle technique de réflectométrie d'impulsion qui peut employer ces signaux comme stimulus est présentée. Les signaux sont employés dans un modèle de guide d'ondes qui simule les scénarios défavorables de mesures et calculent les impédances. Des mesures de modèles sont alors comparées aux mesures réelles de fonction de réflexion de deux prototypes fabriqués pour montrer les limitations de la réflectométrie d'impulsion lors de calculs de l'impédance de longs objets.  Les pertes viscothermiques et les caractéristiques de rayonnement d'extrémité ouverte mesurées en utilisant une installation de réflectométrie d'impulsion sont alors comparées à leurs valeurs théoriques prévues. En conclusion, l'impédance d'entrée calculée à partir de plusieurs embouchures de saxophones sont présentées ainsi qu'une nouvelle méthode pour mesurer la fréquence tubulaire de résonance d'une embouchure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gary Scavone</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz29w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3014168</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Acoustics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv935576z"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Novel approaches towards conversion of organics in supercritical water</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sobhy Ramadan, Amr Mohamed</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des nouveaux approches et systèmes expérimentaux ont été appliqués pour étudier et analyser la conversion de certains produits organiques choisis dans l'eau supercritique (SCW). Des flammes à haute pression d'air-méthanol ont été produites dans une cellule originale à flamme visible (VFC) construite pour la première fois par des composants disponibles sur le marché. Des images originales de flamme dans l'eau supercritique SCW, prises par un appareil-photo (NIR) à proche-Infrarouge, ont été utilisées pour analyser l'allumage, les caractéristiques, et l'extinction de la flamme. Des nouvelles données ont été également rapportées sur la formation de suie à partir de la combustion du naphtalène et la génération des oxydes d'azote (NOx) dans l'eau SCW. La cellule hydrothermique d'enclume de diamant à micro-échelle (DAC) et la microscopie Raman ont été combinées dans une nouvelle approche pour l'observation in-situ et l'analyse des processus de SCW du naphtalène et du decachlorobiphenyl (10-CB). Une source d'excitation Raman (laser) de NIR (785nm) a fourni une position de compromis adéquate dans les spectres Raman obtenus entre la forte fluorescence des matières organiques lorsqu'elles sont irradiées par rayonnements laser visible et l'interférence de la bande large d'eau avec les rayonnements infrarouge. La donnée obtenue à partir du système DAC-Raman a été utilisée pour identifier la phase et les changements chimiques dans le système organique-SCW. Des résultats originaux indiquant la dégradation de 10-CB en présence de méthanol ont été obtenus. Des réacteurs tubulaires en lots (TBRs) ont été utilisés pour reproduire des expériences DAC-Raman sur la 10-CB sous des pressions pratiques et avec des concentrations précises pour obtenir des quantités suffisantes aux analyses quantitatives. Des nouveaux résultats ont montrés que la présence de 25% en méthanol par volume permet la réduction de plus de 56% en oxyg</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Novel experimental systems and approaches were applied to study and analyze the conversion of selected organics in supercritical water (SCW). High-pressure methanol-air flames were generated in a new and original Visual Flame Cell (VFC) designed and constructed using common commercially-available components. Original SCW flame images, collected using a near-Infrared (NIR) camera, were used to analyze flame ignition, flame characteristics, and flame extinction. New data were also obtained on soot formation and generation of nitrogen oxides (NOx) during the combustion of naphthalene in SCW.    The micro-scale hydrothermal diamond anvil cell (DAC) and Raman microscopy were combined in a novel approach for the in-situ monitoring and analysis of SCW processes involving naphthalene and decachlorobiphenyl (10-CB). A NIR (785nm) Raman excitation source (laser) provided the needed middle ground between a strong fluorescence background from organic species irradiated by lasers in the visible range and the water peak interference experienced with infrared (IR) sources. Data collected with the DAC-Raman system were used to identify phase and chemical changes in the SCW-organic system. Original results indicating the degradation of 10-CB in the presence of methanol were obtained.       Tubular batch reactors (TBRs) were used to reproduce the DAC-Raman experiments with 10-CB under practical pressures and precise concentrations for obtaining larger reaction product volumes for quantitative analyses. New results showed that the presence of 25% methanol by volume leads to over 56% reduction in oxygen demand for total conversion of 10-CB in faster, cleaner, less corrosive, and lower temperature conditions.  This work is an integration of information from three separate experimental systems for practical understanding of SCW as a potential tool for environmental remediation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roderick I. L. Guthrie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t914t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935576z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Environmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g771r"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A study of internal defibrillation efficacy using finite element analysis: a 3D isotropic finite element model of the myocardium electric fields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Golshayan, Maryam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La fibrillation ventriculaire (FV) est un état dans lequel la cavité inférieure du coeur montre une motion asynchrone et chaotique, empêchant le coeur de pomper le sang et l'oxygène au corps. La FV est considérée comme un arrêt cardiaque soudain, responsable de la mort subite de 300,000 personnes chaque année aux Etats-Unis. Afin d'inverser cette condition mortelle, le recours le plus efficace est la délivrance d'un choc électrique directement au niveau du coeur à l'aide d'un Défibrillateur Cardioverteur Implantable (DCI). Le principal problème de l'utilisation des DCIs est le placement des électrodes défibrillateurs pour permettre au courant d'être conduit optimalment à travers du muscle cardiaque, en particulier, le myocarde ventriculaire gauche. Selon l'hypothèse de la masse critique, la défibrillation sera réussi quand 75% du tissu de myocarde est inactivé par le choc de défibrillation. Le seuil de défibrillation ou la tension efficace minimale exigée pour donner des résultats réussis est suggéré d'être liés à la distribution du gradient de la tension myocardique, toutefois, il n'a pas été mesurée. En outre, le but est de maintenir le seuil de défibrillation aussi bas que possible pour essayer de maximiser le succès de la défibrillation, réduire au minimum le risque des dommages de myocarde et des arythmies cardiaques provoqués par des chocs à haute intensité, et aussi permettre de réduire la taille de la batterie ainsi que prolonger la durée de la vie utile du dispositif. De diverses techniques numériques ont été utilisées pour modeler le coeur afin de résoudre les équations régissant requises pour obtenir la distribution de gradient de la tension myocardique pendant la défibrillation. La méthode des éléments finis (FEM) a été d'intérêt particulier car elle peut gérer les domaines irréguliers, les hétérogénéité de matériel, et les conditions aux limites complexe de problèmes dans la bioélec</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Ventricle fibrillation (VF) is a condition in which the heart's lower chambers show an unsynchronized and chaotic motion which prevents the heart from pumping blood and oxygen to the body. VF is considered a sudden cardiac arrest and it is responsible for 300,000 sudden deaths in the USA yearly. The most effective way of reversing this life threatening condition is to apply an electrical shock directly to the heart using an Implantable Cardioverter-Defibrillator (ICD). The main issue in using ICDs is the placement of the defibrillating electrodes so that the current can be optimally channeled through the cardiac muscle, particularly in the left ventricular myocardium. According to the critical mass hypothesis, defibrillation will be successful when 75% of the myocardium tissue is halted by the defibrillation shock. The defibrillation threshold (DFT) or the minimum effective voltage required for successful results is suggested to be related to the myocardial voltage gradient (VG) distribution, but it has not been quantified. Moreover, the goal is to keep the DFT as low as possible to try to maximize the success of defibrillation, minimize the chance of myocardium damage and cardiac arrhythmias caused by  high-intensity shocks, and also potentially reduce the battery size and as well as prolong the device's useful lifespan.  Various numerical techniques have been used to model the heart to solve the governing equations required to obtain the myocardium VG distribution during electrical defibrillation. The Finite Element Method (FEM) has been of particular interest since it can handle the irregular domains, material inhomogeneities, and complex boundary conditions of problems in bioelectricity. In this thesis, a finite element model of the heart tissue is constructed in order to study and optimize the defibrillation mechanism. The modelling process starts with a surface reconstruction based on radial basis function interpolation to generate the triangular surface me</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steve J. McFee</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt32v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g771r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8p58pg734"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Design, synthesis, and characterization of new fluorescent probes for in vivo redox visualization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Oleynik, Paul</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nous avons initié un programme de recherche qui a pour but de développer des sondes fluorescentes, sensibles aux radicaux libres, qui soient solubles dans les solutions lipidiques. Ces sondes devront pouvoir rapporter les activités anti-oxidantes des bi-couches lipidiques. Ce travail fournit des informations importantes pour la conception rationnelle de colorants dérivés du pyrrométhane qui pourront servir d'indicateurs fluorescents "on-off" de la visualisation des réactions redox. Dans cette thèse, nous rapportons les propriétés du nouvel indicateur Trolox-PM605 (B-TOH) qui montre un comportement fluorescent  "on-off" marqué en présence de radicaux en solutions homogènes et micro-homogènes. Les spectres d'absorption et de fluorescence, les taux de fluorescence quantique, et la durée de vie de la fluorescence pour cette sonde quand dissoute dans des solvants organiques ainsi que dans des vésicules lipidiques de dimirystoyl de phoshatidylcholine (DMPC) en suspensions dans l'eau sont également rapportées.  Les propriétés analogues photophysiques du PM605 (le précurseur fluorophore utilisé pour la synthèse du B-TOH) et du PM-OH (son dérivé acétyle) ainsi que celles d'une sonde contrôle, le 3,5-Di-tert-butyl-4-hydroxybenzoic acid-PM605 (PM-BHB, dont il est attendu d'observer une plus faible réactivité envers les radicaux libres) ont ainsi été mesurées. Nous rapportons également le profil temporel d'émission du B-TOH, du PM-BHB ainsi que du PM-OH, à la suite de leur exposition prolongée aux radicaux peroxydes en solution dans des solvants organiques ou des suspensions aqueuses de liposomes. De précises analyses électrochimiques et des études des produits d'oxidation HPLC ont permis l'observation de la croissance de l'émission du B-TOH, qui se déroule via la désactivation d'un processus de Transfert d'Electron Photo-induit (TEP), ce processus ne s'opérant que dans le contexte du B-TOH réduit. A la suite de l'exposition du B-T</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>We have initiated a research program intended to prepare lipid soluble free radical sensitive fluorescent probes which can readily report the antioxidant activity within the lipid bilayers. This work provides a substantial amount of information useful in the rational design of pyrromethane dye-based off-on fluorescent probes/switches for redox visualization. In this thesis we report the photophysical properties of a newly prepared Trolox®-PM605 dye (B-TOH) which exhibits a marked off-on fluorescence behaviour in the presence of radicals in homogeneous and microheterogeneous solutions. The absorption and fluorescence spectra, fluorescence quantum yields, and fluorescence lifetimes for this probe when dissolved in organic solvents, as well as in dimirystoyl phosphatidylcholine (DMPC) lipid vesicle suspensions in water are reported herein. The analogous photophysical properties were measured for PM605, the precursor fluorophore used in B-TOH synthesis, its deacylated derivative PM-OH, and a control probe 3,5-Di-tert-butyl-4-hydroxybenzoic acid-PM605 (PM-BHB, which is expected to have a lower reactivity towards radicals) adduct whose synthesis is further described herein. We also report the emission time profile of B-TOH, PM-BHB, and PM-OH following their prolonged exposure to peroxyl radicals in organic solvents and liposome water suspensions. Via careful electrochemical analysis and HPLC oxidation product studies, the observed emission growth of B-TOH is shown to occur via the deactivation of a Photoinduced Electron Transfer (PET) process, operative only in reduced B-TOH. Following exposure of B-TOH to free radicals and subsequent oxidation, PET is surpressed. In summary, we report a novel hydrophobic fluorescent antioxidant indicator with optimum off/on ratio properties for homogeneous solution studies. Antioxidant depletion and the onset of radical mediated oxidation can be directly monitored following emission enhancement over time, thus dramatically facilitati</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gonzalo Cosa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz91s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pg734</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak0698b368"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Environmental conditions favouring ice pellet aggregation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carmichael, Hannah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Winter precipitation is an important issue in Canada because of its common occurrence and associated destructive consequences.  Prediction of the precipitation type when temperatures are near 0°C is often difficult because so many types can occur.  This study examines the microphysics of ice pellet formation, in particular the ability of these to form aggregates and the consequences of these aggregates.   This issue was examined by modelling the freezing of a distribution of precipitation particles as they fall through the atmosphere and interact through collisions.  Three mechanisms for aggregation were examined, collisions among the particles involved in these mechanisms were modelled and the relative importance of each mechanism was determined.  It is shown that, for the conditions considered, aggregates are often able to collect freezing rain drops and that aggregation can sometimes be very effective at eliminating freezing rain but the conditions need to be precise for this to occur.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les divers types de précipitations observées durant les tempêtes hivernales sont souvent la cause d'inconvénients durant cette période au Canada.  Il est difficile de prédire ces divers types de précipitations du fait de leur sensibilité à certaines conditions atmosphériques, en particulier à des températures près de 0°C.  Cette étude examine la microphysique de la formation des granules de glace.  Plus précisément, la capacité de ces granules de former des agrégats et les conséquences de ces agrégats sur les autres types de précipitation présents.  Cette recherche repose sur l'étude du regel d'une distribution de pluie verglaçante dans une atmosphère sous le point de congélation à l'aide de simulations incluant les interactions entre particules.   Une attention particulière a été prêtée sur trois principaux aspects.  Premièrement, trois mécanismes formant des agrégats de particules ont été étudiés.  Deuxièmement, les collisions parmi les particules entraînées dans ces mécanismes ont été modélisées.  Finalement, l'importance relative de chaque mécanisme a été déterminée. Les résultats illustrent que pour les conditions atmosphériques considérées, la pluie verglaçante est souvent collectée par les agrégats de particules formés durant leur descente dans l'atmosphère.  De plus, l'agrégation de particules s'avère efficace à l'élimination complète de la pluie verglaçante dans des conditions atmosphériques précises et favorables.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ronald Stewart</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b6285.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b368</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Atmospheric Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xv680"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Determining the Zeta function of curves via p-adic cohomology and deformation theory</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grand'Maison, Jérôme</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse comporte deux parties principales: les deux ont pour objet de calculer la fonction Zêta de certains types de courbes. La première partie contient des considérations théoriques et pratiques pour faire fonctionner l'algorithme de K. Kedlaya et certaines de ses généralisations. On résume les propriétés importantes de la cohomologie de Monsky et Washnitzer, les conjectures de Weil et on rassemble les pièces du casse-tête pour en arriver à un algorithme de P. Gaudry et N. Gürel pour calculer la fonction Zêta d'une courbe superelliptique. Dans la deuxième partie, nous présentons un algorithme pour calculer la fonction Zêta d'une courbe Cab en utilisant la théorie de la déformation. La stratégie générale, attribuée à A. Lauder, est d'étudier la variation de l'action de Frobenius le long d'une certaine famille de courbes. Cet algorithme, presque prêt à utiliser, généralise des travaux similaires de R. Gerkmann et H. Hubrechts.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis has two main parts: both of which aim at computing the Zeta function of some curves. The first part contains the theoretical and practical considerations to make K. Kedlaya's algorithm and some of its generalizations work. We review important properties of the Monsky-Washnitzer cohomology, the Weil conjectures and piece the bits together in order to provide an algorithm that would compute the Zeta function of a superelliptic curve, due to P. Gaudry and N. Gürel. In the second part, we present an algorithm to compute the Zeta function of a Cab curve using deformation theory. The general strategy, due to A. Lauder, is to study the variation of the Frobenius action along a certain family. This almost fully practical algorithm generalizes similar work by R. Gerkmann and H. Hubrechts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Henri Darmon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw59c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xv680</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vf23p"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Enhanced symmetries, duality invariance and moduli stabilization in String Gas Cosmology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Patil, Subodh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This manusript based thesis explores the consequences of string gas cosmology for the moduli problem in string theory. We compile three published papers which set up the formalism and technique of massless string gas cosmology as developed by the author in collaboration with Robert Brandenberger, and explores the consequences of such a framework for late time cosmology. We find that when consistently coupled to the massless background of string theory (given a fixed dilaton), a fluid of massless strings can stabilize all radial and shape moduli of a toroidal compactification of bosonic or heterotic string theory. This stabilization mechanism is consistent with observational bounds coming from fifth force experiments and reproduces all of the desirable features of late time cosmology. We identify the open issues associated with the string gas framework as it stands, and propose directions for future work. We also investigate the possibility that string gas cosmology might offer a dynamical solution to the  moduli problem.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette these basee par manusript explore les consequences de la cosmologie de gaz des cordes pour le probleme de modules dans la theorie des cordes. Nous compilons trois papiers publies qui installent le formalisme et la technique de la cosmologie de gaz des cordes sans masse comme developpee par l'auteur en collaboration avec Robert Brandenberger, et explorons les consequences d'un tel cadre pour la cosmologie de temps tardives. Nous constatons qu'une fois uniformement couple au fond sans masse de la theorie de corde (donne un dilaton fixe), un fluide des cordes sans masse peut stabiliser tous les modules de radial et de forme d'un compactification toroidal de theorie bosonic ou heterotique de corde. Ce mecanisme de stabilisation est conforme aux limites d'observation venant des experiences de force cinquiemes et reproduit tous les dispositifs souhaitables de cosmologie de temps tardives. Nous identifions les issues ouvertes liees au cadre de gaz de corde sans modification, et proposons des directions pour les travaux futurs. Nous etudions egalement la possibilite que la cosmologie de gaz de corde pourrait offrir une solution dynamique au probleme de modules.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robert Brandenberger</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd970.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf23p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atq57nt65t"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mining displacement and learning in struggle in Ghana</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kwai Pun, Valerie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Despite their enormous mineral wealth, communities affected by large-scale mining in Ghana struggle to survive amidst its tremendous ecological and social impacts.  Ghana's adoption of structural adjustment (SAP) in 1983 and its more recent status as a Highly Indebted Poor Country (HIPC) has prompted an unprecedented liberalization in the mining sector, favoring the interests of multi-national corporations (MNCs).    As the clamour for gold escalates, community responses and resistance to exploitative mining activity has grown, demanding corporate social and environmental responsibility, fair compensation and development for the communities.  Emerging within this movement are NGO-community partnerships, which are an important site for informal learning engagements – a type of learning not given enough attention by researchers. This exploratory case study uses document analysis to investigate these NGO-community responses to MNC-led mining development Ghana, to unearth the forms that learning takes in this struggle.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>En dépit de leur énorme richesse minérale, les communautés affectées par l'exploitation extrême au Ghana luttent pour survivre parmi les impacts écologiques et sociaux énormes. L'adoption au Ghana d'une programme d'ajustement structural (SAP) au 1983 et plus récents le statut d'un pays pauvre et fortement endetté (HIPC) a incité la libéralisation accrue dans le secteur de extraction dans l'intérêt des sociétés multinationales (MNCs). Pendant que la demande pour l'or augmente, les réponses de la communauté et la résistance à l'extraction exploitante ont ainsi augmenté, en demandant la responsabilité sociale et environnementale des corporations, compensation juste et développement pour les communautés. Émergent dans ce mouvement sont les associations entres les O.N.G's et les communautés, qui sont un emplacement important des étude sans cérémonie - un type d'étude souvent négligée par des recherchistes.  Cette étude exploratoire emploie l'analyse de document pour étudier ces réponses de  l'O.N.G.-communauté au développement de extraction des MNC au Ghana, pour déterminer les formes d'étude dans cette lutte.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dip Kapoor</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Steve Jordan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg42q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nt65t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Adult and Continuing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g7721"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Use of machine-learning and visualization techniques in the evaluation of factors affecting Milk Urea Nitrogen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ramírez Mendoza, Jessica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>  Studies suggest that milk urea nitrogen is influenced by multiple dietary and non-dietary factors; however most studies continue evaluating those effects independently. Further information is required in order to understand the properties, variations, and applicability of milk-nitrogen fractions by the producers. The objective of this study was to use machine-learning and visualization techniques in the investigation and evaluation of multiple factors altering milk urea nitrogen. Records from the Quebec Dairy Production Centre of Expertise (Valacta) were used in the analyses. After edits, the data consisted of 2,382,043 milk test-day and feeding composition records from Ayrshire, Brown Swiss, Holstein, and Jersey cows. Mean milk urea nitrogen varied across breeds (12.13 ± 3.71 mg/dL; 13.52 ± 3.82 mg/dL; 11.1 ± 3.43 mg/dL; and 13.78 ± 3.8 mg/dL in Ayrshire, Brown Swiss, Holstein, and Jersey, respectively) and across lactation (milk urea nitrogen concentrations increased with parity number).   Decision-trees were generated to determine the attributes associated with milk urea nitrogen levels. Results indicated that the most significant variables altering milk urea nitrogen were milk-fat percentage, dietary crude protein, herd size, and somatic cell count. Milk-fat percentage and dietary crude protein appeared to interact with milk urea nitrogen over the entire lactation. Visualization techniques aided in the identification of changes in feeding practices. During early stages of lactation, producers tended to offer diets with high crude protein content. During medium and late stages of lactation, producers seemed to over-feed their cows, producing an increase in milk urea excretion. Apart from sub-optimal management practices, these results also point to higher feeding costs as well as potential increases in environmental emissions of nitrogen and ammonia.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>  Des recherches indiquent que l'azote d'urée du lait est influencé par des multiples composantes alimentaires et par des autres composantes non alimentaires; toutefois la plupart des recherches continuent á évaluer ces effets indépendamment. D'information additionnel est requis afin de comprendre les propriétés, les variations, et l'applicabilité des fractions azotes d'urée du lait pas les producteurs. L'objectif de cette étude était d'utiliser l'apprentissage automatique et des techniques de visualisation dans l'investigation et l'évaluation des facteurs multiples pouvant altérer l'urée du lait. Des données du Centre d'expertise en production laitière du Québec (Valacta) ont été utilisées pour accomplir ces analyses. Suite à des procédures d'édition, les données se résumaient à un total de 2,382,043 entrées jour de test contenant l'information sur la production laitière et les composantes alimentaires des vaches de race Ayrshire, Suisse Brune, Holstein, et Jersey. La moyenne de l'urée du lait variait à travers les races (12.13 ± 3.71 mg/dL; 13.52 ± 3.82 mg/dL; 11.1 ± 3.43 mg/dL et 13.78 ± 3.8 mg/dL pour les Ayrshire, Suisse Brune, Holstein, et Jersey respectivement) et aussi selon la parité (les concentrations d'urée du lait augmentaient avec la parité).  Des arbres de décision ont été réalisés pour déterminer les attributs associés aux niveaux d'urée du lait. Les résultats ont démontrés que les variables les plus significatives pouvant altérer l'urée du lait étaient le pourcentage de gras du lait, la protéine brute alimentaire, la taille du troupeau et les comptage leucocytaire. Le pourcentage de gras du lait et la protéine brute alimentaire semblaient interagir avec l'urée du lait sur l'ensemble de la lactation. Les techniques de visualisation ont aidés dans l'identification des changements au niveau de l'alimentation. En début de lactation, les producteurs avaient tendance à offrir des rations riches e</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kevin Wade</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms66b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g7721</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Animal Culture and Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>