<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agt54kp98n"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Dietary outcomes of a school-based trial to reduce risk factors for coronary heart disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Esslinger, Krista</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The dietary outcomes of a school-based heart health promotion program in a low-income, multiethnic, inner-city neighbourhood of Montreal, Canada, were investigated. Eight intervention schools and sixteen control schools participated in the project from 1993 to 1997. Twenty-four hour recall data, as well as data on anthropometric and sociodemographic characteristics, were collected from a subsample of all students in grades 4--6 (aged 9--12 years) at baseline (n = 498), after two years (n = 491), and after four years (n = 347). There were no significant differ in nutrient intakes between 1995 and 1997, so these data were combined for analyses. Compared to students in control schools, students exposed to the program had a significantly increased mean intake of vitamin C per 1000 kcal (4184 kJ) (p = 0.0013). Compared to students in designated intervention schools at baseline, mean make of vitamin C per 1000 kcal was significantly increased (p = 0.002) and mean folate intake was significantly domed (p = 0.0058) in exposed to the program. When the intervention group was restricted to only those students who had received 16 hours or more of program exposure (n = 113), there were no significant differences in any nutrient intakes when compared to control students or students in intervention schools at baseline. This program was unsuccessful in changing nutrient intakes of school-aged children, contributing further evidence that conscious dietary change is difficult to achieve by means of a school-based program with a reasonable number of curriculum hours.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gray-Donald, Katherine</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w6639.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp98n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Coronary heart disease -- Nutritional aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coronary heart disease in children -- Prevention</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children -- Nutrition -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nutrition -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Evaluation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj098zd015"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of a prefeeding oral stimulation program on the feeding performance of preterm infants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fucile, Sandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is a lack of knowledge on the effect of an oral stimulation program, prior to the introduction of oral feeding, in preterm infants who are less than 30 weeks gestational age. The objective of this study was to assess whether a prefeeding oral stimulation program enhances the oral feeding performance of preterm infants born between 26--29 weeks gestational age. A randomized trial was carried out. Thirty-two infants completed the study. The experimental group received the oral stimulation program. The control group received the sham stimulation program. The outcome measures were defined as: time to attain independent oral feeding, overall intake, rate of milk transfer (ml/min), maturation of sucking and length of stay at the hospital. The experimental group attained independent oral feeding faster and demonstrated consistently greater overall intake and rate of milk transfer than the control group, as their oral feeding regimen was advanced. These findings are attributed in part to a more mature sucking pattern observed in the experimental group. There was no difference in length of stay at the hospital between the two groups. This study demonstrates that an early oral stimulation program can enhance the development of sucking. This supports the concept that development of sucking is dependent on both physiological maturation and external experiences. Such a program may be included in neonatal developmental care plans because it is safe, simple and inexpensive.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gisel, Erika</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Lau, Chantal</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q750.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd015</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97ks32w"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of mercury and selenium complex in ringed seal liver</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ha, Pengcheng, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ringed seal (Phoca hispida) is a major component and a major source of mercury (Hg) in the Inuit traditional diet. A high correlation between Hg and selenium (Se), as different forms of Hg-Se complex, has been reported in many species of marine mammals. The chemical form of the Hg-Se complex in ringed seals has never be characterised. In this study, Hg and Se concentrations in different seal tissues: liver, kidney, muscle and brain, were measured. The highest Hg and Se concentrations were found in the liver and a strong linear correlation was also observed between Hg and Se concentration in the seal liver. Extensive chromatographic and mass spectrometry techniques have been used to isolate and characterize the Hg and Se ligands in seal liver. Extraction of Hg and Se showed that Hg and Se were bound to ligands within the cell membranes of ringed seal liver. The Hg/Se binding protein has a MW range of about 65 kDa and Hg and Se had a 1:1 molecular ratio. The Hg/Se binding protein may contain 3 major polypeptides with MW of 6510.8, 14305.1 and 14353.1 Da. The toxicology of this Hg/Se binding protein will be studied using an animal feeding experiment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chan, Laurie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988m90k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks32w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ringed seal -- Québec (Province) -- Kuujjuaq Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Selenium -- Bioaccumulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mercury -- Bioaccumulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ringed seal -- Northwest Territories</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pp885"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluating count models for predicting post-release faults in object-oriented software</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fahmi, Mazen</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis empirically compares statistical prediction models using fault count data and fault binary data. The types of statistical models that are studied in detail are Logistic Regression for binary data and Negative Binomial Regression for the count data. Different model building approaches are also evaluated: manual variable selection, stepwise variable selection, and hybrid selection (classification and regression trees combined with stepwise selection). The data set comes from a commercial Java application development project. In this project special attention was paid to data collection to ensure data accuracy. The comparison criteria we used were a consistency coefficient and the estimated cost savings from using the prediction model. The results indicate that while different model building approaches result in different object-oriented metrics being selected, there is no marked difference in the quality of the models that are produced. These results suggest that there is no compelling reason to collect highly accurate fault count data when building object-oriented models, and that fault binary data (which are much easier to collect) will do just as well. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Madhavji, Nazim</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>El-Emam, Khaled</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z29v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp885</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r742d"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Differentiating pain-and innocuous tactile-related activation of human primary somatosensory cortex using temporal analysis of fMRI</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, Jen-I, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The role of primary somatosensory cortex (S1) in pain perception remains uncertain. Human imaging studies have had variable success in showing pain-related activation in S1, and single-unit recordings in primate S1 have revealed few nociceptors. This study assessed the fMRI time course of S1 activity in humans during noxious heat and innocuous tactile stimulation to determine if temporal differences in the perception of these stimuli would be reflected by temporal differences in S1 activation. Four normal subjects participated in three fMRI sessions each. Thermal (painful heat 45--46°C; neutral heat 35--36°C) and tactile stimuli (brushing at 2Hz) were applied to the left leg on separate runs. Activation maps were generated comparing painful to neutral heat and tactile to rest. Directed searches were performed on identified S1 regions reliably activated by brush and noxious heat stimuli, from which regions of interest (ROI) were selected in each subject. Time course for each stimulus modality was extracted from these ROIs, and data were further averaged to examine the mean time course of activation per stimulus cycle. Both brushing and noxious heat produced significant activation within contralateral S1 which could be differentiated by the time course of activation relative to the onset of stimulation. These data indicate that S1 cortex is involved in the processing of nociceptive information. The data are consistent with other indications that this structure has a role in the perception of pain intensity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Duncan, Gary H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj410.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r742d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074x11c"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A GIS editor for a database programming language</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chen, YuLing, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Geographical Information Systems (GIS) have become a more and more important application of database systems. Most general-purpose database systems do not contain a graphical display interface which is indispensable in GIS applications. This thesis presents the design and implementation of a GIS editor (Geditor) for a relational database programming language. It builds a graphical map display interface into the database language and integrates a set of GIS functions. Two interfaces are built in Geditor. One is with the database programmer and the other is with the GIS End-User. The former interface implements a new syntax (gedit) into the database language for the database programmer to call and display the Geditor GUI. The latter implements a GUI with the GIS End-User to view the map and perform a series of fundamental GIS functions. Geditor stores both spatial and non-spatial data in the relational database. The implementation utilizes the spatial capabilities of the relational database programming language to the largest extent. This demonstrates the feasibility and the simplicity of implementing GIS applications in an integrated approach using relational databases. It also provides a flexible and extendable framework by designing an extendable syntax and utilizing the event handler mechanism which is the characteristic of active databases. Java, especially the JFC Swing package is used extensively in the implementation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Merrett, Tim H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c33z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x11c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322g183"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of caffeine intake during pregnancy on the risk of intrauterine growth retardation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chevalier, Isabelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We estimated the effect of caffeine intake from tea, coffee, and colas on the risk of mild and severe intrauterine growth retardation (IUGR) through a case-control study in 500 live singleton infants born at Sainte-Justine Hospital, in Montreal, between May 1998 and July 2000. Cases of IUGR as well as one sex, race and gestational age-matched control per case were identified at birth. Data were abstracted from medical charts and post-delivery questionnaires, and were analysed using conditional logistic regression. Average caffeine intake in pregnancy was not a significant predictor of mild or severe IUGR (for mild IUGR, OR for &gt;300 mg/day of caffeine vs. none:1.21, 95%CI [0.33, 4.40]; trend: p = 0.28). Moderate first-trimester caffeine use significantly increased the risk of mild (OR 2.41, 95%CI [1.01, 5.75]), but not severe, IUGR. Reduction of caffeine use at the onset of pregnancy was protective for mild and severe IUGR (OR 0.34, 95%CI [0.13, 0.92], and 0.55, 95%CI [0.32, 0.94], respectively).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Infante-Rivard, Claire</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j38608754.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g183</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Obstetrics and Gynecology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A44558g083"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A new synthetic route to sol-gel materials containing nonlinear optical chromophores</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chaumel, Frederic</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Network formation using chlorotris(diethylamino)silane [ClSi(NEt 2)3], tetrakis(dimethylamino)silane [Si(NMe2) 4], and tetrakis(diethylamino)tin [Sn(NEt2)4], and NLO-active chromophore was investigated to yield inorganic-organic hybrid materials for 2nd-order nonlinear optics. In contrast to hybrids obtained from Si(NEt2)4, those prepared from ClSi(NEt 2)3 and Sn(NEt2)4 were insoluble even in high boiling solvents. Facile hydrolysis of the NLO-active dye was found to occur in these hybrids due to the catalysis of HCl and the high reactivity for ClSi(NEt2)3 and Sn(NEt2)4 respectively. Due to the insolubility of the networks, it was not possible to determine if the dye present in these networks was physically trapped or covalently bound to the inorganic matrix. It was observed that the method used for the hydrolysis of M--NR2 bond played an important role in the stability of the Si--OR bond for hybrids prepared from Si(NMe 2)4 and Sn(NEt2)4.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kakkar, Ashok K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236397x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g083</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Inorganic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am326m366p"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aggressive care following hospital admission for acute myocardial infarction : analysis of effects on mortality using instrumental variables</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beck, Christine Ann</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Certain regions adopt an aggressive approach (routine cardiac catheterization and frequent invasive revascularization) to care for acute myocardial infarction (AMI), while other regions adopt a conservative approach (selective use of invasive procedures). Administrative data provide a means to estimate the effects of these variations on patient outcomes, but they are limited by their potential for confounding bias due to unobserved case-mix variation as treatment assignment is not random. This study applied instrumental variables, a methodology that can account for this bias, to estimate the effectiveness of aggressive care in a Canadian patient population. The study used administrative data of hospital admissions and health services for all patients admitted for a first AMI in Quebec in 1988 (n = 8674). Incremental (marginal) mortality up to 4 years after admission was measured using distances to hospitals offering aggressive care as instrumental variables. Patients living closer to hospitals offering aggressive care were more likely to receive aggressive care than patients living further away (e.g. 26% versus 19%, respectively, received catheterization within 90 days). However, instrumental variable estimation found that aggressive care was not associated with marginal mortality benefits in comparison to conservative care (e.g. adjusted difference at 1 year: 4%; 95% CI: -11% to 20%). The aggressive approach to post-AMI care is not associated with marginal mortality benefits in Quebec.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gyorkos, Theresa W.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pilote, Louise</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h1468.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m366p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7w62fb20q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Pattern formation in models of charge density waves</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bates, Wilfred Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We investigate the phenomenon of phase organization in charge density waves. Coppersmith and Littlewood [87] have argued that charge density waves become organized into a "minimally stable" state when subject to a pulsed driving force. They have also proposed that the pulse duration memory effect, observed by Fleming and Schneemeyer [86], is evidence for this self organizing behaviour. We review the microscopic origins of charge density waves, experimental results, and theoretical models of charge density waves. We also review theories of complex systems, and, in particular, the phase organization theory proposed by Tang et al. [87]. We focus on how the phase organization theory applies to the dynamics of charge density waves. We investigate phase organization in a model of elastically coupled particles subject to a periodic potential and a pulsed driving force. By numerical simulation of the model, we show that the phase organization behaviour is contingent on the existence of a large number of inequivalent metastable configurations in the model. We also show that this model is equivalent to a purely elastic model of charge density waves interacting with impurities. We further investigate phase organization in a model of charge density waves that has been proposed by Karttunen et al. [99], in which the dynamical generation of phase slips is naturally accounted for. Based on the results of numerical simulations, we argue that phase slips reduce or eliminate the phase organization behaviour of charge density waves by breaking the elasticity of the system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grant, Martin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r4986.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb20q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t8190"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biosorption of heavy metals by red algae (Palmaria palmata)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaugeard, Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The research presented in this thesis entailed an investigation of heavy metal uptake by Palmaria palmata, a red marine alga. The alga was dry and organically certified. The heavy metals of interest were those commonly found in the wastewaters of the printed wiring board industry, namely Cu2+Pb2+, Cd2+, Zn 2+ and Ni2+. The ultimate objective of the work was to determine whether or not the factors expected to influence the metal uptake to the greatest extent could be optimized within functional ranges, leading eventually to process design (beyond the scope of this thesis). These factors were pH, temperature, initial concentration of metal in aqueous solution, and contact time. A number of preliminary experiments were performed to establish a basis for the design of the optimization studies. Although it was not possible to adequately define optimal regions of operation for the biosorption of heavy metals by Palmaria palmata , general trends were elucidated, and the limitations of the methodology used were clarified. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prasher, S. O.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw446.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t8190</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sorbents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Printed circuits industry -- Waste disposal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dulse</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heavy metals -- Absorption and adsorption</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aft848s35q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The community of higher Diptera associated with sedge meadows (Carex, Cyperaceae) in southern Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Beaulieu, Frederic</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The higher Diptera (Brachycera) fauna of sedge meadows (Cyperaceae, Carex) was studied at the Lac St. Francois National Wildlife Area in southern Quebec. Flies were collected weekly from May to October 1999 using sweeping and pan traps at three sampling sites representing two types of Carex habitat. Over 10,000 specimens, representing 34 families and more than 300 species, were collected. Dolichopodidae, Chloropidae, Sciomyzidae, Syrphidae and Sphaeroceridae were highest in species richness in all sites, and Ephydridae were very high in two of the sites. The above families, along with Phoridae, Chamaemyiidae and Muscidae, were also the most abundant. Overall species composition differed between sites and is apparently influenced by the type of vegetation and substrate. Correspondence analysis was used to investigate the habitat preferences of the 37 most abundant species. The feeding habits and host plants of many Diptera species were newly established by rearing adults from plants infested by larvae.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wheeler, T. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk653.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s35q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diptera -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diptera -- Food -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carex -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182n05h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Regulatory aspects of airline alliances : a case study of Star Alliance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keller, Klaus</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The formation of airline alliances has been a distinctive feature of the airline business at the threshold of the new millennium. This is due to the framework of Bilateral Air Transport Agreements, which condition the grant of traffic rights to substantial ownership and effective control being vested in nationals of one of the contracting parties. Further regulatory aspects pertaining to airline alliances include competition law review, traffic rights, and slot allocation. This thesis seeks to elucidate how Star had to adapt its strategic choices to this framework. The outcome will be that in particular the lack of regulatory convergence in competition law matters constitutes a hindrance to a global alliance such as Star. The issue of ownership and control might represent a further obstacle to an alliance intending to rely on mergers or major share holding, an ambition that Star has not nourished so far. Open Skies agreements in force between the U.S., Canada, and several member states of the European Union give alliances full commercial opportunities, unhindered by restrictive capacity or approval of fares provisions. The principles as regards slot allocation, on the other hand, have enabled alliances to build up their hubs as fortresses. The issues of competition law, and ownership and control illustrate that it has become increasingly insufficient to rely on a merely bilateral approach to global problems. Eventually, satisfactory solutions may only be achieved on a multilateral level. The onus thus is on aviation regulators to come up with a more suitable framework for aviation in the next century. Multilateralism, however, might turn out to herald the end to the alliance phenomenon. Once the bilateral strait jacket put aside, the aviation industry will consolidate like any other industry: by mergers, that is.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>van Fenema, Peter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j69q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182n05h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Competition, International</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Deregulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Airlines -- Deregulation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1v53k000m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Customs valuation and transfer pricing : is it possible to harmonize customs and tax rules?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jovanovich, Juan Martʹin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is an overlap between the transfer pricing concepts that apply under tax and under customs regimes. This thesis aims to demonstrate (i) that customs and tax laws often share common principles in respect of related-party transactions; (ii) that transfer pricing as agreed to under one discipline should be recognized under the other; (iii) that the OECD Transfer Pricing Guidelines constitute a body of rules that is appropriate to supplement the related party provisions of the GATT/WTO Valuation Code ("GVC"); and (iv) that such guidelines are generally in accordance with the provisions of the GVC and its general principles and objectives. This thesis also analyzes the tax and customs value of imported goods, and identifies which additions to or deductions from customs value might have to be taken into account in comparing tax and customs results. The thesis concludes with an analysis of the circumstances and conditions under which the introduction of transfer pricing compensatory adjustments to transaction value would be consistent with Article 1 of the GVC.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>De Mestral, Armand L. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pf82w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k000m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Taxation -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tariff -- Law and legislation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transfer pricing -- Taxation -- Law and legislation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2z10ws13d"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Remoteness of damage in contract law : an agreement-centred approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kramer, Adam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis concerns the legal rules of contractual remoteness: these rules govern the extent of liability that is imposed on a breaching party to compensate for the adverse consequences that the breach causes. It is argued that the allocation of responsibility for such consequences is contained implicitly in the contract: every contract extends beyond its express terms, and the allocation of responsibility for the consequences of breach is one of the matters to which it extends. This latter assertion is supported by the argument that an assumption of responsibility for the consequences of breach is a fundamental part of what it means to make a promise. Hence the rules of remoteness are merely a specialised application of the general legal principles that are used to discover the unexpressed part of an agreement. These legal principles can be seen in operation in the implication of terms and the interpretation of expressed terms.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t825.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws13d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Contracts -- Great Britain</dc:subject><dc:subject>Breach of contract -- Great Britain</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liability (Law) -- Great Britain</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9880vs763"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The commercialisation of the international space station</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Koulikova, Ioulia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The assembly of the International Space Station opened a new era of space exploration. It also created new challenges for the lawyers that had to deal with new issues related to this endeavour. This study will focus on the prospect of commercialisation of the ISS and on the legal problems that could appear with respect to this undertaking. By examining available markets and managing structure of the ISS, this study will reveal the potential and the drawbacks of the international enterprise. Furthermore, the detailed analysis of the Intergovernmental Agreement signed by the State Partners to the ISS will describe the particularities of ISS' legal regime, especially emphasising on the Intellectual Property provisions and other issues not covered by the cross waiver of liability.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jakhu, Ram</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q26w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs763</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Space stations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Space industrialization</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5138jg700"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The concept of multicultural education in western societies and its relevance to Japanese education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wada, Ryoko</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objectives of this study were (1) to examine the nature and extent of cultural diversity in Japan; (2) to ascertain the meaning of multicultural education in both the North American and Japanese contexts; and (3) to make judgements concerning the relevance of multicultural education to Japanese education. It was determined that Japanese society is indeed a culturally diverse one, that the cultural minorities are relatively small in numbers and that the Japanese government has traditionally followed a policy of the cultural assimilation of minorities. Using conceptual analysis to investigate the meanings of multicultural education, the study found that the concept as developed in North America includes such elements as intercultural education, multiethnic education, minority education, human rights education, anti-racist education, democratic education, political education, education for social justice and peace education. These supporting meanings were found to have both distinctiveness yet also overlapping value associations. The study reached the conclusion that a qualified concept of multicultural education has relevance to Japanese society, but that the degree of relevance depends upon the extent to which the government follows policies that strengthen or moderate traditional cultural values, recognizes and supports the development of minority cultural communities and encourages openness in its immigration and refugee policies.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Smith, D. C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q01s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jg700</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Multicultural education -- Japan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Japan -- Ethnic relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Education -- Japan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multicultural education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053h95q"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Perceptive legitimacy : the NPT and it behavioural prescriptions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Torchetti, Paolo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Truths are illusions about which one has forgotten that this is what they are. - Nietzsche On March 5th 1970, a long process of international negotiation and power brokering culminated into the Nuclear Proliferation Treaty. As a result the 121 signatory states were legally subject to the norms, values, principles, and behavioural prescriptions of the nuclear proliferation regime. Twenty-nine years after the treaty's entrenchment, however, the nuclear proliferation regime and its enforcement agencies still face many of the same challenges that have plagued its implementation since its conception. The purpose of this analysis is to examine the causal relationship between the perception of the political legitimacy among the signatory members of the NPT, the likelihood of adherence to these behavioural prescriptions and to provide a framework to understand what would make for a legitimate treaty in the eyes of its members. This analysis will reveal that signatory members of the NPT who perceive the treaty as illegitimate are more likely to either defect or disobey the obligations of the treaty than those signatory members who perceive the NPT to be legitimate. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul, T. V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm282.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h95q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nuclear nonproliferation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z273f"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Tourism, stakeholder networks and sustainability : the case of the Vinales Valley, Cuba</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thivierge, Pascale</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The rapid growth of the Cuban tourist industry into the island's main currency generator fostered the emergence of new tourist stakeholders, from both the public (state-owned tourist facilities) and private sectors (micro-enterprises or cuentapropistas). It is crucial to understand how new participation and new organisational structures in the industry can shape and enhance the long-term sustainability of tourism in Cuba. A case study of an emergent alternative tourism destination in Western Cuba (Vinales Valley) reveals complex and striking relationship patterns between stakeholders. In particular, the degree of participation in the industry by the region's various tourism entities is highly uneven, with state entities dominating, as expected. My discussion of the findings suggests that Cuba could draw from its experience in creating well-organized networks of mass organizations to foster a climate of trust and the increased participation among tourist stakeholders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Milne, Simon</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Ewing, Gordon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b070h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z273f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Tourism -- Cuba -- Vinales Valley</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ecotourism -- Cuba -- Vinales Valley</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w665v"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The student-teacher dialogue : an autobiographical discussion of choice, possibility and the teaching-self in the process of becoming</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walsh, Jean, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an investigation of the relationship between education, freedom and the teaching self. Adopting the paradigm of qualitative research, it integrates an autobiographical perspective in which, drawing on the author's experience and perceptions of the shortcomings of traditional teaching attitudes and practices, the thesis aims to explore concepts and approaches which identify possible educational alternatives. The writings of educational philosopher, Maxine Greene, provide the theoretical framework for this study. Based on central themes identified in her work, a theoretical analysis of the principal concepts of freedom, community, imagination, narrative and identity is provided.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood, Elizabeth</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838237d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w665v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education -- Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abk128c72s"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Culture and Values in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The piecing of identity : an autobiographical investigation of culture and values in language education</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mueller, Caroline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study will explore my own perception of my personal and professional roles as a language teacher in Nunavik and in Japan. In this qualitative study, I attempt to understand the negotiation of language and culture both in and out of the classroom. Using the autobiographical narrative method, I investigate questions about language and identity through my own personal lens and voice. My inquiry comprises two elements; it examines and interprets key episodes in my life as a learner and teacher, and as a researcher, I link these topics to theoretical and empirical knowledge. My narrative begins with the early years of my life as a Francophone immersed in an English neighbourhood in Montreal, grounding it in the particular experiences of my own learning and teaching. The study also includes a comparative analysis of my teaching experiences in Northern Quebec and in Japan. The journals I kept throughout my teaching assignments provide material for analysis which contributes a unique perspective to the body of literature addressing the relationship between culture, values, language and identity. I close the discussion with recommendations for the improvement of second language teaching and teacher development in intercultural contexts.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wood, Elizabeth J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h6382.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128c72s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Languages, Modern -- Study and teaching -- Japan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Languages, Modern -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nunavik</dc:subject><dc:subject>Language and culture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Languages, Modern -- Study and teaching -- Québec (Province) -- Nunavik</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225c86c"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Isaiah Berlin's contribution to liberal theory : pluralism as a romantic response to liberalism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Montminy, Annick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Isaiah Berlin's idea of value pluralism has traditionally been seen as supportive to liberalism. Recently however, the idea of an implicit connection between pluralism and liberalism has been questioned by theorists arguing that there is no theoretical link between both, and that in fact, pluralism presents obstacles to liberalism. In this thesis, I present pluralism as being a romantic response to Enlightenment-inspired liberal theory. My claim is that liberalism, even though it cannot be derived from a pluralist moral theory, provides strong support, both in practice and historically, to our pluralist moral condition. In chapter 1, I explain Berlin's conception of history and the importance of the context. I also contrast pluralism with other liberal theories to lay the foundation of my argument. In chapter 2, I present Berlin's highly original conception of human nature, and his defence of negative liberty. In chapter 3, I demonstrate how pluralism is a romantic response to traditional liberalism by exploring two liberal themes that were both redefined in new terms following the romantic revolt, namely rationality and tolerance. Finally, in chapter 4, I argue that pluralism does not entail liberalism, but that none the less a liberal society is the political arrangement best suited to the fact that human beings disagree about ends, and that values and ways of life are incompatible and incommensurable.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Patten, Alan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg718.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c86c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Berlin, Isaiah, Sir</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liberalism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ams35tb32p"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Entre histoire et historiette : le travail ferronien de la citation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Montpetit, Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents our study of Jacques Ferron's work on quotation. Jacques Ferron's goal was to let "history live as a novel". This analysis is based on three little stories (historiettes): "De Loudun a Ville-Marie", "Saint Tartuffe" and "La prise Parmanda". We have divided the work into two complementary objectives. Firstly, to find the sources Ferron quoted in order to put them against the three little stories he has written. The reader can therefore observe the different types of modifications the writer has operated in his sources. The second objective of our research is a detailed analysis of the most important "deviation" cases: the counterfeiting and the copying; two procedures that permit Ferron to erase the first occurrence of a quotation. Our goal is not to accuse Ferron of plagiarism which is of no interest due to the fact that we are not analysing the writings of a historian, but those of a writer. We do however, want to emphasize the importance of "intertextuality" in Ferron's inspiration and composition of three little stories.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763886d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb32p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plagiarism</dc:subject><dc:subject>History -- Methodology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ferron, Jacques -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intertextuality</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c35h"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Much more than music video : an examination of Canadian response to American paradigms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Morris, Samantha Mary</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although the relationship between Canadian and American culture is often discussed in terms of dominance and dependency, there is little cultural scholarship that examines how Canadians interpret American cultural products and how Canadian "replicas" of American products encompass infatuation and imitation of American popular culture while simultaneously offering critique, resistance and parody. By comparing the evolution of MuchMusic and MTV and the "supertext" of the two networks---programming philosophy, musical and non-musical shows, VJ's, and television aesthetics---I address how MuchMusic functions as both an example of uniquely Canadian sensibilities and as an example of Canada's complicated relationship with the United States.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Straw, Will</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t39q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c35h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mass media and culture -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>MuchMusic (Television program)</dc:subject><dc:subject>MTV Networks</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nn20r"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Integration et transnationalisme chez les Dominicains de Montreal</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dancause, Jacques-Luc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The integration of immigrants into host societies has been a topic of longstanding interest in the sociology of migration, whereas the study of transnationalism has only emerged in the last few years. Globalization, fueled by the rapid development of transportation and communication technologies, has been one of the principal factors in the rise of transnationalism. The aim of this study is to clarify the links between the immigrants' integration into the host society and the transnational activities in which they get involved. The initial hypothesis of this study was that immigrants' involvement in narrow transnational activities is linked to their weaker integration into Quebec society. To test this hypothesis, a series of interviews was conducted with members of the Dominican community of Montreal. These Dominicans were involved in varying levels of transnational activities within political, economic, and cultural spheres. The interviews were aimed at determining the integration process experienced by the different interviewees. The results of this study showed, in contrast to the hypothesized predictions, that involvement in transnational activities was not linked to lesser levels of integration. In fact, the Dominicans involved in the most intensive transnational activities revealed a capacity to integrate into the receiving society as easily as other Dominicans, often showing a greater dynamism in their integration. Involvement in intensive transnational activities seems to show a capacity on the part of some immigrants to grow and develop in two universes at the same time, that of the receiving and that of the sending society.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Locher, Uli</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j979z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn20r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Group identity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nationalism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dominican Republic -- Emigration and immigration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dominicans (Dominican Republic) -- Cultural assimilation -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>National characteristics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>