<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atm70mw50g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The art of giving : cooperation, reciprocity and household economic strategies among soapstone carvers in Qimmirut (Lake Harbour). NWT</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dupuis, Michele</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines soapstone carving among Inuit in Lake Harbour, NWT, as a socially adapted form of employment. A time allocation diary, participant observation and informal interviews were implemented. The empirical evidence reveals two important aspects of soapstone carving. First, carving acts as an important source of income for the mostly part-time carvers and their families in Lake Harbour. As such, carving functions as part of a household economic strategy that serves to capitalize the harvest of country food. Second, it notes that Inuit often produce carvings collectively, usually with the help of family members. Also, the returns from the carvings are shared not only among those who participate in the production of the sculpture, but among members of the extended family as a whole, following the patterns of kinship-based food-sharing. Thus, not only is carving an important supplement to other forms of income, it is an integral part of the existing social forms of Inuit society, most notably generalized reciprocity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wenzel, George</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh53b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw50g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Stone carving -- Northwest Territories</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jc64g"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Chrétien et la théorie celtique : état présent d'études</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lotz, Kelye L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since their composition during the middle to late twelfth century, Chretien's tales of Arthur and his chivalrous knights have fascinated generation upon generation of storytellers and their audiences, as well as literary critics and historians. Originally thought to have sprung from the newly civilized and thoroughly christianized courts of Marie of Champagne, daughter of Eleanor of Aquitaine, eighteenth century literary historians suggested that the legends behind the tales may have originated in the lost mythologies of Celtic Ireland and Wales. The following thesis examines the evolution of the theory of celtic origins of Chretien's Romans de la Table Ronde.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stefano, G. Di</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js36d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jc64g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chrétien, de Troyes, 12th cent. -- Sources</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1v53jz385"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Islam and politics under the 'new order' government in Indonesia, 1966-1990</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Truna, Dody S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The 'New Order' government, under President Suharto's leadership, has undertaken different initiatives in the face of both 'political' Islam and 'religious' Islam in Indonesia. Since coming into power in 1966, it has exercised strict control over 'political' Islam; on the other hand, its attitude towards 'religious' Islam has generally been tolerant and even supportive. The result has been a considerable weakening of Islamic political forces but a rapidly developing 'religious' Islam. This reality has forced the present-day generation of Indonesian Muslim thinkers to take an approach which is different from that of the previous generation in responding to the government's policies towards Islam. Unlike their predecessors, some of whom had too ideological and formalistic a conception of an Islamic state, the present Muslim thinkers take an approach which is for the most part politically non-partisan. There has been a growing tendency among them to denounce the efficacy of Islamic political parties. They see that the realization of an Islamic community and the well-being of the ummah will come about not through exclusive and uncompromising political actions but through socioeconomic and cultural means and the ability to be less exclusive and willing to work with those who share different ideas. As a result of efforts along these lines, the relationship between the Muslim community and the government has improved substantially. Nevertheless, it remains to be seen whether or not this developing 'religious' Islam will, at some future date, be transformed into a powerful 'political' Islam.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Turgay, A. Uner</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386k61s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz385</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Indonesia -- Politics and government -- 1966-1998</dc:subject><dc:subject>Islam and politics -- Indonesia</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw95051755"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Une étude des caractéristiques de l'emploi de directeur adjoint d'école au Québec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>St-Pierre, Marc</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>School vice-principals never aroused so much the interest of educational researchers. The studies done were mostly of a descriptive nature and only a very small number were in a formal, theoretical context. A tendency is emerging in education and consists of recognizing more and more the importance of the vice-principal's role in the schools, specially from the perspective of educational change. The purpose of the study was to assess the level of internal motivation for a sample of school vice-principals and examine the vice principals job using the Job Characteristic Theory developed by Hackman and Oldham (1980) as a theoretical base, in an effort to identify specific aspects of the job that might be improved. The Job Diagnostic Survey was used to obtain data from a sample of 131 vice-principals in francophone public schools across the province of Quebec. One way analysis of variance and t-test were used to identify significant differences within groupings and between levels of independent variables: gender, age, years of experiences in education, as vice principals, types of schools, size of schools and willingness to be promoted. The sample of school vice-principals reported moderately high levels of internal motivation. Examination of the specific job characteristics showed high levels of skill variety and only low to moderate levels of autonomy and job feedback. Finally job incumbents reported moderate levels of satisfaction with conditions of employment, although there were a number of differences within groupings by independent variables indicating low level of general satisfaction and satisfaction with salary.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barnabe, Clermont</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k842p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95051755</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>School principals -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5138jg034"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessing movement skills in children with autism : a generalizability analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sykes, Jeffrey T. (Jeffrey Thomas)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The movement skill abilities of fourteen children with autism were assessed on three movement tasks: the overhand throw, kick and horizontal jump. Skill level was assessed both quantitatively and qualitatively. Correlations were calculated to determine the relationship between these two measures on all skill items. A Generalizability Analysis was conducted to determine the minimal conditions required to observe reliably the movement skills of children with autism. The conditions generalized in this study were observers and trials. The results indicated that there was a significant relationship between quantitative and qualitative measures on the horizontal jump and the kick. A correlation of.37 was obtained for the overhand throw, but was not considered significant. Results of the generalizability analysis indicated that reliable results were obtained with one observer and one trial for all three skill items.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, Greg</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f473b.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jg034</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Motor ability in children -- Testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Autistic children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924c98j"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Linguistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Complex predicate formation in Ainu</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tajima, Masakazu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Lexicalists assume that words with derivational morphology and compound words are not formed by syntactic transformation (Selkirk, 1982). The Lexicalist Hypothesis implies that the principles of universal grammar are not operative to word formation. This thesis argues that a word is composed of lexical constituents and post-lexical constituents, and that the post-lexical constituents can incorporate into a verb, to form the complex predicate. This formational process is subject to syntactic constraints and principles. Therefore, I claim that the principles of universal grammar are also operative to word formation. This hypothesis will throw a new light upon the area of language acquisition of complex predicates.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, M. C.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m535s.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c98j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ainu language -- Word formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Word formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ainu language -- Verb phrase</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988m240"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of rolling parameters on the no-recrystallization temperature (Tnr) in Nb-bearing steels</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bai, Deng Qi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The recrystallization behavior of three Nb-bearing HSLA steels was investigated during multipass deformation under continuous cooling conditions. The niobium concentrations of these steels varied from 0.05 to 0.09 wt%. The specimens were tested on a computerized torsion machine using a simulation schedule of 17 passes. Deformation temperatures of 1180$ sp circ$C to 700$ sp circ$C were employed, together with pass strains of 0.1 to 0.7, strain rates of 0.2 to 10 s$ sp{-1}$, and interpass times of 2 to 200 seconds. By means of mean flow stress vs. 1000/T diagrams, the effect of reheating temperature, initial grain size, and chemical composition on the T$ sb{ rm nr}$ (temperature at which recrystallization is no longer complete) was determined. Reheating temperature and microalloying elements have significant influence on the T$ sb{ rm nr}$, while initial grain size has no effect on the T$ sb{ rm nr}$ during multipass deformation. Furthermore, the effect of deformation parameters such as the pass strain, strain rate, and interpass time on the T$ sb{ rm nr}$ during multipass deformation was investigated in this way. The T$ sb{ rm nr}$ decreases with increasing strain and also decreases slightly with increasing strain rate. There is a T$ sb{ rm nr}$ minimum at times of about 12 $ sim$ 15 seconds and both increases and decreases from this value raise this characteristic temperature. When the interpass times are short, solute atoms control the rate of recrystallization, the extent of which decreases as the time is decreased. When the interpass times are long, precipitation takes place and retards recrystallization, so that the extent of softening decreases as the time is extended instead. The evolution of Nb(C,N) precipitation during simulated rolling was studied with the aid of carbon extraction replication and electron microscopy. Finally, by applying the additivity rule to the isothermal model of Dutta and Sellars, continuous cooling T$ sb{ rm nr}$'s were predicted from recrystallization-precipitation-temperature-time (RPTT) diagrams; these are shown to be in good agreement with the experimental observations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yue, S.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jonas, J. J.</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dd66w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m240</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z708x93m"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Wideband CELP speech coding</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abboud, Karim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this thesis is to study the coding of wideband speech and to improve on previous Code-Excited Linear Prediction (CELP) coders in terms of speech quality and bit rate. To accomplish this task, improved coding techniques are introduced and the operating bit rate is reduced while maintaining and even enhancing the speech quality. the first approach considers the quantization of Liner Predictive Coding (LPC) parameters and uses a three way split vector quantization. Both scalar and vector quantization are initially studied; results show that, with adequate codebook training, the second method generates better results while using a fewer number of bits. Nevertheless, the use of vector quantizers remain highly complex in terms of memory and number of computations. A new quantization scheme, split vector quantization (split VQ), is investigated to overcome this complexity problem. Using a new weighted distance measure as a selection criterion for split VQ, the average spectral distortion is significantly reduced to match the results obtained with scalar quantizers. The second approach introduces a new pitch predictor with an increased temporal resolution for periodicity. This new technique has the advantage of maintaining the same quality obtained with conventional multiple coefficient predictors at a reduced bit rate. Furthermore, the conventional CELP noise weighting filter is modified to allow more freedom and better accuracy in the modeling of both tilt and formant structures. Throughout this process, different noise weighting schemes are evaluated and the results show that the new filter greatly contributes in solving the problem of high frequency distortion. The final wideband CELP coder is operational at 11.7 kbits/s and generates a high perceptual quality of the reconstructed speech using the fractional pitch predictor and the new perceptual noise weighting filter.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kabal, Peter</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq23g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708x93m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225c233"><ual:graduationDate>1993</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Toll-quality speech coding at 8 kbs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maroun, Nabih</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There has been an ongoing effort to achieve very high quality speech coding at medium transmission bit rates. Consequently, the TIA has chosen the Vector SUM Linear Predictive (VSELP) implementation of an 8 kb/s coder to be the standard for North-American cellular digital telephony. However, it was only recently that, in view of the increased research focus on developing toll-quality speech coding at such bit rates, the CCITT has imposed a set of specifications for standardizing low-delay coders operating at 8 kb/s. The Low-Delay Code Excited Linear Predictive (LD-CELP) suggested by Chen is presently the only potential candidate for CCITT standardization, achieving a one-way coding delay of 10 ms. However, just like the VSELP coding algorithm, the 8 kb/s LD-CELP version does not quite yield toll-quality reconstructed speech. The purpose of the work in this thesis is to establish the minimum requirements for a coding structure capable of generating toll-quality coded speech at 8 kb/s. The purpose of this thesis is to show that, by slightly relaxing the coding delay constraint, perceptual enhancement techniques yield toll quality coding after redesigning and fine-tuning the optimization and quantization procedures of a CELP coder.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kabal, Peter</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806103g.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c233</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67js37p"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Calvino's desiring machines : literature and the non-human in Deleuze and Calvino</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bourassa, Alan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis stages a meeting between the work of French philosopher Gilles Deleuze and the short fiction of Italian writer Italo Calvino. This meeting has as its subject the question of the human and the non-human. What forces make up the human? What assemblages of elements make up language, literature, subjectivity? And what does it mean that these forces come from outside the human at the same time as they create the human? Calvino is often accused of being an unemotional writer, lacking in human warmth. With this I agree completely. Calvino does lack human warmth because he allows non-human forces to penetrate his writing, taking it beyond conventionalized and banal prefabricated emotion into a dimension of new intensities. Deleuze will provide us with a vocabulary of concepts with which to discuss these non-human forces and their potential for moving the human out of itself and into a new assemblage of thoughts, passions and actions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Massumi, Brian</ual:supervisor><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r8986.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js37p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Deleuze, Gilles, 1925-1995</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calvino, Italo -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qj94b"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modeling and control of a robotic joint with in-parallel redundant actuators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Boulet, Benoit</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The first part of this thesis includes a brief comparison between electric motors and hydraulic actuators for high performance robotics applications. Hydraulic actuators with fast valves are shown to be superior because of their large torque to mass ratios and their extended bandwidth. One such hydraulic actuator is characterized and its highly nonlinear dynamics are modeled and identified. A simulator implementing this dynamic model is shown to predict the system's behavior satisfyingly. A lead lag force controller that yields a large bandwidth and good accuracy is also designed. The second part is devoted to the modeling and control of an in-parallel actuated, redundant, revolute joint mechanism. An autonomous kinematic calibration method is presented, and tested on a prototype of the joint. The actuator forces are optimized to reduce internal force, and to minimize their maximum magnitude. A method to generate a pre-load force in the joint to eliminate backlash is also presented. Finally, a PD controller, a robust PID controller, and a robust $H sp{ infty}$-optimal controller are designed to control the joint angle. Results are presented for position and impedance control experiments, and the PD and $H sp{ infty}$-optimal controllers are shown to be superior to the PID controller in terms of trajectory tracking and robustness in variations in the joint's inertia. A variable bandwidth, nonlinear position controller is also developed and tested experimentally.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x020p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qj94b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asj1393181"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cytokine gene expression in human immunodeficiency virus infected myeloid cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>D'Addario, Mario G., Jr.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Results indicate that U9-IIIB and PLB-IIIB cells stimulated with PMA, LPS or recombinant cytokines transcribed and translated significantly higher levels of TNF-$ alpha$, IL-1$ alpha$, IFN-$ alpha$, IL-1$ beta$, and IFN-$ beta$. Furthermore it appears that HIV infection of PLB-985 cells induces monocytic differentiation and alterations in the binding of NF-$ kappa$B related proteins. PLB-IIIB cells demonstrated characteristics reflecting differentiation including morphological alterations, changes in c-fms and c-myc proto-oncogene expression, and increased expression of CD14 cell surface antigen. Examination of the IL-1$ beta$ promoter revealed a DNA sequence capable of interacting with the NF-$ kappa$B family of proteins; oligonucleotides containing 1-3 copies of this IL-1$ beta$-$ kappa$B sequence were synthesized and shown to bind NF-$ kappa$B proteins from LPS and PMA treated U937 and U9-IIIB cells. Recombinant NF-$ kappa$B protein subunits specifically bound monomeric and dimeric copies of this IL-1$ beta$-$ kappa$B sequence and binding was eliminated by competition with unlabeled wild type but not mutant oligonucleotides. Results indicate that IL-1$ beta$ gene expression may be significantly elevated in HIV infected cells and that transcriptional regulation by NF-$ kappa rm B /{ it rel /}$ proteins may mediate its activation.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht10x.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1393181</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pp12t"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A mechanical theory for liquid crystalline polymers : formulation and predictions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Farhoudi, Yalda</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the present thesis, a continuum tensorial theory has been formulated to describe the isothermal coupling of rheology and microstructure of nematic liquid crystalline polymers. The theory was shown to properly reduce, in special cases, to the long established Ericksen's transversely isotropic liquid and Leslie Ericksen's theories. The new theory formulated in this thesis, was used to develop a simplified two dimensional and uniform model for rectilinear simple shear flow of uniaxial, rodlike nematics. The microstructural order balance yields a system of non-linear differential equations that was solved numerically to obtain the orientational and rheological transient response of the material to shear start-up and cessation of shear. The rheological transient response including overshoots in shear start-up and scaling of the relaxation time with shear rate in cessation of shear were in good agreement with experimental results. Parametric study was performed using the shear rate; the frequently reported change in sign of normal stress differences with shear rate was captured. Continuum mechanical explanations were provided for observed unusual phenomena. Furthermore, the theory was extended to model the orientational behavior of biaxial and discotic nematics in start-up of simple shear flow.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt86m.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp12t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajm214q30w"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Contour closure and the perception of shape</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elder, James H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>By modulating the degree of closure of the outlines, I show that two-dimensional shape processing is rapid for closed stimuli but slow for open stimuli. I further show that search speed can be characterized as a smooth, monotonic function of the degree of closure, supporting the notion of a perceptual closure continuum. This continuum is shown to be naturally parameterized by a dot-spacing metric, and experiments with different types of fragmentation lead to the hypothesis of a Minimax Principle of closure, which imposes a partial ordering over all fragmentations of a given contour. Using search speed as a metric for the perceptual closure of various figures leads to an equivalence relation between perceptual closure and the confidence of object inference. Under this metric, perceptual closure is found to be independent from various surface completion and texture processes and highly sensitive to contrast sign reversal, supporting the existence of a limited-complexity shape from contour process in early vision. Perceptual closure is shown to be nonlinear in several respects: a simple model of one such nonlinearity is proposed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh55w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q30w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ang451j783"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Renewable Resources</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of co-administration of fluoride and aluminum on the metabolism of these two ions in the American kestrel (Falco sparverius)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chu, Jee Yan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In order to test the hypotheses: (1) that the digestive absorption of fluoride (F) is affected by the presence of aluminum (Al), and (2) that the distribution of F absorbed among organs/tissues is affected by Al, 36 American kestrels (Falco sparverius) were randomly divided into 6 groups of 6, and given oral doses daily for 30 days according to the following scheme: (1) deionized water only, (2) 30 mg/kg F$ sp-$, (3) 24 mg/kg F$ sp-$, (4) 24 mg/kg Al$ sp{3+}$, (5) 30 mg/kg F$ sp-$ + 24 mg/kg Al$ sp{3+},$ (6) 24 mg/kg F$ sp-$ + 24 mg/kg Al$ sp{3+}$. Excreta was collected every 24 hours between dosing. Femurae, kidneys, hearts, alimentary canals, skeletal muscle, and livers were obtained from all birds at the end of experiment. All samples were analyzed for F, Al, total phosphate (P) and calcium (Ca). F excretion was significantly higher in birds given 30 mg/kg F$ sp-$ + 24 mg/kg Al$ sp{3+}$ than in their counterparts which received the same amount of either F or Al alone (p $&lt;$ 0.05). Excretion of Al was also elevated in all groups (except those only given water) from the level of excretion before the experiment commenced (p $&lt;$ 0.05), despite the fact that 2 groups out of those 5 received F only. P and Ca contents of excreta were not affected by the oral dose. F contents in femurae from groups receiving both F and Al were significantly lower compared to those levels in those birds which were given F only (p $&lt;$ 0.05). Significantly more Al was found in kidneys from the group receiving 30 mg/kg F$ sp-$ + 24 mg/kg Al$ sp{3+}$ than in those groups given only 1 of the 2 ions (p $&lt;$ 0.05).</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t46j.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j783</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>American kestrel -- Metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluorides -- Metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g6377"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Low root-zone temperatures and soybean (Glycine max (L.) Merr.) N2- fixing symbiosis development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lynch, Derek H. (Derek Henry)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research tested the hypotheses that (a) suboptimal root-zone temperatures (RZT) limit the soybean-Bradyrhizobium N$ sb2$-fixing symbiosis primarily through an inhibition of symbiosis establishment and (b) this inhibition is modified by the genotype of micro- or macrosymbiont. Controlled environment and field experiments were conducted utilizing two soybean genotypes and six B. japonicum strains. At 19$ sp circ$C RZT fixed nitrogen levels decreased by 30-40%, predominantly due to a restriction in the latter stages of nodule development. Reductions of 10% and 30% in specific nodule activity rates at 19$ sp circ$C and 15$ sp circ$C RZT respectively, indicated nodule function to be comparatively insensitive to low RZT. Soybean genotypes did not differ in seedling nodulation or N$ sb2$-fixation under cool-soil, field or controlled environment, conditions. At all temperatures, commercial B. japonicum strain 532C was more efficient, but not effective, than strains obtained from the cool-soils of Northern Japan. Under cool-soil field conditions, two of the latter strains increased seedling nodulation and N$ sb2$-fixation.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf75p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g6377</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nitrogen-fixing microorganisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soybean</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6t053h24r"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Renewable Resources</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of seeding density and nitrogen fertility on the yield and quality of a hard red spring wheat in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Migner, Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An experiment was conducted for two years to determine the effect of seeding rate, and nitrogen fertility on the yield and quality of hard red spring wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) in Quebec. The experiment was conducted on a Ste-Rosalie series soil (humic gleysol), in the St-Hyacinthe region, 50 km east of Montreal. The design of the experiment was a split-plot design. The treatments in the main plots were the plant densities while the nitrogen treatments (rate of nitrogen, number and timing of the applications and formulation of fertilizer nitrogen) were applied to the sub-plots. Nitrogen had a significant effect on yields in 1987, but not in 1986. Maximum yield was 6838 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ in 1986 and 3807 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ in 1987. Protein concentration was increased by higher nitrogen rates in both years. The yield and protein concentration were affected by low precipitation in 1987. Applying the nitrogen later in the season increased the protein concentration in both seasons. It also decreased yield in 1987, but this was caused by lack of water in late June and July 1987. Formulation of nitrogen fertilizer did not have an effect on yield and protein content of the crop.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pr55r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h24r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wheat -- Yields</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitrogen fertilizers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akh04dq84m"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rhizome bud production and growth characteristics of clonal colonies in two biotypes of quackgrass (Elytrigia repens (L.) Nevski)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Neeser, Christophe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study examined the effect of density on rhizome bud production in quackgrass (Elytrigia repens (L.) Nevski). The treatments consisted of two biotypes (L8 and L9), and nine density levels ranging from 1 to 22 plants m$ sp{-2}$. The results showed that bud production per plant diminished with increasing density in both biotypes. However, biotype L8 was less productive at low densities, but almost equal to L9 at higher densities. A second experiment was undertaken to measure the expansion of clonal colonies and the distribution of shoots within these colonies. For both biotypes the growth rate was highest in late summer and early fall, but colonies of L9 grew more rapidly. Biotype L9 had 59% of its total biomass located within 40 cm of the centre as compared with 81% in L8. Overall, Biotype L9 produced more rhizome buds, responded more strongly to intraspecific interference, and grew more rapidly as a colony.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk858.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dq84m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Weeds -- Control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quitch-grass -- Propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quitch-grass -- Cultural control</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nm70r"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Meteorology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fresh water forcing of the North Atlantic</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Aura, Stella M. (Stella Marris)</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Several numerical experiments are carried out using the Bryan-Cox Ocean General Circulation Model to investigate the variability of the North Atlantic thermohaline circulation under steady, non-zonal, surface forcing and realistic geometry. To this end the annual mean surface forcing fields were derived from the climatological data sets of Levitus (1982), Hellerman and Rosenstein (1983) and, Schmitt et al. (1989). Further, Arctic freshwater flux, an important part of the hydrological cycle within the North Atlantic Deep Water formation region, is taken into account. It is found that under present-day climatological surface forcing the system may oscillate at interdecadal period. The mechanism driving the oscillations is linked to changes in both the horizontal and vertical extent of convection in the northern "Labrador Sea". The structure of the surface freshwater flux forcing plays a major role in both the initiation and sustenance of the interdecadal oscillations. Allowing for a freshwater flux into the northern region of the "Labrador Sea" inhibits the interdecadal variability. The oscillations, however, appear, relatively insensitive to Arctic fresh water transport into the "Greenland Sea". A detailed three-dimensional discussion of the physics behind the interdecadal oscillations is presented.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g143v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm70r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67js397"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Central nervous system and peripheral signs of opioid abstinence</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fundytus, Marian Elaine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It was hypothesized that a metabolite of morphine, morphine-3-glucuronide (M3G), contributes to the expression of symptoms seen during withdrawal from morphine. To test this hypothesis, the behaviors observed during precipitated withdrawal from morphine and sufentanil were compared. Sufentanil was chosen because, like morphine, it acts primarily at the mu opioid receptor, but has different metabolites. Differences in the abstinence syndromes produced by the two drugs may therefore be attributable to the actions of metabolites, rather than the primary opioid actions of morphine and sufentanil. Although there were some differences in the occurrence of symptoms, morphine and sufentanil withdrawal were very similar. Therefore, the evidence was inconclusive as to the contribution of metabolites during withdrawal. Systemic administration of M3G alone and in combination with morphine produced no withdrawal-like behaviors. However, when these drugs were given centrally, withdrawal-like behaviors were observed in conjunction with seizures. The seizures were not attenuated by naloxone (but were alleviated by an anti-convulsant), indicating that they were not mediated by opioid receptors. The behaviors resembled those seen by previous investigators following high doses of morphine. The results suggest that M3G may play a role in the toxic effects of high doses of morphine.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q19n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js397</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Opioids -- Physiological effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>Opioid habit</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amp48sd883"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanosensory neurons in culture : morphology and electrophysiology</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Golas, Lillian B.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Crustacean mechanosensory neurons, isolated by enzymatic digestion from abdominal muscle receptor organs of Homarus americanus and Procambarus clarkii, maintain characteristic morphological and electrophysiological phenotypes in culture. New outgrowth occurs at both the axonal and dendritic poles. The patterns of outgrowth are distinct and in keeping with the sensory function. The cut axonal end gives rise to few elongated processes which rarely branch. In contrast, the new growth at the dendritic pole consists of multiple, short ($&lt;$10 um) processes which resemble normal sensory termini. Cultured tonic and phasic sensory neurons respond to depolarizing current injections with characteristic firing patterns. Single channel patch clamp studies have identified at least four different ion channels. In Homarus, three channel types are voltage but not stretch sensitive. One channel type identified in Procambarus, displays both voltage and stretch sensitivity. These cultured mechanosensory neurons have the potential to be useful models for the study of the mechanisms of mechanotransduction.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs92n.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sd883</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanoreceptors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crustacea</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zp63q"><ual:graduationDate>1992</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Resource discovery in an internet environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Deutsch, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines issues relevant to the design of distributed resource location systems capable of functioning in a multi-user, multi-computer internet environment. Central to this work is the concept of "resource discovery", that is, the act of discovering the existence of classes of resources, locating specific instances of such classes, and accessing these instances. The problems of resource discovery in a network of hundreds of thousands, or even millions of computers are fundamentally different from those encountered in a local area network environment. In this thesis, an architecture for a resource discovery service is proposed that allows individual users to locate and access arbitrary collections of resources throughout a large-scale internet. Resources served by this system may be typed and treated as individual objects in a distributed, automatically maintained information system.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d66p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zp63q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asf268642v"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On-farm evaluation of cultivation, cover crops and chemical banding for crop and weed management in integrated farming systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Samson, Roger A. (Roger Anthony)</ual:dissertant><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580n80w.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268642v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Field experiments -- Ontario -- Case studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weeds -- Integrated control -- Ontario -- Case studies</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj6731518r"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Renewable Resources</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of bromoxynil herbicide on experimental prairie wetlands</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Robinson, Richard D. (Richard Daniel)</ual:dissertant><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg24r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731518r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Herbicides -- Environmental aspects -- Manitoba</dc:subject><dc:subject>Constructed wetlands -- Manitoba</dc:subject><dc:subject>Herbicides -- Toxicology -- Manitoba</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2j62s604c"><ual:graduationDate>1989</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quota values and investment decisions of dairy farmers : a Delphi application</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Coyle, Nelson</ual:dissertant><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q20d.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s604c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dairy farmers -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairy farmers -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairying -- Economic aspects -- Ontario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Delphi method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dairying -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>