<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abv73c278d"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Real-time immersive articulation of the human body in the WITS virtual training environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Badra, Fady</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the potential of using virtual reality (VR) to implement virtual environments for training in suitable tasks, and demonstrates that this potential can be fulfilled. The Virtual Reality Welding Intelligent Tutoring System VR-WITS incorporates advanced features such as 3D video display, sophisticated navigation and object manipulation interfaces, human representation and an expert system to validate operations. All these human-computer interaction techniques are brought together, they offer the opportunity of learning with a virtual training environment rather than the usual classroom-like experience. VR-WITS is a VR-based "learn-by-doing" system developed for the training of maintenance workers in performing grounding welds of various equipment. In particular, this thesis describes the design and implementation of a synthetic human model to be incorporated in virtual environments (VE) for training purposes. The human puppet represents the trainee in the virtual world. This puppet is capable of performing task simulations and mimicking the trainee movements in real-time. Interaction mechanisms are analyzed and described and then experimental results are presented and discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malowany, A. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd67j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c278d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education, Technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150m176"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>High-speed low-cost Delta-Sigma modulation techniques for analog-to-digital conversion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abcarius, John, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>As digital electronics becomes increasingly popular, the need for efficient data conversion to provide the link to our analog world grows all the more important. To sustain the current rate of technological advancement, the requirements on the data conversion systems are becoming more stringent. Wireless communication systems demand high speed, high performance analog-to-digital conversion front-ends. Furthermore, consumers demand quality electronics at low cost, which precludes the use of expensive analog processes. This thesis investigates the potential of DeltaSigma modulation techniques in addressing both of these issues through the design, implementation and experimentation of several prototype integrated circuits. Delta-Sigma modulation has recently become widely recognized for its ability to perform high performance data conversion without the use of high precision components. To extend these benefits to wireless applications, a novel eighth-order bandpass DeltaSigma modulator for A/D conversion will be presented. The modulator design is developed beginning at the signal processing level and realized in a 0.8mu BiCMOS process using the switched-capacitor (SC) technique. To address the cost issue, the design of a data conversion system based on the DeltaSigma modulation technique using an economical purely digital CMOS implementation is investigated. The distortion performance of experimental prototypes implemented using switched-capacitor (with capacitors realized using MOSFETs) and switched-current techniques is assessed. This work therefore contributes to the ongoing drive to improve the performance and applicability of the DeltaSigma modulation technique in meeting modern-day data conversion needs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Roberts, Gordon W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k022n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m176</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322g47j"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Karl Barth's view of war</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sansom, Heather R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis seeks to contribute to scholarship on the great Swiss theologian, Karl Barth, and to the ongoing discussion of theology and politics by examining Barth's view of war. There has so far been only one monograph on Barth's view of war: John Howard Yoder's Karl Barth and the Problem of War (1970). Whereas Yoder's work is restricted to Barth's general discussion of war in his Church Dogmatics, and to a partial glance at his response to World War Two (WWII) and the Cold War, this thesis expands and completes the picture by examining Barths, overall theo-ethical framework, and his attitude to World War I. Pushing a little further into Barth's theology, I start by re-evaluating the significance of Barth's key ethical concept of the Grenzfall ('extreme case')---particularly his use of it in relation to the problem of war. Briefly, rather than being a 'cop-out' clause (Yoder's thesis), the Grenzfall serves as a descriptive, conceptual short-hand for Barth's contextually-engaged, prophetic stance with regard to war. This is shown most clearly in his responses in word and deed to World War One (WWI---ignored by Yoder), WWII and the Cold War. Following my examination of the Grenzfall, I chart Barth's path through these three situations: No substantial work has previously been done on Barth's response to WWI, largely because much of it is articulated in a series of sermons which have not yet been translated. Uncovering Barth's thought in these sermons---hitherto largely ignored in both dogmatic and ethical scholarship---I compare Barth's early, middle and later responses to concrete, historical wars, and relate these to his use of the Grenzfall in the ethical discussion of his Dogmatics.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Klempa, William J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fr05r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g47j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>War -- Religious aspects -- Christianity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Barth, Karl, 1886-1968 -- Views on war</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3484zj82c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>"The mongrel-girl of noman's land" : Mina Loy's Anglo-mongrels and the rose as autobiography</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mortensen, Melanie J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis analyzes the long poem Anglo-Mongrels and the Rose by the modern poet Mina Loy according to its function as autobiography. Loy's intellectual environment prior to the poem's 1923 to 1925 publication and, in particular, the writing of the philosopher Henri Bergson shape her thinking about the self and consciousness. This intellectual background provides a foundation for a consideration of Loy's abstract poetic autobiography as what Loy called "auto-mythology." The abstraction of modern poetics provides a medium for Loy's expression of alienation as the hybrid offspring of an ethnically mixed marriage. Loy's long poem treats her heritage and upbringing in a mixed Jewish and Christian household; the effect of this intermingling of religion and ethnicity, or what was then considered race, is integral to understanding both her autobiographical expression of alienation and her optimism about the possibilities for Bergson's "creative evolution."</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rimstead, Roxanne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hr81q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj82c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Loy, Mina. Anglo-mongrels and the rose</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A76537323q"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Haydn's early symphonic development sections and eighteenth-century theories of modulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keuchguerian, Anait</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The tonal organization of the first-movement development sections of ten Haydn symphonies (nos. 1, 4, 6, 10, 13, 15, 19, 24, 31 and 72), all in D major composed between 1758 and 1765, is directly linked to eighteenth-century theories of modulation. The recent theoretical or musicological literature, with the exception of H. C. Robbins Landon's Haydn: Chronical and Works (1976--1980), has concentrated on Haydn's later high classical style generally ignoring these earlier works composed during his largely self-didactic, most formative years. After evaluating the analytical procedures established by Webster (1991), Wheelock (1992), Sisman (1993) and Haimo (1995) in chapter one, chapter two reviews tonal theories of some eighteenth-century writers. Chapter three presents analytical observations on the Morzin Symphonies (nos. 1, 15, 4, 10). Chapter four extends the discussion of chapter two and focuses on theoretical concepts that determine rank ordering of scale-steps in relation to the tonic. Chapter five focuses on tonal procedures employed in the developments of early Esterhazy symphonies (nos. 6, 13, 72, 24, 31) all of which feature cadentially-confirmed tonicizations of scale-step vi paired with recapitulatory from the main theme. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McLean, Don</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z310c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537323q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Symphonies -- Analysis, appreciation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Modulation (Music)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Music theory -- History -- 18th century</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jw76g"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Islamic Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modern Qurānic exegesis : a comparative study of the methods of Muḥammad Abduh and Muḥammad Rashīd Riḍā</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jafar, Iftitah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is an attempt to analyze and compare the methods of exegesis of `Abduh and Rid&amp;dotbelow;a. The analysis focuses on their works of Qur'anic exegesis, especially their joint project Tafsir al-Manar. Their school of exegesis and principles of exegesis are a reflection of the socio-political setting in which they found themselves. They provide an antithesis to the schools and principles of exegesis favoured by traditional exegetes. `Abduh and Rida accused traditional exegetes of deviating from the guidance of the Qur'an by allowing their exegesis to develop into an intellectual exercise in grammar, theology, jurisprudence or even philosophical dispute. In the views of `Abduh and Rid&amp;dotbelow;a, traditional exegetes tended to treat the Qur'an as a justification of their position in debate, a tendency that should be reversed. Both men tried to reformulate the approach of Qur'anic hermeneutics which they regarded as being applicable to social issues. Due to the differences in their respective intellectual backgrounds, experiences and attitudes towards different schools of thought, they applied different methods of interpretation. `Abduh was consistent in his modernist call to go "back to the Qur'an," for which he extracted guidance from the Qur'an through his own perception. As a consequence he limited the use of the intertextual approach to h&amp;dotbelow;adith and philological analysis in his commentaries. Rid&amp;dotbelow;a, on the other hand, extended their use in his interpretation. Rid&amp;dotbelow;a also favoured the use of scientific knowledge in exegesis which `Abduh rejected due to its relativity. Rid&amp;dotbelow;a's interpretation was also characterized by the extensive use of the opinions of earlier exegetes, which `Abduh tended to neglect.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boullata, Issa J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn824.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw76g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Muḥammad Rashīd Riḍā</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muḥammad ʻAbduh, 1849-1905</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jt41g"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Les femmes et le système juridique en Inde : entre l'idéologie et les faits: analyse anthropologique de la conception des droits à travers les transactions économiques au moment du mariage</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bates, Karine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Around the world, scholars and politicians are engaged in a passionate debate concerning the universality of Human Rights. The problem of inequality between men and women concerning property rights is also part of this dispute. The transposition of human rights in another cultural context may create conflicts with new fundamental values. In a cultural context that differs from the western one, those rights don't always have their place or they may be reinterpreted accordingly with different cultural visions of what is a just society. In order to get a better understanding of this problem, this research is proposing an analysis of the relation of Indian women with the courts regarding dowry death cases, especially in Maharashtra. The increasing number of those death cases are a contemporary manifestation of inequality. The apparition of this very Indian crime is linked with the augmentation of the frequency of the dowry practice despite the Dowry Prohibition Act (1961). Through the study of jurisprudence, ethnographies and some interviews conducted with Indian women living in Montreal, it is possible to identify factors influencing the relationship of women with respect to their rights and the Indian legal system. The proposed study shows that case analysis, combined with other research techniques, is an essential tool for understanding the dynamics between laws and practices. All findings lead to the following conclusion: legal anthropology can bring light into the debate concerning the universality of Human rights.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Attwood, D. W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n3293.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt41g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociological jurisprudence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- India</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dowry -- India</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2676x931"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of causality between money supply and retail food prices in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wu, Qionglin, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses the issue of the existence of a causal relationship between the change in the food component of the consumer price index and change in the money supply (money base and M1) by using monthly Canadian data from January 1968 to March 1997. A bivariate vector autoregressive (VAR) model is used to describe the relationship between money supply and food price on the basis of identifying the two conditions that the three series are first difference stationary series and the money stock and price series are not cointegrated. Saunders' lag order selection criterion developed from Akaikes final prediction error (FPE), and Hsiao's lag selection procedure are used to identify the order of lags of each variable in VAR model. The models perform well through all diagnostic checks. All hypotheses are tested by using the likelihood ratio statistic and the chi2-statistic. The Granger test of causality is discussed and implemented in this research. By comparing the causality results of the seasonally adjusted series with those of seasonally unadjusted series we find that they are very sensitive to the seasonal adjustment of the series. For the seasonally adjusted series there is no relationship between money base (MB) and the food component of the consumer price index (FCPI) and there is a unidirectional causal relationship between M1 and FCPI (from M1 to FCPI). But for the seasonally unadjusted series there is a feedback relationship between M1 and FCPI and there is a unidirectional flow from MB to FCPI. The difference of the results is consistent with the findings of Sargent and other writers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baker, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b105d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x931</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food prices -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Money supply -- Canada</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x6025"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The distribution of the low density lipoprotein receptor related protein-2 (LRP-2) in the male and female reproductive tracts of the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wosu, Uchechi Amy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study examines the distribution of the low density lipoprotein receptor related protein-2 (LRP-2) in the reproductive tracts of male and female rats. LRP-2 has been shown to facilitate the endocytosis, and lysosomal degradation of the glycoprotein SGP-2 in cultured cells. SGP-2 has been found in the male reproductive tract, is thought to be involved in sperm maturation. The apical surfaces of the epithelia of the efferent ducts as well as the intermediate zone, proximal caput, corpus, and cauda regions of the epididymis showed pronounced peroxidase staining for LRP-2. Immunogold labeling representing LRP-2 was observed in endocytic vesicles and early endosomes in the single labeling experiment. Labeling was much more significant in the efferent ducts than the epididymis. The double labeling experiment for LRP-2 and SGP-2 showed colocalization in the endocytic vesicles and early endosomes. SGP-2 also labeled the late endosomes and lysosomes. These results suggest that, LRP-2 mediates the endocytosis of SGP-2, and afterward is recycled back to the cell surface. The second aspect of the study examines the distribution of LRP-2 and SGP-2 in the epithelium of the uterus and the oviduct, in relation to the different stages of the estrus cycle. The surface epithelium and the epithelial cells lining the glands of the uterus were for the most part devoid of staining for LRP-2, except in the estrus stage when a strong reaction was seen in the apical region of the cells. The epithelium lining the glands of the uterus showed strong staining, while weak immunoperoxidase staining was observed for SGP-2 in the uterine surface epithelium in every stage of the estrus cycle. The epithelium of the proximal and distal, oviduct showed very little staining if at all for LRP-2 and SGP-2 for all stages of the estrus cycle. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morales, Carlos R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v12p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x6025</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axs55mf01s"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Evaluation de l'impact alimentaire du programme nutrionnel "Mangeons en coeur" et validation d'un questionnaire de comportement alimentaire</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ward, Ellen, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An evaluation of the impact of the nutritional program "Mangeons en coeur" was conducted with 64 participants in this program. The two study objectives were to measure any changes in the dietary intake of program participants and to evaluate the performance of a food habits questionnaire in evaluating change in fat intake at the individual level. The dietary evaluation by the diet history indicated no change in the total intake of lipids (31% of energy as lipids) over the course of the program. Comparisons of the total lipid intake as measured by the diet history and food habits questionnaire indicated significant correlations at both baseline and at the end of the program.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gray-Donald, Katerine</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n998x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mf01s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Diet -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nutrition surveys -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lipids in human nutrition -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Food habits -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akk91fn82g"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ecology of the wood turtle, Clemmys insculpta, Québec, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Walde, Andrew D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The most northeasterly population of wood turtles (Clemmys insculpta ) was studied during 1996 and 1997 in Quebec, Canada. A total of 188 turtles (55 males, 83 females, and 50 immatures) was captured, measured and marked for future identification. The adult sex ratio was not significantly different from 1:1. Males were significantly larger than females for measures of carapace length, 214.5 and 201 mm, respectively. Wood turtles from northern populations are larger than those from southern regions. The population density was estimated to be 0.44 turtles/hectare. Courtship occurred in the spring but was more common in the fall. Nesting occurred in mid-June with nesting activity taking place at all times of the day but more frequently in early morning and evening. Females migrated over 3 km to a nesting area and exhibited nest fidelity. Sixty-six percent of turtles nested in 2 consecutive yr and these females were significantly larger than turtles that nested in only 1 yr of the study. There was no mammalian predation but, some arthropods were suspected of being predators. Mean clutch size was 10.1 (range = 5--20) eggs. Comparisons with other populations of C. insculpta are also made.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Titman, Rodger</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc47z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn82g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Wood turtle -- Québec (Province)</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Azs25xb714"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Implementing of G.I.S. spatial operations in a database system</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Valdivia Martínez, Angélica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis presents a set of basic spatial operations implemented in a relational programming language. Our aim in undertaking this work was to demonstrate that a general purpose database system offers the needed flexibility for developing independent applications to manipulate spatial data. Thus, we exploited an existing Relix system by using both relational algebra functions and a relational database model. Effectiveness, rather than high performance, is the central issue in this work. Of the two aspects (spatial and descriptive) of geographical data, we address only the spatial component. A spatial operation manipulates geometric data objects such as points, lines, and polygons. A relational data model for storing graphic data, and the spatial operations to manipulate them, are needed. For this purpose, some data models together with manipulation techniques are analyzed. We designed and implemented computational geometry vector-based algorithms such as measurements, calculations, buffers, and overlays for two-dimensional objects using relational algebra. We also consider the important issue of interaction with commercial systems. We used other GIS such as ARC/INFO and MapInfo for data entry and display of results. Moreover, we developed C routines to communicate Relix with the GIS. We document the usage of each operation and the relational algebra routines. We also provide examples which illustrate the operations. We conclude that the relational algebra can be effectively applied to produce spatial operations in a unified system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Merrett, T. H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br62m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb714</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Information Science</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A765373240"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physiology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modulation of atrial natriuretic peptide receptors in rat pregnancy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Vaillancourt, Patrice A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mechanisms underlying the net fluid/electrolyte gain during pregnancy are not fully understood. Utilizing virgin, pregnant (7, 16 and 21 days gestation), estradiol-17beta- or progesterone-treated female rats, we have examined the role of atrial natriuretic peptide (ANP) and of its receptors in the adaptation of body fluid homeostasis during pregnancy. Pregnancy and progesterone attenuate the ANP-mediated inhibition on aldosterone production in adrenal zona, glomerulosa (ZG) cells. The ribonuclease protection assay and Western analysis revealed that ZG natriuretic peptide guanylyl cyclase-linked (GC) receptors are mainly GC-A and that they are downregulated by pregnancy. In addition, pregnancy downregulates GC-A and GC-B receptors in the uterus; however, it does not modulate GC-linked receptors in the lung. It is concluded that the downregulation of ZG GC-A receptors could lead to a decrease in the aldosterone-suppressant effects of ANP and that the decrease in uterine GC-A and GC-B receptors could lead to a decrease in the tocolytic effects of ANP during pregnancy.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mulay, Shree</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z9928.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765373240</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqf85nd24g"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular basis for the enantiopreference of lipase from Pseudomonas cepacia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tuomi, William Victor</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An empirical rule which predicts which enantiomer will be preferred by lipases (triacylglycerol hydrolases) based on the relative sizes of the substituents has previously been developed for secondary alcohols. This rule was then extended towards primary alcohols for lipase from Pseudomonas cepacia (PCL). However, the rule for primary alcohols shows an opposite enantiopreference compared to the rule for secondary alcohols. Furthermore, it is no longer valid when an oxygen lies at the stereocentre. This thesis explores the molecular basis for the empirical rule for primary alcohols and why the rule is no longer valid when an oxygen lies next to the stereocentre. Molecular modeling studies on 2-methyl-3-phenyl-1-propanol and 2-phenoxy-1-propanol, both as the free substrate and covalently linked to the active site of PCL were performed. The modeling studies were then supported by two series of laboratory experiments: determination of the kinetic constants, kcat and Km; and chemical modification of PCL by acetylation and nitration.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kazlauskas, Romas</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999877n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd24g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz87n"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optical field response from structured nano- and mesocomposites</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tuling, Russell J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Molecular self-assembly (MSA) was used to fabricate multilayered composites on silicon, silicon monoxide and silica substrates. 3-mercaptopropyltrimethoxysilane (MPTMS) was grafted onto the substrates, followed by chemisorbed silver colloidal nanoparticles. 1,4-benzenedimethanethiol (BDMT) was used to chemisorb gold to silver colloidal nanoparticles forming an MPTMS-silver-methyl-BDMT-gold heterostructure. A self-poling stilbazole dye---(E)-[4- N,N-(octadecylmethylamino)styryl]pyridine (ODMASP)---was integrated with a mercaptoacetic acid (MAA) spacer into an MPTMS-silver-MAA-ODMASP heterostructure by MSA of ODMASP C18 alkyl tails. ODMASP on fractal silver aggregates enhanced the 2nd-order nonlinear susceptibility implying that silver colloid intensified the electrical field to produce a c2 of 1.48 x 10-22 C3/J 2 (4.00 x 10-8 esu). We used x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), ultraviolet-visible (UV-VIS) spectroscopy and second harmonic generation (SHG) for characterization. We described the synthesis of a tolane dye---N-4-[(4 '-nitrodiphenylethynyl)phenyl]-bis-2 ′-diethanethiolamine (NDPEPD)---by palladium-catalyzed cross-coupling. Corona poled NDPEPD-doped poly(styrene) films produced a c2 of 1.5 x 10-23 C3/J 2 (0.4 x 10-8 esu).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andrews, Mark P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh23k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz87n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avt150m18g"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Using radiocesium (137Cs) to measure and compare the bioenergetic budgets of juvenile Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar) and brook trout (Salvelinus fontinalis) in the field</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tucker, Strahan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Through the 137Cs mass balance method, annual consumption rates were estimated for juvenile Atlantic salmon parr and precocious males, as well as brook trout from 4 sites within the Ste Marguerite river system, Quebec. With explicit age analysis, feeding rates and growth rates were derived on an individual fish and age class basis. These represent the first consumption estimates for Atlantic salmon in the wild. The individual fish approach provided a range of data for a single site, as opposed to a single estimate per age class, allowing for an evaluation of the relationship between consumption and growth for each species or life-history variant. Subsequently, the concept of field maintenance ration was introduced as the intercept of consumption over growth. Salmonid feeding rates were coupled with density estimates to derive total fish exploitation rates for two streams. The application of age- and site-specific feeding rates derived from the 137Cs mass balance method, solved a long standing paradox in stream ecology as all previously inferred salmonid exploitation rates have been in excess of prey turnover. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rasmussen, J. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g48t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m18g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Atlantic salmon -- Québec (Province) -- Sainte-Marguerite River -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brook trout -- Québec (Province) -- Sainte-Marguerite River -- Growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atlantic salmon -- Food -- Québec (Province) -- Sainte-Marguerite River</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brook trout -- Food -- Québec (Province) -- Sainte-Marguerite River</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abz60cz76x"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>On a special case of the Strong Littlewood Conjecture</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trudeau, Sidney</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A special case of the Strong Littlewood Conjectures asserts that &amp;dvbm0;cosnx+cosmx&amp;dvbm0;1 ≥&amp;dvbm0;cosx+cos3x&amp;dvbm0; 1, or equivalently, &amp;dvbm0;cosnxcosmx&amp;dvbm0;1 ≥&amp;dvbm0;cosxcos2x&amp;dvbm0; 1. This thesis investigates a method of proof (as proposed by I. Klemes) for each of these and their extension to concave functions in general.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Klemes, Ivo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h6624.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz76x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343v161"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Macronutrient composition of maternal diet affects hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal responsiveness in developing rat pups</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Trottier, Geneviève</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We studied the consequences of providing rat dams with elevated levels of dietary fat during lactation on stress responses in the offspring at different stages of development. High-fat feeding increased total milk lipid levels, and led to increased lipid deposition and plasma leptin levels in pups. Ten-day-old neonates from high-fat fed mothers had reduced stress responsiveness compared to controls. In contrast, 35-day-old pups from mothers fed high-fat diets showed greater stress-induced ACTH secretion. These findings indicate that maternal diet has effects on hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) responsiveness, which can persist after weaning to a normal rat chow diet. We also investigated macronutrient selection in the offspring, since differences in nutrient preferences may produce long-lasting consequences of lactational diet. However, our results did not support an involvement of maternal diet in postweaning nutrient selection. Furthermore, HPA stress responses were no longer related to maternal diet once offspring reached maturity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Walker, Claire-Dominique</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp53n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v161</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Human Development</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apg15bh24v"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular phylogeography of Dryas integrifolia : glacial refugia and postglacial recolonization</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tremblay, Nicolas-Olivier R.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis addresses the consequences of the last glaciation on the distribution and genetic diversity of arctic flora. The principal aim is to infer the full-glacial and postglacial migrational history of Dryas integrifolia M. Vahl. (Rosaceae) from the intraspecific phylogeny of cpDNA haplotypes along with pollen and macrofossil distribution data. The results suggest that four refugia existed during the last glaciation and that each served as significant sources of recolonization when the ice retreated. The two most important refugia are located in the northwestern Arctic (Beringia and the High Arctic), with two other refugia located southeast of the ice sheet and along the coastal regions of the eastern Arctic. High genetic substructure among populations is likely attributable to past vicariance and recent recolonization events, whereas high local diversity is probably indicative of recolonization from several sources and high gene flow in recent time.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Schoen, Daniel J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m403m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh24v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dryas -- Arctic regions -- Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glaciers -- Arctic regions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plants -- Migration -- Arctic regions</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj6731617p"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Optimal management of a transboundary fishery with specific reference to the Pacific salmon</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tian, Huilan, 1964-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Managing a common property resource, especially one jointly owned by two nations, is a formidable problem as it involves both incentives to cooperate and incentives to cheat. Often conflicts flare up, followed by efforts of reconciliation, which are interrupted again by new conflicts. A classic example of this is the Pacific salmon fishery, which is jointly harvested by the U.S.A and Canada. To understand the nature of this conflict, and to make policy recommendations, a game-theoretic approach is developed in this thesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Thomassin, Paul J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx52q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731617p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Fishery management -- Pacific Coast (North America)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pacific salmon fisheries -- Pacific Coast (North America) -- Management</dc:subject><dc:subject>Game theory</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9019s457k"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Test of a new prototype of multiwire proportional chamber with pixel pad cathode readout</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Teodorescu, Octavian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new prototype of multiwire proportional chamber (MWPC) with pixel configurated pad cathode was built as a joint effort by McGill University, Lund University and Oak Ridge National Laboratory as part of the development of the tracking system of the PHENIX detector at the Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider (RHIC). This thesis first describes the implementation of a new readout electronics for the pad chambers. In this electronics, the charge of the pads is digitized using a preamplifier/shaper/discriminator integrated CMOS chip with adjustable threshold. All chips and components are mounted on specially designed 48-channel readout cards using chip-on-board (COB) technology. Using this new readout, the performance of the pad chamber is tested with cosmic rays and X-ray source. The prototype response, efficiency and gain are measured as functions of detector operating conditions. The operation of the chamber shows a very good stability over long periods of testing. Excellent efficiencies, above 99%, are observed in tests using discriminator thresholds between 2--4 fC, which represents 1--1.5% of the most probable anode charge produced at a normal anode voltage of 1850V. Under this conditions, the reconstructed hit patterns are relatively small. This is leading to a very good position resolution of about half of the cell size. An excellent description of chamber behavior was obtained using Monte Carlo simulations. showing that we can use these simulations to predict and optimize the performance of such chamber.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barrette, Jean</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s65f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s457k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physics, Nuclear</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f462758f"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Methods to predict and reduce trace metal levels in lettuce grown on contaminated urban soils = Méthodes pour prédire et réduire les métaux traces dans la laitue cultivés sur des sols contaminés</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tambasco, Giuseppe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work in this thesis demonstrates whether resins are better than conventional soil extractants at predicting plant metal concentrations, and whether low-cost soil treatments can effectively reduce metal content and concentrations in lettuce leaves. Researchers have shown that ion exchange resins can simulate root metal uptake behaviour by acting as ion sinks. Chemical extractants on the other hand, generally do not behave in this manner. Thus, we would expect resins (in either bead or membrane form) to predict plant metal concentrations better than conventional extractants. For the first study, a procedure using anion exchange resin membranes (AEM) treated with either EDTA or DTPA chelators was chosen, since previous studies showed this method to be effective at predicting plant metal uptake, and practical for routine laboratory use. In addition, several conventional extractants were selected for comparison. For the second part of the thesis, a study was undertaken to test the effectiveness of various food processing byproducts to stabilize metal contaminants in soils, and compare the results with those of a Na-based aluminosilicate (zeolite). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hendershot, William H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268732t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462758f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Ion exchange resins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil pollution -- Environmental aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trace elements -- Environmental aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lettuce -- Effect of pollution on</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metals -- Environmental aspects</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj96023100"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Small scale flow features near a straight coastline and wharf area in the Lower St. Lawrence estuary</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sun, Xumin, 1972-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Small-scale flow features were examined near a straight coastline off Ste. Flavie and an adjacent wharf in the Lower St. Lawrence estuary, using moored current meter and acoustic doppler current profiler (ADCP) data. The leading order velocity was found to be dominated by the mean and lunar semi-diurnal (M2) tidal currents. In the straight shoreline area, no eddy was found. The presence of stratification led to baroclinic low frequency (LP, including the mean) velocities with depth. Freshwater forcing and wind stress dominated the "non-tidal" surface layer dynamics. Near the bottom, friction and other factors induced an Ekman-like spiral in the LP velocity profile. The tidal currents were barotropic, with the M2 constituent dominating the tidal energy. In the wharf area, flow in the lee was found to be an order of magnitude weaker than the free strewn flow offshore. Time-mean spatial eddies were also evident in the lee. Evolution maps within a single M2 tidal cycle show the existence of transient eddies, characterized by a pair of counter-rotating eddies generated both during maximum flood and ebb tide.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ingram, Grant</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p930v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96023100</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical Geography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acf95jd471"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Should we limit prenatal testing for adult-onset disorders?</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sun, Chia Chia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Should we limit prenatal diagnosis for adult-onset disorders? Since genetic medicine has dissociated its eugenic past, the principle of respect for autonomy has become a model for conduct. However, this model promotes individualism and neglects the impact on disabled people. Since the implications of aborting a fetus with possibly four decades of health are potentially greater for society, moral theories that incorporate meaning about communal bonds may be more appropriate. An ethics of care is proposed as an alternative model for justifying prenatal diagnosis for congenital diseases. However, the theory is limited to the private sphere and potentially less applicable to late-onset diseases. Broader theories of relation-based ethics, such as in communitarianism and its feminist interpretation, provide the basis for asserting that the impact of aborting a fetus with an adult-onset disease should be examined by turning to the communities that are affected, including families coping with, and individuals living with, adult-onset diseases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Glass, Kathleen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881p22s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jd471</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asn00b106p"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of vasa during oogenesis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Styhler, Sylvia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Drosophila melanogaster gene vasa is known to be necessary for the establishment of a functional pole plasm, as well as for the completion of oogenesis. To further elucidate its role, we have created a null mutation of the vasa gene and examined vasa-null ovaries for defects. Analysis of these ovaries has revealed that vasa is involved in various aspects of oogenesis, including the growth of germ-line cysts, oocyte differentiation, anterior-posterior egg chamber patterning, and dorsal-ventral follicle patterning. In addition, vasa-null oocytes fail to show efficient accumulation of various localized RNAs, such as Bicaudal-C, Bicaudal-D, egl, enc, orb, oskar , and nanos, but still show accumulation of gurken RNA. Interestingly, the accumulation of GURKEN protein in the oocyte is severely reduced, and that of BICAUDAL-C is substantially decreased in null mutants. These results suggest a possible role for vasa in activating translation of targeted RNAs during oogenesis.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lasko, Paul</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3303.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b106p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Oogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>