<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87pv13v"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Consequences of American investment in Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kelly, Michael. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject of American investment in Canada is a topic on the mind of many Canadians. Insofar as it is a major part of the overall pattern of American investment abroad it is al so a serious concern to the United States. For the latter the main problem it poses is the strain placed on its balance of payments. For the Canadian, however, the problem is not so transient. It is the long-run effects rather than the short-run which worries him. The short-run effects of American investment in Canada have been beneficial; the stimulant of increased demand has spread to other sectors of the economy and prosperity has followed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Levitt, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq932.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pv13v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xw465"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relationship between climate, ablation, and run-off on an arctic glacier</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Keeler, Charles. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The analysis of glacier wasting is a tripartate study which includes: the measurement of the quantity of wasting, an examination of the causes of wasting, and an investigation of the means of disposal of the waste products. This particular investigation is an attempt to improve upon the accuracy of measurements of wasting so that future investigators will be able to make more meaningful statements regarding cause. In the 1930's the first quantitative studies of the heat exchange at a melting ice surface were made in Scandinavia. By measuring the heat received at the surface from radiation, convection and conduction from the atmosphere, glacial-meteorologists were able, with limited accuracy, to relate the heat received at the surface to the melt measured from the surface lowering of the glacier. This type of study has now been carried out in many varied locations with a concommitant rise in the sophistication of the observational techniques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Muller, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd509.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw465</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t9862"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Labour problems in the industrialization of Pakistan</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kazi, Sadat. I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subject matter of this study is the analysis of “Labour Problems in the Industrialization of Pakistan". Industrial development has become a major consideration of policy for underdeveloped countries. Pakistan, like at her emerging nations, has commit ted herself to the rapid industrialization of her primarily agricultural economy. She aspires, through it, to attain higher living standards, to eliminate mass illiteracy, and to eradicate diseases. “Industrialization refers to the actual course of transition from the traditional society towards industrialism". (1) For such a process of development a country needs capital, technology, natural resources, entrepreneurs and skilled and professional manpower.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Woods, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d348h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t9862</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqb98mj95d"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>I. Studies of factors which influence the patency of the internal mammary artery implantation. II. Treatment of heart block using the transplanted sympathetic chain</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kato, Yutaka</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has been estimated that of the total deaths due to heart disease one-third may be attributed to primary coronary artery insufficiency related to atherosclerosis as the dominant factor, one third to primary coronary insufficiency associated with cardiac hypertrophy and increased work arising from valvular lesions and hypertension, and one-third to primary myocardial insufficiency. In other words, two-thirds of the deaths from heart disease may be traced directly or indirectly to coronary artery insufficiency (Rowe 1960). Wearn in 1933 described arterioluminal vessels running from the coronary arteries through the myocardium to the ventricular cavities, arterioluminal sinusoids passing deviously through the myocardium, connecting the arterial lumen to the ventricular cavity and the Thebesian veins communicating with the coronary venous system and ventricular lumen.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Palmer, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm76n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mj95d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agm80j010j"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Guidance in a boys’ club: a community organization approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Katadotis, Peter</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Boys’ Clubs are presently undergoing a painful period of re-orientation. They are beginning to look beyond their boy-centered recreational programs into the community and the manifold problems and challenges it presents. They are, in the language of the Boys' Clubs, becoming extremely "guidance conscious." The purpose of this study is to examine the guidance component of a guidance conscious Boys' Club.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ross, V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tz74q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j010j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A70795c36q"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A histochemical and cytological study of the development of the shell in the gastropod, Helisoma duryi eudiscus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kapur, Shakti. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The mechanism of the formation of the molluscan shell has been the subject of controversy since the first observations were made by Reaumer in 1709 on the normal growth and regeneration of shells. There is considerable agreement on the sites of secretion of the shell materiel and the histological identity of these tissues. However, controversy centres about the mechanism by which the organic matrix of the inner layers of the shell is released into the extra-pallial space, by which it is deposited and subsequently calcified. The controversy has, of late, gained importance in that it provides excellent possibilities for the study of the organic composition of the calcifying matrices and their manner of calcification.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gibson, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bx86x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795c36q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Zoology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j245t"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Temporal discrimination in rats during continuous brain stimulation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaplan, Joel. N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Kaada (1951) reported that electrical stimulation immediately anterior to and directly below the genu of the corpus collosum (septal area) produced inhibition of various autonomic and somatamotor responses. On the other band, he found that stimulation above the corpus collosum in the area of the anterior and midcingulate cortex yielded facilitation of these same reactions. Based on Kaada's data, McCleary (1961) found a difference between these two loci at the behavioral level. Cats sustaining bilateral subcallosal lesions were deficient in acquiring a passive avoidance response (PAR).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malmo, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794081545.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j245t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g6103"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The genetics of ragweed hay fever</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kallio, Eleanor. I.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Ragweed hay fever makes thousands of people miserable every year. These people have an allergy to ragweed pollen. The characteristic symptoms include rhinitis, sneezing, nasal blockage and itching of the nose, eyes and throat. These symptoms appear in sensitive people soon after ragweed pollen is introduced into the environment. They occur every year from about the middle of August until the first frost, during the time that the wind-pollinated plant is dispersing its heavy load of pollen. The plants causing most trouble are the short ragweed, Ambrosia artemisiifolia L. var. elatior (L.) Descourtils, giant ragweed, Ambrosia trifida L., and western ragweed, Ambrosia psilostachya DC. var. coronopifolia (T. &amp; T.) Farw. (Bassett and Frankton, 1961).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Fraser, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719q65w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g6103</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n204259d"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Etiology of chronic murine pneumonia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Joshi, Narendra. N.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The etiology of endemic pneumonia in rats has been investigated, and the specific cause of the condition was established. A viral agent was isolated in rat embryo skin primary tissue cultures, and postulates have been fulfilled for identifying this viral agent with endemic pneumonia in rats. Some characteristics of this virus were established. A method for demonstrating the cytopathogenic agent, involving two-step incubation of inoculated tissue cultures at two different temperatures has been described. This technique was successfully employed for the isolation of the virus responsible for endemic pneumonia in rats.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Blackwood, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d5701096.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204259d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zr987"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Volume change, moisture retention and permeability of clay-sand mixtures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Jong, Eeltje</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Water movement in clay soils is influenced by the volume changes associated with water content changes, and by the water retention characteristics of the soils. These properties are all dependent upon particle-size distribution. This thesis attempts to establish relations between texture and shrinkage, moisture retention, and permeability for a simplified soil system consisting of mixtures of clay and glass beads. Observations are explained in terms of the present theories for soil-water interactions. The thesis is subdivided into four chapters. The first chapter gives an account of present views on soilwater interactions, and is included to facilitate discussion in the later chapters.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Warkentin, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96024484.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zr987</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945v386"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experiment in delinquency</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Jones, Beau. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Research between the two world wars on the causes of juvenile delinquency was dominated by scholars from Chicago. It was a period of exploration on a grand scale in which sociologists were aligned with each other in their search to uncover sociological factors in crime causation and in their desire to maintain an approach which was distinct from other approaches to the problem – namely that of psychologists. It was a period in which great contributions were made to theory and methodology. And it provided the foundations for the post war theories with which this research project is primarily concerned.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Solomon, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zf64n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v386</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z903351s"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Deglaciation and emergence of the Webb Bay – Port Manvers run area of Labrador</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Johnson, John. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Labrador's coastal scenery is dominated by evidence of Pleistocene glaciation. Before World War II only a few, generally bread studies touching on this subject bad been made in Labrador. From these the overwhelming effect of continental glaciation became clear. However, the chronology of glaciation had yet to be established, and little regional evidence bad been obtained to support existing hypotheses explaining the character and effects of Labrador-Quebec's glaciation. Expeditions like that of Vainö Tanner (1944) have shown that studies in detail or concentrated in small areas are essential if the deglaciation and emergence of coastal Labrador are to be understood.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bq08w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903351s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As1784q053"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Considerations in the dynamics of clay soils</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Japp, Robert. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Strain rates ranging from 20% to 100% per second were used in consolidated-undrained triaxial tests, to investigate the influence of rate effects on the behaviour of cohesive soils. To apply the required loading rates, a hydraulic test unit was designed. Techniques were developed for producing saturated remoulded samples and for measuring the applied stresses, strain and pore pressures in the dynamic test. Electrical instrumentation was used for sensing and recording the transients. No pore pressure measurements were obtained in the dynamic tests conducted. For the same consolidation pressure, the strength of samples as determined in a triaxial test increased with increasing strain rates. Rate dependent dilatational effects are not the predominant cause of the observed behaviour.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tq423.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784q053</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074z576"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Torque meters based on magnetic-stress anisotropy</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ionides, Rudolf. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A theory of operation, design recommendations and performance limits of torque meters, based on magnetic-stress anisotropy, have been established. The theory, based on considerations of total magnetic-crystal energy, successfully explains both the qualitative and quantitative behaviour of these devices. The theory has been checked and the design recommendations have been established by measurement of the behaviour of steel and nickel torque tubes of various wall thicknesses over a range of magnetizing force, frequency and stress. It has been established that sustained accuracies of better than 1% are readily obtained, the limit of accuracy being of the order of 0.1%. Such devices are simple, robust and have an output power sufficient to operate a meter directly.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Barton, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t570w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074z576</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A05741w20n"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The release of the vasoactive polypeptide bradykinin in experimental haemorrhagic shock in dogs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Innes, Bruce. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Discussions with regard to circulatory alterations in shock and the end results of these changes have gone on for many years. As early- as 1944 vasoexcitor and vasodepressor substances in shock states were postulated and efforts were made to identify the substances responsible. These studies represented one of the first steps in the search to find a single substance as a common denominator in various forms of shock. Recent studies of polypeptides, their biological activity and affect on vasomotor tone have suggested their possible importance in shock states. The more recent studies by Moffat on Bradykinin release in pancreatitis, and by Thal on the release of vasoactive peptides in experimental bowel ischaemic shock models have been the two main studies that led to the quantitative measurement of the release of Bradykinin in experimental haemorrhagic shock.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hampson, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p831h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741w20n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Surgery, Experimental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1g05fg35x"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Monte-Carlo simulation of neutron streaming in a nuclear reactor</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hyder, Syed. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The gaps in a nuclear reactor, provided for experimental research or the flow of a coolant gas, permit the neutrons to flow from one region of the reactor to another. This effect, referred to as streaming, is usually accounted for in reactor design calculations by Behrens’ theory an application of the chord method originally developed by Cauchy. A Monte-Carlo program has been developed in this study to test the validity of Behrens’ theory, and to extend its applications by considering effects not included in that theory. Various void shapes and sizes relative to the moderator have been studied. Results have been obtained for cases where the theory is difficult to apply.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Edis, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw311.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fg35x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A08612s09w"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of French</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Le rôle de la femme dans le théâtre de Paul Claudel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Huzarewitz, Helen. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Je médite depuis longtemps le rôle de la femme dans le théâtre de Claudel. Or aucun écrivain français si ce n'est Racine n'a créé de femme qui puisse être comparée à la femme claudélienne sans souffrir de la comparaison. Les grands rôles féminins dans le théâtre de Claudel – ceux de Prouhèze, d'Ysé et de Violaine -- sont uniques dans leur profondeur et leur puissance et une étude sérieuse des rôles mineurs découvre une richesse peu soupçonnée au premier abord. D'ou vient cette richesse? Elle vient de la conception que Claudel a eue de la Femme. Elle vient du rôle qu'il lui a donné de jouer dans son théâtre, rôle qui murit d'une pièce a l'autre. Ce qu'est la femme, simple suggestion, dans Tète d'Or 1889, s’épanouit et atteint sa formulation finale dans le Soulier de Satin de 1924.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Champigneul, Y.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tz750.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s09w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>French</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2801pk80n"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A method for the detection of atomic hydrogen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hurlburt, Douglas. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A recombination bolometer for the detection of atomic hydrogen was designed and constructed. The bolometer consisted of a platinum disk, to the back of which was bonded a small bead type thermistor. The recombination of atoms upon the surface of the disk provided sufficient heat that a substantial change in the resistance of the thermistor was observed. As part of a testing program for the device, the relative sensitivity defined as (change in temperature/relative number of atoms present) was measured for atomic hydrogen, nitrogen and oxygen. Since the three atoms studied are paramagnetic, it was possible to determine their relative populations by making use of a μ-wave absorption spectrometer. The results of the sensitivity measurements yielded a nitrogen sensitivity of .083 and an oxygen sensitivity of .0024, where the hydrogen sensitivity is taken to be unity. The "decay time", defined as the time required for the temperature of the device to drop 63.2% of the total temperature change when the radicals were turned off was measured to be 15 seconds vs. a calculated value of 25.5 seconds.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Farnell, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jc405.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk80n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445ch75x"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Central nervous system mediated cardiovascular responses to drugs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Huq, Shariful</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In earlier reported studies from this laboratory (Share and Melville, 1961; Varma et al, 1962; and Melville and Share, 1963) it was shown that injection of the convulsant drug, picrotoxin, into the lateral cerebral ventricles of cats and rabbits can lead to a rise in arterial blood pressure associated with various types of electrocardiographic ST-T alterations and cardiac arrhythmias (bradycardia, tachycardia, extrasystoles and even ventricular fibrillation in rabbits). It was suggested that these cardiovascular effects of picrotoxin were mediated through central excitation of adrenergic mechanisms, probably involving "release" of catecholamines (noradrenaline mainly) from the hypothalamus and midbrain.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Melville, K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf94n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445ch75x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kt918"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Notes on the neural control of breathing</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Houseley, Michael. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In his review of 1946 Pitts (110) presented a concept of the central nervous control of breathing which accounted for many of the experimental observations made up to that time, and in particular for the phenomenon of maintained inspiration or apneusis seen in vagotomized animals sectioned at the midpontile level (69, 100, 112, 133, 137). According to the hypothesis propounded by Pitts there are anatomically separate inspiratory and expiratory centres in the medulla, located in close spatial relationship one to the other. These centres could be differentially activated by localized electrical stimulation of points in the medulla (112).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Robson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jj053.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kt918</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bx876"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of History</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>British missions and imperialism in Afirca, 1875-1900</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hornby, Allon. E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>"In the nineteenth century the white has made a man out of the black, and in the twentieth, Europe will make a world out of Africa." These words, written by W. G. Blaikie, author of "Life of Livingstone," express the fairly general attitude of the last twenty years of the nineteenth century in Britain. Africa, a few years earlier, had been comparatively unknown, except along the coast lines. Livingstone, with his adventurous and noble feats, had changed this greatly, and had made Africa a focal point of interest, not only for the casually curious, but also for the statesman, merchant, and missionary.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reid, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dk14x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx876</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>History</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ath83m296f"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The toxemia of halo blight of bean</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hoitink, Henricus. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The toxigenic theory of plant disease explains the occurrence of pathological disturbances in advance of the invading pathogen as the effect of a toxin produced in the course of host-pathogen interaction. A considerable amount of work has been done on such diseases, which are called toxemia; however much of it is still a matter of controversy. Much more research must be done on this subject before many of the concepts involved can be accepted. At present, there is need for studies to show that pathogens can produce the same toxins both in axenic culture and in infection, and that injection with toxins can reproduce the physiological disturbances and the symptoms characteristic of the disease.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Coulson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g77m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m296f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52jc41f"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The yield, botanical composition and quality of forage as influenced by chemical fertilizers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hew, Ewan. G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In a report presented by Frens (1955) it was pointed out that, apart from some exceptional cases, an extension of the present grassland area could not be advocated in a great number of countries. Consequently, efforts will have to be concentrated on intensifying the production of the existing grassland area or improving the quality of grass. It was stressed that at the same time the best possible management practices would be required. On the basis of the 1951 census, Raymond (1958) in a bulletin on pastures for Quebec showed improved pastures in the province as having a carrying capacity of 1.6 acres per animal unit whereas when the total area - 4,768,313 acres - is considered, a carrying capacity of almost exactly 3 acres per animal unit is obtained.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Steppler, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70n002m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jc41f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gp42b"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A comparative study of the external anatomy of Conophthorus Hopkins (Coleoptera: scolytidae) with a taxonomic interpretation of species in Ontario</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Herdy, Harry</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The infestation of Pinus species in Ontario by species of Conophthorus Hopkins has been recognized for some time. Damage to the cones and shoots of eastern white pine, Pinus strobus Lamb., by Conophthorus coniperda (Schwarz) was noticed about 1884 (Harrington 1902a). Similar damage to red pine, P. resinosa Ait., due to C. resinosae Hopkins was reported by Harrington (1902a) to have been discovered several years later in 1887. Thomas and Lindquist (1956) and Herdy and Thomas (1961) have reported that shoots of jack pine, P. banksiana Lamb., are infested by Conophthorus species. The mining of Scots pine shoots, P. sylvestris Lamb., has also been mentioned by Thomas and Lindquist (1956), although the presence of Conophthorus species on this tree species does not seem to be extensive.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Leroux, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n462b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp42b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Entomology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257j30f"><ual:graduationDate>1964</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The spatial structure of Barbadian peasant agriculture</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Henshall, Janet. D.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study is based on twenty weeks field work in the Caribbean during the months of May, June, July, August and September, 1963. Three weeks of this time were spent working in the libraries of the University of the West Indies at Mona, Jamaica and St. Augustine, Trinidad and of the University of Puerto Rico at San Juan, Puerto Rico. Brief visits were made to other islands, for example Tobago, St. Lucia, Martinique, Antigua and St. Maarten, for comparative purposes. The research project was undertaken as part of the McGill University Geography Department Tropical Programme. In Barbados the Programme has emphasised research into land use and the development of peasant agriculture.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Haver, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z518.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257j30f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>