<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hr93h"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Schulich School of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The application of exercise physiology on flute pedagogy: Optimizing deliberate embouchure muscle training</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martins de Oliveira, Andre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse, sur l'activation des muscles péribuccaux durant le jeu de la flûte, vise à comprendre leur participation dans la formation de l'embouchure du flûtiste en vue d'appliquer certains principes d'entraînement de la physiologie de l'exercice à la pratique de la flûte et, ainsi, potentiellement améliorer le développement musculaire et l'acquisition de compétences menant à la maîtrise de l'instrument. Les données électromyographiques de surface (sEMG) de 3 muscles péribuccaux (orbicularis oris superior - OOS, depressor anguli oris - DAO et zygomaticus major - ZYG) ont été mesurées bilatéralement auprès de 14 flûtistes, des hommes (n = 4) et des femmes (n = 10), possédant une vaste expérience instrumentale (x ̅ = 14 ± 6,7 ans) et étant âgés de 18 à 50 ans (x ̅ = 26 ± 10).  Les participants ont joué a) une gamme chromatique, b) un exercice de sonorité de Marcel Moyse, et c) le premier mouvement de la sonate de Bach pour flûte en do majeur. Les mesures ont permis d'établir : la corrélation entre les notes jouées et l'activation musculaire, la fatigue engendrée par l'exercice de sonorité, et la distinction entre les patrons musculaires utilisés durant le morceau et l'exercice.  Les résultats démontrent: un changement significatif (p ≤ 0,001) d'activation des muscles péribuccaux durant les notes du registre aigu, faisant ressortir une corrélation linéaire positive entre les deux variables (coefficient de Pearson, r &gt; 0,85); un état de fatigue induit par l'exercice (p ≤ 0,01); et une activation musculaire d'une intensité et variabilité supérieures durant la sonate, bien que ces derniers résultats ne soient pas significatifs selon l'analyse post hoc (correction de Bonferroni). Ces résultats, combinés aux caractéristiques physiologiques des muscles faciaux, suggèrent que les stratégies de pratique visant à développer l'embouchure devraient : prioriser l'entraînement intermittent plutôt que continu; opter pour un entraînement axé sur la force ou l'endurance selon le niveau d'intensité de l'extrait musical; et donner la priorité aux pièces de répertoire plutôt qu'aux exercices.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis examined the activation of perioral muscles during flute playing in order to elucidate embouchure muscle recruitment and, in turn, enable the application of exercise physiology training principles on flute practice, thereby potentially improving muscle development and skill acquisition during flute mastering. Surface electromyographic (sEMG) data of 3 muscles (orbicularis oris superior – OOS, depressor anguli oris – DAO, and zygomaticus major – ZYG) were collected bilaterally from 14 players with an extensive background on the instrument (x ̅= 14 ± 6.7 years), both male (n = 4) and female (n = 10), aged 18-50 (x ̅= 26 ± 10). Participants played a) a chromatic scale, b) Marcel Moyse's widespread tone exercise, and c) the first movement of the Bach sonata for flute in C major. Three assessments were derived from these excerpts, identifying: the correlation between pitch and muscle activation, the fatiguing effect of the tone exercise, and the distinction in muscles' behavior while playing the piece versus the exercise. Results showed: a significant change (p ≤ 0.001) in the activation of all the muscles as pitch moved toward the high register, evidencing a positive linear correlation between both variables (Pearson's r &gt; 0.85); a fatigued state induced by the tone exercise (p ≤0.01); and superior intensity and variability in the muscle activation recorded during the repertoire piece, although these last results were not significant according to the post hoc analysis (Bonferroni correction). These results, in conjunction with the physiological characteristics of facial muscles, suggest that flute practice aiming to develop the embouchure should: center on interval training rather than a continuous one; aim for a strength- or endurance-oriented training, depending on the intensity level of the musical excerpt; and prioritize the practice of repertoire pieces over exercises.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Isabelle Cossette</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd33f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr93h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v838271q"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microwave fluidized bed drying of celery: drying kinetics and exergy analysis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kaur, Amanat</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des expériences ont été menées pour étudier la cinétique de séchage des morceaux de céleri dans un séchoir à lit fluidisé assisté par micro-ondes et pour étudier l'efficacité énergétique et exergétique du processus. Dans la première partie, la cinétique de séchage du céleri a été étudiée à l'aide d'un séchoir à lit fluidisé assisté par micro-ondes à différentes températures de l'air de séchage (45 ° C, 55 ° C et 65 ° C) et à différentes densités de puissance initiale en micro-ondes (0, 1 et 2 W/g). Un modèle composite central a été utilisé pour définir les combinaisons de facteurs. La qualité du produit séché, la masse du produit, la température de l'air, l'humidité relative de l'air et la consommation d'énergie électrique ont été utilisés pour évalue la performance du processus de séchage. La température et l'humidité relative de l'air à la sortie du séchoir ont été utilisées pour estimer la perte de potentielle. Les résultats ont montré que le modèle de Midilli-Kucuk était le meilleur pour prévoir le rapport d'humidité (mass humide/masse sèche) en fonction du temps. Quelle que soit la température, l'utilisation de l'énergie micro-ondes a permis de réduire le temps de séchage de plus de 50%. La consommation électrique a diminué avec l'augmentation de la température de l'air et de la densité de puissance des micro-ondes. Le temps de séchage le plus rapide a été atteint à 65 ° C avec une densité de puissance des micro-ondes de 2W/g. Cependant, les essais de séchage effectués à une densité de puissance de 2 W/g ont entraîné un brunissement partiel du céleri coupé, alors qu'aucun effet défavorable n'a été observé sur la qualité du produit final à 0 et à 1W/g. Les conditions de séchage n'ont pas affecté les propriétés de réhydratation du produit final.Dans la deuxième partie, une analyse d'énergie et d'exergie a été réalisée pour de séchage du céleri dans un séchoir à lit fluidisé assisté par micro-ondes. Les essais ont été conduits à différents rapports de recirculation d'air (0, 0,5 et 1) et à différentes densités de puissance initiale de micro-ondes (0, 0,5 et 1 W/g). Un modèle composite central a été utilisé pour définir les combinaisons de facteurs. La masse du produit, la température de l'air, l'humidité relative de l'air, la vitesse de l'air et la consommation d'énergie électrique ont été utilisés pour monitorer la performance énergétique du séchoir. Les résultats ont indiqué que l'ajout de micro-ondes permettait de réduire le temps de séchage alors que l'augmentation du taux de recirculation d'air n'avait pas d'effet sur celui-ci. La consommation totale d'énergie et la consommation d'énergie spécifique du processus de séchage ont diminué avec l'augmentation de la densité de puissance initiale des micro-ondes et l'augmentation de la quantité d'air recyclé dans le système. La recirculation de l'air a permis d'accroître l'enthalpie de l'air entrant dans la chambre de séchage et de réduire la consommation d'énergie. L'exergie d'évaporation a été affectée par l'application de micro-ondes mais n'est pas affectée par le taux de recirculation de l'air. La consommation maximale d'énergie disponible a été atteinte pour la recirculation à 100% de l'air extrait. Ainsi, une plus grande quantité de recirculation de l'air a conduit à un meilleur système de séchage plus efficace sans affecter les temps de séchage.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Experiments were conducted to study the drying kinetics of celery pieces in a microwave assisted fluid bed dryer and to investigate the energy and exergy efficiency of the process. In the first part, the drying kinetics of celery was studied using a microwave assisted fluidized bed dryer at different drying air temperatures (45°C, 55°C and 65°C) and at different initial microwave power densities (0W/g,1W/g and 2W/g). A central composite design was used to set the factor combinations. Dried product quality, product mass, air temperature, air relative humidity, and electric power consumption were used to monitor the performance of the drying process. The temperature and relative humidity of the air at the exhaust of the dryer were used to estimate the loss of drying air potential. The results showed that the Midilli-Kucuk equation model was best in predicting the moisture ratio as a function of time. At any given temperature, the utilization of the microwave energy reduced the drying time by more than 50%. The electric power consumption decreased with an increase in air temperature and microwave power density. The fastest drying time was achieved at 65°C with microwave power density of 2W/g. Drying trials performed at a power density of 2W/g resulted in partial browning of cut celery, whereas no adverse effect was seen on the final product quality at 0W/g and 1W/g. Drying conditions did not affect the rehydration properties of the final product. In the second part, an energy and exergy analysis were performed on drying celery in a microwave assisted fluidized bed dryer at different recirculation ratios (0, 0.5 and 1) and at different initial microwave power densities (0W/g,0.5 W/g and 1W/g). A central composite design was used to set the factor combinations. Product mass, air temperature, air relative humidity, air velocity and electric power consumption were used to monitor the energy performance of the dryer. The drying time reduced with the addition of microwaves whereas recirculation ratio had no significant effect on it. Total power consumption and specific energy consumption of the drying process decreased with increasing initial microwave power density and increasing amount of exhaust air recycled into the system. Recirculation of exhaust air resulted in higher enthalpy of inlet air and lowered energy consumption. Exergy of evaporation was affected by the application of microwaves but remained unaffected by the recirculation ratio. The maximum consumption of available energy was achieved for the 100% recirculation of exhaust air. Thus, higher amount of recirculation of exhaust air resulted in a better sustainable drying system.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>G. S. Vijaya Raghavan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv91p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838271q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bioresource Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ajh343v225"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Biological and Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Assessing the effects of H2O2-induced oxidative stress on the viscoelastic properties of pre-osteoblast cells using quartz crystal microbalance with dissipation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shoaib, Saadia</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Oxidative stress, which is, linked to numerous diseases results from an imbalance in cellular redox state causing damage to the cell cytoskeleton and morphology, thereby affecting the cells' viscoelastic properties. In this study, we introduce a quartz crystal microbalance with dissipation (QCM-D) biosensing strategy to assess the effects of oxidative stress on the viscoelastic properties of MC3T3 cells modulated by varying concentrations of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2). We successfully tracked the changes in dissipation (ΔD-responses) caused by the interaction of H2O2 with MC3T3 cells' monolayer attached to a poly-D-lysine-coated polystyrene quartz sensor. While recovery of ΔD-response curve close to the baseline was obtained with low concentration (25 M), higher concentration treatment (50 M-10 mM) showed no recovery due to the rigidity of cell monolayer and/or mass loss relative to the control. Imaging techniques such as scanning electron, atomic force and fluorescence microscopy showed that upon 25 M H2O2 treatment, cell morphology recovered and appeared similar to control cells, whereas, higher concentrations (50 M-10 mM) resulted in the shrinkage of the cytoskeleton, loss in cell density and cells appeared to be apoptotic/necrotic, all of which was supported by live/dead cell assay results. Finally, total antioxidant (TAC) assay confirmed that while cells' metabolic state recovered from 25 M H2O2 treatment, higher concentrations led to a decline in antioxidant levels. Altogether, these results suggest that QCM-D biosensor is a viable tool for distinguishing between oxidative eustress and distress and hence, the developed QCM-D protocol can be used to investigate the effects of oxidative agents on cell viscoelastic behavior, which will allow the establishment of in vitro bone disease model associated with oxidative stress. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le stress oxydant est le résultat d'un déséquilibre de l'état d'oxydoréduction cellulaire. Ce phénomène est accompagné de lésions au niveau du cytosquelette et de la morphologie cellulaire, affectant ainsi les propriétés viscoélastiques des cellules. Dans cette étude, nous présentons une nouvelle stratégie de biodétection par microbalance à quartz avec dissipation (QCM-D) pour l'évaluation des effets du stress oxydant sur les propriétés viscoélastiques des cellules MC3T3 exposées à diverses concentrations de peroxyde d'hydrogène (H2O2).  Nous avons suivi avec succès les variations de dissipation (ΔD-réponses) provoquées par l'interaction du H2O2 avec une monocouche de cellules MC3T3 fixée à un capteur à quartz recouvert de poly-D-lysine. Bien que la récupération de la ΔD-réponse ait été obtenue avec une faible concentration (25 µM), un traitement à concentration plus élevée (50 µM-10 mM) n'a montré aucune récupération comme on peut le voir par la rigidité accrue de la monocouche cellulaire et /ou la perte de masse par rapport au témoin. Nous avons démontré par microscopie électronique à balayage, à force atomique et à fluorescence que 280 minutes après l'élimination du traitement à 25 µM de H2O2, la morphologie des cellules retrouvait une apparence semblable à celle des cellules témoins. En revanche, à concentration plus élevée (50 µM-10 mM) nous avons observé un rétrécissement du cytosquelette, une perte de densité cellulaire, et des cellules apoptotiques / nécrotiques. Toutes ces observations ont été appuyées par des tests de viabilité cellulaire. Enfin, une analyse de la capacité antioxydante totale (TAC) a confirmé que, malgré le rétablissement de l'état métabolique des cellules après le traitement à 25 µM, des concentrations plus élevées ont entraîné une baisse des niveaux d'antioxydants. Ces résultats dans leur ensemble démontrent que le comportement viscoélastique des cellules peut être utilisé pour déterminer la récupération des cellules soumises au stress oxydant.  Le biocapteur QCM-D peut donc être utilisé comme un outil pour distinguer le stress oxydant de la détresse. Le protocole de QCM-D développé peut servir à étudier les effets des agents oxydants sur les propriétés viscoélastiques de diverses lignées cellulaires. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Maryam Tabrizian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913s05b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v225</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj3860909r"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The impact of antiretroviral therapy on the evolution of Fc region mediated humoral immunity toward HIV infection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leeks, Christopher</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Secondary analyses of RV144, the only vaccine trial ever shown to provide significant protection against human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, have revealed that immunoglobulin G (IgG) antibody (Ab) dependent cellular cytotoxicity (ADCC) activity correlated with vaccinee protection from HIV (Haynes et al., 2012). ADCC is a humoral immune response that depends on the use of Ab fragment crystallizable (Fc) regions to direct HIV lysis through the engagement of Natural Killer (NK) cells. Therefore, RV144 provides an impetus to further characterize immune responses like ADCC that require Ab Fc regions to attract immune system components capable of lysing extracellular HIV virions and HIV infected cells. Antiretroviral therapy (ART), accessed by approximately half the current HIV+ population and recommended immediately upon HIV infection for the vast majority of people by the International Antiviral Society (IAS), is one such factor that has not been assessed for its ability to impact Ab Fc region mediated (Fcm) immunity, despite its ubiquity (Günthard et al., 2016; WHO, 2016). This study investigated the evolution of IgG Fcm immunity over the course of early HIV infection in ART naive individuals and also in individuals who began receiving ART treatment within six months of HIV infection. The ability of blood plasma donated by HIV+ patients in the Montreal Primary Infection Cohort (MPIC) to mediate ADCC and other HIV antigen specific Fcm immune functions, including Ab dependent phagocytosis (ADCP), Ab dependent complement deposition (ADCD) and Ab dependent trogocytosis (ADCT) was assessed. Total and HIV envelope (Env) gp120 glycoprotein specific IgG titers were quantified in the plasma samples. Comparing equal levels of IgG between the plasma samples, ADCP activity was measured toward an Env gp120 target, while ADCD, ADCC and ADCT activities were measured toward target CCR5+ NK cell resistant CEM (CEM.NKr.CCR5) cells infected with bonafide HIV. These particular HIV infected target cells do not expose cluster of differentiation (CD)4 induced (CD4i) epitopes, which are susceptible to Fcm immunity and are protected by the virus during physiological infection. ADCC, ADCP and ADCT were found to mount significantly over time during untreated HIV infection, yielding Spearman correlation coefficients (rs) of rs=0.3836, rs=0.3532 and rs=0.1975, respectively (corresponding to probability [p] values of p=0.0005, p=0.0013 and p=0.0494, respectively), while ADCD activity did not increase as infection progressed. Analysis of covariance (ANCOVA) was calculated between ART treated and ART naive individuals to determine whether ART administration affected the evolution of Fcm immune responses over time. F-scores of 4.72394 (p=0.0313) and 11.6545 (p=0.0008) portrayed that ART administration did indeed mitigate the evolution of ADCC and ADCD responses, unlike ADCP and ADCT. Generalized linear mixed models (GLMMs) and the variance weighted least squares (VWLS) method were then able to deduce the impact of ART initiation timing on the evolution of ADCC, ADCP, ADCD and ADCT responses, after separating the treated patients into three groups, based on whether their ART administration started within 69 days, between 70 to 124 days, or after 124 days post HIV infection. These statistical analyses revealed that early treatment timing did not affect the evolution of ADCC or ADCP responses in the MPIC plasma donors investigated and actually preserved ADCD and ADCT responses over time, as compared to later ART initiation. Collectively, these results do not reject the current IAS consensus that immediate ART treatment initiation is ideal for the preservation of health in people who become infected with HIV. The results do show however, that ADCC, ADCP, ADCD and ADCT activities can be directed towards HIV epitopes that do not require gp120 binding to CD4.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les analyses secondaires de l'essai sur le vaccin RV144 ont montré que l'activité de cytotoxicité cellulaire dépendante des anticorps (Abs) (ADCC) de l'immunoglobuline G (IgG) était en corrélation avec la protection du vaccin contre le virus de l'immunodéficience humaine (VIH) (Haynes et al., 2012). Donc, le RV144 fournit de l'impulsion pour caractériser davantage les réponses immunitaires comme ADCC qui besoin les régions Fc pour attirent des composants du système immunitaire capables de lyser des virions du VIH extracellulaires et des cellules infectées par le VIH. La thérapie antirétrovirale (TAR) est un facteur qui n'a pas été évalué pour sa capacité à avoir un impact sur immunité des Abs induite par la région Fc, malgré son omniprésence. Cette étude a examiné l'évolution de l'immunité des Abs induite par la région Fc au cours de l'infection précoce de VIH chez des personnes qui ne sont pas sous TAR et des personnes ayant commencé à recevoir des traitements TAR dans les six mois suivant leurs infections. La capacité du plasma sanguin provenant de patients VIH+ de la cohorte d'infections primaires de Montréal à conduit l'ADCC et d'autres fonctions de l'immunité des Abs induite par la région Fc spécifiques à l'antigène du VIH, y compris la phagocytose dépendante de l'Abs (ADCP), la déposition du complément dépendante de l'Abs (ADCD) et la trogocytose dépendante de l'Abs (ADCT), a été mesuré. En comparant des niveaux égaux d'IgG entre les échantillons plasmatiques, l'activité de l'ADCP a été mesurée contre une cible gp120, tandis que les activités de l'ADCD, de l'ADCC et de l'ADCT ont été mesurées contre des cellules CEM infectées par le virus VIH. Ces cellules CEM cibles infectées par le VIH n'exposent pas d'épitopes induite par CD4, qui sont sensibles à l'immunité médiée par la région Fc et qui sont protégés par le virus lors d'une infection physiologique. ADCC, ADCP et ADCT ont montré une augmentation significative au fil du temps pendant une infection VIH non traitée, donnant des coefficients de corrélation de Spearman (rs) de rs=0,3836, rs=0,3532 et rs=0,1975, respectivement (correspondant aux valeurs de probabilités [p] de p=0,0005, p=0,0013 et p=0,0494, respectivement), tandis que l'activité de l'ADCD n'a pas augmenté avec la progression de l'infection. Une analyse de covariance (ANCOVA) a été calculée entre des individus traités par la TAR et des individus qui ne sont pas sous ART, afin de déterminer si l'administration de TAR affectait l'évolution des réponses immunitaires mesurées au fil du temps. Les valeurs de F de 4,72394 (p=0,0313) et de 11,6545 (p=0,0008) ont montré que l'administration de TAR atténuait l'évolution des réponses ADCC et ADCD, contrairement à ADCP et ADCT. Modèles mixtes linéaires généralisés et la méthode des moindres carrés pondérés par la variance ont ensuite permis de déduire l'impact du calendrier de traitement sur l'évolution des réponses ADCC, ADCP, ADCD et ADCT après avoir séparé les patients en trois groupes. Le premier groupe contenait des patients ayant commencé leurs traitements de TAR dans 69 jours après leurs infections de VIH, le deuxième entre 70 et 124 jours et le troisième après 124 jours d'infection. Ces analyses statistiques ont dévoilé que l'initiation traitement au plus tôt n'affecte pas l'évolution des réponses ADCC ou ADCP chez les donneurs étudiés et qu'il préservait les réponses ADCD et ADCT au fil du temps, comparé à des traitements de TAR commencé plus tard après l'infection. Dans son ensemble, ces résultats ne rejettent pas le consensus courant de l'IAS selon lequel l'initiation immédiate de TAR est idéale pour la conservation de la santé des personnes infectées par le VIH. Les résultats montrent cependant que les activités ADCC, ADCP, ADCD et ADCT peuvent être dirigées vers des épitopes du VIH ne nécessitant pas de liaison de gp120 à CD4.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nicole F. Bernard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk29t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860909r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r7792"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Bioresource Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Street tree pits as bioretention units: analysis of their performance in a residential area of Montreal, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frosi, Marcelo</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Urbanization, increased surface impermeability, and climate change have resulted in changes in the quantity, intensity and quality of urban stormwater runoff. Urban stormwater runoff has ecological impacts. Generally, these impacts are related to the total and peak flow volumes, and the presence of contaminants in runoff. Low impact development (LID) techniques are emerging as alternatives to traditional stormwater management systems to mitigate these impacts. One such technique is to combine soil, plants and infrastructure in a bioretention unit. This technique involves the use of multiple smaller units spread across an area; street tree pits may be suitable as bioretention units.The objective of this research was to analyze different designs of newly developed tree pits as bioretention units in the city of Montreal. These tree pits soil comprise the soil of the open part, where trees are planted, and the soil underneath the sidewalk. The two design factors were soil organic matter (SOM) content, and the permeability of the surrounding area (sidewalks and front lawns). A total of 24 tree pits were used in this study. The concentrations of trace metals and sodium were analyzed in soil solution and soil matrix. Using the estimated water flux mass flux of each contaminants was calculated.  The mean contaminant concentration increased from the surface to the deep sampling depths (e.g. 46% for Ni, and 18% for Cu) but taking into account the accompanying decrease in water volumes, mass flux of contaminants decreased with the increase in depth (e.g. 72% for Ni, and 81% for Cu). In addition, tree pits with higher SOM content presented a higher reduction of mass flux of contaminants than tree pits with lower SOM content between surface and deep sampling depths. For example, tree pits with higher SOM content reduced the mass flux of Cr and Cu by 65%, and 86%, respectively, while tree pits with lower SOM content reduced the mass flux of Cr and Cu by 39% and 73% respectively.Tree pits with higher SOM content presented higher concentrations of Cr, Cu and Pb in the soil matrix. For instance, in the soil matrix of tree pits with higher SOM, Cr and Cu concentrations were 19.9 mg kg-1 and 15.3 mg kg-1, respectively, but were 17.4 mg kg-1 and 13.5 mg kg-1, respectively, in tree pits with lower SOM. This corroborates the observed effect on mass flux of Cr and Cu. In addition, an overall increase of contaminants was observed over time. For example, the concentration in soil of Cr increased from 15.9 mg kg-1 to 20.0 mg kg-1 and of Ni from 11.9 mg kg-1 to 14.4 mg kg-1 representing increases of 26% and 21% after about 18 months of monitoring. The soil matrix contained approximately one third of the maximum permitted concentration of contaminants stipulated by the Canadian Council of Ministers of the Environment for Cr and Ni in residential and park areas.  High local permeability and high SOM bioretention units are recommended to mitigate the adverse effects of urbanization on runoff quality and quantity. In this study, tree pits with higher SOM retained contaminants better for all contaminants analyzed (except Pb). The increase in permeability of surrounding surfaces decreased the observed flux of water as well as the mass flux of contaminants observed in the open part of the tree pit. The reduced flux of water in the open part of the tree pit was likely a result of increased infiltration into the soil of the lawn and through the permeable sidewalk. The soil underneath the sidewalk is the same as, and contiguous with, the open area of the tree pit so it is designed to retain runoff contaminants. In this study, higher local permeability and higher SOM were both generally correlated with lower mass flux of contaminants and water. Tree pits can be used as bioretention units having their performance improved by increasing SOM and local permeability.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'urbanisation, l'augmentation de l'imperméabilité des surfaces et les changements climatiques ont entraîné des changements dans la quantité, l'intensité et la qualité des écoulements des eaux pluviales. Les techniques de développement à faible impact (DFI) émergent comme étant des alternatives possibles aux systèmes traditionnels de gestion des écoulements des eaux pluviales pour atténuer ces impacts. L'une de ces techniques est un système de biorétention dans lequel le sol, les plantes et les infrastructures sont combinés dans une unité de filtration. Cette technique implique l'utilisation de plusieurs petites unités réparties sur une zone donnée; les fosses d'arbres peuvent convenir à une unité de biorétention. L'objectif de cette recherche était d'analyser différentes configurations de fosses d'arbre en tant qu'unités de biorétention dans la ville de Montréal.  Les deux facteurs de configuration étaient la teneur en matière organique du sol (M.O.) et la perméabilité de la zone (trottoirs et pelouses) sur la performance des unités de biorétention. Au total, 24 fosses d'arbres ont été utilisées dans cette étude. La concentration de métaux lourds et sodium a été analysée dans la solution et la matrice de sol. Le flux d'eau a été estimé et utilisé pour estimer le flux de masse des contaminants. La concentration moyenne en contaminants augmentait de la surface aux profondeurs d'échantillonnage (e.g. 46% pour Ni et 18% pour Cu), mais le flux massique de contaminants diminuait avec l'augmentation de la profondeur (e.g. 72% pour Ni, et 81% pour Cu). En outre, des fosses d'arbres avec une teneur en M.O. supérieure présentait une réduction plus importante du flux de masse de contaminants que les fosses arborées avec une teneur en M.O. inférieure entre les profondeurs d'échantillonnage de surface et profondes. Par exemple, des fosses d'arbres avec une teneur en M.O. supérieure a réduit le flux de masse de Na et Ni dans 87% et 80%, respectivement, tandis que les fosses d'arbres avec une teneur en M.O. inférieure réduit le flux de masse de Na et Ni dans 66% et 62% respectivement.Les fosses d'arbres avec une teneur en M.O. supérieure présentaient des concentrations plus élevées de Cr, Cu et Pb dans la matrice du sol. Par exemple, dans la matrice de sol des fosses d'arbres avec une teneur en M.O. supérieure les concentrations de Cr et de Cu étaient respectivement de 19,9 mg kg-1 et 15,3 mg kg-1, tandis que dans des fosses d'arbres avec une plus faible teneur en O.M les concentrations étaient 17,4 mg kg-1 et 13,5 mg kg-1, respectivement. Ceci corrobore avec l'effet observé sur le flux de masse de Cr et de Cu. De plus, une augmentation générale des contaminants au fil du temps a été observée. Par exemple, la concentration dans le sol de Cr a augmenté de 15,9 mg kg-1 à 20,0 mg kg-1 et la concentration de Ni de 11,9 mg kg-1 à 14,4 mg kg-1, soit 26% et 21% d'augmentation après environ 18 mois de suivi, respectivement.L'augmentation de la perméabilité locale et de le M.O dans les unités de biorétention sont recommandées pour atténuer les effets néfastes de l'urbanisation sur la qualité et la quantité des eaux de ruissellement. Dans cette étude, les fosses d'arbres avec une plus grande teneur en M.O. ont montré une meilleure performance dans la rétention des contaminants (sauf Pb). L'augmentation de la perméabilité des surfaces environnantes a diminué le flux de masse des contaminants prélevés dans la partie ouverte de la fosse. Le sol sous le trottoir fait partie de la fosse d'arbre et est conçu pour retenir les contaminants des eaux de ruissellement. Dans cette étude, l'augmentation de la perméabilité locale et l'augmentation de le M.O. dans le sol étaient corrèle avec une réduction générale du flux massique de contaminants et d'eau à travers la partie ouverte de la fosse d'arbre.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grant Clark</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g56h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r7792</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bioresource Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nn72h"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of denervation in skeletal muscle of pre-frail/frail elderly women</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Sonjak, Vita</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le processus de vieillissement est associé à un déclin progressif de la masse musculaire squelettique et de sa function, entraînant une diminution de la fonction physique et un risque accru de fragilité. Les recherches sur les mécanismes contribuant à l'atrophie musculaire liée à l'âge ont révélé un rôle important dans le remodelage et la perte de la fonction mitochondriale altérée et de l'unité motrice (MU). Nous avons précédemment montré la présence de dénervation et son rôle modulateur sur la fonction mitochondriale chez les hommes octogénaires. Cependant, il existe peu de données sur les femmes âgées, qui risquent davantage de devenir physiquement fragiles et vivent plus longtemps avec une dépendance fonctionnelle. Le but de cette thèse est d'évaluer les modifications de la fonction mitochondriale, la présence d'une dénervation musculaire persistante et son rôle modulateur sur la fonction mitochondriale chez les femmes âgées pré-fragiles / fragiles, ainsi que l'importance de la dénervation pour l'atrophie musculaire chez les femmes âgées pré-fragiles / fragiles. À titre de comparaison, nous évaluons l'ampleur de dénervation musculaire chez les athletes maîtres (MA), qui conservent leur masse musculaire et leur fonction physique à un âge avancé. Nous montrons ici que les femmes âgées fragiles (AF, 77,9 ± 1,5 ans) comparées aux jeunes contrôles inactifs (JI, 24,0 ± 1,0), ont la capacité respiratoire mitochondriale du muscle latéral lateral réduite, ce qui semble être dû à une réduction du contenu mitochondrial plutôt qu'à un dysfonctionnement intrinsèque de mitochondries. D'autre part, les femmes AF ont présenté un taux élevé de dérivés réactifs de l'oxygène (DRO) augmentées par unité de mitochondrie normalisée en inhibant le signal ROS sensible à la dénervation en inhibant la phospholipase A2 cytoplasmique, suggérant que la dénervation module la fonction mitochondriale dans AF de la même manière que nos précédentes observations chez les hommes octogénaires. Conformément à ces résultats, nous avons démontré la présence de changements morphologiques induits par la dénervation dans le groupe AF, notamment le groupement de myofibres du même type, des changements dans le type de myofibre (isoforme de la chaîne lourde de la myosine (MHC) avec une abondance accrue de fibres co-exprimant différentes protéines isoformes du MHC et accumulation de petites fibres angulaires. Les femmes AF ont également présenté une plus grande abondance de fibres positives à la molécule d'adhésion des cellules neurales (NCAM) et la présence de noyaux pycnotiques, considérés comme des marqueurs associés à la dénervation. Ensuite, nous avons démontré qu'une population qui maintient une fonction physique élevée, les maîtres en athlétisme octogénaires de classe mondiale (MA, 80,7 ± 2,5 ans), par rapport au groupe FE, avait une plus faible abondance de fibres exprimant la NCAM et un plus de regroupement de fibres lentes avec une quantité accrues de fibres par groupe. Cela suggère que la rétention de la masse musculaire et de la fonction musculaire chez les personnes âgées dont le fonctionnement est optimal est associée à une plus grande capacité de réinnervation. Toutes ces données démontrent que, chez les femmes AF, la dénervation a le potentiel de moduler la fonction mitochondriale et contribue à l'atrophie musculaire et au handicap physique liés à l'âge, comme l'indique la présence de changements morphologiques et de biomarqueurs induits par la dénervation dans le muscle vieillissant. En revanche, les personnes âgées très fonctionnelles présentent des caractéristiques compatibles avec une plus grande capacité de réinnervation, compatibles avec l'idée que la dégénérescence musculaire et l'érosion résultante de la fonction physique avec le vieillissement sont en partie liées à l'ampleur de la dénervation persistante.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The aging process is associated with progressive decline in skeletal muscle mass and function contributing to impaired physical function and increased risk of frailty. Investigations on underlying mechanisms contributing to age-related muscle atrophy have revealed an important role of mitochondrial dysfunction and motor unit (MU) remodeling and loss. We have previously shown the presence of denervation and its modulating role on mitochondrial function in octogenarian men. However, limited data exists in elderly women, who are at a higher risk than men of becoming physically frail and who live longer with functional dependence. The aims of this Dissertation are to assess (i) mitochondrial function changes, and the potential modulating role of denervation on mitochondrial function in prefrail/frail elderly women, and (ii) the significance of denervation to muscle atrophy in pre-frail/frail elderly women. For comparison, we assessed the degree of muscle denervation in world class octogenarian master athletes (MA), who better retain muscle mass and physical function in advanced age. Here we showed that frail elderly women (FE, 77.9 ± 1.5y) compared to young inactive (YI, 24.0 ± 1.0) controls, have reduced vastus lateralis muscle respiratory capacity, which seemed to be due to reduced mitochondrial content rather than intrinsic dysfunction of mitochondria because the reduction in respiration was proportional to a reduction in the mitochondrial outer membrane protein, voltage dependent anion channel (VDAC). On the other hand, FE women displayed increased reactive oxygen species (ROS) per unit of VDAC that was normalized by blocking the denervation-responsive ROS signal through pharmacological inhibition of cytoplasmic phospholipase A2 (cPLA2). As such, our results suggest that denervation modulates mitochondrial function in FE similar to our previous observations in octogenarian men. Consistent with these findings, we also demonstrated the presence of denervation-induced morphological changes in the FE group compared to YI controls, including grouping of myofibers of the same type, changes in myofiber type (myosin heavy chain (MHC) protein isoform) characterized as increased abundance of fibers co-expressing multiple MHC isoforms, and an accumulation of small fibers that frequently have angular shape. Compared to YI group, FE women also displayed a higher abundance of neural cell adhesion molecule (NCAM) positive fibers and the presence of pyknotic nuclei, which are well-established marker of denervation. Next, we demonstrated that a population that maintains high physical function in advanced age, world class octogenarian track and field athletes (MA, 80.7 ± 2.5y), compared to FE group, had lower abundance of fibers expressing NCAM and greater slow fiber type grouping with increased fiber number per group. This suggests that retention of muscle mass and function in high functioning elderly is associated with a greater capacity for reinnervating denervated muscle fibers such that over time, fewer fibers are lost. All together these data demonstrate that in FE women, denervation is an important modulator of mitochondrial function and contributes to age-related muscle atrophy and physical impairment as indicated by the presence of denervation-induced morphological changes and biomarkers in aging muscle. In contrast, highly functioning elderly adults exhibit features consistent with a greater reinnervation capacity, which likely plays a key role in their lesser degree of muscle degeneration and greater retention of physical function.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Dennis Jensen</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jose A. Morais</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558g350.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn72h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623f77n"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of non-targeted strategies for the analysis of trace organic contaminants in honey</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>von Eyken Bonafonte, Annie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des nouveaux contaminants et toxines sont découverts en permanence dans les aliments. Aussi, le monde de l'analyse des aliments s'intéresse de plus en plus aux outils permettant la détection et l'identification des contaminants inconnus ou inattendus. Ce type d'analyse, que l'on appelle non-ciblée, ne s'appuie pas sur un étalonnage à partir du composé chimique pur, ce qui ouvre la porte à des nouvelles applications en termes d'authentification et de sécurité alimentaire. L'objectif de cette thèse était le développement d'une méthode d'analyse non-ciblée pour l'analyse des contaminants organiques traces dans le miel. Tout d'abord, une méthode rapide, basée sur l'injection directe en HPLC-QTOF-MS a été développée et validée avec succès pour l'analyse ciblée de 7 médicaments vétérinaires dans le miel. Le mode d'acquisition indépendante des données All-Ions MS/MS a été utilisé. Ces données ont permis la confirmation de l'identité des analytes ciblés et ont démontré le potentiel non-ciblée de l'approche. Dans une seconde étude, l'impact du prétraitement des données sur l'identification non-ciblée des traces de contaminants organiques dans le miel a été étudié, ceci en utilisant les même 7 résidus vétérinaires comme composés modèles. L'impact de 7 paramètres a été évalué, et seule la fenêtre d'expansion pour l'extraction des chromatogrammes et la moyenne des scans inclus dans les spectres ont influencé de façon significative les résultats. Ces résultats montrent que les paramètres de prétraitement des données peuvent affecter l'identification des contaminants traces dans les aliments. Le workflow d'identification optimisé fut ensuite appliqué pour cribler 55 échantillons de miel à l'aide d'une bibliothèque de 43 composés en lien avec le miel. La tylosine A et l'hydroxyméthylfurfural furent positivement détectés dans ces échantillons de miel. Par la suite, le workflow non-ciblé développé a été appliqué au criblage de composés associés aux plastiques dans 104 échantillons de miel. Au total, 662 composés possibles, issus d'une bibliothèque de composés associés aux plastiques, ont été détectés dans le miel. L'identité de deux de ces substances, à savoir l'adipate de bis(2-éthylhexyle) et le phosphate de tris(2-butoxyéthyl), a été confirmée avec étalons des composés purs. Les compositions chimiques des échantillons de miel vendus dans des pots en verre ou en plastique furent comparées à travers 3 approches de traitement de données différentes. Ces approches menèrent à différentes listes des composés pertinents. Ce résultat montre que les méthodes de traitements des données couramment utilisées en métabolomique par exemple doivent être sélectionnées prudemment quand elles sont appliquées à l'identification de contaminants traces dans les aliments. Enfin, la dégradation thermale du médicament vétérinaire tylosine A a été étudiée pour des solutions aqueuses et du miel. Les résultats, en termes de taux de dégradation de la tylosine A et de production de tylosin B correspondirent à ceux décrits dans la littérature. Pourtant, grâce à l'approche non-ciblée de cette étude, deux nouveaux produits de dégradation potentiels, à savoir OMT et lactenocine, ont été identifiés. Les produits de dégradation dans les solutions aqueuses, le miel dopé et le miel naturellement contaminé étaient différents. Ceci confirme que les études des modèles aqueux ou les matrices alimentaires dopées ne sont pas suffisantes pour comprendre la dégradation thermale des antibiotiques dans des matrices alimentaires. La possibilité de semi-quantification de la tylosine B dans le miel en utilisant la tylosine A, sa substance mère, comme référence a été aussi évaluée. Les résultats ont montré qu'il s'agit d'une stratégie raisonnable dans le cadre de l'analyse non-ciblée. En conclusion, cette recherche a montré, à travers le miel comme matrice d'étude, que l'approche non-ciblée améliore la caractérisation des contaminants chimiques et de leur devenir dans les aliments.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Due to the constant increase of contaminants and toxins reported in food, the world of food analysis is shifting towards the detection and identification of currently unknown or unexpected contaminants using non-targeted analysis. As it does not rely on the initial use of analytical standards, the non-targeted approach opens the door for new applications in the field of food authentication and food safety. The chemical risk assessment community has highlighted the need to further develop non-targeted methods to better characterize human exposure to chemicals, and to identify potential risk compounds in food matrices.  The overall objective of this work was the development of a non-targeted method for the analysis of trace organic contaminants in honey. First, a fast screening and quantification method was successfully developed and validated for the targeted analysis of 7 veterinary drug residues in honey, using direct injection high-performance liquid chromatography coupled to quadrupole time-of-flight mass spectrometry (HPLC-QTOF-MS). A data-independent All-Ions MS/MS mode was used to continuously record MS and MS/MS data at four different collision energies, and allowed for the confirmation of the identity of the target analytes, showing the non-targeted potential of the method. Next, the data pre-treatment steps for the non-targeted identification of trace organic contaminants in honey were studied using the same 7 veterinary drugs as case study. The impact of 7 parameters on the correct identification of the target compounds was assessed, and only the expansion window for chromatogram extraction and the average scans included in the spectra influenced the identification results significantly. These findings confirmed that data pre-treatment parameters can affect the identification of trace contaminants in food. The optimized identification workflow was used to screen 55 honey samples from the Canadian market using a library of 43 honey-related compounds, which led to the detection of tylosin A and 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) among these samples. Then, the optimized non-targeted workflow was applied to the screening of plastic-related compounds in 104 honey samples, and a total of 662 compounds were tentatively detected using a library of leachable and extractable compounds. The identity of two of these compounds, namely bis(ethylhexyl) adipate (DEHA) and tris (2-butoxyethyl) phosphate (TBOEP), was further confirmed with pure analytical standards. The chemical burden in honey samples sold in either glass or plastic jars was compared using 3 data treatment approaches, each of which resulted in a different list of relevant contaminants. These findings showed that some of the most commonly used data treatments in metabolomics need to be carefully selected when it comes to identifying trace contaminants in food. Finally, the degradation of the veterinary drug tylosin A in water, spiked honey and incurred honey after different thermal treatments was studied using the optimized non-targeted method. The results, in terms of rates of degradation of tylosin A and increase of tylosin B were in agreement with the literature. However, the non-targeted approach used for this study led to the tentative identification of two new degradation products, namely 5-O-mycaminosyltylonolide (OMT) and lactenocin. The degradation products identified in water, spiked honey and incurred honey appeared to be different, reinforcing the conclusion that relying only on the water model or spiked food matrix is not sufficient to understand the thermal degradation of antibiotics in food matrices. The possibility of a semi-quantification of tylosin B in honey using tylosin A, its parent compound, was also assessed, proving that it  can be a suitable strategy in non-targeted analysis. Overall, this research demonstrated that non-targeted analysis can improve the characterization of contaminant occurrence and fate in food, using honey as a key example.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stephane Bayen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k40m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f77n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac821gn246"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Mechanism of thienopyridone and iminothienopyridinedione inhibition of PRL phosphatases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhang, Zhidian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les phosphatases de la régénération hépatique (PRL ou PTP4A) sont des phosphatases à double spécificité qui favorisent la progression du cancer. Ils s'agissent donc de cibles anticancéreuses très importantes. La thiénopyridone (TP) et son dérivé plus puissant, l'iminothiénopyridinedione (ITP), ont été proposées comme inhibiteurs sélectifs des PRLs, mais leur mécanisme d'inhibition n'a pas encore été établi. Notre plan expérimental ci-dessous consiste à effectuer des expériences de RMN ainsi que des essais de phosphatases in vitro afin de démontrer que la TP et l'ITP inhibent les protéines phosphatases de manière non-spécifique en catalysant l'oxydation de leur cystéine catalytique. Nos résultats démontrent que la TP et l'ITP catalysent en effet l'oxydation de PTP1B, mais aussi celle de la thiorédoxine-1 et de petites molécules tels que le TCEP, le DTT et le glutathion. Ainsi, la TP et l'ITP agissent en tant que catalyseurs pour l'oxydation générale, et leur sélectivité rapportée est peut-être due à la susceptibilité des PRLs à l'oxydation. Enfin, bien que la TP et l'ITP inhibent efficacement les PRLs, leur implication dans les études sur la fonction cellulaire de ces phosphatases est problématique en raison de la probabilité d'effets hors-cible.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Thienopyridone (TP) has been proposed as a selective inhibitor of phosphatases of regenerating liver (PRLs or PTP4A), dual specificity phosphatases that promote cancer progression and are attractive anticancer targets. TP and iminothienopyridinedione (ITP), a more potent derivative, were shown to be effective inhibitors but the mechanism of inhibition was not established. Here, we use NMR experiments and in vitro phosphatase assays to show that TP and ITP inhibit protein phosphatases non-specifically through oxidation of the phosphatase catalytic cysteine. We demonstrate that TP and ITP catalyse the oxidation of PTP1B and thioredoxin-1 as well as the small molecules TCEP, DTT, and glutathione; thus, TP and ITP act as catalysts for general oxidation. The reported selectivity of TP and ITP is likely due to the higher susceptibility of PRLs to oxidation. In conclusion, while TP and ITP effectively inhibit PRLs, their use for studying the cellular function of PRLs is problematic due to the likelihood of off-target effects.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kalle Burgess Gehring</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k80b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn246</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2b88qf21r"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Urban Planning</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fostering happiness among public transit users: Analyzing customer satisfaction surveys through non-traditional approaches</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Grise, Emily</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Les enquêtes de satisfaction des usagers sont un des outils les plus utilisés dans le secteur des transports en commun pour mieux comprendre les perceptions, les attitudes et les comportements des voyageurs. L'efficacité des politiques et des stratégies d'amélioration du service conçues à partir des données de satisfaction est actuellement limitée par les méthodologies utilisées pour analyser ces données. L'objectif général de cette thèse est d'obtenir une meilleure compréhension de la satisfaction des usagers des transports en commun en intégrant des facteurs personnels, spatiaux et contextuels. L'objectif de cette étude vise à répondre à la question suivante : Comment analyser et utiliser efficacement les données relatives à la satisfaction des usagers pour développer des améliorations ciblées de la qualité du service? Cette thèse s'articule autour des quatre objectifs suivants :1.Dévoiler les différences de perception relatives à la qualité du service entre des quartiers avec différents profils socio-économiques, dans un secteur très concurrentiel et étroitement réglementé ;2.Développer une approche de segmentation du marché des transports en commun intégrant des facteurs personnels, spatiaux et contextuels ;3.Comprendre dans quelle mesure les correspondances influencent le niveau de satisfaction du trajet ; 4.Obtenir une meilleure compréhension de la façon dont les mesures de performance des transports en commun peuvent être intégrées à l'analyse de la satisfaction des usagers pour aider à mieux comprendre la satisfaction globale.Les quatre objectifs de recherche correspondent chacun à un chapitre d'analyse de la présente thèse. Ces chapitres se complètent et visent collectivement à améliorer les méthodes d'analyse des données relatives à la satisfaction des usagers actuellement en vigueur afin de permettre une meilleure connaissance du secteur des transports en commun.Le chapitre final regroupe les faits saillants des chapitres précédents et présente leurs implications en termes de politiques et de recherche pour permettre une meilleure compréhension de la satisfaction des usagers. Plus précisément, ce mémoire apporte de nouveaux éléments par rapport aux connaissances préexistantes qui s'articulent autour des quatre points suivants: •Identifie des lacunes importantes dans la manière dont les données relatives à la satisfaction des usagers sont actuellement analysées ;•Développe des méthodologies reproductibles pour intégrer les données spatiales dans l'analyse des niveaux de satisfaction, ainsi que pour appliquer des techniques d'analyse spatiale visant à examiner le niveau de satisfaction à l'égard du service à l'échelle locale (c.-à-d. au niveau du trajet ou du quartier) ;•Démontre comment les données détaillées sur les trajets peuvent être utilisées pour comprendre l'influence des caractéristiques spécifiques de service sur les niveaux de satisfaction ;•Montre comment les données relatives à la performance du transport en commun peuvent être intégrées aux analyses de satisfaction pour permettre une compréhension plus complète des niveaux de satisfaction des usagers. Dans la mesure où les usagers sont les meilleurs juges de la qualité du service, cette thèse montre comment les agences de transport en commun peuvent analyser plus efficacement les perceptions des usagers vis-à-vis du service telles qu'exprimées dans les enquêtes de satisfaction afin d'élaborer des politiques d'amélioration du service qui auront le plus d'impact sur les usagers.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Customer satisfaction surveys are one of the most heavily utilized tools within the public transit industry to gain insight into the perceptions, attitudes and behaviours of customers. The efficacy of policies and service improvement strategies derived from satisfaction data are presently limited by the methodologies that are used to analyze this data. The overarching goal of this dissertation is to expand the understanding of public transit customer satisfaction through incorporating personal, spatial and contextual factors. This research goal will be achieved through answering the following research question: How can customer satisfaction data be effectively analyzed and utilized to generate targeted service quality improvements? This dissertation consists of four research objectives which are as follows:  1.To show differences in perceptions of service quality across different socioeconomic neighbourhoods in a highly competitive and well-monitored transit market; 2.To develop a transit market segmentation approach that includes personal, spatial and contextual factors; 3.To understand the extent to which transfers influence trip satisfaction; 4.To expand our understanding of how public transit performance measures can be integrated into satisfaction analyses to better predict overall satisfaction.The four research objectives each correspond to an analysis chapter comprising this manuscript-based dissertation. These chapters build on one another, and collectively aim to advance existing methods of analyzing customer satisfaction data for better knowledge of the transit market. The first two chapters of this dissertation present spatial methods of analyzing customer satisfaction data. Chapter two examines satisfaction with bus service across neighbourhoods of varying socio-economic status in London, UK. This spatial method allows agencies to identify areas for improvement at a more disaggregate level than previous research. The third chapter presents a new market segmentation approach that incorporates spatial and contextual factors that have not previously been incorporated into the practice of segmenting the transit market. This new method is demonstrated using a sample of commuter rail users in the Greater Toronto and Hamilton Area, Canada. The remaining two chapters demonstrate how contextual and operational data can be incorporated into satisfaction analyses. Chapter four explores the relationship between transferring and trip satisfaction using a survey of transit commuters to McGill University. In Chapter 5, satisfaction levels among users of a local and a limited-stop bus service in Vancouver, Canada are studied, while controlling for operational characteristics describing the service these users experienced, such as crowding. A concluding chapter consolidates the findings of these chapters and presents policy and research implications to support a better understanding of satisfaction. More specifically, this dissertation contributes to the knowledge in the following four ways:m •Identifies important shortcomings regarding how customer satisfaction data is analyzed; •Develops reproducible methodologies to both integrate spatial data into the analysis of satisfaction levels, as well as to apply spatial analysis techniques to examine satisfaction with service at a local scale (i.e. the route or neighbourhood level); •Demonstrates how detailed trip data can be applied to understand how specific service characteristics influence satisfaction levels; •Shows how transit performance data can be integrated into satisfaction analyses to provide a more complete understanding of passenger satisfaction levels. As customers are the most important judges of service quality, this dissertation demonstrates how transit agencies can more effectively analyze customer perceptions of service as stated in satisfaction surveys and generate policies for service improvements that will have the strongest impact on riders.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elgeneidy, Ahmed</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h1760.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qf21r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Urban Planning</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913s06m"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>To speak or not to speak: silence in classrooms</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Park, Jihae</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The enrollment number of Chinese students in North American universities is increasing every year. Even though graduate courses are discussion-based, many university instructors have experienced the "silent Chinese" phenomenon in classrooms. This study looks through investigating the reasons for Chinese international students' silence in classrooms. Basil Bernstein's language code theory was used as a theoretical framework to explain the difficulties international students experience in speaking up in class. From students' narratives, the aim of this study is to understand genuine reasons for their silence so that the school community can better assist students with diverse backgrounds. Using in-depth interviews, this study explores six international Chinese students' experiences studying abroad in a graduate program at a large university in Canada. Three themes were identified from the interviews: First, language proficiency; second, previous schooling experience in China; and third, Chinese typical culture of face. This thesis concludes with implications on how this study to understand Chinese international students' difficulties can bring in great learning opportunities to the classroom and also create a multicultural classroom that values diverse ideas.Keywords: Chinese international students, silence in classrooms, face culture, language codes</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le nombre d'inscriptions d'étudiants chinois dans les universités nord-américaines augmente chaque année. Bien que les cours de troisième cycle soient basés sur des discussions, de nombreux professeurs d'université ont expérimenté le phénomène du «chinois silencieux» dans les salles de classe. Cette étude examine les raisons du silence des étudiants étrangers chinois dans les salles de classe. La théorie des codes linguistiques de Basil Bernstein a été utilisée comme un cadre théorique pour expliquer les difficultés rencontrées par les étudiants internationaux pour s'exprimer en classe. À partir des récits des élèves, l'objectif de cette étude est de comprendre les véritables raisons de leur silence afin que la communauté scolaire puisse mieux assister les élèves d'origines diverses. À partir d'entrevues approfondies, cette étude explore les expériences de six étudiants chinois internationaux qui étudient à l'étranger dans le cadre d'un programme de cycles supérieurs dans une grande université canadienne. Les entretiens ont permis de dégager trois thèmes: premièrement, la maîtrise de la langue; deuxièmement, une expérience scolaire antérieure en Chine; et troisièmement, la culture de visage typique chinoise. Cette thèse se termine par des implications sur la manière dont cette étude visant à comprendre les difficultés des étudiants étrangers chinois peut apporter de grandes opportunités d'apprentissage en classe et également créer une classe multiculturelle qui valorise des idées diverses.Mots-clés: étudiants internationaux chinois, silence en classe, culture chinoise du face, codes de langue</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ratna Ghosh</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408034g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s06m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Integrated Studies in Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah989r5290"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Air and Space Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>International point-to-point suborbital transportation: The need for global governance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Napolitano, Ermanno</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The last decade has been characterized by the development of a nascent aerospace industry whichseems ready to take off, the major point of interest being Point-to-Point (PTP) international suborbitaloperations. The current regimes of air law and of space law were established at a time when the possibility of hybrid aerospace activities was not envisaged, and the development of such aerospace operations poses many serious legal and practical questions that remain unanswered to thisday. Suborbital vehicles seem to operate in both airspace and outer space, but it is unclear where, legally, airspace ends and outer space begins, and if, between the two, there is a "buffer zone" within which different laws apply. It is also unclear whether such vehicles are aircraft, space objects or aerospace objects. In brief, it is unclear which legal regime should apply to them and, from a legal point of view, this is not acceptable. As suborbital vehicles will use the same airspace as that traversed by aircraft, their proliferation would pose serious challenges, especially in terms of safety and liability. The thesis investigates the legal reasons and basis for ICAO to take a lead indeveloping new rules for aerospace activities through a proactive approach, which would serve to address the issue in the near term. Such approach serves as a basis for an evolutionary one for the long term. The key contribution of this thesis is to add a small chapter to the scientific literature supporting the passage from lex lata to lex de ferenda for the collectivity's benefit.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La dernière décennie a été caractérisée par le développement d'une industrie aérospatiale naissante semblant être prête à décoller et dont le point d'intérêt majeur sont les opérations suborbitales « Pointà-Point » (PàP). Les régimes de loi aérienne et de loi spatiale furent établis à un moment où la possibilité d'activités aérospatiales hybrides n'était pas envisageable, et le développement de ces opérations pose plusieurs questions légales et pratiques d'une grande importance qui demeurent nonrésolues à ce jour. Les véhicules suborbitaux semblent opérer dans l'espace aérien et dans l'espace extra-atmosphérique, mais il n'est pas clair, légalement parlant, où l'espace aérien termine et où l'espace extra-atmosphérique débute, ou s'il y a une zone tampon dans laquelle différentes lois seraient appliquées. Il est aussi peu clair si ces véhicules suborbitaux sont définis comme aéronefs, objets spatiaux ou objets aérospatiaux. Bref, le choix du système légal qui leur est applicable est peu clair, et ceci est inacceptable d'un point de vue légal. Puisque les véhicules suborbitaux partageront l'espace aérien traversé par les aéronefs, leur prolifération posera de sérieux défis, tout particulièrement en termes de sécurité et de responsabilité légale. Ce mémoire examine, par le biais d'une approche proactive utile à court terme, les raisons et bases légales pour que l'OACI prenne les devants dans le développement de nouveaux règlements pour les activités aérospatiales. L'approche proactive proposée sert de base pour une approche évolutionnaire applicable au long terme. L'utilité principale de ce mémoire est de faire une petite contribution à la littérature scientifique supportant le passage de lex lata à lex de ferenda pour le bénéfice de la collectivité.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ram S. Jakhu</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc622.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r5290</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Air and Space Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nk399"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geometric multigrid preconditioning for the nonconforming voxel finite element method in electromagnetic scattering</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hussain, Nizamuddin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The nonconforming voxel finite element method (NVFEM) is a special kind of finite element method that builds a structured grid of cubical elements of varied sizes, thereby simplifying the meshing of complex structures. Beginning with a coarse uniform mesh, the NVFEM generates a series of meshes by refining only the heterogeneous elements. This leads to staircase approximation of material interfaces. To lessen the staircase error, the mesh needs to be refined to a sufficiently high degree, but this can cause a considerable increase in the number of degrees of freedom (DOFs) in the mesh, which in turn results in a large linear system of equations. One way to reduce the cost of NVFEM is to solve the equations with an iterative method together with a carefully designed preconditioner.     In this thesis, a preconditioner based on the geometric multigrid (GMG) method is proposed and tested, for use in solving electromagnetic wave scattering problems in the frequency domain. The iterative method employed is the conjugate gradient (CG) method. A GMG preconditioner is a natural choice for the NVFEM, since the NVFEM provides a hierarchy of nested grids, which permits effective inter-grid transfer operations of prolongation and coarsening.     A theoretical estimate of the asymptotic cost of the operations performed by the proposed preconditioner is made. According to this estimate, the preconditioner requires only O(N) computational work per CG iteration, where N is the number of DOFs. The effectiveness of the preconditioner is assessed with the help of numerical experiments. Scattering objects of various geometrical shapes and material composition are considered, in domains about a wavelength across. Test cases have up to 26 million DOFs. For each case, the iteration count as well as the time taken for the iterative solution (including the time to build preconditioning matrices) are recorded. For all cases, the calculation time grows almost linearly with N. The experiments suggest that the per iteration cost is in agreement with the theoretically predicted cost. A comparison with the SSOR preconditioner shows that not only is the proposed preconditioner significantly faster, but also the speedup increases with N.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La méthode des éléments finis voxel non conforme (NVFEM) est un type spécial de méthode des éléments finis qui construit une grille structurée d'éléments cubiques de tailles variées, simplifiant ainsi le maillage de structures complexes. En commençant par un maillage uniforme grossier, le NVFEM génère une série de maillages en raffinant uniquement les éléments hétérogènes. Cela conduit à des artéfacts en marche d'escalier pour l'approximation des interfaces matérielles. Pour réduire les artéfacts en marche d'escalier, le maillage doit être raffiné à un degré suffisamment élevé, mais cela peut entraîner une augmentation considérable du nombre de degrés de liberté (DOFs) dans le maillage, qui à son tour mène à un grand système d'équations linéaires. Une façon de réduire le coût de NVFEM est de résoudre ces équations avec une méthode itérative et un préconditionneur soigneusement conçu. Dans cette thèse, un préconditionneur basé sur la méthode multigrille géométrique (GMG) est proposé et testé pour la résolution de problèmes de diffusion des ondes électromagnétiques en domaine fréquentiel. La méthode du gradient conjugué (CG) est utilisée comme méthode itérative. Un préconditionneur GMG est un choix naturel pour le NVFEM puisque le NVFEM fournit une hiérarchie de grilles qui permet des opérateurs inter-niveaux de prolongement et de restriction efficaces.Une estimation théorique du coût asymptotique des opérations effectuées par le préconditionneur proposé est faite. Selon cette estimation, le préconditionneur n'a besoin que d'une complexité de calcul O(N) par itération CG, où N est le nombre de DOFs. L'efficacité du préconditionneur est évaluée à l'aide de tests numériques. Des objets de dispersion avec plusieurs formes géométriques et compositions de matière sont considérés, chacun dans un domaine d'environs une longueur d'onde. Les tests possèdent jusqu'à 26 millions de DOFs. Pour chaque test, le nombre d'itérations ainsi que le temps pris pour la solution itérative (y compris le temps de génération de matrices de préconditionnement) sont enregistrés. Pour tous les tests, le temps de calcul croît presque linéairement avec N. Les tests suggèrent que le coût par itération est en accord avec le coût prédit théoriquement. Une comparaison avec le préconditionneur SSOR montre que le préconditionneur proposé est non seulement beaucoup plus rapide, mais aussi que l'accélération augmente avec N.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jonathan P. Webb</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h668s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk399</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak930c051w"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Synaptic adhesion mechanisms in inhibitory synapse development and Alzheimer's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Naito, Yusuke</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La synapse est la plus petite unité computationnelle du cerveau, dont le développement est dirigé avec élégance par la coordination de diverses molécules. Une des familles moléculaires clés dans cette coordination est composée d'organisateurs synaptiques possédant la capacité d'induire de novo l'assemblage des synapses. Dans cette thèse, nous visons à déterminer les rôles physiologiques et pathologiques de ces organisateurs synaptiques par des expériences in vitro et in vivo.Dans le chapitre 3, l' « immunoglobulin superfamily member 21 » (IgSF21) est exposée comme un nouvel organisateur synaptique induisant sélectivement l'inhibition de la différentiation présynaptique. Par le biais d'une analyse protéomique, la neurexine 2α (NRX2α) a été identifiée comme un organisateur présynaptique interagissant avec IgSF21. Étonnamment, IgSF21 recrute et se lie sélectivement à la NRX2α et à aucun autre isoforme. Ces deux protéines forment une interaction trans-synaptique qui est essentielle à l'activité synaptogénique de IgSF21. Nous avons caractérisé une souris déficiente en IgSF21 afin d'en étudier les fonctions physiologiques au niveau du système nerveux central. Nous avons découvert qu'IgSF21 régule positivement le développement des synapses inhibitrices et la transmission synaptique médiée par le GABA dans les neurones pyramidaux de l'aire CA1 de l'hippocampe. Par ailleurs, IgSF21 est indispensable au filtrage sensorimoteur. Pour conclure, IgSF21 organise sélectivement les synapses inhibitrices via une interaction trans-synaptique, essentielle au fonctionnement normal du cerveau, avec la protéine axonale NRX2α. Ce chapitre décrit ainsi un nouvel et unique mécanisme moléculaire impliqué dans le développement présynaptique inhibiteur permettant d'apporter de nouvelles connaissances moléculaires sur la manière dont les organisateurs synaptiques régulent le circuit synaptique complexe médié par le GABA. Dans le chapitre 4, une analyse de liaison de l'oligomère du peptide bêta-amyloïde (AβO) a été réalisé afin d'identifier de nouveaux partenaires de liaison parmi les protéines d'adhésion synaptique, appelées organisateurs synaptiques. Ceci a permis d'identifier une nouvelle interaction entre les neurexines (NRXs) et les AβOs. Les AβOs se lient aux NRXs-β 1/2/3 via leur domaine N-terminal riche en histidine (HRD) mais aussi grâce aux insertions de l'épissage alternatif du 4ème site d'épissage des NRXs 1 et 2. Dans les expériences de formation de synapses artificielles, les AβOs diminuent la différentiation présynaptique excitatrice induite par des protéines interagissant avec les NRXs telles que les neuroligines 1 et 2 (NLG1/2) et les « leucine-rich repeat transmembrane protein 2 » (LLRTM2). L'imagerie par time-lapse a révélé qu'un traitement par des AβOs réduit l'expression de la NRX1β à la surface des axones par le biais de son domaine HRD. De plus, dans un modèle murin transgénique possédant une forme mutée de la protéine précurseur du peptide amyloïde humain, l'expression synaptique des NRXs-β est diminué mais pas celle des NRXs-α. En résumé, nos résultats indiquent que les AβOs interagissent avec les NRXs et qu'il en résulte l'inhibition de la différenciation présynaptique en réduisant l'expression en surface des NRXs-β au niveau de l'axone. Ces découvertes mettent en lumière les rôles pathologiques des organisateurs synaptiques dans la maladie d'Alzheimer et aideront au développement de nouvelles stratégies thérapeutiques visant l'interaction AβO-NRXs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Synapses are the minimal computational units of the brain, whose development is elegantly controlled by molecular coordination. One of the key molecular families directing this coordination is a group of synapse organizers with the ability to induce de novo synaptic assembly. In this thesis, we aim to understand the physiological and pathological roles of synapse organizers by using both in vitro and in vivo approaches. In Chapter 3, we report the identification of immunoglobulin superfamily member 21 (IgSF21) as a novel inhibitory synapse organizer that induces only inhibitory presynaptic differentiation. Through further proteomics screening, we isolated neurexin 2α (NRX2α) as an IgSF21-interacting presynaptic organizer. Interestingly, IgSF21 selectively binds to NRX2a but not any other NRX isoforms and recruits NRX2α to presynaptic sites in a trans-interaction manner, which is essential for the synaptogenic activity of IgSF21. To characterize the physiological function of IgSF21 in the central nervous system, we comprehensively characterized IgSF21 mutant mice. We found that IgSF21 positively regulates inhibitory synapse development and GABA-mediated synaptic transmission in hippocampal CA1 pyramidal neurons and that IgSF21 is indispensable for normal sensorimotor gating. We concluded that IgSF21 selectively organizes inhibitory synapses via its trans-synaptic interaction with axonal NRX2α and that this is essential for normal brain function. This chapter thus uncovers a novel and unique molecular mechanism underlying inhibitory presynaptic development, providing molecular insights into how a synapse organizer regulates complex GABA-mediated synaptic circuitry.In Chapter 4, we screened synapse organizers for amyloid beta oligomer (AβO) binding and identified a novel interaction between neurexins (NRXs) and AβOs. AβOs bind to NRXs via the N-terminal histidine-rich domain (HRD) of β-NRX1/2/3 and alternatively-spliced inserts at splicing site 4 of NRX1/2. In artificial synapse-formation assays, AβOs diminish excitatory presynaptic differentiation induced by NRX-interacting proteins such as neuroligin1/2 (NLG1/2) and the leucine-rich repeat transmembrane protein LRRTM2. As a cellular mechanism, our time-lapse imaging revealed that AβO treatment reduces the surface expression of NRX1β on axons and that this reduction depends on the NRX1β HRD. In transgenic mice with mutated human amyloid precursor protein, synaptic expression of β-NRXs, but not α-NRXs, specifically decreases. In summary, our results indicate that AβOs interact with NRXs and that this interaction inhibits NRXs-mediated presynaptic differentiation by reducing surface expression of axonal β-NRXs. These findings shed light on pathological roles of synapse organizers in Alzheimer's disease and will help to develop new therapeutic strategies targeting AβO-NRXs interaction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hideto Takahashi</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd37j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c051w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v8382720"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The associations between pathological pathways in the progression of Alzheimer's disease</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ali Pascoal, Tharick</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La maladie d'Alzheimer (MA) est pathologiquement caractérisée par l'accumulation progressive de β-amyloïde et de protéines tau ainsi que par la dégénérescence neuronale. Cependant, le lien complexe entre ces processus pathologiques et la démence est peu compris. En fait, le développement de marqueurs biologiques in vivo a considérablement aidé à la compréhension de la progression de la MA. Le modèle de marqueur biologique de la progression de la maladie le plus accepté soutient que β-amyloïde est l'élément déclencheur d'une suite d'évènements menant à l'hyperphosphorylation de tau et à la dégénérescence neuronale, provoquant ensuite la démence. Néanmoins, la présence de dépôt de β-amyloïde dans le cerveau de nombreux individus cognitivement stables et le manque d'élaboration d'un lien réel entre β-amyloïde et la dégénérescence neuronale, ou le déclin cognitif chez les patients atteints de la MA, a été souligné afin de remettre en cause le rôle-clé de β-amyloïde dans la pathogenèse de la MA. Étant donné que toutes les pathologies précédemment mentionnées sont fortement liées à la MA mais ne suffisent pas à causer une démence, il est raisonnable de supposer que les interactions synergiques entre ces voies pathologiques provoquent une vulnérabilité face à la démence. Récemment, il a été supposé que l'accumulation progressive de multiples pathologies cérébrales provoque des modifications neuroépigénétiques à travers des anormalités de l'histone désacétylase de catégorie I (HDAC I) qui déterminent la vulnérabilité du tissu cérébral. Par conséquent, il est possible que le mécanisme biologique par lequel les pathologies cérébrales interagissent avant de mener à la MA repose sur des dérèglements de l'épigénétique cérébral. Cette thèse, composée de deux grandes parties, décrit six études qui utilisent la tomographie à émission de positons et les biomarqueurs du liquide encéphalo-rachidien. Dans la première partie, nous avons testé l'hypothèse que, phénoménologiquement, les interactions synergiques expliquent mieux la progression de la MA que le modèle séquentiel traditionnel de la maladie. La seconde partie teste l'hypothèse que, mécaniquement, les anormalités épigénétiques imposées au tissu cérébral par la coexistence de pathologies sont le lien biologique entre les interactions pathologiques et la progression de la maladie. Premièrement, nous avons montré que, plutôt que des effets indépendants ou séquentiels, l'interaction synergique entre β-amyloïde, tau et la dégénérescence neuronale déterminent la progression de la MA. De plus, nous avons identifié l'existence de seuils de biomarqueurs associés au déclenchement de ces interactions ainsi que leur utilité dans la sélection d'individus, plus susceptibles de progresser, aidant ainsi à l'enrichissement des populations des essais cliniques. Deuxièmement, nous avons montré que les dérèglements epigénétiques associent les pathologies cérébrales et les symptômes de la MA. Plus précisément, nous avons trouvé que la réduction d'HDACs I souligne le mécanisme biologique par lequel β-amyloïde et tau interagissent afin de conduire à la dégénérescence neuronale et aux symptômes cognitifs dans la MA. Ensemble, ces découvertes ont élargi notre compréhension des associations entre les voies pathologiques dans la MA, et comment ces mêmes voies pathologiques interagissent pour causer la démence. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is pathologically characterized by the progressive brain accumulation of amyloid-β and tau proteins and neuronal degeneration. Yet, the complex interplay between these pathological processes and dementia is poorly understood. In fact, the development of in vivo biomarkers has significantly advanced our understanding of AD progression. The most accepted biomarker model of disease progression supports brain amyloid-β as the key trigger of sequential downstream events leading to tau hyperphosphorylation and neuronal degeneration, which in turn leads to dementia. However, the presence of amyloid-β deposition in the brain of numerous cognitively stable individuals and the lack of strong association between amyloid-β and neurodegeneration or cognitive decline in AD patients have been used to question the key role of amyloid-β in the pathogenesis of AD. Since all of the above pathologies are highly linked to AD but are not independently sufficient to determine dementia, it is reasonable to assume that synergistic interactions between these pathological pathways determine the vulnerability to dementia. Recently, it has been proposed that the progressive accumulation of multiple brain pathologies imposes neuroepigenetic modifications through class I histone deacetylases (HDACs I) abnormalities determining brain tissue vulnerability. Thus, it is possible that the biological mechanism by which brain pathologies interact to drive AD relies on dysregulations of the brain's epigenetic landscape. This thesis, composed of two main parts, describes six studies using positron emission tomography and cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers. In part one, we tested the hypothesis that, phenomenologically, synergistic interactions between pathologies better explain AD progression than the traditional sequential disease model. Part two tested the hypothesis that, mechanistically, epigenetic abnormalities imposed on brain tissues by the coexistence of pathologies are the biological links between pathological interactions and the progression of the disease. Firstly, we showed that the synergistic interactions between, rather than independent or sequential effects of, amyloid-β, tau, and neurodegeneration determine AD progression. Also, we identified the existence of biomarker thresholds associated with the triggering of these interactions and their usefulness in selecting individuals that are more likely to progress, for the enrichment of clinical trial populations. Secondly, we showed that epigenetic dysregulations link brain pathologies and AD symptoms. Specifically, we found that HDACs I reduction underscores the biological mechanism by which amyloid-β and tau interact to drive neurodegeneration and cognitive symptoms in AD. Together, these findings have broadened our understanding of the associations between pathological pathways in AD and how these pathways interact to determine dementia.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pedro Rosa</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xx08p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8382720</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395w9613"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cell Wall plasticity regulation in pollen tubes related to mechanical stress</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cameron, Christine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le tube pollinique est une cellule végétale dont la croissance rapide présente des caractéristiques particulières que l'on ne peut assimiler qu'en associant biologie cellulaire et concepts de mécanique cellulaire. Premièrement, les variations temporelles, à intervalles réguliers, du taux de croissance sont régies par un mécanisme de rétroaction associé à la régulation des propriétés mécaniques de la paroi cellulaire apicale et des canaux ioniques mécano- sensibles. Les récents développements en analyse d'images ont permis de faire d'importants progrès dans la quantification de ce mécanisme. Deuxièmement, la croissance invasive du tube pollinique lui permet de pénétrer les tissus du pistil afin de transporter les cellules spermatiques vers leur cible, un ovule. La force exercée par la turgescence est le principal moteur de ce comportement invasif dont les fondements mécaniques ont été caractérisés à l'aide de la technologie Lab-on-Chip (LOC). Troisièmement, le tube pollinique est capable de réorienter sa direction de croissance en réponse à un signal de guidage. Cette réorientation nécessite une régulation complexe des processus de transport intracellulaire contrôlant la croissance polaire. Ce processus morphogénétique repose sur le contrôle spatial précis d'un gradient de propriétés mécaniques de la paroi cellulaire. Les techniques de pointe en imagerie et en micromanipulation ont été déterminantes pour la caractérisation des propriétés biomécaniques de cette cellule,  dont le  rôle  dans le  cycle  reproductif  des plantes est crucial. Il a été récemment démontré que le diamètre du tube pollinique change en réponse à un obstacle mécanique. Ce changement de diamètre suggère l'existence d'un mécanisme adaptatif dans la formation de la paroi cellulaire. Afin de comprendre ce mécanisme, j'ai induit la germination de tubes polliniques de quatre espèces végétales, C. sinensis, N. tabacum, S. chacoense et A. thaliana, dans  des milieux de différentes rigidités. Le but étant de les exposer à différents degrés de stress mécanique lors de la formation des parois cellulaires. Le diamètre des tubes a été comparé au profil de distribution spatial des beta-glycanes pariétaux. Les tubes polliniques ont été spécifiquement marqués par des anticorps afin de montrer la présence de beta-glycanes spécifiques ainsi que les pectines méthyl- estérifiées et dé-estérifiées. Le but de ces marquages est de déterminer si la composition biochimique de la paroi cellulaire serait affectée par les différentes propriétés mécaniques des milieux de croissance des tubes polliniques. Bien que les tubes polliniques de C. sinensis et d'A. thaliana germent in vivo dans différents environnements pistillaires, leurs apex sont caractérisés par une forte concentration en pectines de-estérifiées lorsqu'ils poussent, in vitro, dans des milieux rigides, suggérant ainsi la formation d'un apex plus rigide en réponse au stress. Certains tubes polliniques de N. tabacum et de S. chacoense sont caractérisés par des apex de forme bulbeuse et par une composition biochimie pariétale atypique au niveau apical, suggérant la présence d'un mécanisme adaptatif en réponse au stress. Les apex de forme atypique bulbeuse ont contenu des bas niveaux de pectines de-estérifiées dans la paroi cellulaire en soulignant que les pectines de-estérifiées sont nécessaires pour maintenir le diamètre du tube pollinique pendant la croissance.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The pollen tube is a rapidly growing plant cell that features particular traits that can only be understood when integrating cell biological with cell mechanical concepts. Firstly, regular temporal variations in the growth rate are governed by a feedback mechanism involving the regulation of the mechanical properties of the apical cell wall and mechanosensitive ion channels. Recent developments in image analysis have allowed making significant progress in the quantification of this behavior. Secondly, a pollen tube uses invasive growth to penetrate the flower tissues with the aim to transport the male sperm cells to their target, an ovule. Turgor was recently found to be the driving force of this invasive behavior and the mechanical underpinnings have been characterized using Lab-on-Chip (LOC) technology. Thirdly, the pollen tube is able to reorient its growth direction upon exposure to a guidance cue and the steering mechanism involves the sophisticated choreography of intracellular transport processes serving to fuel the polar growth process. This morphogenetic process relies on the precise spatial control of a gradient in the mechanical properties of the cell wall. Sophisticated imaging and micromanipulation techniques have been instrumental for the advancement in characterizing the biomechanical features of this crucial cell in the plant reproductive cycle. It has been recently shown that the pollen tube diameter changes in response to mechanical hindrance; this change in diameter suggests there is an adaptive mechanism within the cell wall formation pathway. In order to investigate this, pollen tubes from four plant species, Camellia sinensis, Nicotiana tabacum, Solanum chacoense and Arabidopsis thaliana, were germinated in media of varying stiffness to expose them to different degrees of mechanical stress during cell wall formation. Diameter has been correlated with the characteristic spatial profile of the distribution of cell wall polysaccharides. The pollen tubes were stained and immunolabeled to show beta-glycan contents as well as that of methyl esterified and de-esterified homogalacturonan (HG) to determine if the biochemical composition of the cell wall was affected by exposure to different types of mechanical environment. Though they grow in different pistil environments in vivo, both C. sinensis and A. thaliana had higher de-esterified HG content at the tip during growth in the stiff media suggesting the formation of a stiffer tip in response to stress. Some N. tabacum and S. chacoense pollen tubes displayed swollen bulbous tips with abnormal tip cell wall biochemistry suggesting this is an adaptive mechanism in response to stress. The abnormal swollen tips contained low levels of de- esterified HG in the bulbous tip cell wall suggesting this polysaccharide is necessary in maintaining pollen tube diameter during growth.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anja Geitmann</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204138f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w9613</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A41687k41w"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Perceptuo-motor strategies in response to moving obstacles while walking: impact of obstacle characteristics and mobile communication in healthy young and older adults immersed in a virtual environment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Souza Silva, Wagner</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Jusqu'à présent, l'impact des caractéristiques des obstacles (i.e. modalité sensorielle, humain vs. objet) e des caractéristiques des messages téléphoniques sur les stratégies de contournement des obstacles demeure inconnu. Cette thèse est composée de quatre manuscrits (chapitres 2 à 5). Dans le Manuscrit 1, l'impact des caractéristiques des obstacles sur les stratégies de contournement a été évalué chez seize jeunes adultes sains (25.2 ± 2.5 ans) marchant dans un environnement virtuel (EV). Trois conditions d'obstacle ont été examinées: un obstacle de type objet (cylindre), un obstacle de type humain (humain virtuel) et un obstacle de type humain avec des sons de pas. Des dégagements d'obstacles plus petits ont été appliqués en réponse à des êtres humains virtuels par rapport aux cylindres. L'ajout de sons de pas aux êtres humains virtuels n'a pas modifié les distances minimales par rapport à l'absence de son. L'absence d'influence de sons de pas confirme le fait que l'évitement d'obstacles repose principalement sur des informations visuelles, si celles-ci sont suffisamment explicites. Dans le second manuscrit (Manuscrit 2), une expérience utilisant une manette de jeu a permis d'évaluer l'impact de deux modalités sensorielles (visuelles ou auditives) de messages téléphoniques reçus par téléphone portable sur la perception des piétons virtuels venant de différentes directions. Dix-huit jeunes participants (24 ± 2,9 ans) et 15 participants âgés (68 ± 4,2 ans) ont exécuté une tâche de reconnaissance de message, une tâche de détection d'obstacle et double tâche combinant reconnaissance de message et détection d'obstacle. La précision du contenu du message (PCM) n'a été réduite que chez les personnes âgées, plus avec les messages texte que audio. Dans les deux groupes, les messages audio ne donnaient pas de temps de détection d'obstacle différent de celui observé en l'absence de messages. Les résultats montrent que les messages texte, mais non les messages audio, compromettent la détection des autres piétons. Dans le Manuscrit 3, nous avons estimé à quel point la reconnaissance de messages texte par rapport à des messages téléphoniques audio affectait la capacité à contourner un obstacle lors de la marche chez de jeunes adultes et des personnes âgées. Seize participants jeunes (24 ± 3 ans) et 14 participants âgés (68 ± 4,5 ans) ont participé. L'EV, les tâches et les conditions de message testés étaient tels que décrits dans le Manuscrit 2. Les deux groupes d'âge ont montré une réduction de la PCM et de la vitesse de marche, ainsi qu'un plus grand nombre de collisions, lors de la reconnaissance de messages texte par rapport aux messages audio. Comparativement aux jeunes adultes, les participants plus âgés ont montré une réduction supplémentaire de la PCM, davantage de collisions, mais une vitesse de marche similaire. Les participans âgées ont également subi des collisions et une PCM réduite avec les messages audio. Dans le Manuscrit 4, on a examiné dans quelle mesure la reconnaissance de messages visuels (texte) à différentes étapes de la stratégie d'évitement influait sur le contournement d'obstacles chez des participants adultes jeunes et plus âgés. Les participants, l'EV et les tâches étaient tels que décrits dans le Manuscrit 3. Les conditions de message téléphonique consistaient toutefois en un message texte envoyé tôt (0,5 m: au début du mouvement des piétons virtuels) ou plus tard (2,5 m: pendant la stratégie d'évitement) pendant la stratégie de contournement d'obstacles. Dans les deux groupes, la PCM a été réduite pour les messages précoces, bien que les adultes âgés aient présenté une détérioration plus importante que les participants plus jeunes. Une vitesse de marche plus lente et des collisions plus fréquentes ont été observées en réponse aux message précoces vs. messages tardifs. Les messages tardifs ont aussi mené à un évitement et à une vitesse de marche plus rapides que lors des autres conditions. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Obstacle circumvention has been investigated in a variety of settings which manipulated features of both obstacles (static and dynamic) and environments (virtual reality and real world). Until now, however, information about the impact of obstacle characteristics (human vs. non-human, sensory modality) on obstacle circumvention strategies was lacking. Furthermore, the extent to which obstacle circumvention strategies in young and older adults are differentially affected by phone message characteristics such as their sensory modality (visual vs. audio messages) and the timing at which they are delivered, remained unknown. This dissertation is composed of four manuscripts (chapters 2-5), through which the aforementioned gaps are addressed. In Manuscript 1, the impact of obstacle characteristics to circumvention strategies was assessed in sixteen healthy young adults (25.2 ± 2.5 years) walking in a virtual environment (VE). Three obstacle conditions were experimented: a non-human obstacle (cylinder), a human-like obstacle (virtual human) and a human-like obstacle with footstep sounds. Smaller obstacle clearances were applied in response to virtual humans compared to cylinders. The addition of footstep sounds to virtual humans did not modify minimal distances compared to when no sound was provided. Smaller obstacle clearances in response to virtual humans suggests the implementation of less conservative strategies. The lack of influence of footstep sounds supports the fact that obstacle avoidance primarily relies on visual information, should it be explicit enough. In Manuscript 2, a seated joystick-based experiment assessed the impact of two sensory modalities (visual vs. auditory) of mobile phone messages on the perception of virtual pedestrians approaching from different directions. Eighteen healthy young (24 ±  2.9 years) and 15 older adults (68 ± 4.2 years) participated in a message deciphering task, an obstacle detection task, and a dual-task condition combining message deciphering and obstacle detection tasks. An ecological VE was created depicting a subway station. Delayed obstacle detection time (ODT) was found in both age groups in response to text messages compared to other conditions. The accuracy of message report (AMR) in presence of approaching obstacles was only reduced in older adults, and more so with texts vs. audio messages. In both age groups, audio messages yielded no different obstacle detection time than that seen in the absence of messages. Results show that text messages, but not audio messages, compromise the detection of approaching pedestrians. In Manuscript 3 sixteen young (24 ± 3 years) and 14 older adults (68 ± 4.5 years) participated. The VE, tasks and message conditions tested were as described in Manuscript 2, only in the context of walking. Both age groups show reduced AMR and walking speed, as well as more collisions when deciphering text vs. audio messages. Compared to young adults, however, older participants showed further reduction of AMR, more collisions but similar walking speeds. In Manuscript 4, the extent to which deciphering visual (text) messages at different stages of the avoidance strategy affects obstacle circumvention in healthy young and older adults was investigated.  Testing conditions consisted of messages delivered early (0.5m: at onset of interferer movement) or later (2.5m: during the avoidance strategy) in the obstacle circumvention strategy. In both groups, the AMR was reduced for early vs. late texts, although older adults showed larger deterioration compared to younger participants. Locomotor outcomes showed no significant difference between young and older participants. Early texts led to slower walking speed and more frequent collisions compared to late texts and the no-message condition. Late texts yielded faster onset time of avoidance and walking speed compared to the other conditions.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Anouk Lamontagne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0969421.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k41w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v771m"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Geochemical and textural indicators of syn-eruptive degassing during recent rhyolitic eruptions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Paisley, Rebecca</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Silicic volcanoes are capable of producing dangerous explosive eruptions and the effusion of lava and domes. Observations from recent rhyolitic eruptions demonstrated how the transition between these two end-member behaviours is markedly complex. Fractures, commonly preserved as tuffisite veins, are transient permeable pathways that allow for the punctuated but efficient escape of volatiles. They are considered key enablers of degassing but their interactions with deeper, gas-rich reservoirs and influence on melt chemistry are not fully understood. Preserved 210Pb-226Ra isotope disequilibria, volatile trace element heterogeneity, and complex vein and breccia textures in volcanic bombs have been previously associated with gas fluxing within the conduit. In this thesis I utilise both textural and chemical heterogeneity preserved in samples from the first observed rhyolite eruptions, Chaitén (2008) and Cordón Caulle (2011-2012), to assess how degassing processes are preserved from the dm to nm scale. 210Pb-226Ra isotope and trace element analyses were conducted on 'mini-bulk' samples of tuffisite veins and their respective hosts to understand gas flow through fractures, from deeper reservoirs. The lack of 210Pb-226Ra disequilibria preserved in veins constrains the upper limit for the volume of magma that can be degassed by a tuffisite vein during its lifetime. Whilst trace element enrichments and depletions in veins record preferential gas fluxing (e.g. Li, Cu, Pb, Tl, Bi), results are limiting because tuffisites and breccias, which preserve the fracturing process, are comprised of clasts that have each undergone differing degrees of degassing. To further constrain gas fluxing and clasts' individual histories, electron microprobe and laser ablation ICP-MS analyses were undertaken across mm to µm-scale textures in samples from Cordón Caulle. Chemical and textural heterogeneity are strongly linked, depletions of metals (e.g. Zn, Pb, Tl) in veins highlight scavenging by the fluxing volatile phase. Trace element systematics constrain minute-hour fracture lifespans and show how these increase towards the surface and with eruption duration. Trace element analyses are analytically limited to the order of 10s of microns to yield accurate and precise results. But texturally fracturing processes can be investigated to the nm scale. The study of the interfaces between host and vein material show how veins exploit pre-existing bubble networks and can infill them with ash. Rheological weaknesses are exploited to allow cycles of fragmentation, degassing, sintering and healing of melts. Post-fracture melt compaction highlights how even small veins can degas vesicular magmas on the cm-scale.By investigating fracture processes texturally and chemically at differing analytical scales, I constrain (1) the degree to which fractures and permeable gas reservoirs interact; (2) the timescales fractures outgas for; and (3) how heterogeneity is preserved as a function of depth in the conduit and eruption duration. Fractures exploit pre-existing permeable networks at depth, extracting volatiles on a cm-scale, but not enough magma is degassed to induce 210Pb-226Ra isotope disequilibria in tuffisite veins. The channelling of volatiles from reservoirs through fractures in the conduit plug results in metal exchange with transported shards and localised volatile exchange at fracture-host interfaces (constraining fracture lifespans). Outgassing at the near-surface, later in the eruption, occurs for longer resulting in a greater degree of metal and textural heterogeneity. In conclusion, I show fractures play a fundamental spatial and temporal role in degassing of silicic magmas and can directly impact the changing explosive-effusive behaviour observed during eruptions.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les volcans siliciques sont capables de produire des éruptions explosives dangereuses, où de mener à l'épanchement de lave et la formation de dômes. Les observations d'éruptions rhyolitiques récentes ont montré à quel point la transition entre ces deux comportements extrêmes est complexe. Les fractures, généralement préservées sous forme de veines tuffisitiques, sont des voies perméables transitoires qui permettent l'échappement ponctuel mais efficace des éléments volatiles. Elles sont considérées comme des catalyseurs essentiels du dégazage, mais leurs interactions avec des réservoirs plus profonds et riches en gaz et leur influence sur la chimie des masses fondues ne sont pas entièrement comprises. L'enregistrement du déséquilibre isotopique 210Pb-226Ra, l'hétérogénéité des éléments-traces volatils et les textures complexes des veines et des brèches dans les bombes volcaniques ont déjà été associés à des flux de gaz dans le conduit. Dans cette thèse, j'utilise l'hétérogénéité texturale et chimique préservée dans des échantillons des premières éruptions observées de rhyolite, Chaitén (2008) et Cordón Caulle (2011-2012), pour évaluer la façon dont les processus de dégazage sont préservés de l'échelle décimétrique à nanométrique.Des analyses d'isotopes 210Pb-226Ra et d'éléments-traces ont été effectuées sur des échantillons représentatifs de veines tuffisitiques et de leurs encaissants respectifs afin de comprendre le flux de gaz à travers les fractures à partir de réservoirs plus profonds. L'absence de déséquilibre isotopique 210Pb-226Ra enregistré dans les veines contraint la limite supérieure du volume de magma qui peut être dégazé par une veine tuffisite pendant sa durée de vie. Bien que les enrichissements ou appauvrissements en éléments-traces dans les veines indiquent un flux gazeux préférentiel (par exemple, Li, Pb, Tl, Bi), les résultats sont mitigés, car les tuffisites et les brèches, qui préservent le processus de fracturation, sont constituées de fragments ayant subi différents degrés de dégazage. Pour contraindre davantage le flux de gaz et les histoires individuelles des clastes, des analyses par microsonde électronique et par ICP-MS à ablation laser ont été effectuées sur des textures  allant d'échelle millimétrique a micrométrique sur des échantillons du Cordón Caulle. Les hétérogénéités chimiques et texturales sont fortement liées, et des appauvrissements en métaux (par exemple, Zn, Pb, Tl) dans les veines mettent en évidence la récupération par le passage de la phase volatile. La systématique des éléments-traces contraint les durées de vie des fractures avec une précision allant de la minute à l'heure et montre comment la durée de vie augmente vers lorsque l'on se rapproche de la surface et augmente avec la durée de l'éruption. Les processus de fracturation texturale peuvent être étudiés à l'échelle nanométrique. L'étude des interfaces entre la roche encaissante et le matériau de la veine montre comment les veines exploitent les réseaux de bulles préexistants et peuvent les remplir de cendres. Les faiblesses rhéologiques sont exploitées pour permettre des cycles de fragmentation, de dégazage, de frittage et de cicatrisation des masses fondues. La compaction post-fracture du magma souligne le fait que même de petites veines peuvent dégazer des magmas vésiculaires à l'échelle centimétrique.En examinant les processus de fracture selon leur chimies et textures, à échelles analytiques différentes, je contraint (1) le degré d'interaction des fractures et des réservoirs de gaz perméables; (2) les échelles de temps selon lesquelles les fractures dégazent ; et (3) la façon dont l'hétérogénéité est préservée en fonction de la profondeur dans le conduit et de la durée de l'éruption. En conclusion, je montre que les fractures jouent un rôle spatial et temporel fondamental dans le dégazage des magmas siliciques et peuvent influencer directement le changement de comportement explosif-effusif observé lors des éruptions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hugh Tuffen</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Kim Berlo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s704k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v771m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz92h"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Stereological investigation of serotonin type 3 receptors in the substantia nigra and dorsal raphe nucleus in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Belliveau, Sébastien</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Serotonin (5-hydroxytryptamine, 5-HT) is a common neurotransmitter in mammals, and the serotonergic system plays an essential role in the regulation of various behaviours such as sleep, perception, and cognitive and autonomic functions in the mammalian central nervous system (CNS). Previous studies have investigated the distribution pattern of the 5-HT type 3 (5-HT3) receptor in the brain. Moreover, it has been demonstrated that 5-HT3 receptors are expressed in both the substantia nigra (SN) and the dorsal raphe nucleus (DRN). Here, we determine the quantitative distribution of 5-HT3 receptors in the SN and DRN of the rat.Six rats were deeply anaesthetised with 4% isofluorane in 100% O2 and perfused transcardially with 0.9% saline followed by 4% paraformaldehyde in phosphate buffered saline (pH 7.4). Double immunofluorescence immunohistochemistry was performed on coronal sections (40 μm) of rat brain covering the entire rostro-caudal extent of the SN and DRN with an antibody specific to the 5-HT3A receptor subunit in combination with antibodies targeting the monoaminergic markers tyrosine hydroxylase (TH) and serotonin transporter (SERT). Then, the number of 5-HT3-, TH- and SERT-positive neurons were counted either in the SN or in the DRN using stereological techniques.We found that TH- and 5-HT3A-positive cells are present in the SN, with a higher number of TH- positives cells compared to 5-HT3A-positive cells. We also found that SERT- positive cells are present in the DRN in a higher proportion. In contrast, no 5-HT3A-positive cells were found in the DRN. The present results support the presence of 5-HT3 receptors in the SN, but not in the DRN, and do not support their expression on dopaminergic nor serotonergic cells. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La sérotonine (5-hydroxytryptamine, 5-HT) est un neurotransmetteur répandu chez les mammifères. En effet, le système sérotoninergique joue un rôle essentiel dans la régulation de plusieurs comportements, dont le sommeil, la perception, ainsi que les aspects cognitifs et autonomes du système nerveux central des mammifères. Des études antérieures ont montré la distribution du récepteur 5-HT de type 3 (5-HT3) dans le cerveau et d'autres ont rapporté son expression dans la substance noire (SN) et le noyau dorsal du raphé (NDR). Dans cette étude, nous déterminons quantitativement la distribution des récepteurs 5-HT3 dans la SN et le NDR dans le rat.Six rats ont été anesthésiés avec 4% d'isofluorane dans 100% d'O2 et ont été perfusés transcardialement avec de la saline 0.9% suivi par 4% de paraformaldehyde dans du tampon phosphate salin (pH 7.4). De l'immunohistochimie à double immunofluorescence a été performée sur des coupes coronales (40 μm) de cerveau de rat couvrant la distribution rostro-caudale de la SN et du NDR avec un anticorps spécifique à la sous-unité 3A du récepteur 5-HT3 (5-HT3A) en combinaison avec des anticorps ciblant les marqueurs monoaminergiques tyrosine hyroxylase (TH) et le transporteur de sérotonine (SERT). Ensuite, le nombre de neurones marqués avec 5-HT3, TH et SERT a été compté dans la SN ou le NDR en utilisant des technique stéréologiques.Nous avons trouvé que les cellules positivement marquées avec la TH et 5-HT3A sont présentes dans la SN. Le nombre de cellules marquées avec TH était plus élevé comparativement aux cellules marquées avec 5-HT3A. Nous avons aussi rapporté la présence de cellules marquées positivement avec SERT dans le NDR, sans la présence de cellules marquées positivement pour le récepteur 5-HT3. Les résultats ci-présents soutiennent la présence du récepteur 5-HT3 dans la SN, mais pas dans le NDR. De plus, l'absence d'expression du récepteur 5-HT3 sur les cellules dopaminergiques et sérotoninergiques a été observé.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Philippe Huot</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv90g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz92h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A00000227t"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of legacy and emerging flame retardants, plasticizers and their metabolites in food and breast milk</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Furlong, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tous les jours, nous sommes exposés à une grande variété de produits chimiques, tels que les retardateurs de flamme et les plastifiants, qui sont incorporés dans les produits de consommation. Même à faibles doses, il a été constaté que certains de ces produits chimiques perturbent le système endocrinien de l'organisme. C'est ce que l'on appelle des produits chimiques perturbant le système endocrinien (EDC). En raison de l'omniprésence de ces substances, il est important de surveiller notre exposition potentielle aux EDC dans le régime alimentaire. Dans cet esprit, une méthode d'extraction multi-classe a été développée, optimisée et validée pour les éthers diphényliques polybromés (PBDE), les déchloranes, les esters d'organophosphates (OPE) et leurs métabolites (mOPE). De bonnes récupérations sont obtenues pour tous les analytes dans toutes les matrices (49-122%) avec une bonne répétabilité (RSD 1-10%). Les extraits ont été analysés sur LC-QqQ-MS/MS pour la séparation et la quantification des OPE et des mOPE, ainsi que par GC-MS pour la séparation et la quantification des PBDE et des Déchloranes. La séparation chromatographique des isomères du tri-tolyl phosphate (TCP) et de l'isopropylphényl diphényl phosphate (ip-PDPP) a été réalisée pour la première fois avec LC-QTOF-MS. La méthode a été appliquée à divers échantillons d'aliments, notamment du poisson, du poulet, des légumes, du poisson en conserve, du pain et du beurre ainsi que du lait maternel. Plusieurs des composés analysés ont été détectés au-dessus des niveaux de MLOQ. De plus, la méthode actuelle est plus rapide et moins coûteuse que d'autres méthodes. La présence de 14 OPEs et mOPEs a été étudiée dans 66 échantillons d'aliments composites achetés sur le marché du Grand Montréal. De plus, 100 échantillons de lait maternel ont été recueillis auprès de nouvelles mères à Montréal. Toutes les OPEs analysées ont été détectées au-dessus de la limite de quantification dans au moins une matrice. Afin d'étudier l'effet du conditionnement des aliments sur la migration potentielle des OPE et des mOPE dans les aliments, des échantillons d'aliments emballés et non emballés ont été collectés; cependant, il n'y avait aucune différence dans les niveaux d'OPEs ou de mOPEs dans ces échantillons (p&gt; 0,05). La dépendance vis-à-vis des lipides des OPE a également été étudiée en comparant la teneur en lipides de l'échantillon aux teneurs totales en contaminants présents; aucune tendance n'a donc été observée, suggérant ainsi l'indépendance des lipides des OPEs. Le métabolisme des OPEs a été évalué en normalisant les OPEs détectés par le mOPE correspondant; la plupart des échantillons, y compris le lait maternel, contenaient des taux plus élevés d'OPE dans mOPE. Une exception notable est le pain ayant des niveaux plus élevés deTDCPP / BCIPP, de TCP/DCP et du TCEP/BCEP. Compte tenu de la consommation quotidienne moyenne d'aliments pour le Canadien moyen, l'exposition alimentaire aux OPE était estimée à 12800+/-1500 ng/jour [18322 ng/kg bw/jour]. Plusieurs groupes de population ont été pris en compte pour l'exposition alimentaire, notamment des hommes, des femmes, des enfants (5 à 11 ans) et des jeunes enfants (1 à 4 ans). Pour tous les groupes, les valeurs des OPE étaient inférieures de plusieurs ordres de grandeur aux doses de référence correspondantes pour la santé. En utilisant la méthode d'extraction multiclasse développée, il a été possible d'estimer les niveaux d'exposition alimentaire actuels des OPEs et des mOPEs pour les Canadiens. Sur la base de cette évaluation des risques, la population Canadienne est exposée à un niveau tolérable d'OPE. Cependant, une surveillance attentive devrait être poursuivie et étendue à d'autres groupes d'aliments afin d'obtenir une image complète de l'exposition alimentaire aux OPEs. Avec ces données, les décideurs peuvent prendre des décisions plus éclairées en ce qui concerne les produits chimiques de remplacement.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>On a daily basis, we are exposed to a wide variety of chemicals, such as flame retardants and plasticizers, that are incorporated into consumer products. Even at low doses, some of these chemicals have been found to disrupt the body's endocrine system, these are known as endocrine disrupting chemicals (EDCs). Due to the ubiquity of these substances, it is important to monitor our potential exposure to EDCs through diet. With this in mind, a multiclass extraction method was developed, optimized and validated for Polybrominated Diphenyl Ethers (PBDEs), Dechloranes, Organophosphate esters (OPEs) and their metabolites (mOPEs). Good recoveries are obtained for all analytes in all matrices (49-122%) with good repeatability (RSD 1-10%). The extracts were run on LC-QqQ-MS/MS for the separation and quantification of OPEs and mOPEs as well as GC-MS for the separation and quantification of PBDEs and Dechloranes. The chromatographic separation of Tri-tolyl phosphate (TCP) and isopropylphenyl diphenyl phosphate (ip-PDPP) isomers was achieved for the first time using LC-QTOF-MS. The method was applied to various food samples including fish, chicken, vegetables, canned fish, bread and butter as well as breast milk. Moreover, the current method is quicker, and less costly than other methods due to the reduction of required materials and processing steps. The occurrence of 14 OPEs and mOPEs was investigated in 66 composite food samples purchased from the greater Montreal market. Also, 100 breast milk samples were collected from new mothers in Montreal. All OPEs analyzed were detected above the quantification limit in at least one matrix. To investigate the effect of food packaging on the potential migration of OPEs and mOPEs into food, both packaged and non-packaged food samples were collected; however, there was no difference in the levels of OPEs or mOPEs in these samples (P&gt;0.05). The lipid dependence of OPEs was also investigated by comparing the lipid content of the sample to the total levels of contaminants present; no trend was observed, thus, further suggesting the lipid independence of OPEs. The metabolism of OPEs was assessed by normalizing the detected OPE by the respective mOPE; most samples, including breast milk contained higher levels of OPE to mOPE. A notable exception is bread having higher levels for Tris(1,3-dichloro-2-propyl) phosphate to Bis(1-chloro-2-propyl) phosphate (TDCPP/BCIPP), Tris-tolyl phosphate to di-tolyl phosphate (TCP/DCP) and Tris(2-chloroethyl) phosphate to Bis(2-chloroethyl) phosphate (TCEP/BCEP); this may be due to the high temperature processing needed to bake bread.Considering the daily average intake of food for the average Canadian, the dietary exposure to OPE was estimated to be 12800 +/- 1500 ng/day [18322 ng/kg bw/day]. Several population groups were considered for dietary exposure including men, women, children (5-11 years) and young children (1-4 years). For all groups, values of OPEs were several orders of magnitude lower than their corresponding health-based reference doses. mOPEs currently do not have reference dose values and therefore are not included in the exposure assessment. The exposure to OPEs through breast milk for young infants (3 months) was also considered. Both males and females as well as high and low consumption patterns were assessed. For all groups, values of OPEs were several orders of magnitude lower than their corresponding health-based reference doses. By using the developed multiclass extraction method, it was possible to estimate the current dietary exposure levels of OPEs and mOPEs for Canadians. Based on this preliminary risk assessment, the Canadian population is exposed to a tolerable level of OPEs through diet, however, careful monitoring should continue and be expanded to other food groups in order to obtain a complete picture of dietary exposure to EDCs. With these data, policy makers can make more informed decisions with regards to replacement chemicals.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stephane Bayen</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Cariton Kubwabo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b823z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000227t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225d28p"><ual:graduationDate>2018</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Exploration of neogenin expression and function in the developing dorsal root ganglia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wiedman, Candice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Le système nerveux est composé de plusieurs types de neurones qui ont des identités uniques et sont générées à partir de cellules progénitrices. Notre compréhension des mécanismes moléculaires impliqués dans la différentiation des neurones demeure incomplète. La formation des ganglions de la racines dorsale (DRG) durant le développement embryonnaire représente un excellent système pour étudier comment la diversité neuronale est générée.  Les cellules de la crête neurale produisent les cellules gliales et les nombreux types de neurones sensoriels arborant des fonctions distinctes dans le DRG. Le récepteur Neogenin joue un rôle dans plusieurs processus du développement du système nerveux, y compris la survie neuronale et la différenciation. Pour commencer à définir le rôle  de Neogenin dans le développement des neurones sensoriels du DRG, j'ai examiné son patron d'expression dans cette structure à l'aide du gène rapporteur lacZ chez les souris NeogeninGT/+. Mes études démontrent que β-galactosidase est grandement exprimé dans le DRG des souris NeogeninGT/+ tout au long du développement du DRG. Toutefois, son expression est plus élevée dans un sous-ensemble de neurones DRG qui inclue des neurones proprioceptifs et des neurones mécanoréceptifs exprimant TrkB. Une analyse du développement des DRGs chez des souris knockout pour Neogenin a révélé que ce récepteur n'est pas nécessaire pour la formation du DRG, pour la survie des neurones du DRG et pour la production de neurones nociceptifs exprimant Runx1. D'autres études seront nécessaires pour examiner si Neogenin est requis pour la génération d'autres populations de neurones sensoriels du DRG, y compris les mécanorécepteurs et les propriocepteurs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The nervous system is comprised of many cell types with unique identities; progenitor cells give rise to these mature neurons. The molecular mechanisms involved in how a population of progenitor cells generates mature neurons with different molecular identities remains to be fully understood. Dorsal root ganglia (DRG) formation during embryonic development is an excellent system to study how diversity is generated: neural crest cells generate the glia and the multiple types of functionally distinct sensory neurons in the DRG. One protein of interest is Neogenin. Neogenin plays a role in many developmental processes, including survival and differentiation. To begin to define a role for Neogenin in DRG sensory neuron development, I examined the expression of Neogenin in the DRG using β-galactosidase as a reporter in Neogenin+/GT mice. These studies show that β-galactosidase in Neogenin+/GT mice is widely expressed throughout the DRG early in mouse development. Over time, β-galactosidase expression is observed at higher levels in a subset of DRG neurons that include proprioceptive neurons and TrkB+ mechanoreceptive neurons. An analysis of the development of DRGs in Neogenin null mice revealed that Neogenin is dispensable for DRG formation, for survival of DRG neurons, and for the production of Runx1-positive nociceptive neurons. Further studies should examine whether Neogenin is required for the generation of other populations of sensory DRG neurons, including mechanoreceptors and proprioceptors.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jean-Francois Cloutier</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw65f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d28p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax920fz93s"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ensemble learning for decision making in sustainable infrastructure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Alobaidi, Mohammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Inferences about the prospective state of natural and man-made systems play a major role in designing better infrastructure and assessing the resiliency of current ones. The rapid change of such systems' responses prompts the urgent need to re-evaluate our understanding of the evolution of such systems. New predictive analytics are, hence, important for all energy, water and earth aspects of sustainable infrastructure. Ensemble learning, a branch of artificial intelligence, ushers innovative modeling approaches which are recent advancements in machine learning. According to a predefined ensemble architecture, a number of machine learners are generated and their inferences are integrated to produce stable and improved generalization ability. In order to advance the utilization of ensemble learning in sustainable infrastructure applications, along with developing novel ensemble frameworks, an interdisciplinary research approach is essential. To this extent, this dissertation deals with the development of generalized ensemble learning frameworks, inspired from a wide range of recent engineering problems in energy, water and earth. The results from a comprehensive ensemble analysis approach for the problem of seismic-induced liquefaction prediction emphasizes on the importance of the diversity-in-learning concept, which facilitates the development of a novel ensemble framework to exploit the diversity concept and tackle the requirements of the decentralized and disaggregated energy forecasting problems. The latter is a crucial research endeavor to develop stable ensemble-based regression models for time series forecasting, in general, and helps in innovating a new class of hybrid ensemble learning frameworks which are used in the design of flood detection systems.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Des défis nouveaux et de plus en plus importants en matière d'environnement, d'eau et d'énergie, sont une partie indispensable de tout plan de développement en cette ère. Comme les inférences d'un système sont issues de l'observation des interrelations entre les variables directrices, la collecte et l'analyse de données sur ce système à l'aide d'un ensemble approprié d'approches et d'hypothèses sont deux aspects clés pour percer le mystère derrière toute dynamique de ce système. L'évolution rapide des réponses et des comportements de tous les systèmes, par rapport à ce qui a été observé au cours des siècles précédents, rend invalide les méthodes de compréhension classique utiliser jusqu'à nos jours dans ces systèmes. L'analyse prédictive est donc importante pour tous les aspects de l'énergie, de l'eau et de l'environnement. Depuis récemment, les méthodes ensemblistes constituent un booster de l'apprentissage automatique appliqué et sont de plus en plus populaires en raison de leurs meilleures performances. L'apprentissage ensembliste suggère généralement le processus de génération de plusieurs modèles de prédiction combinés pour faire une prédiction, que ce soit à des fins de classification ou de régression. Les travaux de recherche sont orientés vers le développement de modèles d'ensembles généralisés, qui conviennent à un large éventail d'applications dans les domaines de l'eau, de l'énergie et de l'environnement. Différentes études seront effectuées à l'aide de ces approches, et ce, dans le cadre de l'apprentissage automatique, afin de combler l'écart en matière d'expertise interdisciplinaire dans les domaines mentionnés ci-dessus. Le caractère interdisciplinaire de ce travail se manifeste à partir de l'étude des techniques d'apprentissage automatique dans différents domaines. En d'autres termes, ce dernier est un effort de recherche crucial pour développer des modèles de régression stables basés sur des ensembles pour la prévision, en général, et permet d'innover une nouvelle classe de cadres d'apprentissage hybrides utilisés dans la conception de systèmes de détection d'inondation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mohamed Meguid</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v070q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz93s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anv935519b"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Silicon subwavelength grating structures for wavelength filtering applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Naghdi, Behnam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La photonique est au cœur d'une révolution dans les communications et a montré un grand potentiel dans une large gamme d'applications allant des liaisons de données aux biocapteurs, ce qui a conduit à des efforts croissants dans le développement de circuits intégrés photoniques pour des fonctions de traitement de signaux optiques. Dans le cadre de ce développement, les structures subwavelength grating (SWG) ouvrent de plus en plus d'opportunités dans la conception de dispositifs photoniques intégrés pour contribuer à la conception de circuits photoniques plus complexes. Le succès peut être attribué aux avantages que les structures de SWG peuvent offrir; tels que le contrôle de l'indice de réfraction et de la biréfringence des matériaux optiques sans modifier le processus de fabrication standard, ce qui permet d'optimiser les caractéristiques des dispositifs optiques pour les besoins spécifiques des applications. Dans cette thèse, nous démontrons et étudions les possibilités offertes par les SWG dans la conception de filtres sélectifs en longueur d'onde avec des applications dans le traitement du signal optique et la photonique à micro-ondes. Tout d'abord, nous proposons et démontrons une nouvelle conception de coupleurs contre-directionnels (contre-DC) dans laquelle un guide d'ondes SWG remplace l'un des guides d'ondes asymétriques des conceptions conventionnelles. Les dispositifs fabriqués sur la plate-forme SOI montrent une suppression supérieure à 35 dB du couplage codirectionnel indésirable et une plage spectrale supérieure à 120 nm sans interférence des réflexions intra-guides, grâce à l'important décalage de phase optique entre le guide d'onde segmenté SWG et son guide d'onde continu voisin. Nous étudions les effets de l'adaptation de la période du guide d'onde SWG, de la distance entre les deux guides et de la longueur de couplage sur les caractéristiques spectrales du dispositif, le changement de la distance entre 100 nm et 500 nm permettant des largeurs de bande de 18,2 nm. jusqu'à 0,9 nm. Ensuite, nous personnalisons les caractéristiques spectrales des contre-DC basées sur les SWG. En réduisant l'écart entre les guides d'ondes SWG et strip, nous démontrons un compromis entre la suppression des lobes latéraux et le taux d'extinction bande passante/arrêt afin d'améliorer les performances du dispositif en tant que multiplexeur optique à sauts optiques potentiels. Les conceptions avec différentes largeurs de bande passante de 12 nm, 9 nm et 6 nm montrent un rapport de suppression des lobes latéraux de 10 dB à 20 dB et un rapport d'extinction de 15 dB à 35 dB. Nous obtenons également un pic de transmission résonant dans la bande d'arrêt de la réponse spectrale du dispositif en introduisant un déphasage de π dans les réseaux du guide d'ondes SWG. Le pic de résonance a une largeur de bande de 1 nm et un taux d'extinction de 7 dB, l'utilisation du guide d'onde SWG dans la structure d'un tel coupleur permettant aux caractéristiques du pic de résonance d'être très sensibles au matériau de gaine applications.Enfin, dans la mesure où le multiplexage par répartition en longueur d'onde sur des liaisons optiques fournit une solution efficace au défi de la bande passante des communications hors puce et sur puce, nous présentons un multiplexeur optique goutte-à-goutte optique photonique silicium compact à quatre canaux, rendu possible par les contre-DC basées sur SWG. Les bandes passantes du dispositif montrent des pertes d'insertion sur la puce inférieures à 1,8 dB, avec une largeur de bande large de 3 dB, d'environ 6,7 nm, convenant au multiplexage par répartition en longueur d'onde grossière (CWDM) dans les applications d'interconnexion optique à courte portée. La transmission d'un flux de données de 10 Gbit/s à travers différents canaux du multiplexeur entraîne des pénalités de puissance négligeables, tandis que les pénalités de puissance induites par diaphonie sont inférieures à 2,8 dB.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Photonics lies at the heart of a revolution in communications and has shown great potential in a wide range of applications from data links to biosensors, leading to the growing efforts in the development of photonic integrated circuits for optical signal processing functions. As part of this development, subwavelength grating (SWG) structures are opening more and more opportunities in the design of integrated photonic devices to contribute to the design of more complex photonic circuits. The success can be attributed to the advantages that SWG structures are able to offer; such as control over the refractive index and birefringence of optical materials without changing the standard fabrication process, which allows for the characteristics of optical devices to be optimized for specific requirements of the applications.In this thesis, we demonstrate and investigate the possibilities that SWGs offer in design of wavelength selective filters with applications in optical signal processing and microwave photonics. We firstly propose and demonstrate a novel design of contra-directional couplers (contra-DCs), in which an SWG waveguide replaces one of the asymmetric waveguides of the conventional designs. Fabricated devices on the SOI platform show over 35 dB suppression of undesired codirectional coupling and larger than 120 nm spectral range free from the interference of intrawaveguide reflections thanks to the large optical phase-mismatch between the segmented SWG waveguide and its nearby continuous waveguide. We study the effects of tailoring the period of the SWG waveguide, the gap distance between the two waveguides, and the coupling length on the spectral characteristics of the device where changing the gap distance from 100 nm up to 500 nm allows for bandwidths from 18.2 nm down to 0.9 nm. Next, we tailor the spectral characteristics of SWG-based contra-DCs. By tapering the gap distance between the SWG and strip waveguides, we demonstrate a compromise between sidelobe suppression and pass-band/stop-band extinction ratio such that the performance of the device as a potential optical add-drop multiplexer is improved. The designs with different pass-band bandwidths of 12 nm, 9 nm, and 6 nm show 10 dB to 20 dB sidelobe suppression ratio and 15 dB to 35 dB extinction ratio. We also obtain a resonant transmission peak in the stop-band of the spectral response of the device by introducing a  phase shift into the gratings of the SWG waveguide. The resonant peak has 1 nm bandwidth and 7 dB extinction ratio, where the use of the SWG waveguide in the structure of such coupler allows the characteristics of the resonant peak to be highly sensitive to the cladding material, which is of strong desire in integrated sensing applications.Finally, as wavelength division multiplexing over optical links provides an effective solution for the bandwidth challenge of off-chip and on-chip communications, we demonstrate a compact silicon photonic four-channel optical add-drop multiplexer enabled by SWG-based contra-DCs. Pass-bands of the device show on-chip insertion losses below 1.8 dB with wide 3dB bandwidth of ~6.7 nm suitable for coarse wavelength division multiplexing (CWDM) in short-reach optical interconnect applications. Transmission of 10 Gbit/s data stream through different channels of the multiplexer results in negligible power penalties while interferometric crosstalk-induced power penalties are below 2.8 dB.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lawrence R. Chen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408035r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935519b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avm40xt98h"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Compactness and noncompactness of Yamabe-type problems on manifolds with boundary</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Shaodong</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The study of semilinear partial differential equations has proven to be of great importance in the fields of Physics and Geometry. Solutions to such equations correspond in particular to standing waves in Schr\"odinger equations and metrics with constant curvature on Riemannian manifolds. In this manuscript, we obtain existence results of blowing-up solutions as well as compactness results to Yamabe-type equations on manifolds. In particular, in a joint work with Jérôme Vétois, we construct blowing-up solutions to a Yamabe-type equation on the standard sphere with dimension n=4. Then, we construct blowing-up solutions on the standard half-sphere in dimensions n \geq 3. Finally, joint with Sérgio Almaraz and Olivaine Queiroz, we prove a compactness theorem to the boundary Yamabe problem in the scalar flat case in dimension n=3.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>L'étude des équations aux dérivées partielles semi-linéaires s'est révélée d'une grande importance dans les domaines de la physique et de la géométrie. Des solutions de telles équations correspondent en particulier à des ondes stationnaires dans les équations de Schr\"odinger et à des métriques de courbure constante sur des variétés riemanniennes. Dans ce manuscrit, nous obtenons des résultats d'existence de solutions explosives ainsi que des résultats de compacité pour des équations de type Yamabe sur les variétés. En particulier, dans un travail en collaboration avec Jérôme Vétois, nous construisons des solutions explosives pour une équation de type Yamabe sur la sphère standard en dimension n=4. Ensuite, nous construisons des solutions explosives sur la demi-sphère standard en dimension n \ge 3. Finalement, en collaboration avec Sérgio Almaraz et Olivaine Queiroz, nous prouvons un théorème de compacité pour le problème de Yamabe à bord dans le cas à courbure scalaire nulle en dimension n=3.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jerome Vetois</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pengfei Guan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602316n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt98h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mathematics and Statistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx59n"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Energy democracy and the co-evolution of social and technological systems</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Burke, Matthew</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>En tant que systèmes sociotechniques intégrés, les systèmes d'énergies renouvelables co-évoluent avec de nouveaux arrangements sociaux, tandis que les institutions sociales de l'ère des combustibles fossiles sont transformées pour une ère d'énergies renouvelables. Cette recherche explore cette proposition en examinant le phénomène récent de la démocratie énergétique de trois façons: 1) en identifiant et en se livrant de manière critique à la théorie implicite sous-jacente à la démocratie énergétique 2) en évaluant les façons dont la démocratie énergétique a ou n'a pas permis des changements dans les politiques publiques, et 3) en examinant les initiatives de la démocratie énergétique dans la pratique, pour comprendre comment les énergies renouvelables sont actuellement mises en œuvre à des fins de transformation sociale.Les systèmes énergétiques décentralisés, tels que ceux basés sur les énergies renouvelables, offrent une plus grande flexibilité et se prêtent plus facilement à une organisation décentralisée du pouvoir politique et économique, et vice versa, une relation décrite comme l'énergie-politique distribuée. Cette recherche identifie un ensemble de trois objectifs et 26 résultats escomptés pour la démocratie énergétique et présente un résumé descriptif de 22 instruments de politiques publiques associés à un programme de démocratie énergétique. Une évaluation de la congruence entre les résultats et les instruments montre qu'une attention relativement forte est portée à la récupération démocratique du secteur de l'énergie et une attention moindre à la résistance aux régimes énergétiques dominants. L'analyse finale montre qu'un ensemble de neuf initiatives pour la démocratie énergétique sont présentement opérationnelles dans l'est du Canada et dans le nord-est des États-Unis. La recherche synthétise un récit de transition partagé entre ces initiatives, mettant l'accent sur un engagement à un niveau élevé d'énergies renouvelables, un contrôle public et local sur les systèmes énergétiques, et un changement social plus large porté par la transition énergétique. Trois types distincts de démocratie énergétique et leurs récits associés sont proposés: «communautés locales et régionales», «partenariats publics» et «mouvements sociaux»; ceux-ci reflétent les différences liées à la définition des problèmes, à la forme et à la spécificité des solutions envisagées, à la position critique ou d'opposition, au positionnement historique, et à l'échelle, l'agence et le mode d'organisation sociale. Dans l'ensemble, cette recherche démontre que les systèmes d'énergies renouvelables peuvent changer et influence déjà la société actuelle de combustibles fossiles, mais un avenir de transformation énergétique exige des mobilisations sociopolitiques permanentes et à différentes échelles. Ce travail implique que si l'on souhaite un plus grand changement technologique, il faudra accorder plus d'attention au sélection et stabilisation d'institutions adaptées à des sociétés alimentées par les énergies renouvelables.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>As integrated sociotechnical systems, renewable energy systems co-evolve with new social arrangements, as social institutions of the fossil-fuel era are transformed for an age of renewables. This research explores this proposition by examining the recent phenomenon of energy democracy in three ways: 1) by drawing out and critically engaging with the implicit theory underlying energy democracy 2) by assessing the ways energy democracy has or has not enabled policy changes, and 3) by examining energy democracy initiatives in practice to understand how renewable energy is currently put to work for social transformation.Decentralized energy systems such as those based on renewables offer greater flexibility and more readily organize and enable distributed political and economic power, and vice versa, a relationship described as distributed energy-politics. The research proceeds to identify a set of three goals and 26 intended outcomes for energy democracy and presents a descriptive summary of 22 policy instruments associated with an energy democracy agenda. An assessment of congruence among outcomes and instruments finds more attention given to reclaiming the energy sector and less to resisting dominant energy regimes. The final analysis finds a set of nine initiatives for energy democracy presently operating in eastern Canada and the northeastern United States. The research synthesizes a shared transition narrative among these initiatives, converging around commitments to high levels of renewables, public and local control over energy systems, and broad social change through energy transition. Three distinct types of energy democracy and their associated narratives are proposed as "local and regional communities," "public partnerships," and "social movements," reflecting differences related to problem framings, form and specificity of solutions, critical or oppositional stance, historical positioning, and scale, agency and mode of social organization. Together this research demonstrates that renewable energy systems can, and already do, work to change a fossil-fuel society, yet a transformative energy future requires ongoing sociopolitical mobilizations across multiple levels of change. This work implies that if greater technological change is desired, more attention needs to be given to the selection and stabilization of the corresponding institutions necessary for societies powered by renewable energy. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter Gilbert Brown</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Jennie Stephens</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt99s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx59n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Natural Resource Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j764h"><ual:graduationDate>2019</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Nickel-oxide-based electrodes for energy storage applications</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gomez Vidales, Abraham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse présente une étude compréhensive de l'utilisation d'électrodes d'oxyde de nickel pour des applications de stockage d'énergie, en se concentrant spécifiquement sur des cathodes pour la production d'hydrogène par l'électrolyse de l'eau et des électrodes pour des supercondensateurs électrochimiques. L'objectif de cette recherche est de développer des matériaux à base de Ni-oxyde (Ni-Co-oxyde, Ni-Mo-oxyde, et Ni-Mo-Ir-oxyde) pour obtenir (i) une haute activité électrocatalytique et une stabilité à long terme dans la performance de la réaction de dégagement d'hydrogène (HER), et (ii) une haute capacité de stockage d'énergie dans une variété de conditions d'opération (c'est à dire, composition d'oxyde métallique, type d'électrolyte, pH, et température).Les différentes variétés de couches à base d'oxyde de nickel ont été fabriqué sur un substrat de titanium en utilisant une méthode de décomposition de sel thermique. Les couches ont été caractérisé par plusieurs techniques de caractérisation de surface, tel que la spectroscopie de photoélectrons X (XPS), la spectroscopie dispersive d'énergie (EDS), la diffractions de rayons X (XRD), et la microscopie électronique à balayage (SEM), pour connaître leur composition chimique, structure, et morphologie. En même temps, des techniques électrochimiques, tel que la polarisation linéaire de Tafel (LTP), voltampérométrie cyclique (CV), chronoampérométrie (CA), chronopotentiométrie (CP), et la décharge galvanostatique (GCD) ont été employé pour déterminer l'activité électrochimique, la surface active, la stabilité à long terme, et la capacité de charge-décharge des couches.En premier, l'activité électrocatalytique de cathodes de différentes variétés de Ni-Co-oxyde pour la HER a été étudié dans des médias acides et alcalins. Les électrodes se sont révélés être d'une structure semi-crystalline, donnant une morphologie de surface caractérisé par un facteur de rugosité plutôt élevé (jusqu'à 25). Le Ni0.2Co0.8-oxyde a été identifié comme le meilleure candidat de matériel d'électrode, ce qui est liée à l'effet de surface. De plus, il a montré une stabilité éléctrocatalytique beaucoup plus élevé que celle des autres matériaux. Cependant, son activité intrinsèque s'est révélé être bien plus basse que celle de l'échantillon de contrôle (un métal de nickel pure).Les propriétés électrocatalytiques de Ni-Mo-oxyde pour la production d'hydrogène dans des électrolytes acides, alcalis et neutres ont ensuite été étudiées. Ces oxydes ont démontré de meilleures performances que le nickel pur, ainsi qu'une stabilité sur toute l'échelle de pH, même pendant l'électrolyses à long terme dans des médias acides. La recherche a démontré que le revêtement le plus extrinsèquement actif était le Ni0.6Mo0.4-oxyde (dans les trois cas d'électrolytes). De plus, ce revêtement avait la plus haute activité intrinsèque dans l'électrolyte neutre. Dans les électrolytes acides et alcalis, le revêtement de Ni0.8Mo0.2-oxyde a démontré la plus haute activité intrinsèque. Cette performance supérieure a été attribuée à une augmentation de la surface électrochimiquement active, ainsi que l'activité électrochimique du matériel.Considérant les excellents résultats obtenus avec les électrodes de Ni-Mo-oxyde (spécifiquement le revêtement de Ni0.6-Mo0.4-oxiyde qui a démontré la meilleur performance) , l'ajout d'iridium (un excellent mais dispendieux catalyste) a été étudié pour la production d'hydrogène et le development d'electrodes de supercondensateurs.Dans tous les cas, les électrodes de Ni-Mo-Ir-oxyde ont démontré de meilleures performances dans des électrolytes acides comparées aux électrodes de nickel pur pour la RDH.Selon les résultats de la thèse présentée, il a été conclu que les électrodes à base d'oxyde de nickel représentent d'excellents candidats pour le stockage d'énergie électrochimique pour la production d'hydrogène à partir d'électrolyse de l'eau et pour le stockage d'électricité dans des supercondensateurs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This Ph.D. thesis presents a comprehensive study on the use of nickel-oxide-based electrodes for energy storage applications, focusing specifically on cathodes for production of hydrogen by water electrolysis and electrodes for electrochemical supercapacitors. The main objective of this research was to develop Ni-oxide-based materials (Ni-Co-oxide, Ni-Mo-oxide, and Ni-Mo-Ir-oxide) to achieve (i) high electrocatalytic activity and long-term performance stability in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and (ii) high energy storage capacity under various operating conditions (i.e. metal oxide composition, electrolyte type, pH, and temperature).The Ni-oxide based coatings of various compositions were fabricated on a titanium substrate through a thermal-salt decomposition method. The coatings were characterized by several surface-characterization techniques, such as X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM), to know their chemical composition, structure, and morphology. At the same time, electrochemical techniques such as linear Tafel polarization (LTP), cyclic voltammetry (CV), chronoamperometry (CA), chronopotentiometry (CP), and galvanostatic charge-discharge (GCD) were employed to determine their electrochemical activity, active surface area, long-term stability, and charge-discharge capacity.First, the electrocatalytic activity of Ni-Co-oxide cathodes of various compositions for HER in acidic and alkaline media was studied. The electrodes were found to be of a semi-crystalline structure, yielding a surface morphology characterized by a relatively high surface roughness factor (up to 25). The Ni0.2Co0.8-oxide was identified as the best electrode material candidate, due to the surface-area effect. Furthermore, it showed a significantly higher electrocatalytic stability compared to Ni. However, its intrinsic activity was found to be lower than that of the control sample (pure metal nickel).The electrocatalytic properties of Ni-Mo-oxides for hydrogen production in acidic, alkaline, and neutral electrolytes were studied next. These oxides showed a better performance than pure nickel, and they were stable in the whole pH scale, even during long-term electrolysis in an acidic medium. The most extrinsically active coating was found to be Ni0.6Mo0.4-oxide (in all three electrolytes), and this coating showed the highest intrinsic activity in the neutral electrolyte. In the acidic and alkaline electrolytes, the Ni0.8Mo0.2-oxide coating was found to be the most intrinsically active. This superior performance was attributed to an increase in the electrochemically active surface area, as well as the electrochemical activity of the material.Considering the excellent results obtained with the Ni-Mo-oxide electrodes (specifically the Ni0.6-Mo0.4-oxide coating, which was the best performing composition), the addition of iridium (an excellent but expensive catalyst) was investigated for hydrogen production and in the development of electrodes for supercapacitors.In all the cases, the Ni-Mo-Ir-oxide showed a better performance in an acidic medium when compared to nickel for HER. These results were attributed to both the increase of surface area and a possible modification of the electronic structure of the coatings. In addition, deactivation/re-activation experiments were done in the presence of the most common impurities found in commercial electrolytes during hydrogen production (Cu, Fe, Cu + Fe). These experiments showed that the Ni-Mo-Ir- electrodes were much more resistant to deactivation and can be, in addition, reactivated to a higher activity degree than pure nickel cathodes.Based on the results of this thesis, it was concluded that nickel-oxide-based electrodes are excellent candidates for alternative electrochemical energy storage systems (hydrogen production by water electrolysis and electricity storage in supercapacitors).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sasha Omanovic</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d82m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j764h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>