<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0g354g93j"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Parametric methods for nonlinear system identification</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kukreja, Sunil L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we have developed practical methods for the identification of linear, nonlinear and hybrid (multimode) systems which are applicable under relatively general conditions, i.e., when assumptions and conditions of the estimation technique are not violated. Since these algorithms were not designed specifically with any system(s) in mind, they should be applicable to experiments on a variety of systems in many different disciplines. Results demonstrate that the (polynomial) NARMAX (Nonlinear Autoregressive, Moving Average eXogenous) model class is useful for modeling the input-output behavior of a block-structured representation of two biological models. Extensive simulations demonstrated that our bootstrap model order selection (BMOS) and bootstrap structure detection (BSD) algorithms have a high probability of success for selecting the order and structure of NARMAX models and are robust in the presence of measurement noise. In addition, we illustrate that the NARMAX model structure is well suited for modeling dynamics of nonlinear hybrid systems and develop a modified extended least squares (MELS) algorithm to estimate coefficients of these systems. Application of this algorithm to a model of the vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR) showed that it is a robust method for estimating the coefficients of multimode systems.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kearney, Robert E.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Galiana, Henrietta L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w90t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g93j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z256s"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Solvent extraction and liquid membrane separation of rhodium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ashrafizadeh, Seyed Nezameddin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The aim of this work was to develop a viable solvent-extraction based system for the separation of rhodium (Rh) from aqueous chloride solutions. Ultimately, two different systems were developed. Kelex 100, a commercially available derivative of 8-hydroxyquinoline, was used as the extractant reagent in both of these systems. One of the systems involved the supported liquid membrane (SLM) extraction of Rh. In this system a very thin microporous "Gore-Tex" polymer sheet, impregnated with an organic solution of Kelex 100, served as the SLM. The other system involved the conversion of the chlorocomplexes of Rh to bromocomplexes prior to their solvent extraction with Kelex 100. The results of the lab-scale experiments using a SLM of Kelex 100 having a surface area of 44 cm2 are reported. The optimum conditions for Rh permeation were found as a feed solution of 2.5 M HCl and a strip solution of 0.1 M HCl. The SLM was quite stable at the optimum conditions with no sign of organic loss or membrane deterioration after 72 hours of operation. It was determined that the HCl activity gradient across the membrane acts as the driving force that "pumps" the non-aquated Rh chlorocomplexes against their concentration gradient. The mechanism of Rh permeation was the ion-pair formation between the protonated Kelex 100 and RhCl6 3- complexes. The rate of Rh permeation was in the order of 10-6 mol.m-2.s-1. The mechanism of HCl and H2O permeation, which were co-extracted along with Rh chlorocomplexes, were found to be the hydration of protons at the low feed acid region and the formation of microemulsions at the high feed acid region. The permeated acid and water were separated from the SLM receiving phase by contacting the latter phase with an organic solution of trioctylamine (TOA). The chlorocomplexes of Rh(III) and acid are readily extracted to the TOA organic phase and subsequently subjected to differential stripping with a concentrated solution of Cl- and a mild NaOH solution, respectively. By interfacing the TOA solvent extraction with the SLM of Kelex 100 highly concentrated solutions of Rh (at least 10 times the initial concentration) and raffinates essentially free of rhodium were produced. The UV-Visible investigations revealed that the bromocomplexes of Rh undergo aquation to a much lesser extent than that of the chlorocomplexes. The chlorocomplexes of Rh were converted to bromocomplexes by precipitating first the Na(NH4)2Rh(NO2)6 salt and subsequently dissolving that in an HBr solution. The newly formed bromocomplexes of Rh(III) responded very favorably to extraction with Kelex 100. Relatively high distribution coefficients, about 20, and very steep extraction isotherms were generated. The freshly loaded Kelex 100 organic was efficiently stripped upon contact with a strip solution of 6--8 M HCl and a contact time of 10--12 hours. The developed system shows high promise from a practical implementation point of view.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Demopoulos, G. P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns59g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z256s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zq16j"><ual:graduationDate>1994</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Low severity electrochemical liquefaction of wood</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Wang, Lijie, 1963-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Direct liquefaction of wood with aqueous HI solution to a wood oil product under low severity conditions, atmospheric pressure and low temperature around 125°C, was investigated in two stages. The first stage involved batch reactor studies. The wood-HI liquefaction reaction is fast, nearly complete in as little as 20s when the initial aqueous phase concentration is 57 wt% HI or greater. Yield of the char-type residue, a major problem in other liquefaction processes, is completely eliminated provided the final aqueous phase concentration is 50 wt% HI or above. The performance of this process with wood is better than would be predicted from experiments on the liquefaction of wood components determined separately. Removal of oxygen from polymeric wood components is accomplished with oxidation of I- to I2. The second stage tested a novel concept for closing the HI → I2 → HI loop, an electrochemical liquefaction reactor (ECLR) with liquefaction in the cathode cell where I2 is simultaneously reduced back to I- . Electrolysis of water at the anode generates O2 and the H+ required at the platinum cathode for HI regeneration. Without wood liquefaction, current efficiency for I2 reduction is 90--100% and I2 concentration can be maintained at about 0.1 M, which is about 10% of that without I2 reduction. Preliminary ECLR tests in batch and batchwise-continuous modes demonstrated simultaneous wood liquefaction and electrochemical reduction of I2 in the presence of the viscous wood oil. Also the iodine content of the crude wood oil is thereby reduced by about 60%, where this limit is imposed by the strong physical association between I2 and various functional groups in the product. Generation of H2, the competitive reaction, can be avoided. ECLR characteristics were determined from a continuous run in a sealed reactor at a steady aqueous phase concentration of 55 wt% HI with a cathode current density of 0.81 A/cm2 at a cell voltage of 6 V. Carbon base yields were 84.2% crude wood oil product, 4.9% methyl iodide from the lignin methoxy groups and no production of the char-type residue common to other biomass liquefaction processes. Of the I2 produced, 93% would be reduced to HI, the other 7% being I2 associated physically with the product. Of the H+ generated at the anode, about half is used for HI regeneration and half for electrochemical liquefaction reactions as reflected by the exceptionally high levels of hydrogen retention and oxygen removal of the wood oil relative to the wood, above 85% in both cases.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Douglas, W. J. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs59f.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq16j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture, Wood Technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Chemical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq811km358"><ual:graduationDate>1995</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Two-mode optical fiber sensors for concrete structures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lisboa, Osni</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>An optical fiber bending sensor and a quasi-distributed optical fiber sensor, where isolated sensing regions can be designed to sense strain, bending, etc., are developed as sensor candidates for smart civil engineering materials and structures. Both sensors use two-mode fibers. With the same two-mode fibers, acousto-optic frequency shifters are developed as the main components to accomplish these sensors. Elliptical-core two-mode fibers are chosen to improve the stability and sensitivity of the sensors. A perturbation theory approach is used to investigate the sensing mechanism of the bending sensor. A system to simultaneously measure all the sensing regions of the quasi-distributed sensor is also demonstrated. Because conventional polymer-based fiber coatings often do not adequately protect the fibers themselves nor the fiber sensors during their installations into the concrete or metallic structures, two different processing methods are introduced. They provide superior protection to the fibers and sensors for the installation. The first method is to coat the fiber with a thick metallic layer (aluminum or tin) using a continuous casting process. Coating thicknesses of 0.5 to 1.5 mm and length up to 3 m are presented. Using a birefrigent fiber coated with such a thick metallic layer, a sensor for dynamic load or pressure was also implemented. The second method uses the thermal spray technology for directly embedding optical fibers and sensors into or surface attaching them onto concrete and metallic plates. Finally, a sol-gel based process is used for coating optical fibers with piezoelectric lead zirconate titanate films. Coating thicknesses up to 120 mum have been achieved. Piezoelectric-coated fibers can be used as in-line optical fiber signal processing components for various fiber sensors relevant for smart structure applications. As an example, an in-line fiber phase modulator is also developed. Theoretical analysis is carried out based on an axial-symmetrical multi-layer structure operated in a radially resonant configuration. The phase modulation induced by radial acoustic modes excited on optical fibers, with a coating thickness of 120 mum and length of 5.8 cm, ranges from 100 kHz to 25 MHz.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jen, Cheng-kuei</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj85h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km358</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zw12n"><ual:graduationDate>1996</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Control of ITH percussive longhole drilling in hard rock</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Amjad, Muhammad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis aims to develop a comprehensive strategy for automatic control of the ITH percussive drilling process. Such automation would provide the benefits of improved productivity and quality in terms of penetration rate and hole deviation, as well as enhanced hole quality and machine life. Analysis of field data acquired from drilling experiments performed at INCO's Little Stobie Mine is presented. As a result of this analysis, a control algorithm is formulated to enhance the drilling process efficiency. This algorithm calculates the specific energy (SE) of the rock and adjusts the applied feed force based on this SE value, using a relationship obtained from the field data analysis. A model of the percussive drilling process is developed and simulated in software. The proposed control algorithm is tested through simulations on this simulated drilling process. The results of the simulation show a significant increase in efficiency of the drilling process. As a result of vibration data analysis it is concluded that vibration should be controlled through an improved design of the shock-absorber, rather than through drilling variables. A detailed shock-absorber test data analysis is therefore presented. Recommendations for design changes in the shock-absorber are also given. Deviation analysis is also presented in the thesis, which shows a poor correlation between the machine variables and the hole deviation data. Hence, it is recommended that deviation be controlled by steering. An innovative guided drilling mechanism for controlling the hole deviation is also proposed. This mechanism consists of an eccentric ITH percussive hammer with controlled rotational speed, which can be employed as an actuator to steer the drill string in a desired direction without using any down hole instrumentation. Modelling and simulation analysis of this system is also presented.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Daneshmend, Laeeque K.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw28k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw12n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mining</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9p290c194"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic analysis of the yeast endo-exonuclease : implications of its involvement in DNA double-strand break repair</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Asefa, Benyam</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Double-strand breaks (DSBs) are one of the most lethal threats to genomic integrity. In the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae, double-strand breaks are primarily repaired via the homologous recombination repair pathway. While the mechanisms underlying this pathway have been generally characterized, the early steps leading to commitment of DSBs to homologous recombination repair are as yet unclear. In particular, it has been shown that the exonuclease processing of DSBs is a critical step prior to strand invasion of a homologous template. Endo-exonucleases represent a class of nucleases that have been linked to recombinational repair processes in various organisms. Early on, a degradative role was ascribed to the bacterial recBCD endo-exonuclease in processing DSBs in a 5' to 3' directionality prior to recA-mediated homologous recombination in E. coli. However, the nuclease responsible for this nucleolytic processing has yet to be identified in yeast. In this dissertation, I demonstrate that RNC1 is a candidate gene that encodes a nuclease with characteristics similar to previously identified endo-exonucleases, and that RNC1 is implicated in homologous recombination repair of DSBs. While the rnc1 null mutant is 10-fold more sensitive to persistent DSB induction than wild-type, a highly lethal rad52 null mutation is suppressed in an rnc1 knockout, indicating that RNC1 acts at an earlier step in the homologous recombination repair pathway than RAD52. Furthermore, in the absence of RNC1, the non-homologous end-joining pathway, mediated by the KU80 gene product, appears to play a more dominant role in repairing DSBs. Moreover, a ku80 rnc1 double mutant is hypersensitized to DSB induction. Biochemical analysis of the purified RNC1 protein revealed that it has endonuclease activity on single-strand DNA as well as processive exonuclease activity on double-strand DNA with a 5' to 3' directionality. In vivo, this exonuclease activity was implicated in the processing of DSBs prior to repair. Our findings show that RNC1 possesses nucleolytic activities characteristic of previously identified endo-exonucleases, and confirm its role in the homologous recombination repair pathway. Intriguingly, RNC1 was also shown to exhibit methyltransferase activity which directs the modification of a specific base, m5U 54, in elongator tRNA. While the biological significance of this activity is as yet unclear, it is attributable to a domain in the RNC1 protein separate from that engaging in DNA repair processes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chow, Terry</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9354657.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c194</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8910jw293"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development of motor behaviors and activity patterns of spinal neurons in the zebrafish embryo</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Saint-Amant, Louis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The development of spinal circuits underlying motor behaviors was examined in zebrafish. Zebrafish embryos showed three sequential, stereotyped behaviors: a transient period of spontaneous coiling contractions, followed by touch-evoked rapid coils, and swimming. Lesioning the hindbrain eliminated swimming and touch responses, but not the spontaneous contractions. The first (spontaneous) behavior was chosen for further analysis in order to characterize the underlying circuit. In vivo patch clamp recordings were obtained from identified spinal neurons. These neurons showed periodic depolarizations that triggered rhythmic bursts of action potentials with a frequency and duration that were consistent with those of the spontaneous contractions. As with the behavior, transecting the spinal cord at the hindbrain border did not affect the rhythmic activity patterns of the neurons. Surprisingly the contractions and the periodic depolarizations were insensitive to both general and specific blockade of synaptic transmission. The periodic depolarizations were suppressed by heptanol and by intracellular acidification treatments that are known to uncouple gap junctions, indicating that electrotonic synapses could underlie network synchronization during the earliest motor behavior. Paired recordings were obtained from identified spinal neurons. These showed that active ipsilateral neurons were electrically coupled in a simple network consisting initially of motoneurons and only three types of interneurons. Therefore, this early spinal circuit consists of rhythmically active and electrically coupled neurons. Furthermore, this circuit is also initially independent of the main neurotransmitter systems, sensory inputs, and descending hindbrain projections. The descending projections are required later in development for the onset of touch responses and swimming.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>apeau, Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c47g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw293</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Motor neurons</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zebra danio -- Embryos -- Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Motor ability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zebra danio -- Nervous system</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk307"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Identification of bacterial genes regulated by the Escherichia coli transposable phage ner protein homologue, NlpSfs 7, a histone-like protein</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rongy, Manuelle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>DNA-binding proteins such as IHF play a crucial role in bacterial survival. IHF is involved in many biological processes in E. coli and possibly in other bacteria. It was hypothesized that another protein, Nlp, belongs to a family of conserved DNA-binding proteins, and this protein was shown to be non-essential for cell viability, but highly conserved among the Enterobacteriaceae. As Nlp appears to play a role in gene regulation, we wished to identify all Nlp-regulated genes. nlp was cloned into pBAD18-Kan generating pMM5, where Nlp expression was under the control of arabinose. Strain LF20300 was transformed with pMM5 and then lysogenized with the lacZ transcriptional fusion reporter vector Mu dI to create a library of approximately 10,000 clones. This library was screened on plates containing either glucose/X-gal or arabinose/X-gal in order to identify genes whose expression was altered upon production of Nlp. Two clones, 90-6 and 205-15, were identified which displayed increased beta-galactosidase expression in the presence of Nlp. Further studies with these two clones have shown the insertion of a single Mu dI phage within clone 90-6 and a double insertion within clone 205-15. Cloning and sequencing of one of the Mu dI insertions of strain 205-15 has identified the yqhG gene as being one of the genes whose expression may be altered in the presence of Nlp.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DuBow, M. S.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r30r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk307</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w402r"><ual:graduationDate>2002</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Laws</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Comparative Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>L'evolution du controle judiciaire de la competence d'attribution des tribunaux administratifs</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Perrault, Gabrielle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the last fifteen years, the Supreme Court of Canada operated a substantial move regarding judicial review of administrative action. It abandoned the formal approach which rested upon a jurisdictional/non jurisdictional qualification in order to show more deference towards specialized agencies. The development of a pragmatic and functional analysis has led to the determination of appropriate standards of review for each decision. This thesis is divided in three parts. The first one is dedicated to the study of the fundamental principles underlying judicial review; the second part starts by examining the ultra vires doctrine and then proceeds to describe the different steps which led to a unified theory focussing on the determination of the appropriate standard of review. Finally, the last part looks at the way courts evaluate the tribunal's relative expertise and at the phenomenon of interpretive pluralism.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Morissette, Yves-Marie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v020h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w402r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3As4655j25d"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Screening methods to identify stereoselective hydrolases for synthetic applications : empirical rules to predict the enantiopreference of aspergillus niger lipase ; novel spectrophotometric assays to rapidly measure the activity and stereoselectivity of hydrolases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Janes, Lana Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Although chemists often exploit the high stereo selectivity of hydrolytic enzymes to produce pure enantiomers, the difficulty in selecting the best hydrolase from hundreds of commercial hydrolases and microorganisms remains a major deterrent to their wider use. Moreover, the emerging ability to create large libraries of recombinant enzymes demands fast and simple selection methods. The current method of selection is time-consuming because it requires carrying out small-scale reactions and measuring enantiomeric purity. This thesis focuses on the development of methods to speed up this selection process. We first report the development of empirical substrate models for Aspergillus niger lipase (ANL) to predict which enantiomer of a racemate reacts faster. For secondary alcohols, a rule based upon the size of the substituents at the stereocentre of a substrate previously proposed for other lipases and esterases works for ANL. Surprisingly, a rule based upon charge rather than size of the substituents can predict the preferred enantiomer of alpha-amino acids. These qualitative rules aid in the design of new synthetic applications of ANL. Next, we report the development of a spectropholometric assay to accurately but rapidly measure the enantioselectivity of a hydrolase towards a target substrate without measuring enantiomeric purity called "quick E". The initial rates of hydrolysis of each enantiomer of a substrate are separately measured relative to a reference compound. The ratio of the two relative rates yields the enantioselectivity. We first developed this method for chromogenic esters. Next, to extend quick E to non-chromogenic esters, we developed a pH indicator assay to quantitatively detect ester hydrolysis. We optimized this method for screening in 96-well plates for speed. Finally, we apply these spectrophotometric assays to solve a synthetic problem. Dioxolane nucleosides are powerful pharmacological agents used in the treatment of HIV and hepatitis-B virus but their syntheses require expensive and tedious silica gel chromatography to separate mixtures of diastereomers. Using the quick E method, we rapidly identify two hydrolases that produce the desired dioxolane diastereorner in good yield and excellent diastereomeric excess (&gt;98%). Overall, our screening methods are simpler to perform than traditional methods and require significantly less substrate and hydrolase (mug quantities per measurement) without compromising sensitivity and quantitativeness.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kazlauskas, Romas J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r311.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j25d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry, Organic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atx31qk41h"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Molecular regulation of interleukin-8 in human colonic epithelial cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yu, Yi, 1965-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Interleukin-8 is a chemokine which is chemotactic for neutrophils and T-lymphocytes and plays a crucial role in the pathogenesis of inflammatory bowel disease. Intestinal mucosal epithelial cells produce IL-8 in response to pathogens which mediates bidirectional communication between pathogen and host. The objective of this study was to investigate the molecular mechanisms involved in IL-8 gene regulation in T84 human colonic epithelial cells. To determine if IL-8 plays a role in the pathogenesis of intestinal amebiasis, the effect of Entamoeba histolytica on IL-8 gene expression was investigated. E. histolytica secreted components enhanced IL-8 mRNA expression and protein production in the absence of amebae-enterocyte contact. The proinflammatory cytokines IL-1beta and TNF-alpha were not involved in IL-8 protein production. As PGE2 is central in mucosal inflammation, the effect of PGE2 on IL-8 gene expression was determined. Using purified PGE2 and PGE2 receptor agonists, it was shown that PGE2 coupled to the EP4 receptor and triggered cAMP-dependent PKA signaling which upregulated IL-8 mRNA expression at the posttranscriptional level. Elevation of [Ca 2+]i from intracellular Ca2+ stores by A23187 or thapsigargin stimulated IL-8 mRNA transcription and IL-8 protein production through the activation of calcineurin. Moreover, IL-8 3'-UTR had a strong suppressive effect on CAT reporter gene expression in COS7 cells by reducing its mRNA level. A unique fragment (nt 2387-2743) containing AU rich elements was shown to attenuate CAT mRNA expression by destabilizing the transcripts. Secondary structure but not AU rich elements played a major role in CAT mRNA turnover.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chadee, Kris</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b59n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk41h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Genetic regulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Prostaglandins E -- Synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inflammatory bowel diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interleukin-8</dc:subject><dc:subject>Entamoeba histolytica</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Az029p632c"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Institute of Parasitology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic variation and multiple mechanisms of anthelmintic resistance in Haemonchus contortus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Blackhall, William James</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Anthelmintic treatment of livestock is an important aspect of the control of gastrointestinal parasites. Resistance to anthelmintics is common, and an understanding of resistance requires knowledge of an anthelmintic's mode(s) of action and mechanism(s) of resistance. The parasitic nematode, Haemonchus contortus, has developed resistance to benzimidazoles and avermectins/milbemycins. Proposed mechanisms of resistance are here supported by genetic changes observed in genes whose protein products are believed to interact with these anthelmintics. Statistically significant differences in allele frequencies were observed between untreated and ivermectin- and moxidectin-treated strains in a gene encoding a putative glutamate-gated chloride channel alpha subunit, a proposed target of avermectins/milbemycins. One allele appeared to be associated with resistance. Similar changes in allele frequencies in the same strains occurred in a gene encoding a subunit of a gamma-aminobutyric acid receptor. Significant differences in allele frequencies of a gene encoding a P-glycoprotein were found in strains of H. contortus treated with ivermectin and moxidectin compared to derived, untreated strains. In all treated strains, one allele appeared to be associated with resistance. Similarly, allele frequencies of this gene were significantly different between a cambendazole-treated strain and its derived, untreated strain. These results implicate glutamate-gated chloride channels and gamma-aminobutyric acid receptors in mechanisms of resistance to avermectins/milbemycins and implicate P-glycoprotein in a mechanism of resistance to avermectins/milbemycins and benzimidazoles in H. contortus.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beech, R. N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh173.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p632c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Drug resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sheep -- Parasites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Haemonchus contortus</dc:subject><dc:subject>P-glycoprotein</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ivermectin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benzimidazoles</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab5644t243"><ual:graduationDate>1999</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Music</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An application of Max/MSP in the field of live electro-acoustic music : a case study</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Protsidym, Oles</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>For many years the integration of real-time digital audio signal processing with dynamic control has been one of the most significant issues facing live electro-acoustic music. While real-time electro-acoustic music systems began to appear as early as the 1970's, for approximately two decades a lack of portability and prohibitive cost restricted their availability to a limited number of electronic music studios and research centers. The rapid development of computer and music technologies in the 1990's enabled desktop-based real-time digital audio signal processing, making it available for general use. The introduction of the Max/MSP programming language in the 1990's ushered in a new era in electro-acoustic music by bringing a new unified environment for real-time digital signal processing and dynamic control to a wide audience. The potential of the Max/MSP programming environment for applications to live electro-acoustic music is the subject of this thesis. A prototype example of a real-time electro-acoustic music system based on Max/MSP is developed and discussed.* *This dissertation includes a CD that is compound (contains both a paper copy and a CD as part of the dissertation). The CD requires the following applications: Mac OS 8.5; Opcode Max 3.5; Opcode OMS 3.6.2; Cycling '73 MSP; Microsoft Word 98; &amp; Finale 3.5.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Pennycook, Bruce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr575.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t243</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Computer music</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0v838222s"><ual:graduationDate>1997</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Central serotonin (5-HT) neurons in the control of the cerebral circulation : anatomical basis and functional receptors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cohen, Zvi, 1967-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Serotonin (5-hydroxytryptamine, 5-HT) is known to influence cerebrovascular functions such as local cerebral blood flow (CBF) and blood brain barrier (BBB) permeability, and has been implicated in cerebrovascular diseases. The present study used a multifaceted approach to determine the distribution, density and origin of the 5-HT innervation of blood vessels at the base of the brain and overlying the cerebral cortex as well as those embedded in the cortical parenchyma. In addition, the type(s) of 5-HT receptor(s) present on intracortical blood vessels as well as their precise cellular localization within the vessel wall was investigated. Firstly, in extracerebral blood vessels, we showed that perivascular serotonergic nerve fibers, immunocytochemically identified for the 5-HT synthesizing enzyme, tryptophan hydroxylase (TPH), are greatly reduced following removal of the superior cervical ganglia, but not after specific lesion of the ascending 5-HT fibers originating from the brainstem raphe nuclei. In addition, we demonstrated that the distribution pattern of TPH-immunolabelled perivascular fibers differed from those containing noradrenaline (identified by dopamine-beta-hydroxylase). These results suggest the existence of a subset of distinct 5-HT nerve fibers in extracerebral arteries and that the serotonergic innervation; most probably, arises from the superior cervical ganglia or a structure closely related to it. Secondly, in investigating the serotonergic input to the intraparenchymal microcirculation at the ultrastructural level, we found that central TPH-containing nerve terminals are intimately associated with intraparenchymal blood vessels and that these neurovascular associations were closer and/or more frequent in brain regions where manipulations of the brainstem raphe neurons elicited significant changes, as compared to relatively unresponsive cerebral area. These associations frequently involved the perivascular astrocytes, suggesting a possible intermediary role for these non-neuronal cells in the control of microvascular functions. Furthermore, the associations between 5-HT-synthesizing nerve terminals with the microvascular bed appeared relatively selective since neurovascular noradrenaline nerve terminals in the same cortical subdivision did not share the same characteristics in terms of frequency, intimacy or distribution around the vessel walls. Finally, in an attempt to identify the exact site(s) of action of 5-HT on the blood vessels, we characterized, via reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction and second messenger assays, the 5-HT receptor(s) present on human intracortical blood vessels as well as in cell cultures of human brain astrocytes and of endothelial and smooth muscle cells of micro-vascular origin. We reported the differential expression not only of messages but also of functional proteins for specific 5-HT receptor subtypes in the different cellular compartments of the blood vessel wall; a finding fully compatible with the ability of 5-HT to regulate microvascular perfusion and BBB permeability. Altogether, the present thesis provides an anatomical substrate for the 5-HT-mediated responses in the microvascular bed. It demonstrates that the indoleamine can affect the microvascular bed by interacting either directly with endothelial and/or smooth muscle cells or indirectly with the perivascular astroglial cells suggesting that the neuronal-glial-vascular triad most likely constitutes the functional unit in the regulation of microvascular related responses. These studies are likely to contribute significantly to our understanding of the relationships between 5-HT and non-neuronal vascular and astroglial cells as they relate to the mechanisms involved in the regulation of CBF and BBB.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hamel, Edith</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm66n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838222s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000001804"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Surgical Research</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Platelet activating factor's role in regulating apoptosis in immature B cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Toledano, Baruch Joseph</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>B lymphocyte development is characterized by deletion, via apoptosis, of immature cells that are stimulated via the BCR in the absence of a second signal. We have investigated whether platelet-activating factor, a potent B lymphocyte activator, can provide a complementary signal with BCR ligation in order to abrogate apoptosis. Cross-linking of the sIgM on Ramos B lymphoblastoid cells using anti-IgM antibodies (2mug/ml) caused PCD in 34 +/- 5.4% of the cells. Co-incubation of PAF (10-7M) with alphaIgM led to a significant decrease in apoptotic cells as measured by DNA laddering and TUNEL assay (13.8 +/- 3%). The effect of PAF was dose dependent (10-7--10-9M), and was inhibited by the specific PAF receptor antagonist, WEB 2170. PAF protected cells from the effect of alphaIgM for up to one hour after it was added. alphaIgM-induced PCD in Ramos cells is blocked by catalase, and therefore PCD is caused in part by the production of toxic hydroxyl radicals from hydrogen peroxide. We investigated the action of PAF on markers of intracellular oxidation. H2O2 in low doses induced apoptosis, via production of OH· radicals. PAF inhibited H2O2 induced apoptosis in Ramos cells; it also attenuated H2O 2 and alphaIgM-mediated increases in hydroxyl radical (OH· ) as measured by the oxidation of 2',7 '-dichlorofluorescein diacetate (DCFH-DA) to DCF, and blocked the depletion of GSH induced by alphaIgM. PAF maintained IgM secretion, greatly inhibited by incubation with alphaIgM alone.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jensen, G.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mazer, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s411z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000001804</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nj82c"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of strategic influences on orienting visual attention to spatial locations : a developmental perspective</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hayduk, Steven J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Attentional orienting involves two neuroanatomically and functionally separate components, the reflexive and voluntary attentional sub-systems, which interact to orient attention on the environment. Three experiments, in which a cueing paradigm was used, examined reflexive and voluntary orienting over later childhood development (i.e., 8--14 years old) in order to explore the mechanisms underlying the development of the control of attentional orienting. Experiments 1 and 2 explored whether reflexive and voluntary orienting develop in parallel, and examined the influence of cue predictability on attentional orienting during development. Experiment 3 explored the role of explicit instructions in the influence of cue predictability on voluntary and reflexive orienting. The results indicate that the development of attentional orienting over later childhood is a reflection of the operation of an underlying mechanism, general developmental changes in speed of processing. Apart from this mechanism, the efficiency of attentional orienting remains the same across age. In addition, the influence of cue predictability on attentional orienting reflects the operation of a low-level mechanism which operates independently of strategic influences; this mechanism may be covariance detection and judgment. The implications of these conclusions for modeling attentional orienting, and the development thereof, are considered.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruck, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r016g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj82c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Visual perception in children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Attention in children</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqn59q573z"><ual:graduationDate>1998</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Anthropology as a metaphor for knowing in Anne Carson's poetry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Poutanen, Minna J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis examines the trope of anthropology in the Canadian poet Anne Carson's work. This trope functions as an extended metaphor to describe the study of cultures, texts, and the "alien countries" of other human souls. Anne Carson rejects anthropological practices that aim at the "invasion" of the other, and associates such practices with the actions of seeing, projecting and even "devouring." Instead she favours anthropological approaches that foster mutual "encounters", such approaches being typically charged with the actions of listening, absorbing and breathing. This distinction becomes crucial when we consider its implications for reading and writing about Anne Carson's work. Can a reader encounter rather than invade a poem? What meaning can the reader find in such an encounter if, unlike the practice of anthropology, it is undertaken in written form and in isolation? Might we conclude that all responses to poetry emerge not from the fullness and immediacy of an encounter, but precisely from the impossibility of ever undergoing the experience of such an encounter?</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cooke, Nathalie</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407z85k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q573z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Carson, Anne, 1950- -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xw70z"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Post-elastic behavior of bolted connections in wood</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kharouf, Nourhene</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A nonlinear finite element model is developed to study the behavior of single- and double-bolted timber connections with relatively low member thickness-to-fastener diameter ratios. These structural joints tend to fail in a brittle fashion. The established model is capable of predicting the post-elastic deformations of the connections locally and globally, and the unequal load fractions transferred by each bolt in a two-fastener connection. The ADINA software package is used to generate the model. The problem presents two types of non-linearity. The first is due to geometric effects caused by increased sliding contact between the bolts and the oversized holes in the wood member. Contact is simulated using the Lagrange Multiplier algorithm available in ADINA. This algorithm enforces the compatibility of surface displacements at the wood member which is the contactor surface, and Coulomb frictional conditions over the contact segments, with a coefficient of friction of 0.7. The second non-linearity results from the material post-elastic behavior adjacent to the contact points. A plasticity-based compressive constitutive material model is developed to represent wood as elasto-plastic orthotropic according to the Hill yield criterion in regions of bi-axial compression. Linear elastic orthotropic response is applied otherwise. The model is incorporated as a user-supplied material model of ADINA to carry out the analysis. The performance of the program and the effectiveness of the elasto-plastic material model are first verified with examples from the literature. Thereafter, numerical simulations of the post-elastic deformations of one- and two-bolt connections are compared to experimental results from tensile tests undertaken on glued-laminated timber connections with stocky bolts and subject to monotonic loading. Characterization tests are undertaken to obtain stiffness and strength for compression and tension parallel and perpendicular to grain, and shear, required as input in the new material model. Five configurations of single-bolt connections and four configurations of double-bolt connections have been tested with different combinations of end distance, edge distance, and spacing between bolts. Reasonable agreement is found between numerical and experimental load vs. strains obtained using single axis strain gages and strain rosettes mounted in regions of stress concentrations. The model is capable of tracing the post-elastic global deformation as obtained from experimental load vs. displacements of LVDT's mounted on specimens. The non-linearity of these load-slip curves is primarily caused by the inelastic wood deformation beneath the bolts at low load levels. This behavior explains the redistribution of load proportions among the bolts in a double-bolt connection. Under test configurations forces are unequally shared between the bolts even at the ultimate load. As a consequence, joint capacity as estimated with the proposed elasto-plastic material model is bounded by the so-called European Yield Model, which assumes equal load distribution among the bolts at ultimate, and the linear elastic model. Observed shear-out brittle failures of wood bolted connections are believed to be caused by excessive combined shear and tension perpendicular to grain along the sides of the contact zone.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>McClure, Ghyslaine</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Smith, Ian</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm65g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw70z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engineering, Civil</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ak643b274r"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Religious Studies</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A genealogy of a German-Lutheran two-kingdoms concept : from a German theology of the status quo to an East German theology of critical solidarity</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kline, Scott Travis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation traces the social-theological history of a German-Lutheran two-kingdoms concept---an often ambiguous social-ethical theory used by German-Lutheran theologians to interpret their social world and to define the relational boundaries for the church's existence in society. This study consists of three parts, each of which represents a fundamental rupture in the German social order: Part one examines the formation of a two-kingdoms doctrine in the modern world. The opening chapter (chapter two) establishes Martin's Luther's use of a two-kingdoms hermeneutic as way to challenge late-medieval Catholic Church authority and to empower ("sacralize") the social sphere. Chapter three surveys the work of German-Lutheran theologians who found in Luther's two-kingdoms concept a model that corresponded to the modern public-private social structure. The intersection of Luther's concept and modern social theory enabled theologians to understand the social, economic, and political changes taking place in Germany and, wittingly or unwittingly, to validate the status quo. Part two analyzes various applications and critiques of the two-kingdoms doctrine in Germany from 1919 to 1945. Chapter four focuses on the efforts of Emanuel Hirsch, Paul Althaus, Paul Tillich, and Karl Barth to construct a theology that addressed the crises of modernity: the loss of national identity, the failure of post-Enlightemnent rationalism, and the collapse of traditional political structures. Chapter five examines the work of Dietrich Bonhoeffer, who developed a critical two-kingdoms perspective to (re)define the ethical relationship between the "church for others" and the "world come of age." Part three considers the reception of the two-kingdoms doctrine in the East German church (1949--1990). The objective of chapter six is to illustrate the various ways in which theologians in the German Democratic Republic nuanced a two-kingdoms concept to make sense of the church's missionary task in socialism. This chapter also demonstrates the links between Bonhoeffer's ethic of responsibility and an East German theological ethic of critical solidarity---a social-ethical theory articulated by pastors and theologians such as Bishop Albrecht Schonherr and Heino Falcke. This study concludes with a brief discussion of the two-kingdoms doctrine's capacity to protect and to resist the status quo.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Gregory</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s21c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b274r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Germany (East) -- Church history</dc:subject><dc:subject>Luther, Martin, 1483-1546</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church and state -- Germany (East)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lutheran Church -- Doctrines</dc:subject><dc:subject>Church and state -- Lutheran Church</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524jq43q"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Electoral despotism in Kenya : land, patronage and resistance in the multi-party context</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Klopp, Jacqueline M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Africa, the new electoral freedoms of the 1990s often ushered in not less but more violence and corruption. Somewhat paradoxically, democratization appeared to lead to greater despotism. Current theories of democratic transitions fail to adequately explain this negative "fall out". On the one hand, by focusing on formal institutional change, most transitions theory marginalizes the "informal" politics of patronage and violence. On the other hand, theorists of "informal" politics tend to assume that formal institutional change does not impinge on patrimonial dynamics. This thesis explains how the advent of electoral freedom challenges patrimonialism and, in the process, deepens local despotism. By a careful look at the Kenyan case, this thesis argues that the re-introduction of multiple political parties posed a genuine challenge to highest level patronage networks. This challenge consisted of "patronage inflation": competitive elections escalated demands for and promises of patronage just as international conditionalities and economic difficulties led to a decline in traditional supplies of patronage. Further, with multiple political parties, voters gained bargaining power to demand both resources and accountability. A critique of patrimonialism emerged into the public realm, particularly from those who had lost out in the spoils system, the growing numbers of poor and landless. These challenges were met by counter-strategies on the part of those most set to lose by a turnover in elections. With the introduction of alternative political parties, President Moi and key patronage bosses instigated localized but electorally beneficial violence in the form of "ethnic clashes". In their struggle to maintain patrimonial dominance, they also increasingly turned to less internationally scrutinized public lands as a patronage resource, leading to increasing and increasingly violent "land grabbing". This triggered counter mobilizations which aimed at reasserting local co</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Oxhorn, Philip</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn417.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq43q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Democracy -- Kenya</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kenya -- Politics and government -- 1978-2002</dc:subject><dc:subject>Patronage, Political -- Kenya</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qt65f"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Serotonin-mediated activation of rapamycin-sensitive S6 kinase-S6 ribosomal protein signal transduction pathway in synaptosomes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Khan, Asad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The restriction of long-term synaptic changes to specific synapses can be explained by the formation of synaptic tags that specifically mark activated synapses. Rapamycin and inhibitors of translation block the maintenance of synapse specific facilitation in Aplysia sensory to motor neuron synapses by inhibiting a signal transduction pathway that is involved in regulating the phosphorylation of translational regulators. The phosphorylation and subsequent activation of S6 kinase is an important target of rapamycin. Aplysia S6 kinase and its substrate S6 ribosomal protein were cloned to test whether rapamycin blocks synapse specific facilitation in Aplysia by inhibiting the phosphorylation and activation of S6 kinase. Serotonin, which induces synapse specific facilitation increased phosphorylation of S6 kinase in a rapamycin-sensitive manner at Thr399 in Aplysia synaptosomes. The serotonin induced phosphorylation of S6 kinase at Thr399 was dependant on protein kinase A (PKA) and protein kinase C (PKC), was independent of phosphoinositide-3 kinase and was occluded by the phosphatase inhibitor calyculin-A. Serotonin also increased S6 kinase activity and led to both, a rapamycin-sensitive increase in phosphorylation and increase in the level of S6 ribosomal protein in synaptosomes. The serotonin induced increase in the levels of S6 ribosomal protein in synaptosomes was due to a rapamycin sensitive increase in translation/stabilization of the S6 ribosomal protein. These results provide important insight into a pathway through which the levels of translation factors may be increased specifically at activated synapses leading to the formation of a long-term synaptic tag.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Sossin, Wayne</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf483.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt65f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ahm50tt33x"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effect of artificial and natural plant structures on host searching behavior of the egg parasitoid Trichogramma SPP. (Hymenoptera:Trichogrammatidae)</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gingras, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Differences in plant structure and host abundance, distribution and density within and between plants may affect host finding success of searching parasitoids. The main objective of this research consisted in developing and validating a model that can predict parasitism by Trichogramma evanescens on various plant structures. Also, we evaluated the effect of both artificial and natural plant structures on host encountering success and on searching behavior of two species of Trichogramma. Size (S), heterogeneity (H) and connectivity (C) define plant structure. The development of the model of parasitism was based on laboratory experiments using three dimensional artificial plants of different combinations of S, H and C. The model was then validated with experiments, within greenhouse, using natural cruciferous plants of different structures. Significant regressions of observed values of parasitism as a function of those predicted by the model were obtained. The effect of plant structure on two species of Trichogramma was studied by using three species of Lepidoptera and three structurally different but closely related crucifers. Also the distribution pattern of parasitized eggs according to leaf side and plant height was characterized. A repeated measure ANOVA in time where plant ages defined the repeated measures showed that all three main effects (plant, host, parasitoid) had significant effect on parasitism and only the parasitoid x plant structure interaction was significant. Mean percent of parasitism was higher on cabbage, intermediate on broccoli and lower on Brussels sprouts whereas cabbage appeared to be intermediate in plant structure, broccoli appeared to be the most simple and Brussels sprouts the most complex plant structure. On simple plant structure, both wasp species performed well on the three varieties of plant but T. evanescens outperformed T. pretiosum more often on the various plant structures. A doubly repeated measures ANOVA in space revealed significant effects of leaf side and plant height on parasitism, being greatest under leaf surface and at the base of the plant. The interaction between those two variables was not significant. The effect of plant structure on searching behavior of T. evanescens was determined by direct observation of individual females searching on simple and complex plant structures during 1 hour. Time, frequence and sequence associated to activities and plant parts explored were obtained and analyzed. Plant structure had significant effect on time budget associated to activities (walking, resting, flying) and plant parts explored. This study demonstrates that plant structure mediates ecological interactions by affecting host finding success and this may have important implications in population dynamics, evolution of hosts and parasitoids but also in biological control programs.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Boivin, Guy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr661.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt33x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cruciferae -- Diseases and pests -- Biological control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trichogramma evanescens -- Behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cruciferae -- Anatomy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lepidoptera -- Biological control</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adn39x308r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Aphasic speech errors : spontaneous and elicited contexts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gordon, Jean K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The goal of the current study was to investigate the retrieval of phonological word forms during the speech production of persons with aphasia, in order to inform models of the structure and function of the phonological lexicon. Using a naturalistic, connected speech task (picture description) and a more structured, single-word production task (picture naming) several characteristics of the target and its phonological 'neighbourhood' were examined, specifically: the target word's frequency of occurrence; the number of words which are phonologically similar to the target (neighbourhood density); and the average frequency of those 'neighbours' (neighbourhood frequency). To assess the influence of these factors on a target's susceptibility to error, the neighbourhood values of the words produced incorrectly in the picture description task were compared to those of a comparable corpus of correctly produced words from the same speech samples. In the naming task, target susceptibility was assessed by analyzing the error rates on individual stimulus items. The results of both tasks indicated that the lower a target's frequency of occurrence was, and the fewer neighbours it had, the more susceptible it was to error. To assess the impact of the neighbourhood on the outcome of the error, neighbourhood values of the errors produced were compared to those of their targets. In neither task were errors found to differ significantly from their targets in frequency or neighbourhood density. These results contribute to the literature on lexical access primarily by extending findings of neighbourhood effects in normal speech production to the aphasic population. In doing so, the present study lends support to the basic tenets of the Neighborhood Activation Model (Luce &amp; Pisoni, 1998), and to the notion of the continuity thesis, in which aphasic deficits are hypothesized to reflect quantitative, rather than qualitative, differences from normal processing. Results are also in agreement with previous studies illustrating that aphasic error outcomes are strongly constrained by a number of linguistic factors which also constrain normal error production. Results are interpreted as consistent with an interactive connectionist framework of speech production.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Baum, Shari R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k8846.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x308r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af4752j44v"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biological significance of colour pattern and variation in the green poison frog, Dendrobates auratus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gray, Heather Marie</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The assumption that the colours of the green poison frog, Dendrobates auratus, serve as a warning of unpalatability is not supported because the requirements of the theory of aposematism are not met. The theory predicts that the aposematic coloration be conspicuous to potential predators, yet this cannot be demonstrated. The only predator found for D. auratus was the theraphosid spider, Sericopelma rubronitens, which hunts using vibrational cues. Only after sampling all frogs offered did spiders reject the toxic D. auratus over nontoxic Physalaemus pustulosus. The spider's decision to reject D. auratus as prey was made without visual input, and therefore the colours and toxicity of the frogs are decoupled with respect to this predator. Discovering that the crab Armases angustum is a predator of D. auratus tadpoles suggests that D. auratus is most vulnerable to predation during the nontoxic tadpole stage. Indirect methods of estimating predation were unsuccessful. The use of plasticine model frogs to estimate avian predation yielded no useful information and although traumatic injury is usually attributed to attempted predation, this is not true for tropical anurans. The levels of traumatic injury for D. auratus and a cryptic nontoxic frog Physalaemus pustulosus were similar when the life span of the frogs was taken into account. The traumatic injuries in these frogs are a function of interactions with small invertebrates that are neither predator nor prey. The theory of aposematism also predicts that there should be low pattern variation within an aposematic species so that a single search image can be formed and avoided. The patterns of D. auratus are individually distinct and there is significant interpopulational variation in appearance due to differences in colour, pattern and animal size. Selection for conspicuous visual intraspecific communication may have resulted in these differences in appearance. Mitochondrial 16S rRNA and cytochrome b sequence data ind</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Green, David M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989141.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j44v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Poisonous animals</dc:subject><dc:subject>Green poison frog -- Color</dc:subject><dc:subject>Green poison frog -- Predators of</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mk62h"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The contribution of descending fibers from the rostral ventromedial medulla to nociception, and to opioid and non-opioid analgesia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gilbert, Annie-Kim</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis investigated the contribution of descending fibers from the rostral ventromedial medulla (RVM) to nociception, and to opioid and non-opioid analgesia in rats. Inactivation of descending fibers was induced by microinjection of the GAGA-A agonist muscimol in the RVM, and nociception was evaluated using the tail immersion, hot plate and formalin tests. In all three tests, microinjection of muscimol (6.25--400 ng) in the RVM increased nociceptive responses of animals, suggesting that descending fibers tonically inhibit dorsal horn neurons of the spinal cord. In the formalin test, microinjection of muscimol (50 ng) in the RVM reduced the slope of the formalin concentration-response relation, so that responses were increased at low, but not at high concentrations of formalin. Conversely, microinjection of the GABA-A antagonist bicuculline in the RVM decreased the slope of the formalin concentration-response relation, so that responses were decreased at high but not at low concentrations of formalin. Microinjection of muscimol in the RVM abolished analgesia induced by systemic morphine in the tail immersion and hot plate tests, but only decreased analgesia by 60% in the formalin test. Microinjection of muscimol (50 ng) in the RVM abolished morphine analgesia elicited intracerebroventricularly, suggesting that the supraspinal effects of morphine are mediated via descending fibers from the RVM. Peripheral effects may account for the residual analgesic effect of systemic morphine after inactivation of descending fibers in the formalin test. Microinjection of muscimol (50 ng) in the RVM abolished buprenorphine analgesia in all tests. The dopamine uptake inhibitor nomifensine was devoid of analgesic activity in the tail immersion and hot plate tests. In the formalin test, nomifensine produced a dose-dependent analgesia, which was not affected by the microinjection of muscimol (50 ng) in the RVM. It is concluded that, descending fibers from the RVM tonically inhib</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Franklin, Keith</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn001.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk62h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Pain -- Physiological aspects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neural transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>Analgesics</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>