<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ab2773z72q"><ual:graduationDate>1973</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An application of programmed instruction to the learning of selected badminton skills</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Thirunavakarasoo, Vasudevan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of the study was to develop an illustrated linear programmed text of badminton skills for grade nine girls and to evaluate whether this programme was more or less effective than the conventional teacher-directed method. The subjects were enrolled in the Mount Royal High School. One grade nine class of twenty subjects used the programmed text while another grade nine class of twenty-three followed traditional teacher-directed method. Both classes were pre-tested using two tests of badminton skills, the Miller Wall Volley and the Short Serve Tests. At the conclusion of fourteen instructional periods the two tests were repeated. Independent and non-independent "T" tests were employed to analyse the data. Between group analysis indicated that there was no significant differences in achievement in badminton between the two classes. Within group analysis showed the teacher-directed class displayed an increase in mean scores on the Short Serve but no significant differences on the Miller Wall Volley Test. Those in the programmed instruction group made significant gains in bath tests.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Wilkinson, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pd749.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773z72q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>