<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arr171z84b"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Nursing</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Infant, mother and contextual factors related to mothers' interactions with their very-low-birthweight infants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Feeley, Nancy</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While there is evidence that the interactions that occur in the early years of life between very-low-birthweight (VLBW) infants and their mothers affects later child development, little is known about the factors that are associated with responsive and sensitive mother-VLBW infant interaction. Belsky's (1984) model of the determinants of parenting proposes that multiple child, parent, and contextual factors influence parenting behaviour. This prospective study examined the combined influence of a set of infant (i.e., birthweight and perinatal illness severity), mother (i.e., state anxiety and parenting sense of competence), and contextual variables (i.e., maternal received and perceived helpfulness of support, and marital adjustment) on mother-infant interaction, and assessed which factors were associated with sensitive and responsive interaction. The participants were 72 mothers and their VLBW infants (&lt;1500 grams). Infant, mother, and contextual variables were assessed at 3- and 9-months of age (corrected). At 9 months, mother-infant teaching interactions were observed in the home and later coded using the Nursing Child Assessment Teaching Scale (NCATS). Hierarchical multiple regression analyses were used to examine the relationship between mother-infant interaction and the infant, mother and contextual variables. The prospective model explained 33% of the variance in the interactive behaviour of the dyad. Dyads whose interaction was more sensitive and responsive at 9 months included mothers who were better-educated, less anxious at 3 months, and reported higher perceived support at 3 months. The concurrent model explained 29% of the variance in the interactive behaviour of the dyad. Dyads whose interaction was more sensitive and responsive included mothers who were better-educated and reported higher perceived support at 9 months. The hypothesis that the mother variables would be more important than the contextual variables in explaining mother-infant interaction was not supported. The findings highlight the importance of examining multiple infant, parent, and contextual variables to explain mother-VLBW infant interaction.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gottlieb, L. N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp639.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z84b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Nursing</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9g54xk286"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A novel method for the production of a selenium-enriched yeast</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ferhane, Akila</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Selenium (Se) is an essential element. Supplementation of Se as yeast-Se in animal and human diets has been proven to have beneficial health effects. The goal of this study was to add a maximum amount of Se in yeast metabolism in order to optimize its incorporation in amino acids. A bakery yeast strain of Saccharomyces cerevisiae (S. cerevisiae) was studied for its tolerance to Se when the latter was incorporated at different levels. Fermentations were run at 27°C for 8 h and 24 h. The maximum Se incorporation was achieved when 12.6 mmol of Se, as sodium selenite salt, was added to the culture medium and fermented for 24 h. A final Se concentration of 1550 +/- 35 mug/g yeast was obtained by this treatment. Different yeast strains of S. cerevisiae were also studied for their capacity to incorporate Se. Five yeast strains of wine and four yeast strains of beer were fermented for 24 h and tested for their capacity to incorporate Se. The amount of 12.6 mmol Se was added in the growth medium. A maximum of 642.6 +/- 3.6 mug Se/g yeast was found to be incorporated in Uvaferm BC wine strain. Uvaferm windsor of beer strain was able to incorporate a maximum of 826.8 +/- 10.4 mug Se/g yeast. These yeast strains could be used as alternatives for Se supplementation. Se speciation was carried out on the bakery yeast strain containing 1550 +/- 35 mug Se/g yeast, using Fast Phase Liquid Chromatography (FPLC) and amino acid analysis. Out of 1550 +/- 35 mug Se/g yeast, 57.5% Se was present as selenoaminoacids. The yeast extract contained 147 +/- 14 mug/g of SeCys, 248 +/- 13 mug/g of SeCyst and 295 +/- 17 mug/g of SeMet. Yeast cell walls contained 65 +/- 8 mug/g of SeMet; 69 +/- 5 mug/g of SeCyst and 67 +/- 9 mug/g of SeCys. These selenoaminoacids are known for their beneficial health effects. The produced Se-enriched bakery yeast could be used, after evaluated to be toxicologically safe, as an efficient dietary supplement.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chan, H. M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430640w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk286</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Selenium in human nutrition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Biotechnology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amg74qn66h"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Therapist interpretations and client change : an investigation of process in non-dynamic psychotherapies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gazzola, Nicola</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This research investigated the relationship between therapist interpretations and optimal in-session client processes by employing two distinct but complementary studies. In the first study, the data were collected from 20 psychotherapy sessions conducted by exemplary psychotherapists of three different theoretical orientations: Client-Centered Therapy (CCT), Rational-Emotive Behavior Therapy (REBT), and Gestalt/Existential Therapy (GT). The results of the quantitative analysis indicated that interpretations were used with equal frequency across therapeutic approaches. Therapist interpretations were neither superior nor inferior to other interventions in relation to the occurrence of optimal in-session client processes. In the second study, the data were collected from 12 sessions equally divided between CCT, REBT, and GT. A qualitative method was employed to discover potential differences between interpretations in the three distinct therapeutic approaches as well as the differences between client processes subsequent to those interpretations. By allowing conceptual categories to emerge from this qualitatively analyzed data, it was found that interpretation was not a uniform construct across the three schools. Both common and unique features of the use of interpretations in CCT, REBT, and GT were found. The three approaches each had their own specific pattern of interpretation content as well as style of delivering the interpretations. Interpretations that were followed by optimal in-session processes were qualitatively different from those that were not. The results of these two studies support the notion that interpretation is a common therapeutic element but that different therapies nonetheless accentuate different aspects of interpretation. Implications for psychotherapy integration are offered and the findings are discussed with reference to theory and clinical practice. Future research directions for examining therapist interpretations are proposed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stalikas, Anastassios</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw161.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn66h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychotherapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tq97f"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Patterns of benzodiazepine use and risk of injury in the elderly</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bartlett-Esquilant, Gillian</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background. Benzodiazepines are sedative-hypnotic medications frequently prescribed in elderly patients for several clinical indications. An association with increased risk for falls has been reported but there is continued debate regarding which specific benzodiazepines are associated with this risk. Objectives. To estimate the risk of injuries from falls associated with benzodiazepine use in an elderly cohort taking into account patient characteristics and changes in patterns of use over time. Methods. Using information from provincial administrative health databases, 462,543 community-dwelling, 66 year old Quebec residents were screened for benzodiazepine use in 1989. Subjects who did not use benzodiazepines in 1989 were observed for the next five years to estimate incidence rates and evaluate patient characteristics associated with new use for thirteen benzodiazepines. Patterns of use for incident users were characterized in terms of duration, dose and frequency of switching or adding benzodiazepines. New methods were developed to model the past cumulative dose and duration of benzodiazepine exposure. The impact of benzodiazepine exposure on risk of injury was estimated using Cox proportional hazards analyses with time-dependent covariates to take into account changes in dose and patterns of use. Results. The overall incidence rate for benzodiazepines was 88.7 per 1,000 person-years, with higher rates in women (95.0) than men (81.8). Predictors of incident use were different in individual products and there were systematic differences between users and non-users. Use of anti-depressants in 1989 was the strongest predictor for incident benzodiazepine use (HR 1.45 to 3.07, p &lt; 0.0001). The median duration for uninterrupted periods of use was 31 days (mean = 75.5 days, sd = 137.2). The mean dose was almost half the recommended maximum adult daily dose and only 8.6% of subjects exceeded the maximum. Older age at date of first prescription significantly increased the likelihood of increasing duration and dose overtime (OR = 1.02, p &lt; 0.0001). All benzodiazepines except clonazeparn were significantly associated with an increased risk of injuries from falls (p &lt; 0.05). The best predictive model for most benzodiazepines included a cumulative measure of duration and current dose. Conclusion. Benzodiazepines are associated with an increased risk of injuries from falls in elderly patients, however duration of exposure may be more critical than dose. Physiological dependence and withdrawal symptoms appear to play an important role in increasing the risk for many benzodiazepines.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Abrahamowicz, Michal</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md51s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tq97f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Public Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw3763866x"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Circulation and mixing in the St. Lawrence estuary</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bourgault, Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Circulation and mixing processes in the St. Lawrence Estuary are examined using both newly acquired and historical observations, as well as numerical modeling. In the Summer of 1997 a field experiment was undertaken to verify the prediction of a three-dimensional numerical model on the occurrences of shear instabilities within the upper estuary. The instabilities were found as predicted and documented from acoustic imaging, current profiler and density measurements. The instabilities, as in the case of Kelvin-Helmholtz instabilities, first develop in the form of wavelike disturbances before they break. The unstable waves have wavelength of around 140--150 m and a vertical extent of between 10 and 25 m. It is shown that the modeled gradient Richardson numbers near the pycnocline are reasonably well reproduced and appear to be useful for the prediction of flow instabilities in such a complex environment. The seasonal variability of the general circulation and mixing is examined with a newly developed laterally averaged numerical model. The model takes into account tidal forcing and a realistic topography while forced with a large seasonal change in the river discharge. The model is able to reproduce important processes associated with the tidal forcing and mean conditions (density field, residual circulation). The numerical results show that mixing in the St. Lawrence Estuary is not evenly distributed. Mixing is found to be large near the sill at the head of the Laurentian Channel, as previously thought, as well our new results show that equivalent levels of mixing are also found near English Bank and near Ile-aux-Coudres. During the spring freshet, when the river discharge is 40% higher than normal, the limit of salt intrusion is moved seaward by approximately 12 km, the residual circulation is intensified by approximately 10%, and the turbulent vertical mass flux increases throughout owing to greater availability of freshwater. The results also suggest that during high runoff periods, the vertical stability of the water column increases in the upper estuary. The model is also used to assess the impacts of climate change on the estuarine dynamics. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lin, Charles A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x617.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763866x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physical Oceanography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av979v463v"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Development and application of biotechnological tools in the major crop plant, Brassica napus</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Babwah, Andy Videsh</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A two-component transposable element system consisting of a stabilized Activator (Acst) and a chimeric Dissociation (Ds) element has been introduced into the genome of Brassica napus. This Acst/ Ds system incorporates the use of several highly effective screenable and selectable markers. One of these markers is the maize Lc gene, a transcriptional regulator of flavonoid biosynthetic genes. This substrate-independent screenable marker was tested for the first time in B. napus and I show that when overexpressed, there is augmented trichome production and a light-dependent, enhanced accumulation of anthocyanins in B. napus plants. The phenotypes are expressed under a wide range of conditions, are visually distinct, and are observed throughout plant development. When used as a visual marker for the Acst element, Lc B. napus plants were rapidly identified among F2 segregating populations. As part of my goal to develop a very efficient Acst/Ds system for use in B. napus, a conditional negative selectable marker, the E. coli codA gene, was also tested for the first time in B. napus. This was done because use of a substrate-dependent negative selectable marker can facilitate the rapid and reliable identification of stable Ds transposition events when used as a marker for the Acst T-DNA. The enzyme cytosine deaminase, encoded by the codA gene, catalyzes the deamination of the non-toxic compound 5-fluorocytosine (5-FC) to the highly toxic compound 5-fluorouracil. In codA transformed B. napus seedlings, expression of cytosine deaminase results in a severe suppression of growth and this phenotype is dependent on the presence of the 5-FC substrate. Wild-type seedlings, however, lack endogenous cytosine deaminase activity and appear unaffected by the presence of 5-FC in the growth media. These results indicate that codA has the potential to be used effectively in B. napus as a substrate-dependent negative selectable marker for the Acst T-DNA. To determine if Ac transposase cou</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Waddell, Candace S.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Brown, G. G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br10v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v463v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Transposons</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rape (Plant) -- Cytogenetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rape (Plant) -- Biotechnology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic markers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j715k"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A combined approach for analysis of single crystal nickel base superalloys</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bande, Gilbert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The purpose of this research is to develop a new tool for mechanical design and analysis of single crystal (SC) nickel base superalloys used in gas turbine engine components. The principle of this tool is based on the extension of the predictive models for isotropic material behavior to anisotropic materials such as SC nickel, base superalloys. This objective is achieved by combining the two main approaches used in the literature for SC materials development: the macroscopic approach and the microscopic approach. For that reason, this theory is designated as the "combined approach " (CA). The structure of the CA theory requires two main elements: a viscoplastic model (that admits a yield function) and a slip factor. The viscoplastic model describes the behavior of the material in the macroscopic level. Conversely, the slip factor based on the crystallographic theory, accounts for the micro-slip state that dominates SC materials during deformation. In order to determine the slip factor, a preliminary slip trace study of the crystal is established. Also to determine material constants from experimental data, a procedure has been developed to reduce the 3D basic equations into a one-dimensional form. The model has been evaluated for its predictive capability on SC material behavior including orientation dependence of the initial yielding, tension/compression asymmetry, stress-strain response, fully reversed cyclic response, creep response and relaxation response. In almost all the cases, good correlation has been observed between the predicted responses and experimental data, when available. Furthermore, it is believable that the CA can be successfully used for many other SC materials such as the body-centered-cubic (b.c.c) or the hexagonal-closed-packet (h.c.p). In view of all these results, the CA theory seems to offer the greatest promise in this regard. Limitations and future development needs are discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nemes, James Alan</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq158.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j715k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adj52w647x"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>DNA replication and methylation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tavares de Araujo, Felipe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>One of the main questions of modern biology is how our cells interpret our genetic and epigenetic information. DNA methylation is a covalent modification of the genome that is essential for mammalian development and plays an important role in the control of gene expression, genomic imprinting and X-chromosome inactivation (Bird and Wolffe, 1999; Szyf et al., 2000). Furthermore, changes in DNA methylation and DNA methyltransferase 1 (DNMT1) activity have been widely documented in a number of human cancers (Szyf, 1998a; Szyf et al., 2000). In Escherichia coli, timing and frequency of initiation of DNA replication are controlled by the levels of the bacterial methyltransferase and by the methylation status of its origin of replication (Boye and Lobner-Olesen, 1990; Campbell and Kleckner, 1990). In mammalian cells, however, the importance of methyltransferase activity and of DNA methylation in replication is only now starting to emerge (Araujo et al., 1998; Delgado et al., 1998; DePamphilis, 2000; Knox et al., 2000). The work described in this thesis focuses mainly on understanding the functional relationship between changes in DNA methylation and DNMT1 activity on mammalian DNA replication. In higher eukaryotes, DNA replication initiates from multiple specific sites throughout the genome (Zannis-Hadjopoulos and Price, 1999). The first part of the thesis describes the identification and characterization of novel in vivo initiation sites of DNA replication within the human dnmt1 locus (Araujo et al., 1999). Subsequently, a study of the temporal relationship between DNA replication and the inheritance of the DNA methylation pattern is presented. We also demonstrate that mammalian origins of replication, similarly to promoters, are differentially methylated (Araujo et al., 1998). We then tested the hypothesis that DNMT1 is a necessary component of the replication machinery. The results presented indicate that inhibition of DNMT1 results in inhibition of DNA replication (Knox et al., 2000). Finally, results are presented, demonstrating that the amino terminal region of DNMT1 is responsible for recognizing hemimethylated CGs, DNMT1's enzymatic target. Taken together, the results presented in this thesis demonstrate that DNMT1 is necessary for proper DNA replication and that DNA methylation may modulate origin function.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zannis-Hadjopoulos, Maria</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr55m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w647x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0p096872j"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>DNA replication in human transformed cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tao, Liang, 1960-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cell transformation and malignancy may modulate some regulatory parameters of DNA replication, resulting in altered features of initiation of DNA replication in these cells. The objectives of this research were to examine the possibility for tumor-specific DNA replication origins and activation of replication origins in human transformed cells. Conventional PCR was used to detect chromosomal activities of several known and putative replication origins in four human cell lines (HeLa, NSF, WI38 and SK-MG-1). Quantitative comparison of origin activities demonstrates that origins associated with c-myc and NOA3 were approximately twice as active in HeLa cells as in NSF cells. To test whether the differential origin activities at certain loci in HeLa and NSF cells were due to shifts in origin usage among multiple initiation sites, DNA replication initiation sites and initiation frequencies over 12.5 kb of the human c-myc locus, including 4.6 kb of new 5 ' sequence, were determined by competitive PCR. In this study, one predominant site was located at ~0.5 kb upstream of the exon 1, and a second new major site was identified in exon 2. The relative usage of origins over the same region of the c-myc locus in the two types of cells was similar, but activities of all origins in HeLa cells were approximately twice those in NSF cells. In order to better determine if cell type (Hela vs. NSF) or transformation were most likely responsible for altered origin activities, we studied initiation of replication in an isogenic cell pair, WI38 and SV40-transformed WI38 (WI38 VA13 2RA). We found, once again, that the activities of all origins at the c-myc locus were approximately twice as high in immortalized and transformed WI38(SV40) cells as in WI38 cells. This also suggests that the increased activities of origins at the c-myc locus in HeLa cells are caused by the processes leading to malignancy. Although there was significantly increased activity of promoter P2 (7.5--8.0-fold), it had no preferential influence on origin activities at the major sites. Finally, the potential associations between the DNA replication origin activity and transcription activity through higher order regulation by nuclear structure have been discussed.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Price, G. B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr26x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096872j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9593tw80f"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Vasoregulatory gene expression and vascular contractility following hypoxia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Topors, Mourad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The overall aim of this thesis was to analyze the expression of key vasoregulatory genes in the vascular endothelium and smooth muscle following hypoxia. Hypoxia caused a reversal in endothelial cell function such that the vascular endothelium enhanced alpha-agonist induced contractions. Downregulation of endothelial nitric oxide synthase (eNOS) and impaired endothelium-dependent vasodilation were observed in the aortas of rats exposed to hypoxia for 12 and 48 hours. Following stimulation of aortic rings with acetylcholine, cyclic GMP and nitrite levels were also reduced. Decreased endothelial NO release may impair the vascular responses which defend vital organ oxygenation. This decrease in the capacity for vasodilator synthesis following hypoxia cannot by itself, however, mediate the observed enhancement of contractility. An increase in aortic endothelin-1 (ET-1) mRNA and protein was localized to the vascular endothelium. Treatment with the ET-1 receptor antagonist, BQ123, mimicked endothelial denudation and confirmed that locally secreted ET-1 accounts for endothelium-dependent enhancement of contractility. Concurrently, hypoxia caused an endothelium-independent impairment of smooth muscle reactivity to alpha-adrenoreceptor activation. Despite a decrease in eNOS in the aorta of rats exposed to hypoxia, Ca2+-dependent NOS activity remained unchanged suggesting the upregulation of neuronal NOS (nNOS). In endothelium-denuded aortic rings from hypoxic rats, L-NAME enhanced the contractile response to phenylephrine. In addition, it normalized the hypoxia-induced hypocontractility in intact aortic rings. The presence of nNOS was confirmed by Western blot analysis, immunohistochemistry, in situ hybridization and RT-PCR. Rat nNOS mRNA transcript bearing the alternately spliced exon 1b was shown to be expressed in the medial layer of aortas from hypoxic rats and in vascular smooth muscle cells cultured under hypoxic conditions. Cloning and analysis of the 5' regulatory</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ward, Michael E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nj792.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw80f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Animal Physiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4m90dx09f"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Ab-initio modelling of transport in atomic scale devices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Taylor, Jeremy, 1974-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we develop a novel ab-initio technique to study transport in atomic scale devices based on a self-consistent solution of the Kohn-Sham equations for open systems in and out of equilibrium. Starting from the central motivating theorems of density functional theory, we introduce the basis of the ab-initio technique as currently practiced in condensed matter physics. The Kohn-Sham Hamiltonian is solved numerically by employing a Fireball atomic orbital basis set to transform the problem into matrix form. In order to study open systems, a natural screening approximation is introduced and it is demonstrated that, for the systems studied in this work, the Kohn-Sham potential is effectively screened and the screening approximation is appropriate for the study of atomic scale devices. The method developed in this thesis is contrasted with previous studies of transport in atomic scale devices and it is argued that it presents a significant advance and makes it possible to solve problems which could not previously be studied. A few representative studies were undertaken in order to illustrate the advantage of using a self-consistent ab-initio method to study quantum transport in open systems. Several short carbon chains were coupled to Al electrodes and it was found that charge transfer plays a role in aligning the Fermi level with standing wave resonance peaks inside the atomic chain. Our study of a C60 molecular junction predicts a substantial equilibrium conductance due to charge transfer doping of three extra electrons inside the C60. Furthermore, these extra electrons may be depleted by an external gate voltage, reducing the conductance and thus producing a field-effect molecular switch. Transport and charge transfer were studied in a number of nanotube devices. Preliminary results are in agreement with recent experimental and theoretical results.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Guo, Hong</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1412.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx09f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics, Condensed Matter</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9306t080d"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Alliances as institutions : persistence and disintegration in security cooperation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rafferty, Kirsten</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the end of the Cold War, the central puzzle of alliance theory is no longer why or how do alliances form, but (1) why do some alliances persist beyond the conditions in which they were created and (2) of these, why do some evolve in new directions ? Traditional realist scholarship cannot account for the persistence or evolution of military alliances when threats recede. This dissertation devises a model of alliance institutionalization and norm formation to explain and predict these processes. When multidimensional threats exist, states facing a common threat ally, but they formalize and institutionalize the alliance so it can better manage multiple threats. Institutionalization encourages conditions conducive to persistence and evolution in two ways. First, by facilitating consultation and cooperation, it increases transparency, improves the performance of the alliance, and makes it costly for allies to renounce commitments or otherwise abandon one another. Second, institutions foster norms that in turn induce a form of attachment, or "loyalty" to the institution. The strength of the norms embodied in the alliance and the allies' assessment of performance determine the behavior of institutionalized alliances. The alliance persists unaltered when performance is satisfactory, but norms are weak. It evolves, or expands its purpose and activities, when satisfactory performance combines with strong constitutive norms. Erosion occurs when strong norms encourage allies to salvage a poorly functioning alliance by curtailing its scope. Dissolution takes place when unsatisfactory performance and weak norms fail to prevent exit. The most significant findings of this dissertation are that given institutionalization and norms, states do not exit an alliance immediately following a significant alteration in the strategic context or a decline in performance, but they try to preserve it. Only when these efforts fail will they curtail or dissolve the relationship. The dissertation tests the model by engaging in a comparative analysis of Cold War institutionalized alliances: the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the Warsaw Pact, the Southeast Asia Treaty Organization, and the Australia, New Zealand, and U.S. alliance. Therefore, policy makers should not assume that evolving institutionalized alliances are adversarial or rush to respond with destabilizing counter alliances and, to minimize the possibility of conflict, allies engaging in evolution must clearly communicate their objectives to non-participants.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Paul, T. V.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k811.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t080d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Alliances</dc:subject><dc:subject>International relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Security, International</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6w924d389"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Fighting against the "evil" : religious and cultural construction of the first psychotic experience of youth living in Sao Paulo, Brazil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Redko, Cristina Pozzi</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The outbreak of the first psychotic episode disarrays the person's everyday experience and of significant others. This work takes the notion of experience as the key mediating variable to understand how the cultural and social frame affects the experience of psychosis. Culture contributes to the articulation of the experience of psychosis through its influence on individual, family, and community reactions. I focused on the first psychotic experience of low-income youth living in Sao Paulo, Brazil because one can see more clearly the role played by the cultural and social dimensions, since the process of experiencing psychosis is not yet totally settled. I emphasized the basic strategies created by psychotic patients and their families to reorganize their experience of themselves and of the world, and the dynamics and underpinning of these strategies in relation to cultural signifiers. I particularly explored how psychotic patients and their families appropriate, borrow and transform cultural signifiers, and more specifically religious signifiers, in their attempt to cope with psychosis. Religious signifiers are pervasive and diverse in Brazilian culture; furthermore different people may or may not resort to or be affected by religious idioms and signifiers in a similar way. A wide range of variation in the use of religious idioms and signifiers can be expected among patients, at different moments of their life history, and when the experiences of patients and significant others are compared. Religion can have a positive impact over the experience of psychosis, a negative, or even a neutral impact depending on the person and circumstances. My work also demonstrates that psychotic patients are subjected to a double-process of marginality due to their poor living conditions and to urban violence; and to the fact that their marginality is further accentuated by the psychotic episode. People's reactions also vary and change in relation to the kinds of behaviours manifested by psychotic patients, in addition to the social role of each family member and the family dynamics at play. More generally, people's reactions work in a kind of "feed-back loop," since family reactions modify the subjective world and reactions of patients, while patients' reactions modify family attitudes and behaviours.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Corin, Ellen</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397985d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d389</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychoses -- Brasil -- São Paulo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mental illness -- Social aspects -- Brasil -- São Paulo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psychiatry and religion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poor -- Brasil -- São Paulo</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5m60qt645"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The development of mother tongue and second language reading in two bilingual education contexts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Riches, Caroline</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The effects that various forms of bilingual education may have on children's reading development are of concern to parents and educators alike. In this thesis, I investigate the development of mother tongue and second language reading in two bilingual education contexts, and assess the effects of the language of initial formal reading instruction upon this development. This study examines children's reading within the home, classroom and community environments. The research involved two Grade 1 classes mainly comparing the language of initial formal reading instruction. One site was a French immersion school offering a 50% English/50% French program in which initial formal reading instruction was in English. The second site was a French school, with a majority of anglophone students and initial formal reading instruction was in French. The participants in this study were 12 children from each class, their parents, and the classroom teachers. Three main tools of inquiry were used: classroom observations were carried out in each of the two classes during the Grade 1 school year; samples of oral reading and retellings, in English and in French, were collected from the participating children for miscue analysis, and informal interviews were conducted with all the participants. The analysis revealed that regardless of the language of initial formal reading instruction, the children's reading abilities developed in both languages. Children tended to feel more comfortable reading in the language in which they had been formally instructed but, despite this, meaning-construction was more effective in the mother tongue. Differences in reading abilities for both groups could be accounted for by limitations in knowledge of the second language rather than by language of initial instruction. Finally, children with initial formal reading instruction in the second language easily applied their reading abilities to reading in their mother tongue. The conclusions drawn from this inquiry are that having supportive home and community environments, exemplary teachers and constructive classroom environments enables children to use their creative abilities and language resources to make sense of reading in two languages. It is the continuities and connections between these elements which enables children to transcend any difficulties arising from the fact that reading is being encountered in two languages.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Donin, Janet</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg561.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt645</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Reading</dc:subject><dc:subject>French language -- Study and teaching -- Immersion method</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amc87ps05r"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Gaiete perverse et rire de force dans l'œuvre de Victor Hugo</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Prévost, Maxime</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis studies the theme of laughter in the works of Victor Hugo, distinguishing two topical networks: that of perverse gaiety and that of forced laughter. Part One (La Gaiete perverse) shows how Hugo, drawing various commonplaces related to cruel laughter in the gothic novel, creates a first family of characters whose laugh derives from their demented nature (the monster, the headsman, the priest, the outlaw, the mob, the court jester). Part Two (La Tristesse des justes) concerns the Hugo which, between 1845 and 1862, fashions a mythology of the People renewing with commonplaces related to perverse gaiety, which he now links to characters seen as pillars of the Second Empire (the tyrant, the soldier, the police officer). While the wicked laugh, the just man cries, and the laughter of the oppressed (the convict, the prostitute, the street urchin) is constrained. Part Three (Le Rire de force) considers three works dating from Hugo's exile, including L'Homme qui rit, where the author clearly defines what constitutes forced laughter: a victim's exultation caused by the perversity of his social torturer, the tyrant. This transition from perverse gaiety (which stems from individual perversion) to forced laughter (the result of society's perversion) will be interpreted as the reflexion of a shift in the identity of Hugo's implied reader. While the first Hugo wrote about the people, the later Hugo aspires to write for the people, which considerably affects the meaning conferred to various commonplaces used throughout his writing career.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Duquette, Jean-Pierre</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw179.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps05r</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Laughter in literature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885 -- Criticism and interpretation</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad791sh906"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The Eocene cichlids (Perciformes:Labroidei) of Mahenge, Tanzania</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Murray, Alison M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A new genus and five new species of fossil cichlid fishes (Perciformes: Labroidei) are described from Mahenge, Tanzania. These cichlids represent the oldest confirmed fossils of the family, dating from the middle of the Eocene. The specimens share many lepidological characters, and, from comparison with other members of the family, are identified as being a monophyletic group. Therefore, they are described as belonging to a single genus, Mahengechromis gen. nov., named for the type locality. Detailed anatomical study of the well-preserved specimens allows five species to be identified, M. plethos, M. rotundus, M. brachycranium , M. ellipticus, and M. curvifrons spp. nov. These species are distinguished on the basis of osteological characters, including the shape of the frontal bones, hyomandibulae and opercular bones. The species are believed to be endemic to the type locality, which, along with monophyly of the species, indicates that these fishes formed a species flock. This suggests that the capacity for cichlids to form species flocks arose early in the family's history. Previously published phylogenetic analyses of the family Cichlidae have included few characters that can be used to incorporate fossil material. Osteological features that may be useful for determining relationships are identified and used in a phylogenetic analysis of the family. The results of this analysis are compared with the results of previous analyses to determine the usefulness of the characters. This comparison indicates that most osteological characters are homoplastic among cichlids, although some of the characters may prove to be phylogenetically useful. Although phylogenetic analysis of osteologic characters does not result in a well-resolved phylogeny, the most parsimonious placement of the fossil cichlids from Mahenge is in a relatively basal position among the African lineages, as the sister group to the hemichromine cichlids from West Africa. The biogeographic relationships of members of the Cichlidae are examined based on information from the fossil record and the interrelationships of the lineages within the family. Two suggestions have been made for the age of the family; either the cichlids originated in the Early Cretaceous or they evolved near the end of the Mesozoic. The later time of origin would have required a trans-Atlantic dispersal. Based on the distribution of Recent and fossil cichlids, the latter hypothesis is accepted. A reconstruction of the dispersal patterns and possible means of dispersal are evaluated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carroll, Robert L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz339.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sh906</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Labroides -- Tanzania -- Mahenge</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cichlids, Fossil -- Tanzania -- Mahenge</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acr56n282d"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Management</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Technological evolution and the 'construction' of dominant designs in the imaging industry</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Munir, Kamal A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>All industries occasionally experience technological shocks or 'discontinuities.' These discontinuities may be competence-enhancing or competence-destroying. Competence-destroying discontinuities threaten to render existing capabilities obsolete and lead to 'eras of ferment' in which the new technology competes with the old one. At the same time, several designs within the new technology struggle for dominance. Managers faced with such a situation need to make several important decisions, perhaps the most important of which involve the selection of technologies to adopt or develop. Existing competencies and market positions provide strong constraints on the objective of meeting evolving customer expectations. The decisions are expensive and fraught with risks. Naturally, a better understanding of how technologies tend to evolve and why particular designs become dominant, while others, equally plausible ones, do not, would help managers make more informed decisions and avoid costly mistakes or even the prospect of lock-out. This primary aim of this dissertation was the development of a better theoretical understanding of this complex process. Relying primarily on archival data, narratives were constructed around four cases of radical technology shifts in the photographic industry. When woven with existing theoretical insights, these narratives yielded a new perspective on technology dominance. It proposes that contrary to the popular perception that customers eventually adopt technologies that meet their needs 'better,' the success or failure of a new technology is dependent on the extent to which its proponent can build it into the emerging institutional context. This involves opening the design up to embody the interests of key stakeholders as well as structuring the field. At the same time associations and linkages are created between the technology and existing structures. "Enrolling" institutions in this manner stabilizes the nascent technology, reducing its disruptiveness and creating positive externalities around it. How long the design stays dominant depends upon its position in the industry architecture (Christensen, 1997). If it is positioned as an obligatory passage point (Latour, 1987), it is likely to stay dominant for much longer than if it is simply the foremost technological solution to the central problem.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Phillips, Nelson</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161789v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n282d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Photographic industry -- Technological innovations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Technological innovations</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s161790m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Differential processing and sorting of nerve growth factor and brain-derived neurotrophic factor in hippocampal neurons</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mowla, Seyed Javad</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>We have examined the biosynthesis, post-translational processing and sorting of neurotrophins in both constitutive and regulated cells infected with a pro-NGF, pro-BDNF and/or pro-NT-3 encoding vaccinia virus. Our results show that: (1) pro-BDNF is generated as a 32 kDa precursor that is N-glycosylated and glyco-sulfated in its prodomain. The precursor undergoes N-terminal cleavage to generate mature BDNF (14 kDa) as well as a truncated form of the precursor (28 kDa). (2) Both 32 and 28 kDa BDNF are released into media and are able to stimulate TrkB auto-phosphorylation. (3) The production of 28 kDa BDNF, unlike that of mature BDNF, occurs in the ER and is generated by a novel enzyme called subtilisin/kexin isozyme-1 (SKI-1) at the RGLT 57&amp;darr;SL site. (4) Results obtained from pulse-chase experiments, secretagogue-induced release, and immunocytochemistry suggest that, NGF and NT-3 are primarily secreted constitutively while BDNF is principally directed to the regulated secretory pathway. (5) In contrast to homodimeric NT-3, NT-3/BDNF heterodimer is primarily sorted to the regulated secretory pathway suggesting that for the NT-3/BDNF heterodimer, the presence of a single pro-BDNF chain is sufficient for packaging into large dense-core secretory vesicles and subsequent regulated release. (6) Blocking furin activity in AtT-20 cells with alpha1-PDX as well as increasing the level of expression of NGF and NT-3 precursors partially directed them into the regulated secretory pathway. Therefore, neurotrophins can be sorted into either the constitutive or regulated secretory pathways, and sorting may be regulated by the efficiency of furin cleavage in the TGN. This mechanism may explain how neuron-generated neurotrophins can act both as survival factors and as neuropeptides.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Murphy, Richard A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns56n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161790m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w401g"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biomedical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An inverse-problem approach to spatial distortion correction in MRI</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Munger, Patrice</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis treats of the issue of distortion in magnetic resonance (MR) imaging, with focus on Echo Planar imaging (EPI) and anatomical 3D imaging. After a review of MR theory, the principle of image formation, an analysis of distortion in the context of MRI and field mapping principles, an analysis of the EPI image formation process, which reveals the two-dimensional nature of the EPI point-spread function (PSF), is presented, and a full 2D correction technique based on the inversion of the 4D tensor EPI imaging equation using the Conjugate Gradient (CG) method is proposed. A 1D approximation of the technique is also derived for cases where the PSF can be approximated as being one-dimensional, such as in Fourier imaging, or EPI imaging in fields with low field inhomogeneity. The proposed technique is demonstrated by means of computer simulations, and several aspects of its implementation are studied. A comparison between different correction methods based on field map data, still using computer simulations, is presented and reveals the behaviour of the different methods when applied in non-ideal conditions. Finally, the practical application of the proposed method is demonstrated on real EPI scans and gradient echo images. This work reveals some interesting characteristics of the correction method based on the CG algorithm, like fast convergence, possibility to recover from severe distortions and EPI B0-induced ghost artifacts reduction, but it also points out limitations of this correction method, such as potentially high computational cost and noise sensitivity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peters, Terry M.</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pike, G. Bruce</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv28x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w401g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Atb09j719p"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Animal Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Proliferation and apoptosis of bovine mammary epithelial cells : roles of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 4E and Escherichia coli mastitis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Long, Ezhou</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Milk yield is dependent on both the number and secretory activity of mammary alveolar cells. The number of cells is controlled by their proliferation and death. In the first study, the effect of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 4E (eIF-4E) on the growth of a bovine mammary epithelial cell line, MAC-T, was investigated. Compared to the parental controls, overexpression of mouse wild-type (wt) eIF-4E in 11A, a subclone of MAC-T cells, increased the growth rate and saturation density (number of cells per well at confluence), whereas overexpression of a mutant eIF-4E (W56A) decreased growth rates and saturation densities. Furthermore, cyclin D1 expression among the 4E-overexpressing and parental cells was compared. Compared to the controls, the amounts of cyclin D1 mRNA and proteins were higher in the cells overexpressing wt eIF-4E but lower in the cells with mutant eIF-4E expression. Our results suggest that altered expression of eIF-4E leads to changes in cyclin D1 expression, which consequently modulate the growth properties of MAC-T 11A cells. Because of its unknown sequence, bovine eIF-4E cDNA was then cloned in the second study. Its coding region consists of 651 nucleotides which encode 217 amino acids (AAs). Bovine eIF-4E cDNA shares 94%, 89% and 94% homology with those of human, mouse and rabbit, respectively. Differences in protein sequences between bovine and human, mouse and rabbit eIF-4E are 2, 4, and 3 AAs, respectively. Furthermore, expression of eIF-4E in bovine mammary tissues at different physiological periods was investigated by Northern blot analysis, using the cloned cDNA as the probe. eIF-4E was not detectable at prepubertal period and expressed at a very low level at the third estrous cycle. In the lactating mammary tissues, eIF-4E was highly expressed. Differential expression of eIF-4E in bovine mammary gland at distinct physiological stages indicates its potential involvement in mammary development. Cell proliferation and apoptosis were also studied in the Escherichia coli (E. coli)-infected bovine mammary glands in the last study. Both proliferation and apoptosis increased in the mastitic tissue, as determined by immunohistological assays. Compared to the controls, expression of the pro-apoptotic proteins, Bax and interleukin-1beta converting enzyme (ICE), increased at 24 h and 72 h post-infection, whereas expression of the anti-apoptotic protein Bcl-2 decreased only at 24 h post-infusion. Induction of extracellular matrix (ECM)-degrading enzymes, including matrix metal loproteinase-9 (MMP-9), stromelysin-1 (SL-1) and urokinase-type plasminogen activator (uPA), was also observed in the mastitic tissue. Therefore, apoptosis may be mediated through pathways involving the actions of Bcl-2, Bax and ICE, and may partially be accounted by ECM breakdown. Taken together, our study has demonstrated the effect of eIF-4E on bovine mammary cell proliferation. In addition, its involvement in bovine mammary gland development has been suggested. Finally, increased mammary cell apoptosis and proliferation during E. coli-induced mastitis has been revealed, in association with altered expression of apoptosis-related genes and ECM-degrading enzymes. Understanding the regulation of mammary cell proliferation and death may eventually lead to improvement of milk production.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Zhao, Xin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz816.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j719p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Dairy cattle -- Diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mastitis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Growth factors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apoptosis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abr86b4975"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Involvement of the Met receptor tyrosine kinase in the development of human breast cancer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Jenny Catherine, 1970-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Met is a transmembrane receptor tyrosine kinase whose ligand is hepatocyte growth factor/scatter factor (HGF/SF). HGF/SF stimulates epithelial cell mitogenesis, motility and branching tubulogenesis. Met and HGF/SF are essential for embryonic development, and are implicated in oncogenesis. In this thesis, the possible role of Met in the development of human breast cancer is examined. The MET gene is located at chromosome 7q31, a region frequently deleted in breast cancer. In this thesis, I demonstrate that MET is included in the smallest common region of deletion of chromosome 7q31 in breast cancer, and is therefore a candidate for a breast cancer tumor suppressor gene. To investigate this further, I elucidated the intron-exon structure of the MET gene. The MET gene is composed of 21 exons, spanning approximately 130 kilobases(kb) of chromosomal DNA. Interestingly, the first coding exon of MET, exon 2, is unusually large, at 1214 nucleotides (nt). Exon 2 is subject to alternative splicing in all epithelial cells studied, and is skipped to produce a 7kb mRNA species which does not encode a protein product. Furthermore, in seven of 13 human breast cancer cell lines studied, exon-skipping of MET exon 2 occurs more frequently when compared to two immortalized breast epithelial cell lines. These seven breast cancer cell lines have an altered ratio of Met mRNA isoforms, with increased levels of the non-protein-encoding 7kb exon 2-skipped mRNA, and a corresponding decrease in the expression of Met receptor in these cells. Significantly, in all other carcinoma types studied to date, the Met receptor is expressed at high levels, as in normal epithelial cells, indicating that loss of Met protein is specific to breast carcinoma cells. The alteration in the normal splicing pattern of MET is correlated with alterations in the normal pattern of expression of SR splicing proteins, which are responsible for regulating alternative splicing. I propose that loss of Met is an event s</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Park, Morag</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq98q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b4975</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hr38f"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Purification, cloning, and functional studies of a new transcriptional factor luxt from Vibrio harveyi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lin, Yi Hsing, 1969-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A luxO DNA binding protein (LuxT) was purified to homogeneity from V. harveyi after five major chromatography steps including a highly effective DNA affinity chromatography step and reverse phase HPLC. The sequences of three tryptic peptides obtained on digestion of the purified protein did not match any sequences in the protein data bank indicating that LuxT is a new V. harveyi protein. Inverse PCR was conducted sequentially to obtain the complete gene (luxT) coding for a protein of 153 amino acids which shares homology with the AcrR/TetR family of transcriptional regulators. Gene disruption of luxT in V. harveyi increased luxO expression and affected the cell density dependent induction of luminescence showing that LuxT is a repressor of luxO. As LuxT also affected the survival of the V. harveyi cells at high salt concentration and close homologues were present in other bacterial species suggested that the LuxT regulatory protein appears to be a general rather than a lux-specific regulator. The rpoS gene in V. harveyi has been cloned in this work and shown to code for a protein with high homology to the RpoS proteins in other species. The null mutant of RpoS has been constructed and the effect of rpoS deletion on stress resistance as well as the cell density dependent luminescence in V. harveyi were examined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Meighen, E. A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md522.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr38f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Microbiology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xd39h"><ual:graduationDate>2001</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Sociology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cultural sensitivity in the context of ethnic polities : a comparison of two families service agencies</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leung, Ho Hon, 1961-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This study explores the complex issues in culturally sensitive social services in the context of ethnic polities. We examine the reasons why the social service sector fails to provide equitable services to minorities. We explore the concept of ethnic match, services delivered by ethnic personnel, in an ethnic agency and using ethnic practice, as an attainable solution to the problems, by comparing with a Chinese and a Jewish ethno-specific family service agency in Montreal. The ways they deliver sensitive services to communities members and the challenges they face are documented. The dynamic of the ethnic polities in which these two agencies operate is also examined. We argue the formation and functioning of these agencies are shaped by a set of internal factors (within the communities) and external factors (in Quebec society). Culture plays a vital role in service delivery and help seeking, and also in the organization of these ethnic communities. Policy implications are discussed, and future research is suggested.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Weinfeld, Morton</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft021.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd39h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chinese -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jews -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Family services -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Minorities -- Services for -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Av692t795m"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Illitization and chloritization of illitesmectite and chloritesmectite mixed-layer clays in high-grade diagenetic and very low-grade metamorphic environments of Gaspe Peninsula, Quebec Appalachians, Canada : problems and solutions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shata, Salah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The present study deals with three main mineralogical and geochemical problems related to the behaviour of two common clay minerals---illite and chlorite---in the Lower Paleozoic sedimentary sequences of high-grade diagenetic and very low grade metamorphic (VLGM) zones in the Quebec Appalachians, Gaspe Peninsula. In high-grade diagenetic to VLGM zones, illite and chlorite coexist, but as they are notoriously fine-grained and intimately intergrown, tracing the chemical changes in chlorite with conventional (wet chemical method or electron microprobe) methods is a difficult task. A refined XRD method for the determination of the structural formula of chlorites was developed in this study. Application of this program to high-grade diagenetic to VLGM chlorite from the Gaspe Peninsula revealed that these chlorites are of "ripidolitic" to "pycnochloritic" composition and show a compositional homogenization in the anchizone, as compared to chlorite of the diagenetic zone. With increasing metamorphic grade, chlorites become less siliceous, have decreasing octahedral-site vacancies, and approach the ideal trioctahedral chlorite composition. Although Fe-asymmetry increases, the [Fe (total)] decreases, which may reflect a preferential decrease in [Fe (total)] in the brucite-like sheet. At high (&gt;80%) illite levels in mixed-layer illite smectite, the gradual improvement of illite crystallinity (IC), coupled with advancing VLGM conditions, suggests some modification of the clay mineral structure, possibly involving loss of the still existing expandable layers. Failure to detect expandable components in anchimetamorphic illitic materials upon glycolation has led previous investigators to rule out the existence of expandable components beyond the high-grade diagenetic zone. X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns and high-resolution transmission electron images of n-alkylammonium-cation-treated clay minerals showed the presence of expandable layers in high-grade diagenetic to VLGM phyllosilicates and document the impact of these expandable layers on IC measurements. With advancing diagenetic to VLGM grade, the intermediate metastable phases of a rectorite-like R1-ordered layer structure, either with an intermediate or high-charge vermiculite interface, and an R3-ordered structure are found in the fine fraction. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hesse, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c435s.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t795m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j054c"><ual:graduationDate>2000</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Depression and war : three essays on the Canadian economy 1930-45</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Rogers, Sean</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Two main points histories of the Second World War in Canada traditionally emphasize are (1) the role of war-related fiscal policy in finally ending the Great Depression and (2) the success of government control over the economy. Potential output estimates show a large output gap still in existence in 1939, with it quickly closing by 1941. The Dominion government's war-related fiscal policy emerges as the factor explaining this rapid recovery. But Dominion fiscal policy was also important to recovery before the war. Canada's participation in bi-lateral trade negotiations, which lowered tariffs, the chief instrument of contemporary Dominion government fiscal policy, in reciprocation for similar concessions, stimulated exports, the chief source of recovery before the war. The matter of success rests largely on how well the Department of Munitions and Supply achieved the Dominion government's strategic aims during the war. Two strategic aims identified in this thesis are the government's desire to minimize the costs associated with war production and to avoid over-expansion in the iron and steel industry. Examining the production records of the Dominion Steel and Coal Company (Dosco), a primary iron and steel firm, and the Trenton Steel Works, a secondary manufacturing firm, shows how the government allocated production in a least cost manner among Canadian producers, consistent with the first of these two aims. Through its Crown Corporations, the Department also strove to minimize the costs associated with establishing war plant. Concerning the second aim, the government avoided rehabilitating Dosco's steel plate mill until sufficient domestic demand warranted it. With its capacity extraneous to the Canadian industry, the government closed the mill after the war. In contrast to the importance previous research placed on political factors in explaining the government's conduct of the war effort, this thesis argues that considerations production costs and input prices were a vital part of the government's decision making process.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacKinnon, Mary</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp46w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j054c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Steel industry and trade -- Canada -- History</dc:subject><dc:subject>Depressions -- 1929 -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Economic aspects -- Canada</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canada -- Economic conditions -- 1918-1945</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>