<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9z903366d"><ual:graduationDate>2009</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of a novel pre-pore loop antibody against rat TRPV1</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hua, Pierce</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Splice variants of the transient receptor potential vanilloid type-1 (TRPV1) channel appear to be involved in the physiological detection of extracellular fluid (ECF) osmolality in the supraoptic nucleus (SON) and organum vasculosum lamina terminalis (OVLT). It remains to be determined whether these splice variants are directly involved as pore-forming proteins in the osmosensory transduction complex. Since these TRPV1 splice variants are not sensitive to capsaicin antagonists, such as capsazepine (Sharif Naeini et al., 2007), novel tools that specifically interfere with ion permeation through TRPV1 are required for functional studies on the involvement of this channel. In this study, we developed rabbit polyclonal antibodies targeting specifically the extracellular pre-pore loop region of rat TRPV1 (PH-4281). Histological results showed that PH-4281 is specific to rat TRPV1 and TRPV1 expression is found in regions that are known to be osmosensitive. PH-4281 could be used as a specific tool to study the osmosensory transduction complex.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s3951.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903366d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Sensory Receptor Cells -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRPV Cation Channels -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Osmolar Concentration</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arb68xg52g"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reliability of spasticity measurement based on tonic stretch reflex threshold</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Calota, Andra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Studies suggest that deficits in central regulation of stretch reflex thresholds (SRT) underlie both spasticity and other disorders of motor control. We investigated intra- and inter-evaluator reliability to quantify spasticity based on tonic SRT (TSRT) and the relationship between TSRT and Modified Ashworth Scale (MAS, clinical assessment of resistance to stretch). Spasticity was evaluated in 20 subjects with chronic stroke-related spasticity in two different days, by three evaluators. Twenty different velocity-dependent dynamic SRT (angle where biceps brachii EMG signal increased for a given velocity of stretch) were recorded. TSRT (excitability of motoneurons at 0°/sec) was then computed. Spasticity was also estimated with MAS. Reliability was moderately good for subjects with moderately high spasticity (intra--evaluator: 0.46 to 0.68, inter--evaluator: 0.53 to 0.68). There was no correlation between TSRT and MAS since they measure different phenomena. TSRT is a promising new measure of spasticity. Further improvements for its quantification are suggested.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b330.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xg52g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Reflex, Stretch</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cerebrovascular Accident -- physiopathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muscle Spasticity -- physiopathology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Muscle Spasticity -- diagnosis</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afb494c96k"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Focal plane array-Fourier transform-infrared (FPA-FTIR) spectroscopy as a tool in the simple and rapid classification of common environmental and food spoilage fungi</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pinchuk, Orley R. (Orley Rachel), 1980-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Environmental and food spoilage fungi cause billions of dollars in damage in North America alone each year, in the form of rotted wood and crops, spoiled food, and human and animal illness. Each of these threats could be drastically reduced if early and more rapid detection processes are developed to replace the serological methods that are currently in practice. The current North American protocol for establishing identification of contaminating fungi both in environment and food have a time frame of approximately one week to twenty-two days. The use of a Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectrometer, coupled with a focal-plan-array (FPA) detector, can theoretically shorten the time (analysis within minutes after obtaining a pure culture) it takes to identify and classify a fungal cell. FPA-FTIR spectroscopy is advantageous as little to no sample preparation is required and results are obtained in less than one minute per sample. The fungal subset chosen for this study includes representatives from five phyla, including Zygomycota (Mucor heimalis), Ascomycota (Neurospora crassa, Ophiostoma minor, Chaetomium globosporum, Alternaria brassicicola), Basidiomycota (Schizophyllum commune, Chaetomium globosporum), Deutromycota (Aspergillus niger, Penicillium notatum, Aureobasidium pullulans) and the Mycetozoa (dictyostelium discoideum, physarum polycephalum). Different variables were tested and evaluated, including variability in growth parameters, wet deposition of fungi versus dry smearing of fungi, optimal absorbance range, and spectral processing parameters as well as discrepancies from one instrument to another, as well as spectral reproducibility from one instrument to another. By following the experimental protocol developed, reproducible spectra were attained, and differentiation of the fungi within the set selected for this study was achieved. The results of this work demonstrate that FPA-FTIR spectroscopy can potentially be employed for the accurate identification of environmental and food spoilage fungi.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n61z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c96k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Food spoilage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Infrared imaging</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fungi -- Identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Focal planes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ac534fs44n"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Cycle-to-cycle control of plastic sheet heating on the AAA thermoforming machine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Yang, Shuonan, 1984-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The objectives of this project are (1) to reduce the excursions between real heater temperatures and the desired values, and (2) to realize cyclic production of plastic sheets on the AAA thermoforming machine. At first, present relevant knowledge and modeling of the AAA machine are covered. A programmable pre-processing module is inserted before the heaters to prevent the input commands from delaying in heater response. The results prove that the excursions can be theoretically reduced to zero. Based on the Terminal Iterative Learning Control (TILC) algorithm, a hybrid dual-mode cascade-loop system is designed: the inner loop monitors the real-time temperatures for PID control in Mode 0, while the outer loop reads temperatures and commands once per cycle to decide the necessity of switching mode. A more realistic version with flexible cycle length and instant response to operator's commands is also designed to simulate the real operating circumstance.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042x71x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fs44n</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Iterative methods (Mathematics)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thermoforming</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intelligent control systems</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j4687"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Random controlled free radical copolymerization of acrylic acidstyrene and tert-butyl acrylatestyrene mixtures using nitroxide mediators</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lessard, Benoît H., 1985-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Controlled free radical polymerization facilitates the production of polymers with highly defined microstructures like traditional ionic polymerization; but in contrast allows for previously unattainable monomer combinations such as acrylic acid in its non-protected form. Incorporation of acrylic acid into styrene was done by random copolymerization of acrylic acid (directly and in its protected form as tert-butyl acrylate) with styrene. Styrene/tert-butyl acrylate (S/t-BuA) as well as styrene/acrylic acid (S/AA) mixtures were copolymerized to form tapered or gradient copolymers. Using an alkoxyamine unimolecular initiator, 2-[N- tert-butyl-2,2-(dimethylpropyl)aminooxy] propionic acid (BlocBuilder RTM), along with additional free nitroxide (SG1), the effect of acid protection on polymerization kinetics and copolymer composition was determined. Adding 4.5 mol% SG1/BlocBuilderRTM greatly improved the control of S/t-BuA copolymerization with low polydispersities (1.14-1.22) whereas the S/AA required higher levels of SG1 to produce polymers with low polydispersities that were comparatively still broader compared to the S/t-BuA system (polydispersities ~ 1.3-1.4 at 9 mol% SG1/BlocBuilderRTM). S/AA copolymerization required higher SG1 concentrations to compensate for degradation of SG1 by attack from the acrylic acid monomer.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nf82k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j4687</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Acrylic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polystyrene -- Synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copolymers -- Synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitroxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>Styrene</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acrylates</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An009w595z"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>RF compression of electron bunches applied to ultrafast electron diffraction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chatelain, Robert P., 1982-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The dynamics of atomic scale structures during structural change can be studied by Ultrafast Electron Diffraction (UED). The time resolution needed to reveal the fastest dynamics is 100 fs. Sub-angstrom structural resolution becomes possible with 1-1000 pC of charge necessary for diffraction pattern analysis during subtle structural changes. This combination of requirements cannot currently be realized due to the space-charge temporal broadening inherent to bunches of electrons of high fluence and short temporal duration. Simulations show that the incorporation of a specially designed Radio-Frequncy (RF) cavity into the UED apparatus removes this technical limitation. The RF cavity reverses the near linear position-momentum distribution of the temporally broadened electron bunch, causing the bunch to recompress itself as it propagates. It is found that our proposed method allows for sub-100 fs bunches with maximum charge of 0.6 pC, almost 3 orders of magnitude improvement over today's state of the art.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j947.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w595z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cavity resonators</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laser pulses, Ultrashort</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electrons -- Diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Radio frequency</dc:subject><dc:subject>Picosecond pulses</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r477q"><ual:graduationDate>2008</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pathology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of bone morphogenic proteins and transforming growth factor [beta] on in-vitro endothelin-1 production by human pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Star, Gregory</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Introduction: Idiopathic Pulmonary arteriole hypertension (IPAH) is a rare but severely debilitating disease that strikes women to men at a ratio of 3:1. Endothelial cell (EC) dysfunction is a hallmark of the disease. This includes rapid growth of the ECs until the occlusion of the vasculature as well as decreased blood levels of vasodilators. Markedly increased levels of endothelin-1, a potent vasoconstrictor and smooth muscle mitogen, have been noted in IPAH patients. Recently mutations in the bone morphogenic protein receptor type II (BMPRII) have been linked to the disease. Interestingly mutations in activin-like kinase-1 (ALK-1) and endoglin have been linked to hereditary haemorrhagic telangiectasia (HHT), a disease that results in PAH clinically indistinguishable from IPAH. All of these proteins are either receptors or co-receptors to members of the TGFbeta superfamily. The connection of these mutations to the disease still remains largely a mystery to researchers and the effects of either bone morphogenic proteins 2, 4, 7 or TGFbeta levels on endothelin-1(ET-1) production in human microvascular endothelial cells cultured from normal lungs (HMVEC-LBI) are unknown. Methods: HMVEC-LBI cells were cultured in the presence of various concentrations of BMP 2,4,7 and TGFbeta, in complete media or serum starved conditions. After allotted time points the media was collected and assayed by ELISA, meanwhile the cells were lysed and protein content assayed for normalization purposes. Small Mothers against Decapentaplegic (SMAD) 1/5 phosphorylation was also measured. Results and Conclusions: Despite evidence that all BMPs used were biologically active, namely through SMAD phosphorylation studies, only BMP7 at very high dosages increased ET-1 production levels. TGFbeta had a more pronounced effect at earlier time points with lower concentrations. The results provide insights on the effects of an important group of proteins, the BMPs and TGFbeta, on lung microvascular ECs and which are likely the key cellular player In IPAH development. These findings may have clinical relevance in terms of control of the disease and understanding the normal response of these cells BMPs and TGFbeta.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mg65j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r477q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Bone Morphogenetic Protein 4 -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bone Morphogenetic Protein 7 -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endothelin-1 -- biosynthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lung -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bone Morphogenetic Protein 2 -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endothelium, Vascular -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transforming Growth Factor beta1 -- metabolism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A000003709"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of CD4⁺ Foxp3⁺ naturally-occurring regulatory T cells in the host immune response to Plasmodium chabaudi AS</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>St-Pierre, Jessica</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Naturally-occurring CD4+Foxp3+ regulatory T cells (nTreg) play a central role in maintaining immune self-tolerance as well as modulating immunity towards pathogens. Pathogens may establish chronic infections in immunocompetent hosts by engaging nT reg in order to promote immunosuppression. The goal of the research described here is to test the hypothesis that nTreg modulate protective immunity to malaria, and consequentially affect susceptibility to the parasite. To investigate this question, the functional dynamics of CD4+Foxp3 + nTreg cells were evaluated in mice infected with blood-stage Plasmodium chabaudi AS. Adoptive transfer of nTreg to infected wild-type C57BL/6 (B6) mice or infection of transgenic B6 mice over-expressing Foxp3 resulted in increased parasitemia and reduced survival compared to control mice. Moreover, while resistant B6 mice exhibited decreased splenic nT reg frequencies at day 7 post infection, susceptible A/J mice maintained high numbers of nTreg at this time. Investigation of the effects of nTreg regulation on immune cell function in P. chabaudi AS-infected mice revealed that increased nTreg frequencies led to decreased malaria-specific lymphoproliferation and increased systemic levels of IL-10. Unlike B6 mice, increased splenic nTreg frequencies in infected A/J mice correlated with decreased effector T cell proliferation and IFN-gamma secretion, decreased B cell and NK cell proliferation as well as deficient IFN-gamma secretion by NK cells. Finally, nTreg proliferated within infected sites in both B6 and A/J mice, albeit to a greater extent in susceptible A/J mice. Altogether, these results demonstrate that nTreg suppressed anti-malarial immunity, and in turn promoted parasite growth and persistence.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c97v.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000003709</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>T-Lymphocytes, Regulatory -- immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antigens, CD4 -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Forkhead Transcription Factors -- metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Malaria -- immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasmodium chabaudi -- immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f7284"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigations of the biocatalytic activity of human P450 2D6</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zhao, Jin, 1975-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The cytochrome P450 enzymes (CYPs) are very attractive biocatalysts because of their ability to regio- and stereo-selectively catalyze the insertion of a single atom of molecular oxygen into inactivated C-H bonds. There are many drawbacks, however, limiting the use of these enzymes in organic synthesis, including the need for expensive cofactors, low stability, and low tolerance to organic solvents. The goal of this thesis was to overcome some of these drawbacks for human CYP2D6. This isoform was selected because of its broad substrate promiscuity and high importance in drug metabolism. We have tested inexpensive chemicals to replace the natural cofactors of CYP2D6, NADPH and cytochrome P450 reductase (CPR). The results showed that cumene hydroperoxide and tert-butyl hydroperoxide can successfully substitute CPR and NAD(P)H with retained regio- and stereo-selectivity. Moreover, with these surrogates, product formation and initial rates are increased by as much as two fold compared to the use of the natural cofactors. It is widely accepted that even small proportions of organic solvents in the buffer can deactivate most enzymes including P450s. Our studies on the biocatalysis of CYP2D6 in organic solvent/buffer emulsions showed that under the optimized conditions, as much as 76% of the enzyme activity was retained. Product formation in biphasic solvent systems is comparable whether the natural redox partner and cofactor are used, or a surrogate. In addition, a correlation was observed between the log P and the suitability of a solvent for enzymatic activity, with higher log P resulting in higher enzymatic activity. These results were obtained with dextromethorphan (DXM), a water soluble substrate. A very hydrophobic substrate, 7-benzyloxy-4-N,N-diethylaminomethyl-coumarin (BDAC), was also tested successfully to demonstrate the utility of this method. Lyophilization is usually required to remove water before using enzymes in nearly anhydrous solvents. This physical process is harmful to P450 enzyme activity. We therefore tested numerous sugars as lyoprotectant during lyophilization. Addition of trehalose or sucrose before lyophilization allowed the retention of 80% of the CYP2D6 activity, compared to 40% remaining activity in its absence. CYP2D6 co-lyophilized with trehalose was next tested in selected hydrophobic organic solvents in the absence of water. The enzymatic activity was found to strongly depend on the hydrophobicity of the solvent. Interestingly, the enzyme showed higher catalytic ability in n-decane or n-dodecane than in the standard buffer. This was unexpected considering that the activity of most enzymes was reported to decrease to 10% or less in nearly anhydrous organic solvents. The last objective of this thesis was to improve the stability and/or activity of CYP2D6. Use of DNA self-assemblies to encapsulate P450 enzymes was envisaged to potentially increase their stability. Indeed, DNA assemblies have many advantages compared to traditional solid supports reported for enzymes. Our preliminary results showed that CYP2D6 templated the formation of cyclic DNA dimeric and tetrameric over polymeric self-assemblies. Characterization of the CYP2D6 activity in the presence of the DNA self-assemblies revealed no loss of activity or stability.</dc:abstract><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fg47q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f7284</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Cytochrome P-450 CYP2D6</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cytochrome P-450</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Amw22v9380"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemical Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Interaction of DEHA with mammalian cells</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>McGlynn, Andrea</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This project studied the biodegradation of a plasticizer, di-(2-ethylhexyl) adipate (DEHA), by two mammalian cell lines, HepG2 and WIF-B, in vitro . An MTT assay showed that DEHA had a toxic effect on both cell lines. Despite this, both hepatocyte cell lines successfully degraded the plasticizer. Metabolites were identified and quantified by gas chromatography. HepG2 cells showed minimal alcohol dehydrogense activity and this resulted in the accumulation of 2-ethylhexanol. WIF-B cells were able to breakdown the alcohol and produced 2-ethylhexanoic acid. It is important to note that an enzyme was essential for this step in the degradation of the plasticizer, as this proves that it was biodegradation and not physical degradation. By comparing the metabolites formed and the order of their appearance, the degradation pathway in these mammalian cells was found to be similar to the established degradation pathways for bacteria, fungi and yeast.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236594h.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v9380</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Liver cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasticizers -- Biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasticizers -- Toxicology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carboxylic acids -- Biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carboxylic acids -- Toxicology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kf36b"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Elastin in zebrafish and mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Bhanji, Tania</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The extracellular matrix is a vital component of the cardiovascular system, in that, it not only provides structural support but also plays a critical role in the maintenance of cellular stability. One of the major components of the vascular matrix is elastin, which confers vessels with the specialized property of stretch and recoil. Elastin deficiency has been implicated in many vascular diseases and determined experimentally to be a negative regulator of smooth muscle cell proliferation. In zebrafish, two elastin genes have been identified, which are actively expressed during development. Based on this finding, protein production and spatial localization for the two elastin proteins was studied by immunohistochemistry with specific antibodies. Results revealed a global distribution for elastin 1 in the ventral aorta and swim bladder, whereas elastin 2 was preferentially localized to the bulbus arteriosus indicating a possible specialized function of elastin 2 in this structure. This observation, and the unique physiological property of this structure, suggests a possible reason for the preservation of both elastin genes during evolution. In the second part of this study, elastin-null mice were studied to uncover the impact of the loss of elastin on the expression of other elastic fiber-associated proteins. The expression of fibrillin-1, the major component of microfibrils, was not altered in the absence of elastin, implying that elastin is not necessary for the formation of microfibrils. On the other hand, both fibulin-2 and -5 were upregulated in the absence of elastin, suggesting that expression of these genes are controlled by elastin. Overall, this study highlights the importance of elastin in evolution, as well as its potential role in the regulation of expression of other matrix molecules.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80j0255.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kf36b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Elastin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Extracellular Matrix Proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mice -- genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zebrafish -- genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awm117s57g"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Study of two putative prostate cancer tumor markers</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Shun, Kitty</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The following thesis is based on my study of two candidate prostate cancer tumor markers, namely telomerase and CD9. Accordingly, the thesis will be divided in two main chapters describing the results obtained for each protein. Although these proteins are de-regulated in prostate cancer cells, little is known about their regulation and function in prostate cells. For example, telomerase is generally inactive in normal cells and reactivated in cancer cells and CD9 is a transmembrane protein that is lost as prostate cancer progresses. In chapter 2, I will show that introduction of normal human chromosomes into mouse melanoma cells can shut down its telomerase activity by inhibiting hTERT transcription and that the gene encoding this regulator is likely located on human chromosome 17p11.1. Additionally, following further characterization of CD9 partners in chapter 3, we will learn more about the likely mechanism by which CD9 induces mitotic catastrophe when over-expressed in prostate cancer cells.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dt138.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s57g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zx907"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Quality of life and its predictors among the elderly Chinese people living in Montreal, Canada</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Tianli, 1976-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>While Quality of Life (QOL) among aging populations has been attracting more and more attention in the last few years, little QOL research has been carried out among the elderly Chinese minority. This is a cross sectional study aimed at estimating the Quality of Life (QOL) and exploring QOL indicators among the elderly Chinese people living in Montreal. Forty-one volunteer study participants, 65 years or older were recruited from 12 Chinese community centers in Montreal. Their QOL was measured by the Ferrans and Powers Quality of Life Index (1985). The study results showed that participants generally described a very high level of life satisfaction. Living arrangements, gender, education and social support were found to be important QOL indicators. This study has important implications for health service and policy and raises the need for further future research using a larger random sample.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf53r.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zx907</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Gerontology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225f79c"><ual:graduationDate>2007</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Division of Neuroscience</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Basal and stress-reactive cortisol levels in patients with Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lai, Wai Bun Benjamin</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases (IBD) are chronic remitting-relapsing diseases of the gastrointestinal tract. Psychological stress has long been suspected to play a role in the pathogenesis and symptom exacerbation of IBD. The goal of this study was to examine whether or not there exist any differences in the stress reactivity in patients with IBD when compared to healthy controls. Salivary cortisol was employed as a biomarker to assess the activity of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis---normally activated upon the perception of a psychological stressor---in IBD patients and healthy controls. Ten quiescent IBD patients were recruited and each was asked to identify a healthy age- and gender-matched friend to participate in the study to act as a control. In addition, 10 healthy age- and gender-matched subjects who were not friends of the IBD patients were recruited as a second control group. All subjects completed 4 psychological questionnaires: the NEO Personality Five Factor Inventory; the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale; the Perceived Stress Scale; and the Coping Inventory for Stress Situations. Subjects were asked to sample their saliva at home in order to discern their basal salivary cortisol secretion pattern. As well, subjects underwent a psychosocial stress protocol, the Trier Social Stress Test (TSST), during which saliva samples were obtained to determine their stress-reactive cortisol levels. Results from this study indicate that IBD patients and their friends are significantly more agreeable in personality and showed a blunted HPA response to the TSST, when compared to healthy non-friends. These results point to a distinct personality profile and a possible social support phenomenon among IBD patients and their friends, which may modulate HPA reactivity to psychological stress and contribute to the differential cortisol response observed.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x752k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225f79c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Neuroscience</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Am900nz301"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of CD3 chains in thymocyte differentiation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Brodeur, Jean-François</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>T cell development in the thymus is a highly evolved process. Signal transduction is critical to mediate maturation of T cells. Expression of pre-T cell receptor (pre-TCR) and TCR complex on cell surface allows signal transduction that is critical for T cell maturation. Four CD3 chains, which are gamma, delta, epsilon, and zeta, are associated with the two types of receptor complexes and play essential roles in T cell activation. While CD3gamma-, epsilon-, or zeta-deficient mice show impaired pre-TCR function, CD3delta deficiency impairs thymocyte development at the double positive (DP) stage indicating that it is not required for pre-TCR-mediated double negative (DN) to DP transition. In the present thesis, we have assessed the role of two highly homologous CD3 chains, CD3gamma and CD3delta, in the DN to DP transition. We describe two mouse models to show that CD3delta is required for pre-TCR-mediated DN to DP transition. We also show that the cytoplasmic domain of CD3gamma plays a critical role in the DN to DP transition depending on the genetic background.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh22c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nz301</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514nq027"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The role of the androgen receptor CAG repeat polymorphism in the AR-T877A prostate cancer somatic mutant</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Southwell, Jason M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The androgen receptor plays a critical role in both normal and neoplastic prostate growth. The first exon of the androgen receptor contains a polymorphic CAG repeat region that has been implicated in the development of prostate cancer. Epidemiologic studies suggest that shorter CAG repeats are associated with an increased risk of prostate cancer. Interestingly, the length of the CAG repeat region in the androgen receptor is inversely correlated with the transactivational competence of the receptor. This provides a biologically plausible mechanism by which the more active androgen receptors with shorter CAG repeats can contribute to prostate cancer. However, the effect of variation in CAG repeat length is unknown in the late-stages of the disease. The primary goal of the work presented in this thesis was to determine the effects of different AR CAG repeat lengths in a late-stage prostate cancer environment where androgen receptor mutations are more common and may override the functional attributes of short CAG repeats. To that end, we have assessed the effects of CAG repeat lengths in a common prostate cancer mutant androgen receptor Thr877Ala. Our results suggest that the Thr877Ala mutant exhibits different transactivation trends than the wild-type receptor with respect to CAG repeat length. These data may indicate that, although CAG length may have a significant effect in wild-type receptors and in early disease, the activity of mutant receptors found in later stages of prostate cancer may limit the CAG effect.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2688941.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nq027</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Oncology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An870zv24h"><ual:graduationDate>2006</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The ecological value of hedgerows for conserving temperate forest herbs in agricultural landscapes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Roy, Valérie, 1981-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is growing evidence that the achievement of biodiversity conservation objectives at the regional scale will have to take into account not only habitats within reserves, but also the contribution of semi-natural habitats in production landscapes. This requires knowledge of the conditions that maintain or enhance biodiversity in these suboptimal habitats. I focused on a system of forest patches and hedgerows in an agricultural landscape as habitats for dispersal-limited native forest herbs to (1) identify species-specific traits that appear to either limit or facilitate survival or colonization of forest herbs in hedgerows compared to forest patches, and (2) to evaluate the relative contribution of landscape and local variables in explaining patterns of forest herb species richness, abundance, and diversity in hedgerows. A fourth-corner analysis revealed that traits such as early spring flowering, ant dispersal or a lack of vegetative propagation can reduce the likelihood of native forest species to benefit from hedgerows. Conditional autoregressive models showed that landscape variables, specifically hedgerow age and neighboring forest area, largely account for species diversity in hedgerows.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w3431.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zv24h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural landscape management -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Windbreaks, shelterbelts, etc. -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Forest plants -- Conservation -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2n49t583z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Second Language Education</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation into variability of tasks and teacher-judges in second language oral performance assessment</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kim, Youn-Hee, 1979-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Abstract not available.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p28c.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t583z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Language and languages -- Ability testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oral communication -- Ability testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Korean speakers</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax633f4870"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Plant Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The landscape ecology of the invasive species Phragmites australis in anthropogenic linear wetlands</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maheu-Giroux, Mathieu, 1981-</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The recent and rapid expansion of Phragmites australis in North America provides an opportunity to relate dispersal patterns to landscape structure. Linear wetlands, such as roadside or agricultural ditches, may serve as corridors that facilitate dispersal at the landscape scale, but there is little quantitative information on patterns of invasion in these habitats. Remote sensing data, GIS, and field observations were used (1) to assess the feasibility of mapping populations of P. australis in linear wetlands and (2) to quantify and explain recent invasion patterns of P. australis in two periurban areas of southern Quebec. An accuracy assessment demonstrated the reliability of aerial photographs to map populations in linear habitats. The intrinsic growth rate observed is high compared to those reported in natural wetlands. Spatial analysis revealed that colonization events are not constrained by the network's configuration. Logistic regressions confirmed the effect of road corridors on the spread of P. australis.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bn102.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f4870</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Plant invasions -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phragmites australis -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agq67jv76s"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic risk factors for suicide in major depression : a focus on the serotonin transporter and tryptophan hydroxylase-2 genes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lopez de Lara Gutierrez, Catalina</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Growing evidence suggests a partial genetic determination of suicide predisposition, with most studies focusing on serotonergic genes. Inconsistent results have characterized the serotonin transporter (5-HTT) gene, whereas few studies have investigated the recently discovered brain specific tryptophan hydroxylase 2 (TPH2) gene. At the same time, most of these studies have not controlled for associated psychopathology, an important confounder. Therefore, association studies were conducted to investigate the role of the 5-HTT and TPH2 genes in suicide susceptibility in the context of major depression and their effect on impulsive-aggressive behaviors (IABs), a possible intermediate phenotype. Finally, suicide predictors were investigated while controlling for genetic, clinical and behavioral risk factors. Certain 5-HTT and TPH2 genetic variants were significantly implicated in the vulnerability to suicide, however, no effect on levels of IABs was observed. Genetic and clinical suicide predictors were identified while controlling for other risk factors. Further studies in larger samples are necessary to replicate these findings and detect possible small genetic effects.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw33f.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jv76s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5999n701z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigation of impulsive-aggressive behaviors in suicide : a clinical and genetic approach</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Zouk, Hana</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Impulsivity and aggression have been shown to be important behavioral correlates of suicide. Neurobiological and genetic studies, mostly focusing on the serotonergic system, have demonstrated that these behaviors not only have clinical implications in suicide but also play an important biological role in increasing suicide risk. It remains unclear, however, how impulsivity and aggression might mediate suicide risk. The first study presented here was carried out to investigate clinical, behavioral and psychosocial correlates of impulsivity in suicide completers. Impulsive suicides were characterized by a greater psychiatric comorbidity as well as increased levels of aggression, and were more likely to be affected by negative life events. In a separate study, the effect of genetic variants of the 5-HT1B gene on impulsive aggressive behaviors (IABs) in suicide, as well as their contribution to overall suicide risk, was investigated. One 5-HT1B promoter variant significantly influenced levels of aggressive behaviors in suicide completers, suggesting that aggression plays a role as an intermediate phenotype that increases propensity to suicide. Both studies highlight the importance of the role of IABs in mediating suicide at both clinical and biological levels.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m898.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n701z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Genetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3t945v54k"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Screening for cognitive impairment following stroke : Rasch analysis of the Mini-Mental State Exam</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Xenopoulos, Agnes A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Stroke is a leading cause of disability for adults. Several studies confirm cognitive impairment in persons following stroke. Every stroke patient should have rapid access to cognitive screening and evaluation. In this study, Rasch analysis was used to determine the suitability of the telephone version of the Mini-Mental State Examination (MMSE) in screening for cognitive impairment in persons with stroke. The specific objectives were to determine the range of difficulty represented by the items of the telephone version of the MMSE, to identify the hierarchy of item difficulty and to compare the French and English versions of the test. Rasch analysis was conducted on data obtained from 267 persons with first-ever stroke who completed the telephone version of the MMSE at 1 month post stroke. Results indicated that the telephone version of the MMSE did not target the full range of the persons' cognitive ability, especially for those with 'higher' cognitive ability. The item difficulty ranged from (-3.258 to 2.585 logits), and the average person mean (2.351 logits) was greater than the average item mean set at 0. The test was easy for most persons; the majority were situated above the mean item difficulty. Fit of the items to the Rasch model is discussed with alternate scoring methods suggested.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903367p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v54k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1r66j469h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Role of CD3 delta in T cell development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Pan, Qinghua</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The T cell receptor (TCR)/CD3 complex consists of a TCRalphabeta heterodimer and invariant CD3gamma, delta, epsilon and zeta chains. CD3 components play a critical role in T-cell development and function. Thymocyte development is impaired at the CD4-CD8- double negative stage in CD3gamma-, epsilon-, or zeta-deficient mice, whereas CD3delta deficiency impairs thymocyte maturation at the CD4+CD8 +double positive stage. However, the stoichiometry of CD3gamma and CD3delta chains on the surface TCR/CD3 complex has not been determined. In the present study, transgenic mice expressing a truncated form of CD3delta and CD3gamma that lacked the whole cytoplasmic domain were employed to show that the surface TCR/CD3 complex contains one molecule each of CD3delta and CD3gamma. During our studies, we found that the human CD3delta/epsilon transgene could rescue thymocyte development not only in CD3epsilon -/- mice, but also in CD3gamma-/- mice. Our data suggested that CD3delta may be required for the preTCR function in human, but not in mice.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c984.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j469h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology, Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arf55zc33h"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Modeling development and evolution of the wing-patterning network in insects</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Nahmad Bensusan, Marcos</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Gene regulatory networks control patterning and growth in a developing organism. However, environmental factors may also dramatically affect development to produce morphological diversity. In ant species for example, environmental cues determine whether a winged queen or a wingless worker or soldier will develop from a fertilized egg. A mathematical model of the gene network that controls wing development in a group of insects is presented. Despite the complexity of the network, numerical solutions of the equations tend to a steady-state that correlates with the experimental expression patterns. Theoretical analysis provides insight into the mechanisms that control patterning of the wing. The effects of genatic and environmental perturbations, which are simulated by varying the parameters of the model, on the dynamics of gene expression and growth are studied. The results predict perturbations that might be responsible for suppressing wing development in some ant species. This work provides insight into the mechanisms by which wing suppression may have evolved.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n218p.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zc33h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biophysics, General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A12579w98z"><ual:graduationDate>2005</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Peptidergic sensory and parasympathetic fibre sprouting in the mucosa of the rat urinary bladder in a chronic model of cyclophosphamide-induced cystitis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dickson, Laura Alison</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chronic bladder pain is becoming more and more prevalent and yet there is a lack of effective treatment because there is so little known about the mechanisms causing this type of pain. A possible etiology of chronic bladder pain is persistent inflammation. It has been proposed that inflammation initiates neurological changes in the bladder and CNS which could lead to sensitization of the bladder to cause chronic pain and frequency. Both autonomic and sensory innervation changes in the periphery can lead to hyperalgesia and allodynia, thus we have chosen to look for autonomic and sensory innervation changes that occur in the bladder in a model of chronic cystitis. In this study, we used a well established animal model to investigate changes in the peptidergic and parasympathetic innervation of the bladder following chronic bladder inflammation. Adult female Sprague-Dawley rats were injected with either 70mg/kg cyclophosphamide diluted in saline, i.p., once every 3 days or saline. After 10 days, all animals were tested for urinary frequency and number of low volume voids, as well as symptoms of spontaneous pain. At the end of 12 days, all animals were perfused with histological fixatives and the urinary bladders processed for immunofluorescence using antibodies against calcitonin gene-related peptide (CGRP) and the vesicular acetylcholine transporter (VAChT) as markers, respectively, of peptidergic primary afferent fibres and parasympathetic efferent fibres. We show that animals treated with cyclophosphamide had inflamed bladders and displayed high urinary frequency as well as some indicators of spontaneous pain, such as piloerection and a rounded-back posture. Furthermore, they had a significant increase in the density of both parasympathetic and peptidergic sensory fibres in the bladder mucosa and an increase in peptidergic sensory fibres in the detrusor muscle. Thus from our results, we propose that parasympathetic and sensory peptidergic innervation changes can occur in the bladder following chronic cystitis. Since we observed that the parasympathetic and peptidergic fibres often wrapped around one another or were in close proximity, these two fibre populations may be interacting with each other to lead to and maintain sensitization. These innervation changes may be responsible for prolonged and exacerbated urinary symptoms and may play a role in diseases where there is chronic urinary pain, such as in interstitial cystitis.</dc:abstract><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074z73k.PDF</ual:fedora3Handle><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579w98z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>