<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c5856"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reversible disturbances of function following cortical insult</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Forgays, Donald G.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Historically, there have been two main approaches to the analysis of cerebral function. From one point of view, it has been maintained that different psychological attributes or functions reside in different parts of the cerebrum. In contrast to this, the position has been held by many that there is no such localization of function. It is now quite clear that many functions can be localized, in the sense that a loss of a limited region of cerebral tissue results in a qualitatively limited, or restricted, loss of function, and a loss of much cerebral tissue elsewhere in the brain does not produce the same loss.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hebb, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg977.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c5856</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6682x711b"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The design of a dual frequency short wave antenna</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fairley, Randolph Douglas</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Broadside arrays employing tiers of horizontal colinear elements have attained considerable prominence in the short-wave broadcasting field. One may, in fact, cite many of their characteristics as standards by which other radiating systems are judged. As conventionally designed, however, the broadside array is used for single frequency operation only. If consideration be given to the number of frequency bands which must be used to provide optimum broadcast service throughout the cyclical variations in ionospheric density, a very costly set of arrays is indicated.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Watson, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xz362.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x711b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bx67q"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of English</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Leaf without shadow</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Fague, William Robert</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Warren thought of many, many things with his duffle bag heavy on his shoulder, his fingers flexing and tightening around the curve of the thick, steel railing, his eyes passing lightly over the business of unloading a troopship, but most of all he thought about going home. For him the worst of the Army was over; for him, even though the actual fighting had ceased many months ago, there had followed the ordeal of occupation, the dreary policing of unpoliceable people. He watched the gangplank moving slowly; he tried to be patient.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Files, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m516w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx67q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>English</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gh13p"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of disilyl alkanes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>English, William David</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The chemistry of organo-metallic compounds has been an important field of investigation, providing a link between organic and inorganic chemistry. Valuable organo-metallic compounds of many uses have been discovered or synthesized: drugs, such as the arsenic compounds; reaction intermediates, such as Grignard reagents and lithium alkyls; and polymeric substances, such as the silicones. The organic chemistry of Group IV elements is interesting because these elements, being tetracovalent, can act much more like carbon than any other hetero elements can.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb92q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gh13p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avq27zr766"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The iron formation of Snelgrove Lake, Labrador</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Engineer, Behram Burjorji</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>During the summer of 1949 the writer was engaged by the Labrador Mining and Exploration Company of Montreal on a survey party mapping an area in central Labrador and, in particular, a band of iron-bearing formation that runs through it. In the winter of the same year a petrographic study of the formation was undertaken at McGill University, by the writer, and is the subject of this thesis. The iron formation lies between the lakes Snelgrove, to the south east, and Comeback, to the north, both of which are situated within the Dyke Lake Sheet and lie in the concession of the above-mentioned company.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Holcomb, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74ct94v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zr766</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Awp988p170"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Kinetics and properties of ascorbic acid oxidase</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Elliott, Bernard Burton</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Since the discovery of ascorbic acid oxidase by Szent-Gyorgyi (55) in 1931, an ever increasing number of plant species and parts have been shown to contain the enzyme. The following list (Table I) of ascorbic acid oxidase-containing plants has been compiled from the literature up to and including 1950. The list, though small, includes plants from eleven families of the Monocotyledoneae and Dicotyledoneae. Several investigators (16, 20, 55, 62) consider that ascorbic acid oxidase in these plants plays a terminal role in their respiration but others (2, 7), are not in agreement with this view owing mainly to the limited distribution of the enzyme. The work reported here has been chiefly devoted to a study of the kinetics of the enzyme as a contribution to the general knowledge of the respiratory enzymes of plants.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Waygood, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042x38w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p170</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Botany</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8k71nm48g"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The huronian rocks of Northwestern Ontario</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Eade, Kenneth E.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Extending eastward from the Sault Ste. Marie area of Ontario, along the north shore of Lake Huron, thence northeastward through the Sudbury and Lake Wanapitei areas, to the Gowganda and Cobalt areas and on into the Province of Quebec, there is a belt of Algonkian rocks of Huronian age. They consist for the most part of clastic Sediments, quartzites, arkoses, greywackes, conglomerates and possibly tillites, with minor amounts of limestone and volcanic extrusive rocks. The rocks of this belt have been the subject of much study and many reports.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Clark, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236561z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nm48g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0z709102z"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geological Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Map area west of Timmins Bay, Lake Attikamagen, Labrador</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dubuc, Fernand</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The area to be described is situated in Labrador (latitude 54° 52' N., longitude 66° 30' W.) on the concession of Labrador Mining and Exploration Company. It lies just west of Timmins Bay, Attikamagen Lake, and covers an approximately rectangular area of a little less than 2-1/2 square miles. (See map, page 4). The area is accessible from Knob Lake using the Company’s seaplanes, the distance being approximately 12 miles eastward.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gill, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924f94v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709102z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apv63g340f"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Philosophy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A discussion of Benedetto Croce’s philosophy of history</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kushner, Eva</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It would be unfaithful to Croce's own principles to attribute to the historical genesis of his philosophy excessive importance. But though one must recognize that it is not a mere product of circumstances, it is necessary to grasp the nature of the background against which it arose. Only then will its polemical character become apparent, and only then will it assume the place due to it in the chain of philosophical progress. We must not attempt to consider his philosophy of history as a system to be connected with other systems; the changing, prolific nature of Croce's thought as well as his own assertions in his "Autobiography" forbid such an approach; and to systematize where the author himself does not would be too presumptuous a project, and might falsify the understanding of Croce's thought in the process of crystallizing it.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Klibansky, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk51z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g340f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Philosophy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c586g"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agronomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Relation of estimates of the availability of phosphorus to soil treatments and to crop yields</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Doyle, James John</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>"Phosphorus is so basic to the whole problem of crop production that probably no other subject in the field of soil fertility has received more attention than the phosphorus problem in its various soil-plant and soil-animal relationships and it probably will continue to challenge the best efforts of investigators for many years”. (27). "Phosphorus is the only element which must be purchased and returned to the most common soils of the United States, it is the key to permanent agriculture on these soils". (20).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>DeLong, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv84m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c586g</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ax346d738t"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anatomy</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Demonstration of a ‘steady state’ of thyroidal iodine</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dougherty, Joan L.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Nowadays it is customary to regard all cells as miniature physical-chemical factories with specializations particular to each tissue or organ. The activity of cells may involve only the synthesis of substances for the upkeep of the cells themselves, or, in addition, the synthesis of substances to be released to the outside. In the latter case, raw materials are taken into the cell, incorporated into some new substance, and then released in this new form into the extra-cellular spaces or to the outside. The activity of such a secreting cell can be subdivided into a number of phases. Those may be performed singly or simultaneously.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>MacIntosh, F.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f692z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d738t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anatomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Acn69m7292"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of the motivational factor involved in academic success</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dickie, Robert Daniel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This investigation is an attempt to obtain a quantitative measure of the motivational factor involved in academic achievement at the university level. Intelligence tests can be used successfully to discriminate between those who would most likely profit from a university education and those who would not, but their ability to predict success within the university group itself, is of a low order. The primary assumption in this piece of research is that prediction at this level involves more factors than intelligence, and that probably the most important among these other factors is motivation. If tests of these two factors were used conjointly, it is assumed that they would provide a better predictive statistic than either used separately. Since there is no known test of human motivation this investigation is an attempt to develop one.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Ferguson, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wt79q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m7292</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Arx913t10d"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The y-ray induced oxidation of Fr+2 ion in dilute aqueous solution</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dewhurst, Harold A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1895, Roentgen (1) discovered that invisible rays emanating from an electrical discharge tube produced blackening of a covered photographic plate. In the following year Beoqueral (2) observed a similar phenomenon produced by invisible rays from uranium-containing compounds. These were the first observations of a chemical change produced by ionizing radiations. The discovery of the radioactivity of radium by Mme. Curie (3) in 1898 led to the observation of a multitude of other effects produced by these radiations. For example, it was a matter of great concern that aqueous solutions of radium compounds continuously evolved hydrogen and oxygen.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vm26z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913t10d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad217qt120"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The meaning of diabetes mellitus to the patient : with special reference to a group of twenty-five patients at the Royal Victoria Hospital 1942-43</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dennis, Margaret A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diabetes Mellitus is a chronic disease which requires active participation by the patient in order for treatment to be effective. Because of the responsibility which must be placed upon the diabetic and the nature of the symptoms of the disease as well as its complications, it is reasonable to expect that such an illness would create special problems for those who have it. The provision of adequate instruction to permit diabetics to carry out the treatment prescribed is a prime requisite. Some degree of intelligence is necessary to absorb the instruction given.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Grundy, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q352.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qt120</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g584p"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Protamine-heparin titration methods for the determination of circulating anti-coagulants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>De Leeuw, Nannie K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The hemorrhagic syndromes that occurred after atomic bomb irradiation (1) have attracted attention, because the phenomena did not seem to be fully explicable on the basis of thrombocytopenia alone. It was first suggested by Allen and Jacobson (2), that an excess of heparin in the blood might be the cause of the decreased coagulability and bleeding tendency after acute ionizing irradiation. Allen then developed a heparin-protamine titration test (3) tor the demonstration of heparin or heparin-like substances in the circulating blood.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Lowenstein, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv85w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g584p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6395wb81s"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Zoology Department</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Biology of daphnia</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Darrell-McPhee, Gloria</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Swammerdam, the Dutch scientist, was the first author who took notice of any of the Daphniae. In his Historla Insectorum Generalis, 1669, he gave a description of a species of Daphnia, which resembled Daphnia pulex and which he named Pulex arboreus or arborencens. He stated that its beak was slender and pointed, and was used for drawing up food. He called the second antennae arms and described their motion as three-fold—rectilinear, unequal, and gyratory. He asserted that there were two eyes which seemed to be joined together. Merrett mentioned Daphnia in his Pinax rerum Britannicarum, published in 1677.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Berrill, N.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s353h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb81s</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Zoology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A9s1619499"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of potassium deficiency on gastric secretion</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Currie, Donald J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In October 1946 a dog was prepared in these laboratories with a large partially innervated gastric pouch. The pouch was a modification of the Cope operation (30), a pouch made from the lesser curvature of the stomach. The dog was standardized to the various gastric function tests and was maintained on a normal kennel diet of minced meat. Within 48 days the volume of gastric juice secreted by the pouch increased from an average of 50 c.c. to an average of 135 c. c. daily. There was also noted an increase in the amount of water taken and in the volume of urine excreted.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t259k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1619499</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Medicine</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Avh53x007d"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>3-Hydroxyethyl glucose</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Creamer, George Bernard</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In a Ph.D. Thesis submitted in 1946 from this Laboratory, Tasker prepared in pure form the series of the monoethyl ethers of the polyethylene glycols, R(OCH2CH2)n0H, where n was 1, 2 or 3. The tendency of several of these compounds to form peroxides when exposed to light and air was noted, the esters made with p-toluenesulfonyl chloride (tosyl chloride) and pyridine were prepared, and the replacement by iodine atoms of the tosyloxy groups in the products was studied. Tasker then applied the tosylation-iodination technique to a commercial hydroxyethyl ether of cellulose, but his results made it clear that side-reactions of an unexpected nature were occurring. In the light of the knowledge gained from his studies in the polyethylene oxide series, Tasker put forward suggestions concerning the possible nature of the side-reactions. These suggestions, however, were only tentative, because at that time the literature contained no reference to the existence of an hydroxyethyl derivative of a simple sugar, the chemical behavior of which would serve as a model for the probable behavior of an hydroxyethylcellulose.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Purves, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x712m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x007d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6969z4167"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Social Work</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Social Work</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Reading difficulties as a social work problem: a study of social and emotional factors in reading difficulties, and the role of the social worker in the treatment of reading difficulties</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Crane, J. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Irrespective of the setting within which he works, the social worker is likely to encounter children who are not making progress in school because of difficulties with reading. Such children tend to become "problem children," and to find their way into Child Guidance Clinics and Juvenile Courts. Retardation in reading makes school work progressively more difficult for the child, since, as he advances in grades, his success in all subjects tends to depend more on reading ability. As he experiences failure in his school work, he is apt to lose interest in it and eventually leave school before he has reached a level of attainment consistent with his actual native capacities.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Younge, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt88q.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z4167</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Work</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An870zt90w"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effect of oxygen enrichment of the air intake of a diesel engine on the exhaust gas composition and the combustion processes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cooper, Ross Malcolm</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Small additions of oxygen to the air intake of a Diesel engine increase the temperature at which the combustion processes occur in the cylinder, and have very pronounced effects on the composition of the exhaust gases. Under no load conditions and at constant speed, the concentration of nitrogen oxides continuously increases with enrichment, while those of aldehydes and carbon monoxide decrease. Similar trends are observed for a medium load at constant speed. The behavior may be explained by the effect of an increased temperature. Beyond a critical oxygen enrichment of the intake, a reaction temperature is eventually reached at which partial dissociation of carbon dioxide becomes a factor and the concentration of carbon monoxide begins to rise. The concentration of nitric oxide in the exhaust, being independent of the nature of the fuel, is a measure of the maximum reaction temperature reached during combustion, and this is probably true of all combustion processes in which air is the supporting element. Investigation shows that addition of various gases to the air intake might prove valuable as an experimental technique in the study of combustion processes.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gauvin, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462858n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zt90w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At722hd082"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Nutrition</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Studies of the effect of polymerizing temperatures on the nutritive value of herring and linseed oils</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Clark, Barbara Elizabeth</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Diets containing unheated and heat polymerized herring and linseed oils were fed to male white rats. The oils were incorporated in the diets at 20$ (herring and linseed) and 10$ (linseed) levels. Linseed oil, segregated by propanol or with additions of antioxidants were tested. Supplements of sheep feces and dried brewers yeast were fed with linseed oil diets to determine their prophylactic and curative properties. Heat polymerization decreased the nutritive value of the oils as assessed by the growth rates, feed consumption, and the physical condition of the animals. Increasing the heated oil content of the diet from 10 to 20% resulted in lower growth rates. Propanol segregation or the additions of antioxidants to the heated linseed oil showed no effect on the nutritive value. Yeast was found to have slight prophylactic and curative properties when fed with heated oil diets.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crampton, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074z33m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hd082</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Nutrition</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aq524js11v"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Experimental Surgery</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Experimental studies on complete deprivation of arterial supply to the liver, with special reference to welch bacillus infection</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chau, Andrew Y.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>It has been known for many years that complete ligation of the arterial supply to the liver was rapidly fatal in several mammalian species. Considerable speculation as to the pathological changes and mechanism of death have failed to uncover a satisfactory explanation. In general, if the portal vein is left intact, arterial ligation alone does not produce definite infarction, but a focal or massive necrosis usually appears within twenty-four hours. In 1949 it was reported by Markowitz, Rappaport and Scott that dogs which were treated with penicillin were able to survive complete hepatic arterial ligation.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Webster, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x098.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524js11v</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8c97kt64c"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Methods of evaluation the germicidal activity of quaternary ammonium compounds</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chaplin, Charles Eric</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The quaternary ammonium compounds (QAC) are complex organic compounds possessing great surface activity and germicidal properties. At the present time there are hundreds of preparations on the market in the United States and about 100 licensed for sale in Canada which are compounded from or are composed entirely of one of the many QAC available. About 45 per cent of those available in Canada are composed in whole or in part of di-isobutylphenoxyethoxyethyl dimethyl benzyl ammonium chloride which, for brevity, will be referred to as Hyamine 1622, the trade name given this substance by the manufacturers, Rohm and Haas of Philadelphia, Pa.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gray, P.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zx56x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kt64c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agricultural Bacteriology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A794081367"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of an axial pressure gradient on the boundary layer</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Chant, Raymond Earle</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A review of the literature on laminar and turbulent boundary layers was made; a resume of this is included. The review and resume cover both theoretical and experimental studies, and was used to indicate the methods employed in expressing the results. The experimental work described in the thesis consisted of a series of tests carried out in a variable pressure wind tunnel. The results of the tests enabled a study of the effects of an adverse pressure gradient on the characteristics of a turbulent boundary layer to be made. The studies confirm salient known effects of an axial pressure gradient on the boundary layer. A method of expressing the boundary layer growth in terms of a parameter containing the pressure gradient is pointed out, and suggestions are made for further studies of this nature.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Mordell, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hs90w.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/794081367</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3At435gh14z"><ual:graduationDate>1950</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of radiation on the properties of quarter-wavelength resonant unshielded parallel-wire transmission lines in frequency range 300 Mc/sec. to 1300 Mc/sec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Carr, Edward Francis</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>There is at present uncertainty as to whether radiation takes place from the length of a transmission line as well as the terminations, or from the terminations alone. An attempt has been made to determine the answer to this question, for the case of odd quarter wavelength resonant lines. A short historical survey of the different theoretical considerations, and the reasoning behind them, is given as a preamble to the present investigation. The resonant line method of Chipman was used to measure impedance of resonant lines for various resonant lengths and at various frequencies. From this data, the apparent terminating resistance (radiation resistance) is obtained. The current approximate expression for radiation resistance of a quarter wavelength resonant line is found to be in error by a factor of two. A theoretical curve corresponding quite closely to empirical results for short line lengths is found.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Chipman, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30px115.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gh14z</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>