<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2r36v2127"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The economics of forage utilization in beef cattle production in the province in Quebec</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mayers, John. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Beef cattle production in Eastern Canada has changed considerably in the last twenty years. Prior to that, it was believed that beef could be produced economically only on cheap marginal land under a rather extensive system of farming. Since then, such factors as scarcity of farm labour, tendency towards specialization and good markets have influenced the production of beef cattle on the more fertile and extensively cultivated land. In this way, they are regarded as economical converters of unsaleable and bulky crops, as restorers of organic matter and fertility to the soil and as a means of utilizing more efficiently and economically available farm labour throughout the year.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Haver, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w56z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v2127</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abc386p159"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Spallation products of dysprosium</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>May, Mortimer</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The recent achievement of the separation of rare earths, and the availability of pure rare earth elements have given a great impetus to the study of their nuclear properties. The greater part of the research done in this region has been to obtain the decay schemes of the various radioactive rare earth nuclides. In this work, a study has been made of the radioactive spallation products of natural dysprosium produced by the bombardment of protons within an energy range of 8 - 90 Mev. Decay characteristics of the reaction products, as well as excitation functions (a plot of yield, expressed as a cross section, versus projectile energy) of natural dysprosium have been obtained.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yaffe, L.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj45x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386p159</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afx719q711"><ual:graduationDate>1968</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>fre</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Département de langue et littérature françaises</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>La présence anglaise dans le roman Canadien-français</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Foley, Katharine A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude, orientée sur l'idée des deux solitudes sociales que séparent les Franco-américains et les Anglo-américains, vise à une présentation bien plus qu'à une interprétation de la présence anglaise dans le roman canadien-français. [...]</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Reverchon, M. Th.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gx29p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719q711</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Literature, Canadian (French)</dc:subject><dc:subject>French-Canadian fiction -- History and criticism</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514np91x"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Early biochemical alterations in rat liver following carbon tetrachloride intoxication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Maximchuk, Arlene. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Carbon tetrachloride (tetrachloromethane, CCl4) was discovered in 1839 by the French chemist and physician, H. V. Regnault, as a product of the action of chlorine upon chloroform in sunlight (1). It is almost insoluble in water, but is miscible with chloroform, alcohol, ether and benzene (1, 2, 3). Its non-flammability and low cost are the chief factors combining to make CC14 one of the most widely-used volatile solvents today. Hardin (1) has prepared an interesting review which traces the history of CC14 through its various applications and uses. For approximately 12 years (1865-67), CCl4 had a short and unhappy trial as an anaesthetic, and was proven to be inferior to chloroform in this capacity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Rubenstein, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591c727.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np91x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2514np926"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The reactions of active nitrogen with molecular oxygen, atomic oxygen and hydrogen</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mavroyannis, Constantine</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>For the reaction of nitrogen atoms with molecular oxygen, the nitrogen and oxygen atom concentrations were estimated, at different temperatures and pressures, by addition of excess N0 and measurement of N2O and NO produced. The rate constant was given by 2.3 x 10^12 exp(-5,900/RT) cc mole^-1 sec^-1. The maximum production of oxygen atoms was found to correspond to the maximum amount of HCN produced in the active nitrogen-ethylene reaction. A rate constant of 1.83(+- 0.2) x 10^15 cc^2 mole^-2 sec^-1 was determined for the reaction of nitrogen atoms with oxygen atoms, in the absence of molecular oxygen, at pressures of 3, 3.5 and 4 mm, in an unheated reaction tube. The nitrogen atom consumption was estimated by titrating active nitrogen with NO at different positions along the reaction tube. Using the same titration method, the rate constant for the decay of nitrogen atoms, in an unheated vessel, was found to have the value of 5.2 x 10^15 cc^2 mole^-2 sec^-1, with y= 7.5 (-+ 0.6) x 10^-5, in the pressure range from 0.5 to 4 mm. Under similar conditions, and by similar methods, a value of 4.87(+- 0.8) x 10^14 cc^2 mole^-2 sec^-l was obtained for the rate constant of the reaction between nitrogen atoms and hydrogen atoms, over the pressure range from 2.5 mm to 4.5 mm.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h0869.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np926</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ap2677031m"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Political Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Canadian foreign aid, 1950-1960: parliamentary policy; administration; content</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Matthews, Joan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In the Introduction, the problems of reconstruction and development of the under-developed countries were noted. The motives behind Canadian foreign aid were then analyzed and two dominating motives appeared evident - humanitarian, and enlightened ‘self-interest’. Chapter one, an analysis of the evolution of parliamentary policy of the three major Canadian political parties, revealed that there were no basic differences among the parties regarding the acceptance and support of foreign aid programs. Such differences as did exist were rather those of degree. Chapter two, an analysis of the administration of foreign aid, revealed that until 1960, the administrative machinery was not adequate to scope with the increasing scope of foreign aid, largely because of a divided responsibility.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brecher, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn99t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2677031m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics and Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A2v23vx590"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Survey of the theory of the firm</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martin, Fernand</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Economics started by being political economy. No wonder then, except for Marshall, that the firm as a subject of study has been somewhat neglected. This political bias remained prevalent in the profession until quite recently. In the beginning, the main efforts were spent on the study of aggregates, for example, industries, and what is regarded today as macro-economies and economic development. The excursions into micro-economies were brief and were oriented towards the making of special tools to meat particular situations. The micro-theories of the 1870's are still the backbone of our body of economic knowledge in that area, although again and again they have been criticized as false and based on outmoded psychology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Beach, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kx43p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx590</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics and Political Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Apr76f7195"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Health Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Factors influencing the permeability of salivary glands</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martin, Konrad. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Electrical stimulation of the cervical sympathetic trunk or administering adrenaline or noradrenaline leads to pronounced changes in the composition of saliva obtained from the cat's submaxillary gland by simultaneous and/or subsequent chorda stimulation. The concentration of nonelectrolytes found in "normal" parasympathetic saliva rises and the gland becomes permeable to larger molecule: sucrose (MRD = 3.9 A) and raffinose (MRD = 5.1 A) diffuse freely from the plasma into the saliva whereas normally a radius of 3.2 A seems to be limiting. Molecules with radii exceeding 6A show restricted diffusion and inulin (MRD = 14.8 A) does not appear in the saliva under any circumstances.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Burgen, A.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8063665.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f7195</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ag445ch84w"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Analysis of proton inelastic scattering cross sections</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Mark, Shew-Kuey</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>A simple semi-classical calculation of direct inelastic scattering of protons by atomic nuclei is performed. The method employed is based on the Impulse Approximation and the variable density Fermi gas model with a diffuse surface. Only those nucleons in the surface of the target nucleus are considered to be capable of contributing to direct interactions. Total inelastic scattering cross sections are presented, and then used to analyze the (p pxn) reaction cross sections of Au197. The method followed is essentially that already proposed by Kavanagh and Bell. Contributions from direct processes inside the nuclear volume have been accounted for by adding the results of Jackson, and Compound nucleus contributions have been ignored. Good agreement between calculations and experiment has been obtained.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Kavanagh, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g8531.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445ch84w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar494vp56t"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A two variable optimizing controller</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Malowany, Alfred. S.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Mass production, an economic adventure, quickly capitalized on the use of machinery. In the endeavour to achieve more self sufficient machinery, units called "controllers" were invented to replace man's supervision of machines. Process control engineering is the study and design of such "controller" systems. In a feedback control system the control philosophy is that of generating some function of the output, comparing this with an input signals and generating an error signal with which to control the process. Figure 1.2 shows such a closed-loop system with its set point adjustment.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>D’Ombrain, G.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xn18c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp56t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Electrical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3f4628873"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Changes in EEG and other physiological measures during serial mental performance</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacNeilage, Peter. F.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned particularly with the relation between EEG, and other physiological functions and behaviour within the midrange of psychological function. This midrange is the area bounded on the one hand by the onset of drowsiness in the subject, and on the other by the onset of general behaviour disorganization because of overexcitement, extreme stress, and such states. The broad characteristics of EEG to be found within this range have been outlined by Lindsley (1960): “----- the most aroused or excited state behaviorally is represented by a low voltage fast EEG picture, and is paralleled by poor attention and behavioral efficiency.”</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Malmo, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wk758.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4628873</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4b29b956q"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An investigation of the nutritional desirability of cooking the grain component of the “cereal mix” used in mink rations intended for breeding female mink and for growing and furring kits; and of replacing brewers’ yeast by wheat germ in these same diets</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>MacNaughton, Donald. A.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In Newfoundland the production of ranch mink has been carried on, on a limited scale, for well over twenty years. However, during the last seven years, with the assistance and encouragement of the Newfoundland Government, mink ranching has been co-ordinated and largely centralized near the southern end of Trinity Bay. This region of the Avalon Peninsula was chosen for several reasons, the most important of which was its close proximity to a supply of a large variety of marine products. Trinity Bay is a centre of pothead whale fishing and consequently whale meat and whale liver are normally available as ingredients in mink rations.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Crampton, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh245.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b956q</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Animal Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ank322j312"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effective stresses in silts</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lyell, Alexander, P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The shear strengths of silt samples of a given porosity were compared for three different types of triaxial test, under varying conditions of lateral pressure, drainage and saturation. The three types of triaxial test conducted were: I) Unconsolidated drained test on dry silt. II) Unconsolidated undrained test on partially saturated silt. III) Unconsolidated drained test on a partially saturated silt. The maximum strength was exhibited by the dry silt and was considered to be primarily a function of the effective stress on the contact area.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Yong, R.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9033611.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j312</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6q182p744"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Part I. The structure of catalposide. Part II. Carbonium ion formation at the C-10 position in 2,5-seco-a-bisnorcholestane structures</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lunn, William. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The work described in this thesis falls into two distinct sections; Part I, in which the elucidation of the structure of catalposide is given, and Part II, concerned with carbonium ion formation at the C-10 position in 2,5- seco-A-bisnorcholestane structures. Until a year ago studies on catalposide had been of a most elementary character, the first details regarding its structure being reported at the American Chemical Society Meeting of September, 1960. These preliminary results accord, in part, with those obtained simultaneously in this laboratory, and are discussed within the framework of Part I.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Edward, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw21n.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182p744</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aqr46r4712"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Agriculture</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of mineral nutrition and certain other environmental factors on loose smut development in barley</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lukosevicius, Petras. P.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Loose smut of barley caused by Ustilago nuda (Jens.) Rostr. is a disease that becomes evident mainly after heading of the host. The spikes of infected plants emerge from the boot slightly earlier than those of healthy Plants. Powdery masses of spores are formed in place of kernels. These masses of spores are covered at first with a membrane, which ruptures early to expose the dark brown chlamydospores. Under certain conditions, sori may form in the upper leaves mostly in the nag leaf. These sori appear five to ten days before heading. The chlamydospores are dislodged from the smutted heads by air currents at the time healthy plants are in flower, leaving bare rachises.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Klinck, H.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765374599.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r4712</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agronomy</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ah128nj349"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Geography</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Deglaciation and postglacial emergence of Northernmost Labrador</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Löken, Olav. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Northern Labrador lies within the Canadian Shield, its bedrock being generally Precambrian in age or, more accurately, Archean in the area covered by this study. (Map 2) (Piloski 1954). Highly metamorphosed paragneisses and gneisses of granitic composition are the major rock-types, but granite and quartzites occur as well. The bedrock is generally coarse grained and weathered into a very rough surface, on which striae are usually absent. In the areas of gneiss, the local variation in petrography is large, as quartz-inclusions and inclusions of granites are numerous (Ill. 80). Because of this, the identification of erratics is extremely difficult, and in no case was the source-area of a suspected erratic boulder determined.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bird, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn51d.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj349</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8w32r896x"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Some aspects of brightness discrimination in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liss, Philip. H.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The subjects were twenty-four 200 to 220 gm, male hooded rats from the Royal Victoria colony. All animals were constantly supplied with food and water, with either one or two rats in a cage. The apparatus was a slight modification of the one used by Thompson and Bryant (195.5). It consisted of a V-shaped choice chamber, 5" wide at the narrow end and 14" wide at the wide end, and a goal box, 14" wide and 12" long. Both choice chamber and goal box bad light-brown walls 13" high. The choice chamber had a grid floor, while the floor of the goal box was made of wood. Two windows at the wide end of the choice chamber, each 4" x 41/2", 3” apart and 1” from the bottom, provided the only entrances into the goal box.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bryden, M.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dh151.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r896x</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6h440x411"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The retarding potential diode for energy gap measurements on superconductors</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lichtenberger, Gunter. J.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Starting with the Bardeen Cooper Schrieffer theory of a superconductivity, it is Shown how C. R. Crowell derived a work function difference between the normal and superconducting states, in terms of the energy gap of a superconductor, from the difference in the free energy between the states. The design and use of a retarding potential planar diode, and the associated circuitry required to observe temperature dependent work function changes near 4°K, are described. Measurements were carried out on a lead sample, above and below its superconducting transition temperature (7.2°K). The failure to observe work function changes related to superconductivity is discussed in terms of a different approach to the theory.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Carruthers, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f720x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440x411</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8623j253h"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Rate constants for some active nitrogen reactions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Levy, Eric. M.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Just over three-quarters of a century ago, Warburg (1) noticed that nitrogen, at low pressures and under the influence of an electrical discharge, emitted a bright yellow glow. In 1900, Lewis (2) observed that the glow persisted for some time after the discharge had ceased and made a number of studies of the spectrum of the glowing gas. Strutt (later Lord Rayleigh) investigated the phenomenon in a more systematic manner (3,4,5,6), and discovered that the glowing gas bad rather remarkable chemical properties. He named the glowing gas "active nitrogen", and suggested that many of its properties could be attributed to the presence of atomic nitrogen.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Winkler, C.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw22x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j253h</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aww72bg24w"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>100 MeV proton beam monitoring devices</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lee, Jonathon. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Methods for monitoring the intensity of the external proton beam from the 100 Mev McGill Synchrocyclotron were investigated. By using the Faraday Cup and the ionization chamber, it is possible to measure the beam current over a range 10^-14 amp. to 10^-8 amp. An integrator circuit providing the suitable ranges was built and calibrated to 0.4% accuracy. For low beam intensity, high background and short burst experiments, the C11 activation method is recommended. The cross section for C11 activation has been measured to be (63.8 +0.8/-0.6) mb for 96 Mev protons. This will then provide an additional accurate monitor for beam intensity.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Frisken, W.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mg50x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bg24w</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Anz806367f"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Shift of the antiferromagnetic transition of dysprosium under high pressure</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Landry, Peter. C.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Dysprosium, one of the rare earth elements, has undergone a great deal of experimental and theoretical investigation in the past few years, principally due to its variety of magnetic states in accessible temperature regions. In particular, it passes from the paramagnetic to the anti-ferromagnetic state at a Néel temperature of 177 K and from the antiferromagnetic to the ferromagnetic state at a Curie temperature of 88 K. It has very recently been determined by neutron diffraction studies that the antiterromagnetic state has a spiral magnetic configuration in which the atomic magnetic moments are lined up ferromagnetically in the basal planes of the hexagonal close-packed lattice.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Stevenson, D.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784q10z.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806367f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agx41mn52p"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Effects of convulsants on the cerebral carbohydrate amino acid metabolism</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lahiri, Sujata</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Tissues are both morphologically and physiologically divisible into at least two phases. One phase is comprised of either cellular or intracellular material which performs the specific function characteristic of the tissue (for example contraction in the case of the muscle or conduction in the case of nerve). In brain this phase consists of the neurons with its nucleated cell body, axons and dendrites. The other phase is extracellular and contains those anatomic elements and associated fluids essential for the physical support and nutritive maintenance of the cellular phase. In addition there are blood vessels, interstitial fluids, and non nervous connective tissue; the ependyma which lines the ventricles, the neuroglia cella and fibers.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Quastel, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765374602.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn52p</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biochemistry</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A8049g8549"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Physiological studies on three species of Entamoeba</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lachance, Philip</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In 1878, Butschli (1878) proposed the name Amoeba blattae for a new species of rhizopod from the alimentary canal of a cockroach, Peri-planeta (then, Blatta) orientalis. This endoparasite was subsequently transferred by Leidy (1879) to his new genus, Endamoeba. A few years later, Casagrandi and Barbagallo-Rapisardi (1895, 1895a) thought, in their turn, that the parasitic amoebae should be separated generically from the free-living ones. But, unaware of the existence of the genus Endamoeba, they proposed Entamoeba as a generic name for both Amoeba blattae and for the large non-pathogenic amoeba of the human intestine, Amoeba coli Grassi (1879).</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Cameron, T.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw144.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g8549</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Zoology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A1n79h803c"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Earth Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Field expression on some rock types with special reference to anorthosite</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lasalle, Pierre</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Chemical weathering of rocks including anorthosite is studied experimentally. Photographic expression of anorthosite is then outlined and statistical studies of slopes and grain size of products of weathering are made. Then tone of aerial photographs and color photography are considered. It is concluded that anorthosite should weather faster in areas where vegetation is present, and that the geomorphic expression of anorthosite is mainly related to jointing; in other aspects of surface expression, anorthosite is not different from other rock types.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Elson, J.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sk861.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h803c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Geological Sciences</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Af7623h16b"><ual:graduationDate>1962</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Engineering</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Part 1. Construction and calibration of the McGill supersonic wind tunnel</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kwok, Chi. K.</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The design and construction of the McGill intermittent, suckdown supersonic wind tunnel and its instrumentations are described. It operates on the pressure differential between the atmosphere and a 320 cu. ft. vacuum. storage tank. The running time for Mach number of 1 .8 is in the vicinity of twelve seconds with a test section area of approximately four sq. in.. Theoretical as well as experimental performance curves for the wind tunnel are presented. Calibrations of a Mach 1.8 axisymmetric nozzle and a Mach 1.8 two-dimensional nozzle are given in detail. The Mach number distribution compares favourably with other supersonic wind tunnels. The tunnel is being used to study supersonic flow in ducts, and problems concerning multiple shock waves and orifice experiments.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Newman, B.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v933m.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623h16b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Mechanical Engineering</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>