<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xv312"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating the effects of the von Hippel Lindau tumor suppressor on extracellular matrix function</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Panneton, Vanessa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La protéine von Hippel Lindau (pVHL) est un suppresseur de tumeur qui joue un role intégrale dans le développement de ccRCC. À date, plusieurs efforts ont été dirigés pour mieux comprendre ce role en tant que charactérizer sa function dans la dégradation de HIF et durant le processus de remodeler de la matrice extra-cellulaire (MEC). Le but de notre recherche était de charactérizer le méchanisme moléculaire par laquelle pVHL règle l'assemblée de la MEC. Pour attainder ce but, nous avons établis trois objectifs. Premièrement, nous avons voulu cerner si le role dont pVHL joue comme ubiquitine-ligase est indépendant de son role comme régleur de l'assemblée de la MEC. Deuxièmement, dans l'espoir de mimer la MEC défectueuse qui est observée avec les cellules qui n'expriment pas pVHL, nous avons diminué l'expression de collagène type IV dans les cellules dans lesquels pVHL est exprimé et nous avons mesuré la capacité de ces cellules à envahir une matrice artificielle. Finalement, nous avons visé à identifier le site d'intéraction spécifique de pVHL sur COL4A2. Nous étions capables de conclure que l'activité de ligase associée avec pVHL fonctionne indépendamment de sa fonction dans la régulation de la MEC. Nous avons aussi trouvé qu'en diminuant l'expression de collagène type IV dans les cellules 786-0, nous avons réussi à diminuer la capacité de ces cellules à envahir la MEC. Finalement, nous avons trouvé que pVHL intéragit avec un morceau de COL4A2 de 120kDa.   </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The von Hippel Lindau protein (pVHL) is a tumor suppressor that is known to play an important role in clear cell renal cell cancer (ccRCC) development. Many efforts towards understanding the role of pVHL in ccRCC have focused on characterizing its function in HIF degradation and extracellular matrix (ECM) remodeling. The purpose of the current study was to characterize the molecular mechanism by which pVHL regulates assembly of the ECM. To this end, we defined three objectives. First, we sought to determine if pVHL's role as a ubiquitin ligase was independent of its role as a regulator of ECM assembly. Second, in the hope of mimicking the defective ECM that is observed in pVHL null cells, we down-regulated type IV collagen in cells expressing wild type pVHL and then measured the ability of these cells to invade ECM in vitro. Lastly, we aimed to identify the specific binding site of pVHL on alpha 2 collagen type IV. Based on our results, we were able to conclude that pVHL's ubiquitin ligase function is independent of its function in ECM regulation. We also found that decreasing type IV collagen in 786-0 cells resulted in a decreased ability of these cells to invade the ECM. Lastly, we determined that pVHL binds to a 120kDa COL4A2 species.  </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Arnim Pause</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150j602.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xv312</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g3075"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Psychiatry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Sexual function impairment in women with systemic sclerosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Knafo, Ruby</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La sclérose systématique (SSc) se caractérise par un dysfonctionnement auto-immune et une fibrose diffuse qui occasionne un épaississement des tissues conjonctifs et qui a un effet sur de multiples organes. Le dysfonctionnement sexuel est souvent retrouvée chez les femmes atteintes de SSc, mais ceci n'est discuter qu'infréquement dans les revues scientifiques. Cette thèse démontre que le dysfonctionnement sexuel est un problème aussi important pour les femmes atteintes de SSc que pour les femmes atteintes d'autres maladies où le dysfonctionnement sexuel est plus mis en valeur. Cette thèse démontre également que la douleur est un indicatif important chez les femmes avec la SSc. Les professionnels de la santé devraient être au courant des symptoms de SSc reliés au dysfonctionnement sexuel chez leurs patients.  Ils devraient aussi être capables de leur offrir un protocole de traitement. Plus d'attention au dysfonctionnement sexuel chez les femmes atteintes de SSc, ainsi qu'aux facteurs qui pourraient être relié au dysfonctionnement sexuel, est nécessaire.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Systemic Sclerosis (SSc) is a rare autoimmune disease that is characterized by abnormal fibrotic processes that cause thickening of connective tissues, and affects multiple organ systems including the skin. Sexual impairment is often reported by women with SSc, but is rarely addressed in the scientific literature or by health providers. This research demonstrates that sexual impairment is as important a problem for women with SSc as it is for women with other illnesses where sexual impairment receives greater attention, and that pain is an important indicator of sexual function in women with SSc. Health providers should be aware of the symptoms of SSc that may be related to sexual impairment in their patients, and should be able to offer treatment strategies or referral if necessary. More research in needed to assess a full range of somatic, psychological, and scleroderma specific variables that may influence sexual function among women with SSc.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brett David Thombs</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d00t.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g3075</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Behavioral</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rk670"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Microwave osmotic dehydration of apples («Red Gala») under continuous flow medium spray conditions (MWODS) for improving moisture transport rate and product quality</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Azarpazhooh, Elham</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La déshydratation osmotique à l'aide des micro-ondes (MWOD) est une nouvelle technique avec un bon potentiel pour plus d'efficacité de séchage osmotique des fruits et légumes. Il combine le chauffage micro-onde avec la déshydratation osmotique pour améliorer le taux de transfert de l'humidité dans le procédé de déshydratation osmotique et la qualité du produit. Des études préliminaires ont été effectuées pour comparer la cinétique de déshydratation osmotique des cylindres de pommes (Rouge Gala) à déshydratation osmotique sous conditions de flux continu de pulvérisation (MWODS) avec déshydratation osmotique à l'aide des micro-ondes sous flux continu d'immersion (MWODI), ainsi que séchage osmotique le conventionnel (COD) en mode d'immersion (CODI) et en mode de pulvérisation (CODS). Les résultats ont montré que le processus de MWODS a considérablement amélioré le taux de transfert d'humidité à partir du fruit et a limité  le gain des solides en même temps. Dans la deuxième partie, le modèle d'Azuara à deux paramètres et le modèle de diffusion classique ont été évalués pour décrire la cinétique de transfert de masse des cylindres de la pomme (Rouge Gala) pendant MWODS, MWODI, COD et CODI. Les résultats ont montré que les deux modèles décrivent adéquatement la cinétique transitoire de transfert de masse pendant le processus d'OD, mais le modèle Azuara était supérieur. MWODS a aussi été étudié pour évaluer l'effet des différentes variables de processus (concentration en saccharose, la température du moyen, le taux de flux et le temps de contact) en utilisant la méthodologie de surface de réponse et la décomposition rotative du programme global. Les modèles prédictifs ont été développés pour relier les variables de réponse aux paramètres du procédé. Enfin, des études d'optimisation ont été menées pour élucider les conditions optimales de transformation sous MWODS. L'étude a démontré que la perte d'humidité (ML), les gains de solides (SG) et les pertes de poids (WR) ont été plus prévisibles à des concentrations de saccharose, températures de moyen, temps de contact et taux de flux plus élevés. Une deuxième étape de séchage a été évaluée employant l'air de séchage conventionnel par rapport à la lyophilisation pour identifier les systèmes efficaces pouvant préserver la qualité des fruits osmotiquement déshydratés. L'effet du prétraitement du MWODS sur la cinétique du séchage à l'air et l'effet des paramètres de qualité (couleur, texture, et caractéristiques de réhydratation) des cylindres de pomme (Rouge Gala) ont été évalués. Les résultats ont révélé que le temps de séchage diminue avec l'augmentation des concentrations et de la température du moyen du traitement MWODS. Par rapport aux échantillons témoins non traités, les MWODS échantillons séchés à l'air était ont un coefficient de diffusivité de l'humidité (Dm) plus entée. En termes de paramètres de qualité, le processus de MWODS avec séchage à l'air arrive à un produit avec un changement de couleur inférieur et une structure plus tendre. Le produit séché à l'air sans MWODS avait les caractéristiques de qualité le moins souhaitable. Bien que la couleur a été mieux préservé dans le produit lyophilisé, le produit était beaucoup plus fragile que le produit MWODS avec séchage à l'air. La capacité de réhydratation des produits de MWODS séchés à l'air est supérieure de celle des produits séchés à l'air et celle des produits lyophilisés.En général, cette recherche contribue à une meilleure compréhension du comportement de transfert d'humidité à micro-ondes pendant la déshydratation osmotique sous flux continu du moyen avec de la pulvérisation. Avec une deuxième simple étape du séchage à l'air, le processus peut produire des produits de pomme avec une haute qualité.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Microwave osmotic dehydration (MWOD) is a novel technique with a good potential for more efficient osmotic drying of fruits and vegetables. It combines the microwave heating with osmotic dehydration for enhancing moisture transfer rate in the osmotic dehydration process and product quality. Preliminary studies were carried out to compare the osmotic dehydration kinetics of apple (Red Gala) cylinders in microwave osmotic dehydration under continuous flow medium spray conditions (MWODS) with microwave osmotic dehydration under continuous flow medium immersion conditions (MWODI), as well as conventional osmotic drying (COD) in immersion (CODI) and spray (CODS) modes. The results showed that the MWODS process considerably enhanced the moisture transfer rate from the fruit, and limited the solids gain at the same time. In the second part, the two-parameter Azuara model and the conventional diffusion model were evaluated for describing the mass transfer kinetics of apple (Red Gala) cylinders during MWODS, MWODI, CODS and CODI. The results showed that both models adequately described the transient mass transfer kinetics during the OD process; however the Azuara model was superior.  MWODS was further studied to evaluate the effect of various process variables (sucrose concentration, medium temperature, flow rate and contact time) by using response surface methodology and a central composite rotatable design. Predictive models were developed relate the response variables to process parameters. Finally optimization studies were carried out to elucidate optimal processing conditions under MWODS. The study demonstrated that moisture loss (ML), solids gain (SG) and weight reduction (WR) were predictably higher at higher sucrose concentrations, higher medium temperatures, longer contact times and higher flow rates.  Since OD only results in partial dehydration, a second stage drying was evaluated employing conventional air drying and compared with freeze drying to identify cost effective systems for preserving the quality of the osmotically dehydrated shelf-stable fruits. The effect of MWODS pretreatment on air-drying kinetics and quality parameters (color, texture, and rehydration characteristics) of apple (Red Gala) cylinders was evaluated. The results revealed that drying time decreased with increasing concentrations and medium temperature of the MWODS treatment. Compared with untreated control samples, MWODS air-dried samples had higher coefficient of moisture diffusivity (Dm). In terms of quality parameters, the MWODS air-drying combination process resulted in a product with lower color change and a more chewy structure. The air dried product without MWODS had the least desirable quality characteristics. While the color was better preserved in the freeze dried product, it was much more brittle than MWODS – air-dried product. The rehydration capacity of MWODS air-dried products was lower than freeze-dried products and higher than air-dried.  Overall, the thesis research contributes to a better understanding of the moisture transfer behavior during microwave osmotic dehydration under continuous flow medium spray processing conditions. Together with a simple second stage air-drying it can produce high quality dehydrated apple products.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg32v.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rk670</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A4f16c316c"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Human Genetics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Toll-like receptor-4 and insulin like growth factor pathways influence survival and intestinal homeostasis in cystic fibrosis mice</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Canale, Juan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cystic fibrosis (CF) is a common and lethal genetic disease affecting various organs such as lungs, pancreas and intestine. The intestinal disease severity widely varies among patients and plays a critical role as it regulates body weight gain, the characteristic growth deficit of these patients which is of great importance as it predicts for lung disease and survival. Modifier genes, apart from the disease causative gene, regulate the intestinal phenotype. Our objective was to use CF mice to identify genes or pathways influencing the severity of CF intestinal disease to better our understanding of the disease pathogenesis and to provide genes for clinical investigation.We made use of the CF mouse model, as they also present the low body weight phenotype and share similar intestinal alterations characteristic of CF patients, to evaluate factors contributing to the growth deficit in CF.Initially, in this thesis, we identified a negative correlation between body weight and the histological feature of crypt-villus axis (CVA) height in CF mice, thus uncovering a phenotypic response to non functional Cftr which is related to CF intestinal disease severity. We also identified specific genes of a proliferative response to be differentially expressed in the ilea of CF mice compared to non-CF controls, among these, were toll-like receptor 4 (Tlr4) and insulin-like growth factor-I (Igf-I). Based on these previous findings, we investigated the role of these candidates in the proliferative response of the CF intestine and their contribution to weight gain by i) creating and evaluating a Cftr/Tlr4 double mutant mouse and by ii) treating CF mice with an Igf-I modulatory recombinant protein. Interestingly, Tlr4 proved to be implicated in early survival due to mechanisms unrelated to the proliferative response but possibly due to immune and/or mucus secretory actions, whereas Igf-I may potentially play a critical role as an intestinal adaptive-inducing factor influencing mouse body weight.In conclusion, in this thesis we have successfully identified two candidate modifier genes implicated in the CF intestinal response which modulate survival and intestinal adaptation, and provide strong evidence for their possible evaluation as targets for CF therapy.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La fibrose kystique (FK) est une maladie génétique commune et mortelle qui affecte plusieurs organes tels que le pancréas, les poumons et les intestins. Lorsque la maladie affecte les intestins, la sévérité des symptômes n'est pas la même chez tous les patients La sévérité des symptômes intestinaux joue un rôle très important car un déficit de croissance et de prise de poids sont fortement liés aux chances de survie et à la sévérité des symptômes pulmonaires.  Les gènes modificateurs, en plus du gène qui cause la fibrose kystique, sont responsables de la sévérité des symptômes intestinaux. Notre objectif était d'étudier des souris qui ont la fibrose kystique afin d'identifier des gènes ou des processus qui affecteraient la sévérité des symptômes intestinaux afin d'améliorer nos connaissances des mécanismes pathogéniques et afin de suggérer des gènes qui pourraient être évalués cliniquement.Nous avons utilisé des souris qui ont la fibrose kystique pour évaluer les facteurs qui contribuent au déficit de croissance de la FK, car elles représentent bien cette maladie puisqu'elles ont un faible poids ainsi que des malformations intestinales qui sont caractéristiques des patients qui ont la FK.Premièrement, nous avons identifié une corrélation négative entre le poids de la souris et un marqueur histologique du rapport de la hauteur villosités / cryptes, ce qui est un phénotype qui indiquerait une influence du gène mutant Cftr sur la sévérité de symptômes intestinaux. Nous avons aussi identifié des gènes impliqués dans la prolifération cellulaire qui étaient exprimés de façon différente dans les iléons des souris FK que dans les iléons des souris non-FK tels que toll-like receptor 4 (Tlr4) et insulin-like growth factor-I (Igf-I).Nous avons décidé de confirmer le rôle de ces candidats dans la réponse proliférative dans les intestins des souris FK et de leur contribution à la prise de poids des souris FK en i) créant et évaluant les souris double mutantes Cftr/Tlr4 et en ii) traitant des souris FK avec une protéine recombinante qui régule Igf-I. Nous avons découvert que le gène Tlr4 était impliqué dans la survie des souris, possiblement de façon immunologique ou par la sécrétion des muqueuses, mais non de façon proliférative alors que Igf-I pourrait être un facteur d'adaptation des intestins qui influencerait le poids des souris.En conclusion, dans cette thèse nous avons identifié deux gènes modificateurs qui seraient impliqués dans la réponse intestinale de la fibrose kystique et qui sont associés à la survie et à l'adaptation à la maladie, ainsi que démontré que ces gènes seraient de bons candidats thérapeutiques.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christina Haston</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b3880.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c316c</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - General</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axg94hp91j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Atomic contacts characterized by force and current</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hagedorn, Till</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un contact entre atomes est la réduction d'un système électronique à la plus petite échelle actuellement accessible. La microscopie à champ ionique (field ion microscopy, FIM) et la microscopie à effet tunnel (scanning tunneling microscopy, STM) simultanément à la microscopie à forces atomiques (atomic force microscopy, AFM) ont été utilisées pour caractériser le contact atomique entre une pointe de tungstène (W(111)), un palpeur pour le STM, et un échantillon d'or (Au(111)). La pointe a été imagée par FIM avec une résolution atomique et reconstruite par un modèle de balle tridimensionnel. La force et le courant ont été mesurés simultanément pendant que la pointe s'approchait de l'échantillon d'or (111) atomiquement plat pour y former un contact.Une description détaillée de la production et de la caractérisation des pointes par l'utilisation d'un système d'attaque électrolytique, développé pour cette thèse, est présentée. L'adaptation de la reconstruction par modèle de balle tridimensionnel au cristal de tungstène ccc(111) est décrite, puis utilisée pour reconstruire les pointes W(111). En utilisant plusieurs de ces pointes, les forces à longue portée du système pointe-échantillon ont été analysées en utilisant de récents modèles théoriques, ce qui a permit de conclure que les contributions des forces de van der Waals et des forces électrostatiques sont négligeables pour des pointes de rayon inférieur à r_pointe = 15 nm, compte tenu de la précision du système FIM-STM/AFM employé pour les expériences.En lien avec les simulations qui prennent en compte les forces d'interaction pointe-échantillon et les propriétés conductrices de la séparation des contacts, des données de force et de courant pour différentes modifications structurelles de la jonction tunnel W(111)-Au(111) sont présentées et analysées. Entre autres choses, il est montré que la jonction W-Au, pour les géométries étudiées dans cette thèse, ne présente pas les propriétés conductrices d'un contact monoatomique.En comparant différentes approches théoriques qui traitent de la corrélation entre la force et le courant dans une jonction tunnel de type STM, les données pour la jonction W(111)-Au(111) sont mises en relation avec ces lois de puissance. Les résultats de cette thèse indique une proportionnalité F^2 ~ I_t pour une pointe de tungstène à 3 atomes faisant contact avec un échantillon d'or (111) atomiquement plat.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contacts between atoms present the reduction of an electronic system to the smallest scale accessible at the present. Field ion microscopy (FIM) and simultaneous scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) and atomic force microscopy (AFM) were used to characterize atomic contacts between a tungsten (W(111)) STM-tip and a gold (Au(111)) sample. The STM-tip was imaged with atomic resolution using FIM and reconstructed in a three dimensional ball model. Force and current were measured simultaneously while the tip approached an atomically flat Au(111) sample to form a contact.A detailed description of the tip production and characterization using an etching setup that was developed for this thesis is introduced. These tips are characterized by field ion microscopy (FIM). The adaptation of a well known three dimensional ball model reconstruction to the tungsten bcc(111) crystal is described and utilized to reconstruct FIM micrographs of W(111) STM-tips. Using several of such tips, the long-range forces of the tip-sample system were analyzed using recent theoretical models, concluding that van der Waals and electrostatic force contributions were negligible for tips with a radius smaller than r_tip = 15 nm within the precision of the FIM-STM/AFM system that was employed for the experiments.Force and current data for different structural modifications of the W(111)-Au(111) SPM tunneling junction are presented and discussed. Findings include that the W-Au junction in geometries which were examined in this thesis do not exhibit the conductive properties of a one-atom contact.A comparison of different theoretical approaches that treat the correlation of force and current in a STM type tunneling junction is presented and the results of this thesis support a F^2 ~ I_t proportionality for a three-atom tungsten tip contacting an atomically flat Au(111) sample.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Peter H. Grutter</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n51k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hp91j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Solid State</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3n203z483"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>School of Computer Science</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An epistemic analysis of authentication</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Frydrychowicz, Maja</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Authentication protocols aim to prevent agent impersonation: A is authenticated to B if B knows who A is. Many formal approaches have been used to verify authentication in distributed systems; however, although authentication is directly related to agent knowledge, it has only been formally defined using process algebra, usually in terms of constraints on the order of protocol events. In response, we use epistemic modal logic to define authentication in terms of common knowledge as a form of coordinated action. We apply our definition to verify the Needham-Schroeder-Lowe Public-Key Protocol, as well as its predecessor, the Needham-Schroeder Public-Key Protocol, which is vulnerable to an impersonation attack. In doing so, we reason about knowledge evolution with an epistemic satisfaction relation on state-action histories. The results of our verification extend previous process-algebraic analyses of the two protocols by highlighting the role of agent knowledge.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Les protocoles d'authentification ont pour but d'empêcher l'usurpation d'identité: A est authentifié à B si B connaît l'identité de A. Il existe plusieurs approches formelles pour vérifier l'authentification dans les systèmes informatiques distribués. Cependent, bien que l'authentification soit directement liée à la connaissance des agents, elle a seulement été définie de façon formelle avec des algèbres de processus, le plus souvent en termes de contraintes sur l'ordre des évènements d'un protocole. Afin de combler cette lacune, nous utilisons la logique modale épistémique afin de définir l'authentification en termes de connaissances communes et donc comme un exemple d'actions coordonnées. Nous appliquons notre définition à la vérification formelle du protocole Needham-Schroeder-Lowe, ainsi qu'à son ancêtre, le protocole Needham-Schroeder, qui est vulnérable à une attaque d'usurpation d'identité. Ce faisant, nous raisonnons sur l'évolution de la connaissance avec une relation de conséquence épistémique définie en lien à des séquences état-action. Les résultats de notre vérification ajoutent aux autres analyses par algèbres de processus de ces deux protocoles en mettant de l'avant le rôle de la connaissance des agents.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Prakash Panangaden</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx26x.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n203z483</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ar207tp70t"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Economics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The economic integration of Canadian immigrants</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Dean, Jason</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This dissertation contributes to a strand of literature on the economic integration of immigrants in Canada's labour market. My first essay examines the economic return to human capital acquired abroad using an improved identification strategy of foreign education and work experience. My second essay examines whether education-job mismatches, on the part of immigrants, possibly explain their poor labour market outcomes. My final essay provides new evidence on the economic assimilation of U.K. immigrants in Canada over the late 19th and early-20th-century.In my first essay I exploit the enhanced details on education attainment provided in the Survey of Labour and Income Dynamics (SLID) to decompose aggregate human capital variables into more precise measures of foreign and Canadian locations than those employed in related Census-based studies. I find that measurement error associated with using imprecise measures exaggerates the portability (in terms of economic returns) of foreign schooling and the degree of immigrant wage assimilation. However, the virtually zero returns to foreign work experience, commonly found in the literature, cannot be attributed to measurement error. Thus, this dimension of human capital receives virtually no recognition for immigrants and it is mainly responsible for the substantial estimated wage gaps in the standard human-capital-adjusted earnings function.The contribution of my second essay is an investigation of the importance of education-job mismatches in explaining the poor labour market outcomes observed for immigrants to Canada. Immigrants have a modestly lower incidence of working in jobs related to their education than do the Canadian-born, and there is a sizable wage penalty for working in unrelated jobs. The lower incidence of matching, found among immigrant workers, can explain a sizable portion of their lower returns to foreign education credentials, and also the immigrant-native wage gap among university educated workers. By contrast, foreign education and work experience acquired abroad is not discounted in the Canadian labour market for immigrants who are successfully matched.My final essay examines the economic assimilation of pre-war U.K. immigrants using recently digitized samples of the 1901 and 1911 censuses. These nationally representative samples allow for a more comprehensive examination of immigrant assimilation than existing published evidence which is limited to cross-sectional samples of Montréal and Toronto. Estimates of within-cohort earnings growth show that these newcomers, despite their cultural similarities with the Canadian-born, experienced sizable earnings disadvantages upon arrival coupled with slow subsequent earnings growth. However, most immigrant cohorts achieved earnings parity with comparable Canadian-born workers over their working life unlike that found for Montréal and Toronto. Thus, although the government's desire was to attract the most industrious and hard working immigrants, arrivals from the British Isles may have been negatively selected in terms of unobservable labour market characteristics. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse contribue à la littérature qui examine l'intégration des immigrants au marché de travail Canadien. Le premier essai étudie le retour au capital humain  acquis à l'étranger sur le marché de travail Canadien utilisant des stratégies améliorées d'indentification de ce dernier. Mon deuxième essai examine des conséquences économiques de l'absence de la correspondance parfaite des professions que les immigrants au Canada peuvent obtenir avec leurs disciplines d'études. Mon troisième essai produit des faits stylisés nouveaux au sujet de l'intégration des immigrants de provenance du Royaume-Uni  au Canada durant la fin du 19ème au début du 20ème siècle.Dans mon premier essai j'exploite des détails améliorés de l'Enquête sur la dynamique du travail et du revenu à fin de décomposer le capital humain a des portions acquises à l'étranger et des portions acquises au Canada.  Je trouve que l'erreur de mesure associée à l'emploi des indicateurs imprécis avait causé la sous-estimation de l'écart entre le retour sur le capital humain acquis à l'étranger et celui acquis au Canada dans les études précédentes. Je trouve, en revanche, que le capital humain acquis à l'étranger reçoit un retour nul au Canada et cela explique la quasi-totalité de l'écart de revenu entre les immigrants et les natifs.Mon deuxième essai examine l'importance de la correspondance imparfaite entre les disciplines d'études et la profession des immigrants au Canada pour expliquer leurs performances économiques inferieures. Je trouve que cette correspondance imparfaite est un peu plus fréquente chez les immigrants et qu'elle a cependant des conséquences négatives non-négligeables sur le salaire. Cette probabilité plus faible que des immigrants puissent travailler dans un domaine proche de leurs disciplines d'étude explique une portion considérable de l'écart de salaire entre les immigrants et les natifs comparables ainsi que leurs retours du capital humain plus bas. Mon troisième essai porte un regard nouveau sur la question d'intégration des immigrants de provenance du Royaume-Uni durant la fin du 19ème siècle au début du 20ème siècle en utilisant des données récemment numérisées des recensements de l'époque. L'échantillon que j'utilise dans cette recherche représente la distribution nationale de ces immigrants contrairement aux échantillons auparavant utilisés qui portaient seulement sur les immigrants résidant au Québec et en Ontario. Mes estimations montrent que ces immigrants, malgré leur similarité culturelle avec les natifs, ont subi un écart du salaire considérable ainsi qu'un taux de croissance du salaire plus bas en comparaison avec les natifs. Cependant, je trouve que la plupart de ces immigrants ont ultimement arrivé à un salaire équivalent aux natifs comparables durant leurs vies professionnelles. Je trouve aussi que le gouvernement, malgré son intention, a échoué d'attirer les immigrants industrieux et entreprenants en raison des facteurs inobservables conduisant à une sélection peu efficiente de ces immigrants. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jennifer Hunt</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Mary Elizabeth MacKinnon</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4625823.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp70t</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Economics - Labor</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A7s75dc84m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparison of prior distributions for bayesian inference for small proportions</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Liu, Guoyuan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Often, Bayesian analyses for epidemiological applications use objective prior distributions. These prior distributions are chosen with the goal of allowing the posterior distribution to be determined by the observed data alone. While this is achieved in most situations, it is not the case for Bayesian estimation of a small proportion. Such a situation might arise, for example, when estimating the prevalence of a rare disease. Several candidate objective prior distributions have been proposed for a Binomial proportion, including the Uniform distribution and Jeffrey's distribution. Each of these prior distributions may lead to very different posterior inferences when the number of events in the Binomial experiment is small, but it is unclear which of these would lead to better estimates on average. We explore this question by examining the frequentist performance of the posterior credible interval in two problems: i) estimating a single proportion, ii) estimating the difference between two proportions. The credible intervals obtained when using standard objective prior distributions as well as informative prior distributions motivated by real-life examples are compared. To assess frequentist performance, numerous statistics, including average coverage and average length of the posterior credible intervals were considered.  </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Souvent des analyses bayésiennes de données  épidémiologiques utilisent les distributions à priori objectives. Ces distributions à priori sont sélectionnées de sorte que les distributions à posteriori soient déterminées uniquement par les données observées. Bien que cette méthode soit efficace dans plusieurs situations, elle ne l'est pas dans le cas de l'estimation bayésienne de petites proportions.  Cette situation peut survenir, par exemple lors de l'estimation de la prévalence d'une maladie rare. Plusieurs distributions à priori objectives ont été proposées pour l'estimation d'une proportion, telle que, par exemple la distribution uniforme de Jeffrey. Chacune de ces distributions à priori peut conduire à de différentes distributions à posteriori lorsque le nombre d'événements dans l'expérience binomiale est petit. Mais il n'est pas clair laquelle de ces distributions, en moyenne, donne de meilleurs estimés. Nous explorons cette question en examinant la performance fréquentiste des intervalles crédibles à posteriori obtenus, respectivement, avec chacune de ces distributions à priori. Pour évaluer cette performance, nous considèrons des statistiques comme la couverture moyenne et la longueur moyenne des intervalles crédibles à posteriori. Nous considérons aussi des distributions à priori  plus informatives comme les distributions uniformes définies sur un sous-intervalle de l'intervalle [0, 1]. La performance des distributions à priori est évaluée en utilisant des données simulées de situations où l'intérêt de recherche est concentré sur l'estimation d'une seule proportion ou sur la différence entre deux proportions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Nandini Dendukuri</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Elham Rahme</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9030230.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dc84m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Biostatistics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aj67314224"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Civil Law</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Faculty of Law</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Breaking the circular argument: the rights of indigenous and other socio-ethnic distinct peoples in Brazil</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Martins Casagrande, Melissa</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette thèse propose que l'interprétation actuelle des droits constitutionnellement reconnus aux peuples autochtones et d'autres peuples socio-ethniquement différenciés au Brésil est consolidé par un faux raisonnement classifié ici comme un argument circulaire. L'argument repose sur la négation, par l'État, de la pleine jouissance des droits constitutionnellement garanties aux peuples autochtones et, dans une certaine mesure, d'autres peuples socio-ethniquement différenciés, sur l'affirmation que ces peuples ne possèdent pas l'autonomie cognitive pour exercer ces droits. La circularité de l'argument réside dans le fait que cette apparente absence d'autonomie cognitive est souvent le résultat des actions de l'État. La perpétuation de l'argument circulaire dans les processus de prise de décisions des trois pouvoirs gouvernementaux est décrite et sa connexion avec les modes d'exclusion promues par l'État est mise en évidence. Une perspective de réinterprétation constitutionnelle pluraliste est alors proposée comme une contribution potentielle à la rupture de l'argument circulaire. </dc:abstract><dc:abstract>This thesis argues that the current interpretation of constitutionally recognized rights of indigenous and other socio-ethnic distinct peoples in Brazil is entrenched in a circular argument logical fallacy. The argument consists in the denial by the State of the full enjoyment of constitutionally recognized rights of indigenous peoples, and to some extent, other socio-ethnic distinct peoples, by maintaining that these peoples lack agency to exercise such rights. The circularity of the argument resides in the fact that this perceived lack of agency is often the result of State practice. The perpetuation of the circular argument within decision-making processes of all branches of government is described and their connection to patterns of exclusion promoted by the State is established. A pluralist constitutional reinterpretation perspective is presented as a potential contribution to break the circular argument. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Colleen Sheppard</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw54g.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67314224</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Social Sciences - Law</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adb78tc345"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The sequential function of Hox genes in limb development</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Cwajna, Mark</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Des expériences de perte de fonction ont démontré que la  mise en place  de l'architecture du squelette des membres requière la fonction des gènes HoxA et HoxD. Cependant, le rôle de ces gènes au cours de l'osteochondrogenèse est inconnu. Le but de mon projet de recherche était de définir ce rôle.En absence des gènes HoxA/D, le développement des membres est compromis dès les stades précoces, bien avant le début de l'osteochondrogenèse. Par conséquent, j'ai généré et analysé des inactivations conditionnelles des gènes HoxA/D dans le lignage osteochondrogenic afin d'établir le rôle de ces gènes au cours du développement osseux. Mes résultats montrent que la croissance des os en développement requiert la fonction des gènes HoxA/D dans le lignage osteochodrogénique. De plus, la comparaison entre l'inactivation ubiquitaire et conditionnelle permet de mieux comprendre la contribution précoce et tardif des gènes HoxA/D dans la formation du squelette des membres.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Loss-of-function experiments have demonstrated that the establishment of the limb architecture relies upon the function of HoxA and HoxD genes, which are required from early limb bud stages onwards. While there is a tight link between Hox genes and skeletal development, Hox function during osteochondrogenesis remains unclear.Without HoxA/D genes there is an early development arrest, resulting in drastic truncation of the limb skeleton. The severity of this mutation made its analysis uninformative regarding the specific function of HoxA/D genes at later stages of limb development. In order to investigate Hox function during later stages of osteochondrogenesis, we generated conditional Hox inactivations in the osteochondrogenic lineage to circumvent the early affect of HoxA/D loss of function.Comparing the ubiquitous Hox deficiency and specific inactivation in limb skeleton progenitors suggests that HoxA/D genes are needed early on for normal bone patterning and also at later stages to support normal bone growth.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Marie-Therese Kmita</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fr690.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc345</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Genetics</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akw52j8466"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Anthropology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The differential impact of war and trauma on Kosovar Albanian women living in post-war Kosova</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Kienzler, Hanna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The war in Kosova had a profound impact on the lives of the civilian population and was a major cause of material destruction, disintegration of social fabrics and ill health. Throughout 1998 and 1999, the number of killings is estimated to be 10,000 with the majority of the victims being Kosovar Albanian killed by Serbian forces. An additional 863,000 civilians sought or were forced into refuge outside Kosova and 590,000 were internally displaced. Moreover, rape and torture, looting, pillaging and extortion were committed. The aim of my dissertation is to rewrite aspects of the recent belligerent history of Kosova with a focus on how history is created and transformed through bodily expressions of distress. The ethnographic study was conducted in two Kosovar villages that were hit especially hard during the war. In both villages, my research was based on participant observation which allowed me to immerse myself in Kosovar culture and the daily activities of the people under study. The dissertation is divided into four interrelated parts.The first part is based on published accounts describing how various external power regimes affected local Kosovar culture, and how the latter was continuously transformed by the local population throughout history. The second part focuses on collective memories and explores how villagers construct their community's past in order to give meaning to their everyday lives in a time of political and economic upheaval. The third part looks at how women create, change and, thereby, influence collective memories through bodily expressions of distress. Finally, the fourth part makes apparent how through clinical practice and traditional healing, history, collective memories and traumatic memories are negotiated and invested with new meanings and attributions. The dissertation concludes with a focus on the interrelation of collective and traumatic memories which generate and justify women's health problems. In this context, it is argued that patient-practitioner interaction should be perceived as an opportunity to build ethical relationships which go beyond the relatively narrow medical mandate by providing women with "tools" to create social spaces in which they can live and commemorate in a healthy way.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La guerre au Kosova a eu un impact profond sur la vie de la population civile et a été une cause majeure de la destruction matérielle, de la désintégration du tissu social et de problèmes de santé. Au courant des années 1998 et 1999, le nombre de meurtres a été estimé à 10,000, la majorité des victimes étant des Albanais du Kosova tués par les forces serbes. De plus, 863,000 civils ont été recherchés ou contraints à prendre refuge en dehors du Kosova, et 590,000 ont été déplacés à l'intérieur du territoire. En outre, des viols, de la torture, des pillages et des extorsions ont été commis. L'objectif de ma thèse consiste à revoir les aspects de l'histoire récente du Kosova belligérant en mettant l'accent sur la façon dont l'histoire est créée et transformée à travers les expressions corporelles de détresse. L'étude ethnographique a été menée dans deux villages kosovars, qui ont été particulièrement touchés pendant la guerre. Dans les deux villages, ma recherche s'est basée sur l'observation participante, qui m'a permis de me plonger dans la culture kosovare et les activités quotidiennes de la population à l'étude. La thèse est divisée en quatre parties interdépendantes. La première partie recensent les écrits traitant des différents régimes politiques externes qui ont affecté la culture locale kosovare, et comment celle-ci a été continuellement transformée par la population locale au cours de l'histoire. La deuxième partie s'attarde aux mémoires collectives et explore comment les villageois construisent le passé de leur communauté, afin de donner un sens à leur vie quotidienne à une époque de bouleversements politiques et économiques. La troisième partie examine la façon dont les femmes créent, changent et, par conséquent, influencent les mémoires collectives à travers des expressions corporelles de détresse. Enfin, la quatrième partie met en évidence comment, à travers la pratique clinique et les rites de guérison traditionnels, les mémoires collectives et les traumatismes sont négociés et investis de nouvelles significations et attributions. La thèse conclut en mettant l'accent sur l'interdépendance des mémoires collectives et des traumatismes, qui génèrent et justifient les problèmes de santé des femmes. Dans ce contexte, il est soutenu que l'interaction patient-praticien devrait être perçue comme une occasion d'établir des relations éthiques qui vont au-delà du mandat relativement étroit de la médecine en offrant aux femmes des «outils» pour créer des espaces sociaux dans lesquels elles peuvent vivre et commémorer de façon saine.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Allan Young</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945r158.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j8466</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Anthropology - Medical and Forensic</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Axk81jk698"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Characterization of the interaction between the adaptor protein Nck and the protein kinase PKR</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Abu-Thuraia, Afnan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>La protéine kinase PKR, activée par l'ARN double brins (ARNdb), est connue pour jouer un rôle inhibiteur de la traduction des protéines. La régulation de PKR est donc critique pour le maintien de l'homéostasie cellulaire. Nous avons précédemment identifié la protéine adaptatrice Nck 1 comme étant un potentiel régulateur de l'activation de PKR, suivant son interaction avec PKR. Dans la présente étude, nous avons été en mesure de confirmer que, dans des conditions physiologiques, Nck-1 peut limiter l'activation de PKR par l'ARNdb. Cependant, le contrôle qu'exerce Nck-1 sur PKR est réversible puisque, lorsque la quantité d'ARNdb dépasse une certaine concentration, PKR est activée et alors Nck-1 se dissocie de PKR, l'empêchant ainsi de limiter son activation. Nos données démontrent également que Nck-1 doit être dans sa forme native pour interagir et moduler l'activation de PKR. De plus, il semble que l'interaction entre Nck-1 et PKR ne nécessite pas que les différents domaines homologues de Src (SH2 et SH3) présents chez Nck-1 soient fonctionnels. De plus, nous avons observé que Nck-1 interagit à la fois avec les domaines N- et C-terminaux de PKR. Nous démontrons également que lorsque les niveaux d'ARNdb atteignent un niveau seuil, Nck-1 se dissocie de PKR non pas à cause d'une compétition avec l'ARNdb, ni à cause d'un changement de conformation de PKR ou son autophosphorylation, mais est plutôt dû à l'activation du domaine catalytique de PKR. De plus, il semble que Nck-1 puisse être phosphorylé par PKR in vivo. Nck-1 est donc non seulement un modulateur de l'activation de PKR mais peut également servir de substrat pour PKR. Ceci nous amène donc à proposer que la phosphorylation de Nck-1 par PKR activée soit responsable du mécanisme de dissociation entre Nck-1 et PKR. En conclusion, nos résultats confirment Nck-1 comme étant un nouveau modulateur cellulaire de PKR, en limitant son activation dans des conditions physiologiques.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Tight regulation of the double-stranded RNA (dsRNA)-activated protein kinase (PKR) is critical for the maintenance of cellular homeostasis due to its potent inhibitory role on general translation. Previously, we have identified the adaptor protein Nck-1 as a novel cellular regulator of PKR activation through its interaction with PKR. In this study, we further confirmed that Nck-1 limits PKR activation under normal conditions. However, we demonstrate that the control of PKR activation by Nck-1 is reversible, since significant levels of dsRNA override Nck-1's negative control of PKR activation and induce dissociation of Nck-1 from PKR. Our data show that Nck-1 needs to be in full length to interact and modulate PKR. In addition, we observed that the interaction of Nck-1 with PKR is independent of any functional Src-homology domains of Nck-1, but our findings showing that Nck-1 interacts with both the N- and C-terminus of PKR challenge this concept. Nonetheless, we uncovered that upon significant levels of dsRNA, dissociation of Nck-1 from PKR is due to the activation of the catalytic activity of PKR rather than to competition by dsRNA binding or change of PKR conformation during its activation. Finally, we provided further evidence supporting the occurrence of Nck-1 phosphorylation by PKR in vivo.  Hence, Nck-1 not only buffers PKR activation but appears to be a substrate of PKR. Therefore, we propose that PKR-mediated phosphorylation is part of the mechanism that promotes Nck-1 dissociation from activated PKR. Taken together, our data confirm Nck-1 as a novel cellular modulator of PKR that limits PKR activation under physiological conditions.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Louise Larose</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z5620.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jk698</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A6108vb631"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Chemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Preparation and characterization of azobenzene polyelectrolyte multilayers for photo-reversible bio-surfaces</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Lu, Xiao Yu</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Une série de polyélectrolytes contenant des chromophores d'azobenzène photo-réversibles avec de divers groupes fonctionnels a été synthétisée, caractérisée et assemblée sur des surfaces par la technique de couche-par-couche pour construire des films multicouches biocompatibles pour de telles applications biologiques comme diriger optiquement la croissance des cellules. Polymères azoïques avec des groupes fonctionnels encombrants, hydrophobiques et peu ionisables avaient tendance à former des agrégats dans les solutions polaires et dans des films solides, donnant ainsi lieu aux décalages vers le violet, aux films épais et à l'hydrophobicité élevée de surface. P(DR1A-co-AA) avec le groupe de nitro et le plus stable p(DR2A-co-AA) étaient remarquables pour leur efficacité à produire la photo-commutation de l'énergétique de surface, dont ampleur pourrait être réglée par des facteurs géométriques de l'éclairage comme la direction incidente de la poutre de pompe et sa direction de polarisation linéaire. Cette dépendance géométrique a suggéré que la photo-réponse dominante était la réorientation moléculaire d'azobenzène, qui était encore examinée par l'intermédiare de polarisée dichroism linéaire infrarouge pour déterminer l'orientation synchronisée des divers groupes fonctionnels. En outre, des études de biréfringence ont révélé que l'orientation moléculaire azoïque pourrait avoir lieu entièrement sous l'eau, qui a donné la raison pour les essais préliminaires de la biocompatibilité des films azoïques avec des cellules de neurones. Enfin, les rendements quantiques pour les deux photo-isomerisations azoïques, trans-cis et cis-trans, ont été mesurés et ont montré une dépendance claire de la teneur en eau.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A series of polyelectrolytes containing photo-reversible azobenzene chromophores with various head groups were synthesized, characterized, and self-assembled onto surfaces via the layer-by-layer technique to construct biocompatible multilayer films for such biological applications as optically directed cell growth. Azo polymers with bulky, hydrophobic and non-ionizable head groups tended to form aggregates both in polar solutions and in solid films, thus giving rise to blue shifts in UV-Visible spectra, thick films, and increased surface hydrophobicity. P(DR1A-co-AA) with a nitro head group and the more stable p(DR2A-co-AA) stood out from the series due to their efficient photo-induced surface energy switching, whose magnitude could be tuned by such geometric factors of illumination as the incident direction of the pump beam and its linear polarization direction. This geometric dependence suggested that the dominant photo-response was the molecular re-orientation of azo chromophores, which was further probed by polarized infrared linear dichroism to determine the synchronized movement of different azo functional groups. Furthermore, birefringence studies revealed that the photo-induced orientation of the azo groups could occur entirely under water, which lent motivation for preliminary biocompatibility tests of the azo films with neural cells. Lastly, the quantum yields for both trans-cis and cis-trans photo-isomerizations of azo were measured and showed clear dependence on water content.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Christopher Barrett</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784q71p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb631</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Chemistry - Physical</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Att44pn21k"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Comparing the cost-effectiveness of different standardized tuberculosis treatment regimens in settings with varying prevalence of drug-resistant tuberculosis</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Law, Yuen Shan</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Background: There is a growing need to identify appropriate standardized treatment strategies that will adequately treat drug-resistant TB (DR-TB) and prevent multidrug-resistant TB (MDR-TB). Methods: We built a Markov model comparing treatment-related morbidities, mortality and costs in Ecuador, Brazil and hypothetical settings with varying prevalence of DR-TB. We compared four treatment strategies: 1) standard WHO-recommended treatment strategy; 2) adding EMB throughout 6-month initial treatment; 3) strengthening WHO standard retreatment with 2nd-line drugs; and 4) treating failures from initial treatment with a standardized MDR regimen. We also compared four combinations of those strategies. Probabilities of tuberculosis outcomes were derived from published literature. Costs were collected using direct surveys.Results: Strengthening retreatment with second-line drugs was highly cost-effective in Ecuador and Brazil. Adding EMB throughout initial treatment prevented acquired drug resistance and TB deaths, but led to excess cases of blindness.Conclusion: There is growing evidence that the WHO standard retreatment regimen is inadequate and should be strengthened with second-line drugs.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Contexte: Des stratégies normalisées de traitement de la tuberculose résistante et de prévention de la tuberculose multi résistante doivent être identifiées.Méthodes: La morbidité, la mortalité et les coûts associés au traitement de la tuberculose en Equateur, au Brésil et dans des contextes hypothétiques ont été comparés dans un modèle de Markov. Quatre stratégies ont été évaluées: 1) le traitement normalisé recommandé par l'OMS, 2) l'ajout d'EMB au traitement initial, 3) le renforcement du retraitement avec des médicaments de 2e ligne, 4) l'utilisation d'un traitement normalisé pour la tuberculose multi résistante lors d'échec du traitement initial. Les probabilités ont été tirées de la littérature. Les coûts ont été recueillis par questionnaires.Résultat: Renforcer le retraitement a un rapport coût-efficacité élevé en Équateur et au Brésil. Ajouter l'EMB pendant le traitement initial prévient le développement de résistance et les décès, mais conduit à une augmentation des cas de cécité.Conclusion: La stratégie de retraitement normalisé de l'OMS devrait être renforcée avec des médicaments de deuxième ligne.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Andrea Benedetti</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Richard Ian Menzies</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k761p.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn21k</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A0k225b34d"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Engineering</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Mining and Materials</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An open source engine for the processing of electron backscatter patterns</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Tetreault-Pinard, Philippe</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Electron backscatter diffraction (EBSD) is a recognized characterization technique for the scanning electron microscope. Over the last quarter century, several major advancements improved this technique and expanded its applications to the fields of materials engineering and geological science. These improvements have been primarily related to the commercialization of EBSD systems. With their conviviality and ease of use, these systems have reached a broad audience and have contributed to the maturation of EBSD. However, from another perspective, they have also limited the development by the EBSD community: researchers facing atypical problems do not have the opportunity to modify and improve commercial systems to meet their specific needs. Innovation is left to the scientists and engineers working at EBSD companies. This work offers a solution to this problem by the development of an open source, freely available software, EBSD-Image, for processing of diffraction patterns acquired by an EBSD system.Built on top of image analysis software, EBSD-Image provides a flexible and structured interface to implement new algorithms to process and extract information from diffraction patterns. Two applications are given to demonstrate the analytical benefits of the software. In one application, the calculation of different metrics to evaluate diffraction quality led to a more accurate characterization of the microstructure of Zr-2.5Nb pressure tubes. In the other, quantitative measurements of the deformation induced during metallographic specimen preparation were made, in addition to the development of a new quality metric to assess the deformation level in a sample.Furthermore, this work presents tools to validate new algorithms via the generation of simulated diffraction patterns as well as utilities to process and analyze large data sets on a distributed computing grid. Two file formats are introduced to provide a more practical way of processing large numbers of diffraction pattern image files and to share the results of an analysis. Finally, an equation linking the two resolutions of the Hough transform for diffraction patterns of any size and a method to remove artifacts created by vertical Kikuchi bands in the Hough space are proposed.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La diffraction d'électrons rétrodiffusées (EBSD) est une technique de caractérisation reconnue en microscopie électronique en balayage. Au cours du dernier quart de siècle, plusieurs progrès ont amélioré cette technique et ont élargi le spectre de ces applications dans les domaines du génie des matériaux et des sciences géologiques. Ces améliorations ont principalement été reliées à la commercialisation des systèmes EBSD. Avec leur convivialité et leur simplicité d'utilisation, ces systèmes ont permis de rejoindre un plus grand public et ainsi de permettre la maturité de l'EBSD. Toutefois, ils ont également limité la communauté scientifique de participer au développement de cette technique. Les chercheurs qui font face à des problématiques inhabituelles n'ont pas la possibilité de modifier et de perfectionner les systèmes commerciaux pour répondre à leurs propres besoins. L'innovation est réservée aux scientifiques et aux ingénieurs travaillant pour les compagnies d'EBSD. Avec le développement d'un logiciel gratuit à code source libre pour le traitement des diagrammes de diffraction acquis par un système EBSD, EBSD-Image, ce travail propose une solution à ce problème.Conçu à partir d'un logiciel d'analyse d'images, EBSD-Image offre une interface flexible et structurée pour l'implémentation de nouveaux algorithmes afin de traiter et d'extraire un maximum d'informations des diagrammes de diffraction. Deux exemples d'application sont présentés pour démontrer les avantages analytiques du logiciel. L'évaluation de la qualité de la diffraction a permis, pour l'un des deux exemples, de caractériser avec une plus grande exactitude la microstructure des tubes de forces d'alliage Zr-2.5Nb et, pour l'autre, de mesurer quantitativement le niveau de déformation induit lors de la préparation métallographique d'échantillons ainsi que de développer une nouvelle mesure de la qualité pour évaluer la déformation.En outre, ce mémoire présente des outils pour la validation de nouveaux algorithmes par la génération de diagrammes de diffraction simulés et des fonctions utilitaires pour le traitement et l'analyse d'un large ensemble de données sur une grille de calcul. Deux formats de fichier sont introduits afin de fournir une méthode plus pratique pour la manipulation d'un grand nombre de fichiers et de permettre le partage des résultats d'une analyse. Finalement, une équation reliant les deux résolutions de la transformée de Hough pour des diagrammes de diffraction de n'importe quelle dimension et une méthode pour éliminer les artéfacts dans l'espace de Hough engendrés pour les bandes de Kikuchi verticales sont proposées.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Raynald Gauvin</ual:supervisor><ual:supervisor>Pierre Hovington</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc20k.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b34d</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Engineering - Materials Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A5425kb08j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Biochemistry</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Novel roles for Bcl2 family proteins at the endoplasmic reticulum</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Heath-Engel, Hannah</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The Bcl2 family proteins are central regulators of apoptosis; the primary form of physiological cell death. Furthermore, inappropriate activation or silencing of Bcl2 family members has been associated with cancer development and treatment resistance. These proteins therefore represent attractive therapeutic targets, and, in consequence, an increased understanding of the roles played by Bcl2 proteins will be important for the development and implementation of targeted therapies. Although best characterized with respect to their role at the mitochondria, it is now evident that Bcl2 proteins also function at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). The focus of this thesis is on the role of Bcl2 proteins at the ER, specifically with respect to cell death initiated by the ER localized proteins Bik and p20Bap31. Bik and p20Bap31 were previously shown to initiate similar proapoptotic pathways, characterized by an early release of ER calcium stores, and inhibitable by Bcl2. The results of the current study are two-fold: first, using ER-targeted Bak and Bcl2 (Bakb5 and Bcl2b5) in a Bak/Bax deficient background, I have shown that Bik can disrupt an interaction between Bak and Bcl2 at the ER. Furthermore, Bik could overcome the protective effect of Bcl2b5 with respect to Bakb5. This finding provides the first direct evidence for regulation of cell death via binary interactions between Bcl2 family members at the ER. The second part of this study was designed to determine the roles of Bax/Bak and ER-restricted Bcl2 in the p20Bap31-initiated pathway. Using E1A/DNp53 transformed wild-type and Bax/Bak double knockout baby mouse kidney epithelial cells, I have shown that ectopic expression of p20Bap31, but not of Bik, can initiate a paraptosis-like form of non-apoptotic, Bax/Bak independent, cell death. Of particular importance, cell death could be delayed by Bcl2b5, in the absence of Bax/Bak; pointing to a novel, Bax/Bak independent, prosurvival role for Bcl2 at the ER. In summary, this study demonstrates the ability of Bcl2 family members to regulate cell death through binary interactions at the ER, and of Bcl2 to inhibit cell death in a Bax/Bak independent manner. Furthermore, a novel non-apoptotic cell death pathway initiated by p20Bap31 expression is identified.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>La famille de protéines Bcl2 a une importance fondamentale dans le contrôle de l'apoptose; la forme principale de mort cellulaire physiologique. De plus, le développement de cancers et la résistance aux thérapies sont associés à l'activation ou la suppression de membres de la famille Bcl2. Cette famille de protéines représente une cible thérapeutique intéressante et par conséquent, une connaissance approfondie des rôles des protéines Bcl2 sera important pour amener et exécuter des thérapies ciblées. Tandis que le rôle de ces protéines à la mitochondrie est bien caractérisé, une fonction des protéines Bcl2 au niveau du réticulum endoplasmique (RE) est maintenant évidente. Cette thèse porte sur le rôle des protéines Bcl2 au niveau du RE, particulièrement concernant l'apoptose initiée par Bik et p20Bap31, deux protéines qui sont localisés au RE. Les voies de signalisation proapoptotique qui sont initiées par Bik et p20Bap31 sont caractérisées par une libération précoce d'une réserve de calcium du RE et sont inhibées par Bcl2. Les résultats de l'étude présente portent sur deux domaines: premièrement, en empruntant des formes de Bak et Bcl2 qui sont ciblées au RE (Bakb5 et Bcl2b5) sur un fond déficient en Bak et Bax, je démontre que Bik est capable de perturber l'interaction entre Bak et Bcl2 au RE. En outre, Bik peut surmonter l'effet protectrice contre l'apoptose de Bcl2b5 par rapport à Bakb5. Ce sont les premières évidences qu'une interaction binaire entre des membres de la famille Bcl2 au RE peut contrôler la mort cellulaire.  La deuxième partie de cette étude était conçu pour déterminer le rôle de Bax/Bak et Bcl2 localisé uniquement au RE, dans la voie de signalisation initiée par p20Bap31. En utilisant des cellules provenant de l'épithélium rénale de souris nouveau-nés transformées par E1A/DNp53, soit de souche sauvage ou avec double knockout des gènes Bax et Bak, je démontre que l'expression ectopique de p20Bap31, mais non pas de Bik, peut initier une forme de mort cellulaire non-apoptotique indépendante de Bax/Bak qui ressemble la paraptose. Un résultat d'importance primordiale est qu'un délai de mort cellulaire attribué à Bcl2b5 s'avère dans l'absence de Bax et Bak, ce qui suggère un rôle pro-survie inattendu de Bcl2 au RE indépendant de Bax/Bak. Cette étude démontre une capacité de contrôler la mort cellulaire des membres de la famille Bcl2 par des interactions binaires au RE et une fonction inhibitrice de Bcl2 sur la mort cellulaire indépendante de Bax/Bak. De plus, une nouvelle voie de signalisation de mort cellulaire non-apoptotique initiée par p20Bap31 est identifiée.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Gordon C. Shore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rt651.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb08j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Cell</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3A3r074v437"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>A transcriptome analysis of mouse pituitary development: implication of Etv1 and Pax7 transcription factors in POMC transcription and cell differentiation</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Budry, Lionel</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Organe clé du système endocrinien, l'hypophyse est depuis longtemps le centre d'un inépuisable intérêt scientifique. De la caractérisation des hormones qu'elle produit à la compréhension des mécanismes qui contrôlent leur libération, les intenses investigations dont elle a été l'objet ont par le passé fait l'objet d'un prix Nobel.Plus récemment dans ce domaine, l'attention s'est concentré sur l'étroit contrôle transcriptionnel auquel sont assujettis les gènes qui codent pour les hormones hypophysaires. Notre laboratoire a précédemment défini les rôles de Tpit et NeuroD1 dans la transcription du gène de la Pomc et dans la différenciation des cellules qui l'expriment. Ces deux régulateurs transcriptionnels n'expliquent cependant pas à eux seuls tous les mécanismes de la différentiation des cellules Pomc. Nous avons donc entrepris un crible systématique du transcriptome hypophysaire durant le développement et dans la glande adulte à la recherche de nouveaux régulateurs transcriptionnels. À l'aide d'outils bio-informatiques, nous avons observé à l'échelle génomique des variations concertées de groupes de gènes biologiquement pertinents pour le développement et la maturation de l'hypophyse. Une approche de type « gène candidat » nous a permis d'identifier de nouveaux facteurs de transcription propres aux cellules Pomc-positives. Tout d'abord, nous avons démontré pour la première fois l'expression de Etv1, un facteur à domaine Ets préférentiellement exprimé dans les cellules Pomc dans l'hypophyse. Etv1 s'est révélé être un important activateur transcriptionnel de Pomc en collaboration avec Tpit et Pitx1. Par ailleurs, nous avons démontré l'expression spécifique de Pax7 dans les cellules mélanotropes de l'hypophyse, établissant ainsi les bases transcriptionnelles de la différence entre les deux lignées qui expriment la Pomc. À l'aide de la souris inactivée pour Pax7, nous avons montré l'impact de ce facteur sur le programme génétique des cellules Pomc. Pax7 joue un rôle majeur à la fois dans l'activation des gènes mélanotropes et dans la répression des gènes corticotropes. En résumé, notre analyse bio-informatique s'est révélée riche en données extrêmement pertinentes pour la compréhension de la biologie hypophysaire, comme le montre la description du rôle de Etv1 et de Pax7 dans la biologie des cellules Pomc.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>As the key organ in the endocrine system, the pituitary has long been the subject of intense scientific questioning. From the characterization of pituitary hormones to the understanding of the mechanisms controlling their release, the study of the pituitary yielded great discoveries, some being awarded a Nobel prize. More recently, the transcriptional control of genes encoding pituitary hormones was the object of much attention. In that context, our laboratory described the function of Tpit and NeuroD1 in the control of POMC-expressing cell differentiation and POMC cell-specific transcription and regulatory mechanisms. These two important genes do not suffice however to explain every aspect of POMC cell differentiation. We thus undertook the systematic screening of the developing and adult pituitary transcriptome in a search for novel transcriptional regulators. Using state of the art bioinformatic tools, we observed the concerted variations of biologically relevant gene groups as the organ develops and matures. Using a candidate gene approach, we identified new transcription factors expressed in POMC lineages. We describe for the first time the expression of Etv1, an Ets-domain containing factor, in the pituitary. We showed that Etv1 expression is specific to POMC cells and that it is important for activation of Pomc transcription in collaboration with Tpit and Pitx1. Furthermore, we demonstrated the melanotroph-specific expression of Pax7 in the pituitary, establishing a clear distinction between the two Pomc-expressing lineages at the transcriptional level. Using Pax7 knock-out mice, we determined the impact of this transcription factor on the genetic program of Pomc cells. Pax7 plays a major role in activating melanotroph genes and repressing corticotroph genes. In summary, our bio-informatic analysis yielded extremely relevant data with regard to pituitary development, particularly through the elucidation of key critical roles for Etv1 and Pax7 in Pomc cell biology.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacques Drouin</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773w045.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v437</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Molecular</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Agf06g308f"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Genetic and biochemical characterization of dihydrolipoamide dehydrogenases (LPD) in Sinorhizobium meliloti</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Babic, Branislav</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Afin d'étudier la fonctionnalité des déshydrogénases du dihydrolipoamide de Sinorhizobium meliloti, les gènes lpdA1, lpdA2 et lpdA3 ont été mutés par la méthode de mutagenèse dirigée par le recombinaison cross-over unique, au moyen de plasmides suicides modifiés pVIK112.  Le mutant lpdA1n'a pas été capable de croître sur le pyruvate, et sa croissance a été considérablement retardée sur les autres sources de carbone qui furent essayées.  L'activité du complexe pyruvate déshydrogénase n'a pas été décelée dans ce mutant, et la régulation du lpdA1 ne dépendait pas de la présence de pyruvate.  Ce mutant était Nod +, mais il paraissait être Fix-.  Bien que le mutant  lpdA2 s'avéra capable de pousser sur toutes les sources de carbone qui furent essayées, sa croissance fut ralentie de façon appréciable sur les milieux pyruvate, arabinose , glutamate et leucine.  L'activité de la déshydrogénase α-ketglutarate était presque abolie, mais le mutant a été capable de fixer l'azote atmosphérique.  L'expression du mutant lpdA2 a été augmentée au cours de la croissance sur l'arabinose, le malate et le succinate.  L'expression du mutant lpdA3, autrement impossible à distinguer de la souche mère RMG212, a été considérablement retardée sur la leucine, qui a aussi augmenté l'expression du lpdA3.  L'activité de la déshydrogénase à chaîne ramifiée α-cétoacide n'était pas détectable dans ce mutant, mais il a été capable de fixer l'azote atmosphérique.  Cette étude a démontré que les gènes lpdA codent pour des protéines fonctionnelles qui sont des éléments constitutifs de trois complexes enzymatiques différents.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>To investigate the functionality of the Sinorhizobium meliloti dihydrolipoamide dehydrogenases, the lpdA1, lpdA2, and lpdA3 genes were mutated through the site-directed, single cross-over recombination, using modified pVIK112 suicide plasmids.  The lpdA1 mutant failed to grow on pyruvate, and was significantly delayed on other tested carbon sources.  The activity of the pyruvate dehydrogenase complex was not detected in this mutant, and the regulation of the lpdA1 was not dependent on the presence of pyruvate.  This mutant was Nod+, but appeared Fix-.  Although the lpdA2 mutant was able to grow on all of the tested carbon sources, it was significantly delayed growing on pyruvate, arabinose, glutamate, and leucine.  The activity of α-ketglutarate dehydrogenase was almost abolished, but the mutant was able to fix atmospheric nitrogen.  The expression of the lpdA2 was upregulated during growth on arabinose, malate, and succinate.  The lpdA3 mutant, otherwise indistinguishable from the wild-type RmG212, was significantly delayed growing on leucine, which also upregulated the expression of the lpdA3.  Although the  activity of the branched-chain α-ketoacid dehydrogenase was not detectable in this mutant, it was able to fix the atmospheric nitrogen.  This study demonstrated that the lpdA genes encode functional proteins that are constitutive elements of the three different enzyme complexes. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brian T. Driscoll</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x59r.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g308f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Biology - Microbiology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Asq87bt869"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Investigating the effects of chemotherapeutic agents for testicular cancer on the male reproductive system, progeny outcome and spermatogonial stem cells in the rat</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Marcon, Ludovic</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Testicular cancer (TC) is the most common type of cancer affecting men between the ages of 15 and 35 years old. The standard chemotherapy for testicular cancer is a combination of bleomycin, etoposide and cisplatin (called BEP regimen) that results in cure rates over 90%. In order to determine whether the BEP regimen induces adverse effects on the male reproductive system and progeny outcomes, in chapter 2, male Sprague-Dawley rats were treated with a combination of bleomycin, etoposide and cisplatin for 9 consecutive weeks. BEP treatment resulted in decreased testis and epididymal weights, and sperm counts, but despite the dramatic effects on spermatogenesis, paternal exposure to BEP did not affect fertility, nor were there adverse effects on litter size, pre-and post-implantation losses, fetal weight and death rate or sex ratio observed among progeny sired by treated males; however, increased mortality was observed in pups during the perinatal phase. In chapter 3, we evaluated the reversibility of a subchronic BEP treatment on the male reproductive system and progeny outcome. Male rats were treated with a 9 week subchronic BEP regimen; progeny outcome parameters were determined every 3 weeks for a total of 9 weeks during recovery. Subchronic BEP caused transient defects on spermatogenesis; however, a prolonged increase in pre-implantation loss was observed up to 9 weeks after completion of the treatment, suggesting that spermatogonial stem cells may be affected. Thus, in chapter 4, the impact of BEP chemotherapy on spermatogonial stem cells (SSCs) was investigated. Testicular cell suspension from BEP-treated GCS-EGFP transgenic rats were transplanted into busulfan-treated recipient nude mice. The number and length of colonies-derived from transplanted stem cells was assessed as a function of stem cell activity after exposure to BEP. Finally, in chapter 5, we assessed the in vitro effects of bleomycin, etoposide and cisplatin alone and in combination on cultured rat stem/progenitor spermatogonia. These results indicated that BEP has deleterious effects on male reproductive functions including SSCs and progeny outcomes.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Le cancer testiculaire (ou cancer du testicule) est le type de cancer le plus commun chez les hommes âgés de 15 à 35 ans. La chimiothérapie de première ligne  pour le cancer du testicule est la combinaison de bléomycine, étoposide et cisplatine (appelé protocole BEP) qui permet un taux de guérison de plus de 90%. Afin de déterminer si le protocole BEP induit des effets néfastes sur le système reproducteur mâle ainsi que sur la progéniture, dans le second chapitre, nous avons traités des rats mâles (Sprague-Dawley) avec une combinaison de bléomycine, étoposide et cisplatine pendant 9 semaines consécutives. Le protocole BEP entraîna la diminution du poids des testicules et des épididymes, du nombre de spermatozoïdes, mais en dépit des effets spectaculaires sur la spermatogénèse, l'exposition du père au protocole BEP n'affecta pas la fertilité et aucun effet ne fut observé sur la taille de la portée, les pertes aux stades pré- et post- implantatoires, le poids et la mortalité fœtale ou encore sur le ratio mâle/femelle des fœtus issus de pères traités. Cependant, une augmentation de mortalité peu de temps après la naissance fut  observée. Dans le chapitre 3, nous avons évalué la réversibilité des effets du protocole BEP sub-chronique sur le système reproducteur mâle et la progéniture. Des rats mâles furent traités avec un protocole BEP sub-chronique de 9 semaines ; les paramètres de la progéniture furent déterminés toutes les 3 semaines pour un total de 9 semaines pendant la période de rétablissement. Le protocole BEP sub-chronique entraîna des effets transitoires sur la spermatogénèse, cependant une augmentation prolongée des pertes pré-implantatoires fut observé jusqu'à 9 semaines après la fin du traitement, suggérant que les cellules souches germinales puissent être affectées. Ainsi, dans le chapitre 4, l'impact de la chimiothérapie BEP sur les cellules souches germinales (CSGs) fut étudié. Des suspensions de cellules testiculaires provenant de rats transgéniques GCS-EGFP traités avec le protocole BEP furent transplantées dans des testicules récipiendaires traités au busulfan de souris immunodéficientes. Le nombre ainsi que la longueur des colonies provenant des cellules souches transplantées fut déterminé pour évaluer la capacité des cellules souches germinales exposées au BEP à rétablir la spermatogénèse. Enfin, dans le chapitre 5, nous avons évalué les effets in vitro de la bléomycine, de l'étoposide et du cisplatine seul ou en combinaison sur des cultures de spermatogonies. Ces résultats indiquent que le protocole BEP produit des effets néfastes sur les fonctions reproductives incluant les cellules souches germinales et la progéniture.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bernard Robaire</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j6029.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bt869</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Aw9505091b"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Physics</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Inelastic electron tunneling spectroscopy in molecular electronic devices from first-principles</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Ji, Tao</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>In this thesis, we present the first-principle calculations of inelastic electron tunneling spectroscopy(IETS) in single molecular break junctions. In a two-probe electrode-molecule-electrode  setup, density functional theory(DFT) is used for the construction of the Hamiltonian and the Keldysh non-equilibrium Green's function(NEGF) technique will be employed for determining the electron density in non-equilibrium system conditions. Total energy functional, atomic forces and Hessian matrix can be obtained in the DFT-NEGF formalism and self-consistent Born approximation(SCBA) is used to integrate the molecular vibrations (phonons) into the framework once the phonon spectra and eigenvectors are calculated from the dynamic matrix. Geometry optimization schemes will also be discussed as an indispensable part of the formalism as the equilibrium condition is crucial to correctly calculate the phonon properties of the system.To overcome the numerical difficulties, especially the large computational time demand of the electron-phonon coupling problem, we develop a numerical approximation for the electron self-energy due to phonons and the error is controlled within numerical precision. Besides, a direct IETS second order I-V derivative expression is derived to reduce the error of numerical differentiation under reasonable assumptions. These two approximations greatly reduce the computation requirement and make the calculation feasible within current numerical capability.As the application of the DFT-NEGF-SCBA formalism, we calculate the IETS of the gold-octanedithiol(ODT) molecular junction. The I-V curve, conductance and IETS from ab-inito calculations are compared directly to experiments. A microscopic understanding of the electron-phonon coupling mechanism in the molecular tunneling junctions is explained in this example. In addition, comparisons of the hydrogen-dissociative and hydrogen-non-dissociative ODT junctions as well as the different charge transfer behaviors are presented to show the effects of thiol formation in the ODT molecular junction.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Dans cette thèse, nous présentons des calculs ab initio de la spectroscopie à effet tunnel par électron inélastique (IETS)appliqués à des jonctions moléculaires. Dans le cadre d'une configuration électrode-molécule-électrode,la théorie de la fonctionnelle de la densité (DFT) est utilisée pour construire l'hamiltonien et les fonctions de Green hors-équilibres(NEGF) sont employées pour déterminer la densité électroniquedans des conditions hors-équilibre. Le cadrede la DFT-NEGF nous permet de calculer des quantités telles que la fonctionnelle d'énergie totale,les forces atomiques ainsi que la matrice de Hessian. L'approximationauto-consistante de Born (SCBA) est employée afin d'intégrer les vibrations moléculaires (phonons) dans le formalisme DFT-NEGF,une fois que le spectre des phonons et les vecteurs propres ont été calculés à partir de la matrice dynamique. Des méthodes d'optimisations géométriques sont aussi discutées en tant que part indispensable du formalisme,étant donné que la condition d'équilibre mécanique est essentielle afin de calculer correctement les propriétés des phonons du système.Afin de surmonter les difficultés numériques, particulièrement concernant la grande demandecomputationnelle requise pour le calcul du couplage électron-phonon, nous développons une approximation numérique pour la self-énergie associée aux phonons. De plus, en employant quelques hypothèses raisonables, nous dérivons une expression pour l'IETS calculée à partir de laseconde dérivée de la courbe I-V dans le butde réduire l'erreur associée à la différentiation numérique. L'utilisation de ces deux approximations diminuent grandement les exigences computationnelles et rendent les calculs possibles avec les capacités numériques actuelles.Comme application du formalisme DFT-NEGF-SCBA, nous calculons l'IETS de la jonction moléculaire or-octanedithiol(ODT)-or. La courbe I-V, la conductance et l'IETS obtenues par calculs ab initio sontdirectement comparées aux données expérimentales. Une compréhension microscopique du couplage électron-phonon pour une jonction moléculaire à effet tunnel est élaborée dans cet exemple. De plus, des comparaisons entre les jonctions ODT à hydrogène dissociatif et à hydrogène non-dissociatif ainsi queles différents comportements de transfert de charges sont présentés afin de montrer les effets de la formation du thiol dans la jonction moléculaire ODT.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Hong Guo</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w502c.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505091b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Solid State</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Abg257f445"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Academic achievement in First Nations adolescents: the role of parental and peer attachment in promoting successful outcomes</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>D'Arrisso, Alexandra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Cette étude porte sur l'examen du lien entre les relations d'attachement et la réussite scolaire chez les adolescents des Premières Nations.  L'attachement à la mère, au père et aux pairs est analysé en utilisant l'Inventaire de l'Attachement aux Parents et aux Pairs (IPPA : Inventory of Parent and Peer Attachment, de Armsden &amp; Greenberg, 1987), et les notes finales sont utilisées comme mesure de la réussite scolaire.  Soixante-seize étudiants des Premières Nations provenant d'une communauté éloignée du nord du Québec ont participé à cette étude.  Les résultats de l'analyse de régression indiquent que l'attachement au père prédit de manière significative la réussite scolaire.  Ce constat soutient l'idée que les pères aborigènes du Canada pourraient représenter une ressource non-exploitée dans la promotion de la réussite de leurs enfants (Ball &amp; George, 2006).  Par ailleurs, les recherches futures devraient se concentrer sur la pertinence d'utiliser une conceptualisation occidentale de l'attachement auprès d'adolescents des Premières Nations, compte-tenu du cadre environnemental et culturel unique dans lequel ils vivent.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>The present study is an examination of the association between attachment relationships and academic achievement in First Nations adolescents.  Mother, father and peer attachment was assessed using the Inventory of Parent and Peer Attachment (IPPA; Armsden &amp; Greenberg, 1987) and final grades were used as a measure of academic achievement.  Seventy-six First Nations students from a remote community in northern Quebec participated in the study.  The results of a regression analysis indicated that attachment to father significantly predicted academic achievement.  This finding supports the notion that Aboriginal fathers in Canada may represent an untapped resource in promoting the successful outcomes of their children (Ball &amp; George, 2006).  Future research should focus on whether Western conceptualizations of attachment are appropriate for use with First Nations adolescents in light of the unique cultural and environmental settings in which they live. </dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacob A. Burack</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n370j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257f445</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Ad504rk69j"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Children's anti-social and pro-social lies to familiar and unfamiliar adults</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Williams, Shanna</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Même si les parents incitent leurs enfants à ne pas mentir, ces derniers sont souventtémoins de mensonges dans leur environnement familial. À ce jour, aucune étude nes'est intéressée à l'utilisation spontanée du mensonge par l'enfant dans la relation avecson parent, bien que ce comportement soit observé d'abord dans le contexte familial etque les parents en discutent avec leurs enfants (Wilson, Smith, &amp; Ross, 2003). L'objectifde cette étude est d'examiner les comportements trompeurs chez les enfants dans lecontexte de la dyade parent-enfant. Les mensonges à caractères pro-sociaux etantisociaux ont été examinés lorsque les enfants mentaient à un parent ou à un adulteinconnu. Afin d'étudier les mensonges antisociaux, une version modifiée du temptationresistance paradigm de Talwar et Lee (2002) fut employée. Afin d'étudier lesmensonges pro-sociaux, le dispapointing gift paradigm de Talwar, Murphy et Lee (2007)fut utilisé. Les résultats démontrent qu'à travers différents types de mensonges, lesenfants ont tendance à mentir davantage à un adulte inconnu (un assistant de recherche)qu'à une figure parentale.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Although parents will frequently instruct their children not to lie, children will oftenobserve lie-telling within their immediate surroundings (i.e., the family environment). Todate, no empirical research has examined children's spontaneous lie-telling within thecontext of different inter-personal relationships (i.e., familiar versus unfamiliar adults),despite lie-telling being first observed by children within the family and often discussedwith children by parental figures (Wilson, Smith, &amp; Ross, 2003). The aim of the currentstudy is to examine children's spontaneous deceptive behaviour within the parent-childdyad. Children's antisocial and prosocial lies to a parent versus an unfamiliar adult wereexamined. To examine antisocial lie-telling, a modified version of Talwar and Lee's(2002) temptation resistance paradigm was used. To examine prosocial lie-telling, adisappointing gift paradigm (Talwar, Murphy, &amp; Lee, 2007) was used. Results indicatethat across different types of lies children are more likely to lie to an unfamiliar adult thanto a parental figure.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Victoria Talwar</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s0499.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rk69j</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Psychology</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3An583xv33m"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Doctor of Philosophy</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>The effects of greenhouse-gas and surface thermal forcing on the stratosphere</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Winter, Barbara</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>This thesis is concerned with the possible future changes in the stratosphere as a result of climate change. In this context, the climate change forcing can be separated into two components: (i) radiative forcing due to a doubling of the atmospheric CO2 mixing ratio, and (ii) surface thermal forcing. My focus is on the response in the circulation of the Northern Hemisphere stratosphere in winter. All experiments are carried out with a chemistry-climate model (CCM, i.e. an atmospheric general circulation model coupled to a chemistry model), the IGCM-FASTOC, and all results shown are averages over 100-year or 50-year simulations in timeslice mode (i.e. every year can be considered as one member of an ensemble having 50 or 100 members). This allows statistically robustresults in a region of high variability in the temperature and wind fields.When the IGCM-FASTOC is coupled to a mixed-layer slab ocean, the Arctic lower stratosphere in winter warms by up to 4K under 2xCO2 conditions, with associated weakening of the polar vortex and enhancement of the Brewer-Dobson circulation (BDC). This change is related to a significant increase in the Rossby wave forcing near the vortex core starting in January, followed by anincreased wave forcing at the lower edge of the polar vortex in February. Maximum wave forcing is found both to begin earlier in the winter and to be distributed over a longer period of time in the 2xCO2 climate. Results from four additional pairs of simulations (control and 2xCO2), in which sea and/or land surface temperatures were either calculated interactively, prescribed as a climatological cycle, or prescribed as interannually varying monthly-mean fields, demonstrate that the interannual variability in sea and land temperatures, and the adjustment of oceans and lands to the atmosphere and to one another, are essential in order to maintain realistic stratospheric forcing by Rossby waves and to adequately capture the stratospheric response to global warming. Specifically, when the land is interactive but the slab ocean is replaced by prescribed interannually varying monthly-mean temperatures, the stratospheric response is qualitatively similar to the fully interactive case, but has lower amplitude and is statistically significant over a smaller area.In the experiment without interannual variability, there is no response in stratospheric dynamics.To assess the impact of surface temperatures on the stratospheric circulation, a separate suite of experiments was carried out in which a 2K temperature anomaly was added to the control surface temperature at all gridpoints within latitudinal windows of 10 or 30 degrees. Thermal surface forcing applied anywhere equatorwards of 20N, or continuously from the equator to 30N, increases the generation of planetary waves in the troposphere, resulting in increased upward propagation. Consequently, a greater flux of wave activity enters the mid- to high latitude stratosphere and breaks in the polar vortex,increasing the BDC and leading to a warm anomaly in the polar stratosphere. Ozone concentration increases at high latitudes and decreases at low latitudes. Thermal surface forcing imposed between 30N and 60N has the reverse effect and leads to a stronger and colder vortex. Thermal forcing applied polewards of 60N has little effect on tropospheric baroclinicity, but results in a sufficientdecrease of the vertical flux of planetary wave activity that the vortex becomes anomalously strong and cold. In all cases when surface forcing is imposed only polewards of 30N, the ozone concentration decreases at high latitudes but is not affected at low latitudes. Combining the forcing in an equatorial and a mid-latitude band leads to a response similar to that of the equatorial forcing, demonstrating that the subtropical surface temperature changes dominate the sign of the surface-driven response in the vortex.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>Cette thèse étudie les possibles futurs changements dans la stratosphère dus au forçage par les changements climatiques. Dans ce contexte, les changements climatiques peuvent être séparés en deux composantes: (i) le forçage radiatif dû à un doublage de la concentration de CO2 dans l'atmosphère et (ii) le forçage thermique à la surface. L'emphase est mise sur la réponse dans lacirculation de l'Hémisphère nord en hiver. Toutes les expériences sont réalisées au moyen d'un modèle climat-chimie (un modèle de la circulation générale de l'atmosphère couplé à un modèle de chimie), le IGCM-FASTOC, et les résultats présentés sont les moyennes sur 100 ou 50 ans de simulations en mode répété (ou stationnaire, i.e. chaque année peut être considérée comme un membred'un ensemble ayant 100 ou 50 membres). Ceci permet d'aboutir à des résultats qui sont statistiquement significatifs dans une région où la température et les vents sont hautement variables.Lorsque le IGCM-FASTOC est couplé à un océan homogène de 25m de profondeur et que les températures de surface sont calculées de façon interactive, la réponse dans la basse stratosphère de l'Arctique à un doublage de CO2 est un réchauffement de 4K, accompagné d'un affaiblissement du vortex polaire et d'une augmentation de la circulation Brewer-Dobson (CBD). Ces changements sont reliés à une importante augmentation du flux vertical d'ondes Rossby, qui décélèrent le centre du vortex dès le mois de janvier, puis son bord inférieur en février. Le forçage maximal du vortex par les ondes débute plus tôt dans la saison hivernale et dure pour une plus grande période de temps dans le climat 2xCO2. Quatre paires de simulations supplémentaires (contrôle et 2xCO2) ontété réalisées, dans lesquelles les températures à la surface de l'océan et/ou de la terre étaient soit calculées de manière interactive, soit prescrites comme cycle climatologique fixe ou ayant une variabilité interannuelle. Ces expériences démontrent que la variabilité interannuelle, tout comme les ajustements des températures de surface à l'atmosphère ou des températures de la terre à celle des océans, sont essentielles pour maintenir un forçage réaliste du vortex par les ondes Rossby et donc pour capturer la réponse auxchangements climatiques de façon adéquate. Quand la surface terrestre est interactive mais l'océan couplé est remplacé par des températures imposées qui varient à l'échelle interannuelle, la réponse dans la stratosphère est qualitativement semblable à celle de l'expérience ayant l'océan interactif; par contre, cette réponse a une amplitude inférieure en plus d'être statistiquement significative sur une région moins importante. Les expériences sans variabilité interannuelle ne montrent aucun changement de la circulationdans la stratosphère.Pour évaluer l'importance du rôle de la température de surface dans la circulation stratosphérique, j'ai entrepris une nouvelle série d'expériences dans lesquelles une anomalie thermique de 2K est imposée à tous les points de grille à l'intérieur de bandes zonales larges de 10 ou de 30 degrés de latitude. Lorsque le forçage thermique est imposé à la surface entre 0N et 20N, ou de façon continue entre 0N et 30N, un plus grand flux d'activité ondulatoire accède à la stratosphère dans les moyennes et hautes latitudes. Les ondes se cassent dans le vortex, menant à une augmentation de la CBD et à une anomalie positive dans température de la stratosphère polaire.  Un forçage thermique imposé à la surface entre 30N et 60N donne le résultat inverse, soit un vortex plus fort et plus froid. Le forçage thermique imposé à la surface au nord de 60N affaiblit suffisamment le flux vertical d'activité ondulatoire pour que levortex en résulte plus froid et plus fort également. Lorsque le forçage thermique est appliqué à la fois dans une bande équatoriale et dans une bande des moyennes latitudes, le forçage dans les subtropiques domine le signe de la réponse dans le vortex polaire.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Michel Bourqui</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2685489.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xv33m</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Physics - Atmosperic Science</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Akp78gg72b"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Student outcomes in inquiry instruction</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Gyles, Petra</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>Un survol de la littérature des résultats d'élèves ayant suivi une démarche par investigation raisonnée nous a  permis d'établir une liste de résultats d'étudiants avec 23 critères  référentiels. Ceux-ci incluaient des résultats plus usuels, tels que la connaissance du contenu ou les habiletés procédurales, mais aussi des résultats moins souvent abordés, comme la créativité, la motivation, les habiletés à collaborer, et l'autonomie. Cette liste a été adaptée sous forme de questionnaire visant à déterminer jusqu'à quel point les divers résultats étaient perçus en classe par les enseignants dans leur auto-évaluation des divers niveaux d'utilisation (faible/moyen/élevé) de leur approche par investigation raisonnée. Des analyses ont été faites avec un échantillon de 74 individus. L'auto-analyse des enseignants de l'approche par investigation raisonnée était définitivement reliée de façon significative à la démarche par investigation de la catégorie des compétences d'apprentissage et de la motivation personnelle. Selon les enseignants, l'utilisation modérée de l'approche par investigation a permis aux élèves d'adopter de nouveaux rôles d'apprenants. Les enseignants ont semblé percevoir des changements dans le rôle des élèves avant  de les constater dans leurs rangs, mais ce résultat pourrait s'expliquer par la reconnaissance de la valeur positive de la collaboration, et, de façon inattendue, de la mémorisation aux niveaux supérieurs de l'approche par investigation raisonnée.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>A literature review of student outcomes from inquiry instruction generated a list of 23 criterion-referenced student outcomes.  These included more commonly addressed outcomes such as content knowledge and process skills, and less commonly addressed outcomes such as creativity, motivation, collaborative ability, and autonomy.  This list was adapted into a questionnaire probing to what extent the various outcomes were perceived in classrooms by teachers working at varying self-rated levels of inquiry use (low, middle, high).  Analyses were performed on a sample of 74.  Teachers' self-ratings of inquiry use were significantly and positively related to the inquiry outcomes categorized as learning competencies and personal motivation.  At moderate levels of inquiry use, teachers recognized that students adopted new learning roles.  Teachers appeared to perceive changes in students' roles before their own but this result could be explained by recognition of the positive value of collaboration and, unexpectedly, memorization within high levels of inquiry.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Bruce M. Shore</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fb95j.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gg72b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Education - Curriculum and Instruction</dc:subject></rdf:Description><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Adv13zt62f"><ual:graduationDate>2011</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Arts</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>An examination of the attentional blink effect in children and adolescents with autism spectrum disorders</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Leibovitch, Fallyn</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>AbstractThe current study is an investigation of attentional blink (AB) in children and adolescents with autism spectrum disorders (ASD). Attentional Blink refers to the brief lapse in visual processing when the eye rapidly moves from one location to another. The aim of the study was to determine whether individuals with ASD experience a more pronounced or longer AB than comparisons. Eleven children and adolescents with ASD and 11 typically developing children were matched on verbal and non-verbal mental age (MA) and presented with a dual-stream rapid serial visual presentation containing images of animals (targets) and objects (distractors), and instructed to identify the animals. No significant group differences were found in accuracy rates, indicating that temporal dynamics of attention might be intact in ASD. However, differences were found in accuracy rates when the participants were divided by MA, regardless of diagnosis, indicating a developmental trajectory of AB, for individuals with and without ASD.</dc:abstract><dc:abstract>RésuméCette étude porte sur le phénomène « d'attentional blink » (AB) chez les enfants et les adolescents atteints de troubles envahissants du développement (TED). L'« attentional blink » correspond au bref laps de temps pendant lequel le traitement visuel est défaillant lorsque le regard se déplace rapidement d'un endroit à l'autre. L'objectif de cette étude est de déterminer si les individus atteints de TED présentent un AB plus prononcé ou plus long que les individus témoins. Onze enfants et adolescents atteints de TED et 11 enfants au développement typique étaient appariés selon leur âge mental (AM) verbal et non verbal et devaient visionner une série de présentations doubles visuelles rapides contenant des images d'animaux (cibles) et des objets (distracteurs), et parmi lesquelles ils devaient identifier les animaux. Aucune différence significant entre les groupes n'est trouvée au niveau de l'exactitude des réponses, indiquant que la dynamique temporelle de l'attention pourrait être intacte dans les TED. Cependant, des différences sont trouvées au niveau de l'exactitude des réponses lorsque les participants sont regroupés en fonction de l'AM, indépendamment du diagnostic, indiquant ainsi une trajectoire développementale de l'AB, chez les individus présentant ou non un TED.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Jacob A. Burack</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j136b.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zt62f</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Psychology - Developmental</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>