<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ual="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca/" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:schema="https://schema.org/" xmlns:etdms="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><rdf:Description rdf:about="http://example.org/oai%3Aescholarship.mcgill.ca%3Afj236535b"><ual:graduationDate>1972</ual:graduationDate><dcterms:language>eng</dcterms:language><schema:inSupportOf>Master of Science</schema:inSupportOf><dc:contributor>Department of Medicine</dc:contributor><dcterms:publisher rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/McGill_University"/><dcterms:title>Calcium and phosphate homeostasis after the discovery of calcitonin investigation into the action of calcitonin on the kidney</dcterms:title><ual:dissertant>Hadjipavlou, Alexander</ual:dissertant><dc:abstract>The cellular control of calcium and phosphate is still confusing and controversial. The reviewer has tried to put useful hypotheses and existing knowledge into a more or less unified theory like all theories based on rational hypothesis this review may usefully serve in making predictions that could be experimentally tested. Calcitonin lowers the plasma calcium and phosphate, while parathormone lowers the plasma phosphate and increases the plasma calcium. However, it appears that calcitonin does not act as a competitive antagonist of parathormone but acts on a different cellular pathway. The action of calcitonin on the kidney is the subject of this experimental work. Direct infusion of calcitonin into the renal artery of thyroparathyroldectomized dogs resulted in an increased urinary excretion of phosphate; and appeared to have no effect GD the renal binding of calcium, sodium, chloride, potassium, urinary flow and pH.</dc:abstract><ual:supervisor>Brooks, E.</ual:supervisor><dc:identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v592h.pdf</dc:identifier><ual:fedora3Handle>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236535b</ual:fedora3Handle><dc:subject>Experimental Surgery</dc:subject></rdf:Description></rdf:RDF>