<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4/metadata.xsd"
          xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <identifier identifierType="DOI">10.7939/DVN/WVRWMV</identifier>
    <creators><creator><creatorName>Geary, Janis</creatorName><nameIdentifier schemeURI="https://orcid.org/" nameIdentifierScheme="ORCID">0000-0002-0743-8713</nameIdentifier><affiliation>(University of Alberta)</affiliation></creator></creators>
    <titles>
        <title>DNA barcoding publications</title>
    </titles>
    <publisher>UAL Dataverse</publisher>
    <publicationYear>2017</publicationYear>
    <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset"/>
    <relatedIdentifiers><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="DOI" relationType="HasPart">doi:10.7939/DVN/WVRWMV/7SO5KR</relatedIdentifier><relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="DOI" relationType="HasPart">doi:10.7939/DVN/WVRWMV/X88ETG</relatedIdentifier></relatedIdentifiers>
    <descriptions>
        <description descriptionType="Abstract">I searched the Scopus database for peer-reviewed literature that referenced any of four seminal barcode papers (Hebert et al. 2003; Hollingsworth et al. 2009; Schoch et al. 2012; Stoeckle and Hebert 2008). The search, conducted in January 2015, yielded 3557 scientific journal publications from 2003-2014. I, and a research assistant, extracted variables for each article including: publication source; publication year; number of citations; and author names and institutional affiliations. A research assistant trained in programming used a customized computer program to combine synonymous names of single individuals and separate identical names of different individuals. From this database I generated variables for presence of authors with institutional affiliations in high, middle, or low income countries (World Bank 2016); presence of authors from mega-biodiverse countries (Mittermeier 1997); and whether or not the paper was published in a highly ranked journal. I assigned an income variable using four-categories of Gross National Income (GNI) per capita levels from the World Bank (upper income, >=$12,476; upper middle income, $4,036 to $12,475; lower middle income $1,026 to $4,035; and low income, ≤$1,025). I used InCites Journal Citation Reports (Thomson Reuters 2016) to identify the top 10 ranking journals in each field category relevant to DNA barcoding.</description>
    </descriptions>
    <contributors><contributor contributorType="ContactPerson"><contributorName>Geary, Janis</contributorName><affiliation>(University of Alberta)</affiliation></contributor></contributors>
</resource>
