<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4/metadata.xsd"
          xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <identifier identifierType="DOI">10.7939/DVN/QYMAYV</identifier>
    <creators><creator><creatorName>Derocher, Andrew</creatorName><nameIdentifier schemeURI="https://orcid.org/" nameIdentifierScheme="ORCID">0000-0002-1104-7774</nameIdentifier><affiliation>(University of Alberta)</affiliation></creator></creators>
    <titles>
        <title>Replication Data for: Togunov RR, Derocher AE, Lunn NJ, Auger-Méthé M. 2021. Characterising menotatic behaviours in movement data using hidden Markov models. Methods in Ecology and Evolution.</title>
    </titles>
    <publisher>UAL Dataverse</publisher>
    <publicationYear>2021</publicationYear>
    <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset"/>
    
    <descriptions>
        <description descriptionType="Abstract">Data to support: Togunov RR, Derocher AE, Lunn NJ, Auger-Méthé M. 2021. Characterising menotatic behaviours in movement data using hidden Markov models. Methods in Ecology and Evolution. File description File: WH_X33406_location_data.csv Field Description Units time Date of GPS location obtained by telemetry collar. YYYY-MM-DD hh:mm x X coordinate1 Degrees longitude y Y coordinate1 Degrees latitude u10 ‘u’ (west to east) component of wind at 10m elevation2 m/s v10 ‘v’ (south to north) component of wind at 10m elevation2 m/s 1Unprojected locations in WGS84 (EPSG:4326) 2 Wind estimates are bilinearly interpolated from ECMWF’s ERA5 reanalysis: Hersbach, H., Bell, B., Berrisford, P., Hirahara, S., Hora_nyi, A., Mun~oz-Sabater, J., Nicolas, J., Peubey, C., Radu, R., Schepers, D., Simmons, A., Soci, C., Abdalla, S., Abellan, X., Balsamo, G., Bechtold, P., Biavati, G., Bidlot, J., Bonavita, M., Chiara, G. & et al. (2020). The ERA5 global reanalysis. Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society, 146(730), 1999-2049. http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/qj.3803 File: WH_X33406_location_data.xlsx An excel file containing WH_X33406_location_data.csv.</description>
    </descriptions>
    <contributors><contributor contributorType="ContactPerson"><contributorName>Derocher, Andrew</contributorName><affiliation>(University of Alberta)</affiliation></contributor></contributors>
</resource>
