<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4/metadata.xsd"
          xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <identifier identifierType="DOI">10.7939/DVN/WUDIRK</identifier>
    <creators><creator><creatorName>Kuhn, McKenzie</creatorName><affiliation>(University of Alberta)</affiliation></creator></creators>
    <titles>
        <title>Greenhouse gas, chemistry, and macrofossil data for a peatland lake in northern Alberta</title>
    </titles>
    <publisher>UAL Dataverse</publisher>
    <publicationYear>2021</publicationYear>
    <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset"/>
    
    <descriptions>
        <description descriptionType="Abstract">The data is provided in one xlsx file. The file (“Eli_data”) has nine tabs: “ReadMe”, “Summary_data”, “ebullition_data”, “Diffusion_data”, “Chamber_Data”,“Porewater_data”, “Incubation_data”, “DIC_Data,””macrofossil_data,” and “Bulk_density.” “ReadMe” contains all of the header and unit information for each of the six data sheets. “Summary_data” includes water chemistry, meteorological data, and averaged GHG flux data for each of the lake locations per sampling day over 2017 and 2018. “Flux_data” includes CH4 flux measurements for each individual chamber, bubble trap, or modeled diffusive flux from 2017. “Porewater_data” includes all of the porewater CH4 and DIC sediment porewater profiles from each lake location over 2017 and 2018. “Incubation_data” includes the sediment CH4 and CO2 production rates from laboratory incubations. “Macrofossil_data” includes the average macrofossil counts as relative percentages throughout the sediment profile from the center of the lake. “Bulk Density” includes the sediment bulk density throughout the sediment profile. The sediment was dried at 110°C and was determined according to Chambers et al (2011). All data is from one lake (“Eli”) in northern Alberta (59.48 N, 117.18 W, surface area = 0.05 hectares). See “ReadMe” tab for more information on the types of data represented and the collection/analysis methods.</description>
    </descriptions>
    <contributors><contributor contributorType="ContactPerson"><contributorName>Kuhn, McKenzie</contributorName><affiliation>(University of Alberta)</affiliation></contributor></contributors>
</resource>
