<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Cardio-respiratory Function, School Age Abilities and Quality of Life in Extremely Low Birth Weight Infants</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10954</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-11-28</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2017-05-29" type="RELEASED">1</version></verStmt><biblCit>MacLean, Joanna; Hendson, Leonora; Adatia, Ian; Majaesic, Carina; Lovering, Andrew; Thompson, Richard; Nicholas, David; Thebaud, Bernard; Stickland, Michael, 2016, "Cardio-respiratory Function, School Age Abilities and Quality of Life in Extremely Low Birth Weight Infants", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10954, UAL Dataverse, V1</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Cardio-respiratory Function, School Age Abilities and Quality of Life in Extremely Low Birth Weight Infants</titl><altTitl>New Breath Study</altTitl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10954</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">MacLean, Joanna</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Hendson, Leonora</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Adatia, Ian</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Majaesic, Carina</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Oregon">Lovering, Andrew</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Thompson, Richard</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Nicholas, David</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Ottawa">Thebaud, Bernard</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Stickland, Michael</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta">MacLean, Joanna</producer><prodDate>2012</prodDate><prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac><software>REDCap</software><software version="21">SPSS</software><software version="21">LabChart</software><software version="21">Vmax Encore by Carefusion</software></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="joanna.maclean@ualberta.ca">MacLean, Joanna</contact></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">infant, extremely premature</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">exercise test</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">quality of life</keyword><keyword>neurobehaviour</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">infant</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">cohort studies</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">pediatrics</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">intensive care units, neonatal</keyword><keyword>respiratory function</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">ventilatory response</keyword></subject><abstract>This study examined cardio-respiratory function, school age abilities and quality of life in a large cohort of children 8 to 12 years of age born extremely preterm (EP).</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="1997">1997</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2014">2014</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2012">2012</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2014">2014</collDate><dataKind>Questionnaire data; Interview data; Clinical data; Anthropometric data; Experimental data; Physiological data</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Edmonton</geogCover><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit><universe>Children 8 -12 years of age who were born extremely preterm (≤28 weeks gestation) between 1997 and 2004 and treated in a large regionalised neonatal intensive care unit in western Canada.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><frequenc>Data was collected at one time point.</frequenc><sampProc>There were 103 participants who were born preterm and 64 control children in this follow-up study. Initial contact with families of EP born children was by letter with follow-up phone calls. After agreement to participate, families were asked if they could identify a friend of their child who was born at term, healthy and interested in participating. Friends were scheduled on the same activity day. Additional community controls were recruited through key contacts and poster advertisements.</sampProc><sources><dataSrc>Child Sleep Habits Questionnaire (CSHQ); Child Health Questionnaire (CHQ) - Parent Report; Child Behaviour Check List (CBCL); Parent Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL); Child Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL); Adolescent Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL); Asthma Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL)</dataSrc></sources><collMode>Face-to-face interview; Self-administered questionnaire: Paper; Physical measurements and tests; Chart review; Physiological measurements and tests</collMode><collSitu>All families with a participating child were mailed a package of questionnaires prior to the activity day. This included the Child Sleep Habits Questionnaire (CSHQ); Child Health Questionnaire (CHQ) - Parent Report; Child Behaviour Check List (CBCL); Parent Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL); Child Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL); Adolescent Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL); and the Asthma Pediatric Quality of Life Survey (PedsQL). On the activity day children completed lung function testing, including spirometry, lung volumes and diffusion capacity, and cardio-pulmonary exercise testing (CPET) using a cycle ergometer.   A sub-set of children completed additional testing including oxygen (O2) and carbon dioxide (CO2) response testing, echocardiography, and quality of life interviews. If additional testing could not be completed in a single day, families were asked if they were willing to return on a separated day for echocardiography. Some quality of life interviews were completed by phone.  Medical chart review was completed for children born EP. This was restricted to the child's NICU chart which included a copy of the delivery record and included both free text and tabulated data. The data extraction was carried out by experienced neonatal research nurses.  Height was recorded, without shoes, using a fixed stadiometer. Weight was measured with exercise clothing, without shoes, using a digital scale. Height, weight and body mass index (BMI) were converted to z-scores using normative data from the Centre for Disease Control.</collSitu><conOps>RECap data validation was built into forms.</conOps><cleanOps>Outliers were checked and validated. Families were contacted if data was missing.</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail/><useStmt><conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1136/ thoraxjnl-2015-207736</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>MacLean JE, DeHaan K, Fuhr D, et al. Altered breathing mechanics and ventilatory response during exercise in children born extremely preterm. Thorax. 2016;71(11):1012-1019. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2015-207736.</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="http://thorax.bmj.com/content/early/2016/06/03/thoraxjnl-2015-207736.abstract"/></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr></codeBook>