<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Impact of Emergency Department Probiotic Treatment of Pediatric Gastroenteritis: Randomized Controlled Trial</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10896</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-10-21</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2017-05-26" type="RELEASED">3</version></verStmt><biblCit>Freedman, Stephen; Farion, Ken; Schuh, Suzanne; Gouin, Serge; Williamson-Urquhart, Sarah; Sherman, Philip; Willan, Andrew; Goeree, Ron; Johnson, David; Black, Karen; Schnadower, David; Gorelick, Marc, 2016, "Impact of Emergency Department Probiotic Treatment of Pediatric Gastroenteritis: Randomized Controlled Trial", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10896, UAL Dataverse, V3</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Impact of Emergency Department Probiotic Treatment of Pediatric Gastroenteritis: Randomized Controlled Trial</titl><altTitl>ProGut Study</altTitl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10896</IDNo><IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT01853124</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Freedman, Stephen</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario">Farion, Ken</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="The Hospital for Sick Children">Schuh, Suzanne</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Sainte Justine">Gouin, Serge</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Williamson-Urquhart, Sarah</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Toronto">Sherman, Philip</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Toronto">Willan, Andrew</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="McMaster University">Goeree, Ron</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Johnson, David</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="BC Children’s Hospital">Black, Karen</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Washington University School of Medicine">Schnadower, David</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Children’s Hospital of Wisconsin">Gorelick, Marc</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Calgary">Freedman, Stephen</producer><prodDate>2013</prodDate><prodPlac>Calgary, Alberta</prodPlac><software>REDCap</software></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Calgary" email="stephen.freedman@albertahealthservices.ca">Freedman, Stephen</contact><depDate>2016-09-29</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">diarrhea</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">digestive system diseases</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">gastrointestinal diseases</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">emergency departments</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">probiotics</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">pediatrics</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">randomized controlled trial</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">gastroenteritis</keyword></subject><abstract>PROGUT is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, six-center, Canadian, emergency department trial to determine whether the administration of a probiotic agent (Lacidofil) will result in a significantly lower proportion of children developing moderate to severe disease over the subsequent 2 weeks and will not be associated with a significantly greater occurrence of side effects.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2013-10">2013-10</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2017-07">2017-07</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2013-10">2013-10</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2017-06">2017-06</collDate><dataKind>Clinical data; Questionnaire data</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover> Calgary</geogCover><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Montreal</geogCover><geogCover>Quebec</geogCover><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Ottawa</geogCover><geogCover>Ontario</geogCover><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Toronto</geogCover><geogCover>Ontario</geogCover><anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit><universe>Children aged 3 months to 48 months who present at an emergency department  with less than 72 hours of gastroenteritis symptoms (vomiting and diarrhea).</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><frequenc>Data will be collected daily until both the diarrhea and vomiting have resolved.</frequenc><sampProc>The sample size estimate was based on the assessment of the between-group difference in proportions of children with a post-randomization score on the Modified Vesikari Scale (MVS). Our estimate for the development of moderate to severe episodes of acute gastroenteritis in the controls is based on data collected as part of two evaluations of the MVS in nearly 750 children in U.S. and Canadian emergency departments. Approximately 25% of eligible children had scores consistent with moderate to severe disease. Employing a baseline probability of 25% in the controls, the required sample size to compare proportions between two groups is 670. Based on previous work, a 10% loss to follow-up, 5% drop out, and 2.5% drop in probabilities was assumed. Adjustment for O'Brien-Fleming monitoring boundaries requires a further 2% increase. Thus, the final sample size required is 886.</sampProc><targetSampleSize><sampleSize>886</sampleSize></targetSampleSize><sources><dataSrc>Modified Vesikari Score</dataSrc></sources><collMode>Telephone interview; E-mail interview; Chart review; Database review</collMode><collSitu>Informed consent will be obtained from each participant's legally authorized guardian prior to enrollment into the study. Once consent is provided, the first dose will be administered. The sachet's contents will be sprinkled into 30 mL of oral rehydration solution (ORS). Caregivers will receive instructions on study drug administration, completion of study forms, what and how much fluid to drink, criteria for seeing a health care practitioner.    All patients will take one sachet every 12 hours for 5 days, at meal time, even once symptoms have resolved. The dose will be repeated once should vomiting occur within 15 minutes of medication administration. Children who are hospitalized will continue as per study protocol. Daily Telephone/Electronic Survey Communication: At the first visit, caregivers will be asked their preferred method of communication (electronic or telephone). Caregivers will be contacted daily by the identified method until both the diarrhea and vomiting have resolved. A standardized collection form will be employed. Detailed questioning will follow positive responses. Data regarding revisits, intravenous hydration, hospitalization, and microbiology testing will be verified by reviewing each hospital's medical record database. Provincial databases and Canadian Institute for Health Information databases will also be empl&#xd;
oyed to verify future health care provider use.</collSitu></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail><avlStatus>Data is not available because the study is still recruiting.</avlStatus></setAvail><useStmt/></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1186/1745-6215-15-170</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>Freedman SB, et al. Impact of Emergency Department Probiotic Treatment of Pediatric Gastroenteritis: Study Protocol for the PROGUT (Probiotic Regimen for Outpatient Gastroenteritis Utility of Treatment) Randomized Controlled Trial. Trials 15 (2014):170.</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24885220"/></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f6812" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6812" level="datafile"><labl>Freedman_ProGut_DataDictionary_2014-03-06.csv</labl><txt>Data dictionary for Impact of Emergency Department Probiotic Treatment of Pediatric Gastroenteritis: Randomized Controlled Trial REDCap project. It lists metadata (variables) for the following data: Demographics; Follow-up Preference; Dehydration Assessment and Study Drug Administration; Medications Administered in the Emergency Department; Subsequent Emergency Department Visits; Subsequent Hospital Admissions; Primary Admission - Admission to hospital at enrolment ED visit; Microbiology Testing; Patient Disposition; Study Materials Given Upon Discharge from Emergency Department; IgA Testing; Follow-Up Medical Care; Ongoing Symptoms; Medication Compliance (Day 5); Serious Adverse Events; Study Withdrawal/Early Termination/Loss to Follow Up Form</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/plain; charset=US-ASCII</notes></otherMat></codeBook>