<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>The CHAPTER I Study: Evaluation of Novel Transition Interventions for Youth With Congenital Heart Disease</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10906</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-10-21</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2017-05-26" type="RELEASED">2</version></verStmt><biblCit>Mackie, Andrew; Magill-Evans, Joyce; Rempel, Gwen; Rankin, Kathryn; Robert, Cheri; Dodd, Bernadette; Islam, Sunjidatul; Schuh, Michelle; Nicholas, David; Vonder Muhll, Isabelle; McCrindle, Brian; Yasui, Yutaka, 2016, "The CHAPTER I Study: Evaluation of Novel Transition Interventions for Youth With Congenital Heart Disease", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10906, UAL Dataverse, V2</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>The CHAPTER I Study: Evaluation of Novel Transition Interventions for Youth With Congenital Heart Disease</titl><altTitl>Congenital Heart Adolescents: Program of Transition Evaluation Research (CHAPTER)</altTitl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10906</IDNo><IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT01286480</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Mackie, Andrew</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Magill-Evans, Joyce</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Athabasca University">Rempel, Gwen</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Rankin, Kathryn</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Robert, Cheri</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Dodd, Bernadette</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Islam, Sunjidatul</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Stollery Children's Hospital">Schuh, Michelle</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Nicholas, David</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Vonder Muhll, Isabelle</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Toronto">McCrindle, Brian</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Yasui, Yutaka</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0001-6126-1130">Mackie, Andrew</producer><prodDate>2012</prodDate><prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac><software>REDCap</software><software>SPSS</software><software>Microsoft Excel</software><software>NVivo</software></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="andrew.mackie@ualberta.ca">Mackie, Andrew</contact></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">congenital heart defects</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">adolescent</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">heart diseases</keyword><keyword>patient education</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">randomized controlled trial</keyword><keyword>congenital heart diseases</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">health care transition</keyword></subject><abstract>The objective of this study was to evaluate the feasibility of a cardiology clinic-b&#xd;
ased educational intervention for 15 to 17 year teens with congenital heart disease (CHD), and to determine whether this intervention results in improved self-management skills, teens having greater knowledge of their heart condition, and more teen satisfaction with services. The study showed that an individualised nurse-led teaching session for older adolescents with heart disease results in improved knowledge of their heart and greater self-management skills relative to controls.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2011-01">2011-01</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2013-11">2013-11</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2011-01">2011-01</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2013-11">2013-11</collDate><dataKind>Questionnaire data; Clinical data; Qualitative data</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Edmonton</geogCover><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit><universe>15-17 old adolescents with moderate or complex congenital heart disease or acquired heart disease who are followed in the Stollery Pediatric Cardiology Clinic.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><frequenc>Data was collected at baseline, and at 1 and 6 month follow-ups.</frequenc><sampProc>Anticipating a mean TRAQ self-management baseline score of 3.01 (SD 1.02) (out of a possible 5.0) as reported for adolescents without a transition intervention and an anticipated mean score of 4.0 post-intervention resulting in a change score of 1 (ie, 1 SD), with ?=0.05 and 90% power, 23 patients in each intervention group (total of 46) is required. Assuming that 30% of participants would either withdraw or not complete the 6-month TRAQ questionnaire, the target sample size was 60 study participants. The actual number of study participants was 58. Patients were assigned to groups through block randomization with the unit of randomization being week.</sampProc><targetSampleSize><sampleSize>58</sampleSize></targetSampleSize><sources><dataSrc>Transition Readiness Assessment Questionnaire (TRAQ); Patient Satisfaction Questionnaire (PSQ-18); MyHeart Scale</dataSrc></sources><collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Paper; Self-administered questionnaire: Web-based; Self-administered writings and/or diaries; Observation; Chart review</collMode><collSitu>Adolescents in the intervention group took part in a one-on-one teaching session about health-related decision-making, self-advocacy, and lifestyle issues provided by a nurse. They filled out a 'MyHealth Passport' with information about their health. The study nurse also completed a log and field notes to document any difficulties that were encountered during the intervention and the participant's reaction, level of engagement, questions and body language. Adolescents in the control group received standard of care. They saw a nurse only to measure weight, height, and blood pressure and relied on their cardiologist for information about their heart condition.    All adolescents completed three short questionnaires at the start of the study, and completed them again 1 month later and 6 months later. The follow-up questionnaires were either mailed to participants or done via the internet.    Medical charts were reviewed only for information about participants' heart condition, such as the name of the heart condition, cardiac operations or procedures, cardiac medications, cardiology clinic notes, and inpatient notes for cardiac problems. A nursing log and text and email follow-up of the transition intervention will also be analysed. Upon completing the study questionnaires at the 1 month and 6 month intervals participants were sent a $25 gift certificate.</collSitu><actMin>Stamped envelopes were provided for returning measures. Non-responders received a phone reminder two and four weeks after each questionnaire.</actMin><conOps>Field validations were built into REDCap data collection forms.</conOps></dataColl><anlyInfo><dataAppr>The control group had lower overall response rate at 6 months.</dataAppr></anlyInfo></method><dataAccs><setAvail/><useStmt><conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relMat>MyHealth Passport: http://www.sickkids.ca/myhealthpassport/</relMat><relStdy>The CHAPTER II Study - Congenital Heart Adolescents Participating in Transition Evaluation Research</relStdy><relStdy>The CHAPTER III Study of Young Adolescents: Congenital Heart Adolescents Participating in Transition Evaluation Research</relStdy><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1136/heartjnl-2014-305748</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>Mackie AS, Islam S, Magill-Evans J, Rankin KN, Robert C, Schuh M, Nicholas D, Vonder Muhll I, McCrindle BW, Yasui Y, Rempel GR. (2014) Healthcare transition for youth with heart disease: a clinical trial. Heart. 2014 Jul;100(14):1113-8.</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="http://heart.bmj.com/content/early/2014/05/19/heartjnl-2014-305748.full.pdf"/></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f6847" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6847" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 BaselineQuestionnaires.pdf</labl><txt>The CHAPTER I Study Baseline Youth Questionnaires.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6848" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6848" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 Case Report Form - Medications Update.doc</labl><txt>Case Report Form - Updated Medications Sheet at 6 Month Questionnaire Completion for the CHAPTER I Study. </txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6849" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6849" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 Case Report Form.pdf</labl><txt>Case Report Form for the CHAPTER I Study.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6846" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6846" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 Consent - Intervention.doc</labl><txt>Information and Consent form for the intervention group participating in the CHAPTER I Study.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6851" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6851" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 Consent - Usual Care .doc</labl><txt>Information and Consent form for the usual care group participating in the CHAPTER I Study.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6853" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6853" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 Data - 19April2013 - Deidentified-V1.csv</labl><txt>Excel file with deidentified data corresponding to Youth Questionnaires, and Case Report Forms.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/plain; charset=US-ASCII</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6852" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6852" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 Data Collection- CRF-BCI01 - Intervention log.pdf</labl><txt>Clinic-Based Intervention Log for the CHAPTER I Study.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6850" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6850" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 FollowupQuestionnaires-Intervention.pdf</labl><txt>The CHAPTER I Follow-Up Youth Questionnaires for the intervention group</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6845" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6845" level="datafile"><labl>Mackie CHAPTER1 FollowupQuestionnaires-UsualCare.pdf</labl><txt>The CHAPTER I Follow-Up Youth Questionnaires for the usual care group.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>