<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Chan SES: Development of a Canadian socioeconomic status index for the study of health outcomes related to environmental pollution</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/TCZRUP</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2018-03-07</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2019-09-09" type="RELEASED">2</version></verStmt><biblCit>Chan, Emily; Serrano, Jesus; Chen, Li; Steib, David M.; Jerrett, Michael; Osornio-Vargas, Alvaro, 2018, "Chan SES: Development of a Canadian socioeconomic status index for the study of health outcomes related to environmental pollution", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/TCZRUP, UAL Dataverse, V2</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Chan SES: Development of a Canadian socioeconomic status index for the study of health outcomes related to environmental pollution</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/TCZRUP</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Pediatrics, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada">Chan, Emily</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="School of Public Health, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada">Serrano, Jesus</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Population Studies Division, Health Canada, Ottawa, Canada">Chen, Li</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Population Studies Division, Health Canada, Vancouver, Canada">Steib, David M.</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="School of Public Health, University of California, Berkeley, USA">Jerrett, Michael</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Pediatrics, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada">Osornio-Vargas, Alvaro</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt/><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact email="data@policywise.com">PolicyWise, SAGE</contact><depositr>Osornio-Vargas, Alvaro</depositr><depDate>2018-03-07</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Earth and Environmental Sciences</keyword><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85124194.html">Socioeconomic status</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85104530.html">Environment</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85059518.html">Health</keyword></subject><abstract date="2015-05-23">Background:&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
Socioeconomic status (SES) is an important determinant of health and potential modifier of the effects of environmental contaminants. There has been a lack of comprehensive indices for measuring overall SES in Canada. Here, a more comprehensive SES index is developed aiming to support future studies exploring health outcomes related to environmental pollution in Canada.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
Methods:&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
SES variables (n=22, Census Canada 2006) were selected based on: cultural identities, housing characteristics, variables identified in Canadian environmental injustice studies and a previous deprivation index (Pampalon index). Principal component analysis with a single varimax rotation (factor loadings=¦60¦) was performed on SES variables for 52974 census dissemination areas (DA). The final index was created by averaging the factor scores per DA according to the three components retained. The index was validated by examining its association with preterm birth (gestational age&lt;37 weeks), term low birth weight (LBW, &lt;2500 g), small for gestational age (SGA, &lt;10 percentile of birth weight for gestational age) and PM2.5 (particulate matter=2.5 µm) exposures in Edmonton, Alberta (1999–2008).&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
Results:&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
Index values exhibited a relatively normal distribution (median=0.11, mean=0.0, SD=0.58) across Canada. Values in Alberta tended to be higher than in Newfoundland and Labrador, Northwest Territories and Nunavut (Pearson chi-square p&lt;0.001 across provinces). Lower quintiles of our index and the Pampalon’s index confirmed know associations with a higher prevalence of LBW, SGA, preterm birth and PM2.5 exposure. Results with our index exhibited greater statistical significance and a more consistent gradient of PM2.5 levels and prevalence of pregnancy outcomes.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
Conclusions:&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
Our index reflects more dimensions of SES than an earlier index and it performed superiorly in capturing gradients in prevalence of pregnancy outcomes. It can be used for future research involving environmental pollution and health in Canada.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&lt;strong>These metadata can also be found on SAGE's searchable metadata website:&lt;br>&#xd;
http://sagemetadata.policywise.com/nada/index.php/catalog/14&lt;/strong></abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2006-05-16">2006-05-16</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2006-05-16">2006-05-16</timePrd><dataKind>Mail Questionnaire</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogUnit>Dissemination Area</geogUnit></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><sources><dataSrc>Socioeconomic data were analyzed from the Canadian Census 2006. For our evaluation, we extracted Census data from CANSIM, Canada’s socioeconomic database which provides free access to a range of the latest statistics. The Census was completed on May 16, 2006 and 32.5 million people were included. One in every five households received a long questionnaire with 53 questions in comparison to 8 for the short form. Here, we used data from the long questionnaire forms. These data cover all of Canada’s dissemination areas (DAs), which are small regions consisting of 400 to 700 people. Canada has 52974 DAs, ranging from 34 for Nunavut to 18923 for Ontario.</dataSrc></sources></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><notes type="DVN:TOU" level="dv">CC0 Waiver</notes><notes type="DVN:TOA" level="dv">We are accepting proposals for our 2018 Secondary Data Use Grant starting February 20, 2018. This grant provides $5,000 to successful applicants to undertake research using data in SAGE. The term of the grant is 12 months. The grant offers an excellent opportunity for trainees and new researchers to work with existing birth cohort and survey data. Deadline for applications is April 27, 2018 at 4:00 PM MST.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>No special access conditions or procedures beyond the standard SAGE data access protocol. See: https://policywise.com/initiatives/sage/accessing-data/.&#xd;
&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>They must also contact Dr. Alvaro Osornio-Vargas for permission to use these data: osornio@ualberta.ca.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
Data must be cited in any publication or report using data bibliographic citation. All users of these data must cite the reference Chan et al (2015): https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4517649/.</notes><setAvail/><useStmt/></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1992-y</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>Chan E, Serrano J, Chen L, Stieb DM, Jerrett M, Osornio-Vargas A. Development of a Canadian socioeconomic status index for the study of health outcomes related to environmental pollution. BMC Public Health. 2015;15(1):714. doi: 10.1186/s12889-015-1992-y. </biblCit></citation></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f8912" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/TCZRUP/PQNXCQ" level="datafile"><labl>S11_ChanSES_full_metadata_v01.pdf</labl><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>