<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Prophylactic Peritoneal Dialysis Decreases Time to Achieve a Negative Fluid Balance After the Norwood Procedure</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10918</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-10-21</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2017-05-29" type="RELEASED">3</version></verStmt><biblCit>Ryerson, Lindsay; Mackie, Andrew; Atallah, Joseph; Joffe, Ari; Rebeyka, Ivan; Ross, David; Adatia, Ian, 2016, "Prophylactic Peritoneal Dialysis Decreases Time to Achieve a Negative Fluid Balance After the Norwood Procedure", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10918, UAL Dataverse, V3</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Prophylactic Peritoneal Dialysis Decreases Time to Achieve a Negative Fluid Balance After the Norwood Procedure</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10918</IDNo><IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT01215240</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Ryerson, Lindsay</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Mackie, Andrew</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Atallah, Joseph</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Joffe, Ari</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Rebeyka, Ivan</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Ross, David</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Adatia, Ian</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Ryerson, Lindsay</producer><prodDate>2010</prodDate><prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac><software version="9.2">SAS</software></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="ryerson@ualberta.ca">Ryerson, Lindsay</contact></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">randomized controlled trial</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">infant</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">pediatrics</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">congenital abnormalities</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">congenital heart defects</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">heart diseases</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">peritoneal dialysis</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">catheterization</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">hypoplastic left heart syndrome</keyword></subject><abstract>The objective of this study was to determine whether peritoneal dialysis (PD) catheter insertion decreases the time to achieve a negative 24 hour post-operative fluid balance and improve morbidity in neonates with hypoplastic left heart syndrome (HLHS) or its variants who undergo a Norwood procedure.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2010-09">2010-09</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2013-12">2013-12</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2010-09">2010-09</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2013-10">2013-10</collDate><dataKind>Clinical data; Mass spectrometer data; Medical records</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Edmonton, Alberta</geogCover><anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit><universe>Newborn infants with hypoplastic left heart syndrome (HLHS) or its variants.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><frequenc>Data was collected until patients were discharged.</frequenc><sampProc>There were 22 study participants. We calculated that enrollment of 22 patients would provide statistical power of 80% to detect a 24-hour reduction in the time to negative fluid balance (the minimal clinically important difference) assuming a standard deviation of 20 hours or approximately 0.83 days (based on institutional published data for the mean first postoperative day of negative balance of 2.7  0.83 days), with an alpha (type 1 error rate) of 0.05.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Physical measurements and tests</collMode><collSitu>Demographic variables include Alberta health care number, patient's initials, DOB (dd/mm/yy), birth weight, sex.     Pre-operative variables include ventilation (days), cardiac diagnosis, presence of aortic atresia with mitral stenosis, presence of left or right atrial isomerism, presence of common atrioventricular (AV) valve, presence of more than mild AV valve regurgitation, highest plasma lactate, lowest arterial pH, lowest base deficit, lowest PaO2, peak VIS, and presence of non cardiac anomalies.    Operative variables include weight, age at time of Norwood procedure, CPB time, aortic cross clamp (ACC) time, deep hypothermic circulatory arrest (DHCA) time, regional cerebral perfusion (RCP), additional CPB run, and MUF time.    Post-operative variables include total daily fluid intake (ml/kg/day), daily urine output (ml/kg/day), daily mean ultrafiltration (ml/kg/day), daily chest tube output (ml/kg/day), daily net fluid balance (ml/kg/day), duration of PD (hours), change in PD dialysis solution, change in PD cycle time, time to sternal closure (hours), chest re-opening, post-operative CPR, post-operative ECLS, peak VIS on post-operative day one, peak VIS on post-operative days two to five, highest plasma lactate on post-operative day one, highest plasma lactate on post-operative days two to five, time to plasma lactate ? 2mmol/L, VO2 every four hours for the first 24 hours and then every eight hours for hours 25-72,    SaO2 every four hours for the first 24 hours and then every eight hours for hours 25-72,  SvO2 every four hours for the first 24 hours and then every eight hours for hours 25-72, lowest SvO2 on post-operative day 1 (normal SvO2 in a single ventricle population ? 40%), lowest SvO2 on post-operative days two to five , lowest arterial pH on post-operative day one, lowest arterial pH on post-operative days two to five, lowest base deficit on post-operative day one, lowest base deficit on post-operative days two to five, lowest PaO2 on post-operative day one, lowest PaO2 on post-operative days two to five, time to first extubation, ventilator days, death in PICU, death in hospital, hospital LOS, control group receipt of clinically indicated PD catheter, red blood cell transfusion, complications of PD including small bowel obstruction, peritonitis, bowel perforation, omental herniation, hypokalemia requiring treatment and hyperglycemia requiring insulin infusion at 18-24 month follow-up.</collSitu><cleanOps>REDCap was used to flag inconsistencies and the principal investigator reviewed every record.</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail/><useStmt><conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1016/j.jtcvs.2014.08.011</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>Ryerson, L.M, Mackie, A.S, Atallah, J, Joffe, A.R, Rebeyka, I.M, Ross, D.B, Adatia, I. (2015) Prophylactic peritoneal dialysis catheter does not decrease time to achieve a negative fluid balance after the Norwood procedure: A randomized controlled trial. The Journal of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, 149.1: 222-228.</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jtcvs.2014.08.011"/></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f6833" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6833" level="datafile"><labl>Ryerson_Norwood_case_report_form_April2012.doc</labl><txt>Blank Case Report Form for Prophylactic Peritoneal Dialysis Decreases Time to Achieve a Negative Fluid Balance After the Norwood Procedure </txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6832" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6832" level="datafile"><labl>Ryerson_Norwood_protocol.doc</labl><txt>Study Protocol for Prophylactic Peritoneal Dialysis Decreases Time to Achieve a Negative Fluid Balance After the Norwood Procedure </txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat></codeBook>