<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Gait-focused Physical Therapy Programs for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy: A Mixed Methods Randomized Controlled Trial</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10923</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-10-21</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2017-05-29" type="RELEASED">3</version></verStmt><biblCit>Wright, Virginia; Wiart, Lesley; Rosychuk, Rhonda, 2016, "Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Gait-focused Physical Therapy Programs for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy: A Mixed Methods Randomized Controlled Trial", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10923, UAL Dataverse, V3</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Gait-focused Physical Therapy Programs for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy: A Mixed Methods Randomized Controlled Trial</titl><altTitl>Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Physical Therapy for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy</altTitl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10923</IDNo><IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT02391324</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Holland Bloorview Kids Rehabilitation Hospital">Wright, Virginia</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Wiart, Lesley</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Rosychuk, Rhonda</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="Holland Bloorview Kids Rehabilitation Hospital">Wright, Virginia</producer><producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Wiart, Lesley</producer><prodDate>2015</prodDate><prodPlac>Toronto, Ontario; Edmonton, Alberta; Chicago, Illinois</prodPlac><software>NVivo</software></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="lesley.wiart@ualberta.ca">Wiart, Lesley</contact></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">brain diseases</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">central nervous system diseases</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">exercise</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">motor skills</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">randomized controlled trial</keyword><keyword>mixed methods studies</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">qualitative research</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">pediatrics</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">rehabilitation</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">cerebral palsy</keyword><keyword>robot assisted gait training</keyword><keyword>physical therapy</keyword></subject><abstract>This is a prospective, multi-centre, concurrent mixed methods study comprised of a randomized controlled trial (RCT) and an interpretive descriptive qualitative design. The goal of the RCT is to compare: 1) a walking training program with the Lokomat robotic device (LOK), 2) a functional physical therapy program (fPT) that includes activities to enhance balance/co-ordination/endurance and advanced motor skills conducted over 'real ground', 3) a combined Lokomat + functional physical therapy (LOK+fPT) program, and 4) a regular maintenance therapy condition (CONT). The qualitative part of the study will consist of interviews of children and parents after they have finished the study intervention.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2015">2015</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2019">2019</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2016-01">2016-01</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2019-10">2019-10</collDate><dataKind>Observational data; Clinical data; Interview data; Audiovisual data; Accelerometer data</dataKind><geogCover>Canada; United States</geogCover><geogCover>Toronto, Ontario; Edmonton, Alberta; Chicago, Illinois</geogCover><anlyUnit>Individuals; Parent/child dyad</anlyUnit><universe>Children with cerebral palsy aged 5-18 years who are ambulatory (Gross Motor Function Classification System Levels II and III).</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><frequenc>RCT: Data will be collected at baseline, and at 8 weeks and 20 weeks. The three intervention programs will consist of sixteen 50-minute sessions given twice weekly over 8 to 10 weeks.  Qualitative: Participating parents and children in the RCT will be interviewed within 1 month of intervention completion.</frequenc><sampProc>RCT: The sample size of 144 children represents 9 children per age group (less than 13y; 13 to 18y), GMFCS strata, and intervention combination. An additional 16 participants will be recruited to accommodate an estimated 10 % drop out rate (144/.9) for a total of 160. The 10 % drop out rate was based on the current 7 % drop out rate in the feasibility trial conducted at Holland Bloorview. Sample size calculations were based on pre- to post-intervention change on the primary outcome (Gross Motor Function Measure-66) (GMFM-66) and a two-factor factorial design (F tests). PASS software was used to calculate sample size.     Qualitative: Target sample size: 18 RCT participant child-parent dyads (6 dyads from each site) and 3 parents from each site who declined participation in the RCT. The estimated sample size is based on theoretical understanding of the complexity and variability of the data.</sampProc><sources><dataSrc>Gross motor abilities: GMFM-66 (Dimensions D- Stand &amp; E - Walk/Run/Jump); Challenge Measure (GMFCS level II) and GMFM Dimensions D and E with aids and orthoses (GMFCS III)  Walking capacity/gait: 1- and 6-Minute Walk Test, Bloorview Barefoot Gait Assessment (scored from video)   Individualized goal attainment: Canadian Occupational Performance Measure (COPM) and Goal Attainment Scale (GAS)   Standing and Walking Balance: Pediatric Balance Scale, Quality FM (Stability from GMFM-66 video), Activities Balance Confidence Scale  Functional abilities: PEDI-CAT   Physical Activity levels: Accelerometry (5 days)  Physical Activity Self-efficacy: Self-Efficacy for Physical Activity   Participation: Participation and Environment Measure for Children and Youth (PEM?CY)   Quality of life: KidScreen and Students' Life Satisfaction Scale (SLSS)</dataSrc></sources><collMode>Face-to-face interview; Self-administered questionnaire: Paper; Self-administered questionnaire: Web-based; Observation; Recording; Physical measurements and tests</collMode><collSitu>Qualitative component: Individual interviews with parents (and their children for those in the RCT) will be conducted. Parents&#xd;
will participate in 45-60 min semi-structured, individual interviews conducted by one member of the research team. Children will be interviewed for 20-45 minutes. Data sources will be digital recordings, transcribed text of all interviews, and field notes created by the interviewers. All data will be entered into REDCap, a secure, web-based application for building and managing online research projects.</collSitu><actMin>Calls will be made to participants before their appointments.</actMin><conOps>Assessments will be video-recorded and a random sample of 20 % of the assessment's video-recordings will be scored by an independent assessor who will not be aware of assessment sequence order. This double scoring will be done through the study to flag any scoring issues and allow remedial action.</conOps><cleanOps>Data verification is built into the REDCap data collection forms.</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail><avlStatus>Data is not available because the study is still recruiting.</avlStatus></setAvail><useStmt><conditions>Access to the data is limited to selected members of the research team and to collaborators at local sites of the multi-site study.</conditions></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1186/s12883-016-0582-7</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>Wiart L, Rosychuk RJ, Wright FV. Evaluation of the effectiveness of robotic gait training and gait-focused physical therapy programs for children and youth with cerebral palsy: a mixed methods RCT. BMC Neurology. 2016;16:86.</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="http://bmcneurol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12883-016-0582-7/open-peer-review"/></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f6794" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6794" level="datafile"><labl>Wiart_Consent_parents.doc</labl><txt>Parent Consent Form for Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Gait-focused Physical Therapy Programs for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy: A Mixed Methods RCT</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6800" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6800" level="datafile"><labl>Wiart_Information_Letter_Assent.doc</labl><txt>Information Letter and Assent Form for children participating in Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Gait-focused Physical Therapy Programs for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy: A Mixed Methods Randomized Controlled Trial</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6793" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6793" level="datafile"><labl>Wiart_Information_Letter_parents.doc</labl><txt>Parent Information Sheet  for Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Gait-focused Physical Therapy Programs for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy: A Mixed Methods RCT</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat></codeBook>