<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Peat carbon, δ14C, macrofossil, and humification data from a thawing permafrost peatland in western Canada</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/MKM0ZE</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2019-09-12</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2019-09-12" type="RELEASED">1</version></verStmt><biblCit>Heffernan, Liam, 2019, "Peat carbon, δ14C, macrofossil, and humification data from a thawing permafrost peatland in western Canada", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/MKM0ZE, UAL Dataverse, V1</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Peat carbon, δ14C, macrofossil, and humification data from a thawing permafrost peatland in western Canada</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/MKM0ZE</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Heffernan, Liam</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt/><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="wheffern@ualberta.ca">Heffernan, Liam</contact><depositr>Heffernan, Liam</depositr><depDate>2019-09-12</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Earth and Environmental Sciences</keyword><keyword>Peat</keyword><keyword>Carbon</keyword><keyword>Permafrost</keyword><keyword>Biogeochemistry</keyword></subject><abstract date="2019-09-12">The data provided in one xlsx file has five tabs: read me, bulk density and LOI, carbon content, FTIR and C:N, radiocarbon, and plant macrofossils. The same data is available in separate csv files and all data files are included in one zip file, except for a read me file wihcih is in txt format.. "Read me" contains descriptions of all column headers and data. It provides units of measurement for each. "Bulk density and LOI" contains the bulk density and loss-on-ignition values of peat samples. Bulk density was used with measured carbon content to calculate carbon stocks. LOI was used to aid in identifying transitions between peatland developmental stages. Peat was first dried at 110°C to calculate bulk density and then combusted at 550°C to determine LOI. Both bulk density and LOi were determined according to Chambers et al (2011). "Carbon content" contains the measured carbon content of peat samples. Measurements were determined using a Eurovector EA 3000 Elemental Analyzer (HEKAtech, Wegberg, Germany) from a homogenized sample. A site average (45%) carbon content was used with bulk density measurements to calculate carbon stocks. "FTIR and C:N" contains Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy and molar C:N ratios from peat samples. We analyzed samples for FTIR on an Agilent 660 FT-IR spectrometer (Agilent Technologies Inc., Santa Clara, CA, USA). Calculated molar C:N ratios, were determined using a Eurovector EA 3000 Elemental Analyzer (HEKAtech, Wegberg, Germany) from a homogenized sample. The mean carbon content of peat was 45 ± 3.6% (n = 45). "Radiocarbon" contains the lab ID, uncalibrated age, fraction modern, calibrated 1-sigma age, Bacon model age, material dated, and stratigraphic significance for peat samples across all eight cores. Peat samples were dated using 14C analysis with accelerator mass spectrometry (AMS) at the A. E. Lalonde AMS Laboratory, Ottawa. Bacon model age represents age-depth models that were estimated using the BAcon software (Blaauw and Christeny 2011) "Plant macrofossils" contains measurements from a number of depths across all cores. It contains estimates of % presence of Sphagnum, brown moss, sedge, ligneous matter, and ericaceous rootlets using five ranges (≤ 1%, 1 – 10%, > 10 – 50%, > 50 – 90%, and > 90%) of percentage of peat volume acquired from the mean of five different estimates per 1 cm section. Plant needles and leaves are reported as individuals per cm3. Along with bulk density, LOI,and radiocarbon dates, plant macrofossils were used to identify the main transitions between macrofossil assemblages, peatland stages, and permafrost history at the study site.</abstract><sumDscr/><notes>The data set contains the measured values from the study. Based on the results of the study we find no long-term net change in boreal peatland carbon stores, carbon accumulation, and peat decomposition following permafrost thaw. Using our approach and this data set we rule out large losses and gains of carbon following permafrost thaw.</notes></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><sources/></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><notes type="DVN:TOU" level="dv">CC0 Waiver</notes><setAvail/><useStmt/></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relPubl><citation><biblCit>Chambers, F. M., Beilman, D. W., &amp; Yu, Z. (2011). - Methods for determining peat humification and for quantifying peat bulk density. Mires and Peat, 7(7), 1–10.</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="http://www.mires-and-peat.net/pages/volumes/map07/map0707.php"/></relPubl><relPubl><citation><biblCit>Mauquoy, D., Hughes, P., &amp; van Geel, B. (2010). A protocol for plant macrofossil analysis of peat deposits. Mires and Peat, 7(06), 1–5. https://doi.org/http://www.mires-and-peat.net/map07/map_07_06.htm</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="http://www.mires-and-peat.net/map07/map_07_06.htm"/></relPubl><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1214/11-BA618</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>Blaauw, M., &amp; Christeny, J. A. (2011). Flexible paleoclimate age-depth models using an autoregressive gamma process. Bayesian Analysis, 6(3), 457–474.</biblCit></citation></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f9862" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/MKM0ZE/GIXFVI" level="datafile"><labl>Peat carbon, δ14C, macrofossil, and humification data from a thawing permafrost peatland in western Canada.rar</labl><txt>Zipped files that contains all xlsx, csv, and txt files.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/x-rar-compressed</notes></otherMat></codeBook>