<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Jamieson, Heber Carss</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-b011a9d4b27760ac74bbe6ac0f6c5a8b">
        <p>Physician, Medical historian, 1879-1962.  Heber Jamieson came to Edmonton in 1911 to join the  staff of the Provincial Laboratory of Public Health.  With the establishment of the Faculty of  Medicine at the University in 1913, he became a part-time instructor in basic medical sciences.  In  1914, when Dr. A.C. Rankin, the newly appointed Provincial Bacteriologist and Director of the Provincial Laboratory, left on military service overseas, Dr. Jamieson assumed his duties on a  temporary basis for the next five years.  Appointed lecturer in Medicine in 1920 and associate  professor two years later, he was made professor of the history of medicine in 1925.  Dr. Jamieson also conducted a private practice in internal medicine where his specialized treatment  of diabetic patients gained recognition for excellent results and advanced methods.  In 1943 he was  promoted to the rank of professor of Clinical Medicine and although he retired from the University  in 1946, his long association with the institution was continued in his being named Honorary  Professor of that department.  He retired from private practice in 1950.  In the course of his career, Dr. Jamieson wrote one book, Early Medicine in Alberta, The First  Seventy-Five Years, and numerous articles. Their theme is the development of medical facilities  within the province, with special emphasis on doctors who were in the area before 1910, and on early hospitals and nursing care.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/heber-carss-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Heber Carss fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/heber-carss-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Heber Carss fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1861-1961</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
