<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Nexus Theatre Society</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-7570540b25f1a3c8d1253597ab438f7b">
        <p>Nexus Theatre was founded as a lunch-hour theatre for downtown Edmonton in the autumn of 1982. The group had originated as a cooperative called Tuesday's Players, led mainly by David Russell and Linda Pollard. Their initial production had been the Fringe Festival that summer. In 1983, Russell left to work on his M.F.A. in Directing, and Ben Henderson became the first artistic director. Nexus produced its earliest shows out of the Centennial Library Theatre and the Art Gallery Theatre. In 1983 nexus moved into own space, downstairs at McCauley Plaza. The space was donated by Alberta Government Telephones (AGT) and provided Nexus with offices and rehearsal/performance space. John Milton Branton succeeded Henderson as artistic director in 1987. Branton, though continuing Nexus's lunch hour tradition, put more emphasis on new and locally developed shows. In 1991, when Branton resigned and Earl Klein took over as artistic director, the theatre was showing signs of strain. The time constraints of producing a lunch hour show had always limited the box office, and this reality made Nexus dependent upon fundraising and grants. Additionally, AGT withdrew its sponsorship of the McCauley Plaza Space, leaving Nexus without a stable base. Nexus's financial problems deepened when many corporations in the area shifted to a half-hour lunch. Klein resigned in 1993, and Sean Quigley stepped in as artistic director but Nexus was unable to get out from under its mounting debt load.  Over the next few years, Nexus mounted several works but ultimately was forced to fold in 1995.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/nexus-theatre-society-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Nexus Theatre Society fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/nexus-theatre-society-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Nexus Theatre Society fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1979-1997, predominant 1982-1995</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
