<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Shandro, Hutch</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-3ba2fb324be42495fe59e8b582e69f3d">
        <p>Actor, Director, 1936-1991 Hutchison Shandro was born in Edmonton in 1936, the son of Betty and Joseph Shandro. He grew up in Edmonton and Lethbridge where he attended primary and secondary school. He first attended the University of Alberta in 1954 when he studied chemistry. He graduated with a Bachelor of Science Degree in 1958. He subsequently worked for two years for C.I.L. Industries in Kingston as a chemical technician. While working in Kingston from 1959 to 1961 Shandro maintained his theatrical interests; he played several roles in the semi-professional Domino Theatre Company. He decided to change careers and returned to the University of Alberta to study drama. Graduating with a B.A. in Drama in 1962, Shandro was accepted to study at the prestigious London Academy of Music and Dramatic Art (LAMDA). He studied theatre in London for two years. He returned to Canada to a professional career in theatre as a teacher, actor and director. He remained active in theatre communities across Canada until his death in 1991. Shandro performed, directed and taught at such notable theatrical companies as Holiday Theatre and the Playhouse in Vancouver, the Grand Theatre in London, Theatre Plus in Toronto, the National Theatre School in Montreal, York University, Ryerson Polytechnical Institute, Bishop's University and the Belfry Theatre in Victoria. His involvement in Edmonton theatre included work with Theatre 3, Studio Theatre, Torches Theatre, Circle Eight Theatre and the Edmonton Theatre Associates.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/hutch-shandro-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Hutch Shandro fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/hutch-shandro-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Hutch Shandro fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1936-1991</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
