<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta.  Department of Drama.</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-c98d5873fb9bb9304e04fc1cad8e9a18">
        <p>Studio Theatre was established in 1949 as a place for Drama Division students to practice their craft and hone their skills.  Staff of the Drama Division of the Department of Fine Arts operated the Theatre, and early participants included Robert Orchard, Gordon Peacock, Bert Pullinger, Frank Glenfield, Elizabeth Sterling Haynes, Don Pimm, and Tom Peacocke.  The Theatre site was located in two deserted Second World War Quonset huts.  The Quonset huts, placed side by side, contained between them a stage, auditorium, workshop, drama offices, and foyer.  The first play produced on the Quonset stage was Henry IV, and for the next eight seasons over forty full-act plays, numerous one-act plays, two world premieres, and six Canadian premieres were produced on the Quonset Studio Theatre stage.  The Quonset huts were torn down in 1958, and Studio Theatre was offered auditorium and classroom space in the Education Building (E.A. Corbett Hall).  Studio Theatre occupied this space through to June 1989, winding up its 40th season anniversary with Michael Frayn's Benefactor just prior to the closing of Corbett Hall for renovations on June 17, 1989.  Studio Theatre then operated from the Myer Horowitz stage and, in 1995, moved to its new home in the newly opened Timms Centre. Studio Theatre celebrated its 50th anniversary of operation in the spring of 1999, and continues in the present to provide Edmonton audiences with a varied and unique theatre experience.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/department-of-drama-studio-theatre-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Department of Drama, Studio Theatre fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/department-of-drama-studio-theatre-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Department of Drama, Studio Theatre fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1949-1993</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
