<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Faculty of Arts and Science</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-de674d7c7e477c9cf6e4aa7cbc9054e6">
        <p>At its first meeting in March 1908, the Senate decided to  organize the new University of Alberta with one faculty, that of  Arts and Science.  When it opened its doors in September 1908, the  University consisted of a President, four professors and forty-  five students, in rooms rented from Queen Alexandra School.  Three  of the professors taught subjects in the Humanities, and the  fourth taught in the area of Applied Sciences, which later became the Faculty of Engineering. Dr. W.A.R. Kerr arrived to teach  Modern Languages in 1909, and became the first Dean of the Faculty  of Arts and Science in 1914. The Dean acted for the President  during his absences from campus, chaired many major committees,  and was actively involved in the development of the University.  Before the advent of department chairs, the Dean's Office handled every aspect of financial and academic business for the entire faculty.  The Council of the Faculty was the forerunner of the  General Faculties Council, which is now the academic governing  body of the University.  Arts and Science was separated into two  faculties in 1963. Deans: 1914-1936 William Alexander Robb Kerr; 1936-1938 William  Hardy Alexander; 1938-1945 George Malcolm Smith; 1945-1952 John  Macdonald; 1952-1957 Walter Hugh Johns; 1957-1963 Douglas Elstow  Smith .</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/faculty-of-arts-and-science-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Faculty of Arts and Science fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/faculty-of-arts-and-science-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Faculty of Arts and Science fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1908-1969</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
