<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Faculty of Nursing</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-d49432e6e46316627a7253cca664ca24">
        <p>Nursing courses at the University of Alberta were supported by the Canadian Red Cross from  1918 to 1923.  The School of Nursing was officially established within the Faculty of Medicine in  September, 1923 and the first four baccalaureate students (BScN) graduated in 1928.  The clinical  portion of the course was offered by the University of Alberta Hospital School of Nursing until  1966.  Following the passage of the Universities Act in that year, the School of Nursing became an  autonomous academic unit within the University.  The four-year integrated Baccalaureate in Nursing  program was implemented at this time.  The School of Nursing received Faculty status in 1976.  Graduate degrees have been available since 1975.  Off-campus and collaborative programs with the  community and junior colleges of Alberta have been developed, and the merger of the University of  Alberta Hospitals School of Nursing and the Faculty of Nursing will take place in the fall term, 1991/92.  The goal of the Faculty is to be a centre of excellence in Nursing for the advancement,  dissemination and application of nursing knowledge through teaching, research and public service. Directors: 1937-1940 Agnes Jean MacLeod; 1940-1943 Helen Griffith McArthur; 1943-1946  Madeline McCulla Larson (Acting); 1946-1956 Helen E.M. Penhale; 1957-1975 Ruth Elizabeth  McClure.   Deans: 1976 Ruth Elizabeth McClure; 1976-1980 Amy Elliott Zelmer; 1980-[1982]  Peggy-Anne Field; 1982-1987 Janetta MacPhail; 1987-  Marilyn J. Wood.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/faculty-of-nursing-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Faculty of Nursing fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1906-1991</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
