<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Office of the Vice-President (Research)</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-ba76b5e558911361a24836ae4f2dd6db">
        <p>Assuming roles once held by the President, the Vice-President (Academic) and the Research Grants and Contracts Office (1969-1981) the office of the Vice-President (Research) coordinates and promotes research conducted within the University of Alberta and represents the University's research needs to government and industry.  As overseer of University research, the Vice-President (Research) is responsible for setting policies on contracts, grants, patents and proposals; assisting University departments in obtaining research funding; administering the University Research Fund; evaluating the University's affiliated institutes, centres and companies; and actively seeking out sources of funding.  The Vice- President serves on the President's Executive Committee and other University governing bodies, and is responsible for the Intellectual Property and Contracts Office, the Research Grants Office, liaison with the Faculty of Graduate Studies and Research, and other facilities related to research.  Vice-Presidents (Research): 1981-1987 J. Gordin Kaplan; 1987- Christopher R. James.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-vice-president-research-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Vice-President (Research) fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-vice-president-research-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Vice-President (Research) fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1946-1990</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
