<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Alumni Association</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-434e8d6e3a17c57f13227636046f73da">
        <p>The Alumni Association, formed in 1915, confers automatic lifetime membership, without fee, on every graduate of the University.  It reviews programs, provides advice and support to the University and is represented on the Board of Governors and the Senate.  A president is elected each year to head the Council; the President of the University is an honorary member, and the presidents of the Students' Union and the Graduate Students' Association are ex officio members of the Council.  Branches of the Association have been formed throughout the world and their representatives also sit on the Council. Graduates from the professional schools (Medicine, Dentistry, Pharmacy, Business, Nursing, Education, Forestry) can join special associations which promote the welfare of their Faculty under the aegis of the general Alumni Association. Elected secretaries kept the Association's records from 1915 to 1926.  Geoffrey B. Taylor, Assistant Registrar, provided his unpaid services as Secretary from 1926 to 1946.  A full-time paid position was established in that year. The purpose of the Alumni Affairs Office, headed by a Director, is to provide professional administrative management and support to the Association, and to oversee alumni involvement with the University.  While it may be possible to distinguish between the activities of the Association and the Office, and between some of the papers of each, because the two are so intertwined and because the Office provides all of the administrative support necessary for the functioning of the Association, the Archives has combined the records in this description. Secretaries: 1946-1947 John Clemence Gordon Brown; 1947-1951 John William Evans Markle; 1951-1977 Alex Gilmour Markle</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/alumni-association-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Alumni Association fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/alumni-association-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Alumni Association fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1914-1990</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
