<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Special Sessions</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-5db0603c59e55e8cd80f2282daca8556">
        <p>Special Sessions organizes and administers the instructional  delivery of programs of other academic units.  It provides extra-  sessional credit courses through Spring Session, Summer Session  and the Off-Campus Credit Program, at both undergraduate and  graduate levels, to full-time and part-time students, and in  cooperative programs, such as those with the Department of Adult,  Career and Technology Education, Faculte St-Jean, and Athabasca  University's Sunrise Project.  In 1919 the University, through the Special Sessions Office, became involved in teacher education,  conducting a modest-sized summer program in cooperation with the  provincial Department of Education (the latter had been using  classrooms on the University campus since 1913, to hold classes  during the summer months for teachers who wished to upgrade their  education).  In 1950 the first evening credit courses were offered  through the University.  Classes were held at three locations:  on the Edmonton campus, in Calgary and in Lethbridge.  A University  Senate Committee on Evening Courses was formed; its terms of  reference included responsibility both for credit courses, offered  by Special Sessions, and noncredit courses, offered by the  Department of Extension.  The Evening Credit Division Program was  administered by the Department of Extension until 1955-1956, when  J.W. Gilles, Director of Summer Session, was appointed its coordinator, and a new committee for the program was established  whose terms of reference included only those matters dealing with  credit courses.  When a University of Alberta campus was  established in Calgary, it was made responsible for administration  of the Evening Credit Program in the southern part of the  province.  In 1965 the Summer Session and Evening Program committees were amalgamated on a recommendation of the General  Faculties Council.  The operations of Special Sessions were  consolidated in the early seventies and a new program, Spring  Session, was implemented, modelled after the Summer Session  Program.  The first classes were held in May-June 1972. Integration of late afternoon and evening credit courses held on  campus into the general operations of the University was approved  in 1970.  Courses became the responsibility of the school/faculty  concerned.  Off-campus credit courses remained extra-sessional,  and continued to be administered by the Office of Special Sessions  until 1977, when responsibility for the program was divided  between the Office of the Registrar (student recruitment, community contacts, handling local problems with courses, and  establishing cooperation with other institutions), and the Special  Sessions Office (courses, instructors, dealings with faculties and  departments).  In 1983 Special Sessions became part of the Faculty  of Extension (PAACR, 1987). Directors -  Summer Session: 1945-1949 Herbert Edgar Smith;  [1949-1951] George Murray Dunlop.   Directors -  Special Sessions:  1951-1968 John William Gilles; 1968-1977 Stanley Charles Tremayne  Clarke; 1977-  Kenneth L. Carswell.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/special-sessions-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Special Sessions fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/special-sessions-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Special Sessions fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1916-1974</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
