<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. University Computing Systems</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-415e3370a166591b056fad1ae7b8b050">
        <p>The Office of Administrative Data Processing (ADP) was  established to serve administrative functions of the University  by providing centralized business systems and data processing  expertise, and computer data processing production capability.  It functioned to examine administrative systems, identify  problems, devise improvements, and to help implement recommendations.  In 1967, ADP was mainly responsible for the preparation and processing of punched cards for the accounting systems for student  records, staff payroll and student fees.  With access to Computing  Centre facilities, automation was initiated in 1968.  By 1969 ADP  acquired its own computer, with the agreement that it would  provide operational support for the University Library on its  hardware.  Systems were implemented for payroll, student records,  fees accounting, inter-departmental billing, cheque reconciliation, space utilization and inventory, University  Bookstore, 3AU Fund, and Alumni Affairs.  Department surveys were  undertaken to suggest improvements in administrative practices and  procedures.  In [1974], ADP was renamed Office of Administrative Systems; OAS  and Computing Services merged to form University Computing Systems  in 1988.  At that time, a new advisory committee, the University  Computing Advisory Group, was also created. Records deposited in  the Archives are from ADP/OAS dated prior to the merger. Directors:  [1967-1968] William Barton McMinn; 1969-1974 Gerald  Mulhall; 1974-1988 Peter A. Watts; 1988-1989 Bruce Miller; 1990-  1991 Kenneth Porteous; 1991-  Monica Beltrametti.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/university-computing-systems-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>University Computing Systems fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/university-computing-systems-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>University Computing Systems fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1964-1975</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
