<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Interdisciplinary Studies</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-3e009f4cd63f88b9a5a361eb304de121">
        <p>The establishment of the position of Dean of Interdisciplinary  Studies was approved by the Board of Governors in February, 1975.  The Dean, reporting to the Vice-President (Academic), was charged  with responsibility for the administration of existing  interdisciplinary and multidisciplinary graduate programs, the  development of further interdisciplinary degree programs at the graduate level, and for overseeing institutes and centres whose  activities did not clearly lie within one particular faculty.  Institutes, centres, and programs falling under Interdisciplinary  Studies were the Boreal Institute for Northern Studies, the  Canadian Institute of Ukrainian Studies, the Centre for Advanced  Study in Theoretical Psychology, the Centre for the Study of Mental Retardation, the Devonian Botanic Garden, the Division of  Community Development, the Division of East European Studies, and  the Water Resources Centre.  The duties of the Dean of  Interdisciplinary Studies were transferred to the Vice-President  (Research) in 1981. Deans: 1976-1981 Gerald Seymour Hunter Lock.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/interdisciplinary-studies-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Interdisciplinary Studies fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/interdisciplinary-studies-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Interdisciplinary Studies fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1975-1981</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
