<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Office of the Associate Vice-President (Academic)</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-24f4fa2c90aced1323f5d593004e045f">
        <p>The position of Associate was created in 1971 to assist the Vice- President (Academic) with the increasingly heavy workload.  The Associate was assigned the administrative work connected with the Vice- President's duties as chair of eight committees, member of another ten, supervisor of all the faculties, schools, ancillary services and research institutes, and administrator of all academic appointments. In 1976 a second Associate position was established; in 1978 administration of academic staff contracts was assigned to a third Associate (Academic Administration).  Two more offices were created in 1985: International Affairs, and Information Systems.  The duties of the latter were transferred to the Vice-President (Student and Academic Services) in 1990. Where a Vice-President is absent or for any reason unable to exercise or perform an assigned power, duty or function, the Associate Vice- President is empowered to exercise and perform such power, duty or function. Associate Vice-Presidents: 1971-1980 Willard Finlay Allen; 1976-1980 Jean K. Lauber; 1980- [1985] Ronald D. Bercov; 1980-1988 Amy Elliott Zelmer; 1988- Dianne K. Kieren.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-associate-vice-president-academic-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Associate Vice-President (Academic) fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-associate-vice-president-academic-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Associate Vice-President (Academic) fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1968-1988</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
