<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Office of the Vice-President (Academic)</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-25ec9bfae37dad5af99bcd4e7482d233">
        <p>The Vice-President (Academic) is the senior Vice-President in the University and as such, acts for the President whenever so delegated. Until the establishment of the office in 1955 a senior dean was appointed to this duty on an ad hoc basis. In 1943 an Assistant to the President was appointed to share some of the administrative load placed on this office.  When Dr. Walter Hugh Johns was named to the office of Vice-President in 1955 he continued in his position as Dean of Arts and Science until assuming the office full-time in 1957. In 1963 the title was changed to Vice-President (Academic). Some of the responsibilities of this office are assigned by the Board of Governors upon recommendation of the President, and others are assigned by General Faculties Council.  The Vice-President (Academic) has responsibility for the appointment, the terms of appointment, and the termination of appointment of the faculty members of the University.  The records of the office show that the Vice-President has taken administrative responsibility for the following areas since 1955: teaching faculties and schools; Faculty of Graduate Studies and Research; budget for academic departments; academic policy, planning, program proposals; and staff and student affairs. The Vice-President (Academic) is Chair or member of the major standing committees of the University:  those of the Board of Governors, the Senate, General Faculties Council and the President.  There are numerous national and provincial bodies concerned with education in which the Vice- President (Academic) participates. Executive Assistants: 1943-1946 Clem L. King; 1947-1952 Walter Hugh Johns; [1952-1960] George Samuel    Vice-Presidents: 1955-1959 Walter Hugh Johns; [1959]-1963 Lawrence Harold Cragg; 1963-1964 Herbert Stoker Armstrong; 1964-1969 Max Wyman; 1969-1970 Arthur Gilbert McCalla; 1970-1975 Henry Kreisel; 1975-1979 Myer Horowitz; 1979-1984 R. George Baldwin; 1984-1991 J. Peter Meekison</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-vice-president-academic-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Vice-President (Academic) fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-vice-president-academic-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Vice-President (Academic) fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1926-1990</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
