<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. University Libraries</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-3bed78f61e3e5f2b5b62f9e30aebf86c">
        <p>The University Library System provides informational resources  and services, primarily for the benefit of faculty and students,  in support of teaching and research, but it also makes them  available, with some limitations, to individuals and organizations  outside the University community.  It is heavily used by  government departments, industrial and commercial organizations,  teachers, and medical and legal practitioners.  The University Library System comprises the Bibliotheque Faculte  St.-Jean, the Bruce Peel Special Collections Library, the Herbert  T. Coutts (Education) Library, the Humanities and Social Sciences  Library, the John A. Weir Memorial Law Library, the John W. Scott  Health Sciences Library and the Science and Technology Library  (MAPPS, 03-150-010, 1988).  The Bruce Peel Special Collections Library houses the Universityþs  rare books in the humanities and social sciences.  It also  includes some literary manuscripts, Western Canadiana, all the  University of Alberta theses and dissertations, major holdings in  English literature and 20th-century fine printing.  The Humanities and Social Sciences Library includes the monograph  collection in Rutherford North, the Periodical and Microform  Centre in Rutherford South, Government Publications in Cameron  Library and the business reference library in the Winspear Reading  Room in the Business Building.  The H.T. Coutts (Education) Library, the primary resource library  for the Faculty of Education, contains material on the theory and  practice of teaching.  The Curriculum Collection contains guides  and classroom materials for use with students from kindergarten  to the grade twelve level.  The John W. Scott Health Sciences Library in the Walter C.  Mackenzie Health Sciences Centre contains books and periodicals  for all the fields of the medical sciences and related basic  sciences.  Historical materials are found in the Phyllis Russell  Rare Book Room.  Audiovisual materials on health-related topics  as well as the necessary equipment for their use are also  available (Calendar, 1990/91).  The Science and Technology Library includes the Canadian Circumpolar Library, the Computing Science Reading Room, the  Mathematics and the Physical Sciences Branch Libraries. Chief Librarians:  1908-1911 Eugenie Archibald; 1911-1912 Cecil  Ethelbert Race (Acting); 1912-1921 Frank Gresty Bowers; 1921-  1945 Donald Ewing Cameron; 1945-1955 Marjorie Sherlock; 1955-  1982 Bruce Braden Peel; 1982-1989 Peter Freeman; 1989-1990  John Teskey (Acting); 1990-  Ernie Ingles.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/university-libraries-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>University Libraries fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/university-libraries-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>University Libraries fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1908-1986</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
