<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Office of the Comptroller</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-bbb0818857fe7901c92c2545cff03da9">
        <p>Prior to 1913 the business functions of the University appear to have been under the direction of  the Registrar, who was appointed in 1910.  In 1913 the first Bursar was appointed to take full  charge of the finances of the University, including all receiving and disbursing of moneys.  At its inception, and for some time after, the Office of the Bursar was responsible for all physical  facilities, all personnel matters, and for the academic and general administration of the university.  The Bursar also served as Secretary to the Board of Governors and to various committees which  dealt with academic and non-academic concerns.  As the University grew a number of these functions, such as personnel and physical facilities, were assumed by specialized administrative  units, and in 1968 the accounting functions of the Bursar were assumed by the newly created Office  of the Comptroller.  The Comptroller is the principal accounting officer of the University responsible to the Vice-  President (Administration).  As such, he/she is responsible for: the determination of accounting  policy; internal and external financial reporting; supervision and maintenance of the formal financial  and accounting records; internal control; tax and legal matters; administration of estates; insurance  and risk management; budget control; custody of current leases; contracts; administration of  matching grants and gifts-in-kind programs (shared with the Development Office); the treasury  function of collection, receipt, custody, banking, disbursement, and general administration of all funds in accordance with the policies and procedures established by the Board of Governors.  In conjunction with these responsibilities, the Comptroller provides management accounting and  systems development advice and assistance to ancillary and various other departments.  The  Comptroller is also involved in the development of financial policies, systems, procedures,  regulations, and the forms required for their implementation.  He/she is responsible for the  operation and integrity of the University's financial and accounting computer records.  By virtue of  his/her position, the Comptroller is in regular attendance at meetings of the Audit Committee of the  Board of Governors.  The Comptroller is a member, at times the secretary-treasurer, of a number of  University committees relating to conferences, opening of tenders, benefits and staff travel.  He/she  also serves as Trustee of the Academic Benefits Plans and the Centre for Frontier Engineering  Research. Bursars:  1913-1917 Kenneth Alexander Ashworth; 1917-1919 Duncan Stewart MacKenzie; 1919  Cecil Ethelbert Race (Acting); 1920-1947 Archibald West; 1948-1968 John MacLean Whidden.  Comptrollers:  1968-1980 Murray A. Rousell; 1980-1987 Albert S. "Bert" Knowler; 1988-  Louis  F. Jamernik.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-controller-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Controller fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/office-of-controller-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Office of the Controller fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1909-1991</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
