<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>University of Alberta. Student Services</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-6bfa07ab4f954898d6412be9cc68f45e">
        <p>Student Services was created to consolidate the duties of numerous and often overlapping offices and committees which over the University's history have concerned themselves with student affairs, whether academic, disciplinary, financial or personal.  Responsible to the Vice-President (Student and Academic Services), the Dean of Student Services acts as the office's senior administrator. Under the jurisdiction of the Office of Student Services are included the following agencies:  Career and Placement Services, Disabled Student Services, Effective Writing Resources, International Centre, Native Student Services, Student Counselling Services, Advisory Services Centre, and University Health Services.  The Dean of Student Services holds responsibilities similar to those of the former Provost, Dean of Men and Dean of Women, although, strictly speaking, not a direct successor to them.  As chief administrator and coordinator of the Office of Student Services, the Dean of Student Services (known as Dean of Students until 1985) supervises the major student services divisions and acts as a liaison with University government through membership on the General Faculties Council, Dean's Council, the Senate, the Council on Student Services, and other committees relevant to students' concerns.  The Dean is responsible to the Vice-President (Student and Academic Services). Records concerning students which are held by the Archives were produced by the following bodies and officers which had jurisdiction over student affairs: Advisor to Women Students, 1911-1951; Senate Committee on Student Affairs, 1912-1976; Students' Union Discipline Committee, 1912-[1976]; Residence House Committees, 1912-[1976]; Provost, 1914-1977; Advisor to Women Students and Warden of Pembina Hall, 1938-1945; Professor of Men in Residence, 1938-1946/47; Wardens of Pembina, Athabasca and Assiniboia Halls, [1945]-1966; Advisor to Student Veterans, 1950-[195-]; Dean of Women, 1951-[1976]; Administrator of Student Awards, 1959- ; Advisor to Men Students and Advisor to Foreign Students, 1960-1964; Dean of Men and Foreign Student Advisor, 1964-1975; General Faculties Council, 1966- ; Assistant Dean of Women (residences), 1964-1966; Assistant Dean of Men, 1966-[197-]; Assistant Deans in Residence, 1966-1977; University Ombudsman, 1971-1975; Foreign Student Advisor, 1975- ; Dean of Students, [1976]-1985; Council on Student Services, 1976- ; Advisor on Native Affairs, 1977- ; Vice-President (Student and Academic Services), 1990- . Deans:  [1977] Ruth Groberman (Acting); 1977-1981 Burton M. Smith; 1981-1983 Paul C. Sartoris; (Acting); 1983-  Peter J. Miller.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/student-services-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Student Services fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/student-services-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Student Services fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1913-1987</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
