<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>A Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial to Compare the Effect of Schroth Exercises to Standard Care on Curve Characteristics, Posture, and Quality Of Life in Adolescents With Idiopathic Scoliosis</titl>
               <altTitl>Multicenter Schroth Exercise Trial for Scoliosis (MultiSETS)</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>A Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial to Compare the Effect of Schroth Exercises to Standard Care on Curve Characteristics, Posture, and Quality Of Life in Adolescents With Idiopathic Scoliosis</titl>
               <altTitl>Multicenter Schroth Exercise Trial for Scoliosis (MultiSETS)</altTitl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT01610908</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Parent, Eric</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Schreiber, Sanja</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Hedden, Douglas</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Moreau, Marc</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Hill, Douglas</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Lou, Edmond</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Khodayari Moez, Elham</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Watkins, Elise</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Southon, Sarah</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Parent, Eric<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0003-3835-0607"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2011</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="SickKids Foundation CIHR Institute of Human Development, Child and Youth Health; Glenrose Rehabilitation Hospital Foundation; Scoliosis Research Society"/>
               <software>SAS</software>
               <software>Matlab</software>
               <software>REDCap</software>
               <software>ImageJ</software>
               <software>Konica Minolta Polygon Editing Tool</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="eparent@ualberta.ca">Parent, Eric</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>Author determines access on a case-by-case basis</restrctn>
               <restrctn>Data-sharing agreement, including undertaking of confidentiality</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access is permitted for external researchers, with limitations</conditions>
               <restrctn>Access only for REB-approved projects</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. A basic data sharing agreement form is required (ie. Agree to not attempt to re-identify the records so as to relate the information on the file to a particular person). The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>This multicentre study will be a two parallel arms assessor- and statistician-blinded randomized controlled trial comparing a six-months Schroth exercise intervention added to standard of care (experimental group) to standard of care alone (control group). Combined with standard care, the Schroth intervention group will receive five individual training sessions, followed by weekly group classes and daily home exercises for 6 months. After the first six months, the experimental group will be advised to continue the unsupervised home programme until the discharge from the scoliosis clinic, while the control group will be offered the Schroth treatment for six months. The primary aim is to compare the effect of a 6 month 'Schroth exercise program combined with standard-of-care' to 'standard-of-care alone' on scoliosis curve severity measured using the Cobb angle. Secondary aims include: 1. To determine the effect of Schroth exercises at 6 months on secondary outcomes including quality-of-life, spinal appearance, objective posture and spinal muscle endurance measurements. 2. To determine the efficacy of 6 months of Schroth therapy offered to control participants after completing 6 months in the standard-of care group (using subjects as  their own controls) and 3. To determine if the effects of the 6 months supervised Schroth exercise program can be maintained after supervised therapy is terminated. At Hopital Ste-Justine, the effect of Global Postural Re-education will also be examined because Global Postural Re-education exercises were offered routinely to patients at that institution prior to the trial.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">adolescent</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">posture</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">spinal curvatures</keyword>
               <keyword>physical therapy</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">quality of life</keyword>
               <keyword>muscle endurance</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">exercise</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">radiography</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">randomized controlled trial</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">scoliosis</keyword>
               <keyword>adolescent idiopathic scoliosis</keyword>
               <keyword>schroth exercises</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Calgary, Alberta Children's Hospital</geogCover>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, University of Alberta, Faculty of Rehabilitation Medicine</geogCover>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Quebec, Montreal, CHU Ste-Justine</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">4/1/2011</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">1/1/2017</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">4/1/2011</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">8/1/2016</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Females with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis.</universe>
               <dataKind>Biosamples</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Physical measurements</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Questionnaire data</dataKind>
               <datakind>Radiographic data</datakind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>The target number of study participants is 258. A sample of 129 subjects per group will be sufficient to detect a 0.31 effect size when comparing the change in outcomes between the exercise and control groups with 80% power using a unilateral test and an alpha of 0.05 (104 Schroth and 104 controls in this study + 25 Schroth and 25 controls in the pilot allows a total of 129 per group). We anticipate greater than 80% completion rate based on published data and because the pilot dropout rate was less than 10%.   A unilateral hypothesis is justified by positive published data and our pilot data. The pilot effect size for the Cobb angle was 0.32 and many secondary outcomes had effect sizes exceeding what we are powered to detect as significant. We believe that a 0.32 effect size is clinically important, feasible, and would justify implementing a Schroth program. The trial duration is relatively short which justifies aiming to detect a small effect size (0.2-0.5)132. It would be inadequate to power the trial to detect too small an effect size as patients and families will likely demand evidence of clinically important effects before committing efforts and time required of Schroth exercise programs.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Data is collected at baseline, and at 3 month, 6 month, 9 month and 12 month assessments. Curve severity (Cobb angle) and vertebral rotation will be assessed from radiographs at baseline, 6 and 12 months. Secondary clinical outcomes (back muscle endurance, surface topography measures of posture, and self-reported perceived spinal appearance and quality of life) will be assessed at baseline, and every 3 months until 1-year follow-up.  Information from clinical visits will be assessed at 12 months and at discharge from clinical care to determine if effects of exercises are maintained in the long term.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Face-to-face interview</collMode>
               <collMode>Computer assisted face-to-face interview</collMode>
               <collMode>Pen and paper face-to-face interview</collMode>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Paper</collMode>
               <collMode>Observation</collMode>
               <collMode>Physical measurements and tests</collMode>
               <collSitu>The primary outcome is the Cobb angle measurement at six months. Secondary outcomes will include: (1) Pain, function, self-image and total scores of the SRS-22r scoliosis quality-of-life questionnaire; (2) Spinal Appearance Questionnaire scores; (3) Surface topography parameters that objectively quantify external deformity (aesthetics); (4) Spinal extensors muscle endurance assessed by the Sorensen back endurance test, (5) a rating of global perceived change and (6) apical vertebral rotation measured on radiographs.</collSitu>
               <actMin>The research coordinator will call and email up to three times to remind participants and book evaluations.</actMin>
               <ConOps>Data validation rules were used in REDCap data collection forms. Paper forms were also inspected with the patient present.</ConOps>
               <cleanOps>Removing personal identifiers; Wildcode checking</cleanOps>
               <source>
                  <dataSrc>Sorensen back muscle endurance test; Scoliosis Research Society-22r questionnaire (SRS-22r); Spinal Appearance Questionnaire (SAQ)</dataSrc>
               </source>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <relPubl>Schreiber S, Parent EC, Moez EK, et al. The effect of Schroth exercises added to the standard of care on the quality of life and muscle endurance in adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis-an assessor and statistician blinded randomized controlled trial: 'SOSORT 2015 Award Winner.' Scoliosis. 2015;10:24.</relPubl>
            <relPubl>DOI</relPubl>
            <relPubl>doi:10.1186/s13013-015-0048-5</relPubl>
            <relPubl>https://scoliosisjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13013-015-0048-5</relPubl>
            <relPubl>Schreiber S, Parent EC, Hedden DM, Moreau M, Hill D, Lou, E. Effect of Schroth exercises on curve characteristics and clinical outcomes in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: protocol for a multicentre randomised controlled trial. Journal of Physiotherapy. 2014; 60:4, 234.</relPubl>
            <relPubl>DOI</relPubl>
            <relPubl>doi:10.1016/j.jphys.2014.08.005</relPubl>
            <relPubl>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25439713</relPubl>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
