<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>A Randomized Controlled Trial of Children Undergoing Intravenous Placement in the Pediatric Emergency Department: Distraction to Reduce Pain and Distress</titl>
               <altTitl>The iPad Study</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>A Randomized Controlled Trial of Children Undergoing Intravenous Placement in the Pediatric Emergency Department: Distraction to Reduce Pain and Distress</titl>
               <altTitl>The iPad Study</altTitl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT02326623</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Ali, Samina</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Hartling, Lisa</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Curtis, Sarah</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Scott, Shannon</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Beran, Tanya</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Dow, Nadia</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Rajagopal, Manasi</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Graham, Timothy</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Jou, Hsing</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Ali, Samina<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0002-0595-364X"/>
               </producer>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Hartling, Lisa<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0001-8341-3991"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2015</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Women and Children's Health Research Institute (WCHRI)"/>
               <software version="9">SAS</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="sali@ualberta.ca">Ali, Samina</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>Author determines access on a case-by-case basis</restrctn>
               <restrctn>No direct access for researchers external to the research team</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access is permitted for external researchers, with limitations</conditions>
               <restrctn>Access only for REB-approved projects</restrctn>
               <restrctn>Video recording equipment will capture the patient's facial expressions and body movements, in order to apply an observational distress tool (OSBD), so as to measure the distress experienced by the child. No video recordings will be used in the creation of written, published materials, and only the Research Assistants, the research coordinator and the PI responsible for coding the videos using the OSBD tool will watch the videos. They will not be shared with anyone else, including the rest of the research team.</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
            <setAvail>
               <accsPlac>Data will be kept in a secure office for a minimum of 5 years following completion of the research project. Electronic data will be collected through WCHRI-hosted REDCap, a secure online data platform that is password-protected.</accsPlac>
               <avlStatus>Not yet available: Data may be unavailable because it is still being collected,
            because it is embargoed for a period of time, because it has been superseded,
            etc.</avlStatus>
            </setAvail>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>This study will test if iPads are useful to help lower pain and distress for children who are visiting an emergency department and need an intravenous line put in. The results from this study could be important for many children receiving medical care, as distraction is safe and the use of iPads is enjoyable for many children.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword>distress</keyword>
               <keyword>ipad</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pain</keyword>
               <keyword>healthcare interventions</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pediatrics</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">randomized controlled trial</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pain management</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">emergency departments</keyword>
               <keyword>distraction</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, Stollery Children's Hospital</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">10/1/2015</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">12/1/2016</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">10/1/2015</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">10/1/2016</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Patients between 6 and 11 years old who require IV placement at a pediatric emergency department.</universe>
               <dataKind>Audiovisual data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Clinical data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Observational data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Questionnaire data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>Sample size calculations were conducted using a two-tailed, two-sample Mann-Whitney test for the primary outcome of child-reported pain based on data from our previous trial of music as a distractor for young children undergoing IV insertions. To detect a difference of 2 points on the FPS-R (which is considered clinically important) given a Type I error of 0.05 and 80% power, 40 patients per group is required. We also performed sample size calculations using a two-tailed, two sample t-test, for our other primary outcome of observed behavioural distress using data from our previous trial (i.e., SD=2.77). To detect a large effect size of 0.6 (which we observed in the previous trial) given a Type I error of 0.05 and 80% power, 35 patients per group is required. Recruiting 80 patients overall allows sufficient power to find a difference in both primary outcomes if a difference truly exists.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>All data is collected just before IV placement, at the time of IV placement, and immediately after IV placement.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Face-to-face interview</collMode>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Paper</collMode>
               <collMode>Observation</collMode>
               <collMode>Recording</collMode>
               <collMode>Psychological measurements and tests</collMode>
               <collSitu>Half of the participating children will be given a iPad to use during intravenous placement in addition to standard of care. Children and parents will be able to select their choice of distraction from a selection of games and videos, and they can change their selection as desired during the course of the procedure. The control group will receive standard care, which generally includes the use of topical anesthetic cream. Extra pain score measurements from the child and their caregiver, immediately before and after the intravenous placement, will be collected. The procedure and the child will also be video-taped in order to code the behavioural distress scores afterwards. In addition, parents and health care professionals will also be asked about their satisfaction.</collSitu>
               <ConOps>Paper copies will be in a locked filing cabinet in the research assistants' office located within the ED until the end of the study. Once the data is clean, then the raw data without the identity of the participants will be shared with the statistician and the  team.</ConOps>
               <cleanOps>All of the  data is rechecked by the study coordinator.</cleanOps>
               <source>
                  <dataSrc>Observed Scale of Behavioral Distress-Revised (OSBD-R);  Faces Pain Scale-Revised (FPS-R); The State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI)</dataSrc>
               </source>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <othRefs>Beran, T. N., Ramirez-Serrano, A., Kuzyk, R., Fior, M., &amp; Nugent, S. (2011). Understanding how children understand robots: Animism in the 21st century. International Journal of Human-Computer Studies, 69, 539-550; Beran, T. N., Ramirez-Serrano, A., Kuzyk, R., Nugent, S., &amp; Fior, M. (2011). Would children help a robot in need? International Journal of Social Robotics, 3(1), 83-92; Beran, T. N., Ramirez-Serrano, A., Vanderkooi, O., &amp; Kuhn, S. (2013). Reducing children's distress towards flu vaccinations: A novel and effective use of humanoid robotics. Vaccine, 31(25): 2772-7; Curtis SJ, Jou H, Ali S, Klassen TP.  (2007). A Randomized Controlled Trial of Sucrose and / or Pacifier as Analgesia for Infants Receiving Venipuncture in a Pediatric Emergency Department. BMC Pediatrics, 7: 27; Hartling L, Newton AS, Liang Y, Jou H, Hewson K, Klassen TP, Curtis S. (2013) Music to reduce pain and distress in the pediatric emergency department: a randomized controlled trial of children 3-11 years undergoing intravenous placement. Pediatrics, 167(9): 826-35.</othRefs>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
