<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Alberta Pregnancy Outcome and Nutrition</titl>
               <altTitl>APrON</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Alberta Pregnancy Outcome and Nutrition</titl>
               <altTitl>APrON</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Letourneau, Nicole</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Kaplan, Bonnie</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Field, Catherine</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Bell, Rhonda</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Dewey, Deborah</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Giesbrecht, Gerald</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Lethbridge">Leung, Brenda</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Bernier, Francois</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Gagnon, Lisa</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Tufts University">Eliasziw, Michael</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Farmer, Anna</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Manca, Donna</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">McCargar, Linda</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of British Columbia">Casey, Linda</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">O'Bierne, Maeve</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Singhal, Nalini</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Martin, Jonathan</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Calgary">Alberta Pregnancy Outcomes and Nutrition Team<ExtLink URI="http://www.apronstudy.ca/"/>
               </producer>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="PolicyWise for Children &amp; Families"
                     email="data@policywise.com">Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence</contact>
               <distrbtr abbr="SAGE" affiliation="PolicyWise for Children &amp; Families">Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence<ExtLink URI="https://policywise.com/initiatives/sage/"/>
               </distrbtr>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>APrON data is accessed via SAGE Analytic Environment only. All outputs are vetted prior to release.</restrctn>
               <conditions>Secondary users must consult with APrON team about proposed secondary use and, where requested, collaborate with relevant APrON data guardians before approval for access is given.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
            <setAvail>
               <accsPlac>Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence</accsPlac>
               <avlStatus>Restricted: Data may be available but requires the user to request permission before
            access can be granted.</avlStatus>
            </setAvail>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>Numerous studies have found that nutrient levels in our bodies relate to our physical and mental health. Scientists know much less, however, about the relationship between prenatal nutrition and health (for the mother and child). The Alberta Pregnancy Outcomes and Nutrition (APrON) study is a longitudinal, prospective cohort in Calgary and Edmonton, Alberta, Canada designed to investigate the relationship between maternal nutrient intake/status before, during and after gestation and a) maternal mood, b) birth and obstetric outcomes, and c) infant neurodevelopment. The data for approximately 5000 participants (2200 pregnant women, their offspring and many of their partners) includes information about maternal nutrition, anthropometric, biological, and mental health data at multiple points in pregnancy and the postpartum period, as well as obstetric, birth, health and neurodevelopment outcomes of these pregnancies and infants. Data from the APrON cohort can be used to answer questions related to prenatal nutrition, health and well-being and how they can impact neurodevelopmental and behavioural outcomes from infancy to childhood. Anchor participants were women over 16 years who can understand and answer questions in English, are pregnant for less than 27 weeks and are living in or near Calgary or Edmonton were eligible for recruitment into this study. Associated participants are the biological fathers and offspring resulting from study pregnancies. At this date this deposit of APrON data includes only the anthropometric measurements and questionnaires of survey mothers at the time of pregnancy and immediately post-partum.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
               <keyword>Prenatal Influences</keyword>
               <keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
               <keyword>Mental health</keyword>
               <keyword>Physical Activity</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Calgary, Child Development Centre</geogCover>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, Li Ka Shing Centre</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">2009</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">2013</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">2009</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">2013</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Maternal/infant child dyad</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Pregnant women over 16 years who can understand and answer questions in English and are living in or near Calgary or Edmonton.</universe>
               <dataKind>Anthropometric data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Questionnaire data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Paper</collMode>
               <collMode>Physical measurements and tests</collMode>
               <cleanOps>-Removal of duplicate participant data; -Blank cells coded with appropriate values; -Values checked for consistency; -Illogical values were checked with original hard copies of questionnaires.</cleanOps>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat/>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
