<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Efficacy of Combination Therapy with Intravenous Ketorolac and Metoclopramide for Pediatric Migraine Therapy in the Emergency Department</titl>
               <altTitl>Intravenous Ketorolac and Metoclopramide for Pediatric Migraine in the Emergency Department</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Efficacy of Combination Therapy with Intravenous Ketorolac and Metoclopramide for Pediatric Migraine Therapy in the Emergency Department</titl>
               <altTitl>Intravenous Ketorolac and Metoclopramide for Pediatric Migraine in the Emergency Department</altTitl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT01596166</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Richer, Lawrence</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Richer, Lawrence<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0002-6897-8668"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2012</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR)"/>
               <software>R</software>
               <software>REDCap</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="lricher@ualberta.ca">Richer, Lawrence</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data.The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate whether the combination of ketorolac (an anti-inflammatory pain medication) and metoclopramide (an anti-nauseant that may also relieve migraine headaches) is better than metoclopramide by itself when treating children in the Emergency Department.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">emergency departments</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pediatrics</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">metoclopramide</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">ketorolac</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">intravenous injections</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">emergencies</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">randomized controlled trial</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">migraine disorders</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">headache disorders</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Calgary, Alberta Children's Hospital</geogCover>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, Stollery Children's Hospital</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">2/1/2012</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">4/1/2014</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">2/1/2012</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">4/1/2014</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Emergency Department patients between 6 and 17 years of age presenting with a migraine.</universe>
               <dataKind>Clinical data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Interview data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>This is a randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled, parallel group clinical trial. The treating physician informed patients of the trial at the time a clinical decision was made to treat migraine with an intravenous medication. Patients and parents who gave verbal consent were informed and screened by the research coordinator. Those patients who met inclusion/exclusion criteria, who assented to the study, and whose parents signed consent, were enrolled and randomized to one of two groups: (1) Intravenous metoclopramide with intravenous placebo (0.9% sodium chloride) and (2) Intravenous metoclopramide with intravenous ketorolac. Patient randomization was supported by a web-based randomization system. Patients were allocated using permuted block randomization with variable block sizes at each site. The target number of study participants was 50; the actual number of study participants was 56.    Sample size calculations were based on the primary outcome and a two-sided, two-sample t-test for the comparison of group means using PASS analysis software. A sample size of 25 per group achieves 90% power to detect a difference between group means of about 2 cm (1.96 cm), assuming the standard deviation (SD) is 2.1 cm in each group and a two-sided Type I Error of 0.05.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Outcome assessments were performed every 30 minutes for a total of 2 hours during the active treatment phase from the initiation of the intravenous infusion. A 24-hour telephone follow-up assessed for headache recurrence.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Pen and paper face-to-face interview</collMode>
               <collMode>Telephone interview</collMode>
               <collSitu>The emergency research coordinator (RC) at each site was responsible for administering the headache severity measurement tools and other study data collection forms. A short-form standardized score was used to assess for akathisia at the 2 hour time points. The RC recorded the use of rescue medication following the 1-hour assessment while the patient remained in the Emergency Department. A telephone follow-up at 24 hours by a research staff member assessed each patient's headache status and secondary outcome measures.</collSitu>
               <ConOps>To conform to CONSORT reporting requirements, a Refused, Missed and Other exclusions (RMO) database was developed. Minimal data was obtained such as time of day, sex, age and Canadian Triage and Acuity Scale (CTAS) level in order to compare the enrolled and non-enrolled patients for clear biases. Paper data collection forms (DCF) are the primary instruments.  The research coordinator at the Emergency Department and at the 24-hour follow-up will complete the DCFs and these will be stored in a locked cabinet and office. Data, linked only by study id, will be collected and managed using REDCap electronic data capture (EDC) tools hosted by the Women and Children's Health Research Institute, Clinical Research Informatics Core. A random 10% sample of DCFs will be verified for accuracy of data entry. Identifying information about study subjects will be kept confidential and separate from the electronic database. All persons with access to the data will have training in health information privacy and have signed privacy agreements.</ConOps>
               <source>
                  <dataSrc>Visual Analogue Scale (VAS); Faces Pain Scale - Revised (FPS-R)</dataSrc>
               </source>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat/>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
