<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Evaluating an Internet-based Program for Anxious Youth: a Pilot RCT</titl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Evaluating an Internet-based Program for Anxious Youth: a Pilot RCT</titl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT02059226</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Newton, Amanda (Mandi)</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="IWK Health Centre">McGrath, Patrick</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Curtis, Sarah</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="IWK Health Centre">Fitzpatrick, Eleanor</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="IWK Health Centre">Bagnell, Alexa</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Ottawa">Jabbour, Mona</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Johnson, David</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Rosychuk, Rhonda</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="IWK Health Centre">Young, Michael</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Ohinmaa, Arto</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Joyce, Anthony</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="IWK Health Centre">Wozney, Lori</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Newton, Amanda (Mandi)<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0003-3020-674X"/>
               </producer>
               <producer affiliation="IWK Health Centre">McGrath, Patrick<ExtLink URI="http://www.researchgate.net/profile/Patrick_McGrath"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2014</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Canada</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR); Royal Bank of Canada (RBC) Foundation"/>
               <software>IRIS (http://irisplatform.com/index.php/about-us/)</software>
               <software>SAS</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="mandi.newton@ualberta.ca">Newton, Amanda (Mandi)</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <conditions>Access is limited to selected members of the research team</conditions>
               <conditions>Access is limited to collaborators at local sites of a multi-site study</conditions>
               <restrctn>No direct access for researchers external to the research team</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access to the data is limited to selected members of the research team and to collaborators at local sites of the multi-site study.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>This pilot trial aims to collect the necessary data to inform the planning of a full-scale randomized controlled trial (RCT) to test the effectiveness of the Internet-based CBT program Breathe (Being Real, Easing Anxiety: Tools Helping Electronically). Adolescents will be randomly assigned to either 8 weeks of Internet-based cognitive behaviour therapy (CBT) with telephone and e-mail support (the Breathe program), or a control (minimal intervention) group with 8 weeks of access to a static webpage with general anxiety resources and information. The pilot RCT will (1) define a minimal clinically important difference, as defined by adolescents, for the primary outcome measure, (2) determine a sample size for a full-scale RCT, (3) estimate recruitment and retention rates to determine the number of study sites needed, (4) measure intervention acceptability to inform critical intervention changes, (5) determine the use of co-interventions, and (6) conduct a cost-consequence analysis to inform a cost-effectiveness analysis for a full-scale RCT.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">cognitive behavior therapy</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">adolescent</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">mental health</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">internet</keyword>
               <keyword>intervention</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">randomized controlled trial</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">ehealth</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">anxiety</keyword>
               <keyword>etherapy</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <timePrd event="start">4/1/2014</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">9/1/2016</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">4/1/2014</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">8/1/2016</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Adolescents ages 13 to 17 years old with social anxiety, generalized anxiety, anxiety not otherwise specified, or adjustment disorder as the primary clinical problem</universe>
               <dataKind>Questionnaire data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Usage tracking data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>A total of 160 adolescents were invited to participate with the expectation that 80 adolescents would be enrolled. The final number of study participants  was 92.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Multidimensional Anxiety Scale for Children' questionnaire data are collected at baseline, treatment completion, and at a 3-month follow-up. Minimal Clinically Important Difference (MCID) will be measured at 8 weeks (i.e., post-intervention). Recruitment rate will be measured at 27 months. Retention rate will be measured at 30 months. Intervention acceptability, co-intervention use, resource use/costs, and intervention adherence will be measured at 8 weeks or following module 8 completion (i.e., post-intervention).</frequenc>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Web-based</collMode>
               <collSitu>All secondary outcome data are collected via self-report using the Internet-based platform IRIS.</collSitu>
               <actMin>Adolescents who do not log in to Breathe for one week receive an e-mail encouraging them to log in to complete their weekly module. During the program, adolescents also have access to an Ask the Expert feature where they can e-mail a trained research team member with questions regarding the program and/or treatment.</actMin>
               <source>
                  <dataSrc>Multidimensional Anxiety Scale for Children</dataSrc>
               </source>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <relPubl>Newton, A. S., Wozney, L., Bagnell, A., Fitzpatrick, E., Curtis, S., Jabbour, M., Johnson D, Rosychuk RJ, Young M, Ohinmaa A, Joyce A, McGrath, P. (2016). Increasing Access to Mental Health Care With Breathe, an Internet-Based Program for Anxious Adolescents: Study Protocol for a Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial. JMIR Research Protocols, 5(1), e18.</relPubl>
            <relPubl>DOI</relPubl>
            <relPubl>http://doi.org/10.2196/resprot.4428</relPubl>
            <relPubl>http://doi.org/10.2196/resprot.4428</relPubl>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
