<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Immunological Profiling</titl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Immunological Profiling</titl>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Huang, Vivian</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Elahi, Shokrollah</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Madsen, Karen</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Fedorak, Richard</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Dieleman, Levinus</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Wine, Eytan</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Dunsmore, Garett</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Preconception and Pregnancy in Inflammatory Bowel Disease Clinical Research Program<ExtLink URI="http://pregnancy.ibdclinic.ca/"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2015</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac>
               <software>Microsoft Excel</software>
               <software version="23">SPSS</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="pregibd@ualberta.ca">Huang, Vivian</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>Author determines access on a case-by-case basis</restrctn>
               <restrctn>Data-sharing agreement, including undertaking of confidentiality</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access is permitted for external researchers, with limitations</conditions>
               <restrctn>Access only for REB-approved projects</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. A basic data sharing agreement form is required (ie. Agree to not attempt to re-identify the records so as to relate the information on the file to a particular person). The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>This study aims to answer the question: why do some women flare during pregnancy, while others go into remission?  It looks at changes in cytokines and the immune profile during pregnancy in women with IBD, comparing longitudinal changes by IBD disease types and disease activity, and comparing this to healthy volunteers. As well, outcomes, like preterm delivery, are tracked.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">Crohn's disease</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pregnancy</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">ulcerative colitis</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">cohort studies</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">infant</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">biomarkers</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">cytokines</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">inflammatory bowel diseases</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">immunology</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, Preconception and Pregnancy in Inflammatory Bowel Disease Clinic</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">2015</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">2017</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">2015</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">2017</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Adult women with IBD enrolled in the Preconception and Pregnancy in IBD clinic and healthy volunteers.</universe>
               <dataKind>Biosamples</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Clinical data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>30 study participants were chosen as the sample size so as to have 10 women with Crone's disease, 10 with ulcerative colitis, and 10 healthy controls.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Blood samples were collected at preconception, in each trimester of pregnancy, and cord blood will be collected at birth. Blood samples are also collected if enrolled patients visit the clinic at any point due to flaring or other related issues.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Paper</collMode>
               <collMode>Physical measurements and tests</collMode>
               <cleanOps>Data verification built into protocols.</cleanOps>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <relStdy>Effects of Maternal IBD and IBD Breast Milk on Neonatal Gut Microbiome and Intestinal Inflammation; Elevated Fecal Calprotectin in the Second or Third Trimester of Pregnancy Predicts Preterm Delivery in Women with IBD</relStdy>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
