<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Improving Knowledge Regarding Pregnancy and Inflammatory Bowel Disease</titl>
               <altTitl>Improving Knowledge Regarding Pregnancy and IBD</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Improving Knowledge Regarding Pregnancy and Inflammatory Bowel Disease</titl>
               <altTitl>Improving Knowledge Regarding Pregnancy and IBD</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Huang, Vivian</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Fedorak, Richard</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Wierstra, Kelsey</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="">Bal, Jasmine</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="">Smith, Kayla-Marie</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="">Shipka, Morgan</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="">Sutton, Reed</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="">Manocha, Alisha</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Preconception and Pregnancy in Inflammatory Bowel Disease Clinical Research Program<ExtLink URI="http://pregnancy.ibdclinic.ca/"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2014</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Alberta Innovates - Health Solutions (AIHS)"/>
               <software>Microsoft Excel</software>
               <software version="23">SPSS</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="pregibd@ualberta.ca">Huang, Vivian</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>No restrictions on use</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access is permitted to the general public, without limitations</conditions>
               <conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted to the general public. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access. A basic data sharing agreement form is required (ie. Agree to not attempt to re-identify the records so as to relate the information on the file to a particular person).</conditions>
            </useStmt>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>The study objective is to assess the effectiveness of a  web-based information portal to improve the knowledge and attitudes of patients with IBD with respect to maternal health and chronic disease. This study will help to develop educational tools for improving knowledge regarding pregnancy and IBD. Pre- and post- intervention reproductive knowledge was compared using the CCPKnow (Crohn's and Colitis Pregnancy Knowledge) survey. Patient factors (age, reproductive history, IBD history, medications, education, marital status, clinic/specialist access) and preferences for knowledge translation method were measured and assessed. If a patient was randomized to the interactive group, the effectiveness of videos, slides, sets, PDFs, and mini quizzes were compared. Usage was also tracked, including time spent on modules and components of modules,  number of times accessed.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">Crohn's disease</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pregnancy</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">ulcerative colitis</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">knowledge translation</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">infant</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">maternal health</keyword>
               <keyword>patient education</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">inflammatory bowel diseases</keyword>
               <keyword>patient knowledge</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, Preconception and Pregnancy in Inflammatory Bowel Disease Clinic</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">2014</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">2016</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">6/1/2015</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">12/1/2016</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Adults (both females and males) who have IBD and their partners.</universe>
               <dataKind>Questionnaire data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>The target sample size was 100 study participants; the actual sample size was 80 study participants.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Data collected at baseline, 2 months, and 8 months.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Web-based</collMode>
               <collSitu>Approximately 20 people of the 100 who registered did the baseline survey but did not do the second survey after 2 months.</collSitu>
               <actMin>Reminder emails about the second survey (2 month) were sent out.</actMin>
               <cleanOps>Identifying variables were removed.</cleanOps>
               <source>
                  <dataSrc>CCPKnow (Crohn's and Colitis Pregnancy Knowledge) survey</dataSrc>
               </source>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <othRefs>For more see study website: http://pregnancy.ibdclinic.ca/knowledge-translation-study/    Huang VW, Chang H-J, Kroeker KI, et al. Does the level of reproductive knowledge specific to inflammatory bowel disease predict childlessness among women with inflammatory bowel disease? Canadian Journal of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology. 2015;29(2):95-103.</othRefs>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
