<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Nasal Nitric Oxide Levels in Infants With and Without Congenital Heart Disease</titl>
               <altTitl>Infant Nasal Nitric Oxide Levels in Congenital Heart Disease</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Nasal Nitric Oxide Levels in Infants With and Without Congenital Heart Disease</titl>
               <altTitl>Infant Nasal Nitric Oxide Levels in Congenital Heart Disease</altTitl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT02551107</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Ryerson, Lindsay</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Amirav, Israel</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="">Bates, Angela</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Mackie, Andrew</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Leonard, Heather</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Ryerson, Lindsay<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0002-4919-1309"/>
               </producer>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Amirav, Israel<ExtLink URI="http://www.researchgate.net/profile/Israel_Amirav"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2015</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Women and Children's Health Research Institute (WCHRI)"/>
               <software version="19">PASW Statistics</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="ryerson@ualberta.ca">Ryerson, Lindsay</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <conditions>Access is limited to the research team</conditions>
               <restrctn>No direct access for researchers external to the research team</restrctn>
               <restrctn>Given the small population size and risk of reidentification, no direct access will be provided to the data.</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access to the data is limited to selected members of the research team.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
            <setAvail>
               <accsPlac>Paper case report forms are currently in a locked file cabinet in a locked office.</accsPlac>
               <avlStatus>Not yet available: Data may be unavailable because it is still being collected,
            because it is embargoed for a period of time, because it has been superseded,
            etc.</avlStatus>
            </setAvail>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>This pilot study aims to measure nasal nitric oxide (nNO) in a group of neonates and infants (less than 12 months) with congenital heart disease (CHD) and compare their nNO levels to age matched controls without CHD. CHD patients will be divided into subgroups, based on their cardiac anatomy, to try and identify a level of risk of ciliary dyskinesia within the subgroup of CHD. Each of these sub groups' nNO levels will be compared between groups and against age matched control infants without CHD.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">congenital heart defects</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">heart diseases</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">cardiovascular abnormalities</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">cardiovascular diseases</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">congenital abnormalities</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">nitric oxide</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">infants</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pediatrics</keyword>
               <keyword>congenital heart diseases</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">primary ciliary dyskinesia</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, Stollery Children's Hospital</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">9/1/2015</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">10/1/2016</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">12/1/2015</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">10/1/2016</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Infants less than 1 year old with and without congenital heart disease (CHD).</universe>
               <dataKind>Clinical data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>The target total number of study participants is 120. 60 infants with congenital heart disease and 60 controls. 60 subjects with congenital heart disease will allow for at least three sub groups of cardiac anomalies with 20 subjects per group.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Two samples will be taken five minutes apart.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Physical measurements and tests</collMode>
               <collSitu>A member of the research team will ask the parent to measure the child's nasal NO level. The child's hospital number and age will be collected. For nNO assessment, an inert NO sampling line with a disposable foam olive will be placed into one of the subject's nostrils while the contralateral nostril is left open. Air will be sampled at a constant rate of 0.3 Liters/min from the nose by a chemiluminescent analyzer which provides measurement of the nNO level in parts per billion (ppb).  All nNO measurements will be performed with the subjects supine. Measurements will be obtained using a nasal nitric oxide analyzer (CLD 88 sp).</collSitu>
               <actMin>Two samples will be taken five minutes apart, to assess for test-retest reproducibility, with results for each patient being averaged over the two samples.</actMin>
               <cleanOps>Data was reviewed by principal investigators for completeness and accuracy.</cleanOps>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat/>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
