<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Reduction of Radial Head Subluxation in Children Via a Nurse Initiated Pathway: A Clustered Randomized Control Trial</titl>
               <altTitl>Nurse Reduction of Pulled Elbow</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Reduction of Radial Head Subluxation in Children Via a Nurse Initiated Pathway: A Clustered Randomized Control Trial</titl>
               <altTitl>Nurse Reduction of Pulled Elbow</altTitl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT00993954</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Dixon, Andrew</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Ottawa">Plint, Amy</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Ottawa">Osmond, Martin</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute); Correll, Rhonda (Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute); Clarkin, Chantalle (Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute)">Barrowman, Nick</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute">Correll, Rhonda</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute">Clarkin, Chantalle</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Dixon, Andrew</producer>
               <producer affiliation="University of Ottawa">Plint, Amy<ExtLink URI="http://www.researchgate.net/researcher/13910924_Amy_C_Plint"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2007</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Ottawa, Ontario</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Ontario Ministry of Health and Long Term Care"/>
               <software>SPSS</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="dixon2@ualberta.ca">Dixon, Andrew</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>Author determines access on a case-by-case basis</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access is permitted for external researchers, with limitations</conditions>
               <restrctn>Access only for REB-approved projects</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
            <setAvail>
               <accsPlac>Data is located at the CHEO Research Institute and on Dr. Dixon's hard drive.</accsPlac>
            </setAvail>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>The study's objective was to examine whether triage nurses, trained in the use of a medical directive that taught recognition and treatment of radial head subluxation, could successfully reduce radial head subluxation at a rate similar to physicians. Given the practical constraints at  the time of emergency department triage, this study was designed as a cluster randomized trial where the unit of randomization was a day and the patients on any given day were assigned to the nurse or physician arm for the entire day.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword>nurse treatment</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">emergency departments</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">dislocations</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">wounds and injuries</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pediatrics</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">randomized controlled trial</keyword>
               <keyword>radial head subluxation</keyword>
               <keyword>pulled elbow</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Ontario, Ottawa, Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">9/1/2007</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">12/1/2010</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">10/1/2009</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">12/1/2010</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Children up to 6 years old with a physical exam consistent with radial head subluxation (RHS) which includes not using the affected limb, holding the elbow in extension or slight flexion, forearm in pronation, and patient is distressed only on elbow movement. Injury must have happened within the preceding 12 hours.</universe>
               <dataKind>Clinical data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>Studies have shown that RHS spontaneously reduces in 8% to 16% of cases, that success rates at first reduction attempts are 74%-90%, and that at discharge, 99% have been reduced. We have conservatively estimated a physician success at reduction of 90%. Using a 90% success rate, a 10 %, non-inferiority margin, a type I error=0.05, and power of 80%, 112 patients are needed in each study arm, with a total target of 224 study participants. The actual number of study participants was 245.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Data was collected daily, and charts were reviewed the next day.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Observation</collMode>
               <collSitu>Baseline Assessment: Once a patient was identified by the triage nurse as a possible RHS elbow a 'pulled elbow study form' was attached to the patient's ED chart. Patient age, sex, arm injured, time and mechanism of injury were prospectively collected on all patients. Nurse initiated treatment: The triage nurse recorded the time of the attempt, outcome (success/failure) of reduction attempt, and if relevant, time of normal arm usage, for each reduction attempt. If the patient used the arm normally the physician recorded their discharge assessment. If the patient did not use their arm normally, the physician recorded their training level, time, method, and outcome (success/failure) of each reduction attempt as well as time of normal arm usage. Physician initiated treatment: The physician recorded their level of training, time, method and outcome of each reduction attempt, as well as time of normal arm usage. Other measures: Final diagnosis, discharge time, follow-up recommended, investigations ordered and their results (such as x-rays) were abstracted from the ED chart by the study coordinator. As well a copy of every patient's ED chart was kept in the ED for 4 days after a child's discharge and the study coordinator reviewed these to determine how many patients had a final diagnosis of pulled elbow and were enrolled in the study and how many were missed at triage.</collSitu>
               <actMin>Daily chart reviews ensured that all relevant patients were captured.</actMin>
               <ConOps>Data collection sheets were compared to charts daily to ensure accuracy and consistency.</ConOps>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <relPubl>Dixon A, Clarkin C, Barrowman N, Correll R, Osmond MH, Plint AC. Reduction of radial-head subluxation in children by triage nurses in the emergency department: a cluster-randomized controlled trial. CMAJ: Canadian Medical Association Journal. 2014;186(9): E317-E323.</relPubl>
            <relPubl>DOI</relPubl>
            <relPubl>doi:10.1503/cmaj.131101</relPubl>
            <relPubl>http://www.cmaj.ca/content/186/9/E317</relPubl>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
