<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Single Incision Device (TVT Secur) Versus Retropubic Tension-free Vaginal Tape Device (TVT) for the Management of Stress Urinary Incontinence in  Women: A Randomized Clinical Trial</titl>
               <altTitl>Tension-free Vaginal Tape Management of Stress Incontinence in Women: Randomized Trial of TVT Secur Versus TVT</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>Single Incision Device (TVT Secur) Versus Retropubic Tension-free Vaginal Tape Device (TVT) for the Management of Stress Urinary Incontinence in  Women: A Randomized Clinical Trial</titl>
               <altTitl>Tension-free Vaginal Tape Management of Stress Incontinence in Women: Randomized Trial of TVT Secur Versus TVT</altTitl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT00685217</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Ross, Sue</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Tang, Selphee</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Schulz, Jane</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Murphy, Magnus</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Penticton Regional Hospital">Goncalves, Jose</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Lions Gate Hospital">Kaye, Stephen</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Dederer, Lorel</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Robert, Magali</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Ross, Sue<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0002-0600-4833"/>
               </producer>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Schulz, Jane<ExtLink URI="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Jane_Schulz"/>
               </producer>
               <producer affiliation="University of Calgary">Robert, Magali<ExtLink URI="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Magali_Robert"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2008</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Calgary, Alberta; Edmonton, Alberta; Penticton, British Columbia; Vancouver, British Columbia</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Women's and Children's Health Research Institute (WCHRI); Johnson &amp; Johnson Medical Companies; Alberta Health Services"/>
               <software>Microsoft Access</software>
               <software version="9.3">SAS</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta"
                     email="Sue.Ross@albertahealthservices.ca">Ross, Sue</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>Author determines access on a case-by-case basis</restrctn>
               <restrctn>Data-sharing agreement, including undertaking of confidentiality</restrctn>
               <restrctn>Disclosure of enough data to answer the intended research question</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access is permitted for external researchers, without limitations</conditions>
               <restrctn>Access only for REB-approved projects</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
            <setAvail>
               <accsPlac>Paper copies are archived at Iron Mountain. Electronic database is hosted on a server at the University of Calgary.</accsPlac>
               <avlStatus>Restricted: Data may be available but requires the user to request permission before
            access can be granted.</avlStatus>
            </setAvail>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>The objective of this Canadian multi-centre pragmatic randomized controlled trial was to compare the effectiveness of the new single-incision device, Gynecare TVT Secur, to the established predecate retropubic TVT device, in terms of objective cure of stress urinary incontinence (SUI) at 12 months postoperatively. Other outcomes included: complications, symptoms, and incontinence-related quality of life.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword>single incision device</keyword>
               <keyword>stress urinary incontinence</keyword>
               <keyword>surgical treatment</keyword>
               <keyword>effectiveness</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">randomized controlled trial</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Calgary, Foothills Medical Centre</geogCover>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, Royal Alexandra Hospital</geogCover>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>British Columbia, Penticton, Penticton Regional Hospital</geogCover>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>British Columbia, Vancouver, Lions Gate Hospital</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">5/1/2008</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">4/1/2012</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">5/1/2008</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">3/1/2011</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Women with stress incontinence, defined as leaking with increased abdominal pressure.</universe>
               <dataKind>Clinical data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Questionnaire data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>The sample size estimate for our trial was 300, but the trial stopped early because of poor recruitment. 74 women participated (40 allocated to TVT Secur, 34 to TVT). Data was collected and analysed for 33/40 (83%) of the TVT Secur group and 28/34 (89%) of the TVT group.</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Data was collected at baseline and one year postoperative.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Paper</collMode>
               <collMode>Self-administered writings and/or diaries</collMode>
               <collMode>Experiment</collMode>
               <collMode>Physical measurements and tests</collMode>
               <collMode>Chart review</collMode>
               <collSitu>The trial ended early because of poor recruitment.</collSitu>
               <actMin>Emails were sent out two months before the year follow-up to schedule the appointment and reminders were sent one month before the appointment. If the participant was unable to come in person, questionnaires were sent by mail. Additional contacts were collected for study participants in the event that they were hard to reach or had moved.</actMin>
               <cleanOps>The data entry clerk entered data, and the statistician and data entry clerk checked over all data before analysis. Data was checked for outliers, and range and logic checks were performed. Paper forms were kept and were compared to electronic records in the event of missing or outlying data.</cleanOps>
               <source>
                  <dataSrc>Urogenital Distress Inventory (UDI-6); Incontinence Impact Questionnaire (IIQ-7); the Pelvic Organ Prolapse/Urinary Incontinence Sexual Questionnaire-12, (PISQ-12); the 15D Instrument of Health-related Quality of Life (15D) was included for the proposed economic evaluation which was never done.</dataSrc>
               </source>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <relPubl>Ross S, Tang S, Schulz J, et al. Single incision device (TVT Secur) versus retropubic tension-free vaginal tape device (TVT) for the management of stress urinary incontinence in women: a randomized clinical trial. BMC Research Notes. 2014;7:941.</relPubl>
            <relPubl>DOI</relPubl>
            <relPubl>doi:10.1186/1756-0500-7-941</relPubl>
            <relPubl>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25532604</relPubl>
            <othRefs>Ross S, Robert M, Ducey A.  The short life cycle of a surgical device - literature analysis using McKinlay's 7-stage model.  Health Policy Technol. 2015 Feb 23;4:168-188.</othRefs>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
