<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook>
      <docDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>The Resource Information Program for Parents on Lifestyle and Education (RIPPLE): A Parent-based eHealth Tool to Prevent Childhood Obesity</titl>
               <altTitl>A Brief eHealth Tools Delivered in Primary Care to Help Parents Prevent Childhood Obesity: A Randomized Controlled Trial</altTitl>
            </titlStmt>
         </citation>
      </docDscr>
      <stdyDscr>
         <citation>
            <titlStmt>
               <titl>The Resource Information Program for Parents on Lifestyle and Education (RIPPLE): A Parent-based eHealth Tool to Prevent Childhood Obesity</titl>
               <altTitl>A Brief eHealth Tools Delivered in Primary Care to Help Parents Prevent Childhood Obesity: A Randomized Controlled Trial</altTitl>
               <IDNo agency="ClinicalTrials.gov">NCT02330588</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Ball, Geoff</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Byrne, Jillian</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Cave, Andrew</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Alberta Health Services">Donaldson, Stephanie</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Alberta Health Services">Ellendt, Carol</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Holt, Nicholas</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Alberta Health Services">Jelinski, Susan</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="Ministry of Health, Government of Alberta">Martz, Patricia</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Maximova, Katrina</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Padwal, Raj</AuthEnty>
               <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Wild, T Cameron</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <prodStmt>
               <producer affiliation="University of Alberta">Ball, Geoff<ExtLink URI="http://orcid.org/0000-0002-9432-3120"/>
               </producer>
               <prodDate>2015</prodDate>
               <prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac>
               <grantNo agency="Alberta Innovates - Health Solutions (AIHS); Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR); Public Health Agency of Canada (PHAC)"/>
               <software version="22">SPSS</software>
               <software>Microsoft Excel</software>
            </prodStmt>
            <distStmt>
               <contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="gdball@ualberta.ca">Ball, Geoff</contact>
            </distStmt>
            <serStmt/>
         </citation>
         <dataAccs>
            <useStmt>
               <restrctn>Author determines access on a case-by-case basis</restrctn>
               <conditions>Access is permitted for external researchers, with limitations</conditions>
               <conditions>The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions>
            </useStmt>
            <setAvail>
               <accsPlac>Data captured by the RIPPLE program will be stored on a secure server maintained by Evolution Health Systems, Inc., which is  located in Ontario. Electronic data related to this study will be destroyed after five years and all hard copies will be shredded.</accsPlac>
               <avlStatus>Not yet available: Data may be unavailable because it is still being collected,
            because it is embargoed for a period of time, because it has been superseded,
            etc.</avlStatus>
            </setAvail>
         </dataAccs>
         <stdyInfo>
            <abstract>The objective of this study was to determine the feasibility and preliminary impact of an eHealth screening, brief intervention and referral to treatment (SBIRT) tool delivered in primary care to help parents prevent childhood obesity. The SBIRT was entitled RIPPLE - the Resource Information Program for Parents on Lifestyle and Education. Parents of children were recruited from a primary care clinic and invited to participate in the SBIRT on a study-designated tablet. The SBIRT was brief (~15 minutes) and parents completed it while they awaited their child's upcoming pediatrician appointment. The SBIRT (i) screened for children's weight status using children's measured height and weight, (ii) randomly assigned parents to one-of-four brief interventions (two on nutrition, two on physical activity) or an eHealth control group, and (iii) provided parents with a menu of resources (i.e., online handouts, information on community services) to help prevent obesity in children.</abstract>
            <subject>
               <keyword>obesity prevention</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pediatrics</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">parents</keyword>
               <keyword>ehealth</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">internet</keyword>
               <keyword>nutrition</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">exercise</keyword>
               <keyword>sedentary behavior</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">randomized controlled trial</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">pediatric obesity</keyword>
               <keyword vocab="MeSH">primary health care</keyword>
            </subject>
            <sumDscr>
               <nation>Canada</nation>
               <geogCover>Alberta, Edmonton, The Allin Clinic, Edmonton Oliver Primary Care Network</geogCover>
               <timePrd event="start">10/1/2014</timePrd>
               <timePrd event="end">12/1/2015</timePrd>
               <collDate event="start">7/1/2015</collDate>
               <collDate event="end">10/1/2015</collDate>
               <anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit>
               <universe>Parents and their 5 - 17 year old children receiving health care at the Allin Clinic (Edmonton Oliver Primary Care Network).</universe>
               <dataKind>Anthropometric data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Clinical data</dataKind>
               <dataKind>Questionnaire data</dataKind>
            </sumDscr>
         </stdyInfo>
         <method>
            <dataColl>
               <sampProc>The target number of study participants was 200; the actual number of study participants was 226. Participants were randomly assigned to one-of-four brief intervention arms (n=179) or the eHealth control group (n=47).</sampProc>
               <frequenc>Data was collected at baseline and at one month follow-up.</frequenc>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: E-mail</collMode>
               <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Web-based</collMode>
               <collMode>Physical measurements and tests</collMode>
               <collMode>Psychological measurements and tests</collMode>
               <collSitu>A brief, eight-item Likert scale questionnaire with established face validity was adopted from Campbell et al. (2011) and assessed parents' concern about their child's weight status and intention to change or improve their child's lifestyle behaviors. Specifically, parents assigned to the brief nutrition-based intervention received questions that queried concern about their child's weight and intention to change their child's dietary habits, and parents assigned to the brief physical activity-based intervention received questions that queried concern about their child's weight and intention to change their child's physical activity habits; parents assigned to the control group (Heads Up!) received both sets of questions. As a token of appreciation and to encourage parents to complete the 1-month follow-up measure, parents were given a Can $25 gift card to a local business (eg, grocery store).</collSitu>
               <actMin>Cards reminding parents about the follow-up visit were given out.</actMin>
               <cleanOps>Data contains personally identifying information (email address and date of birth).</cleanOps>
               <source>
                  <dataSrc>Modified version of survey based on the following study: Campbell M, Benton JM, Werk L. Parent Perceptions to Promote a Healthier Lifestyle for Their Obese Child. Social Work in Health Care. 2011; 50:10, 787-800.  doi:10.1080/00981389.2011.597316</dataSrc>
               </source>
            </dataColl>
         </method>
         <othrStdyMat>
            <relPubl>Avis JL, Cave AL, Donaldson S, Ellendt C, Holt NL, Jelinski S, Martz P, Maximova K, Padwal R, Wild TC, Ball GD. Working With Parents to Prevent Childhood Obesity: Protocol for a Primary Care-Based eHealth Study. JMIR Research Protocols 2015;4(1):e35.</relPubl>
            <relPubl>DOI</relPubl>
            <relPubl>doi:10.2196/resprot.4147</relPubl>
            <relPubl>http://www.researchprotocols.org/2015/1/e35/</relPubl>
            <relPubl>Avis JL, van Mierlo T, Fournier R, Ball GD. Lessons Learned From Using Focus Groups to Refine Digital Interventions. JMIR Research Protocols. 2015;4(3):e95.</relPubl>
            <relPubl>DOI</relPubl>
            <relPubl>doi:10.2196/resprot.4404</relPubl>
            <relPubl>http://www.researchprotocols.org/2015/3/e95/</relPubl>
            <relPubl>Byrne J, Wild T, Maximova K, Browne N, Holt N, Cave A, Martz P, Ellendt C, Ball G. A brief eHealth tool delivered in primary care to help parents prevent childhood obesity: a randomized controlled trial. Pediatr Obes; in press.</relPubl>
            <othRefs>Avis JLS, Holt NL, Maximova K, van Mierlo T, Fournier R, Padwal R, Cave AL, Martz P, Ball GDC. The Development and Refinement of an e-Health Screening, Brief Intervention, and Referral to Treatment for Parents to Prevent Childhood Obesity in Primary Care. Telemedicine and e-Health. April 2016, 22(5): 385-394. doi:10.1089/tmj.2015.0128.</othRefs>
         </othrStdyMat>
      </stdyDscr>
   </codeBook>
