<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo usage="primary">
    <title>Programa Nosotros. Message of Hope</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal" usage="primary">
    <namePart>Sergio Contreras</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">cre</roleTerm>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Lito Azocar</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">ctb</roleTerm>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Contributor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <genre>Variety</genre>
  <genre>Community</genre>
  <genre>Interview</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf">1991-11-03</dateCreated>
    <dateIssued encoding="edtf">1991-11-03</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code">spa</languageTerm>
    <languageTerm type="text">Spanish</languageTerm>
  </language>
  
  <physicalDescription>
    
  </physicalDescription>
  <abstract>The newscasters begin talking about Paraguay, talking about the population and then giving a summary of its political history. The country was under military government for many years and by the end of the 1980&#x2019;s they expelled a general and began having real elections with alternative choices (other parties). There were some interviews with the public about how they felt about the elections and interviewed different people on their opinion of new government. Interviewed a women&#x2019;s group and they want the discrimination of working women to stop. Police want respect and a dignified pay. Indigenous people want the government to pay more attention to them &amp; give them proper education. Second part they are interviewing two people in the station: Mario Acuna and Patricia del Rossi. They are representing the missing and the political prisoners from the pinochet regime who are still in prison. Patricia says that the situation for the political prisoners hasn&#x2019;t changed since the regime even though they were given promises, but there sentences haven&#x2019;t been reduced. Mario has visited the jails the political prisoners are in and says that it reminds him of the past and that the conditions in there is like going back into the regime. He goes on to express that he doesn&#x2019;t know why they are still in jail when they had done nothing wrong and that the torturers and other people from the regime that had done crimes against humanity are still free.Says that the political prisoners held there own protests by refusing to eat. They want people to write letters and send them in to plead for the freedom of these political prisoners. Their committee is devoted to the compassion of the political prisoners and wants the latin community to join forces. Then they just show the Chilean traditional ballet folk dance.</abstract>
  <subject>
    <topic>Chilean national folk ballet; ballet folkorico de chile; first democratic vote in paraguay; primero voto democratico en paraguay; political prisoners of chile; presos politicos de chile</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Edmonton</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Alberta</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="original">
    <identifier type="local">programa-nosotros-47</identifier>
  </relatedItem>
  
  <accessCondition type="license">Attribution_4.0_International</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordOrigin>Avalon Media System</recordOrigin>
    <recordContentSource>IEN</recordContentSource>
    <recordCreationDate>20160816</recordCreationDate>
    <recordChangeDate>2016-08-18T09:52:10-06:00</recordChangeDate>
    
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordIdentifier source="Fedora">avalon:354</recordIdentifier>
  </recordInfo>
<physicalDescription><internetMediaType>video/quicktime</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><location><url access="object in context"></url></location></mods>