<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo usage="primary">
    <title>Why Open Educational Resources Are Essential for Learning</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <genre authority="pbcore" valueURI="http://pbcore.org/vocabularies/pbcoreGenre%23event">Event</genre>
  <originInfo>
    
  <dateIssued encoding="edtf">2017-05-11</dateIssued></originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
  </language>
  
  <physicalDescription>
    
  </physicalDescription>
  <abstract>The free sharing of  open educational resources  (OER) can be seen as essential for promoting the creation of content usable in any learning context. OER can be effective in reducing  the knowledge divide that separates and partitions societies.  Educators worldwide continue to face significant challenges related to providing increased access to high quality learning, while containing or reducing costs.  New developments in information technology, especially with tablets, phablets, mobile phones and different gaming devices, highlight the shortcomings and challenges for the traditional education community, as well as those of more flexible providers, such as open universities.  Such developments have the potential to increase access and flexibility in education by rendering it ubiquitous. More recently educators are being forced to focus on the effects of &#x201C;digital locks&#x201D; (Technological Protection Measures) and restrictive licences that come with commercial online content and are turning to OER in order to take full advantage. Presenter: Rory McGreal (UNESCO/COL/ICDE Chair in OER, Co-Editor IRRODL, Athabasca University).</abstract>
  <note type="general">"The Campus Alberta Open Educational Resources (ABOER) Initiative is made possible through an investment from the Alberta government."</note>
  <subject>
    <topic>Open Educational Resources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Alberta OER</topic>
  </subject>
  
  <accessCondition type="license">Attribution_4.0_International</accessCondition>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">Attribution_4.0_International</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordOrigin>Avalon Media System</recordOrigin>
    <recordContentSource>IEN</recordContentSource>
    <recordCreationDate>20170710</recordCreationDate>
    <recordChangeDate>2017-08-02T11:40:30-06:00</recordChangeDate>
    
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordIdentifier source="Fedora">avalon:3358</recordIdentifier>
  </recordInfo>
<physicalDescription><internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><location><url access="object in context"></url></location></mods>