<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>programa-nosostros-49</identifier>
  <air-date>1992-01-19</air-date>
  <contributor>Lito Azocar</contributor>
  <creator>Sergio Contreras</creator>
  <date>1992-01</date>
  <description>Mario Allende begins the show saying it is a night of celebration because finally El Salvador has signed the Treaty of Peace and now the Salvadoran community can look forward to the future and build a new community in peace. Thursday January 16, 1992 Mexico signed the treaty as well which help put an end to the civil war in El Salvador which has been going on for 12 years. This episode is dedicated to El Salvador and he apologizes for not updating on Chile’s situation. For the military the Treaty of Peace will reduce them from 63,165 to 31,000 in the next two years. Mario says that the “cese de fuego” which is a cease fire command will begin in the first week of February. Then they go and show live footage from Mexico in the Palacio Nacional of the a Salvadoran Politician, Schafik Jorge Handal, gives his speech. He begins it by talking about the past and that now the treaty marks the freedom of El Salvador. He says that El Salvador tried to get help from other countries but they all closed their doors to them. He also names people that have died for the cause of bringing peace and they are considered heroes. He gives thanks to the churches that helped the Salvadoran people and as well there were women from Europe who helped the country. Goes back to Mario and he says that the country is going to legalize the rebels as a political party. Then they showed live footage of the president of El Salvador, Alfredo Cristiani, giving his speech in the Palacio Nacional. Mario says that the general secretary of the United Nations said that El Salvador’s Noche Largo (Long Night) is coming to a close. In Latin America they are celebrating and in Edmonton they joined in St. Francis church to celebrate the new found peace. Interviewed people on their reaction, how they felt, and if they would want to return back to El Salvador. Interview with Ronni Tejada says that everyone in the Salvadoran community is happy with this treaty because it will hopefully guarantee the militarization of the country, guarantee the popular vote &amp; wants of the people, and guarantee the only one national civil police. He wants the government to listen to the people basically. Interview with Laura Rodas says she would return back home and would like to get to know her country and the family she has there because she has all these memories from when she was little. Interview with Veronica Ochoa says she is happy with the treaty. She only left because of the war but her parents would like to return and start a new life back home. She hopes that everyone lives in peace now and that they have their human rights.  Interview with Joanne Miazga says she thinks its excellent that the government and the various factions that have been fighting to achieve some independence &amp; control over the Salvadoran economy have reached a settlement that will help the country to progress and give people the opportunity to take control of what is going on in El Salvador and have the opportunity to build a new country that has a vision and maybe be a model for other latin american countries. Back to Mario Allende it shows him back at the station and he has three guests from the Salvadoran community to share their thoughts. Ana Alfaro (part of Servicios Sociales Salvadoreños) says she’s glad they signed the treaty because finally there will be peace. I believe she says it all started when more than 30,000 farmers were massacred. The country has been in 40 years of trying to establish peace. Because of popular sectors and the FLN (policy group) they helped to establish the Peace Treaty. France and Mexico recognized FLN as a bandguardia? (word that I heard , but unsure of). She hopes now that these doors of peace are open that there will be no more fighting. Gladys Moreno (part of the Communidad Salavoreño) it was surprising for her to hear that speech from the president because in december it was said that there was no chance to negotiate with the guerillas, but its good this is happening because they have just been in armed war. They tried hiding the war at first from the world. She quotes the president “not to look back, but to the future” and she is thinks that what they’re doing now will happen &amp; move forward towards peace. The UN and Mexico were a big help making the treaty happen. Leonel Vizcarra (part of Oficina de Informacion El Salvador) says that before another group tried to bring peace to the country, but couldn’t. Now with the help from the UN they could and he’s happy because he can go back to his homeland. Says there are different sectors helping the country now. Appreciates the Canadian government for helping and accepting the Salvadoran people in Canada during these hard times. Mario Allende informs that 35 groups held a candlelight march as a religious prayer to pray for the end of war. Says that everyone in Canadian, Chilean &amp; Salvadoran community are celebrating. Ana Alfaro says the UN tried to get the country a police force, but she is glad that the country did it themselves.Gladys Moreno says that the country has just gone through one stage and now its moving onto another stage, a stage of reconstruction and that people in the community should not abandon them now because they will still need more help.</description>
  <mediatype>movies</mediatype>
  <recording-date>1992-01</recording-date>
  <title>Programa Nosotros. Apurimac</title>
  <collection>nosotrostv</collection>
  <subject>Chapultepec Peace Accords; Acuerdo de Paz de Chapultepec; Palacio Nacional de Mexico; Mexico National Palace; Alfredo Cristiani; Schafik Jorge Handel;</subject>
  <publicdate>2014-05-02 14:14:27</publicdate>
  <uploader>dale.storie@ualberta.ca</uploader>
  <addeddate>2014-05-02 14:14:27</addeddate>
  <collection>university_of_alberta_libraries</collection>
  <collection>toronto</collection>
  <backup_location>ia905807_11</backup_location>
</metadata>
