<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Edmonton Area Survey, 1977</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10576</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2015-09-10</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2018-03-12" type="RELEASED">4</version></verStmt><biblCit>Population Research Laboratory, 2015, "Edmonton Area Survey, 1977", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10576, UAL Dataverse, V4</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Edmonton Area Survey, 1977</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10576</IDNo><IDNo>eas77</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta">Population Research Laboratory</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" abbr="PRL">Population Research Laboratory</producer><prodDate>1977-06</prodDate></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" abbr="DI" URI="https://www.library.ualberta.ca/digital-initiatives">Digital Initiatives</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="data@ualberta.ca">Digital Initiatives</contact><distDate>1977-06</distDate><depositr>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta.</depositr><depDate>2015-09-10</depDate></distStmt><serStmt><serName>Edmonton Area Survey Series</serName></serStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Arts and Humanities</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>demographics</keyword><keyword>accomodations</keyword><keyword>personal safety</keyword><keyword>recreational facilities</keyword><keyword>social contacts</keyword><keyword>social behaviour</keyword><keyword>criminology</keyword><keyword>police</keyword><keyword>community</keyword><keyword>courts</keyword><keyword>civil rights</keyword><keyword>vicimization</keyword><keyword>employment</keyword><keyword>occupation</keyword><keyword>job satisfaction</keyword><keyword>family</keyword><keyword>child rearing</keyword><keyword>finances</keyword><keyword>gun control</keyword><keyword>wire tapping</keyword><keyword>death penalty</keyword><keyword>birth control information</keyword><keyword>abortion</keyword><keyword>working women</keyword><keyword>swine flu</keyword><keyword>immunization</keyword><keyword>quality of life</keyword><topcClas>Public opinion -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Social surveys -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Social conditions -- Statistics</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Economic conditions -- Statistics</topcClas></subject><abstract date="1977-06">The overall objectives of the study can be summarized as follows: a) To collect basic research data about the City of Edmonton and to make this data available to agencies and organizations for the purpose of helping them formulate policy and direct their activities. b) To accumulate archival material for researchers and interested persons to conduct survey research using the resources of students and the Population Research Laboratory that would not have been otherwise possible. c) To provide th&#xd;
e opportunity for researchers to do replication of work to further validate previous findings. d) To establish an organization with the capability of obtaining data for the measurement of social change in the community. e) To permit the opportunity for researchers to refine and test methodological research techniques for the purpose of adding to the knowledge of the survey research process itself. f) To train graduate students in the methods of survey research by allowing them to participate fully in the planning and execution of a large scale survey. Questions were compiled and to them were added specific quality of life questions used in the Michigan Quality of Life Survey (1974) and the National Opinion Research Council Surveys. The basic demographic questions and their format were taken from "Survey Research", a book compiled by the Canada Council's Task Force on Survey Research (Survey Research: Report of Consultative Group on Survey Research, The Canada Council, 1976). Through this replication of questions, we are in a position to compare results obtained in Edmonton with those found in other centers. In the Edmonton Area Study, an attempt is made to provide subjective data that ultimately can be compared against objective data to establish an overall view of well-being in various "life domains" of the inhabitants of Edmonton.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="1977-02">1977-02</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="1977-02">1977-02</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="1977-02">1977-02</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="1977-02">1977-02</collDate><dataKind>Microdata</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>City of Edmonton</geogCover><geogUnit>City of Edmonton</geogUnit><anlyUnit>Respondent</anlyUnit><universe>The Edmonton Area Study population universe was designated as all of the residential telephone subscribers in the city of Edmonton as listed in the June 1, 1976 edition of the Edmonton Telephones Street Numerical Address Directory. Its listings are approximately 2 months old at the issue date. Several other sources were explored for a list of dwellings for the study, such as the City of Edmonton Elections Office and Henderson's Directory. The City of Edmonton did not have their Civic Census listing in a usable form. The most recent Henderson's Directory available was the 1975 edition which was out of date in light of the rate of demolition of buildings and of the new construction in outlying areas of the city.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>Cross-sectional</timeMeth><dataCollector>Population Research Laboratory</dataCollector><frequenc>One-time data collection</frequenc><sampProc>Three hundred and twenty completed interviews were sought. Given an anticipated completion rate of 80% this meant that an original sample of four hundred had to be identified for a sampling fraction of approximately three in a thousand households. A multi-stage area cluster design with stratification, probability proportional to size, and equal probability of selection of each household was used. Respondents were chosen on a quota basis. The procedural rationale was as follows: a) Stratification was used to increase precision. b) Clustering was used to reduce costs (mainly temporal costs such as staff time required to list households and interviewer travel time). The loss of prcision occassioned by clustering was minimized by selecting clusters so as to maximize heterogeneity, that is, the clusters were selected proportionately from the different strata.&#xd;
In addition, the loss of precision was minimized by selecting clusters within each statum using probability proportional to size. c) A quota was used to guarantee a reasonable balance in the representation of males and females. A description of the sampling procedure is as follows: a) Stage 1. All 1971 enumeration areas (EA's) were identified and special EA's such as hospitals, nurses residences, nursing homes, hotels, and military establishments were excluded. These EA's were then stratified by deciles according to average total family income; that is, the first stratum was identified so as to contain the 10% of the EA's with the lowest average total family income levels, and so on. An additional stratum was made up of newly built up areas since 1971. One-tenth of the EA's in each stratum was then randomly selected with probability proportional to size, that is, an EA with twice the number of households of another EA was given twice the chance of being selected. b) Stage 2. The number of interviews assigned to each stratum was determined according to the proportion of the population in that stratum; that is, if a stratum contained 9% of the households then it was assigned 9% or 36 of the 400 interviews. The households to be interviewed were divided equally among the EA's chosen in Stage 1 to represent the stratum; that is, if the stratum contained 6 EA's then each EA was assigned 36/6 = 6 interviews. The households to be interviewed from each EA were chosen systematically from the July 1976 Edmonton Street Address Numerical Directory by taking a random start between l and j inclusive and selecting every jth household where j is the total number of households in the EA divided by the number of households to be selected. c) Stage 3. The respondent was chosen by the interviewer's asking for the male head of the household for the first 33% of the assigned households in each EA. Thereafter either the male or the female head of the household was taken.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Face-to-face interview</collMode><resInstru>Survey</resInstru><collSitu>The training session for interviewing was held early in February of 1977. It began in a seminar room where the interviewers were briefed as to the nature of the study and its objectives. Following this and for the remainder of the morning they were shown a videotape of a simulated interview session. The tape also demonstrated several types of introductions that could be used in different interview situations. During this session the tape was frequently stopped to answer questions or to emphasize important points.</collSitu><actMin>During the afternoon the group was divided into smaller groups in which each interviewer had the opportunity to do an interview with another group member and to watch three similar interviews. After each practice interview the interviewer was given feedback on his performance by the other members of the group. The final part of the day was devoted to informing the interviewers of the administrative details of the study as these pertained to them.</actMin></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail><origArch>Data Library, University of Alberta</origArch><avlStatus>Available</avlStatus><complete>Complete</complete></setAvail><useStmt><confDec>None required</confDec><specPerm>None required</specPerm><restrctn>None</restrctn><contact>Contact: Chuck Humphrey, Data Librarian, University of Alberta.</contact><citReq>Cite Edmonton Area Survey 1977</citReq><deposReq>None</deposReq><conditions>No attempt should be made to disclose individuals in the study nor link records through study with other files.</conditions><disclaimer>None</disclaimer></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f4843" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4843" level="datafile"><labl>1977EdmontonAreaSurvey_Codebook.pdf</labl><txt>Questionnaire and Codebook</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4845" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4845" level="datafile"><labl>1977EdmontonAreaSurvey_Data.tab</labl><txt>Data File</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/tab-separated-values</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4844" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4844" level="datafile"><labl>1977EdmontonAreaSurvey_SamplingReport.pdf</labl><txt>Methodology Report</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>