<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1991</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10561</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2015-09-08</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2018-02-28" type="RELEASED">5</version></verStmt><biblCit>Population Research Laboratory, 2015, "Alberta Survey, 1991", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10561, UAL Dataverse, V5</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1991</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10561</IDNo><IDNo>aas91</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta">Population Research Laboratory</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" abbr="PRL">Population Research Laboratory</producer><prodDate>1991</prodDate></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" abbr="DI" URI="https://www.library.ualberta.ca/digital-initiatives">Digital Initiatives </distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="data@ualberta.ca">Digital Initiatives </contact><distDate>1991-06</distDate><depositr>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta</depositr><depDate>2015-09-04</depDate></distStmt><serStmt><serName>All Alberta Survey Series</serName><serInfo>The 1991 Alberta Survey (AS) was the fifth annual provincial survey administered by the Department of Sociology, University of Alberta, through its research facility, the Population Research Laboratory (PRL). This random sample survey of households in the province of Alberta has enabled academic researchers, local community agencies, and government departments to explore a broad spectrum of social issues in an on-going research framework.</serInfo></serStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Arts and Humanities</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>demographics</keyword><keyword>health</keyword><keyword>environment</keyword><keyword>recycling</keyword><keyword>education</keyword><keyword>public school system</keyword><keyword>separate school system</keyword><keyword>Alberta Universities</keyword><keyword>Alberta Politics</keyword><keyword>Native Canadians</keyword><keyword>Nuclear War</keyword><keyword>Women's issues</keyword><keyword>ethnicity</keyword><keyword>culture</keyword><keyword>impaired driving</keyword><keyword>television</keyword><keyword>work conflicts</keyword><topcClas>Public opinion -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Social surveys -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Social conditions -- Statistics</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Economic conditions -- Statistics</topcClas></subject><abstract date="1991">The 1991 Alberta Survey (AS) was the fifth annual provincial survey administered by the Department of Sociology, University of Alberta, through its research facility, the Population Research Laboratory (PRL)--major topics include demographics, health, environment, education, Alberta political issues, Native Canadian issues, nuclear war and issues, women's role issues, teenage pregnancy, ethnic and cultural group issues, impaired driving, television viewing, work disagreements, political party preference, travel to Calgary, and financial betterment.   This random sample survey of households in the province of Alberta has enabled academic researchers, local community agencies, and government departments to explore a broad spectrum of social issues in an on-going research framework.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="1991-02">1991-02</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="1991-03">1991-03</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="1991-02-04">1991-02-04</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="1991-03">1991-03</collDate><dataKind>Microdata</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><geogUnit>Province</geogUnit><anlyUnit>Individual</anlyUnit><universe>The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing. From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the areas: the City of Edmonton (EAS), the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><dataCollector>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta.</dataCollector><frequenc>One-Time Data Collection</frequenc><sampProc>Main features of the sampling design are as follows: a. Province of Alberta delineated into three areas for telephone interviewing. (1)City of Edmonton. (2)City of Calgary. (3)Remainder of the Province (Other Alberta). b.Two-stage selection process. (1)Selection of households. (2)Selection of respondent within each household. To permit the analysis of each area as a separate entity a minimum sample size of 400 or more for each area of the province was deemed necessary. The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing. From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the areas: the City of Edmonton (EAS) , the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region. For the past five studies, the PRL has annually developed and updated computer files of five-digit telephone banks covering all of Alberta. The samples were drawn from these files by selecting, with replacement, a simple random sample of banks for each area and appending a random number between 00 and 99 to each number selected. All duplicate numbers were discarded. Nursing homes and temporary residences were screened from the sample. Within the household, one eligible person was selected as the respondent for the forty minute interview. A respondent was selected within each household on the basis of gender using the following selection guidelines to ensure an equal selection of male and female participants . a. The dwelling unit must be the person's usual place of residence and he/she must be 18 years of age or older. b. If an adult male answers the phone and is willing to be interviewed, he is the respondent. c. If an adult female answers the phone and there is an adult male present who is willing to be interviewed, int&#xd;
erview the male. If the male is not willing to be interviewed, and the female is willing, interview the female. d. If an adult female answers the phone and there is no adult male present, choose her as the respondent.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Telephone interview</collMode><resInstru>Survey</resInstru><actMin>Thirty-one percent of the respondents were re-contacted by the supervisors either for interview verification or for obtaining additional information. No significant discrepancies or irregularities were found.</actMin><weight>The weighting factors used for the 1991 survey are as follows: Edmonton: .698261 Calgary: .845392 Other Alberta: 1.532129</weight><cleanOps>The data were tabulated and cleaned using the OSIRIS and SPSSx statistical packages, and special programs developed by the PRL. The data cleaning process included wild code, discrepant value, and consistency checks</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo><respRate>The 1991 response rate for Calgary was 73.7%, for Edmonton 71.1% and 77.9% for the rest of Alberta</respRate></anlyInfo></method><dataAccs><setAvail><origArch>Data Library, University of Alberta</origArch><avlStatus>Currently available.</avlStatus><collSize>Four files including: a codebook, a questionnaire, a sampling report, and the data file.</collSize><complete>Complete</complete></setAvail><useStmt><confDec>None required.</confDec><specPerm>None required.</specPerm><restrctn>None</restrctn><contact>Chuck Humphrey, Data Librarian, University of Alberta. Email: chuck.humphrey@ualberta.ca</contact><citReq>Cite All Alberta Survey 1991</citReq><deposReq>None</deposReq><conditions>No attempt should be made to disclose individuals in the study nor link records through study with other files.</conditions><disclaimer>None</disclaimer></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f4807" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4807" level="datafile"><labl>1991AlbertaSurvey_Codebook.pdf</labl><txt>Questionnaire and Codebook</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4808" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4808" level="datafile"><labl>1991AlbertaSurvey_Data.tab</labl><txt>Data File</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/tab-separated-values</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4806" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4806" level="datafile"><labl>1991AlbertaSurvey_SamplingReport.pdf</labl><txt>Methodology Report</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>