<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1994</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10555</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2015-09-08</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2018-02-28" type="RELEASED">4</version></verStmt><biblCit>Population Research Laboratory, 2015, "Alberta Survey, 1994", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10555, UAL Dataverse, V4</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1994</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10555</IDNo><IDNo>aas94</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta">Population Research Laboratory</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" abbr="PRL">Population Research Laboratory</producer><prodDate>1994</prodDate><prodPlac>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta.</prodPlac></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" abbr="DI" URI="https://www.library.ualberta.ca/digital-initiatives">Digital Initiatives </distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="data@ualberta.ca">Digital Initiatives </contact><distDate>1994-06</distDate><depositr>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta</depositr><depDate>2015-09-04</depDate></distStmt><serStmt><serName>All Alberta Survey Series</serName></serStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Arts and Humanities</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>demographics</keyword><keyword>health</keyword><keyword>drugs</keyword><keyword>alcohol</keyword><keyword>television</keyword><keyword>AIDS</keyword><keyword>sexual behaviour</keyword><keyword>condoms</keyword><keyword>support groups</keyword><keyword>affiliation</keyword><keyword>fertility</keyword><topcClas>Public opinion--Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Social surveys--Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta--Social conditions--Statistics</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta--Economic conditions--Statistics</topcClas></subject><abstract date="2012-08-31">The 1994 Alberta Survey (AS) was the eighth annual provincial survey administered by the Department of Sociology, University of Alberta, through its research facility, the Population Research Laboratory (PRL)--major topics included in this survey: demographics, health, television viewing, political/social attitudes, AIDS, support group affiliation, and fertility. This random sample survey of households in the province of Alberta has enabled academic researchers, local community agencies, and government departments to&#xd;
explore a broad spectrum of social issues in an on-going research framework.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="1994-02">1994-02</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="1994-04">1994-04</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="1994-02-20">1994-02-20</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="1994-04-11">1994-04-11</collDate><dataKind>survey data</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><geogUnit>Province</geogUnit><anlyUnit>Individual</anlyUnit><universe>The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing. From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the province: the City of Edmonton (EAS), the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>Cross-Sectional</timeMeth><dataCollector>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta.</dataCollector><frequenc>One-time data collection.</frequenc><sampProc>SAMPLING DESIGN Main Features of Design: a. Province of Alberta delineated into three areas for telephone interviewing. (1)City of Edmonton. (2)City of Calgary. (3)Remainder of the Province (Other Alberta). b.Two-stage selection process. (1)Selection of households. (2)Selection of respondent within each household. To permit the analysis of each area as a separate entity a minimum sample size of 400 or more for each area of the province was deemed necessary. The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing. From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the province: the City of Edmonton (EAS) , the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region. For the past eight studies, the PRL has annually developed and updated computer files of five-digit telephone banks covering all of Alberta. The samples were drawn from these files by selecting, with replacement, a simple random sample of banks for each area and appending a random number between 00 and 99 to each number selected. All duplicate numbers were discarded. Nursing homes and temporary residences were deleted from the sample. Within the household, one eligible person was selected as the respondent for the thirty-three minute interview. A respondent was selected within each household on the basis of gender using the following selection guidelines to ensure an equal selection of male and female participants. a.The dwelling unit must be the person's usual place of residence and he/she must be 18 years of age or older. b.If an adult male answers the phone and is willing to be interviewed, he is the respondent. c.If an adult female answers the phone and there is an adult male present who is willing to be interviewed, interview the male. If the male is not willing to be interviewed, and the female is willing, interview the female. d.If an adult female answers the phone and there is no adult male present, choose her as the respondent.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Telephone interview.</collMode><resInstru>Survey</resInstru><collSitu>If the interviewers were unsuccessful in establishing contact on their first call, they were to make ten callback attempts before declaring a telephone number as "no contact".</collSitu><weight>The weighting factors used for the 1994 survey are as follows: Edmonton: .766012 Calgary: .852006 Other Alberta: 1.387182</weight><cleanOps>The data were tabulated and cleaned using the SPSSx statistical package. The data cleaning process included wildcode, discrepant value, and consistency checks.</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo><respRate>The response rate for the whole sample was 73%.</respRate></anlyInfo></method><dataAccs><setAvail><origArch>Data Library, University of Alberta</origArch><avlStatus>Available</avlStatus><collSize>Includes four physical files: questionnaire, codebook, sampling report, and data set.</collSize><complete>Complete</complete></setAvail><useStmt><confDec>None required.</confDec><specPerm>None required.</specPerm><restrctn>None</restrctn><contact>Chuck Humphrey, Data Librarian, University of Alberta. Email: chuck.humphrey@ualberta.ca</contact><citReq>Cite All Alberta Survey 1994.</citReq><deposReq>None</deposReq><conditions>No attempt should be made to disclose individuals in the study nor link records through study with other files.</conditions><disclaimer>None</disclaimer></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f4784" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4784" level="datafile"><labl>1994AlbertaSurvey_Codebook.pdf</labl><txt>Questionnaire and Codebook</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4785" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4785" level="datafile"><labl>1994AlbertaSurvey_Data.tab</labl><txt>Data File</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/tab-separated-values</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4803" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4803" level="datafile"><labl>1994AlbertaSurvey_SamplingReport.pdf</labl><txt>Methodology Report</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>