<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>All Our Babies/Families (AOB/F)</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10793</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-05-20</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2020-09-29" type="RELEASED">16</version></verStmt><biblCit>Tough, Suzanne; Benzies, Karen; Collisson, Beverly; Graham, Susan; McDonald, Sheila; Slater, Donna; McNeil, Deborah, 2016, "All Our Babies/Families (AOB/F)", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10793, UAL Dataverse, V16</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>All Our Babies/Families (AOB/F)</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10793</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Tough, Suzanne</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Benzies, Karen</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Collisson, Beverly</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Graham, Susan</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">McDonald, Sheila</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Slater, Donna</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">McNeil, Deborah</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Calgary" URI="https://www.ucalgary.ca/stough/">Tough, Suzanne</producer><producer affiliation="University of Calgary" URI="http://nursing.ucalgary.ca/nursing_info/profiles/karen-benzies">Benzies, Karen</producer><producer affiliation="University of Calgary" URI="http://research4kids.ucalgary.ca/profiles/beverly-collisson">Collisson, Beverly</producer><producer affiliation="University of Calgary" URI="https://psyc.ucalgary.ca/profiles/susan-graham">Graham, Susan</producer><producer affiliation="University of Calgary" URI="http://contacts.ucalgary.ca/info/med/profiles/1-4849457">McDonald, Sheila</producer><producer affiliation="University of Calgary" URI="http://www.ucalgary.ca/smrg/faculty/donna-slater">Slater, Donna</producer><producer affiliation="University of Calgary" URI="http://research4kids.ucalgary.ca/profiles/deborah-mcneil">McNeil, Deborah</producer><prodDate>2013</prodDate><prodPlac>Calgary, Alberta</prodPlac><software>SPSS</software><grantNo agency="Alberta Innovates">200700595</grantNo><grantNo agency="Alberta Innovates; Alberta Health Services; Alberta Children's Hospital Foundation; Alberta Health">200700595</grantNo></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="PolicyWise for Children &amp; Families" abbr="SAGE" URI="https://policywise.com/initiatives/sage/">Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence</distrbtr><contact affiliation="SAGE" email="data@policywise.com">Richard, Lucie</contact><depDate>2015-09-03</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/search/?q=&amp;q=cs%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fid.loc.gov%2Fauthorities%2Fsubjects">Pregnancy</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/search/?q=&amp;q=cs%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fid.loc.gov%2Fauthorities%2Fsubjects">Prenatal influences</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/search/?q=&amp;q=cs%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fid.loc.gov%2Fauthorities%2Fsubjects">Prenatal care</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/search/?q=&amp;q=cs%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fid.loc.gov%2Fauthorities%2Fsubjects">Maternal health services</keyword><keyword vocab="LCSH" vocabURI="http://id.loc.gov/search/?q=&amp;q=cs%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fid.loc.gov%2Fauthorities%2Fsubjects">Child health services - utilization</keyword></subject><abstract>The All Our Babies/Families (AOB/F) study is a prospective community-based pregnancy cohort that  follows maternal-infant pairs across the early life course to describes the mental health and psychosocial characteristics of mothers living in Calgary and area, as well as estimating rates of low birth weight, small for gestational age and preterm births. This study is intended to help understand women's prenatal care experiences in Calgary and identify barriers and facilitators to accessing care.   AOB/F data covers subject areas including: a) Maternal Prenatal Health (e.g., prenatal care, maternal gestation); b) Pregnancy History (e.g., previous pregnancies, previous preterm birth); c) Pre-pregnancy (e.g., pregnancy planning advice received, contraception use, pregnancy intention); d) Health Care Services (e.g., utilization of services for mother and baby); e) Food, Exercise and Housing (e.g., nutrition, housing, neighbourhood safety and cohesion); f) Lifestyle (e.g., T-ACE Screen for alcohol consumption risk, smoking, drugs); g) Social Support (Medical Outcomes Study Social Support Scale, partner/relationship satisfaction); h) Mental Health (e.g., Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale, Spielberger State Anxiety Scale, Perceived Stress Scale, optimism [Life Orientation Te&#xd;
st-Revised]); i) Life Events (e.g., previous mental health, abuse); j) Sociodemographic Outcomes (e.g., age, marital status, education, ethnicity, work status); k) Birth Outcomes - maternal and delivery (e.g. site of birth, delivery type, medication, delivery support); l) Birth Outcomes -infant (e.g., sex, birth weight, gestational age); m) Baby Health/Development (e.g., doctor, check-up, vaccinations); n) Parenting/ Postpartum Experiences (e.g. Parenting Morale Index, breastfeeding [Montreal Children's Hospital Feeding Scale], community service utilization)&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
&lt;strong> Searchable metadata can also be found on the SAGE metadata website: &lt;br>http://sagemetadata.policywise.com/nada/index.php/catalog/1&lt;br></abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2007-11">2007-11</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2013-12">2013-12</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2008-05">2008-05</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2014-05">2014-05</collDate><dataKind>Survey</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Calgary and Area, Alberta</geogCover><anlyUnit>Maternal/infant child dyad</anlyUnit><universe>Women able to communicate in written and spoken English, less than 25 weeks pregnant at enrollment, and accessing prenatal care in Calgary in 2008 or 2009.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>Longitudinal</timeMeth><dataCollector>AOB/F team</dataCollector><frequenc>Variable</frequenc><sampProc>No sampling procedure used.   Sample acquired in 2008 - 2010 through:   1) recruitment from health care offices (posters, word-of-mouth) and the regional health services website, and  2) recruitment over the phone (Women receiving prenatal viral serology tests were contacted by Calgary Laboratory Services to request permission to release patient contact information to the AOB/F research staff, who if consenting were contacted to determine eligibility).</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Questionnaire</collMode><resInstru>Structured, with some open-ended questions</resInstru><weight>No weighting</weight><cleanOps>The AOB/F team removed duplicate participant data (same mother/same child - there are some instances of same mother/different child); checked values for consistency; checked illogical values against original hard copies; and removed identifying data</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo><dataAppr>Compared to Maternity Experiences Survey (Canadian cross-sectional survey), AOB/F mothers were older (>35 years), reported a higher household income, were more likely to have received a first ultrasound before 18 weeks gestational age and to attend prenatal or childbirth education classes. Otherwise, AOB/F and MES participant demographic and pregnancy characteristics were similar.  More information available in McDonald, S. W., Lyon, A. W., Benzies, K. M., McNeil, D. A., Lye, S. J., Dolan, S. M., ...&amp; Tough, S. C. (2013). The All Our Babies pregnancy cohort: design, methods, and participant characteristics. BMC pregnancy and childbirth, 13(1), 1.</dataAppr></anlyInfo></method><dataAccs><notes type="DVN:TOA" level="dv">We are accepting proposals for our 2018 Secondary Data Use Grant starting February 20, 2018. This grant provides $5,000 to successful applicants to undertake research using data in SAGE. The term of the grant is 12 months. The grant offers an excellent opportunity for trainees and new researchers to work with existing birth cohort and survey data. Deadline for applications is April 27, 2018 at 4:00 PM MST.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
https://policywise.com/initiatives/sage/secondary-data-use-grant/&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
No special access conditions or procedures beyond the standard SAGE data access protocol. See: https://policywise.com/initiatives/sage/accessing-data/</notes><setAvail><accsPlac>Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence</accsPlac><avlStatus>Available for re-use via SAGE's Data Access Request Process (contact us at data@policywise.com)</avlStatus><collSize>13 files; 37.5 MB</collSize><complete>Items excluded from data deposit include:   1. Blood samples (optional) taken at 18-22 weeks gestation, and 28-32 weeks gestation 2. Cord blood, collected at birth 3. Survey at 5 years postpartum  (omitted because data not ready) 4. Alberta Health Services electronic health medical record, labour and delivery chart (omitted for privacy reasons); records where the participant did not consent to re-use</complete></setAvail><useStmt><confDec>Confidentiality Declaration required as part of Data Access Agreement</confDec><specPerm>Availability of the data is subject to approval after application to SAGE (see website, under Data Access). All data access requests are reviewed by the SAGE Access Review Roster, consisting of a member of the original research team, a member of SAGE and an external reviewer. Approved requests are formalized into a Data Access Agreement, and the data are ma&#xd;
de available in the SAGE Analytic Environment to the data accessor.</specPerm><restrctn>Year 3 data (Q6M, Q6ASQ, Q6CDI) are under embargo until further notice</restrctn><citReq>The following citation is required in all products (i.e. articles, publications or other reporting of the data results): Tough, Suzanne; Benzies, Karen; Collisson, Beverly; Graham, Susan; McDonald, Sheila; Slater, Dawn; McNeil, Deborah, 2013, All Our Babies/Families, doi:10.7939/DVN/10793, Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence [Distributor], V9.  All products must also acknowledge funders and study participants - Please contact SAGE for "AOB/F Cohort Guidelines for Acknowledgement of Scientific Publications and Deliverables" document.  In addition, co-authorship with data authors is required where scientifically appropriate (in accordance with publication author guidelines)</citReq><deposReq>Data accessor must report back on any reports, publications or articles resulting from the use of this data, as per the Data Access Agreement.</deposReq></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relStdy>Alberta Pregnancy Outcomes and Nutrition (APrON)</relStdy></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f12899" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10793/KSVIZX" level="datafile"><labl>S01_AOB_metadata_full_v06.pdf</labl><txt>This file includes all element level metadata.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f12900" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10793/BBAHHP" level="datafile"><labl>S01_AOB_metadata_noelement_v06.pdf</labl><txt>This file includes only study and dataset level metadata (no element level metadata).</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>