<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1996B</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10572</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2015-09-09</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2018-02-28" type="RELEASED">6</version></verStmt><biblCit>Population Research Laboratory, 2015, "Alberta Survey, 1996B", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10572, UAL Dataverse, V6</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1996B</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10572</IDNo><IDNo>aas96b</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta">Population Research Laboratory</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" abbr="PRL">Population Research Laboratory</producer><prodDate>1997-05</prodDate></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" abbr="DI" URI="https://www.library.ualberta.ca/digital-initiatives">Digital Initatives</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="data@ualberta.ca">Digital Initiatives </contact><distDate>1997-05</distDate><depositr>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta.</depositr><depDate>2015-09-09</depDate></distStmt><serStmt><serName>All Alberta Survey Series</serName></serStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Arts and Humanities</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>sociodemographics</keyword><keyword>physical activity</keyword><keyword>exercise</keyword><keyword>Edmonton</keyword><keyword>municipal government</keyword><keyword>smoking</keyword><keyword>tobacco</keyword><keyword>bad breath</keyword><keyword>crime</keyword><keyword>victimization</keyword><keyword>social anxiety</keyword><keyword>reproductive health</keyword><keyword>palliative care</keyword><keyword>cancer</keyword><keyword>HIV</keyword><keyword>AIDS</keyword><keyword>condoms</keyword><keyword>disability</keyword><topcClas>Public opinion -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Social surveys -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Social conditions -- Statistics</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Economic conditions -- Statistics</topcClas></subject><abstract date="1997-05">The 1996 Alberta Survey (AS) was the eleventh annual provincial survey administered by the Population Research Laboratory (PRL), the survey research arm of the Department of Sociology at the University of Alberta. This random sample survey of households in the province of Alberta has enabled academic researchers, government departments, non-profit organizations, and the private sector to explore a wide range of public policy issues in an on-going research framework. Owing to the large number of questions submitted by researchers and organizations, the omnibus Alberta Survey was conducted during two time periods in 1996. Independent samples were drawn and separate questionnaires were administered by telephone interviewers.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="1996-12">1996-12</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="1997-01">1997-01</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="1996-12-06">1996-12-06</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="1997-01-20">1997-01-20</collDate><dataKind>Survey Data.</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><geogUnit>Province</geogUnit><anlyUnit>Individual</anlyUnit><universe>The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing. From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the province: the City of Edmonton (EAS)1, the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>Cross-sectional.</timeMeth><dataCollector>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta.</dataCollector><frequenc>One-time data collection.</frequenc><sampProc>SAMPLING DESIGN Main Features of Design: a. Province of Alberta delineated into three areas for telephone interviewing. (1) City of Edmonton. (2) City of Calgary. (3) Remainder of the Province (Other Alberta). b. Two-stage selection process. (1) Selection of households. (2) Selection of respondent within each household. To permit the analysis of each area as a separate entity, a minimum sample size of 400 or more for each area of the province was deemed necessary. The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing.  From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the province:  the City of Edmonton (EAS) , the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region. A random-digit dialing approach was used to ensure that respondents had an equal chance to be contacted whether or not their household was listed in a telephone directory.  For the past eleven studies, the PRL has developed and updated a database of five-digit telephone banks (i.e. 403-xxx-xx) covering all of Alberta. The 1996 area samples were drawn from this database by using a computer program to select, with replacement, a simple random sample of banks for each area and appending a random number between 00 and 99 to each number selected.  All duplicate telephone numbers were purged from the computer-generated list.   Nursing homes and collective dwellings were also deleted from the sample.  Within the household, one eligible person was selected as the respondent for the thirty-minute interview. A respondent was selected within each household on the basis of gender using the following selection guidelines to ensure an equal selection of male and female participants . a. The dwelling unit must be the person's usual place of residence and he/she must be 18 years of age or older. b. If an adult male answers the phone and is willing to be interviewed, he is the respondent. c.	If an adult female answers the phone an&#xd;
d there is an adult male present who is willing to be interviewed, interview the male.  If the male is not willing to be interviewed, and the female is willing, interview the female. d. If an adult female answers the phone and there is no adult male present, choose her as the respondent.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Telephone interview</collMode><resInstru>Survey</resInstru><actMin>Supervisors monitor call dispositions, field edit, track interviewer productivity, and accumulate data for analysis. If the interviewers were unsuccessful in establishing contact on their first call, they were to make a minimum of fifteen callback attempts before declaring a telephone number as "no contact." Ten percent of the respondents were re-contacted by the telephone supervisors for interviewing validation.</actMin><weight>The weighting factors used for the 1996B Alberta Survey are as follows: Edmonton 0.759319, Calgary 0.866768,  Other Albera 1.375178.</weight><cleanOps>CATI features such as the automatic routing of questions and built-in checks for inconsistencies and wildcodes eliminated the need for editing by the interviewers. SPSS system file was used for additional cleaning procedures.</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail><origArch>Data Library, University of Alberta</origArch><avlStatus>Available</avlStatus><complete>Complete</complete></setAvail><useStmt><confDec>None required.</confDec><specPerm>None required.</specPerm><restrctn>None required.</restrctn><contact>Contact: Chuck Humphrey, Data Librarian, University of Alberta. Email chuck.humphrey@ualberta.ca</contact><citReq>Cite All Alberta Survey 1996b.</citReq><deposReq>None</deposReq><conditions>No attempt should be made to disclose individuals in the study nor link records through study with other files.</conditions><disclaimer>None</disclaimer></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f4832" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4832" level="datafile"><labl>1996bAlbertaSurvey_Codebook.pdf</labl><txt>Questionnaire and Codebook</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4833" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4833" level="datafile"><labl>1996bAlbertaSurvey_Data.tab</labl><txt>Data File</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/tab-separated-values</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4831" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4831" level="datafile"><labl>1996bAlbertaSurvey_SamplingReport.pdf</labl><txt>Methodology Report</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>