<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1995B</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10554</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2015-09-08</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2018-02-28" type="RELEASED">5</version></verStmt><biblCit>Population Research Laboratory, 2015, "Alberta Survey, 1995B", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10554, UAL Dataverse, V5</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 1995B</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10554</IDNo><IDNo>aas95b</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta">Population Research Laboratory</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" abbr="PRL">Population Research Laboratory</producer><prodDate>2010-03-04</prodDate></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" abbr="DI" URI="https://www.library.ualberta.ca/digital-initiatives">Digital Initiatives</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="data@ualberta.ca">Digital Initiatives</contact><distDate>1995-06</distDate><depDate>2015-09-04</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Arts and Humanities</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>demographics</keyword><keyword>health</keyword><keyword>prostitution</keyword><keyword>political and social attitudes</keyword><keyword>career choices</keyword><keyword>support groups</keyword><keyword>fertility</keyword><topcClas>Public Opinion -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Social Surveys -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Social Conditions -- Statistics</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Economic Conditions -- Statistics</topcClas></subject><abstract date="1995">The 1995 Alberta Survey (AS) was the ninth annual provincial survey administered by the Department of Sociology, University of Alberta, through its research facility, the Population Research Laboratory (PRL).  This random sample survey of households in the province of Alberta has enabled academic researchers, local community agencies, and government departments to explore a broad spectrum of social issues in an on-going research framework. Owing to the large number of questions submitted by researchers and organizations, the 1995 Alberta Survey was conducted in two se&#xd;
gments.  Two independent samples were drawn and administered separate questionnaires.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="1995-03">1995-03</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="1995-05">1995-05</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="1995-03-18">1995-03-18</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="1995-05-04">1995-05-04</collDate><dataKind>Microdata</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><geogUnit>Province</geogUnit><anlyUnit>Individual</anlyUnit><universe>The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing.  From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the province:  the City of Edmonton (EAS) , the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>Cross-Sectional</timeMeth><sampProc>SAMPLING DESIGN Main Features of Design: a. Province of Alberta delineated into three areas for telephone interviewing. (1) City of Edmonton. (2) City of Calgary. (3) Remainder of the Province (Other Alberta). b. Two-stage selection process. (1) Selection of households. (2) Selection of respondent within each household. To permit the analysis of each area as a separate entity a minimum sample size of 400 or more for each area of the province was deemed necessary. The population universe designated for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct-dialing.  From this population, three samples were drawn to cover the province:  the City of Edmonton (EAS) , the City of Calgary, and the remainder of the region. For the past nine studies, the PRL has annually developed and updated a database of five-digit telephone banks covering all of Alberta.  The 1995 area samples were drawn from this database by selecting, with replacement, a simple random sample of banks for each area and appending a random number between 00 and 99 to each number selected.  All duplicate numbers were discarded. Nursing homes and temporary residences were deleted from the sample.  Within the household, one eligible person was selected as the respondent for the thirty-three minute interview. A respondent was selected within each household on the basis of gender using the following selection guidelines to ensure an equal selection of male and female participants . a. The dwelling unit must be the person's usual place of residence and he/she must be 18 years of age or older. b. If an adult male answers the phone and is willing to be interviewed, he is the respondent. c.	If an adult female answers the phone and there is an adult male present who is willing to be interviewed, interview the male.  If the male is not willing to be interviewed, and the female is willing, interview the       female. d. If an adult female answers the phone and there is no adult male present, choose her as the respondent.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Telephone interview</collMode><weight>The weighting factors used for the 1995 survey are as follows: Edmonton: .772476 Calgary: .846274 Other Alberta: 1.385239</weight></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail/><useStmt/></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f4782" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4782" level="datafile"><labl>1995bAlbertaSurvey_Codebook.pdf</labl><txt>Questionnaire and Codebook</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4783" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4783" level="datafile"><labl>1995bAlbertaSurvey_Data.tab</labl><txt>Data File</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/tab-separated-values</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4802" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4802" level="datafile"><labl>1995bAlbertaSurvey_SamplingReport.pdf</labl><txt>Methodology Report</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>