<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 2011B</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10006</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2014-04-24</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2018-03-02" type="RELEASED">6</version></verStmt><biblCit>Population Research Laboratory, 2014, "Alberta Survey, 2011B", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10006, UAL Dataverse, V6</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 2011B</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10006</IDNo><IDNo>AAS2011B</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta">Population Research Laboratory</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" abbr="PRL">Population Research Laboratory</producer><prodDate>2013-12-13</prodDate></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" abbr="DI" URI="https://www.library.ualberta.ca/digital-initiatives">Digital Initiatives </distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" email="data@ualberta.ca">Digital Initiatives </contact><distDate>2012-09-09</distDate><depDate>2014-04-24</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Arts and Humanities</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>attitudes towards others</keyword><keyword>Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder</keyword><keyword>sustainable consumption</keyword><keyword>environmental issues</keyword><keyword>injuries in Alberta</keyword><keyword>stress</keyword><keyword>continuing care services</keyword><keyword>cell phone use and driving</keyword><topcClas>Public opinion -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Social surveys -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Social conditions -- Statistics</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Economic conditions -- Statistics</topcClas></subject><abstract date="2012-08-31">The Population Research Laboratory (PRL), a member of the Association of Academic Survey Research Organizations (AASRO), seeks to advance the research, educational and service&#xd;
goals of the University of Alberta by helping academic researchers and policy makers design and implement applied social science research projects. The PRL specializes in the gathering, analysis, and presentation of data about demographic, social and public issues such as the state of Canadians' health and access to healthcare, their educational and labour force lives, and their perceptions and knowledge of the world around them.   The PRL research team provides expert consultation and implementation of quantitative and qualitative research methods, project design, sample design, web-based, paper-based and telephone surveys, field site testing, data analysis, and report writing. The PRL follows scientifically rigorous and transparent methods in each phase of a research project. Research coordinators are members of the American Association for Public Opinion Research (AAPOR) and use best-known practices when conducting all types of research. The PRL maintains a complement of highly trained telephone interviewers and supervisors.   The Population Research Laboratory (PRL) administered the 2011 Alberta Survey. This survey of households across the province of Alberta continues to enable academic researchers, government departments, and non-profit organizations to explore a wide range of topics in a structured research framework and environment. Sponsors' research questions are asked together with demographic questions in a telephone interview of Alberta households.   This data consists of the information from 1203 Alberta residence, interviewed between May 25, 2011 and July 22, 2011. The amount of responses indicates that the response rate, as calculated percentages representing the number of people who participated in the survey divided by the number selected in the eligible sample, was 26.1%.   The subject ares included in the 2011 Alberta Survey A includes socio-demographic and background variables such as: household composition, age, gender, marital status, highest level of education, household income, religion, ethnic background, place of birth, employment status, home ownership, political party support and perceptions of financial status.. Additionally topics covered are attitudes towards others (Racism Free Edmonton Initiative); Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder, sustainable consumption, environmental issues, injuries in Alberta, stress, continuing care services, and cell phone use and driving.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2011-05">2011-05</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2011-06">2011-06</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2011-05-25">2011-05-25</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2011-06-22">2011-06-22</collDate><dataKind>Microdata</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><geogUnit>Province</geogUnit><anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit><universe>This data consists of information collected from 1203 respondents (603 female and 600 male) over the age of 18. Selection of the respondents was based on the selection of a household, and then individuals within the household (Table 1, Page 2). Table 1 also shows the number of interviews for Metropolitan Edmonton, Metropolitan Calgary, other Alberta, and the entire province by gender.   Several socio-demographic and background characteristics such as household composition, age, gender, marital status, highest level of education, household income, religion, ethnic background, place of birth, employment status, home ownership, political party support and perceptions of financial status. (Table 5, Page 8).</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>The main data collection began on May 25, 2011 and was completed on June 22, 2011. CATI interviewers collected data at the University of Alberta. Interviews were conducted between the hours of 9:00 a.m. to 2:00 p.m. and 4:00 p.m. to 9:00 p.m. Mondays through Fridays; 10:00 a.m. to 4:00 p.m. on Saturdays; and between 2:00 p.m. and 8:00 p.m. on Sundays.</timeMeth><sampProc>The main feature of the sampling design was a two-stage selection process: first, based on a selection of households, and second, the selection of a respondent within each household.  The Alberta Survey B aimed for a total sample size of 1200 households across Alberta, with a minimum of 400 respondents in Metropolitan Edmonton1, 400 in Metropolitan Calgary, and 400 from the remainder of the province (other Alberta). The target population was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time&#xd;
of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit that could be contacted by direct dialling.   The PRL used a Random-Digit Dialling (RDD) approach to ensure that respondents had an equal chance to be contacted whether or not their household was listed in a telephone directory. The PRL has developed a database of eight-digit telephone banks covering the Edmonton and Calgary metropolitan areas, as well as the remainder of the province. The 2011 Alberta Survey B sample was generated from these databases by using a computer program to select, with replacement, a simple random sample of banks for each area and appending a random number between 00 and 99 to each number selected. Duplicate telephone numbers were purged from the computer list. Within the household, one eligible person was selected as the respondent.A respondent within each household was selected on the basis of gender using the following selection guidelines to ensure an equal selection of male and female participants.   Some considerations when selecting the individuals interviewed:   a. He/she must be 18 years of age or older.  b. If an adult male answers the phone and is willing to be interviewed, he is the respondent.  c. If an adult female answers the phone and there is an adult male present who is willing to be interviewed, interview the male. If the male is not willing to be interviewed, and the female is willing, interview the female.  d. If an adult female answers the phone and there is no adult male present, choose her as the respondent.  e. If the quota for females is full and a female answers the phone, provided the household has an eligible male, make an appointment to interview the male.   The final sample of 1,203 respondents consisted of 603 females and 600 males.   In terms of sampling error, This study is based on a sample of adults in Alberta rather than the total population of adults in Alberta. All of the descriptive statistics, such as means and percentages, which are calculated using the sample data, could be subject to sampling error. The sampling error is a measure of the validity of the descriptive statistics that are observed in a sample. The estimated sampling error, at the 95% confidence level, for an area sample of 1,203 households assuming a 50/50 binomial percentage distribution is plus or minus 2.8 percentage points. Survey estimates for the subsample of 400 are estimated to be within plus or minus 5.0 percentage points, at the 95% confidence level.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Questionnaire administered through 30- station CATI (Computer-Assisted Telephone Interviewing) system installed on a local area network at the Population Research Laboratory. At the end of the interviewing period, verbatim responses were coded into numeric responses with the coding frames that were either developed by the PRL in previous years or provided by the sponsor. The open-ended codes were then merged with the main SPSS data file for additional cleaning and labelling.</collMode><weight>The sample sizes of completed interviews obtained for Metropolitan Edmonton, Metropolitan Calgary, and Other Alberta are not always proportional to the current Alberta population they are meant to represent. Therefore, statistical weights were calculated for the Alberta Survey B 2011 sample data using population estimates for 2010 (Table 4, Page 6).</weight></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail/><useStmt/></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f854" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/854" level="datafile"><labl>2011bAlbertaSurvey_Codebook.pdf</labl><txt>Questionnaire</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f855" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/855" level="datafile"><labl>2011bAlbertaSurvey_Data.tab</labl><txt>Data File</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/tab-separated-values</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f853" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/853" level="datafile"><labl>2011bAlbertaSurvey_SamplingReport.pdf</labl><txt>Methodology Report</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>