<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Leys Lab Papers</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2020-11-17</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2020-11-18" type="RELEASED">1</version></verStmt><biblCit>Leys, Sally, 2020, "Leys Lab Papers", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG, UAL Dataverse, V1</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Leys Lab Papers</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty>Leys, Sally</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt/><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact email="sleys@ualberta.ca">Leys, Sally</contact><depositr>Leys, Sally</depositr><depDate>2020-01-13</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Earth and Environmental Sciences</keyword><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword></subject><abstract>This is a repository for papers published by Sally Leys and the Leys lab. </abstract><sumDscr/></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><sources/></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><notes type="DVN:TOU" level="dv">CC0 Waiver</notes><setAvail/><useStmt/></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f10422" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/D5I847" level="datafile"><labl>Oxygen and the Energetic Requirements of the First Multicellular Animals</labl><txt>The appearance of multicellular animals during the Neoproterozoic Era is thought to have coincided with&#xd;
oxygenation of the oceans; however, we know little about the physiological needs of early animals or about the environment they lived in. Approaches using biomarkers, fossils, and phylogenomics have provided some hints of the types&#xd;
of animals that may have been present during the Neoproterozoic, but extant animals are our best modern links to the&#xd;
theoretical ancestors of animals. Neoproterozoic oceans were low energy habitats, with low oxygen concentrations and&#xd;
sparse food availability for the first animals. We examined tolerance of extant ctenophores and sponges—as representatives of extant lineages of the earliest known metazoan groups—to feeding and oxygen use. A review of respiration rates&#xd;
in species across several phyla suggests that suspension feeders in general have a wide range of metabolic rates, but&#xd;
sponges have some of the highest of invertebrates and ctenophores some of the lowest. Our own studies on the&#xd;
metabolism of two groups of deep water sponges show that sponges have different approaches to deal with the cost&#xd;
of filtration and low food availability. We also confirmed that deep water sponges tolerate periods of hypoxia, but at the&#xd;
cost of filtration, indicating that normal feeding is energetically expensive. Predictions of oxygen levels in the&#xd;
Neoproterozoic suggest the last common ancestor of multicellular animals was unlikely to have filtered like modern&#xd;
sponges. Getting enough food at low oxygen would have been a more important driver of the evolution of early body&#xd;
plans.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f10426" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/J60EIU" level="datafile"><labl>Phagocytosis of microbial symbionts balances the carbon and nitrogen budget for the deep-water boreal sponge Geodia barretti</labl><txt>Geodia barretti is a massive nearly spherical sponge that forms dense assemblages on the continental shelf&#xd;
of the North Atlantic and the Norwegian Sea. We studied the metabolism of individual sponges collected&#xd;
using a remotely operated vehicle and maintained in large tanks with high volumes of unfiltered water&#xd;
brought from 160 m depth. We used direct methods (In-Ex) to measure excurrent flow rates, oxygen&#xd;
removed, and carbon and nutrient flux through the sponges. G. barretti had very low specific filtration&#xd;
(0.26 mL min21 mL21 sponge tissue) and low respiration (5.34 6 0.98 nmol O2 min21 mL21 sponge tissue;&#xd;
8.44 6 1.51 lmol O2 h21 g C21&#xd;
) rates in comparison to other sponges. A net release of nitrogen was detected&#xd;
as NO2&#xd;
3 . Bacteria were removed from the water filtered with up to 99% efficiency, yet comprised only 5% of&#xd;
the sponges’ total carbon budget; the remainder consisted of dissolved organic carbon and detritus. High bacterial removal was aided by the presence of a tight gasket of cells that surrounds the collar of each choanocyte filter. A test for potential bypass canals showed removal of fluorescent microspheres until they were&#xd;
excreted 5–12 h after feeding. Electron micrographs showed active uptake of Escherichia coli “fed” to the&#xd;
sponge as well as phagocytosis of symbiont microbes by sponge cells in the mesohyl. These data provide the&#xd;
first comprehensive study of metabolism in a deep-water high microbial abundance sponge.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f10423" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/L5DQYU" level="datafile"><labl>Pyrosome consumption by benthic organisms during blooms in the northeast Pacific and Gulf of Mexico</labl><txt>In the fall of 2016 large populations of pyrosomes, preliminarily identified as Pyrosoma atlanticum (Peron,&#xd;
1804), bloomed in the Gulf of Mexico (C. Du Preez, personal observation) and, in the spring and summer of 2017,&#xd;
a bloom occurred in the shelf and off-shore waters from&#xd;
Alaska, through British Columbia, and south to Oregon&#xd;
(I. Perry and M. Galbraith, personal communications).&#xd;
Pyrosomes are a member of the Thaliacean class of colonial pelagic tunicates that also includes salps and doliolids. Pyrosomes are historically rare in northern waters&#xd;
(Van Soest 1981) because they typically live in warm&#xd;
waters from 50° N to 50° S, such as in the Gulf of Mexico. The bloom that occurred in British Columbia during&#xd;
the summer of 2017 is the first recorded pyrosome bloom&#xd;
in these waters. Like other gelatinous zooplankton, these&#xd;
free-floating colonies sink rapidly when they die (Lebrato&#xd;
et al. 2013) and P. atlanticum undertake daily vertical&#xd;
migrations (Andersen et al. 1992). It is very likely, therefore, that these blooms affect benthic food webs.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f10420" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/ZHYZMV" level="datafile"><labl>Suspended sediment causes feeding current arrests in situ in the glass sponge Aphrocallistes vastus</labl><txt>Bottom-contact trawling generates large, moving clouds of suspended sediments that can alter the behaviour of&#xd;
organisms adjacent to trawl paths. While increased suspended sediment concentrations (SSCs) are known to&#xd;
cause glass sponges to arrest filtration in lab studies, the response of sponges to sediment in situ is not yet known.&#xd;
Here we describe arrest behaviours in response to increased SSCs recorded from the glass sponge Aphrocallistes&#xd;
vastus at the Fraser Ridge sponge reef in the Strait of Georgia, British Columbia, Canada. We identified 23 arrests&#xd;
of the sponges’ feeding current during experimental disturbances that raised SSC to between 10 and 80 mg l−1.&#xd;
Single arrests lasted 4.25 ± 1.3 min (±SD) and were characterized by a 2 cm s−1 reduction in feeding current&#xd;
lasting 0.5–3 min (mean 1.91 ± 0.97 min, n=19). In comparison, coughing arrests varied in length&#xd;
(31 ± 22.89 min) with arrest phases lasting 4–15 min (10.46 ± 5.26 min, n=4). Coughing arrests showed a&#xd;
distinctive on/off pattern as sponge filtration returned to normal excurrent velocities, distinguishing them from&#xd;
single arrests. The onset of both arrest types was correlated with elevated SSCs (r=−0.83 to −0.92). Natural&#xd;
SSCs at the reef averaged 4.4 mg l−1 and were correlated with tidal flow (r=0.86 to 0.89). The combined data&#xd;
provide evidence that suspended sediments can stop glass sponge feeding in situ even at SSCs below those known&#xd;
to be generated by trawling.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f10427" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/GJYYQK" level="datafile"><labl>Think like a sponge The genetic signal of sensory cells in sponges</labl><txt>A complex genetic repertoire underlies the apparently simple body plan of sponges. Among the genes present in&#xd;
poriferans are those fundamental to the sensory and nervous systems of other animals. Sponges are dynamic&#xd;
and sensitive animals and it is intuitive to link these genes to behaviour. The proposal that ctenophores are the&#xd;
earliest diverging metazoan has led to the question of whether sponges possess a ‘pre-nervous’ system or have&#xd;
undergone nervous system loss. Both lines of thought generally assume that the last common ancestor of&#xd;
sponges and eumetazoans possessed the genetic modules that underlie sensory abilities. By corollary extant&#xd;
sponges may possess a sensory cell homologous to one present in the last common ancestor, a hypothesis that&#xd;
has been studied by gene expression. We have performed a meta-analysis of all gene expression studies&#xd;
published to date to explore whether gene expression is indicative of a feature's sensory function. In sponges we&#xd;
find that eumetazoan sensory-neural markers are not particularly expressed in structures with known sensory&#xd;
functions. Instead it is common for these genes to be expressed in cells with no known or uncharacterized&#xd;
sensory function. Indeed, many sensory-neural markers so far studied are expressed during development,&#xd;
perhaps because many are transcription factors. This suggests that the genetic signal of a sponge sensory cell is&#xd;
dissimilar enough to be unrecognizable when compared to a bilaterian sensory or neural cell. It is possible that&#xd;
sensory-neural markers have as yet unknown functions in sponge cells, such as assembling an immunological&#xd;
synapse in the larval globular cell. Furthermore, the expression of sensory-neural markers in non-sensory cells,&#xd;
such as adult and larval epithelial cells, suggest that these cells may have uncharacterized sensory functions.&#xd;
While this does not rule out the co-option of ancestral sensory modules in later evolving groups, a distinct&#xd;
genetic foundation may underlie the sponge sensory system.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f10425" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/INHCWL" level="datafile"><labl>Trophic ecology of glass sponge reefs in the Strait of Georgia, British Columbia</labl><txt>Sponges link the microbial loop with benthic communities by feeding on bacteria. Glass sponge reefs&#xd;
on the continental shelf of western Canada have extremely high grazing rates, consuming seven times&#xd;
more particulate carbon than can be supplied by vertical fux alone. Unlike many sponges, the reef&#xd;
building species Aphrocallistes vastus has no microbial symbionts and removes little dissolved organic&#xd;
carbon. To determine how reef sponges therefore get enough food to sustain such substantial grazing&#xd;
we measured stable carbon and nitrogen isotope signatures of water, sediment and sponge tissues.&#xd;
To ensure samples were temporally associated, we also studied the duration particles were retained in&#xd;
tissues in controlled feeding studies using microscopic beads and 13C-labeled bacteria. Although fecal&#xd;
pellets were expelled from sponges within 24hours of feeding, intact bacteria were still found in tissues&#xd;
and sponge tissues retained elevated 13C levels for at least 14 days. These independent lines of evidence&#xd;
suggest that carbon in reef sponge tissues may refect food consumed from days to weeks earlier. Stable&#xd;
isotope analysis suggests that heterotrophic bacteria ingested by the sponges comes from a confuence&#xd;
of trophic subsidies: from terrestrial and oceanic sources, and also potentially on sediment-borne&#xd;
bacteria resuspended by tidal currents.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f10421" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/EAZK76" level="datafile"><labl>Understanding Animal Evolution The Added Value of Sponge Transcriptomics and Genomics</labl><txt>Sponges are important but often-neglected organisms. The absence ofclassical animal traits (nerves, digestive tract, and muscles) makes spongeschallenging for non-specialists to work with and has delayed getting highquality genomic data compared to other invertebrates. Yet analyses of spongegenomes and transcriptomes currently available have radically changed ourunderstanding of animal evolution. Sponges are of prime evolutionaryimportance as one of the best candidates to form the sister group of all otheranimals, and genomic data are essential to understand the mechanisms thatcontrol animal evolution and diversity. Here we review the most significantoutcomes of current genomic and transcriptomic analyses of sponges, anddiscuss limitations and future directions of sponge transcriptomic andgenomic studies.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f10424" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/1T7ZWG/37WGUT" level="datafile"><labl>Wnt signaling and polarity in freshwater sponges</labl><txt>Background: The Wnt signaling pathway is uniquely metazoan and used in many processes during development,&#xd;
including the formation of polarity and body axes. In sponges, one of the earliest diverging animal groups, Wnt&#xd;
pathway genes have diverse expression patterns in different groups including along the anterior-posterior axis of&#xd;
two sponge larvae, and in the osculum and ostia of others. We studied the function of Wnt signaling and body&#xd;
polarity formation through expression, knockdown, and larval manipulation in several freshwater sponge species.&#xd;
Results: Sponge Wnts fall into sponge-specific and sponge-class specific subfamilies of Wnt proteins. Notably Wnt&#xd;
genes were not found in transcriptomes of the glass sponge Aphrocallistes vastus. Wnt and its signaling genes were&#xd;
expressed in archaeocytes of the mesohyl throughout developing freshwater sponges. Osculum formation was&#xd;
enhanced by GSK3 knockdown, and Wnt antagonists inhibited both osculum development and regeneration. Using&#xd;
dye tracking we found that the posterior poles of freshwater sponge larvae give rise to tissue that will form the&#xd;
osculum following metamorphosis.&#xd;
Conclusions: Together the data indicate that while components of canonical Wnt signaling may be used in&#xd;
development and maintenance of osculum tissue, it is likely that Wnt signaling itself occurs between individual&#xd;
cells rather than whole tissues or structures in freshwater sponges.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>