<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>The 2nd Provincial Benchmark Survey 2013: What Albertans Know About Child Development</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10812</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-06-09</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2019-09-09" type="RELEASED">3</version></verStmt><biblCit>Botey, Anna; Tough, Suzanne; Bukutu, Cecilia; Vinturache, Angela; Gibbard, Ben; MacLellan, Kathryn; Bayrampour, Hamideh; Slater, Donna; Breitkreuz, Rhonda; Sakaluk-Moody, Laurel; Lynch, Sue; Hanson, Tara, 2016, "The 2nd Provincial Benchmark Survey 2013: What Albertans Know About Child Development", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10812, UAL Dataverse, V3</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>The 2nd Provincial Benchmark Survey 2013: What Albertans Know About Child Development</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10812</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="PolicyWise for Children &amp; Families">Botey, Anna</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Tough, Suzanne</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Bukutu, Cecilia</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Vinturache, Angela</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Gibbard, Ben</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="Alberta Health Services">MacLellan, Kathryn</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Bayrampour, Hamideh</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Calgary">Slater, Donna</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Breitkreuz, Rhonda</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Sakaluk-Moody, Laurel</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">Lynch, Sue</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="PolicyWise for Children &amp; Families">Hanson, Tara</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta" abbr="PRL" URI="http://www.prl.ualberta.ca/">Population Research Lab</producer><prodDate>2013</prodDate><prodPlac>Edmonton, Alberta</prodPlac><software>SPSS</software></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="Alberta Centre for Child, Family and Community Research" abbr="SAGE" URI="http://www.policywise.com/initiatives/sage">Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence</distrbtr><contact affiliation="Alberta Centre for Child, Family and Community Research" email="data@policywise.com">Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence (SAGE)</contact><distDate>2016-06</distDate><depDate>2016-06-09</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>Child Development</keyword><keyword>Parent education</keyword><keyword>Parenting</keyword></subject><abstract>The 2nd Provincial Benchmark Survey 2013: What Albertans Know About Child Development is a computer-assisted telephone survey of Alberta adults conducted in 2013 that aimed to learn what adults in Alber&#xd;
ta know about children's developmental stages and strategies to support optimal child development, as well as to discover more about adults' beliefs about childcare and children's issues, including the availability of programs and resources. It is a follow up of the 2008 Benchmark Survey (doi:10.7939/DVN/10810), providing both an update/refresh of previous findings and the opportunity to ask additional questions. The original survey in 2008 was adapted from "What Grown-Ups Know About Child Development: A National Benchmark Study". Not all questions in the 2008 survey were repeated in this 2013 survey, and many more questions were added.  Participants were individuals who at the time of the survey were 18 years of age or older and residents of Alberta, who could be contacted by direct dialing of residential numbers, and who had had interaction with a child under the age of 14 years in the past 6 months.  Subjects areas covered include:&lt;br>1. Understanding of child development &lt;br>2. Opinions about child-related issues such as breastfeeding and child care &lt;br>3. Use of parenting supports &lt;br>4. Parenting confidence &lt;br>5. Children's physical activity, sedentary behaviour and sleep habits &lt;br>6. Child care use&#xd;
&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;strong>These metadata are also available through SAGE's searchable metadata website:&lt;br>&#xd;
http://sagemetadata.policywise.com/nada/index.php/catalog/6&lt;/strong></abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2013">2013</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2013">2013</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2013-03-26">2013-03-26</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2013-05-27">2013-05-27</collDate><dataKind>Survey</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Calgary, Alberta; Edmonton, Alberta; Rest of Alberta</geogCover><anlyUnit>Individual</anlyUnit><universe>Albertans 18 years or older who had interaction with a child under the age of 14 years in the past 6 months</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>Cross-sectional</timeMeth><dataCollector>Population Research Lab</dataCollector><sampProc>Random digit dialing was used to contact households. A 3:1 (female:male) gender quota was enforced; at least 50% of respondents were to be non-parents. A minimum of 400 respondents had to be from the city of Calgary; 400 from the city of Edmonton, and the balance across the rest of Alberta.   Within the household, one eligible person was selected as the respondent, based on the following selection guidelines: 1. The respondent must be 18 years of age or older and a resident of Alberta; 2. The respondent must have had interaction with a child under 14 years of age in the past six months; 3. If there is more than one eligible respondent in the home when the interviewer calls, the person with the most recent birthday was interviewed; 4. If the quota was full for a given gender the interviewer asked for the qualifying person in the household of the opposite gender, with the most recent birthday</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Computer-assisted telephone survey</collMode><resInstru>Structured</resInstru><weight>No weighting used</weight><cleanOps>The data were checked for missing values, labels and inconsistencies. Data cleaning included wildcode, discrepant value and consistency checks.</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo><respRate>25.2%</respRate><dataAppr>Survey took, on average, 31 minutes to complete (excluding introductory and screening questions)</dataAppr></anlyInfo></method><dataAccs><notes type="DVN:TOA" level="dv">We are accepting proposals for our 2018 Secondary Data Use Grant starting February 20, 2018. This grant provides $5,000 to successful applicants to undertake research using data in SAGE. The term of the grant is 12 months. The grant offers an excellent opportunity for trainees and new researchers to work with existing birth cohort and survey data. Deadline for applications is April 27, 2018 at 4:00 PM MST.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
https://policywise.com/initiatives/sage/secondary-data-use-grant/&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
No special access conditions or procedures beyond the standard SAGE data access protocol. See: https://policywise.com/initiatives/sage/accessing-data/</notes><setAvail><accsPlac>Secondary Analysis to Generate Evidence (SAGE)</accsPlac><avlStatus>Available for re-use</avlStatus><collSize>1</collSize></setAvail><useStmt><confDec>Yes, a confidentiality declaration is signed as part of the SAGE data access agreement</confDec><restrctn>This dataset is subject to Level 2 access at SAGE (access using Analytic Environment)</restrctn><citReq>-Data must be cited in any publication or report using study bibliographic citation; -Data producer(s) must receive co-authorship on any publication or report where scientifically appropriate; -The following acknowledgement is required in all manuscripts: “We are extremely grateful to all the participants who took part in this study and the whole Benchmark&#xd;
team investigators, and the Research Population Laboratory. The Alberta Centre for Child, Family and Community Research undertook the study with funds provided by Ministry of Heath of the Government of Alberta.” -The logos of ACCFCR and the Government of Alberta Ministry of Health must be included in conjunction with the acknowledgement statement</citReq><conditions>No special access conditions or procedures beyond the standard SAGE data access protocol</conditions></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relMat>1. Yankelvich, D. (2000). What grown-ups understand about child development: A national benchmark survey. CIVITIS Initiative, Zero to Three, Brio, Researched by DYG.  2. Rikhy, S., Tough, S., Trute, B., Benzies, K., Kehler, H.,&#xd;
&amp; Johnston, D. W. (2010). Gauging knowledge of developmental milestones among Albertan adults: a cross-sectional survey. BMC public health, 10(1), 1.  3. Botey, A. P., Gibbard, W. B., MacLellan, K., Bukutu, C., Bayrampour, H., Vinturache, A., ... &amp; Tough, S. (2014). PS-250 What Adults Know About Child Development In Alberta, Canada: Implications For Health Services. Archives of Disease in Childhood, 99(Suppl 2), A203-A203.  4. Pujadas Botey, A., Bukutu, C., Vinturache, A., Gibbard, B., MacLellan&#xd;
, K., Bayrampour, H., Slater, D., Breitkreuz, R., Sakaluk-Moody, L., Lynch, S., Hanson, T.&#xd;
&amp; Tough, S. 2014. What Albertans Know About Child Development: A Comparison of the Provincial Benchmark Surveys 2007 and 2013. Technical Report. Calgary: Alberta Centre for Child, Family and Community Research.</relMat><relStdy>Rikhy, Shivani; Tough, Suzanne; Trute, Barry; Benzies, Karen; Davey, Heather; Johnston, David W., 2008, 'Alberta Benchmark Survey: What Adults Know About Child Development', http://dx.doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10810, Alberta Centre for Child, Family and Community Research, v 1.0</relStdy></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f6825" URI="https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10812/56Z716" level="datafile"><labl>Full_metadata_Benchmark2013.pdf</labl><txt>Contains the full metadata listing for the 2nd Provincial Benchmark (Benchmark 2013) survey. Includes element level metadata</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>