<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10910</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2016-10-21</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2017-05-29" type="RELEASED">3</version></verStmt><biblCit>MacLean, Joanna; Tan, Sara; Fitzgerald, Dominic; Waters, Karen, 2016, "Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10910, UAL Dataverse, V3</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10910</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Alberta">MacLean, Joanna</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Sydney">Tan, Sara</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Sydney">Fitzgerald, Dominic</AuthEnty><AuthEnty affiliation="University of Sydney">Waters, Karen</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta">MacLean, Joanna</producer><prodDate>2007</prodDate><prodPlac>Westmead, New South Wales, Australia</prodPlac><software>SPSS</software><software>Microsoft Access</software><software version="9">Sandman Digital 32+ Amplifier and Elite Sleep Diagnostic Software</software><software version="9">LabChart</software></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="joanna.maclean@ualberta.ca">MacLean, Joanna</contact></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</keyword><keyword>oxygen desaturation</keyword><keyword>intermittent hypoxia</keyword><keyword>minute ventilation</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">infant</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">cohort studies</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">pediatrics</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">cleft palate</keyword><keyword vocab="MeSH" vocabURI="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/">cleft lip</keyword><keyword>hypoxic ventilatory response</keyword></subject><abstract>The objective of this study was to determine the impact of sleep disordered breathing (SDB) in early infancy on ventilatory response in infants. We recruited consecutive infants with cleft lip and/or palate (CL/P) to undergo ventilatory response testing using exposure to a hypoxic (15% O(2) ) gas mixture during sleep. This population is at high risk of SDB because of smaller airway caliber and abnormal palatal muscle attachments predisposing them to airway obstruction of ranging severity from birth.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2007-08">2007-08</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2009-02">2009-02</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2007-08">2007-08</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2009-02">2009-02</collDate><dataKind>Questionnaire data; Clinical data; Anthropometric data; Physical measurements; Physiological measurements; Experimental data</dataKind><nation>Australia</nation><geogCover>Westmead</geogCover><geogCover>New South Wales</geogCover><anlyUnit>Individuals</anlyUnit><universe>Newborn infants with cleft lip and/or palate (CL/P).</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><frequenc>Data was collected at one time point.</frequenc><sampProc>The target subject number was 20. It was chosen based on the number of subjects in previous studies in this area, as the absence of an estimated effect size precluded sample size calculations. The actual sample size was 22. The sample was chosen through consecutive screening and enrollment; all families with infants born with (CL/P) at the Children's Hospital at Westmead during the time of the study were approached to participate</sampProc><targetSampleSize><sampleSize>22</sampleSize></targetSampleSize><sources><dataSrc>American Academy of Sleep Medicine respiratory rules for children; Hypoxia Protocol, described in  Parslow PM, Harding R, Cranage SM, Adamson TM, Horne RS. Ventilatory responses preceding hypoxia-induced arousal in infants: effects of sleep-state. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 2003; 136: 235- 247.</dataSrc></sources><collMode>Face-to-face interview; Telephone interview; Self-administered questionnaire: Paper; Experiment; Recording; Physical measurements and tests; Chart review</collMode><actMin>Standardized data collection forms were used. In the event of missing data, the PI followed up with families.</actMin><conOps>There were standard operating procedures (SOPs) in place for the sleep study and  ventilatory control measures.</conOps><cleanOps>Physiological data was reviewed for outliers.  Individual breaths with tidal volume (VT), respiratory rate (RR) or minute ventilation (VE) that lay outside the 95% confidence interval for all infants were removed as outliers; 99.7% of all measured breaths were included in the final analyses.</cleanOps></dataColl><anlyInfo><dataAppr>The same person collected all the data. The study involved close contact with the infants and thus could not be blinded.</dataAppr></anlyInfo></method><dataAccs><setAvail/><useStmt><conditions>Access to deidentified data may be permitted for external researchers, with limitations. Only researchers with REB-approved projects may be permitted access to the deidentified data. The data producer determines access on a case-by-case basis. Contact the data producer directly to discuss terms and conditions of access.</conditions></useStmt></dataAccs><othrStdyMat><relMat>MacLean JE, Fitzgerald DA, Hayward P, Waters KA.  Cleft lip and/or palate and breathing during sleep.  Sleep Medicine Reviews 2009; 13: 345-354</relMat><relMat>MacLean JE, Fitzsimons D, Fitzgerald DA, Waters KA. The spectrum of sleep-disordered breathing symptoms and respiratory events in infants with cleft lip and/or palate. Archives of Disease in Childhood 2012; 97: 1058-63</relMat><relMat>Smith CB, Walker K, Badawi N, Waters KA, MacLean JE. Impact of sleep and breathing in infancy on outcomes at 3 years of age for children with cleft lip and/or palate. Sleep. 2014; 37: 919-25</relMat><relPubl><citation><titlStmt><IDNo agency="doi">10.1002/ppul.22568</IDNo></titlStmt><biblCit>MacLean, JE, Tan, S, Fitzgerald, DA and Waters, KA (2013), Assessing ventilatory control in infants at high risk of sleep disordered breathing: A study of infants with cleft lip and/or palate. Pediatric Pulmonology, 48: 265-273.</biblCit></citation><ExtLink URI="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ppul.22568/abstract"/></relPubl></othrStdyMat></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f6828" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6828" level="datafile"><labl>MacLean_Vent_Control_consent_form_v2.pdf</labl><txt>Consent form for Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6829" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6829" level="datafile"><labl>MacLean_Vent_Control_detailed protocol.pdf</labl><txt>Detailed study protocol for Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6831" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6831" level="datafile"><labl>MacLean_Vent_Control_enrolment_form.doc</labl><txt>Blank enrollment form for Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6827" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6827" level="datafile"><labl>MacLean_Vent_Control medical_review_form.doc</labl><txt>Blank medical review form used by mothers who participated in Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate. </txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/msword</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f6830" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/6830" level="datafile"><labl>MacLean_Vent_Control_parent_information_sheet_control.pdf</labl><txt>Parent information sheet for the control group participating in Assessing Ventilatory Control in Infants at High Risk of Sleep Disordered Breathing: A Study of Infants with Cleft Lip and/or Palate.</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>