<codeBook xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 https://ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5"><docDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 2005</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10571</IDNo></titlStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distDate>2015-09-09</distDate></distStmt><verStmt source="DVN"><version date="2018-03-02" type="RELEASED">4</version></verStmt><biblCit>Population Research Laboratory, 2015, "Alberta Survey, 2005", https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10571, UAL Dataverse, V4</biblCit></citation></docDscr><stdyDscr><citation><titlStmt><titl>Alberta Survey, 2005</titl><IDNo agency="DOI">doi:10.7939/DVN/10571</IDNo><IDNo>aas2005</IDNo></titlStmt><rspStmt><AuthEnty affiliation="Department of Sociology, University of Alberta">Population Research Laboratory</AuthEnty></rspStmt><prodStmt><producer affiliation="University of Alberta" abbr="PRL">Population Research Laboratory</producer><prodDate>2005-06</prodDate></prodStmt><distStmt><distrbtr source="archive">UAL Dataverse</distrbtr><distrbtr affiliation="University of Alberta Libraries" abbr="DI" URI="https://www.library.ualberta.ca/digital-initiatives">Digital Initiatives </distrbtr><contact affiliation="University of Alberta" email="data@ualberta.ca">Digital Initiatives </contact><distDate>2005-06</distDate><depDate>2015-09-09</depDate></distStmt></citation><stdyInfo><subject><keyword>Arts and Humanities</keyword><keyword>Social Sciences</keyword><keyword>physical activity</keyword><keyword>demographics</keyword><keyword>personal injury</keyword><keyword>injury issues</keyword><keyword>environmental health risks</keyword><keyword>continuing care</keyword><keyword>AADAC</keyword><keyword>emergency vehicles</keyword><keyword>science education</keyword><keyword>reading</keyword><keyword>paid employment and parenting</keyword><keyword>same sex marriage</keyword><topcClas>Public opinion -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Social surveys -- Alberta</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Social conditions -- Statistics</topcClas><topcClas>Alberta -- Economic conditions -- Statistics</topcClas></subject><abstract date="2005-06">The 2005 Alberta Survey (AS) was the 18th annual provincial survey administered by the Population Research Laboratory (PRL). This omnibus survey of households in the province of Alberta continues to enable academic researchers, government departments, and non-profit organizations to explore a wide range of research topics in a structured research framework and environment.</abstract><sumDscr><timePrd cycle="P1" event="start" date="2005-03">2005-03</timePrd><timePrd cycle="P1" event="end" date="2005-05">2005-05</timePrd><collDate cycle="P1" event="start" date="2005-03-03">2005-03-03</collDate><collDate cycle="P1" event="end" date="2005-05-17">2005-05-17</collDate><dataKind>Microdata</dataKind><nation>Canada</nation><geogCover>Alberta</geogCover><geogUnit>Province</geogUnit><anlyUnit>Individual</anlyUnit><universe>The target participant population for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be contacted by direct dialling. From this population, three samples were drawn to cover Alberta, including Edmonton metropolitan area, Calgary metropolitan area, and the rest of the province.</universe></sumDscr></stdyInfo><method><dataColl><timeMeth>Cross-sectional.</timeMeth><sampProc>SAMPLING DESIGN Main Features of Design: a. The province of Alberta was delineated into three areas for telephone interviewing, as follows: (1) Edmonton Metropolitan Area (2) Calgary Metropolitan Area (3) Remainder of the Province (Other Alberta). b. Two-stage selection process (1) Selection of households (2) Selection of respondent within each household. To permit the analysis of each area as a separate entity, a minimum sample size of 400 or more  for each area of the province was instituted. The target participant population for telephone interviewing was all persons 18 years of age or  older who, at the time of the survey, were living in a dwelling unit in Alberta that could be  contacted by direct dialling. From this population, three samples were drawn to cover Alberta,  including Edmonton metropolitan area, Calgary metropolitan area, and the rest of the province. A Random-Digit Dialling approach was used to ensure that respondents had an equal chance to  be contacted whether or not their household was listed in a telephone directory. The PRL has  developed a database of five-digit telephone banks (e.g. 403/780-xxx-xx) covering all of Alberta.  The 2005 Alberta Survey sample was drawn from this provincial database by using a computer  program to select a simple random sample of number banks for each area, and appending a  random number between 00 and 99 to each number selected. Duplicate telephone numbers were  purged from the computer-generated list. Within the household, one eligible person was selected  as the respondent. The mean length of the interview in the 2005 survey was 35.2 minutes. A respondent within each household was selected on the basis of gender using the following  selection guidelines to ensure an equal selection of male and female participants. a. He/she must be 18 years of age or older. b. If an adult male answers the phone and is willing to be interviewed, he is the respondent. c. If an adult female answers the phone and there is an adult male present who is willing to  be interviewed, interview the male. If the male is not willing to be interviewed, and the  female is willing, interview the female. d. If an adult female answers the phone and there is no adult male present, choose her as the  respondent.</sampProc><sources/><collMode>Telephone interviews.</collMode><weight>The weighting factors used for the 2005 survey are as follows: Edmonton Metropolitan 0.949299, Calgary Metropolitan 0.991455, and Other Alberta 1.059497.</weight></dataColl><anlyInfo/></method><dataAccs><setAvail/><useStmt/></dataAccs><othrStdyMat/></stdyDscr><otherMat ID="f4828" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4828" level="datafile"><labl>2005AlbertaSurvey_Codebook.pdf</labl><txt>Questionnaire and Codebook</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4830" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4830" level="datafile"><labl>2005AlbertaSurvey_Data.tab</labl><txt>Data File</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">text/tab-separated-values</notes></otherMat><otherMat ID="f4829" URI="https://dataverse.library.ualberta.ca/api/access/datafile/4829" level="datafile"><labl>2005AlbertaSurvey_SamplingReport.pdf</labl><txt>Methodology Report</txt><notes level="file" type="DATAVERSE:CONTENTTYPE" subject="Content/MIME Type">application/pdf</notes></otherMat></codeBook>