<record><leader>07248nam a2200529oi 4500</leader><controlfield tag="001">6802755</controlfield><controlfield tag="003">CaONFJC</controlfield><controlfield tag="005">20150205153842.0</controlfield><controlfield tag="006">m        d        </controlfield><controlfield tag="007">cr||n|||||||||</controlfield><controlfield tag="008">140425s2015    nju     ob    001 0 eng d</controlfield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">9781118859711</subfield><subfield code="q">pdf</subfield><subfield code="q">electronic bk.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">1118859715</subfield><subfield code="q">pdf</subfield><subfield code="q">electronic bk.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">9781118859780</subfield><subfield code="q">epub</subfield><subfield code="q">electronic bk.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">1118859782</subfield><subfield code="q">epub</subfield><subfield code="q">electronic bk.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">9781118859766</subfield><subfield code="q">paperback</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">9781322349084 (MyiLibrary)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="037"><subfield code="a">666190</subfield><subfield code="b">MIL</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039"><subfield code="a">exclude</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040"><subfield code="a">CaONFJC</subfield><subfield code="c">CaONFJC</subfield><subfield code="e">rda</subfield><subfield code="d">AEU</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2="4" tag="050"><subfield code="a">HV40</subfield><subfield code="b">.L284 2015eb</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="072"><subfield code="a">POL</subfield><subfield code="x">019000</subfield><subfield code="2">bisacsh</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="072"><subfield code="a">SOC</subfield><subfield code="x">016000</subfield><subfield code="2">bisacsh</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="4" tag="082"><subfield code="a">361.3/2</subfield><subfield code="2">23</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="084"><subfield code="a">SOC025000</subfield><subfield code="2">bisacsh</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090"><subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield><subfield code="b">AEGMCT</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="091"><subfield code="a">DO NOT ADD TO THIS RECORD - PSA PROJECT</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100"><subfield code="a">Langer, Carol L.,</subfield><subfield code="e">author.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245"><subfield code="a">Applying theory to generalist social work practice</subfield><subfield code="h">[electronic resource] :</subfield><subfield code="b">a case study approach /</subfield><subfield code="c">Carol L. Langer, Cynthia A. Lietz.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264"><subfield code="a">Hoboken, New Jersey :</subfield><subfield code="b">John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.,</subfield><subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300"><subfield code="a">1 online resource.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336"><subfield code="a">text</subfield><subfield code="b">txt</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337"><subfield code="a">computer</subfield><subfield code="b">c</subfield><subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338"><subfield code="a">online resource</subfield><subfield code="b">cr</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500"><subfield code="a">Machine generated contents note:  CHAPTER 1: The Role of Theories in Social Work Practice Introduction What is Theory? The Relevance of Studying Theory for Aspiring Social Workers Case Example Evidence-Based Practice Further Debates Theoretical Integration Common Elements Implementation of Theory: The Role of Microskills Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 2: Ecological and Systems Theories Introduction A Historical Discussion of Ecological and Systems Theories Ecological and Systems Theories: Theoretical Principles Ecological and Systems Theories: Key Concepts Application of Ecological and Systems Theories within Social Work Practice Case Example Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations of Ecological and Systems Theories Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 3: The Strengths Perspective Introduction A Social Work History Lesson Limitations of the Medical Model Moving Toward a Strengths Perspective The Strengths Perspective: Key Concepts The Strengths Perspective: Principles Application of the Strengths Perspective within Social Work Practice Case Example Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Limitations of the Strengths Perspective Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 4: The Task-Centered Model Introduction Historical Development Theoretical Assumptions The Task-Centered Model and the Helping Process Applicability of Task-Centered Work Compatibility with Social Work Values and Ethics, Systems and Strengths Perspectives Case Example Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 5: Conflict Theory Introduction Historical Development of Conflict Theory Dialectical Materialism Macro Case Example Mezzo Case Example Application of Conflict Theory to Social Work Practice Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations of Conflict Theory Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 6: Humanism and Client-Centered Theory Introduction A Historical Discussion of Client-Centered Theory Key concepts Theoretical Principles Stories from the Field Application of Client-Centered Theory within Social Work Practice Case Example Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations of Humanism Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 7: Cognitive and Behavioral Theories Introduction A Historical Discussion of Behaviorism and Cognitive Theory Key Concepts Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Application of CBT within social work practice Stories from the Field Case Example Student Application of Skills Stenghts and Limitations of Cognitive and Behavioral Theories Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 8: Empowerment Theory Introduction A Historical discussion of Empowerment theory Development of Empowerment in Social Work Theoretical principles Application of empowerment theory within Social Work Practice Case example Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strenghts and Limitations of Empowerment Theory Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 9: Narrative Theory Introduction A Historical Discussion of Narrative Theory Narrative Theory: Theoretical Assumptions Narrative Theory: Key Concepts Application of Narrative Theory within Social Work Practice Case Example Stories from the Field Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations of Narrative Theory Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 10: Solution-Focused Brief Therapy Introduction Theoretical Assumptions of SFBT Historical Development Use of the SFBT in the Helping Process Case Example Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations of the Solution-Focused Model Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 11: Crisis Theory Introduction A Brief History of Crisis Theory Levels of Crisis Stages of Experiencing and Resolving a Crisis Case Example Critical Necessities of Each Stage The Critical Incident Stress Debriefing and Management Protocol Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations of Crisis Theory Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 12: Feminist and Critical Theories Andrea N. Cimino, MSW, PhD Introduction Historical Foundation and Overview of Critical Theory Theoretical Principles of Critical Theory Historial Foundation and Overview of Feminist Theory Theoretical Principles of Feminist Theory Similarities and Differences Key Concepts Principles of Feminist and Critical Theory within Social Work Practice Case Example Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and limitations of Feminist and Critical Theory Approaches Conclusion Resources for Students References Chapter 13: Transtheoretical Model Introduction A HistoricalDiscussion of TTM Key Concepts Theoretical Principles Stages of Change Motivational Interviewing Application of TTM Within Social Work Practice Case Example Stories from the Field Student Application of Skills Strengths and Limitations of TTM and Motivational Interviewing Conclusion Resources for Students References CHAPTER 14: Theory and Practice: Pulling it all Together.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504"><subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references and indexes.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="506"><subfield code="a">Access restricted to authorized users and institutions.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="588"><subfield code="a">Description based on print version record.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596"><subfield code="a">57</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Social service</subfield><subfield code="v">Case studies.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Social case work</subfield><subfield code="v">Case studies.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Social service.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Social case work.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700"><subfield code="a">Lietz, Cynthia A.,</subfield><subfield code="e">author.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="856"><subfield code="3">MacEwan University Access</subfield><subfield code="u">http://lib.myilibrary.com/detail.asp?ID=666190</subfield><subfield code="z">(Single User Access)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949"><subfield code="w">ORDER</subfield><subfield code="h">UAIN</subfield><subfield code="m">GR_MAC_INT</subfield><subfield code="z">MILGMPSA</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926"><subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield><subfield code="w">ORDER</subfield><subfield code="c">1</subfield><subfield code="i">6802755-1001</subfield><subfield code="l">INTERNET</subfield><subfield code="m">GR_MAC_INT</subfield><subfield code="r">Y</subfield><subfield code="s">Y</subfield><subfield code="t">E-RESOURCE</subfield><subfield code="u">2/11/2015</subfield><subfield code="x">E-BOOK</subfield><subfield code="z">MILGMPSA</subfield></datafield></record>