<record><leader>08055cam a2200433 i 4500</leader><controlfield tag="001">6697679</controlfield><controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield><controlfield tag="005">20140911131618.0</controlfield><controlfield tag="008">131024t20152015at a          001 0 eng d</controlfield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="010"><subfield code="a">  2013947483</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="015"><subfield code="a">GBB3A5842</subfield><subfield code="2">bnb</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="7" ind2=" " tag="016"><subfield code="a">016547454</subfield><subfield code="2">Uk</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">9781111540913 (pbk.)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">1111540918 (pbk.)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035"><subfield code="a">ocn864086562</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040"><subfield code="a">UKMGB</subfield><subfield code="b">eng</subfield><subfield code="c">UKMGB</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCO</subfield><subfield code="d">YDXCP</subfield><subfield code="d">BTCTA</subfield><subfield code="d">EEK</subfield><subfield code="d">LTSCA</subfield><subfield code="d">DLC</subfield><subfield code="d">VET</subfield><subfield code="e">rda</subfield><subfield code="d">EDK</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCF</subfield><subfield code="d">UAB</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="050"><subfield code="a">RS57</subfield><subfield code="b">.C87 2015</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="4" tag="082"><subfield code="a">615.1401513</subfield><subfield code="2">23</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090"><subfield code="a">RS 57 C877 2015</subfield><subfield code="b">AEU</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100"><subfield code="a">Curren, Anna M.,</subfield><subfield code="e">author.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245"><subfield code="a">Curren's math for meds :</subfield><subfield code="b">dosages &amp; solutions /</subfield><subfield code="c">Anna M. Curren, Margaret H. Witt.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="3" ind2=" " tag="246"><subfield code="a">Math for meds</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="250"><subfield code="a">Eleventh edition.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264"><subfield code="a">Australia :</subfield><subfield code="b">Cengage Learning,</subfield><subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="264"><subfield code="c">&#169;2015</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300"><subfield code="a">xxii, 359 pages :</subfield><subfield code="b">color illustrations ;</subfield><subfield code="c">28 cm.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336"><subfield code="a">still image</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336"><subfield code="a">text</subfield><subfield code="b">txt</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337"><subfield code="a">unmediated</subfield><subfield code="b">n</subfield><subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338"><subfield code="a">volume</subfield><subfield code="b">nc</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500"><subfield code="a">Includes index.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Preface -- Introduction for the learner -- Introduction for the instructor -- Using the learning package -- Using the online student practice software -- Letter from the author -- Honorarium -- Refresher math pretest -- Section 1: Refresher Math: -- Relative value, addition, and subtraction of decimals: -- Relative value of decimals -- Addition and subtraction of decimals -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Multiplication and division of decimals: -- Multiplication of decimals -- Division of decimal fractions -- Elimination of decimal points -- Reduction of fractions -- Reduction of numbers ending in zero -- Using a calculator -- Expressing to the nearest tenth -- Expressing to the nearest hundredth -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Solving common fraction equations: -- Whole-number equations -- Decimal fraction equations -- Multiple-number equations -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Section 2: Introduction To Drug Measures: -- Metric/international (SI) system: -- Basic units of the metric/SI system -- Metric/SI prefixes -- Metric/SI abbreviations -- Metric/SI notation rules -- Conversion between metric/SI units -- Common errors in metric/SI dosages -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Unit, percentage, Milliequivalents, ratio, and household measures: -- International units (units) -- Percentage (%) measures -- Milliequivalents (mEq) measures -- Ratio measures -- Household measures -- Apothecary measures -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Section 3: Reading Medication Labels And Syringe Calibrations: -- Oral medication labels and dosage calculation: -- Tablet and capsule labels -- Tablet/capsule dosage calculation -- Oral solution labels -- Measurement of oral solutions -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Safe medication administration: -- Medication administration records -- Six rights of medication administration -- Seventh right: partnering with the patient -- Common medication errors -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Hypodermic syringe measurement: -- Standard 3 mL syringe -- Safety syringes -- Tuberculin (TB) syringe -- 5 and 10 mL syringes -- 20 mL and larger syringes -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Parenteral medication labels and dosage calculation: -- Reading metric/SI solution labels -- Percent (%) and ratio solution labels -- Solutions measured in international units -- Solutions measured as Milliequivalents (mEq) -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Reconstitution of powdered drugs: -- Reconstitution of a single-strength solution -- Reconstitution from package insert directions -- Reconstitution of multiple-strength solutions -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Measuring insulin dosages: -- Types of insulin -- Insulin vial and insulin injection pen label identification -- Insulin syringes -- Combining insulin dosages -- Insulin action times -- Insulin injection sites and techniques -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Section 4: Dosage Calculations: -- Ratio and proportion: -- Ratios -- Ratio and proportion expressed using common fractions -- Dosage calculation using ratio and proportion expressed as common fractions -- Ratio and proportion expressed using colons -- Dosage calculation using ratio and proportion expressed with colons -- Calculations when dosages are in different units of measure -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Dimensional analysis/units conversion: -- Clinical ratios -- Basic DA equation -- Equations requiring metric conversions -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Formula method: -- Basic formula -- Use with metric conversions -- Use with units and mEq calculations -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Section 5: Dosage Calculation From Body Weight And Body Surface Area: -- Adult and pediatric dosages based on body weight: Converting lb to kg -- Converting kg to lb -- Calculating dosages from drug label information -- Calculating dosages from drug literature -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Adult and pediatric dosages based on body surface area: -- Calculating BSA from kg to cm -- Calculating BSA from lb and in -- Dosage calculation based on BSA -- Assessing orders based on BSA -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Section 6: Intravenous Calculations: -- Introduction to IV therapy : Primary line -- Secondary line -- Volume-controlled burettes -- Indwelling infusion ports/intermittent locks -- Volumetric pumps -- Syringe pumps -- Patient-controlled analgesia (PCA) devices -- Introduction to IV fluids -- Percentages in IV fluids -- Parenteral nutrition -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- IV flow rate calculation: -- IV tubing calibration -- Using ratio and proportion to calculate gtt/min flow rates -- Using dimensional analysis to calculate gtt/min flow rates -- Formula and division factor methods of flow rate calculation -- Division factor method -- Regulating flow rate -- Correcting off-schedule rates -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Calculating IV infusion and completion times: -- Calculating infusion time from mL/hr ordered -- Calculating infusion completion times -- International/military time calculations -- Standard time calculations -- Labeling solution bags with infusion and completion times -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- IV medication and titration calculations: -- Using ratio and proportion to calculate mL/hr rate for dosage ordered -- Using ratio and proportion to calculate mL/hr rate for dosage per kg ordered -- Using ratio and proportion to calculate infusion titrations -- Using dimensional analysis to calculate mL/hr rate for dosage ordered -- Using dimensional analysis to calculate mL/hr rate for dosage per kg ordered -- Using dimensional analysis to calculate infusion titrations -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Heparin infusion calculations: -- Heparin IV and vial labels -- Calculating mL/hr IV flow rate from units/hr ordered -- Calculation using ratio and proportion -- Calculation using dimensional analysis -- Calculating units/jr infusing from mL/hr flow rate -- Calculation using ratio and proportion -- Calculation using dimensional analysis -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Section 7: Pediatric Medication Calculations: -- Pediatric oral and parenteral medications: -- Oral medications -- Intramuscular and subcutaneous medications -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Pediatric intravenous medications: -- Methods of IV medication administration -- Medication administration via burette -- Using dimensional analysis -- Comparing IV dosages ordered with average dosages -- Summary -- Summary self-test -- Appendix A: Apothecary measures -- Appendix B: ISMP's list of error-prone abbreviations, symbols, and dose designations -- Index.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596"><subfield code="a">42</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Pharmaceutical arithmetic.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Drugs</subfield><subfield code="x">Dosage.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="2" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Drug Dosage Calculations.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700"><subfield code="a">Witt, Margaret H.,</subfield><subfield code="e">author.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949"><subfield code="a">RS 57 C877 2015</subfield><subfield code="c">1</subfield><subfield code="h">UAHL-B</subfield><subfield code="i">0162035161593</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926"><subfield code="a">RS 57 C877 2015</subfield><subfield code="w">LC</subfield><subfield code="c">1</subfield><subfield code="i">0162035161593</subfield><subfield code="d">12/22/2016</subfield><subfield code="e">11/18/2016</subfield><subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield><subfield code="m">UAHLTHSC</subfield><subfield code="n">5</subfield><subfield code="p">$150.00</subfield><subfield code="r">Y</subfield><subfield code="s">Y</subfield><subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield><subfield code="u">9/25/2014</subfield></datafield></record>