<record><leader>06369nam a2200409 i 4500</leader><controlfield tag="001">6786185</controlfield><controlfield tag="003">FlBoTFG</controlfield><controlfield tag="005">20150115163112.0</controlfield><controlfield tag="006">m|||||o||d||||||||</controlfield><controlfield tag="007">cr||||</controlfield><controlfield tag="008">150115t20152015fluad   ob    001 0 eng d</controlfield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">9781466551121 (e-book : PDF)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035"><subfield code="a">ocn895660970</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039"><subfield code="a">exclude</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040"><subfield code="a">FlBoTFG</subfield><subfield code="b">eng</subfield><subfield code="e">rda</subfield><subfield code="c">FlBoTFG</subfield><subfield code="d">AEU</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="050"><subfield code="a">RD118</subfield><subfield code="b">.I43 2015</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090"><subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield><subfield code="b">AEU</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245"><subfield code="a">Imaging for plastic surgery /</subfield><subfield code="c">edited by Luca Saba, Warren M. Rozen, Alberto Alonso-Burgos, Diego Ribuffo.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264"><subfield code="a">Boca Raton, FL :</subfield><subfield code="b">CRC Press :</subfield><subfield code="b">Taylor &amp; Francis Group,</subfield><subfield code="c">2015.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="264"><subfield code="c">&#169;2015</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300"><subfield code="a">1 online resource.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336"><subfield code="a">text</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337"><subfield code="a">computer</subfield><subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338"><subfield code="a">online resource</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504"><subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references and index.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Computed tomography / Michele Anzidei [and four others] -- MRI physics principles / Marta Tom&#225;s Mallebrera and &#193;ngeles Franco L&#243;pez -- Diagnostic ultrasound / Alberto Benito, David Cano, Mariana Elorz, and Pedro Slon -- Nuclear medicine / Alessandra Serra and Mario Piga -- Mammography / Luis Pina Insauti, Jon Etxano Cantera, Pedro Slon, and Arlette Elizalde -- PET-CT in oncology / Anna Margherita Maffione, Sotirios Chondrogiannis, Adriano Marcolongo, and Domenico Rubello -- Sentinel node biopsy : an evolution of the science and surgical principles / Ramin Shayan, Hayley Reynolds, Cara Michelle Le Roux, and Tara Karnezis -- Free flap revascularisation process / Emanuele Cigna [and four others] -- Application of virtual 3D plastic surgery / Alberto Alonso-Burgos, Vachara Niumsawatt, and Warren M. Rozen -- Digital thermographic photography for preoperative perforator mapping / Vachara Niumsawatt, Warren M. Rozen, and Iain S. Whitaker -- Stereotactic image-guided surgery / Vachara Niumsawatt [and four others] -- Lymphatics : anatomy, mapping, and evolving imaging technologies / Ramin Shayan, Iain S. Whitaker, Cara Michelle Le Roux, and Tara Karnezis -- Vascular anomalies in children : tumours and vascular malformations / Luigino Santecchia, Piergiorgio Falappa, and Mario Zama -- Imaging and surgical principles for maxillary reconstruction / Riccardo Cipriani [and five others] -- Imaging for jaw reconstruction / Wei F. Chen, Steven Lo, Anuja K. Antony, and Fu Chan Wei -- Imaging in surgical strategies for facial reconstruction / Francesco Stagno d'Alcontres [and five others] -- Imaging and surgical strategies for cutaneous neoplasm of the scalp / Luca Andrea Dessy [and five others] -- Surgical strategies and imaging for regional flaps in the head and neck / Gary Xia Vern Tan [and four others] -- Imaging for recipient vessels of the head and neck for microvascular transplantation / Gary Xia Vern Tan [and four others] -- Imaging and surgical principles for TRAM (pTRAM) flap / Diego Ribuffo, Matteo Atzeni, Maristella Guerra, and Luca Saba -- Angio-CT imaging of deep inferior epigastric artery and deep superior epigastric artery perforators / Vachara Niumsawatt [and five others] --</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">MR imaging of deep inferior epigastric artery and deep superior epigastric artery perforators / Vachara Niumsawatt, Alberto Alonso-Burgos, Iain S. Whitaker, and Warren M. Rozen -- Surgical principles of deep inferior epigastric artery and deep superior epigastric artery perforator flap / Vachara Niumsawatt, Mark W. Ashton, Warren M. Rozen, and Iain S. Whitaker -- Imaging and surgical principles of the superficial inferior epigastric artery flap / Mark Schaverien -- Surgical principles and breast imaging and monitoring after autologous fat transfer / Paolo Persichetti [and five others] -- Surgical principles and imaging of breast implants and their follow-up / Luca Andrea Dessy [and six others] -- Lymphatic imaging of the breast : evolving technologies and the future / Jaume Masia [and five others] -- Breast imaging for aesthetic and reconstructive plastic surgery / Jeremy Nickfarjam, Oren Tepper, and Nolan Karp -- Imaging for incisional median abdominal wall hernias / Pietro Giorgio Cal&#242; [and five others] -- Imaging and surgical principles of perforator flaps of the trunk / Michel Saint-Cyr -- Phalloplasty in female-to-male sex reassignment surgery / Zden&#283;k Dvo&#345;&#225;k and Ji&#345;&#237; Vesel&#253; -- Imaging and surgical principles of the gluteal arteries and perforator flaps / Julie Vasile, Maria M. Lotempio, and Robert J. Allen -- Imaging and surgical principles of anterolateral thigh perforator flap / Diego Ribuffo [and four others] -- Imaging and surgical principles of anteromedial thigh perforator flaps / Emanuele Cigna, Michele Maruccia, Alessandro Napoli, and Hung-Chi Chen -- Imaging and surgical principles for tensor fascia lata flap / &#214;mer &#214;zkan [and four others] -- Surgical principles of deep circumflex iliac artery / Warren M. Rozen [and five others] -- Imaging and surgical principles of the propeller and perforator flaps of the lower limb / Emanuele Cigna [and five others] -- Lymphoscintigraphy for extremities' oedemas and for sentinel lymph node mapping in cutaneous melanomas of the torso / Giuliano Mariani [and eight others] -- Nuclear medicine as an aid to minimally invasive surgery, with emphasis on hybrid SPECT/CT imaging / Federica Orsini, Alessandra Serra, Mario Piga, and Giuliano Mariani -- Preoperative imaging for reconstruction of the lower extremities / Hidehiko Yoshimatsu and Takumi Yamamoto -- Imaging and surgical principles in hand surgery / Giorgio Pajardi and Andrea Ghezzi -- Imaging and surgical principles of osteomyelitis and pressure ulcers / Bruno Carlesimo, Marco Ruggiero, Federico Lo Torto, and Marco Marcasciano -- Image guided 3D printing and haptic modelling in plastic surgery / Michael P. Chae, David J. Hunter-Smith, and Warren M. Rozen.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="506"><subfield code="a">Access restricted to authorized users and institutions.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596"><subfield code="a">44</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Surgery, Plastic.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700"><subfield code="a">Saba, Luca,</subfield><subfield code="e">editor.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700"><subfield code="a">Rozen, Warren M.,</subfield><subfield code="e">editor.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700"><subfield code="a">Alonso-Burgos, Alberto,</subfield><subfield code="e">editor.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700"><subfield code="a">Ribuffo, Diego,</subfield><subfield code="e">editor.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="856"><subfield code="3">University of Alberta Access</subfield><subfield code="u">http://marc.crcnetbase.com/isbn/9781466551121</subfield><subfield code="z">(Unlimited Concurrent Users)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949"><subfield code="h">UAIN</subfield><subfield code="z">CRC</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926"><subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield><subfield code="w">LC</subfield><subfield code="c">1</subfield><subfield code="i">6786185-1001</subfield><subfield code="l">INTERNET</subfield><subfield code="m">UAINTERNET</subfield><subfield code="r">Y</subfield><subfield code="s">Y</subfield><subfield code="t">E-RESOURCE</subfield><subfield code="u">1/20/2015</subfield><subfield code="x">E-BOOK</subfield><subfield code="z">CRC</subfield></datafield></record>