<record><leader>07972cam a2200505 i 4500</leader><controlfield tag="001">6785889</controlfield><controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield><controlfield tag="005">20150310165059.0</controlfield><controlfield tag="008">130910s2015    caua     b    001 0 eng  </controlfield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="010"><subfield code="a">  2013032636</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="015"><subfield code="a">GBB374237</subfield><subfield code="2">bnb</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="7" ind2=" " tag="016"><subfield code="a">016478181</subfield><subfield code="2">Uk</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">9781452203461 (pbk. : alk. paper)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="a">1452203466 (pbk. : alk. paper)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020"><subfield code="z">9781483300795 (web pdf)</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035"><subfield code="a">ocn856971351</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039"><subfield code="a">exclude</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040"><subfield code="a">DLC</subfield><subfield code="b">eng</subfield><subfield code="e">rda</subfield><subfield code="c">DLC</subfield><subfield code="d">BTCTA</subfield><subfield code="d">YDXCP</subfield><subfield code="d">AU@</subfield><subfield code="d">NGU</subfield><subfield code="d">CDX</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCO</subfield><subfield code="d">OCLCF</subfield><subfield code="d">UKMGB</subfield><subfield code="d">AEU</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="042"><subfield code="a">pcc</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="050"><subfield code="a">P301</subfield><subfield code="b">.B67 2015</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="082"><subfield code="a">808</subfield><subfield code="2">23</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090"><subfield code="a">P301 .B67 2015</subfield><subfield code="b">AEGMCT</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100"><subfield code="a">Brummett, Barry,</subfield><subfield code="d">1951-</subfield><subfield code="e">author.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245"><subfield code="a">Rhetoric in popular culture /</subfield><subfield code="c">Barry Brummett, The University of Texas at Austin.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="250"><subfield code="a">Fourth Edition.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264"><subfield code="a">Los Angeles :</subfield><subfield code="b">SAGE,</subfield><subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300"><subfield code="a">xvi, 323 pages :</subfield><subfield code="b">illustrations ;</subfield><subfield code="c">24 cm</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336"><subfield code="a">text</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337"><subfield code="a">unmediated</subfield><subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338"><subfield code="a">volume</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504"><subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references (pages 305-309) and index.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Machine generated contents note: pt. I THEORY -- 1.Rhetoric and the Rhetorical Tradition -- Definitions and the Management of Power -- The Rhetorical Tradition: Ancient Greece -- The Rise of the City-States: How Democracy Grew Up with Rhetoric -- Rhetoric in Athens -- Plato's Complaints against the Sophists -- Two Legacies We Have Inherited from the Greek Rhetorical Tradition -- Definitions of Rhetoric after Plato -- Rhetoric in the Eighteenth Century -- New Theories (and New Realities) Emerge in the Twentieth Century -- What Changed in the Twentieth Century and Beyond -- Managing Power Today in Traditional Texts: Neo-Aristotelian Criticism -- Summary and Review -- Looking Ahead -- 2.Rhetoric and Popular Culture -- The Rhetoric of Everyday Life -- The Building Blocks of Culture: Signs -- Indexical Meaning -- Iconic Meaning -- Symbolic Meaning -- Complexity of the Three Kinds of Meaning -- The Building Blocks of Culture: Artifacts --</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Contents note continued: An Action, Event, or Object Perceived as a Unified Whole -- ... Having Widely Shared Meanings -- ... Manifesting Group Identification to Us -- Definitions of Culture -- Elitist Meanings of Culture -- Popular Meanings of Culture -- Characteristics of Culture -- Cultures Are Highly Complex and Overlapping -- Cultures Entail Consciousness, or Ideologies -- Cultures Are Experienced through Texts -- Managing Power Today in Texts of Popular Culture -- Four Characteristics of the Texts of Popular Culture -- Summary and Review -- Looking Ahead -- 3.Rhetorical Methods in Critical Studies -- Texts as Sites of Struggle -- Texts Influence through Meanings -- Texts Are Sites of Struggle over Meaning -- Three Characteristics of Critical Studies -- The Critical Character -- Concern over Power -- Critical Interventionism -- Finding a Text -- The First Continuum: Type of Text -- The Second Continuum: Sources of Meanings -- Defining a Context --</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Contents note continued: The Third Continuum: Choice of Context -- The Fourth Continuum: Text-Context Relationship -- "Inside" the Text -- The Fifth Continuum: From Surface to Deep Reading -- The Text in Context: Metonymy, Power, Judgment -- Metonymies -- Empowerment/Dispowerment -- Judgment -- Summary and Review -- Looking Ahead -- 4.Varieties of Rhetorical Criticism: Intervention-Understanding -- An Introduction to Critical Perspectives -- Methods Focused on Power -- Culture-Centered Criticism -- Cultures and Their Own Critical Methods -- Afrocentricity -- Whiteness as a Kind of Culture: Analysis and Examples -- Marxist Criticism -- Materialism, Bases, and Superstructure -- Economic Metaphors, Commodities, and Signs -- Preferred and Oppositional Readings -- Subject Positions -- Standpoint Theory -- Feminist Criticism -- Varieties of Feminist Criticism -- How Do Patriarchal Language and Images Perpetuate Inequality? -- How Can Texts Empower Women? -- Queer Theory --</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Contents note continued: Analysis and Examples -- 5.Varieties of Rhetorical Criticism: Understanding-Intervention -- Methods Focused on Self and Society -- Psychoanalytic Criticism -- Making Minds and Selves -- Desire -- Visual Rhetorical Criticism -- Images as Focal Points of Meaning Attribution -- Images as Focal Points of Collective Memory and Community -- Point of View -- Methods Focused on Story -- Dramatistic/Narrative Criticism -- Language as a Ground for Motives -- Narrative Genres -- Comedy and Tragedy -- The Pentad -- Analysis and Examples -- Media-Centered Criticism -- What Is a Medium? -- Media Logic -- Characteristics of Television as a Medium -- Analysis and Examples -- Characteristics of the Computer and Internet as a Medium -- Analysis and Examples -- Summary and Review -- Looking Ahead -- pt. II APPLICATION -- 6.Paradoxes of Personalization: Race Relations in Milwaukee -- The Problem of Personalization -- The Scene and Focal Events --</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Contents note continued: Problems in the African American Community -- Violence against African Americans -- The School System -- White Political Attitudes -- Tragedy and Metonymy -- Metonymizing the Tragedies -- Metonymy and Paradox -- The Paradox of Identification -- Identification and Race -- Enabling Identification -- Forestalling Identification -- The Persistence of Race -- The Paradox of Action: The Public and the Personal -- Personal Action and Loss of Vision -- The Paradox in Milwaukee -- African Americans "In Need of Help" -- Some Solutions -- Reciprocal Personalization -- Metonymizing Yourself -- Metonymizing Others -- Resources for Careful Metonymy -- Stepping Back from the Critique -- 7.On Gansta Rap, Written with the Help of the Reader -- Gangsta Is about African Americans -- False Claim #1 African American Culture Is Violent -- False Claim #2 African American Culture Is Obsessively Sexual -- False Claim #3 African American Culture Is Crassly Materialistic --</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">Contents note continued: Conclusion -- 8.Simulational Selves, Simulational Culture in Groundhog Day -- Simulation and Groundhog Day -- 9.Media and Representation in Rec.Motorcycles -- Tokens of Expertise -- Tokens of Experience -- Conclusion -- 10.Two Homological Critiques: iPods and Cavemen -- One.Opening My iPod Nano: A Homological Study of Media and Discourse -- Two.Queering the Gecko: Race, Sexual Orientation, and Marginality in GEICO's Cavemen -- Cavemen and Race: The Series -- Cavemen and Sexuality: The Advertisements -- Queering the Gecko.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520"><subfield code="a">This book provides readers with in-depth insight into the techniques of rhetorical criticism to analyze the full spectrum of contemporary issues in popular culture. From movies, magazines and advertisements, to social networking sites, music videos and television shows, this text presents key rhetorical concepts and applies them with critical analysis to a variety of exciting examples drawn from today's popular culture. Moving from theory to practice throughout the text, this book links concepts in an easy-to-understand way. This book covers the concept rhetoric, itself, as well as its place and dynamic change in history, and offers methods to effectively employ rhetorical criticism in daily life. The new edition includes pertinent critical essays and case studies that show readers how the critical methods discussed can be used to study the hidden rhetoric of extended texts, and more.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596"><subfield code="a">29</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Rhetoric.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Popular culture.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650"><subfield code="a">Rhetorical criticism.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949"><subfield code="a">P301 .B67 2015</subfield><subfield code="h">GMCT-OS-B</subfield><subfield code="i">1007405689</subfield><subfield code="p">85.58</subfield><subfield code="k">AVAIL_SOON</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926"><subfield code="a">P301 .B67 2015</subfield><subfield code="w">LC</subfield><subfield code="c">1</subfield><subfield code="i">1007405689</subfield><subfield code="d">4/6/2017</subfield><subfield code="e">3/30/2017</subfield><subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield><subfield code="m">GR_MACEWAN</subfield><subfield code="n">7</subfield><subfield code="p">$85.58</subfield><subfield code="r">Y</subfield><subfield code="s">Y</subfield><subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield><subfield code="u">3/18/2015</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926"><subfield code="a">P301 .B67 2015</subfield><subfield code="w">LC</subfield><subfield code="c">2</subfield><subfield code="i">1007757360</subfield><subfield code="d">9/1/2016</subfield><subfield code="k">RESERVES</subfield><subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield><subfield code="m">GR_MACEWAN</subfield><subfield code="p">$108.45</subfield><subfield code="r">Y</subfield><subfield code="s">Y</subfield><subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield><subfield code="u">8/25/2016</subfield><subfield code="z">TEXTBK-MAC</subfield><subfield code="0">TEXTBK-MAC</subfield></datafield></record>