<oai_dc:dc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><dc:title>Edmonton Area Survey, 1977</dc:title><dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10576</dc:identifier><dc:creator>Population Research Laboratory</dc:creator><dc:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dc:publisher><dc:description>The overall objectives of the study can be summarized as follows: a) To collect basic research data about the City of Edmonton and to make this data available to agencies and organizations for the purpose of helping them formulate policy and direct their activities. b) To accumulate archival material for researchers and interested persons to conduct survey research using the resources of students and the Population Research Laboratory that would not have been otherwise possible. c) To provide th&#xd;
e opportunity for researchers to do replication of work to further validate previous findings. d) To establish an organization with the capability of obtaining data for the measurement of social change in the community. e) To permit the opportunity for researchers to refine and test methodological research techniques for the purpose of adding to the knowledge of the survey research process itself. f) To train graduate students in the methods of survey research by allowing them to participate fully in the planning and execution of a large scale survey. Questions were compiled and to them were added specific quality of life questions used in the Michigan Quality of Life Survey (1974) and the National Opinion Research Council Surveys. The basic demographic questions and their format were taken from "Survey Research", a book compiled by the Canada Council's Task Force on Survey Research (Survey Research: Report of Consultative Group on Survey Research, The Canada Council, 1976). Through this replication of questions, we are in a position to compare results obtained in Edmonton with those found in other centers. In the Edmonton Area Study, an attempt is made to provide subjective data that ultimately can be compared against objective data to establish an overall view of well-being in various "life domains" of the inhabitants of Edmonton.</dc:description><dc:subject>Arts and Humanities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Social Sciences</dc:subject><dc:subject>demographics</dc:subject><dc:subject>accomodations</dc:subject><dc:subject>personal safety</dc:subject><dc:subject>recreational facilities</dc:subject><dc:subject>social contacts</dc:subject><dc:subject>social behaviour</dc:subject><dc:subject>criminology</dc:subject><dc:subject>police</dc:subject><dc:subject>community</dc:subject><dc:subject>courts</dc:subject><dc:subject>civil rights</dc:subject><dc:subject>vicimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>employment</dc:subject><dc:subject>occupation</dc:subject><dc:subject>job satisfaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>family</dc:subject><dc:subject>child rearing</dc:subject><dc:subject>finances</dc:subject><dc:subject>gun control</dc:subject><dc:subject>wire tapping</dc:subject><dc:subject>death penalty</dc:subject><dc:subject>birth control information</dc:subject><dc:subject>abortion</dc:subject><dc:subject>working women</dc:subject><dc:subject>swine flu</dc:subject><dc:subject>immunization</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality of life</dc:subject><dc:date>1977-06</dc:date><dc:contributor>Population Research Laboratory, Department of Sociology, University of Alberta.</dc:contributor><dc:type>Microdata</dc:type></oai_dc:dc>