<oai_dc:dc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><dc:title>The CHAPTER I Study: Evaluation of Novel Transition Interventions for Youth With Congenital Heart Disease</dc:title><dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10906</dc:identifier><dc:creator>Mackie, Andrew</dc:creator><dc:creator>Magill-Evans, Joyce</dc:creator><dc:creator>Rempel, Gwen</dc:creator><dc:creator>Rankin, Kathryn</dc:creator><dc:creator>Robert, Cheri</dc:creator><dc:creator>Dodd, Bernadette</dc:creator><dc:creator>Islam, Sunjidatul</dc:creator><dc:creator>Schuh, Michelle</dc:creator><dc:creator>Nicholas, David</dc:creator><dc:creator>Vonder Muhll, Isabelle</dc:creator><dc:creator>McCrindle, Brian</dc:creator><dc:creator>Yasui, Yutaka</dc:creator><dc:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dc:publisher><dc:description>The objective of this study was to evaluate the feasibility of a cardiology clinic-b&#xd;
ased educational intervention for 15 to 17 year teens with congenital heart disease (CHD), and to determine whether this intervention results in improved self-management skills, teens having greater knowledge of their heart condition, and more teen satisfaction with services. The study showed that an individualised nurse-led teaching session for older adolescents with heart disease results in improved knowledge of their heart and greater self-management skills relative to controls.</dc:description><dc:subject>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</dc:subject><dc:subject>congenital heart defects</dc:subject><dc:subject>adolescent</dc:subject><dc:subject>heart diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>patient education</dc:subject><dc:subject>randomized controlled trial</dc:subject><dc:subject>congenital heart diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>health care transition</dc:subject><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:relation>The CHAPTER II Study - Congenital Heart Adolescents Participating in Transition Evaluation Research</dc:relation><dc:relation>The CHAPTER III Study of Young Adolescents: Congenital Heart Adolescents Participating in Transition Evaluation Research</dc:relation><dc:type>Questionnaire data; Clinical data; Qualitative data</dc:type><dc:source>Transition Readiness Assessment Questionnaire (TRAQ); Patient Satisfaction Questionnaire (PSQ-18); MyHeart Scale</dc:source></oai_dc:dc>