<oai_dc:dc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><dc:title>Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Robotic Gait Training and Gait-focused Physical Therapy Programs for Children and Youth With Cerebral Palsy: A Mixed Methods Randomized Controlled Trial</dc:title><dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10923</dc:identifier><dc:creator>Wright, Virginia</dc:creator><dc:creator>Wiart, Lesley</dc:creator><dc:creator>Rosychuk, Rhonda</dc:creator><dc:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dc:publisher><dc:description>This is a prospective, multi-centre, concurrent mixed methods study comprised of a randomized controlled trial (RCT) and an interpretive descriptive qualitative design. The goal of the RCT is to compare: 1) a walking training program with the Lokomat robotic device (LOK), 2) a functional physical therapy program (fPT) that includes activities to enhance balance/co-ordination/endurance and advanced motor skills conducted over 'real ground', 3) a combined Lokomat + functional physical therapy (LOK+fPT) program, and 4) a regular maintenance therapy condition (CONT). The qualitative part of the study will consist of interviews of children and parents after they have finished the study intervention.</dc:description><dc:subject>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</dc:subject><dc:subject>brain diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>central nervous system diseases</dc:subject><dc:subject>exercise</dc:subject><dc:subject>motor skills</dc:subject><dc:subject>randomized controlled trial</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixed methods studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>qualitative research</dc:subject><dc:subject>pediatrics</dc:subject><dc:subject>rehabilitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>cerebral palsy</dc:subject><dc:subject>robot assisted gait training</dc:subject><dc:subject>physical therapy</dc:subject><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Observational data; Clinical data; Interview data; Audiovisual data; Accelerometer data</dc:type><dc:source>Gross motor abilities: GMFM-66 (Dimensions D- Stand &amp; E - Walk/Run/Jump); Challenge Measure (GMFCS level II) and GMFM Dimensions D and E with aids and orthoses (GMFCS III)  Walking capacity/gait: 1- and 6-Minute Walk Test, Bloorview Barefoot Gait Assessment (scored from video)   Individualized goal attainment: Canadian Occupational Performance Measure (COPM) and Goal Attainment Scale (GAS)   Standing and Walking Balance: Pediatric Balance Scale, Quality FM (Stability from GMFM-66 video), Activities Balance Confidence Scale  Functional abilities: PEDI-CAT   Physical Activity levels: Accelerometry (5 days)  Physical Activity Self-efficacy: Self-Efficacy for Physical Activity   Participation: Participation and Environment Measure for Children and Youth (PEM?CY)   Quality of life: KidScreen and Students' Life Satisfaction Scale (SLSS)</dc:source></oai_dc:dc>