<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">Smart, Brent Maxwell</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="graduation" lang="en">1997-11</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">1997</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Philosophy</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Doctor of Philosophy - PhD</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">"The purpose of this dissertation is to advance our understanding of the intentionality ofmental states through a critical examination of Fred Dretske's theory of mind.Dretske's theorizing is constrained by his desire both to save central features of our""pretheoretic"" conception of mind and, at the same time, to be appropriately ""materialistic""(and hence ""naturalistic""). Dretske's materialism is captured in his claim that: ""...the crucialpoint is that whatever set of facts we select to analyze the mental are facts which, takenindividually, are recognizably physical — the sort that exist, or can exist, in a world devoid ofminds"" (Dretske 1994a, p. 131). Central features of our pretheoretic conception of mind thatDretske wishes to preserve include:- that ordinary categories such as thought, belief, and desire capture real categories ofmental states,- that mental states are certain kinds of representational states, and therefore they havesemantic content (meaning),- that a mental state's having a particular representational content is an explanatorilyrelevant (because causally relevant) fact about it.Dretske proposes that intentional, representational contents of the cognitive states of acognitive system are fixed by the history of information-bearing relations (also called""indicational"" relations) that those states of the system have had to aspects of the system'senvironment. Further, the resulting representational contents are themselves essentially andentirely relational in nature. One cognitive system with an internal configurationtype-identical to another, but with type-distinct (or in the limiting case no) history of indicational relations to its environment, will have type-distinct (or in the limiting case no)representational contents.Within these constraints, then, Dretske must show both how mental representation ispossible and also how it is causal-explanatorily relevant to behaviour. As such, it isindicational relations that need to provide the basis both for an account of how a cognitivestate comes to have its given content, and also for an account of the causal-explanatory rolethat its having that very content may have for the behaviour of the cognitive system whosestate it is. However, 1 argue that indicational relations per se can do neither. This is soparticularly on Dretske's own, strong, conception of indication. Buiiit even on weakerconceptions proposed by others as a remedy, factors which ought to count as intentional byDretske's own lights (and which are importantly non-relational) become important contributorsto intentional content determination in a way that would commit the overall account to ageneral and pervasive circularity. 1 argue that some of these factors, having to do with mattersof ""receptivity"" and perceptual ""discrimination"", are endemic to the very processes of operantconditioning that Dretske must appeal to as contributing to the rise of states with intentionalcontents."</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Arts, Faculty of||Philosophy, Department of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="extent">11327850 bytes</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="mimetype">application/pdf</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/7335</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">Fred Dretske’s information-based theory of intentional states</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017090269</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
