<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">Bligh, Christopher Graham</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">1997</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Architecture</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Master of Advanced Studies in Architecture - MASA</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">This thesis addresses the question of how a dialogue may be developed between the socio-political notion ofpluralism and a pluralistic public sphere, and the design of public space and public architecture. Moreparticularly, it considers how architecture may both accommodate multiple publics while simultaneouslyframing connection or association between them. Following an exploration of this question at an abstract,theoretical level, the thesis moves to a more specific architectural investigation. This investigation takes theform of a design project situated within the Robson Square complex in downtown Vancouver. The complex,constructed in the mid-1970's, was designed by Canada's pre-eminent architect Arthur Erickson and is themajor civic space in the city. The thesis design project undertakes a theoretical re-evaluation and physicalrenovation of this Utopian mega-structure, with the intention of shifting the existing homogeneity andinstitutionality of the complex to align it with the thesis argument.Through the vehicle of a design project,, the abstract theoretical argument is translated and focused through theparticularities of an architecture embedded in its site. This methodology requires the project to address issuesconnected to the existing masterwork, including: the question of how to conceptualize monumentally in a gridcity; the relationship between the 'sacred' space of the civic circumstance and the 'profane' space of the streetand commercial program; the form of the institution within the city; and the issue of working within, andmanipulating, a pre-existing architectural language. Further, the scale of the site is reflected in the scope of thedesign project. The project moves from the development of urban design strategies to the detailed considerationof the material and construction of the different interventions. The architecture remains, however, conceptualand is a demonstration of how the developed strategies may generate form and guide program. Theproject does not attempt to fully develop a building in detail.The thesis concludes with an afterword on the success of the project as a demonstration of the thesis argument.At the same time, the limits of architecture to act as a socio-political device are acknowledged. Further,speculations are made as to the way in which the position and the strategies developed within the thesis mightinform wider discussions on architecture and the urbanism of grid cities such as Vancouver. The key conceptforming the basis of these speculations is the idea of a 'difficult' co-existence of parts and a whole, reflectingthe pluralistic ideal of association within fragmentation.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Architecture and Landscape Architecture (SALA), School of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation" lang="en">Applied Science, Faculty of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="extent">29796395 bytes</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="mimetype">application/pdf</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/5810</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="subject" qualifier="none" lang="en">Robson Square (Vancouver, B.C.)||Cultural pluralism -- British Columbia -- Vancouver||Architecture -- British Columbia -- Vancouver</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">Framing pluralism: a reconfiguration of the Robson Square complex in downtown Vancouver, British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2017061894</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
