<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">Timko, Joleen</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="graduation" lang="en">2001-05</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2001</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Resource Management and Environmental Studies</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Master of Science - MSc</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">Interest in the role that local people's knowledge and experiences can play in naturalresource conservation is increasing throughout the world. This is due in part becauseprotected areas and national parks have repeatedly proven to be unsuccessful inachieving conservation objectives, and in part because they threaten the existence ofnearby rural communities. When severe restrictions are placed on access to the forestresources local people depend upon for survival, poverty is often exacerbated. Theresult is that local people feel contempt and distrust for the protected area.In order to mitigate the impacts that protected areas have had on rural populations, localpeople have become the locus for development activities which either strive tounderstand the value of local ecological knowledge and experiences, or whichencourage local people to participate in often externally-designed initiatives. Only acommunity-based natural resource management (CBNRM) approach, which is groundedin an understanding of local people's realities and livelihood needs, can unite thestrengths of local knowledge and participation.To gain insight into the opportunities and constraints facing planners seeking to take aparticipatory approach to park management, a case study was conducted of Cat BaNational Park, Vietnam. Semi-structured interviews were carried out in two communitieswithin the park, Khe Sau Hamlet and Viet Hai Village. The results show that local peoplein Cat Ba are willing and able to participate in the park's conservation activities, but thatthey are inhibited from doing so by political and socio-economic factors. As well, it wasfound that local people possess detailed ecological knowledge about the park's forestresources. This knowledge has been developed by keen observations of thesurrounding environment for generations. Improving local livelihoods was identified bylocal people as essential to reducing their dependence on forest biodiversity.Drawing on ideas offered by Cat Ba interviewees and analysis of other findings from thecase study, suggestions are offered for capturing opportunities and overcoming barriersto effective participatory park management.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Science, Faculty of||Resources, Environment and Sustainability (IRES), Institute for</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="extent">12856796 bytes</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="mimetype">application/pdf</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/11598</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">Conservation at what cost? : a case study of the social implications of protected areas and the role of local people in Vietnam</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017046351</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
