<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">Cabajsky, Andrea</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="graduation" lang="en">2002-11</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2002</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">English</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Doctor of Philosophy - PhD</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">"'""Transcolonial Circuits': Historical Fiction and National Identities in Ireland, Scotland,and Canada"" explores the intersections between gender, canon-formation, and literarygenre in order to argue that English- and French-Canadian historical fiction wasinfluenced, both in form and content, by the precedent-setting fictions o f Scotland andIreland in the early nineteenth century. Conceived in the spirit o f Katie Trumpener'sBardic Nationalism: The Romantic Novel and the British Empire (1997), this dissertationextends Trumpener's examination of nineteenth-century British and Canadian romanticfiction by exploring in greater detail the flow of ideas and literary techniques betweenIreland, Scotland, and English and French Canada. It does so in order to revise criticalunderstandings of the formal and thematic origins and development of Canadianhistorical fiction from the nineteenth century to the present.Chapter One functions as a series of literary snapshots that examine historicallythe critical and popular reception of novels by Maria Edgeworth and Sydney Owenson inIreland, Sir Walter Scott in Scotland, John Richardson, William Kirby, and JeanMcllwraith in English Canada, and Philippe Aubert de Gaspe and Napoleon Bourassa inFrench Canada. I pay particular attention to the issues o f gender and political ideology asinseparable from the history of the novel itself. In Chapter Two, by focussing on thetravel trope, I examine in detail how Irish, Scottish, and Canadian writers transformed theinvestigative journeys of Samuel Johnson and Arthur Young into journeys of resistanceto the dictates of the metropolis. Chapter Three focuses on the complications of marriageas a metaphor o f intercultural union. It pays particular attention to the intersectionsbetween gender, sexuality, and colonial identity. The Conclusion extends the concernsraised in the thesis about the relationship between historical writing and national identityto the late-twentieth-century Canadian context, by examining the adaptation of literaryand historiographical conventions to the medium of television in the CBC/SRC televisionseries Canada: A People's History, which aired in 2001-02."</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">English, Department of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation" lang="en">Arts, Faculty of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="extent">9662842 bytes</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="mimetype">application/pdf</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/13301</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="subject" qualifier="none" lang="en">Historical fiction, Canadian (English) -- History and criticism||Historical fiction, Canadian (French) -- History and criticism||National characteristics, Canadian, in literature</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">"""Transcolonial circuits"" : historical fiction and national identities in Ireland, Scotland, and Canada"</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2010163337</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://viaf.org/viaf/106564612</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://isni.org/isni/0000000114543629</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
