<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">Puls, Manfred Paul</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">1966</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Physics</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Master of Applied Science - MASc</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">A HeÂ³ cryostat was designed for steady state nuclear magnetic resonance measurements. The cryostat required about one liter of HeÂ³ at NTP. This amount of HeÂ³ was liquified at 1.2Â°K, which was the temperature of the surrounding liquid Heâ&#x81;´ bath, and then pumped on by means of a four-stage mercury diffusion pump. By this procedure, a liquid HeÂ³ temperature of 0.35 K was achieved and maintained for four hours. The r-f coil and sample were in direct contact with the liquid HeÂ³ to ensure sufficient heat transfer between the two. The temperature of the liquid HeÂ³ was measured by means of vapour pressure measurements of the evaporating HeÂ³ and by means of resistance measurements of a carbon resistance in contact with the liquid HeÂ³. The system was non-recirculating, since a total, uninterrupted run of four hours was considered long enough for most experiments. The HeÂ³ could also be retransferred within 20 minutes after such a run, and this process could be continued until in-sufficient quantities of liquid Heâ&#x81;´remained to cool the surroundings.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Science, Faculty of||Physics and Astronomy, Department of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/37817</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="publisher" qualifier="none" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="subject" qualifier="none" lang="en">Nuclear magnetic resonance||Cryostats||Metals</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">He3 cryostat for steady state nuclear magnetic resonance measurements in metals</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none" lang="en">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2012021407</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator" qualifier="none">http://viaf.org/viaf/310520440/</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
