<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Ahmed, Tawfik M.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="graduation" lang="en">2002-05</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2002</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Materials Engineering</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Doctor of Philosophy - PhD</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">The near-threshold fatigue crack propagation behavior of a-phase copper alloys in desiccatedair and several aqueous environments has been investigated. Three commercial alloys ofnominal composition Cu-30Ni (Cu-Ni), Cu-30Zn (Cu-Zn) and 90Cu-7Al-3Fe (Cu-Al) weretested. Fatigue tests were conducted using standard prefatigued single edged notched (SEN)specimens loaded in tension at a high frequency of ~100 Hz. Different R-ratios wereemployed, mostly at i?-ratios of 0.5. Low loading levels were used that corresponded to thethreshold and near-threshold regions where ΔK[sub th] &lt; ΔK &lt; 11 MPa√m.Fatigue tests in the aqueous solutions showed that the effect of different corrosiveenvironments during high frequency testing (~100 Hz) was not as pronounced as wasexpected when compared relative to air. Further testing revealed that environmental effectswere present and fatigue crack growth rates were influenced by the fluid-induced closureeffects which are generally reported in the fatigue literature to be operative only in viscousliquids, not in aqueous solutions. It was concluded that high frequency testing in aqueousenvironments consistently decreased crack growth rates in a manner similar to crackretardation effects in viscous fluids. Several theoretical models reported in the literature haveunderestimated, if not failed, to adequately predict the fluid induced closure in aqueoussolutions.Results from the desiccated air tests confirmed that, under closure-free conditions (high Rratios),both threshold values and fatigue crack growth rate of stage II can be related toYoung's modulus, in agreement with results from the literature. The role of differentmechanical and environmental variables on fatigue behavior becomes most visible in the lowi?-ratio regime, and contribute to various closure processes.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Applied Science, Faculty of||Materials Engineering, Department of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="extent">17618116 bytes</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="format" qualifier="mimetype">application/pdf</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/13296</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">Near-threshold fatigue behavior of copper alloys in air and aqueous environments : a high cyclic frequency study</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator2" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2017040365</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator5" qualifier="none">,</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
