<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Biggs, Wayne Griffin</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">1976</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Plant Science</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Master of Science - MSc</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">"Burns bog is a large sphagnum peat bog occupying approximately 4,000ha of the Fraser River delta in south-western British Columbia.The area has been extensively disturbed by peat extraction, landfillingand other land-uses. Much of the bog remains in a natural or semi-naturalstate. As such it represents one of the largest single tractsof underdeveloped land in the Corporation of Delta. Land developmentand growth in the municipality has been rapid in the past ten years.Because the Burns bog area was not well known and the pressures fordevelopment of the area were mounting, this study was initiated inJanuary 1975.Available existing environmental and land-use information pertainingto the Burns bog area was reviewed and collated. Basic vegetationand wildlife inventories were carried out in the area, and a cover map ofextant vegetation was prepared. Several aspects of peatland ecologywere investigated. These included the determination of the rate ofspagnum peat accumulation, an estimate of the energy (caloric content)of the peat stored with Burns bog, and net primary productivity.The bog was found to be floristically interesting and to be quiteunlike most of the remaining underdeveloped areas of the Fraser River lowland. Because of its large size, waterlogged character, andlocation between the Fraser River, Boundary Bay and the foreshoreareas of Roberts and Sturgeon banks, Burns bog is believed to be animportant natural refuge for many species of birds. The area isan important loafing area for waterfowl, particularly mallard, pintail,and teal, and is a nesting area for a number of raptorial ,passerine and other birds. Perhaps one of the more important birdsof Burns bog is the greater sandhill crane, which nests in the bogin small numbers.Burns bog supports a number of mammal species. In addition toa variety of ""common"" small mammals, the area supports a small numberof black bear, and Columbian black-tailed deer which are believedto be isolated populations.The land-use patterns of lands surrounding the bog area are believedto be of key importance to bird and mammal life in the area. Forexample many species of birds (ducks, raptors and sandhill cranes)and mammals (Columbian black-tailed deer and eastern cottontailrabbit) feed at the interface between the forested sections of thebog and the neighbouring agricultural lands. The agriculturalcharacter of these peripheral lands appears to influence use of thebog by various wildlife species.The peat samples analysed were found to be high in nitrogen andminerals, although these nutrients were not believed to be availablefor plant utilization.The volume of peat in the bog was crudely estimated to be 108.8 hm3 .The dry weight of this material was estimated to be 3,949,440 metrictons, and the caloric content of this material was found to beapproximately 20,023.76 G. cal. This figure is believed to be theapproximate amount of energy stored as peat in the bog.The sphagnum peat accumulation rate and net primary productivityappeared to be considerably higher at hummock sites as comparedto wet depressional areas. The average rate of accumulationof ten samples (six hummock and four -wet depression sites) was foundto be .43 cm/yr, while the average net primary productivity was128.8 g/m2 /yr.The vegetation and wildlife of the bog are largely determined bythe land-use practices surrounding and within the bog. For example,""improving"" the drainage of the area for the agricultural reclamationof the peatland, or for other purposes will probably result in therapid decomposition and subsidence of the drained peat. The increasedavailability of nutrients, and drier conditions will consequentlyalter the vegetation and wildlife species distribution in the bog."</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Land and Food Systems, Faculty of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/41949</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="publisher" qualifier="none" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="subject" qualifier="none" lang="en">Burns Bog, B.C.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">An ecological and land use study of Burns bog, Delta, British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none" lang="en">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator2" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017065471</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator3" qualifier="none">http://viaf.org/viaf/279137030/</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator4" qualifier="none">http://www.isni.org/isni/0000000384984846</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator5" qualifier="none">,</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
