<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Harshaw, Howard W.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="graduation" lang="en">2006-05</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2005</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Forestry</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Doctor of Philosophy - PhD</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">The cases of recreation in the Sea-to-Sky Corridor and Peace Foothills in British Columbia are used toexplore the issues of the representation of outdoor recreation in land-use planning and the participation ofrecreationists in land-use planning. The widening array of outdoor recreation activities in high-use areasposes new challenges to the equitable participation of diverse recreation user groups in land-useplanning. How well have past land-use planning exercises represented the needs of outdoorrecreationists? How well represented do participants of newer recreation activities feel? Moreover, whoshould represent these diverse groups? There has, to date, been very little research in this area.In an attempt to explore these questions and begin building a theoretical framework for understanding keyrelationships, this study measures recreationists' perceptions of representation in land-use planning andtheir participation in land-use planning in the Sea-to-Sky Corridor and Peace Foothills. Relationshipsbetween recreation use and socio-economic characteristics and recreationists' participation andperceptions of representation in land-use planning were examined. Moderate levels of perceivedrepresentation were found for most recreation groups, although some users seemed unclear about howwell they were represented. In sum, some socio-economic characteristics (household income, age, andeducation) were associated with a person's participation in land-use planning; this influence extended toperceived representation through aspects of social capital, as membership in an outdoor recreation cluband degree of recreation specialization were associated with perceived representation. The localness ofrecreationists played a role in their participation in land-use planning; localness also was associated withperceived representation. Outdoor recreation characteristics (recreation specialization, activity choice,the number of activities participated in, annual participation, and club membership) had an influence onrecreationists' likelihood of participation in land-use planning. Logistic regression models suggested thatrecreation specialization and household income contributed to respondents' perceptions of representationin land-use planning; age, recreation specialization, the number of recreation activities participated in,club membership, and local residence contributed to respondents' likelihood of having been a participantof a land-use planning process. The results of this study support four land-use planning strategies thatmay assist planners in increasing actual and perceived representation of recreationists.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Forestry, Faculty of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/18443</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">The representation of outdoor recreation in land-use planning in British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator2" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n00014896</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator3" qualifier="none">http://viaf.org/viaf/22369107</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator4" qualifier="none">http://isni.org/isni/0000000018393157</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator5" qualifier="none">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-9667-2642,</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
