<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Ilsever, Yalcin</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">2000</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Special Education</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Master of Arts - MA</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">"This study proposed an alternative method of scoring theTorrance Test of Creative Thinking: Thinking Creatively with Words(TTCT: Verbal A). This scoring method was compared to theconventional scoring method. I first considered the current methodof scoring, ""the old method"" and then proposed a ""new method"".The old and the new methods of scoring were compared on asubscale of the TTCT. Both the old and the new methods of scoringwere then compared to the Canadian Test of Basic Skills (CTBS) totallanguage scores to determine if a relationship existed between verbalacademic achievement versus the creativity construct.The new scoring method of creativity showed an improvementover the old method of scoring on the TTCT: Verbal A subtest. Thereliability coefficient, for internal consistency, declined from 0.83 to0.54. This decline was interpreted as an improvement because theinitial value of 0.83 was artificially high. This was due, to a very highintercorrelation between fluency and originality (inter-attributecorrelation value =. 97). The new scoring method corrected thisinflation.I found a veiy low, negative correlation between CTBS totallanguage and both the old and the new methods of scoring forcreativity. The correlation coefficients were -.18, and -.17,respectively. This low value negative correlation demonstrated thatcreativity was not connected to verbal academic achievement.Although divergent thinking is the most commonly used aspectof creative thinking, previous researchers (e.g., Runco, 1986) havesuggested that the tests of creativity lack reliability. The issue ofreliability of a test score has generally been defined in terms ofvariation of scores obtained by the individual on successiveindependent testing (Cronbach, 1947). Neither the assumption ofconstancy of true scores nor the assumptions of experimentalindependence can be realized in practice with most psychologicalvariables. Therefore, the composite reliability of a test needs to beconsidered as a concept, which can not be directly measured.Torrance (1986) specifically discouraged the use of composite testscores and instead recommended interpretation of the subscalescores in relation to one another. The fundamental problem currentlyfaced with the TTCT is that scores derived from the same responsedata cause potentially spuriously subscale correlation. This inflatesthe reliability coefficient and seriously jeopardizes score consistencyand reliability.Thorndike (1972) has argued that fluency, flexibility, andoriginality scores tended to be highly correlated, since all areaccumulated over the same set of responses given by theexaminees. This seriously discounts the value of the old scoringformula recommended by the Technical Scoring Formula of theTTCT. This fundamental problem of scoring has been attributed toderivation of five separate scores in that the scores were derivedfrom the same response data (Heasusler &amp; Thompson, 1988).This type of score derivation introduced spuriously high scalecorrelation because the flexibility, fluency, and originality scorestended to be highly correlated.Through some corrective procedures, correcting fluency, Clarkand Mirels (1970) recommended that correlation coefficient valuefrom several measures of Torrance's Test of Creative Thinking(Figure Completion) would decrease. This procedure consisted ofadministering a revised form of the sub-test to 93 students. Thesewere then scored, based on fluency, flexibility, originality, andelaboration. Corrected fluency scores led to lower reliabilitycoefficient values. My study had a similar experience. The alphacoefficient value dropped to .54 from .83, with the new scoringmethod.My research dealt with the score inflation, with the old scoringmethod, scoring inconsistency, and, proposed a new method ofscoring the TTCT. I also highlighted the issue of inter-attribute highcorrelation between fluency and originality attributes. These twoattributes are the main ingredients in assessing creativity.My research focused on the three traits of creativity, namely:(1) the fluency, (2) the originality, (3) the flexibility. These weremeasured with the use of the TTCT: Verbal A: Activity 4: ProductImprovement. The TTCT was administered to a sample of children(N=187) in grades4 to 8. The data was analyzed to assess scorereliability. The existing CTBS total language scores available at theschool were also utilized in order to consider any relationshipbetween creativity and verbal academic achievement.The new scoring method enhanced the reliability coefficientand improved upon the scoring techniques. The new scoringapproach adopted the same scoring techniques as the old method'with the measurement of fluency and flexibility attributes. However,with the measurement of originality attribute, a new approach wasadopted. The new scoring method I have designed considered onlythe two score attributes; fluency and flexibility. The originality score,which is simply a ""fall-out"" from the fluency score, was not included.This exclusion avoided double counting between fluency andoriginality and dealt with the high correlation problem between thesetwo attributes. With the old scoring method, the correlation betweenfluency and originality would be as high as .99 (Thorndike, 1972).This simply indicated that fluency and originality attributes weremeasuring the same creativity dimension. The new method ofscoring rectified this problem.Hocevar (1979) recommended a method as a way of improvingtest reliability. Hocevar's method, however, recommended scoring fororiginality and flexibility and dividing the resulting score by the totalnumber of responses. His recommendation was very valid inimproving discriminant validity and did not address the score inflationand high inter-attribute correlation problem between fluency and,originality. I have somewhat revised his recommended method andproposed that e capture the flexibility and fluency responses anddivide the resulting score by the total number of responses. Thisensured consistency in measurement and corrected the high inter-correlationproblem between the TTCT attributes. It also improvedscore reliability.Under the new method of scoring, each response for flexibilityand fluency is adjusted by dividing the resulting scores by the totalnumber of responses. Since fluency scores tended to be highlycorrelated with the originality scores, this new approach safeguardedagainst duplication in scoring also reduced spurious correlationbetween fluency and originality. Originality attribute was no longerrequired for scoring. Division of both flexibility and fluency by thetotal number of responses also streamlined the overall compositescore.The composite score of the TTCT, under the new methodcontained fluency and flexibility scores. This also ensured that anumber of response which would normally be scored with ""0"",would be considered as part of the fluency score, as originalityattribute was no longer considered.The factor analytic results obtained by Heauslar and Thompson(1988) showed that the TTCT subscale yielded discrete scores. Thegeneral creativity factors were sufficient in assessing creativebehavior. These factors included fluency, flexibility and originality.The total TTCT scores were not recommended (Torrance, 1974;Torrance &amp; Ball, 1984) for assessment of creativity. Herecommended using scores of fluency, flexibility and originality. Thisalso jeopardized the integrity of the total creativity scores.The new method improved the reliability of the test scores ofWe TTCT by enhancing the existing scoring methodology. With theold scoring approach of originality, responses which did not meet thepre-determined fluency categories, were scored a ""0"", regardless ofthe relevancy of response. This diluted the originality scored, anddistorted score reliability. The new method considered all the fluencyresponses and scrutinized all response for consistency under fluencycategory. Fluency attribute was not simply considered as the numberof total ideas, regardless of the degree of relevancy of task on hand.Each response of fluency was evaluated for its relevancy, in view ofthe task, on hand. This streamlined the scoring approach withfluency.With the new method of scoring, the standardized alphacoefficient declined from .83 to .54. The new method of scoringimproved the process and made it easy and more relevant to scorefor fluency and flexibility. A very low, negative linear relationship wasfound between the creativity construct and academic achievement,as represented CTBS total language test."</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation">Education, Faculty of||Educational and Counselling Psychology, and Special Education (ECPS), Department of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/42400</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="publisher" qualifier="none" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">A new method of scoring Torrance's Test of Creativity</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none" lang="en">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator2" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017061620</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator5" qualifier="none">,</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
