<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dublin_core schema="dc">
      <dcvalue element="contributor" qualifier="author">Sievers, Monika</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="date" qualifier="issued">1991</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="campus" lang="en">UBCV</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="discipline" lang="en">Law</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="grantor" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="degree" qualifier="name" lang="en">Master of Laws - LLM</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="abstract" lang="en">"The recent developments in the European Community evoked bythe Single European Act and commonly referred to as the creationof ""Fortress Europe"" by the end of 1992 have been attractedconsiderable attention with respect to economic and politicalintegration in the international arena. Similarly, theconclusion of the U.S.-Canada Free Trade Agreement aiming at aloose form of economic integration received significantrecognition.These two agreements cover not only liberalization of tradein goods and services but moreover, include foreign directinvestment. This is of particular significance since littleprogress has been made in its regulation on an internationallevel in comparison to the regulation of trade in goods. Due tothe fact that direct investment is primarily exercised by largemultinational enterprises it has a larger political impact on thehost countries than trade in goods and services. Foreignownership of local industry creates the concern of economicdependence and of a loss of sovereign powers among hostgovernments. Consequently, governments introduce laws andregulations aiming at the restriction of direct investment offoreign investors.However, as foreign investment augments economic growth, itis of common benefit to both investors and host countries toprovide an investment climate which balances the conflict ofinterest between the need of legal certainty and flexibility forforeign investors arid the safeguard of economic independence andpolitical freedom of host country governments to introduce andmaintain measures deemed necessary for the benefit of theirnational economies.This thesis will demonstrate the most effective regime tosolve this conflict through comparison of the Free TradeAgreement with the Treaty of Rome as amended by the SingleEuropean Act. These agreements have been chosen since theyinvolve two of the triad world economic powers and thus,represent industrialized nations with the highest degree offoreign direct investment aiming at the liberalization of directinvestment in their ""enlarged"" markets.The thesis is divided into three parts. The first andsecond parts will discuss the degree of liberalization of foreigninvestment within the Common Market including the progress madeunder the Single European Act of 1986 and within the free tradearea established by the U.S.-Canada Free Trade Agreement in 1989.The analysis will centre around the issues of free establishmentof companies, the National Treatment Principle, capital movement,and mergers and acquisitions. The third part consists of thecomparative analysis and will provide the final conclusions.The conclusions will show that the two agreements share fewsimilarities but they are characterized by their divergentapproach to direct investment liberalization. It is submittedthat the more comprehensive form of liberalization is reached in the Common Market due to its broad restraint on sovereign powersof its Member States and coherently implemented elimination ofrestrictions on foreign investment. In contrast, the Free TradeAgreement only imposes selected obligations on the parties toliberalize direct investment. It will become clear that the FreeTrade Agreement stands for a settlement of the most vexinginvestment issues between the parties rather than a commitment tovirtually liberalize investment between the U.S. and Canada.In view of this result, recommendations are made to furtherliberalize investment under the Free Trade Agreement. These haveto be seen, however, in the light of numerous economic andpolitical divergencies between the Common Market and the U.S.-Canadian free trade area."</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="affiliation" lang="en">Law, Peter A. Allard School of</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="description" qualifier="scholarlevel" lang="en">Graduate</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="identifier" qualifier="uri">http://hdl.handle.net/2429/42049</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="language" qualifier="iso" lang="en">eng</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="publisher" qualifier="none" lang="en">University of British Columbia</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="rights" qualifier="none">For non-commercial purposes only, such as research, private study and education. Additional conditions apply, see Terms of Use https://open.library.ubc.ca/terms_of_use.</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="subject" qualifier="none" lang="en">Investments, Foreign - European Economic Community countries||Investments, Foreign - Canada||Investments, Foreign - United States</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="title" qualifier="none" lang="en">Liberalization of foreign direct investment : Europe 1992 and the U.S.-Canada Free Trade Agreement</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="text" lang="en">Thesis/Dissertation</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="type" qualifier="none" lang="en">Text</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator2" qualifier="none">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2017089944</dcvalue>
      <dcvalue element="creator5" qualifier="none">,</dcvalue>
   </dublin_core>
