<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:08Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h5784" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h5784</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:00:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Infections caused by antibiotic-resistant bacteria can cause severe problems in patients with a weak immune system, such as those with cystic fibrosis. One such bacterium, Pseudomonas aeruginosa, is extremely difficult to eradicate and is the leading cause of mortality in individuals with cystic fibrosis. One mechanism that Pseudomonas aeruginosa employs to become resistant against antibiotics is biofilm formation. The protective mechanisms present in biofilms appear to be different from those that are responsible for conventional antibiotic resistance. Genetic and biochemical details of the biofilm forming mechanism are only just emerging and genes that contribute to this resistance are a major target for the development of new chemotherapeutic agents. The aminoglycoside response regulator (Arr) protein plays a crucial role in the induction of biofilm formation in Pseudomonas aeruginosa upon exposure to the antibiotic tobramycin. In this thesis, I present the three-dimensional 30 Å resolution structure of Arr, which was obtained using single particle reconstruction, a transmission electron microscopy method (TEM). Preliminary results have also been obtained with additional methods that provide clues regarding Arr's structure: electron crystallography was used to grow two-dimensional crystals of Arr and crystallization trials for X-ray crystallography have been carried out for one of Arr's soluble domains.</description><description>Les infections provoquées par les bactéries résistantes aux antibiotiques posent de graves problèmes aux patients qui ont un système immunitaire faible, en particulier ceux qui souffrent de la fibrose kystique. Une de ces bactéries, la Pseudomonas aeruginosa, est extrêmement difficile à supprimer et, de plus, est la principale cause de mortalité chez les individus atteint de la fibrose kystique. Un des mécanismes que la Pseudomonas aeruginosa emploie pour résister contre les antibiotiques est sa capacité à former des "biofilmes". Les détails génétiques et biochimiques de ces biofilmes émergent seulement récemment et donc la découverte des gènes responsables pour ce mécanisme de résistance est un but important à atteindre avant de pouvoir développer de nouveaux agents chémotherapeutiques contre les infections causées par Pseudomonas aeruginosa. La protéine régulatrice d'aminoglycoside (Arr) joue un rôle important dans la formation de biofilmes dans la bactérie Pseudomonas aeruginosa, une fois que la bactérie à été exposée à l'antibiotique tobramycine. Dans la thèse de maîtrise qui suit, je présente la structure tridimensionnelle de la protéine Arr à une résolution de 30 Å qui a été obtenu utilisant la "single particle reconstruction", qui est une méthode qui utilise la microscopie à transmission électronique (TEM). Des résultats préliminaires qui aident à élucider la structure de Arr ont également été obtenus avec des méthodes supplémentaires: la cristallographie d'électron a été employée pour générer des cristaux bidimensionnels de Arr et puis des essais de cristallisation par cristallographie à rayon X ont été effectuées sur un des domaines solubles de Arr.</description><creator>Wodrich, Miriam</creator><contributor>Albert Berghuis (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Understanding the structural basis of Arr-induced biofilm formation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719r33t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h5784</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>