<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:20:53Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20475" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hg37c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Generalized spike and wave (SW) activity of feline generalized penicillin epilepsy (FGPE), an experimental model of epilepsy exhibiting a sufficient degree of similarity with human generalized 3 Hz SW discharge, depends upon both cortical and thalamic mechanisms. Cortical neurons under the influence of systemic penicillin become more excitable and respond more vigorously to thalamocortical volleys normally inducing spindles or recruiting responses. This increased response of cortical neurons activates phasic recurrent inhibition which remains intact during FGPE as is shown by the preservation of antidromically evoked recurrent inhibition of pyramidal tract cells. Thus, an oscillation between periods of increased and decreased neuronal firing probability ensues which underlies SW discharge in the EEG. The cortex imposes this oscillatory pattern of neuronal discharge upon the thalamus, which by itself, however, is incapable of responding in this matter to systemic penicillin, as it appears from experiments performed in decorticated cats. Nevertheless, the thalamus is not a mere passive follower of the cortex in SW activity, since thalamocortical inputs remain necessary to maintain it. Furthermore thalamic neurons, like cortical ones, undergo a cyclically alternating pattern of increased and decreased firing probability. They display three different modes of phase-locked timing of their discharges in relation to cortical SWs and the cortical neuronal firing pattern. Two groups of cells fire coincidentally with the "spike" of the SW complex, one group reaching its maximum firing probability slightly before, the other slightly after that of the simultaneously recorded cortical neuron. The third group fires during the "wave" of the SW complex and its firing pattern is therefore about 180(DEGREES) out of phase with that of the cortical and the other two groups of thalamic neurons. Thus the substrate of generalized SW discharge seems to be oscillatory activity within a c</description><creator>Avoli, Massimo.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The respective roles of the thalamus and cortex in feline pencillin-induced generalized epilepsy /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f11z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg37c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687j32q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A cohort of 2037 first year elementary school children was established in 1978 and examined annually on two other occasions to study the epidemiology of dental caries. Data on risk factors were collected from the parents through a questionnaire at the same time as the last two dental examinations. Some information on risk factors was also collected from the child at the time of dental examination. Prevalence of caries initially was high and the evolution of prevalence indices over the 24 month period is described. The incidence of caries for deciduous and permanent dentition is given by the relative increment of decay among teeth at risk at the beginning of the interval and those becoming at risk during the interval. Treatment level initially was low but increased between the second and third year of observation. Oral hygiene and nutritional habits did not conform to generally acceptable good preventive practices. Moreover, these behaviors are not stable. Whether by univariate (analyses of variance) or multivariate (multiple linear regression) analyses, certain factors consistently show an influence on dental caries. They are: father's schooling, presence of prostheses in parents, number of visits to the dentist, voluntary consumption of fluoride, number of years of this fluoride consumption, brushing, consumption of soft drinks, candies and vegetables, and eating before bed. These findings lend credence to the belief that despite continuing controversies about risk factors for dental caries, programs aimed at modifying behavior pertaining to the aforementioned factors are justified.</description><creator>Infante-Rivard, Claire.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Prévalence, incidence et facteurs de risque de la carie dentaire dans une cohorte d'âge scolaire élémentaire</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz63z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j32q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732d990n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of these studies was the isolation of corticotropic factors other than ACTH(,1-39) from the bovine and human fetal pituitary gland. The bovine anterior pituitary contains three corticotropic peptides, ACTH(,1-39), ACTH(,1-38) and a putative ACTH(,1-33). The bovine neurointermediate lobe did not contain corticotropic factors different from those found in the anterior lobe. ACTH(,1-38) is formed enzymatically in the fetal calf anterior lobe from ACTH(,1-39). The formation of both peptides in the fetal calf anterior pituitary cell in culture is stimulated by arginine-vasopressin, and a fetal calf hypothalamic extract, and is inhibited by dexamethasone. ACTH(,1-38) appears to be equipotent to ACTH(,1-39) in a fetal calf adrenal cell bioassay, but is only 37% as potent in an isolated rat adrenal cell bioassay. The human fetal pituitary contains four corticotropic peptides, tentatively identified as ACTH(,1-39), phosphorylated-ACTH(,1-39), ACTH(,1-38) and an ACTH(,1-33)-like peptide. The putative ACTH(,1-38) and ACTH(,1-33)-like peptide stimulate dehydroepiandrosterone sulfate but not cortisol production by autologous adrenal cells from 15-17 week old fetuses. They stimulate the production of both steroids by autologous adrenal cells from 18-19 week old fetuses. Three mechanisms have been proposed that explain how these pituitary peptides control the fetal adrenal.</description><creator>Brubaker, Patricia Lee.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Pituitary peptides : isolation and biological function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n21d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d990n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jm32t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phenomenon of photochemical initiation of gaseous detonation waves has been experimentally and theoretically investigated. In the experiments, the flash photolysis technique has been employed and the initiation phenomenon has been directly observed through schlieren photography, while in the theoretical phase, the non-steady reacting flow-field of a photochemically ignited gas mixture has been numerically analyzed. The results conclusively show that the direct detonation initiation can be generated by an intense ultra-violet radiation, and it is shown that the initiation mechanism is mainly attributed to the rapid shock wave amplification occurring in a non-uniformly photo-dissociating gas mixture. It was found that the shock wave amplification is due to the coherent energy release from the non-uniformly reacting gas mixture to the shock wave and that the induction time gradient field generated by the flash photolysis plays an important role in the shock amplification process. Further insight into the fundamental mechanisms of shock wave amplification has been obtained by considering a relatively simple theoretical model. This model illustrates the important role of the induction time gradient field in the shock wave amplification. Finally the concept of shock wave amplification in an induction time gradient field has been further extended to include the problem of transition to detonation in a non-uniformly preheated mixture.</description><creator>Yoshikawa, Norihiko.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Gases.</subject><subject>Detonation waves.</subject><subject>Shock waves.</subject><subject>Explosions.</subject><title>Coherent shock wave amplification in photochemical initiation of gaseous detonations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hg38n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jm32t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3012149</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two experiments were designed as a preliminary exploration of how stress is used by language-impaired children in the comprehension of spoken language. Response time was measured as subjects decided whether a probe word given immediately after a sentence had been present in the sentence. The results of the first experiment indicated that the probe latency technique was sensitive to the effects of word category (content versus function words) and word position on the response times of children with normal language in the kindergarten, first, third, and sixth grades. In the second experiment, the probe latency task was used to study the effects of stress in relation to word category, word position and sentence meaningfulness in a group of language-impaired children to whom control groups were matched for language ability and chronological age. The response times of the age-matched group were not affected by stress, word category or word position variations. The language-impaired and language matched groups responded to variations in stress and word category, and to sentence meaningfulness in similar ways. Response times to function words were increased significantly by the addition of stress. It was concluded that the absence of sensitivity to stress appears not to be a major causative factor of language impairment.</description><creator>Abelson, Annalee.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology.</subject><title>Perception of sentence stress in language-impaired children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149q70h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3012149</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jm31j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possible significance of cognitive and situational factors in determining the response to alcohol suggests that behavioral changes following drinking may reflect a lack of self-control not solely attributable to the pharmacological effect. In an initial experiment subjects were requested to overcome the effects of alcohol (1.32 ml/kg 95% ethanol). In comparison with a no-motivation group (n = 11), motivated subjects (n = 14) demonstrated compensation on aspects of tasks involving memory, coordination and affect. It was speculated that attributions of causality (internal or external) for relative control might influence its occurrence and maintenance. In a second experiment false dose feedback was expected to interact with relative control to affect subjects' (n = 45) attributions. A greater level of sobriety was achieved by subjects who were led to attribute responsibility to themselves. Also, it appeared that further drinking was affected by cognitive influences. Implications of the self-control phenomenon, especially regarding the non-pharmacological role and the etiology of excessive drinking, are discussed.</description><creator>Young, James A. (James Albert), 1951-</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Alcohol -- Physiological effect.</subject><title>Alcohol consumption and response : effects of the cognitive context</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b430s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jm31j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d504k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We say that a restriction theorem holds for a curve (gamma) (t) in (//R)('n) if for all f(epsilon) ((//R)('n)) and for some p and q, there is a constant C(,p,q) such that (VBAR)(VBAR) f (VBAR) (,(gamma)) (VBAR)(VBAR) (,L('q)(du)) (LESSTHEQ) C(,p,q) (VBAR)(VBAR) f (VBAR)(VBAR) (,L('P)((//R)('n))). In Chapter 1, we prove restriction theorems for non-compact plane curves with non-negative affine curvature when 1 (LESSTHEQ) p &lt; 4/3 and (DIAGRAM, TABLE OR GRAPHIC OMITTED...PLEASE SEE DAI) There is an analogous result for space curves in the same chapter. The Hilbert transform along the curve (gamma) is defined by (DIAGRAM, TABLE OR GRAPHIC OMITTED...PLEASE SEE DAI) In Chapter 2, it is shown that when (gamma) has the rapidly decreasing positive affine curvature, H(,(gamma)) is a L('P)-bounded operator for 5/3&lt;p&lt;5/2.</description><creator>Yamaguchi, Ryuji</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Fourier transformations.</subject><subject>Harmonic analysis.</subject><title>Geometry of Fourier transforms and restriction theorems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g598r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d504k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pr21x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The static mechanical properties of the respiratory system have been studied in newborn mammals (body size from rat to pig) and in animals (rats and rabbits) during growth. The elastic recoil pressure at functional residual capacity of the newborn is less than the adult value. The dry lung weight (LW)/body weight (BW) ratio is larger in the newborns (NB) than the adults (A). Functional residual capacity (FRC) is directly related to BW in the newborn. In general the FRC/BW ratio decreases with age while the FRC/LW increases. Respiratory system, lung and chest wall compliance are interspecific constants among newborn mammals. Examination of the NB and A allometric functions suggests that in general changes of respiratory variables are maturation dependent rather than size dependent. From the measurements of respiratory frequency and tracheal dimensions and assuming the calculated tracheal volume to be proportional to dead space the allometric relationship for dead space ventilation may be obtained. By employing the known allometric function for minute ventilation calculation suggests a constant alveolar P(,CO(,2)) and P(,O(,2)) for newborn mammals. Studies of the onset of breathing and the pattern of breathing at 10 min, 60 min, 90 min, and a few days after birth have been made in infants delivered by cesarean section and vaginally. The pattern of breathing at birth is irregular. The largest contribution to the formation of functional residual capacity in the first 30 seconds of life is made by the first breath. The first breath is deeper and slower with a longer expiration than subsequent breaths. The irregularity of the breathing pattern improves from 10 to 90 min after delivery. Breathing frequency remains high in this period (10-90 min) compared to a few days and tidal volume is increased at a few days compared to the early period of life.</description><creator>Fisher, J. T. (John T.)</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Comparative respiratory mechanics in newborn mammals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qs91v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pr21x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r185s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A general route to optically active organosulfur and phosphorus compounds was investigated. Sulfinimides incorporating camphorimide were synthesized directly from a sulfinyl chloride and N-(trimethylsilyl)camphorimide. The diastereomers were found to be inseparable by crystallization or chromatography, although in one case an optically active sulfinamide was prepared by an asymmetric synthesis. The phosphorus-imide bond was formed by coupling of an asymmetric phosphinous chloride and N-(trimethylsilyl)camphorimide. Addition of sulfur gave N-(phosphinothioyl)camphorimides as separable diastereomers. These were converted into optically active thiophosphoryl compounds which were chiral only at phosphorus. The absolute configurations of the diastereomers were obtained by single-crystal X-ray analysis, through NMR techniques and by conversion into phosphinothioic acids. Displacement of camphorimide was effected with organometallic reagents, alcohols and thiols to give optically active phosphine sulfides, phosphinothionates and phosphinodithioates respectively. Optical yields of the products were dependant on the reagents and reaction conditions used. Mechanistic rationales are presented to account for the stereochemical results.</description><creator>Friedlander, Barry Terence.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Phosphorus compounds.</subject><subject>Organosulfur compounds.</subject><title>The synthesis of chiral organosul fur and phosphorus compounds /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62f9176.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r185s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892b66g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis contains a critical review of the most important approaches to reported speech or those pertinent to it in the linguistic literature. Several problems concerning quotation parentheticals and presuppositions have been discussed and some solutions are proposed. The main issue, referred to as "the point of view", is worked out as an extension of the classical notion of transparency and opacity applied to NP, to several other elements of sentence structures. As a result, a set of interpretive rules are formulated which specify whether certain linguistic configurations promote a transparent or opaque interpretation of the sentence or part of it. Also, rules of correspondence are given which stipulate the conditions for semantic well formedness, in the case of omission of information.</description><creator>Forget, Danielle, 1952-</creator><date>1980</date><subject>English language -- Indirect discourse.</subject><subject>French language -- Indirect discourse.</subject><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Syntax.</subject><title>Analyse sémantique et pragmatique du discours rapporté</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634462v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b66g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q488c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Collagen production by skin fibroblast cell strains from normal subjects and age-matched patients with the mendelian disorder--Osteogenesis Imperfecta (OI)--was studied in culture. Number of generations in culture, phase of growth, labelling times, and site of biopsy did not influence collagen production by normal skin fibroblasts. OI cell strains from patients with dominantly inherited OI have abnormal morphology and growth in culture. The ratio of Type I to protype III collagen is reduced in OI Types I, II and IV (Sillence classification). Type III OI could not be distinguished from normal strains by the analysis used. From the collagen phenotype (biochemical parameters) we were able to distinguish different OI phenotypes and to correlate these with clinical phenotypes. One form of OI Type I produces an unstable collagen that is degraded to small peptides in culture.</description><creator>Fraser, Judith.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Fibroblasts.</subject><subject>Osteogenesis imperfecta.</subject><subject>Collagen.</subject><title>Collagen metabolism by fibroblasts from normals and individuals with Osteogenesis Imperfecta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm66j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q488c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311q151</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette these pose l'hypothese de la particularite du groupe des camionneurs de longue-distance (truckeurs) tant sur le plan des realites sous-culturelles que sur celui des discours ideologiques. Le travail de terrain s'est effectue dans le nord-ouest quebecois, c'est-a-dire en Abitibi et a la Baie James. Appliquant le concept de culture la ou l'on aurait tendance a avoir recours au concept du groupe de travail (occupationnel), s'appuyant sur la notion d'ideologie des truckeurs la ou l'on parlerait normalement d'ideologie de classe, l'argumentation demontre que le groupe d'identite en question est un groupe sous-culturel de plein droit, existant dans un territoire abstrait: l'univers routier. A partir de la description detaillee du proces de travail dans la perspective de la vie quotidienne, la these tente de faire l'analyse du "plaisir d'etre truckeur" en developpant une problematique specifique autour de la notion de force ainsi que de celles du controle, du rythme, de la meditation, du tournoi et de la creation de mondes. En ce sens, c'est une contribution a la comprehension des modes d'existence contemporains de la pensee et de la pratique symbolique.</description><creator>Bouchard, Serge.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Québec (Province) -- Social conditions -- 1960-1991</subject><subject>Truck drivers -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Transportation, Automotive -- Québec (Province) -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Nous autres, les gars de truck : essai sur la culture et l'idéologie des camionneurs de longue-distance dans le nord-ouest québécois</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fx598.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311q151</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g825</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A general equation was derived for calculating the weight-average molecular weight of the sol fraction, after gelation, of crosslinked copolymers formed by condensation polymerisation; the equation includes those of Flory and Stockmayer as special cases. In qualitative agreement with a gel-degradation model based on the general equation, soluble degradation products from a polymer gel of well defined structure displayed a pattern of increasing molecular weight with increasing solubilisation; it was also observed that the second virial coefficient and the refractive index increment showed a particular form of variation with molecular weight. The gel-degradation model, applied to the known chemistry of the acid-sulfite delignification of wood, provided a good fit to the experimental points of the previously known topochemical effect. Studies on the preparation of polyether-gel synthons required a detailed review of phase-transfer-catalysed etherification reactions, and provided an explanation for the lower reactivity of (beta)-haloethers relative to alkyl halides.</description><creator>Berry, Richard McKinnon.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Polymers.</subject><subject>Lignin.</subject><subject>Polymers -- Deterioration.</subject><title>The synthesis and degradation of polymer gels /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rm188.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g825</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859g594</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the past decade film analysis and semiotic inquiry have meshed to produce significant changes in film theory. This thesis discusses the philosophical and epistemological shift represented by this development, resulting in the creation of semiotic models (e.g. those of Christian Metz and Umberto Eco) which consistently overemphasize the textual framework for cinematic expression. As a result, problems of performance and interpretation are ignored. The thesis proposes a radically different strategy to explain meaning in film. To solve problems of performance the new concept of projections is proposed. Projections are defined not as images or pictures, but as sites (or performance events) of signification in film. The concept marks a fundamental shift away from close textual readings in its insistence that the cinema must be analyzed as part of a complex process of communication and exchange.</description><creator>Burnett, Ronald Frank.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Language and languages -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Motion pictures -- Philosophy.</subject><title>A philosophical and critical inquiry into film semiotics /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g81w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859g594</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Program in Communications</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w66344634</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Retention of verbal and non-verbal information was assessed in groups of hyperactive, normal and nonhyperactive reading disabled boys matched on age, verbal IQ and socio-economic status. The experimental tasks consisted of a series of verbal and a series of non-verbal measures that were analogous in design. Hyperactive children were comparable to normals in short-term and long-term retention of both verbal and non-verbal stimuli. However, their performance was significantly below that of normal children on tasks requiring effortful mental processing and organization. In contrast, reading disabled children were significantly worse than normals on the experimental tasks of verbal memory. This finding was interpreted as suggesting verbal encoding deficiences in nonhyperactive reading disabled children.</description><creator>Benezra, Esther.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Memory in children.</subject><subject>Hyperactive children.</subject><subject>Reading disability.</subject><title>Verbal and non-verbal memory in hyperactive, reading disabled and normal children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407z13b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66344634</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r875w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pan layers have been observed in profiles of humo-ferric podzol soils of the St. Lawrence Lowland region (Quebec, Canada). Physical, chemical and mineralogical studies were conducted on four selected profiles, three cultivated, and one non-cultivated, in order to assess the influence of cultivation in the development of an agric horizon. The non-clay fractions (2-0.02 mm) of the parent material contained chlorite, mica with feldspar and quartz as the predominant light minerals, hornblende, pyroxenes, olivines, epidote, magnetite, ilmenite, anatase and rutile in the heavy mineral fraction. The fine silt (2-20 (mu)m) and clay (&lt; 2 (mu)m) fractions of the sandy parent material contained primarily quartz, feldspars, chlorite, mica and hornblende minerals. During soil development and formation of agric horizon these minerals underwent weathering at different rates and to different extents. In the fine silt fraction, weathering seemed to occur mostly by fragmentation of particles. In the clay fractions of the cultivated profiles, the phyllosilicates successively formed irregularly interstratified minerals with contractible and expandable vermiculite and smectite but less so in the non-cultivated soil profile. The mineralogical composition of the agric horizon consisted of the non-expanding minerals, with a predominance of illite and chlorite. The release of iron and/or aluminum hydroxy materials resulting from weathering of silicate minerals, and their translocation in the form of organo-metal complexes to where they precipitated due to ionic concentration effects, contributed to the formation of the agric horizon.</description><creator>Seddyk, Esam Abdul-Sattar</creator><date>1979</date><subject>Agriculture, Agronomy.</subject><title>A study of the development of agric horizons in Quebec soils /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301215k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r875w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Soil Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999755d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Amino acid and potassium transport were studied in Alteromonas haloplanktis, strain 214, variant 3 (ATCC 19855). Stationary phase cells exhibited greater transport activity for AIB and K('+) than mid-logarithmic phase cells. Transport activity for amino acids in membrane vesicles was less than 1% of that in intact cells regardless of the method employed to form vesicles. French press disruption of protoplasts gave vesicle preparations with the greatest capacity for amino acid transport. Greater than 85% of the population of membrane vesicles in these preparations was oriented right-side-out as judged by freeze-etch electron microscopy. A membrane-bound, Mg('2+)-stimulated ATPase activity was present in vesicle preparations. Expression of this activity required disruption of the membrane vesicles, indicating its localisation on the inner surface of the vesicle membrane. This is further evidence that the vesicles are oriented right-side-out. K('+) transport was studied in K('+)-depleted cells by a K('+) ion-specific electrode technique. K('+) uptake was shown to be a strictly aerobic process and was concurrent with H('+) efflux. K('+) uptake occurs in response to a membrane potential and is not dependent on ATP. The membrane potential in whole cells was estimated from the K('+) distribution as -151mv. In vesicle preparations, (DELTA)(psi) was estimated by the distribution of ('3)H-TPMP('+) as -87mv. The failure of membrane vesicles to accumulate K('+) may be due to the low membrane potential that is generated in vesicle preparations.</description><creator>Sedgwick, Edward G.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Marine bacteria</subject><subject>Biological transport</subject><title>Studies on transport in whole cells and membrane vesicles of Alteromonas haloplanktis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv87x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999755d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708x44p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oreaster reticulatus was studied in eight populations inhabiting shallow-water grassbeds and/or sand bottoms off Carriacou and Union Island in the Grenadines, and off St. Croix in the U.S. Virgin Islands (Caribbean). The sea star is fundamentally an omnivorous, microphagous substratum grazer: grassblades and/or surface sediments are accumulated beneath the disc by tube feet, and associated micro-organisms and detritus are ingested and digested by extraoral eversion of the cardiac stomach. Substratum grazing involves minimal foraging effort; however, the low concentration of particulate food resources necessitates frequent feeding. O. reticulatus also has a limited capacity for herbivory and can hydrolyze soluble algal cell contents. Opportunistic predation and scavenging of macrofauna may provide an important nutritional supplement, although capturable prey or carrion are generally unavailable or inaccessible to the sea star. Marked differences in individual size, storage and reproductive capacity among neighboring populations of O. reticulatus are attributed to differences in the quality and/or quantity of food resources. Intraspecific competition may limit productivity, particularly in isolated sand patches containing dense and extremely aggregated populations.</description><creator>Scheibling, Robert Eric.</creator><date>1979</date><subject>Starfishes -- Caribbean Sea.</subject><subject>Echinodermata -- Caribbean Sea.</subject><title>The ecology of Oreaster reticulatus (L.) (Echinodermata : Asteroidea) in the Caribbean /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb27h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708x44p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Marine Sciences Centre</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xm67t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The conversion of 8,2'-S-anhydroadenosine to adenosine was studied in order to determine the feasibility of using 8,2'-S-anhydropurine nucleosides for oligoribonucleotide synthesis. Sulfoxide derivatives of 8,2'-S-anhydroadenosine were prepared efficiently; however when they were subjected to Pummerer reaction conditions in an attempt to introduce a 2'-substituent, extensive decomposition occurred. The synthesis of t-butyldimethylsilyl derivatives of cytidine and guanosine nucleosides was accomplished. Preparations were fast and simple, and most of the desired 2',5' diprotected nucleosides were obtained in greater than 50% yield from the nonsilylated nucleosides. Using the phosphorodichlorodite procedure, silylated nucleosides were easily incorporated into ribonucleotides. In addition to 3',5'-linked ribonucleotides, 2',5'- and symmetrically linked ribonucleotides were also prepared. ('1)H, ('13)C and ('31)P nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy was utilized in elucidating the structure of ribonucleotides; enzyme degradations on the completely deprotected ribonucleotides confirmed the position of the phosphate linkages.</description><creator>Schifman, Aria Libi.</creator><date>1979</date><subject>Nucleic acids.</subject><title>Approaches to the chemical synthesis of oligoribonucleotides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x17m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm67t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fp83q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mole drainage is an inexpensive form of drainage particularly suited to clay soils. Mole drainage is approved by Le Conseil des Productions Vegetales du Quebec to drain clay soils with low hydraulic conductivity. A few known trials on this technique of drainage have been done in Ontario and Alberta. In England and New Zealand, this technique is widely used. The large surface of heavy clay soil cultivated in Abitibi-Temiscamingue makes this region an excellent choice for trying this technique. Two sites established on two soil series (Palmarolle, Roquemaure) have been moled in Abitibi-Temiscamingue. These soils represent 21% of the cultivated land in this region. Twelve plots have been moled at varied depths, spaces and lengths. Physical and chemical soil properties have been measured to identify their influence on mole drainage stability. Water table, rainfall and the stability of the mole drains were monitored for three summers. Mole drain stability was observed with a borescope. Maturity growth and yield of a hay crop, and three types of cereals were measured. The mole drainage technique is satisfactory in heavy clay. The organic matter (${&gt;2 %}$), the water content of the soil (${&gt;40 %}$) at moling time and a small amount of rainfall (${&lt;6}$ mm) in the first week after moling positively influenced the stability of the mole drains. Some mole drains have kept 75% of their initial opening after three years of life. The water table was lower on one mole drained site. The yield of the hay and the three cereals were higher on the moled parcels. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Rivard, Pierre J.</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Drainage -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><subject>Clay soils -- Québec (Province) -- Abitibi-Témiscamingue.</subject><title>Evaluation de la technique de drainage-taupe dans les argiles lourdes de l'Abitibi-Témiscamingue</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn009z772.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fp83q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50ts447</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nonciliated epithelial cells of the efferent ducts are specialized in internalizing luminal fluid. They possess an extensive endocytic apparatus which provides an ideal system to study the kinetics of endocytosis. The nonciliated cells actively endocytose sulfated glycoprotein-1 (SGP-1, 70 kDa), a major secretory protein of Sertoli cells. A second form of SGP-1 (65 kDa) present in the secondary lysosomes of Sertoli and nonciliated cells of the efferent ducts is believed to be the equivalent of human prosaposin, the precursor of four small heat stable proteins (saposins A, B, C and D) required for the hydrolysis of sphingolipids by specific lysosomal hydrolases. This study was undertaken to investigate the contribution of Sertoli-derived SGP-1 as well as a putative endogenous SGP-1 within the secondary lysosomes of nonciliated cells. The hormonal control of endogenous lysosomal SGP-1, specifically the influence of testosterone withdrawal and its subsequent replacement was also examined. The results provide evidence that the nonciliated cells of the efferent ducts are involved in the clearance of testicular SGP-1 and reveal the presence of 15 kDa saposins and their 65 kDa precursor in secondary lysosomes of these cells. In addition, the production of an endogenous lysosomal SGP-1 targeted from the Golgi apparatus to the lysosomes after its glycosylation has also been demonstrated. The results further reveal that the endocytosis and lysosomal targeting of SGP-1 in nonciliated cells of the efferent ducts appear to be pituitary controlled.</description><creator>Rosenthal, Allison Lianne</creator><contributor>Morales, Carlos (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hermo, Louis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Sulfated glycoprotein-1 (SGP-1) biosynthesis and its regulation within the nonciliated cells of rat efferent ducts : an in vivo study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv372.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts447</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k343r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Secondary, or AA, amyloidosis is a systemic disease characterized by the extracellular tissue deposition of insoluble, fibrillar amyloid A protein. Aberrant metabolism of serum amyloid A protein by reticuloendothelial cells in the presence of amyloid enhancing factor (AEF) is thought to result in the accumulation of fibrils within the tissue. Treatment of mice with AEF, in conjunction with an inflammatory stimulus, induces amyloid deposition within 48-72 hours. In vivo examination of the effect of AEF on spleen macrophage activation-associated phenotype and functions reveal that AEF has no apparent effect on the ability of spleen and liver macrophages to phagocytose or kill Listeria monocytogenes. It did appear to block enhanced respiratory burst function as well as result in a decrease in the number of cells expressing the MHC Class II surface antigen. Polyacrylamide gel electrophoretic purification of AEF from crude amyloidotic tissue extracts attributed AEF activity to a region apparently consisting of 3 protein species with molecular weights ranging from 63.2 KDa to 47.9 KDa. Ex vivo studies of macrophage function with protein eluted from this "AEF-active" region did not indicate an inhibition of respiratory burst suggesting that the action of AEF may be dependent on the presence of additional, possibly inflammation-associated, component(s).</description><creator>Reid, Caroline L.</creator><contributor>Gervais, Francine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>The role of amyloid enhancing factor in the development of amyloid A amyloidosis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph10j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k343r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w576</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research has two objectives. First, mental health problems among refugee children were studied in terms of the intensity and the form of the symptomatology, and in terms of school performance. Second, the characteristics of the refugee process which influence the manifestation of these problems were identified as specific stressors stemming from the pre-migratory and post-migratory experiences of the refugees. The research was conducted among 156 refugee children, born in Southeast Asia and Central America. The methodology was based on both quantitative and qualitative approaches. Results indicate that the manifestation of emotional problems and the principal risk and protection factors vary greatly as a function of the ethnic origin of the subjects; this seems to be secondary to the interaction of specific cultural and contextual variables. This heterogeneity of the refugee children population put into question the strategies put forward by the schools and the health services for the detection and prevention of mental health problems in these children.</description><creator>Rousseau, Cécile</creator><contributor>Ellen, Corin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Les problèmes émotionnels chez les enfants réfugiés d'âge scolaire : cadre de présentation et facteurs associés</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257f94c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w576</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311q169</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A cost-effectiveness analysis is used to compare two alternative strategies for the control of tuberculosis in facilities providing long-term care to the elderly: (1) systematic screening of all new residents with the Mantoux test to identify persons infected with the tubercule bacillus, and preventive treatment of those who are most at risk of tuberculosis as recommended by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services and (2) clinical follow-up of the index-case contacts as recommended by the Quebec Ministry of Health and Social Services. Incremental effectiveness and cost associated with the American strategy are estimated with a Markov model applied to the Quebec long-term care facilities population. Costs are estimated in the perspective of the health care system. Even though complications due to isoniazid chemoprophylaxis cluster in the year following admission, the American approach is advantageous. At the end of the implementation phase throughout the province of Quebec, this approach prevents 32 cases of tuberculosis annually. The incremental cost is 121 626$ per year for the entire province, 3 822 $ per case avoided, 9 555$ per death avoided, 3 437 $ per life-year saved and 2 756$ per quality-adjusted life-years saved. Those costs compare favourably to other health prevention measures recommended for the elderly population.</description><creator>Marchand, Robert</creator><contributor>Tousignant, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Evaluation économique du dépistage et de la chimioprophylaxie de la tuberculose dans les établissements pour personne âgées</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj59r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311q169</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257f95n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research has indicated that the adjustment of psychiatric patients is adversely affected by family criticism. The present study elaborated on this theme by focusing on fifty schizophrenic patients who were formally interviewed, using a standard visual analog scale format, about their perception of family criticism. Two important conceptual distinctions were proposed. The first was the extent to which criticism was perceived as "constructive" or "destructive", and the second was the extent to which the criticism was perceived to be "person directed" or "behavior directed". Regression analyses were performed in order to determine the predictive utility of the various dimensions of criticism on patient outcomes. The results indicate first, that criticism is not always perceived as negative and secondly, patients who perceived high levels of negative criticism (destructive, person directed) had relatively poor outcomes. Those who perceived high levels of positive criticism (constructive, behavior directed) had more positive outcomes. The results therefore indicate that criticism is multidimensional. This awareness of different meanings of criticism may lead to early identification of adjustment difficulties and subsequent interventions to prevent them.</description><creator>McIntosh Byrne, Donna</creator><contributor>Jean, M. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Nursing.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>The relationship between perceived family criticism and quality of life and relapse rates in patients with schizophrenia /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt52v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257f95n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20500</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>