<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:00:53Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515r83q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The CYP27B1 enzyme that synthesizes 1alpha,25-(OH) 2D, is expressed in chondrocytes, suggesting that local production of 1alpha,25-(OH)2D could play an autocrine or paracrine role in the differentiation of these cells. To test this hypothesis, we have engineered mutant mice that do not express the Cyp27b1 gene in chondrocytes. This led to increased width of the hypertrophic zone of the growth plate at E15.5, increased bone mass in neonatal long bones, and increased expression of the chondrocytic differentiation markers Indian Hedgehog and PTH/PTHrP receptor. VEGF mRNA levels were decreased, accompanied by decreased PECAM-1 immunostaining, suggesting a delay in vascularization. We have also engineered mice overexpressing a Cyp27b1 transgene in chondrocytes. The transgenic mice showed a partial mirror image phenotype compared to the tissue-specific inactivation model. These results support an autocrine/paracrine role of 1alpha,25-(OH) 2D in endochondral ossification and chondrocyte development in vivo. The CYP24A1 enzyme is involved in the catabolic breakdown of 1alpha,25-(OH)2D but also synthesizes the 24R,25-(OH) 2D metabolite. Studies in chicken suggest a role for 24R,25-(OH) 2D in fracture repair. We induced stabilized transverse mid-diaphysial fractures of the tibia in four-month-old wild-type and Cyp24a1-deficient mice. Examination of the callus sections showed delayed hard callus formation in the homozygous mutant animals compared to wild-type littermates. RT-qPCR showed perturbed levels of type X collagen transcripts in mutant mice at 14 and 21 days post-fracture, reflecting the delayed healing. Rescue of the impaired healing by subcutaneous injection of 24R,25-(OH)2D3 normalized the histological appearance of the callus, static histomorphometric index and type X collagen mRNA expression, while 1alpha,25-(OH)2D 3 did not. These results show that Cyp24a1 deficiency delays fracture repair and strongly suggest that vitamin D metabolites hydroxylated at position 24, such as 24R,25-(OH)2D, play an important role in the mechanisms leading to normal fracture healing.</description><creator>Naja, Roy Pascal.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Bone and Bones -- physiology.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Mice, Knockout.</subject><subject>25-Hydroxyvitamin D3 1-alpha-Hydroxylase -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Receptors, Calcitriol -- metabolism.</subject><title>The role of Vitamin D metabolic enzymes in bone development and repair /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n49p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r83q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r207x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Modeling gravity recovery of platinum group minerals (PGMs) in the grinding circuit is based on three components: Ore characterization of gravity recoverable platinum group minerals (GRPGM), their behavior in grinding mills and hydrocyclones, and the performance of the gravity recovery units. This thesis focuses on the first two components. A laboratory methodology to characterize gravity-recoverable platinum group minerals (GRPGMs) in an ore with four incremental liberation and recovery stages was developed. It was applied to quantify GRPGM content of four ore samples from Canada. To measure the behavior of GRPGMs in the grinding circuit, a methodology to characterize the already liberated (or available) GRPGMs in the circuit streams was developed. The availability of GRPGM in streams, such as ball mill discharge, was used to model the behavior of the GRPGMs in the ball mills and hydrocyclones. Combining with the potential GRPGM in an ore, they can be used for design and/or optimization of platinum group mineral recovery circuit. The GRPGM content measured by this methodology varied from 5 to 81% depending on the ore. The GRPGM size distribution varied from fine (most GRPGM below 37mum) to coarse (significant content above 212 mum). The stage size-by-size recovery and the total GRPGM content indicate that the methodology can quantify the GRPGM content of ores. Based on the measurement of the availability of GRPGM in process streams, the behavior of PGMs in ball mills and hydrocyclones is characterized in terms of the less common cumulative selection functions and conventional classification efficiency curves. Mineralogical analysis indicates that sperrylite (PtAs 2) is the dominant platinum mineral at the Clarabelle mill. Its classification efficiency is similar to that of gold, despite its lower density, while grinding rate is significantly higher than gold. The cumulative selection function of platinum and palladium is 1.3 times higher than the ore for size classes above 212 mum and 50 to 70% of the ore below 212 mum. As a result, sperrylite accumulates in finer sizes than native gold in the grinding circuit. The cumulative selection function of the platinum group minerals was calculated for the Clarabelle grinding circuit based on the survey data and the GRPGM contents in the ball mill discharge, cyclone underflow, and overflow. The methodology of characterizing the content of GRPGMs in an ore also offers a way to concentrate the minerals for mineralogical study. The use of secondary electron microscopy (SEM), variable pressure SEM and QEM*SEM for qualitative analysis of platinum group mineral mineralogy is presented and discussed. Most of the GRPGMs recovered are well liberated. Qualitative mineralogical analysis of the GRPGM and its associations in ore samples are also discussed.</description><creator>Xiao, Zhixian, 1970-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Spiral concentrators.</subject><subject>Platinum group.</subject><subject>Ball mills.</subject><subject>Gravity concentrators.</subject><title>Characterizing the gravity recoverable platinum group minerals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js36q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r207x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354j794</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The soil-solution partitioning of dissolved organic carbon (DOC) within mineral soil horizons is primarily controlled by processes of adsorption and desorption. These abiotic processes largely occur within a short equilibration time of seconds to minutes, which generally occur faster than microbial processes. To characterise the adsorption of DOC to mineral soils, I used the Langmuir adsorption isotherm, which holds several advantages to the commonly used linear initial mass (IM) isotherm. One advantage to using the Langmuir isotherm is an estimation of the maximum DOC adsorption capacity (Qmax). The Qmax estimates the number of remaining DOC binding sites available on the mineral soil particle surfaces. I modified the traditional Langmuir isotherm in order to estimate the DOC desorption potential of native soil organic matter (SOC). Sorption characteristics were derived for a broad range of52 mineral soils collected from 17 soil profiles spanning across Canada from British Columbia to Quebec. Mineral horizons with the greatest Qmax included the Fe-enriched B horizons of acidic Podzols and Volcanic soils, followed by B horizons not enriched in Fe, followed by A and C horizons. Podzol B horizons were distinct from all other horizons due to significantly higher desorption potential. Soil properties predicting the adsorption characteristics of DOC also predicted the adsorption characteristics of dissolved organic nitrogen (DON). Adsorption of DOC and DON was tightly coupled (R 2 = 0.86), however the ratio of DOC:DON in the final equilibrium solution lowered for 48 out of 52 minerals horizons. These results suggest that DON may be slightly more mobile than DOC. A short-term (32 day) incubation was perform to establish the fate of indigenous soil C, relative to newly adsorbed soil C to four mineral soils with different adsorption characteristics. Soil columns were leached periodically and sampled for DOC and CO2 production. Two Fe-enriched mineral horizons with high adsorption capacity released low amounts of old SOC, yet released almost all of the newly adsorbed SOC. In contrast, two B horizons without Fe-enrichment released greater amounts of old SOC, and retained a greater fraction of the newly adsorbed SOC than the Fe-enriched horizons. These results identify a contrast between the fate of indigenous and newly adsorbed SOC on mineral soils with differing Qmax. The final component of this study examined changes to the molecular structure of DOC after equilibration with mineral soils. Multiple techniques were used to assess changes in the molecular composition of DOC, including the analysis of aromatic content by specific UV absorbance (SUVA) and fluorescence spectroscopy, analysis of molecular weight distribution (MWD) with high performance size exclusion chromatography (HPSEC) and functional group analysis with Fourier transform infra-red spectroscopy (FTIR). The solution phase DOC generally showed a reduced aromatic content, along with the removal of organic compounds with carboxyl groups. The MWD of DOC was reduced after equilibration to mineral soils, and the reduction in average molecular weight was related to the Qmax of mineral soils. The various components of this thesis have contributed to the overall understanding of controls on the adsorption of DOC and DON species to mineral soils of the Canadian temperate and boreal forest.</description><creator>Kothawala, Dolly N., 1972-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Soils -- Organic compound content -- Canada.</subject><subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- Canada.</subject><subject>Forest soils -- Canada.</subject><subject>Soil absorption and adsorption -- Canada.</subject><title>Controls on the soil solution partitioning of dissolved organic carbon and nitrogen in the mineral horizons of forested soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514np84h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354j794</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kx350</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Hypothalamic Pituitary Adrenal (HPA) axis is the coordinator of adaptive responses to physical and psychological stress. The central nervous system plays a key role in modulation of both basal and adaptive HPA axis functions. In fact, since long ago, animal studies have shown that acute and chronic exposure to glucocorticoids (a stress hormone released due to HPA axis activation, cortisol in humans) affects the function and the morphology of brain areas such as the hippocampus and the cingulate cortex. This thesis is based on novel neuroimaging methodologies used to investigate the interactions of psychological stress, cortisol and the brain. It consists of three functional studies and a morphometric one. In the first functional study we show that the hippocampus (where glucocorticoid receptors are most abundant) plays a role in initiation of an HPA axis stress response. In the second study, we provide evidence that besides hippocampus, the neural activity in the so-called "default mode network" (DMN), especially the anterior cingulate cortex (ACC), relates to interindividual variations in HPA axis response to psychological stress. In the third study we have investigated the cortisol-modulation of the DMN. Again, we provide evidence for a role of the ACC and the orbitofrontal cortex in negative feedback inhibition of the HPA axis activity. Finally, we show a morphological link between the ACC and the cortisol response to awakening which is an index of basal HPA axis activity. Overall, our findings confirm the critical role of the ACC and mesolimbic system in HPA axis regulation. These findings also draw attention to the interactions between functional subregions of the medial prefrontal cortex and states of HPA axis function prior to stress onset---suggesting an interplay of the monitoring and the executive planning roles of the medial prefrontal cortex in behavioral adaptation to stress. Beyond stress research, our findings offer a framework for combining neuroimaging and neuroendocrinology to better understand the interindividual variances in behavior, and perhaps to better identify subgroups at risk of psychological disorders.</description><creator>Khalili-Mahani, Najmeh, 1971-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Hydrocortisone -- secretion.</subject><subject>Stress, Psychological -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Magnetic Resonance Imaging.</subject><subject>Pituitary-Adrenal System -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Hypothalamo-Hypophyseal System -- metabolism.</subject><title>Observing the stressed brain : magnetic resonance imaging of the neural correlates of hypothalamic pituitary adrenal axis function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537443d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx350</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zf63c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis was to understand the spatial patterns and processes responsible for canopy and understorey spider (Arachnida: Araneae) diversity at multiple spatial scales in north-temperate hardwood forests. I sampled tree trunks (sticky traps) and foliage (beating) of sugar maple and American beech tree canopies and their understorey saplings in old growth forests near Montreal, Quebec. Results show the composition of canopy and understorey assemblages differed significantly, and so did sugar maple and American beech canopy assemblages. Each stratum was also dominated by different species. The rank-abundance distribution of species from each habitat wsa also verticaly stratified because it fit different distribution models. Different factors likely structure assemblages in both habitats, particularly since the canopy is a less stable environment. Spiders from canopy and understorey foliage were tested in a laboratory for their propensity to balloon. General linear models indicated that small sized web-building spiders of the RTA and Orbicularia clades have the highest propensity to balloon. Small bodied species initiated ballooning regardless of the habitat they were collected in or their developmental stage. My results support the mixed evolutionarily stable strategy theory and indicate the absence of risk-spreading in the dispersal strategy of canopy spiders. My last chapter focused on dispersal capacity and diversity patterns of spiders at multiple spatial scales. Analyses of the species diversity of limited and high dispersal capacity species subsets through nested-multivariate ANOVA, additive diversity partitioning, and species-abundance distribution curves all point towards species-sorting processes as the main driver of local community spider diversity at the tree and stand spatial scales. Mass-effects and patch-dynamic processes drive site and regional scale diversity patterns. This thesis demonstrates that spiders provide good models to test many biological hypotheses. The research chapters of this thesis test hypotheses on the vertical stratification of forest spider diversity, the evolution of local dispersal adaptations, and the importance of dispersal capacity on species diversity patterns through a metacommunity framework.</description><creator>Larrivée, Maxim.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Sugar maple -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Old growth forest ecology -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Forest canopy ecology -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>American beech -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Spiders -- Ecology -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Diversity of canopy spiders in north-temperate hardwood forests</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741w18m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zf63c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096b59d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regrowth in the lesioned central nervous system is impeded by inhibitory molecules including myelin-associated inhibitors (MAIs) and chondroitin sulfate proteoglycans (CSPGs). Inhibitory molecules engage neuronal cell surface receptors and activate the small GTPase RhoA in injured neurons to mediate neurite outgrowth inhibition through targeted modifications to the cytoskeleton. Inhibition of RhoA with the ribosyltransferase C3 attenuates neurite outgrowth inhibition in vitro and in vivo but the ubiquitous expression and multifunctionality of RhoA may limit the specificity of therapeutic RhoA antagonists. The hypothesis of the thesis is that molecules that functionally interact with RhoA to mediate myelin-dependent inhibition may represent more specific targets for therapeutic intervention. We have explored the contribution of two RhoA interacting proteins to the neurite outgrowth inhibitory effects of MAIs. In Chapter 2 we describe the contribution of the rho effector, Rho kinase (ROCK) to MAI responses in neurons. In Chapter 3 we identify the cytosolic phosphoprotein CRMP4b (Collapsin Response Mediator Protein 4b) as a novel RhoA binding partner that mediates neuronal responses to CNS inhibitors. By structure function analysis we have developed a molecular antagonist of CRMP4b-RhoA binding that promotes neurite outgrowth on inhibitory substrates in vitro and has the potential to be a potent and specific molecular therapeutic for spinal cord injury. In Chapter 4 we identify glycogen sythase kinase 3b (GSK3b) as an important kinase in the MAI pathway that regulates protein interactions with RhoA. This thesis provides insights into the signal transduction machinery that is engaged in response to CNS inhibitors and suggests several novel therapeutic targets to promote axon regeneration following CNS injury.</description><creator>Alabed, Yazan Z., 1979-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Myelin Proteins -- physiology.</subject><subject>Nerve Regeneration -- physiology.</subject><subject>rhoA GTP-Binding Protein -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Neural Inhibition -- physiology.</subject><subject>Receptors, Cell Surface -- physiology.</subject><subject>Axons -- physiology.</subject><title>The role of RhoA interacting proteins in the Nogo signalling pathway of axon outgrowth inhibition /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860b25b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b59d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s597r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Septic shock is a leading cause of death in intensive care units. As part of the septic process, the endothelium becomes activated and propagates the septic condition. It has become evident that reactive oxygen species (ROS) are involved in the signaling of mediators of sepsis, such as tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-alpha) and the lipopolysaccharide coating of gram-negative bacteria (LPS). An important source of these ROS is NADPH oxidase, which is a ubiquitously expressed enzyme complex that also exists in endothelial cells (EC). We showed that O2- from NADPH oxidase was important for LPS, as well as TNF-alpha, induction of two markers of an activated endothelium, interleukin-8 (IL-8) and intercellular adhesion molecule-1 (ICAM-1) in human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVEC). Expression of a gene can be increased by a rise in transcription as well as post-transcriptional changes, such as mRNA stability modifications. We assessed the role of NADPH oxidase in this process and found a complex interaction. Although LPS increases IL-8 transcription, it also destabilizes IL-8 mRNA in a p38 and extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK) MAPK dependent manner, which was only evident after blocking NADPH oxidase. This regulation involved the mRNA de-stabilizing factor tristetraprolin (TTP). In contrast, TNF-alpha enhanced the stability of IL-8, IL-6 and ICAM-1 mRNA in a p38 MAPK dependent, but NADPH oxidase independent manner. Furthermore, LPS did not have an effect on mRNA stability of IL-6 or ICAM-1 in our system. Thus, we conclude from our studies that the NAPDH oxidase is important for the induction of inflammatory molecules in LPS and TNF-alpha treated EC and is also involved in mRNA stability regulation of these molecules in a signal and gene specific fashion.</description><creator>Al Ghouleh, Imad, 1977-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Sepsis -- enzymology.</subject><subject>Reactive Oxygen Species -- metabolism.</subject><subject>NADPH Oxidase -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Endothelial Cells -- pathology.</subject><title>The role of nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (reduced form) oxidase in endothelial activation in sepsis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h075s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s597r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010t551</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prostate cancer remains one of the most commonly diagnosed cancers in men and is a leading cause of cancer death. While great success has been achieved at curing early stage prostate cancer, limited success has been obtained when treating late-stage hormone independent prostate cancer. This is due to the increased propensity for skeletal and non-skeletal metastases. Thus development of novel effective therapeutic modalities against late stage prostate cancer is of critical importance. Towards these objectives, I have focused my attention on the role of prostate secretory protein (PSP-94) which is expressed in normal individuals and in patients with early stage prostate cancer. Using our well established in vivo models of prostate cancer, I have evaluated the ability of PSP-94 and its amino acids 31-45 required (PCK3145) to decrease tumor growth and skeletal metastases in vivo and evaluated the potential mechanism(s) associated with PCK3145 anti-cancer actions. Prostatic cancer can also develop as a result of epigenetic activation of tumor promoting genes. To evaluate the role of methylation in prostate cancer, late stage prostate cancer cells were treated with the universal methylating agent S-adenosylmethionine (SAM) and an anti-sense oligonucleotide directed against MBD2 (AS). Scrambled oligonucleotide was included as a control (S). Both SAM and MBD2-AS resulted in inhibition in uPA, MMP-2 and VEGF production leading to decreased tumor cell invasive capacity. However, SAM and MBD2-AS were not able to either further repress partially methylated genes (GSTP1) or reactivate already methylated genes (AR). Furthermore, SAM and MBD2-AS treatment resulted in significant reduction in tumor growth in vivo . Immunohistochemical and RT-PCR analyses carried out on SAM and MBD2-AS tumors revealed decreased protein and mRNA expression of uPA and MMP-2 which was partially due to increased methylation of the respective promoters even after 10 weeks post in vitro treatment as analyzed by bisulfate sequencing. In addition decreased levels of angiogenesis and tumor survival markers were observed. Collectively, these studies are aimed at the development of novel reliable approached to diagnose and treat advanced, hormone refractory prostate cancer to reduce tumor associated morbidity and mortality.</description><creator>Shukeir, Nicholas.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Prostatic Secretory Proteins -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Bone Neoplasms -- secondary.</subject><subject>Prostatic Neoplasms -- drug therapy.</subject><subject>Antineoplastic Agents -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Peptide Fragments -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Bone Neoplasms -- prevention &amp; control.</subject><title>Molecular mechanism(s) of prostate cancer progression : potential of therapeutic modalities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zm255.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t551</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311s96n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main purpose of this work is to study model category structures (in the sense of Quillen) on the categories of small categories and small symmetric multicategories enriched over an arbitrary monoidal model category. Among these model structures, there is one of the greatest importance in applications. We call it the Dwyer-Kan model structure (for enriched categories or enriched symmetric multicategories), and a large amount of this work is dedicated to establishing it for different choices of monoidal model categories. Another model structure that we study is what we call the fibred model structure, again for both small categories and small symmetric multicategories enriched over a suitable monoidal model category. The other purpose of this work is to study model category structures on the category of comonoids in a monoidal model category.</description><creator>Stanculescu, Alexandru.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Homotopy theory.</subject><subject>Model categories (Mathematics)</subject><title>Homotopy theories on enriched categories and on comonoids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720h40n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s96n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jq21x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary goal of this study is to develop novel metal catalyzed multicomponent reaction methods to generate imidazoles and their derivatives. This is directed towards the assembly of poly-substituted imidazoles, imidazolones and imidazole-containing pi-conjugated polymers. These products are generated in one-pot from such basic components as imines, acid chlorides, carbon monoxide, and/or organostannanes, via the use of palladium catalysis. In Chapter 2, the design of a new palladium catalyzed synthesis of highly substituted imidazoles from imines and acid chlorides is described. This reaction involves the palladium catalyzed generation of 1, 3-oxazolium-5-oxides (Munchnones); which are trapped with N-tosyl substituted imines via a 1, 3 dipolar cycloaddition reaction to form the final products. Overall, this provides a one step method to assemble imidazoles from imines and acid chlorides with excellent regiochemical control. The versatility of this process is demonstrated by the assembly of diversely substituted imidazoles, including those with aryl, alkyl, heterocyclic and vinyl substituents. Chapter 3 describes a new, palladium catalyzed, five component coupling of imines, chloroformates, organotin reagents, carbon monoxide and ammonium acetate to form imidazolones. The key step in this process is the efficient formation of ketocarbamates via the carbonylative cross coupling type reaction of imines, chloroformates and organostannanes. These products can be easily converted into imidazolones via a cyclocondensation with ammonium acetate. The synthesis of pi-conjugated imidazole-containing polymers is described in Chapter 4. This process is designed based upon our previous studies on palladium catalyzed multicomponent synthesis of imidazoles, developed in Chapter 2. It is shown that bifunctional monomers such as di-imines, di-acid chlorides and di-N-tosylimines can be coupled together to assemble pi-conjugated imidazole-containing oligomers and polymers utilizing this same palladium catalyzed reaction. This approach was used to create a novel library of conjugated imidazole polymers. By modifying the substituents on the polymer structures, the UV-vis absorbance and fluorescence excitation/emission spectra of these compounds are varied over a range of 150 nm. In Chapter 5, the palladium catalyzed multicomponent polymerization is discussed in more detail. This includes the analysis of the end groups on the polymer backbone, as well as mechanistic studies into how the polymerization is terminated. These results suggest that the sulfinate anion liberated upon N-tosylimine cycloaddition may be non-innocent in this polymerization, and its presence could lead to termination of the growing polymer chain.</description><creator>Siamaki, Ali Reza, 1965-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Palladium catalysts.</subject><subject>Imidazolines -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Conjugated polymers -- Synthesis.</subject><title>The palladium catalyzed multicomponent synthesis of imidazoles and imidazole-containing [pi]-conjugated polymers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g131c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jq21x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322j19s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Feeding behavior is a complex phenomenon involving homeostatic signals, and non-homeostatic inputs such as visual cues. In primates, exposure to food-related sensory cues has been shown to elicit cephalic phase responses as well as trigger central appetitive processing, in a motivationally-dependent manner. Neural structures consistently implicated in such responses and/or in the regulation of ingestive behavior in general, in both monkeys and in humans, include the amygdala, insula, striatum, hypothalamus, and frontal and occipital cortices. In humans however, the cerebral response to visual food stimulation remains minimally explored. Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) provides information about state-dependent changes in local neuronal activity in vivo. Using fMRI, the present dissertation examined changes in human brain activity to food and nonfood pictures following the pharmacological induction of hunger with the orexigenic hormone ghrelin (Study 1), and following manipulation of the cognitive state of food expectation (Study 2). Our data reinforce the involvement of a distributed frontal-limbic-paralimbic circuit in the central processing of food imagery, under both experimental conditions. The first study revealed that intravenous ghrelin administration potently modulated food-associated neural responses III areas involved in reward, motivation, memory, and attention (amygdala, insula, orbitofrontal cortex, striatum, hippocampus, midbrain, visual areas). This suggests that metabolic signals such as ghrelin may promote food consumption by enhancing the appetitive response to food cues via engagement of the hedonic network. The second study revealed that brain regions activated in the 'expectant' state (i.e. when subjects were anticipating food reward) were at least partially dissociable from those in the 'not expectant' state. In particular, recruitment of the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, a principal component in the cognitive control network, exclusively in the 'not expectant' condition, may signal an attempt to suppress appetite in the absence of food expectation. Areas of convergence were observed in the amygdala and insula. Obesity is rapidly becoming the major cause of excess mortality worldwide; therefore, understanding how the central nervous system controls appetite and nutrient consumption is of considerable interest. The projects in this thesis offer significant insights regarding the effects two select factors (one intrinsic and the other extrinsic) on the neural reaction to visual food stimuli, in healthy male participants.</description><creator>Malik, Saima.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Amygdala -- physiology.</subject><subject>Food.</subject><subject>Magnetic Resonance Imaging.</subject><subject>Frontal Lobe -- physiology.</subject><subject>Feeding Behavior -- psychology.</subject><subject>Ghrelin</subject><subject>Hunger -- physiology.</subject><title>Neural substrates of feeding behavior : insights from fMRI studies in humans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v1962.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j19s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94ht18c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is an accumulating body of evidence suggesting that being raised in a non-intact family may adversely affect child outcomes across a number of developmental domains. There are nevertheless questions re: interpretation for a number of methodological reasons ranging from conceptualization of exposure to analytic approach. Given the dynamic nature of family life for some children today, changes in family structure may need to be captured in a more comprehensive manner. The scientific question is how capturing dynamics of family structure can be achieved. Data were drawn from the National Longitudinal Survey of Children and Youth (NLSCY), an ongoing longitudinal population survey following cohorts of Canadian children from infancy to adulthood across a number of domains of health and well-being. The sample comprised individuals aged 11-14 in cycle five of the NLSCY. We examined different approaches to conceptualizing and modeling the effect of the family structure effect based on previous studies in this area and from the lifecourse epidemiological literature. We examined the effects of current family structure, previous family structures, trajectories of family structure, and change in family structure on externalizing and internalizing behavior in pre-adolescence. We found that the validity of each approach was largely dependent on the specific research question at hand, with each one having its own advantages and disadvantages. Main methodological findings included confounding of the current family structure effect by previous experience, collinearity among family structure main effects, and low analytic power for trajectories. Guided by a conceptual diagram of the underlying causal structure, we also considered the time-varying nature of family income and employment status of the primary household respondent using inverse probability weighting to estimate the causal parameters of a marginal structural model. In one of our most sophisticated conceptualizations of family structure effects, we found that recent change in family structure had a statistically significant effect on the odds of externalizing behavior, OR (95% CI) = 2.95 (1.73-5.02). Overall, our substantive findings were tempered by methodological caveats, which have important implications for future studies in the area and for broader issues related to data collection, study design, and analysis.</description><creator>McDonald, Sheila, 1971 Nov.17-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Parent-Child Relations -- Canada.</subject><subject>Child Behavior -- Canada.</subject><subject>Family Relations -- Canada.</subject><subject>Child Behavior Disorders -- epidemiology -- Canada.</subject><subject>Risk Factors -- Canada.</subject><title>A lifecourse epidemiological study of dynamic family structure and child behavior : conceptualization and modeling issues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh10k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94ht18c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xj35p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While most people with schizophrenia face the functional consequences of a lifelong disorder, very few studies have investigated the specific domain of daily living activities performance. The purpose of this thesis was to examine the relationships between daily activity performance, cognitive deficits, and community functioning in people with schizophrenia. More specifically, the objectives were: 1) to describe functional limitations during daily task performance, 2) to explore the existence of subgroups of participants with similar functional limitations profiles, 3) to explore the relationships between daily task performance and cognitive functions as well as 4) with community functioning. This thesis tested the hypothesis that limitations in task performance negatively influence community functioning. A sample of 82 individuals with schizophrenia and 28 healthy controls participated in this study and were assessed during a meal preparation task with the Perceive, Recall, Plan and Perform (PRPP) System of Task Analysis and on cognitive tests of visuospatial memory, spatial working memory, visuomotor coordination, planning and selective attention. Community functioning was assessed with the Independent living Skills Survey and the Multnomah Community Ability Scale. Limitations in the Perceive, Recall and Plan quadrants of the PRPP System, were found in participants with schizophrenia when compared to a control group (n = 28), as well as in the complete sample (n = 82). Participants in the high-efficiency subgroup ( n =36) were more independent in daily living and performed better on the visuospatial associative learning task than the low-efficiency subgroup (n = 46). At the specific level of individual profiles, participants were distributed along a continuum of low- to high-functioning on the PRPP System factors and on functional, cognitive, and clinical characteristics. The associative learning task was most associated with task performance, along with working memory and planning. Finally, less efficient planning skills were associated with a lower level of community functioning, confirming the hypothesis. These results emphasize the relationship of associative visual memory to daily task performance, as well as that of efficiency in daily activities for residential status. Integrating these findings into the rehabilitation process will contribute to better meeting the needs of people with schizophrenia.</description><creator>Aubin, Ginette.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Psychomotor Performance.</subject><subject>Activities of Daily Living -- psychology.</subject><subject>Social Environment.</subject><subject>Schizophrenia -- diagnosis.</subject><subject>Cognition Disorders -- diagnosis.</subject><subject>Schizophrenic Psychology.</subject><title>Daily activities in people with schizophrenia : relationships with cognition and community functioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wr29n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj35p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gx231</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Uveal Melanoma (UM) is the most common malignant intra-ocular tumor in adults. Despite the high accuracy of clinical diagnosis and advances in local treatment, more than 50% of UM patients develop metastasis within ten years of initial diagnosis. NM23 is a human metastasis suppressor gene. Reduced Nm23-H1 expression is correlated with high metastatic potential in a variety of different cancers including melanoma. C-Met is a receptor tyrosine kinase (RTK) that has been known to stimulate the invasive growth and increase the metastatic potential of cancer cells. Expression of c-Met is correlated with high mortality rate in UM patients. Treatment with CQX-2 inhibitors showed promise as an adjuvant therapy in adenocarcinoma of the colon. A previous report from our laboratory showed that topical treatment with Nepafenac (a CQX-2 inhibitor) delayed the progression of the primary tumor and the formation of metastasis in the experimental rabbit model of UM. The purpose of this thesis is to investigate the expression levels ofNm23-H1 in UM cell lines with different metastatic potentials, in paraffin embedded tissues from primary tumors of UM patients, and in an experimental rabbit model. In addition, the aim of this thesis is to determine whether treating human uveal melanoma cell lines with Nepafenac would increase the expression levels of Nm23-H1 and decrease the expression levels of c-Met in vitro (UM cell lines) and in vivo (experimental rabbit model). To achieve our goal, we used several types of assays in our UM cell lines and paraffin embedded tissues from patient samples and experimental rabbit model, including quantitative immunostaining, quantitative Real-time PCR, and small interference RNA (siRNA). The Real-time PCR results of five human uveal melanoma cell lines showed that expression of Nm23-HI is higher in cell lines with low metastatic potential compared to those with high metastatic potential. The invasive ability of the uveal melanoma cell lines increased after silencing Nm23-H1 expression with siRNA. The increased immunostaining intensity of Nm23-H1 in patient samples is associated with better survival rate. Moreover, treatment with Nepafenac resulted in increase of Nm23-H1 levels and decrease of c-Met levels in both the UM cell lines and the experimental rabbit model. In conclusion, Nm23-H1 is a potent prognostic marker to predict the survival rate of UM patients and it has the potential to identify high-risk patients. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study to show that treatment with COX-2 inhibitor causes an upregulation of Nm23-H1 and downregulation of c-Met in UM. Therefore, treatment with COX-2 inhibitors may be a useful strategy as an adjuvant therapy for UM patients.</description><creator>Bakalian, Silvin.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Tumor Markers, Biological -- genetics.</subject><subject>Uveal Neoplasms -- genetics.</subject><subject>NM23 Nucleoside Diphosphate Kinases -- genetics.</subject><subject>Melanoma -- genetics.</subject><title>The role of Nm23-H1 in uveal melanoma /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p04s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx231</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010t569</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study quasi superharmonic functions in Brelot spaces and the relationship between a reduced function, and harmonic and Jensen measures. We introduce the concept of quasi multiply superharmonic functions on a product of two Brelot spaces and study their properties. A main result obtained is characterizing the quasi superharmonic functions in terms of harmonic, finely harmonic and Jensen measures. Then we prove that a quasi multiply superharmonic function on a product of Brelot spaces equals its lower semicontinuous regularization out side of a 2-negligible set. Further we give a sufficient condition on a Brelot space O under which O becomes an extension space for superharmonic functions. As a result we characterize the extreme Jensen measures in such spaces. Finally we study extreme Jensen measures relative to several classes of multiply superharmonic functions.</description><creator>Alakhrass, Mohammad.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Axiomatic set theory.</subject><subject>Harmonic functions.</subject><title>Superharmonic and multiply superharmonic functions and Jensen measures in axiomatic Brelot spaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b152.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t569</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935643m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite considerable evidence in older populations that food intake can improve mental performance, little is known about the acute effects of feeding on cognition in the newborn period, a time when learning and memory are critical for discovering and adapting to everyday experiences. Feeding occurs well over 2500 times in the first year of life, raising the possibility that iterative effects on cognition may have cumulative effects over time. We recently demonstrated feeding enhancement of memory in two-to-three day old infants. Infants tested after a feed (versus before) displayed better memory for unfamiliar spoken words they previously habituated to and that were represented after a 100s delay. In this Doctoral Thesis, Studies 1 and 2 explore further the influence of feeding on short-term retention of spoken words. Memory was assessed using headturning and the Habituation-Recovery response. Study 1 extended the effect to older infants aged two-to-three weeks. Memory was enhanced after a feed over even longer delays, including 100s, 200s, 300s, 400s, and 500s. The overall gain in memory as measured by prefeed and postfeed differences at each delay was over two minutes long. Because newborn infants are more likely to hear recurrent words spoken by familiar voices, auditory experiences that they preferentially recognize, Study 2 looked at the separate effects of familiarity and feeding. Two day-old infants were assessed for either familiar speech-sound ("baby" spoken by the mother) or unfamiliar speech-sound from Study 1 ("beagle" spoken by a female stranger). The baby-mother sound stimulus was remembered better over a retention interval of 85 seconds than unfamiliar beagle-stranger, suggesting a strong influence of familiarity. To define the extent of the feeding effect, Study 3 examined sensorimotor processing of a reflex response. Three day-olds were assessed on habituation and retention of habituation of the glabella blink reflex over delays of 8s and l8s. No effect of feeding was found. Taken together, the implications of these findings are twofold. First, enhancement of memory for speech-sound by iterative feeding or recurrent exposure to familiar speech-sound stimuli may facilitate the acquisition of language. Second, feeding effects on cognition may depend on the nature of the task and previous experience with the stimulus. Further research is necessary for identifying what kinds of information and what processing abilities are more susceptible to the effects of feeding in early infancy.</description><creator>Valiante, A. Grace (Antonella Grace)</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Cognition -- physiology.</subject><subject>Infant, Newborn.</subject><subject>Language Development.</subject><subject>Infant Nutritional Physiological Phenomena</subject><title>Acute effects of feeding on cognition in healthy well-nourished newborn infants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161973c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935643m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wc07q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chickpea (Cicer arietinum L.) seed is a potential source of protein ingredients with desirable nutritional and functional properties. Knowledge of molecular characteristics of a food protein is essential before a protein can gain widespread use as a food ingredient. The objectives of this study were to prepare chickpea proteins using different extraction methods and precipitation methods and to investigate molecular characteristics using polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (PAGE; Native and SDS), reversed phase high performance liquid chromatography (RP-HPLC) and electrospray ionization mass spectrometry (ESI-MS) techniques. Proteins of ground chickpea seed were extracted with sodium hydroxide (NaOH) and with citric acid solutions and precipitated with addition of acid and by cryoprecipitation. The protein contents of the protein preparation ranged from 49% to 97%. The microstructures of chickpea protein isolates examined by scanning electron microscope (SEM) revealed the presence of starch grains in the cryoprecipitates from citric acid extraction but not in isoelectric precipitates. The globulins (legumins and vicilins), glutelins, and albumins from both citric acid and NaOH isolates were characterized by Native-PAGE. The cryoprecipitates contained mainly the globulin-rich proteins. With SDS-PAGE characterization, protein subunits were identified as follows: (i) legumin subunits: MW 40, 39, 26, 23, and 22 kDa, (ii) vicilin subunits: MW 50, 37, 33, 19, and 15 kDa, (iii) glutelin subunits: 58, 55, and 54 kDa, and (iv) albumin subunits: 10 kDa. Separation of fractions of isolated chickpea proteins by RP-HPLC showed that early eluting fractions (Rt 20-30 min) consisted of subunits of MW 6.5-31 kDa (SDS-PAGE). At elution time 30-36 min, the fractions obtained were composed mainly of mixtures of legumin and vicilin subunits (MW 14-45 kDa). The major subunits of chickpea protein fractions from both cryoprecipitates and isoelectric precipitates are legumin basic subunit (MW~23 kDa) and vicilin-rich proteins (MW~19, 17, 15 kDa). ESI-MS analysis of fractions separated by RP-HPLC showed MW ranging between 5.1 and 53.5 kDa. The subunits of MW 35366, 27626, 22864, 20531, 16092, and 15626 Da of fractions from ESI-MS corresponded to MW 35.3, 28.0, 24.1, 20.5, 16.1, and 15.3 kDa identified in SDS-PAGE. These fractions were identified as legumin-rich and vicilin-rich proteins.</description><creator>Chang, Yu-Wei, 1977-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chickpea -- Seeds.</subject><subject>Seed proteins.</subject><subject>Proteins -- Separation.</subject><title>Isolation and characterization of proteins from chickpea (Cicer arietinum L.) seeds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30px34g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wc07q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g3641</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this study was to design, characterize and test a flow-through extraction cell for rapid determination of toxic metals present in soil and sediment samples. Based on a design elaborated by Jean Bouffard, a Teflon cell was first machined, but it appeared to be leaky and hard to disassemble without breaking the fritted glass discs. To overcome these difficulties, a poly ether ether ketone (PEEK) cell was machined and several parts were modified. Even though the shape and seal of the components seemed to be affected when heated, the cell was working at room temperature and proved promising for future work. Finally, the EPA (Environmental Protection Agency) method 1311 was applied on some real samples, and the extracts were analyzed in order to get reference results that could eventually be compared to results given by extracts obtained with the flow-through cell.* *This dissertation is a compound document (contains both a paper copy and a CD as part of the dissertation). The CD requires the following system requirements: Microsoft Office.</description><creator>Asselin, Julie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Agriculture, Soil Science.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><title>Design of a flow-through extraction cell for rapid determination of toxic metals (arsenic, cadmium, chromium, copper, mercury, lead, tin, zinc) from soils and sediments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j2438.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g3641</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537444p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Discrepancies in ecotoxicity effects data derived from soils amended with dissolved metals in the laboratory and soils from historically aged metal-contaminated sites pose a challenge in deriving environmentally relevant soil quality criteria. In this thesis, the chemical artefacts produced by dissolved metal additions and the subsequent effects on metal bioavailability, toxicity and bioaccumulation are examined. The overall goal of this research is to advance the understanding of soil trace metal bioavailability mechanisms and improve current methods for ecotoxicity testing and bioavailability modeling. The first objective was to develop a leaching method which would minimize the "salt-effect" commonly observed in freshly-spiked soil samples. This was achieved by adapting a column leaching procedure in order to spike and leach larger volumes of test soil as a preparatory step prior to ecotoxicity assays. An experiment was set up to observe changes to leachate chemistry resulting from the dissolved Cu additions and subsequent leaching with two weak electrolyte solutions. Results showed that leaching removed the excess dissolved Cu as well as the excess acidity and base cations that were solubilized during the Cu additions. Differences between control and spiked samples of some key soil solution parameters (e.g. pH, DOC and total dissolved Ca, Mg, Al, Fe) were reduced thereby resulting in a set of spiked samples more conducive to deriving causal dose-response relationships. A second experiment compared soil and soil solution properties of samples which underwent the spike/leach procedure to those of freshly spiked samples. Lower soil pH (up to 0.81 pH units) and DOC concentrations were observed in non-leached samples as well as up to 35-fold and 55-fold increases of dissolved Ca and Mg concentrations, typical of the salt-effect. It was estimated that the non-leached samples contained up to 100-fold greater Cu2+ and 50-fold greater Al3+ activities which, I hypothesized, could result in greater phytotoxicity of non-leached samples. Bioassays were conducted wherein Hordeum vulgare (barley) seedlings were exposed to the leached and non-leached Cu-spiked soil samples for 14 days. The leached samples were less toxic to barley and showed significant increases (up to 1.7-fold) in median inhibitory concentrations (i.e. IC50) for root elongation in two of the three test soils. The Cu2+ fraction was able to explain much of the variability in toxicity between leached and non-leached samples, as well as among the different test soils. One exception was the most acidic test soil for which plants in the leached samples showed up to 10-fold greater toxicity than plants in the non-leached samples, when exposed to similar Cu2+ activities. Soil speciation and bioaccumulation data for Cu, Al and Ca were used to deduce that Ca deficiency and possibly Al toxicity contributed to the toxicity observed in this sample set. In a modeling exercise, the concepts of the terrestrial biotic ligand model (TBLM), which take into account ion competition at the soil solution/root interface, to describe toxic response in our samples. Results showed that the additive effects of Cu and Al toxicity estimated from the Cu-root ligand complex (Cu-BL+) and Al-root ligand complex (Al-BL2+ ) accounted for more of the variability in toxic response data than did the Cu2+ fraction or the Cu-BL+ fraction alone. The model however, could not account for the effects of the Cu-induced Ca deficiency in the most acidic test soil, thus highlighting one of the limitations of the TBLM. This thesis has contributed to the understanding of metal bioavailability mechanisms affected by soil spiking procedures and highlights the benefits of soil leaching in preparing soil samples for ecotoxicity assays which should improve trace metal risk assessment in the future.</description><creator>Schwertfeger, Dina</creator><date>2010</date><subject>Agriculture, Soil Science.</subject><subject>Biogeochemistry.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><title>The effects of soil leaching on metal bioavailability, toxicity and accumulation in Hordeum vulgare cultivated in copper amended soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602446k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537444p</identifier><degree><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569776g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The design of 3D microwave devices can be improved by using computational optimization techniques combined with numerical simulations of the electromagnetic field. However, high accuracy field analysis is often computationally expensive and time consuming. One way to cut costs is to vary the accuracy level of the analysis at different stages of the optimization. This idea is based on the premise that the accuracy need not be constant throughout the optimization, and so the numerical analysis can be run more cheaply without compromising design quality. This thesis presents a software system that minimizes the return loss of 3D microwave devices over a frequency band efficiently through accuracy control. It combines a custom gradient-based optimizer with a p-adaptive frequency-domain finite element solver. The solver computes the cost function and its gradient to a specified accuracy in a cost efficient manner. The p-adaptive solver comprises of two original components: an a-posteriori error estimator to evaluate the error in the cost function gradient, and an error indicator to identify the high error regions in the mesh. The optimizer controls the accuracy of the cost function evaluation through a link with the solver, specifying the required relative error for the gradient at each optimization step. The combined adaption-optimization scheme was applied to 3D rectangular waveguide problems for validation: an E-plane miter bend, a U-bend, an impedance transformer and a compensated magic-T. For comparison, all the problems were also optimized using high-order finite elements at every step. Test results prove the computational efficiency of the new combined scheme at various stages of the optimization. In the early stages, when the element orders are low, the scheme is able to attain similar cost function reductions as the high-order analysis, with computational savings up to a factor of 25. Even in the late stages, when the accuracy is more stringent, the scheme manages a reduction in cumulative computation time of at least a factor of 4.</description><creator>Nair, Dileep, 1976-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Microwave circuits -- Computer-aided design.</subject><subject>Microwave devices -- Computer-aided design.</subject><subject>Finite element method.</subject><subject>Microwave filters -- Computer-aided design.</subject><title>An accuracy controlled combined adaption-optimization scheme for improving the performance of 3D microwave devices over a frequency band /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s838m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569776g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000354x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Whereas first line therapy for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) usually includes a short-acting bronchodilator, there are suggestions that these agents may increase the risk of cardiac arrhythmias. In this thesis, we first assessed the risks associated with short-acting beta-agonists (SABA), long-acting beta-agonists (LABA), ipratropium bromide (IB), and methyl xanthines (MX) within a cohort of COPD patients using the health databases of Saskatchewan. In order to confirm these findings and to address some methodological issues we then replicated this analysis within a larger cohort of patients using the health databases of Quebec. Our first study cohort consisted of 6,018 adults aged 55 and older, newly treated with bronchodilator medications. We found that new users of both IB and LABA increased the risk of arrhythmia (RR 2.39 [95% CI 1.42-4.05] and (RR 4.55 [95% CI 1.43-14.45] respectively). When the cohort was restricted by excluding subjects who had recently either been hospitalised or experienced an exacerbation, the elevated risk associated with the new use of IB persisted (RR 3.65 [95% CI 1.72-7.74]), an effect was detected with new use of MX (RR 5.17 [95% CI 1.38-19.30]), but there was insufficient power to detect an effect associated with the new use of LABA. Due to both power issues and the limited availability of LABA within the Saskatchewan data, we replicated the analysis in a larger new-user cohort of 76,661 Quebec adults aged 67 and over. This study confirmed our earlier results, with an elevated risk of arrhythmia associated with the new use of both IB and LABA (RR 1.43 [95% CI 1.08-1.88]) and (RR 1.54 [95% CI 1.00-2.36]) respectively, as well as with new use of SABA (RR 1.28 [95% CI 1.02-1.61]). Finally, using marginal structural models, we demonstrated that both exacerbations of COPD as well as minor non-event arrhythmias were moderate time-dependent confounders within this setting. In conclusion, we found that new use of bronchodilators in COPD, particularly IB and LABA, was associated with an increase in the risk of cardiac arrhythmias. We also demonstrated the method by which the time-dependent confounder status of specific model covariates may be evaluated.</description><creator>Wilchesky, Machelle, 1965-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Adrenergic beta-Agonists -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Bronchodilator Agents -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Bronchodilator Agents -- adverse effects.</subject><subject>Adrenergic beta-Agonists -- adverse effects.</subject><subject>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive -- drug therapy.</subject><subject>Arrhythmias, Cardiac -- chemically induced.</subject><title>Arrhythmia risk associated with the use of bronchodilators in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease : cohort studies and methodological issues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612s08m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000354x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580r17r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polyelectrolytes coated on high surface curvature nanoparticles (NPs) have been prepared and characterized by a variety of solid-state nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) experiments in order to examine surface interactions, polymer-water association and polymer dynamic properties of layer components. Gold nanoparticles of four nanometers in diameter pre-stabilized by 4-dimethylaminopyridine (DMAP), and silica and neodymium NPs were chosen as substrates for these studies. The high surface to volume ratio provided by such nanoparticles is advantageous for NMR analysis, which requires a high material content for adequate sensitivity. Firstly, poly(styrene sulfonate) was deposited on gold NPs by electrostatic self-assembly where charged polyelectrolytes adsorb onto an oppositely charged substrate. Surface charges on gold NPs were provided by the ligand DMAP that induces a positive charge at the NP surface that is otherwise neutral. Nanoparticle encapsulation by PSS was monitored by the gold surface plasmon absorption band (SPB) which revealed a good stability under assembly conditions where the pH was maintained above the DMAPsoln pKa and for a polymer radius of gyration comparable to the particle radius. An electrostatic association between DMAPbound and PSS, rather than a ligand substitution, was detected by solid state 13C NMR. When a subsequent layer composed of a weak or a strong polycation was added, the stability of the bilayer was found to be dictated by the nature of the multiple, weak interactions of the polymer functional groups (SO3, NH2, N(CH 3)2+Cl-, NH3 +) with the gold surface relative to that of DMAPbound which in turn is influenced by the assembly pH. A detailed study of the interactions between the polyelectrolytes, stabilizers and substrates was also extended to polyelectrolyte multilayers coated on gold NPs of different dimensions. Limitations in the application of the layer-by-layer self-assembly technique to very small NPs were investigated and strategies to optimize the method were proposed. 1H NMR analysis in the solid state and 2H NMR analysis in solution revealed that water association and film dynamics were closely related to the identity of the capping layer and independent of even/odd layer effects. These results were compared to those obtained for larger NP substrates which revealed many similarities between the two systems. A study of the parameters that affect the fabrication of Poly(L-lysine) and DNA polyelectrolyte multilayer films was also conducted for both flat and highly curved surfaces. Such polyelectrolyte films coated on nanopartic1es can be considered as potential vectors for gene therapy. Control over DNA loading into films was performed by varying the ionic strength and pH of polyelectrolyte assembly solutions. DNA density, film degradability and transfection efficiency were examined to determine optimal conditions for vector preparation in gene therapy. Finally, the acid-base properties of lanthanide-based nanoparticles of 10 nm of diameter were explored under a wide range of pH conditions. The interactions of the neodymium oxide nanoparticles with the cationic poly(allylamine hydrochloride) and the anionic poly(styrene sulfonate) polymers were investigated by following spectroscopically optical changes in suspension absorbance and visual changes in NP dimensions. Transparancy and efficiency of stabilization were the evaluated criteria for polymers to be considered as potential stabilizing agents for neodymium oxide NPs used in neutrino detection experiments.</description><creator>Dorris, Annie.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Monomolecular films.</subject><subject>Colloidal gold.</subject><subject>Gold films.</subject><subject>Nanoparticles.</subject><subject>Polyelectrolytes.</subject><title>Preparation and characterization of polyelectrolyte-coated nanoparticles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3335862.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580r17r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cv25n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Retinol (vitamin A) and its active metabolite, all-trans retinoic acid, signal through nuclear retinoic acid and retinoid X receptor (RAR/RXR) heterodimers. These complexes regulate the expression of genes involved in developmental processes such as limb development. In excess, retinoids are potent teratogens and cause marked reductive effects on the developing limb. The goal of this thesis was to elucidate the molecular mechanisms underlying retinoid-induced limb dysmorphogenesis. Specifically, using an in vitro limb culture system, I examined the involvement of one RAR isoform, RARgamma, in mediating retinoid insult. My first objective was to examine how limbs deficient in RARgamma responded to exogenous retinoid exposure. I showed that RARgamma-null limbs (on an RARalpha1-null background) exhibited less severe limb defects following retinoid insult when compared to their wild-type counterparts. Additionally, the absence of RARgamma abolished the retinoid-induced misregulation of genes important for chondrogenesis (Sox9 and Col2a1 ) and limb outgrowth (Meis-1 and -2). The next objective set out to determine how pharmacological activation of RARgamma affected limb development. The RARgamma-selective agonist (BMS-189961) caused limb dysmorphology (namely, effects on cartilage) that was comparable to pan-RAR activation with all-trans retinoic acid. A chondrogenesis-focused gene array analysis identified Mgp and Gdf10 as two RARgamma-responsive genes that may mediate retinoid-induced limb insult. Subsequently, I assessed the functional involvement of Mgp in mediating retinoid teratogenicity. Limbs were treated with all- trans retinoic acid and warfarin (an inhibitor of MGP); warfarin co-treatment rescued limbs from retinoid-induced insult. My final objective was to determine the importance of Gdf10 in mediating limb development. Recombinant human Gdf10-soaked beads were implanted into distal limb structures; ectopic overexpression of Gdf10 in the web (but not the digital ray) resulted in marked proximal limb malformations. Collectively, these studies have illustrated the importance of RARgamma in retinoid teratology and have identified several potential mechanisms by which retinoids cause limb defects.</description><creator>Galdones, Eugene.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Receptors, Retinoic Acid -- physiology.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Vitamin A -- toxicity.</subject><subject>Mice, Knockout.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred C57BL.</subject><subject>Limb Deformities, Congenital -- chemically induced.</subject><subject>Teratogens -- toxicity.</subject><title>The role of retinoic acid receptor gamma in retinoid-induced limb dysmorphogenesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm75c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cv25n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150n50f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dissolved organic matter (DOM) is operationally defined as soluble/colloidal material passing through a 0.45mum filter paper. The importance of DOM in soils relies on its role in soil formation and weathering processes, plant and microbial assimilation and soil and water acidification. However, the scientific community studying DOM still disagrees on whether fresh or humified material is the major source of DOM within the forest floor. One of the factors that could influence the overall importance of DOM production by organic horizons is its potential for biodegradability. In addition, the interaction occurring between the nutrients (i.e. nitrogen (N) and phosphorus (P)) and carbon (C) substrate is believed to be of major importance. To acquire more knowledge on the production and biodegradation of dissolved C, N and P during decomposition of organic matter (OM), I performed laboratory incubations to evaluate rates of production and transformation, the influence of the degree of OM decomposition and stand type on these rates, and the stoichiometric relationships of the different quotients during the incubations. First, I performed a 30-day incubation of coniferous and deciduous OM from 10 Canadian forest floors representing various degrees of OM decomposition and subsequently measured the amount of: dissolved organic carbon (DOC), total dissolved nitrogen (TDN), nitrate (NO3-N), ammonium (NH4-N), dissolved organic nitrogen (DON), total dissolved phosphorus (TOP) and carbon dioxide (CO2-C). I performed water extractions with the same set of samples to evaluate the biodegradability of DOC and DON and the transformations of TDN, NO3-N and NH4-N. Fresh material produces more DOM than humified material; material in the midpoint of decomposition (F horizon) produced the largest amount of DIN. Coniferous and deciduous samples did not display different rates of DOM production, most likely because of the overshadowing effect of OM degree of decomposition. I found strong links between the organic matter and dissolved phase C and N content and C:N quotient. The biodegradation, measured as DOC disappearance and mineralization of CO2-C, showed a discrepancy, reflecting the importance of increasing microbial biomass at the beginning of the incubation in response to priming effect. The sharp decrease of TDN and DON observed in the first few days of the incubation, in addition to increasing amount of dissolved inorganic N as waste products during decomposition of DON, supports this hypothesis. A better understanding of the dynamics of dissolved C, N and P in soil is essential to further understand their role in global elemental cycles, including climate change, forest management and pollution.</description><creator>Turgeon, Julie.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Forest litter -- Biodegradation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Soils -- Organic compound content -- Canada.</subject><subject>Forest litter -- Canada.</subject><title>Production and biodegradation of dissolved carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus from Canadian forest floors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tz725.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150n50f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451n11b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study presents a novel methodology to characterize material plastic behavior within a practical range of stresses, strains, strain rates, and temperatures encountered in the metal cutting process. The methodology is based on integrating a newly developed analytical model with quasi-static tests and orthogonal cutting experiments that incorporate a laser heating system. Friction and heat transfer models are developed to describe the tribological and thermal interactions at the tool-chip interface. These models are implemented in a FEM package in order to improve the accuracy of the simulation of the machining process. The new analytical model, which is developed to predict the distributions of the stress, the strain, the strain rate, and the temperature in the primary shear zone, is based on conceptual considerations, as well as characterization of the plastic deformation process through comprehensive FEM simulations. Orthogonal cutting experiments at room temperature and preheated conditions were carefully designed. While the cutting tests at room temperature provided the constitutive data encountered in the primary shear zone, the preheated cutting tests were designed to capture the material behavior at the high level of temperature and strain encountered in the secondary shear zone. In these preheated cutting tests, a laser beam was employed. Quasi-static tests were also utilized to identify some of the coefficients in the constitutive equations, in order to improve the convergence to a unique solution for the constitutive law. Evaluation criteria were developed to assess the performance of constitutive equations. Based on the developed methodology and the evaluation criteria, a new constitutive equation for Inconel 718 has been proposed. This constitutive equation was further validated by Split Hopkinson Pressure Bar (SHPB) tests and cutting tests in conjunction with FEM simulations. The SHPB test data show an excellent agreement with the proposed material model. The cutting tests and the FEM simulation results also proved the validity of the proposed material constitutive law.</description><creator>Shi, Bin, 1966-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Metals -- Plastic properties -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Metal-cutting -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Finite element method.</subject><title>Identification of the material constitutive equation for simulation of the metal cutting process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924g187.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451n11b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>