<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:12:43Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5775" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n585k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La N6-méthyladénosine (m6A) est une modification post-transcriptionnelle réversible de l'ARN. L'addition de groupements méthyl sur l'adénosine implique un complexe de N6-adénosine-méthyltransférases qui regroupe deux protéines encodées par les gènes METTL3 et METTL14 ; l'appellation « rédactrices » de m6A réfère à ces protéines capables de méthyler l'ARN de façon indépendante. L'utilisation de petits ARN interférents (siRNAs pour small interfering RNAs) dirigés contre METTL3 et METTL14 entraine une diminution du niveau d'ARN présentant des modifications m6A. La présence de m6A au niveau de l'ARN entraine leur interaction avec un autre groupe de protéines que l'on appelle des « lectrices » de m6A ; parmi celles-ci des protéines contenant un domaine YTH comme par exemple YTHDF2 (YTH domain family 2) et hnRNPA2/B1. Les gènes FTO (fat mass and obesity-associated gene) et ALKBH5 (alpha-ketoglutarate-dependent dioxygenase AlkB homologue 5) encodent les principales protéines connues à ce jour comme capable de retirer ou « effacer » les modifications m6A de l'ARN. L'objectif premier de notre étude était d'investiguer le degré de bases modifiées m6A au niveau de l'ARN lorsque l'expression du gène TARDBP, connu pour être impliqué dans la sclérose latérale amyotrophique (SLA), est réduite ou absente. La SLA est une maladie neurodégénérative associée avec une dégénération progressive des neurones moteurs et il est bien établi que plusieurs des gènes impliqués dans la SLA encodent des protéines impliquées dans le métabolisme de l'ARN ou RNA processing (comme par exemple gène TARDBP encodant TDP-43). Nous avons donc entrepris de mesurer le niveau de nucléoside modifié m6A au niveau de l'ARN varie lorsque l'expression de gènes liés à la SLA connus pour leur rôle dans le RNA processing (ex. TDP-43), est diminuée ou supprimée via l'utilisation de siRNAs ou CRISPR/Cas9. Nos résultats démontrent que le pourcentage de m6A (% m6A) diminue lorsque des cellules HeLa sont traitées avec un siRNA agissant sur TARDBP. Cette observation a été validé via l'utilisation de cellules HAP1, une lignée cellulaire haploïde, à l'intérieur desquelles TARDBP avait été inactivé par l'utilisation du système CRISPR/Cas9. La réduction substantielle du pourcentage de m6A dans l'ARN est comparable à celle observée lorsque l'expression de la « rédactrice » de m6A reconnue, METTL3, est réduite par l'utilisation de siRNA. Notre étude est la première à suggérer un rôle possible pour les modifications m6A dans la pathogénicité associée à la SLA. </description><description>N6-methyladenosine (m6A) is a reversible epigenetic post-transcriptional modification of RNA. The addition of methyl groups on adenosine implicates a N6-adenosine-methyltransferase complex constituted of two methyltransferase-like proteins encoded by the genes METTL3 and METTL14. The product of these last two genes are referred to as m6A 'writers' and each one can methylate RNA by itself. In vitro cell assays have shown that when METTL3 or METTL14 is knock down using siRNAs a global decrease of RNA with m6A levels is observed. The presence of m6A methyl groups on RNA is also known to be specifically recognized by proteins referred to as m6A 'reader', for instance the YTH domain family 2 (YTHDF2) member and hnRNPA2/B1. Finally, there are genes encoding proteins able to remove the m6A groups from RNA and these are referred to as 'eraser'; the fat mass and obesity-associated (FTO) and alpha-ketoglutarate-dependent dioxygenase AlkB homologue 5 (ALKBH5) genes encode the two main m6A demethylase. Our study aimed to investigate if an association exists between the level of m6A RNA methylation and expression of TARDBP, which is a gene implicated in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). ALS is a neurodegenerative disorder associated with the progressive degeneration of motor neurons and several genes known to be implicated in ALS are also known to encode products involved at various levels of RNA processing (e.g. TDP-43).  Thus, the objective of this study was to verify if the level of m6A-modified bases in the RNA varied when ALS genes encoding such 'ALS-RNA-processing' genes (e.g. TARDBP encoding TDP-43) were silenced using siRNA, or in one case knocked out using a CRISPR/Cas9 approach. Overall, we observed the percentage of m6A (% m6A) to decrease in HeLa cells transfected with a siRNA targeting TARDBP. This observation was subsequently validated through the use of a haploid cell line, HAP1, in which TARDBP was knocked out using a CRISPR/Cas9 approach. This substantial reduction of % m6A in global RNA was comparable to the reduction observed when the established m6A writer protein METTL3 was silenced using siRNA. Our study points to a possible role for m6A RNA modification at some level of ALS pathogenesis. </description><creator>Quoibion, Amélie</creator><contributor>Patrick Dion (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Guy Rouleau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>m6A RNA methylation and TARDBP, a gene implicated in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m933j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n585k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924f270</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La synthèse protéique est un processus crucial sous-jacent l'homéostasie cellulaire et la réponse aux stimuli environnementaux. La régulation de la traduction d'ARNm en protéines est compliquée et implique de nombreux points de contrôle. Le premier et le plus important de ceux-ci est l'initiation de la traduction, qui permet de prévenir le gaspillage d'énergie que constituerait l'arrêt de la synthèse protéique à des étapes ultérieures. Parmi les acteurs impliqués dans ce mécanisme, les protéines liant le facteur d'initiation de la traduction eIF4E (4E-BPs) jouent un rôle prépondérant de par leur compétition avec eIF4G pour le même site d'interaction sur la protéine liant la coiffe des ARNm, eIF4E. Ainsi, les 4E-BPs empêchent la formation du complexe eIF4F nécessaire au recrutement du complexe ribosomal de pré-initiation 48S. L'action des 4E-BPs est principalement contrôlée via leur phosphorylation par la kinase mTOR, ce qui diminue leur affinité pour eIF4E. L'une des 4E-BPs, 4E-BP2, peut aussi être régulée par déamidation, transformant un résidu d'asparagine en aspartate. La déamidation est l'une des modifications post-traductionnelles les plus communément observées chez les eukaryotes. La déamidation est spontanée, et est généralement considérée comme néfaste, menant à l'apparition d'une nouvelle charge négative sur un protéine, qui devient alors instable et est rapidement dégradée. Nous avons précédemment identifié un site de déamidation dans 4E-BP2 qui apparaît uniquement dans le cerveau. La présente thèse identifie un second tissu exhibant la déamidation de 4E-BP2 et vise à identifier le mécanisme conférant la spécificité de ce processus à ces deux tissus. Ainsi, nous établissons que la déamidation de 4E-BP2 coïncide avec une réduction de l'activité de mTOR et mène à sa dégradation par le protéasome. Sur ces bases, nous présentons l'hypothèse que la réduction programmée de l'activité de mTOR au cours du développement de certains tissus mène à une réduction de l'activité protéasomale, et donc à l'accumulation de 4E-BP2 déaminée.</description><description>Protein synthesis is a crucial process underlying cellular maintenance and cellular response towards environmental stimuli. Regulation of protein synthesis is complicate, elaborate, and involves multiple checkpoints. As the first and also rate-limiting step in mRNA translation, control of translation initiation is beneficial to preserve energy expenditure that would otherwise be lost if translation is to be halted at later stages. Amongst the governing mechanisms of translation initiation, a key regulatory module is the eIF4E-binding proteins (4E-BPs) which inhibit translation by competing with eIF4G for the same binding motif on the mRNA 5' cap binding protein eIF4E. Through competitive inhibition, 4E-BPs prevent the formation of the tripartite eIF4F complex, consequently preventing the formation of the 48S preinitiation complex. This regulation is mainly controlled by phosphorylation of 4E-BPs. Hypophosphorylated 4E-BPs binds with high affinity to eIF4E while fully phosphorylated 4E-BPs undergo a conformational change and is released from its cognate. Deamidation is one of the most common post-translational modifications observed in eukaryotes, where asparagine transforms to asparatate. Each deamidated residue provides an additional negative charge. Deamidation is commonly known to be an unwanted and unregulated event as deamidated proteins usually become unstable and are successively degraded. It was reported that 4E-BP2 exhibits a tissue disparate pattern of deamidation. Specifically, deamidated 4E-BP2 was only observed in the brain. This thesis unveils another location of 4E-BP2 deamidation and aims to delineate the mechanism underlying tissue specific deamidation of 4E-BP2. Deamidation of 4E-BP2 is coincidental with reduction of mTOR activity. 4E-BP2 is also identified to be degraded through the proteasomal pathway. Together, it is hypothesized that specific reduction of mTOR activity within specific tissues renders the proteasome less active, resulting in the accumulation of deamidated 4E-BP2. </description><creator>Truong, Vinh Tai</creator><contributor>Nahum Sonenberg (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>Indentifying the mechanism underlying tissue specific deamidation of translation repressor 4E-BP2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw31p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f270</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kn257</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quebec was less affected by the First and Second World War than the rest of the world. French Canadians didn't feel like they had to be involved in those conflicts that, seemed more European than international to them. The historical context reveals that the geographical distance between Quebec and Europe, as well as the estrangement of their identities regarding the countries that faced it, can explain this feeling they held. Studies about the war in Quebec novels indicate however that those conflicts take a part in the plot, even if they are present only as a backdrop. The aim of this master's thesis is to analyse this second plan action in order to show that the object of awareness that war constitute compels the characters to question themselves and their world and to act in accordance with their new way of thinking the world they live in. In analysing « Trente arpents » by Ringuet (1938), « Bonheur d'occasion » by Gabrielle Roy (1945), « Les Plouffe » by Roger Lemelin (1948), « La Guerre, yes sir! » by Roch Carrier (1968) and « L'Emmitouflé » by Louis Caron (1977) and in taking the definitions of aventure and idylle that Isabelle Daunais gives to read in her essay « Le roman sans aventure », we argue that the war, although it most often remains in the background, embodies, for the character, the representation of an adventure that makes him/her imagine what goes on beyond him/her and what can transform him/her. </description><description>Le Québec a été moins touché que le reste du monde par la Première et la Seconde Guerre mondiale. Considérant ces conflits comme européens plutôt qu'internationaux, les Canadiens français n'ont en général pas senti qu'ils se devaient d'y participer. Le contexte historique révèle que la distance géographique entre le Québec et l'Europe ainsi que l'éloignement identitaire en regard des pays qui s'y affrontent peuvent expliquer ce sentiment. Les études sur la thématique guerrière dans les romans québécois montrent cependant que les conflits mondiaux ne sont pas sans incidence dans la trame fictionnelle des récits où ils trouvent place, même si cette place en est une d'arrière-fond. C'est cette action d'arrière-plan que ce mémoire a pour objectif d'analyser en proposant de montrer que l'objet de conscience que constitue la guerre pousse les personnages à s'interroger sur eux-mêmes et sur le monde qui est le leur et à mener des actions qui sont cohérentes avec leur nouvelle manière de penser ce monde. En étudiant « Trente arpents » de Ringuet (1938), « Bonheur d'occasion » de Gabrielle Roy (1945), « Les Plouffe » de Roger Lemelin (1948), « La Guerre, yes sir! » de Roch Carrier (1968) et « L'Emmitouflé » de Louis Caron (1977) ainsi qu'en empruntant les définitions d' « aventure » et d' « idylle » qu'Isabelle Daunais donne à lire dans son essai « Le roman sans aventure », nous mettons ainsi à l'épreuve l'hypothèse que la guerre, bien qu'elle demeure le plus souvent une trame d'arrière-plan, représente pour le protagoniste sinon une forme d'aventure, du moins la représentation d'une aventure à partir de laquelle il lui est possible d'imaginer ce qui le dépasse et peut le transformer. </description><creator>Genois, Clara</creator><contributor>Isabelle Daunais (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>French Language and Literature</subject><title>Représentation des guerres mondiales dans le roman Québécois: Le rôle du second plan dans le récit</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk70j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn257</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375z981</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abstract: Introduction: Matrix Gla protein (MGP) is a potent inhibitor of extracellular matrix (ECM) mineralization. MGP‐deficiency in humans leads to Keutel syndrome, a rare genetic disease, hallmarked by abnormal soft tissue calcification. How Mgp gene is regulated in various cell types is still not well-understood. In a recent study, SOX9, a chondrogenic transcription factor, has been shown to interact with several regions in the promoter as well as intronic sequences of Mgp gene. In the current study, we investigated the effect of a SOX9 binding intronic sequence on the Mgp promoter activity.Methods: We amplified the rat intronic sequence earlier shown to bind SOX9. This sequence was inserted in front of the 2 kb mouse proximal promoter driving the firefly luciferase gene. This construct was used to transfect ATDC5 chondrogenic cells or primary vascular smooth muscle cells (VSMCs). The transfected cells were grown for 48 hrs and luciferase activity was measured. Results: Transfection of ATDC5 cells by the pMgp-Luc construct induced luciferase activity in ATDC5 cells. Unexpectedly, when the SOX9 binding intronic sequence was added upstream of the promoter, there was a significant downregulation of the luciferase activity in the transfected cells. Co-transfection with a Sox9 expression vector failed to increase the luciferase activity. We next split the intronic sequence into 3 segments and cloned in front of the 2.0 kb Mgp proximal promoter driving the luciferase gene. Interestingly, we found that all 3 fragments induced the luciferase activity. We identified two CCCTC sequences within the intronic sequence, which are known to bind a DNA interacting protein CTCF with promoter silencing activity. Deletion of one CTCF binding site in the intronic sequence was sufficient to inhibit the repressor activity. Conclusion: Our study shows the presence of a regulatory element in the intron 1 of Mgp gene. We identified the presence of two CCCTC binding sites within this intronic sequence, which has been shown to bind SOX9. Selective ablation of the upstream CCCTC sequence leads to an upregulation promoter activity suggesting that the intronic sequence confers important epigenetic regulation of the Mgp promoter</description><description>Résumé Introduction: La protéine Matrix Gla (MGP) est un inhibiteur puissant de la minéralisation de la matriceextracellulaire (MEC). La déficience en MGP chez l'homme conduit au syndrome de Keutel, une maladiegénétique rare, marquée par une calcification anormale des tissusmous. La façon dont le gène Mgp est réglementé dans différents types de cellules n'est toujours pas bien déchiffrée. Dans une étude récente, SOX9, un facteur de transcription chondrogénique, s'est révélé interagir avec plusieurs régions du promoteur ainsique des séquences introniques du gène Mgp. Danscette étude, nous avons étudié l'effet de la séquence intronic de liaison de SOX9 sur l'activité du promoteur Mgp. Méthodes: Nous avons amplifié la séquence intronic du rat précédemment démontrer pour lier SOX9. Cette séquence a été insérée devant le promoteur proximal de souris de 2 kb conduisant le gène de la luciférase de luciole. Cette construction a été utilisée pour transfecter des cellules chondrogéniques ATDC5 ou des cellules tumorales vasculaires primaires. Les cellules transfectées ont été cultivées pendant 48 heures et l'activité de luciférase a été mesurée. Résultats: La transfection des cellules ATDC5 par l'activité luciférase achevée par la construction pMgp-Luc dans les cellules ATDC5. De manière inattendue, lorsque la séquence intronic de liaison SOX9 a été ajoutée avant le promoteur, il y a eu une signifiante régulation négative de l'activité luciférase dans les cellules transfectées. La co-transfection avec un vecteur d'expression Sox9 n'a pas réussi à augmenter l'activité luciférase. Nous avons ensuite divisé la séquence intronic en 3 segments et on a cloné devant le promoteur proximal de Mgp de 2,0 kb menant le gène de la luciférase. C'est intéressant de constater que tous les 3 fragments ont induit l'activité luciférase. Nous avons identifié deux séquences CCCTC dans la séquence intronic, qui sont connues pour lier une protéine CTCF interagissant avec l'ADN avec une activité silencieuse de promoteur. La suppression d'un site de liaison CTCF dans la séquence intronic était suffisante pour inhiber l'activité du répresseur. Conclusion: Notre étude montre la présence d'un élément réglementaire dans l'intron 1 du gène Mgp. Nous avons identifié la présence de deux sites de liaison CCCTC dans cette séquence intronic, ce qui a été montré de lier SOX9. L'ablation sélective de la séquence CCCTC en amont conduit à une activité de promoteur de la régulation positive suggérant que la séquence intronic confère une régulation épigénétique importante du promoteur Mgp.</description><creator>Moshi, Jobran</creator><contributor>Monzur Murshed (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Regulation of matrix Gla protein gene expression by an intronic sequence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j699.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z981</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903236g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coaching research has most often focused on positive coach and athlete behaviours and outcomes. However, less empirical attention has highlighted negative, problematic, and difficult athlete behaviours. Specifically, managing difficult athletes is part of a coach's role and responsibilities, so it is somewhat surprising that there is minimal research on the topic. Thus, the purpose of the present study was to investigate high performance coaches' experiences with difficult athletes, including how they effectively managed these individuals. Semi-structured interviews were conducted with eight Canadian Hockey League (CHL) coaches, who had an average of 21 years of coaching experience. The methodology of transcendental phenomenology (Moustakas, 1994) was used to better understand what difficult athletes were and how coaches managed these individuals by combining the strengths of thematic analysis with individual narrative accounts. The results indicated the coaches' common experiences with difficult athlete through five overarching themes: (a) instilling team culture, (a) difficult athlete characteristics, (c) fostering relationships, (d) managing difficult athletes, and (d) social influences and resources of difficult athletes. Specifically, difficult athletes were described as "negative star players" and "negative leaders" within the team, where they had a negative influence on teammates and impacted proper team functioning. The narrative accounts described that coaches learned how to manage difficult athletes through their personal experiences with them. The findings suggest that managing difficult athletes involves early identification, providing clear roles and expectations, enforcing consequences, and making progress through process goals to learn from mistakes. Coaches either transformed the difficult athlete behaviour by having them buy-in to team concepts or they were unable to make progress with them, which then led to the athlete being traded or deselected. The themes and narratives were synthesized to create the essence of the experience, which highlighted the coaches' commitment to athlete development by utilizing all of the resources at their disposal (e.g., assistant coaches, trainers, athlete leaders, billets). From a practical standpoint, this study provides insights for coaches, athletes, athletic directors, and general managers by highlighting the dynamic processes necessary to manage difficult athletes within an organization. As well, this study offers methodological implications for the application of transcendental phenomenology in the coaching sciences as an effective and systematic approach, along with theoretical implications for leader-member exchange theory within sport and group dynamics research. </description><description>La recherche sur l'encadrement des entraîneurs s'est trop souvent concentré sur les comportements positifs des entraîneurs et des joueurs, ainsi que les résultats positifs obtenus.  Par contre, peu de recherche empirique a démontré les problèmes, les difficultés et les comportements négatifs des athlètes. En particulier, la gérance des athlètes difficiles est une grande partie des responsabilités des entraîneurs. Alors, ceci est très surprenant qu'il y est peu de recherche à ce sujet. Par conséquent, le but de cette étude est d'enquêté sur les expériences des entraîneurs de haut calibre avec des athlètes difficiles, incluant l'encadrement de ceux-ci. Des entrevues semi-structuré ont été fait avec huit entraîneurs de la Ligue Canadienne de Hockey (LCH), qui avaient en moyenne 21 années d'expérience. La méthodologie de la phénoménologie transcendantale (Moustakas, 1994) a été utilisé pour mieux comprendre qu'est-ce qu'un athlète difficile et comment les entraîneurs encadrent ceux-ci en combinant les forces des analyses thématiques avec comptes narratifs individuels. Les résultats on indiqués que les entraîneurs expérimentent des situations similaires avec leurs athlètes difficiles à travers cinq thèmes: (a) inculquer une culture d'équipe, (b) les caractéristiques des athlètes difficiles, (c) favoriser les relations, (d) l'encadrement des athlètes difficiles et (d) les influences social et les ressources des athlètes difficiles. Particulièrement, les athlètes difficiles. Spécialement, les athlètes difficiles étaient décrit comme des «joueurs étoiles négatifs» et des "meneurs négatifs» à l'intérieur de l'équipe, où ceux-ci avaient une influence sur leurs coéquipiers et le fonctionnement de l'équipe. Le narrateur a décrit que les entraîneurs apprenaient des situations qu'ils ont expérimentées par eux-mêmes. Les résultats nous informent que l'encadrement des athlètes à problèmes commence par l'identification précoce de ces derniers, en leur attribuant un rôle clair, en renforçant les conséquences et en utilisant des objectifs pour identifier leur progrès lorsqu'ils apprennent de leurs erreurs. Les entraîneurs ont soit transformé le comportement de leur athlète à problème en le faisant acheter le concept d'équipe ou ils n'étaient pas capable de faire de progrès avec lui ce qui a mené l'athlète à être échangé ou retrancher. Les thèmes et les narrations ont été résumé pour recréer l'essence de leurs expériences, ce qui met en valeurs l'engagement des entraîneurs envers le développement de leurs athlètes utilisant toutes les ressources disponibles (assistant-entraîneurs, meneur de l'équipe, thérapeutes, famille d'accueil). Du côté pratique, cette étude renseigne les entraîneurs, athlètes, directeurs athlétiques et directeur-gérant sur le processus pour encadrer un athlète à problème à l'intérieur de l'organisation. Aussi, cette étude des méthodes dans l'application de ces phénomènes dans la science du « coaching » avec des modèles théoriques pour l'implication des meneurs de l'équipe dans un contexte sportif. </description><creator>Heelis, William</creator><contributor>Gordon Bloom (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Coach leadership experiences in the management of difficult athletes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752k33j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903236g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws94m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the rapid development of online publishing communities and libraries, readers using an online platform face the problem of deciding which story to read from a large collection of varying quality. A good solution is to provide readers with summaries which are much shorter than the original texts. The summaries should select and reorganize the contents of the story, giving readers an overview of the whole story and consequently arousing their interest in reading it. This thesis addresses the problem of automatically generating summaries of fiction. We set up a large dataset with one million online stories along with their summaries. Based on analyzing the fictional summaries of different categories, we introduce six common summary components, of which three are particularly important: the description of main characters, the foundational event, and the hook. Rather than producing an entire summary directly, we propose an approach to producing descriptions of the main characters by inferring character attributes. Several machine learning paradigms are explored to abstract salient attributes of the main characters.</description><description>Avec le développement rapide des communautés et des bibliothèques d'édition en ligne, les lecteurs utilisant une plate-forme en ligne font face au problème de decider quelle histoire lire à partir d'une grande collection de qualité variable. Une bonne solution est de fournir aux lecteurs des résumés beaucoup plus courts que les textes originaux. Les résumés doivent sélectionner et réorganiser les contenus de l'histoire, donner aux lecteurs un aperçu de toute l'histoire et susciter ainsi leur intérêt à le lire. Cette thèse traite du problème de génération automatique de résumés de fiction. Nous avons mis en place un grand ensemble de données avec un million d'histoires et leurs résumés. Sur la base de l'analyse des résumés de différentes catégories, nous présentons six composantes récurrentes communes, dont trois sont particulièrement importantes: la description des caractères, l'événement fondamental et le crochet. Plutôt que de produire directement un résumés complet, nous proposons une approche pour produire des descriptions des caractères principaux en inférlant les attributs de caractères. Plusieurs paradigmes sont explorés à des attributs saillants abstraits des personnages principaux.</description><creator>Zhang, Weiwei</creator><contributor>Jackie Cheung (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Automatic summarization of fiction by generating character descriptions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms385.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws94m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580q193</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objet du présent mémoire est l'analyse d'une contradiction implicite dans la pensée postmoderniste relative à la question de la paternité littéraire. Nous soutenons que la « mort de l'auteur » proclamée par Roland Barthes est incompatible avec la mentalité capitaliste qui est devenue un thème de l'existence de la littérature postmoderne ainsi qu'une de ses conditions externes. Notre analyse d'une sélection de textes de Viktor Pelevine confirme ce problème et nous amène à proposer une possible solution, du moins en ce qui concerne l'œuvre de l'auteur. Il semble y avoir un glissement (tel qu'imaginé par V.V. Vinogradov et sans doute assumé par Barthes) de l'auteur en tant qu'arbitre suprême vers l'écrivain comme seul point de marquage (ce que Fredric Jameson a sans doute anticipé). Ce mémoire explore des questions de paternité littéraire dans Minotaure.com : Le Heaume d'horreur (Шлем ужаса), La Mitrailleuse d'argile (Чапаев и пустота), t, ainsi que dans Homo zapiens (Generation «П») de Pelevine en invoquant l'esthétique de la réception (un prolongement de la « mort de l'auteur » de Barthes), la théorie de l'auteur, ainsi que l'« image de l'auteur » de Vinogradov. </description><description>This thesis seeks to explore a contradiction implicit within postmodernist thought which concerns the question of authorship. It suggests that Roland Barthes's "death of the author" might well be incompatible with the capitalist mentality which has become a theme of as well as an external condition for the existence of postmodern literature. A focused analysis of selected texts by Viktor Pelevin's demonstrates this problem and suggests a possible resolution, at least within this author's works: there seems to be a shift of focus from the 'author' (as conceived by V.V. Vinogradov and perhaps assumed by Barthes), as sole and final arbiter in the question of who dictates the meaning of the text and the 'writer' as the focal point of branding (a point perhaps anticipated by Fredric Jameson). This thesis explores issues of authorship in Pelevin's The Helmet of Horror (Шлем ужаса),  Chapaev and Void, (Чапаев и Пустота), t,  and Generation «П» by referring to reader-response theory (an outgrowth of Barthes's death of the author), auteur theory, as well as Vinogradov's "image of the author."</description><creator>Vinokurova, Valentina</creator><contributor>Laura A Beraha (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</subject><title>Death of the author (?) in Viktor Pelevin's novels: Power, conspiracy, and disappointment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p985f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580q193</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j798b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aim of this Master's study was to investigate gender differences in the response to a fatiguing task and to explore the potential link between the neck/shoulder region and the forearm while performing a manual dexterity (screwing) task at shoulder height. Purdue pegboard and shoulder joint position sense measurements were recorded both before and after the fatiguing task while electromyography (EMG) of eight muscle sites and screwing task performance were recorded during the fatiguing task. Results revealed no change in shoulder proprioception, and improvements in screws/min and in Purdue pegboard performance with time. However, No significant correlations were found between changes in Purdue pegboard scores and shoulder joint position sense errors from pre- to post-fatiguing task. Despite no gender differences in any of these measures, there were significant gender differences in EMG parameters, with females displaying overall higher amplitude and inter-muscle functional connectivity. Results can be interpreted as a possible explanation for why women experience more work-related musculoskeletal disorders compared to men.  </description><description>Le but de cette étude de maîtrise était d'investiguer les différences entre les sexes en leurs réponses à une tâche fatigante, et d'explorer le lien potentiel entre la région du cou/épaule et l'avant-bras en performant une tâche de dextérité manuelle (vissage) à la hauteur de l'épaule. Les mesures au test Purdue pegboard et de proprioception de l'épaule ont été enregistrées avant et après la tâche fatigante, et l'électromyographie (EMG) de huit sites musculaires et la performance de vissage ont été enregistrées au cours de la tâche. Les résultats n'ont démontré aucun changement à la proprioception de l'épaule, ainsi qu'une amélioration avec le temps au taux de vissage par minute et à la performance au test Purdue. Cependant, aucune corrélation significative n'a été démontrée entre les changements aux résultats du test Purdue et les erreurs de proprioception avec le temps. Malgré le manque de différences à ces mesures entre les sexes, les femmes ont démontré différents patrons d'EMG, avec une plus grande amplitude et plus de connectivité intermusculaire. Les résultats peuvent offrir une explication potentielle pour les taux de troubles musculosquelettiques liés au travail plus élevés chez les femmes que chez les hommes.</description><creator>Minn, Sunghoon</creator><contributor>Julie Cote (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Gender differences in the muscular fatigue response and proprioception during a manual dexterity task at shoulder height</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g259z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j798b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws95w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The simulation of energy balance is essential to define soil water and heat flux, and quantifying crop water demand and optimizing irrigation management practices are critical to water resource management in extremely arid desert oases. The objectives of this study were (i) to evaluate the performance of RZWQM2 in simulating energy balance in bare soil ground in the desert-oasis transitional zone thus evaluate the relationship between precipitation and groundwater recharge; (ii) to develop an optimal irrigation scheme for cotton planted in this area using the RZWQM2 model being calibrated against soil moisture content, cotton growth stage, and cotton yield. This study took an irrigated agricultural field in an extremely arid oasis transition zone in Cele, Xinjiang, northwest of China as a research site, and the revised hybrid RZWQM2 model was evaluated in simulating energy balance components, soil water content in different soil layers, crop growth stages and yield under desert climate. The energy balance components were measured on a bare soil near the cotton planting field. The model performed well in simulating total shortwave radiation (Ts) and net radiation (Rn), with coefficient of determination (R2) &gt; 0.93, model efficiency (ME) &gt; 0.80 and percent bias (PBIAS) &lt; ± 20%, while the simulation for ground heat flux (G) was unacceptable, with R2 = 0.818, ME = -0.160 and PBIAS = -102.8%. Although the model failed to satisfactorily simulate ground heat flux, the simulation in surface energy balance was in general acceptable compared with other literatures. The simulated annual average actual ET (42.5mm) is generally lower than precipitation (43.2mm), and the excess water infiltrated into the ground and stored in various depths of the soil profile.  In the irrigated cotton field, the model simulation in soil water is comparable with other research, with evaluation parameters R2 ranging from 0.198 to 0.538, ME from -0.368 to 0.374, PBIAS &lt; ±20% for different layers. The simulation in cotton yield is also satisfactory with (R2) = 0.8, ME=0.75, root mean squared error (RMSE) =415.0kg/ha and relative RMSE (RRMSE)=12.5% for cotton yield. Although model simulated plant emergence dates were generally 6 days late because the model is lack of plastic mulching component after seeding, simulated flowering and bolls cracked dates matched well with those of observed, with the difference around ±4 days. From the simulated water balance data, the annual crop water consumption (actual evapotranspiration, AET) was 52.2cm and 10.1 cm deep percolation, while the simulated annual crop water requirement was 61.3 cm, suggesting a water stress under current irrigation practices and water wasted through deep seepage. A water stress-based irrigation decision support tool was applied to develop an optimal irrigation scheme for the cotton field using the RZWQM2 model, and it could save irrigation water by 4.7% (4.3cm per year) and increase the production by 15.8% (451kg ha-1 per year). It indicated that without canopy on the surface, groundwater would generally be recharged from precipitation though the precipitation is very low and this recharge is very trivial; RZWQM2 was applicable in simulating energy balance components, soil water content and crop production in extremely arid district. Rescheduling of irrigation using a water stress-based method can be used to optimize irrigation water use and cotton production.  </description><description>Permettant de définir les flux de chaleur et d'humidité du sol, de quantifier la demande en eau des cultures, et de mettre en place des pratiques de gestion optimales en matière d'irrigation, une simulation précise du bilan énergétique et du cycle hydrologique d'un oasis situé dans un désert extrêmement aride, s'est avéré essentiel à la gestion de ses ressources hydriques. La présente étude eut pour objectifs : (i) d'évaluer la capacité du modèle RZWQM2 à simuler le bilan énergétique d'un sol nu dans une zone de transition desert-oasis, élucidant ainsi la relation existante entre le taux de précipitation and la recharge des eaux souterraines, (ii) d'utiliser le modèle RZWQM2 — étalonné avec des données locales [Cele, Xinjiang (Chine)] d'humidité du sol (), d'étapes phénologiques et de rendement de la culture — afin de développer un régime d'irrigation optimal pour le coton (Gossypium hirsutum L.) dans une zone de transition oasis-désert hyperaride. Le modèle étalonné fut évalué quant à sa capacité à simuler avec précision les éléments du bilan énergétique,  des différentes couches du sol, ainsi que les étapes phénologiques et le rendement de la culture, sous un climat désertique. Certains éléments du bilan énergétique furent quantifiés sur un terrain dénudé près du champ de coton. Le modèle se montra précis en simulant le rayonnement solaire à ondes courtes (Ts) et le rayonnement net (Rn), présentant un coefficient de détermination (R2) &gt; 0.93, coefficient d'efficacité Nash-Sutcliffe (NSE) &gt; 0.80 et pourcentage de biais (PBIAS) inférieur à ± 20%. Cependant, sa simulation du flux de chaleur dans le sol (G) fut inacceptable (R2 = 0.818, NSE = -0.160, PBIAS = -102.8%). Quoique le modèle fut incapable de correctement simuler la valeur de G, dans l'ensemble sa simulation du bilan énergétique en surface s'avéra acceptable par rapport aux simulations rapportés dans d'autres études. Sur une base annuelle, l'évapotranspiration (ET) réelle moyenne (ETr = 42.5 mm) fut généralement inférieure à la précipitation moyenne (43.2 mm); l'excès d'eau s'infiltrant dans le sol y étant entreposée à divers niveaux du profil du sol. Pour le coton irrigué, la précision du modèle quant au  des différentes couches du sol (0.198 ≤ R2 ≤ 0.538; -0.368 ≤ ME ≤ 0.374; |PBIAS| &lt; 20%) fut comparable à celle rapportée ailleurs. Également, la simulation du rendement du coton s'avéra satisfaisante [R2 = 0.8; ME = 0.75; racine carrée de l'erreur quadratique (RMSEP) = 415.0 kg ha‑1 et RMSEP relative (RRMSEP) = 12.5%]. Le modèle n'étant pas équipé d'un dispositif permettant de simuler le paillage plastique, ses estimations de la levée des cultures furent généralement 6 jours en retard. Par contre, les dates de floraison et de fendaison des capsules correspondirent de près aux dates observes au champ, avec une différence maximale de ±4 jours. A partir du bilan hydrique, la consommation d'eau annuelle de la culture (ETa), la percolation profonde, et le besoin en eau de la culture furent estimés à 522 mm, 101 mm et 613 mm, respectivement, laissant entrevoir qu'un certain stress hydrique avait eu lieu sous le présent régime d'irrigation et qu'une certaine quantité d'eau fut gaspillé par percolation profonde. Par l'entremise du modèle RZWQM2, un outil d'aide à la décision s'appuyant sur le stress hydrique et servant à gérer l'irrigation fut développé, et permît la préparation d'un régime d'irrigation optimal pour le champ de coton. Ce nouveau régime d'irrigation permît une économie de 4.7% en eau d'irrigation (43 mm y-1) et une hausse de production de 15.8% (+451 kg ha-1 y-1). Pour cette zone de transition oasis-désert hyperaride, la présente étude démontra qu'en l'absence d'un couvert végétale couvrant la surface du sol, la recharge des eaux souterraines provint de la précipitation, quoique celle-ci fut faible et la recharge minimale. </description><creator>Liu, Che</creator><contributor>Zhiming Qi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Simulating energy balance and hydrologic cycle in a desert-oasis transitional zone using RZWQM2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cd375.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws95w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514np021</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'acier au carbone (AC) est couramment utilisé dans les systèmes de transport d'eau à cause de ses propriétés mécaniques exceptionnelles. Cependant, l'AC est très susceptible à la corrosion, et la corrosion uniforme est la forme de corrosion la plus commune qui l'affecte. Cette corrosion interne d'équipement en AC est la cause principale de défaillance des systèmes de chauffage/refroidissement à boucle fermée. Les paramètres de qualité d'eau comme la quantité de sels et gaz dissous, le niveau de pH, la température, et l'activité galvanique et microbienne affectent le taux de corrosion interne. Ainsi, il est important de réduire la corrosion interne de l'AC. Une façon courante de réduire la corrosion est d'utiliser des inhibiteurs de corrosion. Cependant, les inhibiteurs de corrosion commerciaux sont toxiques et la recherche actuelle est concentrée sur le développement d'inhibiteur de corrosion écologiques.  L'objectif de cette thèse est d'investiguer la possibilité d'utiliser le caprylate de sodium (CS) comme inhibiteur de corrosion écologique pour les systèmes de chauffage/refroidissement à boucle fermée en utilisant de l'AC comme matériel de construction et l'eau courante de la ville de Montréal comme électrolyte sous des conditions variables: concentration de CS, température de l'eau, pH, et temps d'utilisation. Quatre techniques électrochimiques et la microscopie électronique à balayage ont été utilisées dans cette étude.Les résultats ont démontré que le CS a offert une efficacité d'inhibition de corrosion de 96% à une concentration de 10 Mm, un pH de 8, et à température ambiante (295 K). Cette efficacité d'inhibition dépend de la concentration du CS. Deux régions d'efficacité distinctes (basse/élevée) ont été identifiées, la nette transition entre les deux étant située entre 6.28 mM et 6.3 mM de CS dans l'eau. La transition correspondante d'un bas à haut niveau d'efficacité d'inhibition de corrosion peut être reliée à l'abrupt changement dans la concentration de surface et l'orientation du CS. Des expériences à températures variable ont démontré que le CS peut inhiber la corrosion de manière efficace jusqu'à une température s'élevant à 333K. L'inhibiteur peut également inhiber la corrosion dans une gamme de ph allant de 7 à 10. L'étude cinétique a démontré que l'adsorption du CS sur la surface d'AC était très rapide (moins que deux minutes). De plus, l'analyse de surface par microscopie électronique à balayage a démontré que, pour de l'AC préservé dans une solution de CS a 10mM pendant 30 jours à 295 K, la corrosion était négligeable relativement à un échantillon préservé dans une solution dépourvue d'inhibiteur. En conclusion, le CS peut être utilisé efficacement comme inhibiteur de corrosion pour les systèmes de chauffage/refroidissement en AC, pour des températures s'élevant jusqu'à 333 K.</description><description>Carbon steel (CS) is widely used in water transporting systems because of its exceptional mechanical properties. However, CS is highly prone to corrosion, and uniform corrosion is the most common form of corrosion that affects CS. The internal corrosion of CS equipment is the main reason behind the failure of a closed loop water heating/cooling system. Water quality parameters like dissolved salts and gases, low pH, high temperature, galvanic and microbial activity greatly affect the rate of internal corrosion. Thus, it is important to mitigate internal corrosion of CS. One common way of mitigating corrosion is by using corrosion inhibitors. However, the commercially available corrosion inhibitors are found to be toxic and current research is focused on developing environmentally-friendly corrosion inhibitors.The objective of this work is to investigate the possibility of using sodium caprylate (SC) as an environmentally-friendly corrosion inhibitor for closed-loop-water heating/cooling system with CS as the substrate (material of construction) and the Montreal tap water as the electrolyte, under various conditions; concentration of SC, water temperature and pH, and time. Four electrochemical techniques and scanning electron microscopy were employed in the study.The results revealed that SC offered a 96% corrosion inhibition efficiency at 10mM concentration and at pH 8 and room temperature (295 K). The inhibition efficiency was found to be SC concentration dependent. Two distinctive regions of efficiency (lower/high) were identified, with the sharp transition occurring when going from 6.28mM to 6.3mM of SC in the water. The corresponding low-to-high corrosion inhibition efficiency transition can be linked to the abrupt change in surface concentration and orientation of SC. Experiments at varying temperature revealed that SC can also efficiency inhibit corrosion up to 333K. The inhibitor can also efficiently inhibit corrosion in the pH range form 7-10 pH. The kinetics study showed that adsorption SC onto the CS surface is very quick (within a couple of minutes). Furthermore, surface analysis study using SEM showed that for CS kept in 10 mM SC solution for 30 days at 295 K, there was negligible corrosion as compared to the sample that was kept in the inhibitor-free solution. In conclusion, SC can efficiently be used as a corrosion inhibitor for water heating/cooling systems made of CS, up to 333K.</description><creator>Bordoloi, Ipsita</creator><contributor>Sasha Omanovic (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Inhibition of carbon steel corrosion in closed-loop-water heating/cooling systems using sodium caprylate as an environmentally-friendly corrosion inhibitor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t8831.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np021</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xx48n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse reprend les théories de cohomologie symplectique de Tseng et Yau, qui fournissent des analogues symplectiques des cohomologies de Dolbeault, Bott-Chern et Aeppli pour les variétés complexes. Les propriétés de base de ces cohomologies, telles que leurs théories de Hodge, la finitude de leurs dimensions, leurs propriétés de dualité et les lemmes de Poincaré sont étudiés. Les cohomologies symplectiques sont calculées explicitement dans le cas des fibrés cotangents. Bien que cette thèse ne contienne pas de résultats nouveaux, elle contient des preuves détaillées de certains résultats qui sont énoncés sans preuve dans les travaux de Tseng et Yau. Nous concluons thèse avec des perspectives et des questions ouvertes.</description><description>This thesis is a review of the symplectic cohomology theories of Tseng and Yau, which give symplectic analogues of the Dolbeault, Bott-Chern and Aeppli cohomologies for complex manifolds. Basic features of these cohomologies, such as their Hodge theories, finite-dimensionality, duality properties and Poincaré lemmas are reviewed. The symplectic cohomologies are computed explicitly in the case of cotangent bundles. While none of the results of this thesis are new, we have given detailed proofs of a number of facts which are stated without proof in the foundational papers of Tseng and Yau. The thesis concludes with perspectives and open problems.</description><creator>Nazari Zahraei Motlagh, Erfan</creator><contributor>Niky Kamran (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Symplectic cohomologies and Hodge theories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74ct00k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xx48n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354h81z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes the design of a system of fast scintillation detectors arrayed around the Belle II interaction region with the goal of monitoring all major sources of accelerator beam-related background including injection background during the operation of Belle II.Belle II is a high-luminosity b quark factory facility located at the SuperKEKB electron-positron collider at the KEK laboratory in Japan. The main goal of Belle II is the search for evidence of new physics beyond the standard model of particle physics, through measurements of CP violation, rare decays, and searches for forbidden decays. It will improve the sensitivity to new physics by 1 to 2 orders of magnitude compared to previous B factory experiments. Belle II is currently in its commissioning phase, with first physics collisions planned for 2018. Due to higher beam currents and smaller beam sizes, beam-related backgrounds will be larger in Belle II than the ones experienced in Belle, the predecessor experiment of Belle II. Because these backgrounds can result in radiation damage and degraded detector performance due to high occupancy, real-time monitoring of backgrounds rates is essential. </description><description>Cette thèse décrit la conception d'un système de détecteurs à scintillation rapide répartis en réseau autour du point d'interaction du détecteur Belle II. L'objectif du réseau est de surveiller les sources principales de bruit générées par l'accélérateur dont le bruit d'injection qui survient pendant le fonctionnement de Belle II. Le détecteur Belle II est une usine à quarks b opérant à haute luminosité situé au collisionneur électron-positron SuperKEKB du laboratoire KEK au Japon. L'objectif principal du détecteur Belle II est la recherche de preuves de nouveaux phénomènes physiques au-delà du modèle standard de la physique des particules par la mesure de la violation de la symétrie CP, des désintégrations rares et par la recherche de désintégrations interdites. Une amélioration de la sensibilité à de la nouvelle physique de 1 à 2 ordres de grandeur par rapport aux usines à quarks b précédentes est prévue. Belle II est actuellement dans la phase de mise en service, les premières collisions physiques étant prévues pour 2018. Étant donné les plus grands courants et la plus petite taille des faisceaux, le niveau de bruit causé par le fonctionnement du collisionneur sera plus grand avec le détecteur Belle II que ce qui a été observé avec son prédécesseur, le détecteur Belle. Une surveillance du taux de bruit est essentielle puisqu'il peut causer des dommages par radiation ainsi qu'une détérioration de la performance du détecteur due à la haute occupation.</description><creator>Pikhartová, Helena</creator><contributor>Steven Robertson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Monitoring bean backgrounds at Belle II with scintillator detectors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh610.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h81z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pw26k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of education, as suggested by John Dewey (1916), is to equip every individual with knowledge and experience so they enter life post-graduation as engaged and informed citizens. University provides educational experiences that challenge students and ready them to serve as contributing members of diverse communities. Considering the the 21st century context and the complex issues present around the world, universities should educate, prepare, and empower students to resolve problems in society. This research applies a phenomenographic research approach to explore university students' conceptions of education, leadership, and citizenship. Data reveals that participants found these three themes to converge toward global citizenship, which comprises of six conceptions, including international participation, cross-cultural understanding, humanity, community contributions, travel zones for educational exchange, and world rights. These data offer recommendations for how to integrate global citizenship themes into student leadership development programming and educational opportunities that are relevant, challenging, and fulfilling for international undergraduate students of the 21st century. </description><description>Le but de l'éducation, suggéré par John Dewey (1916), est d'équiper chaque personne avec les compétences et les expériences pour qu'elle entre dans la société. Grâce à leur éducation, ces nouveaux citoyens seraient engagés et éclairés. L'université fournit aux étudiants les opportunités éducatives qui les stimulent et les préparent à devenir des membres des communautés. En considérant le contexte du 21e siècle et les problèmes complexes qui existent dans le monde entier, les universités doivent éduquer, préparer, et responsabiliser les étudiants à résoudre les problèmes de société. Cette recherche utilise une méthodologie qui s'appelle « phenomenography » pour découvrir les conceptions de l'éducation, le leadership, et la citoyenneté chez les étudiants internationaux. Les résultats montrent que ces participants ont trouvé que ces trois thèmes convergent vers l'idée de « global citizenship », ou la citoyenneté appliquée au monde entier. « Global citizenship » inclus six conceptions, comme la participation à l'international, l'appréciation des cultures différentes, l'humanité, la contribution aux communautés, l'échange entre des personnes pour les éduquer, et les droites humains mondiales. Cette recherche offre des recommandations pour intégrer ces conceptions de « global citizenship » dans les programmes de développement pour les étudiants à faire progresser leur leadership. Avec l'intégration de ces résultats, les programmes de développement seraient plus pertinents, stimulants, et satisfaisants pour les étudiants internationaux actuels.</description><creator>Dietzel, Christopher</creator><contributor>Lisa Starr (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Integrated Studies in Education</subject><title>Conceptions of education, leadership, and citizenship: student leadership development for global citizenship</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g5204.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pw26k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128d55b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The PALFA survey, the most sensitive search for radio pulsars, is ongoing at the Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico. The survey has now discovered more than 170 pulsars in the Galactic Plane, and the vast majority of these pulsars have periods shorter than 2 seconds. One reason that pulsar surveys may miss long-period radio pulsars is the strong effect of red noise at low modulation frequencies which reduces the sensitivity in this regime, notably for frequencies smaller than 0.1 Hz. It is possible to address this reduction in sensitivity by using a Fast-Folding Algorithm (FFA), a time-domain search technique that has the advantage of coherently summing all harmonics of a given frequency. The FFA, first introduced by Staelin (1969), has been implemented by scientists at Berkeley to look for transients in Kepler data. We have adapted this time-domain search for radio pulsar searching and applied it to PALFA observations. A basic description of the FFA and specific aspects of applying such an algorithm on pulsar searches will be discussed in this MSc thesis. A sensitivity analysis of the algorithm, conducted using synthetic pulsar signals injected in real observational data, will also be presented. This study shows that the FFA recovers significantly the loss in the survey sensitivity at low modulation frequencies, implying that the PALFA survey should discover more long-period radio pulsars in the future.</description><description>PALFA est le relevé astronomique de pulsars radio le plus sensible au monde. Ce relevé utilise le William E. Gordon Telescope, un radio télescope de 305-m de diamètre à l'Observatoire Arecibo, à Puerto Rico. PALFA a maintenant découvert plus de 170 pulsars dans le disque Galactique. La grande majorité de ces pulsars ont des périodes de rotations inférieures à 2 secondes. Une des raisons pourquoi les relevés astronomiques détectent peu de pulsars ayant de lentes rotations est l'impact nuisible du bruit rouge sur les basses fréquences de modulation, ce qui réduit la sensibilité des relevés dans ce régime (spécialement pour les fréquences de modulation plus petites que 0.1 Hz). Il est possible de (partiellement) remédier à ce problème en utilisant un Fast-Folding Algorithm (FFA), une technique de recherche de signaux périodiques dans le domaine temporel dont l'avantage réside en sa sommation cohérente des composantes harmoniques d'une certaine fréquence fondamentale. Cet algorithme, conçu par Staelin (1969), a été utilisé par des scientifiques à Berkeley dans le but de chercher des transits d'exoplanètes dans les données collectées par le telescope Kepler. Nous avons adapté le programme développé par ces scientifiques pour que ce dernier puisse détecter des signaux de pulsars avec les données recueillies par PALFA. Une description du FFA ainsi que les aspects spécifiques de son application dans notre relevé astronomique seront abordés dans ce mémoire. Une analyse de la performance du FFA, qui a été produite via l'injection de signaux synthétiques de pulsars dans de vrais données de PALFA, sera également présentée. Cette étude démontre qu'en utilisant cet algorithme, notre relevé astronomique est plus sensible aux signaux ayant de longues périodes, ce qui implique que PALFA devrait découvrir plus de pulsars ayant de lentes rotations dans le futur. </description><creator>Parent, Emilie</creator><contributor>Victoria Kaspi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>A search for long-period pulsars with a fast-folding algorithm in the PALFA survey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg24q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d55b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d252w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le gel electrophorese est conventionnellement utilise pour organiser et separer les macromolecules. Recemment, ils ont ete adoptes pour l'organisation et la caracterisation des nanoparticules. Tandis que l'interpretation theoretique de solutions (sans gel) de nanoparticules electrophoreses est bien developpee, des modeles pour l'interpretation des gels de nanoparticules electrophoreses sont nouveaux. Hill (2016) a recemment developpe un modele electrocinetique generale qui tient compte de la polarisation et les effets de relaxations pour calculer la mobilite du gel electrophoretique des nanoparticules spheriques fonctionnalises en les traduisant en particules chargees et non-chargees.Le modele englobe les effets hydrodynamiques base sur l'approximation de Brinkmanpour les particules de taille arbitraire, et inclut des modeles de regulation de la charge de pH. Dans cette etude, le modele a ete appliquee pour comparer avec des calculsindependants dans la litterature (incluant ceux qui ont ete eectuees en utilisant lelogiciel commercial nite-element). Le modele a aussi ete applique pour interpreter des donnees experimentales de gel electrophorese pour PEGlayted nanoparticules avec une fraction variant d'univalent chaines de PEG. Le modele a, avec precision, reproduitles calculs en litterature et elargit le parametre d'espace, demontrant le potentiel pour quantitativement interpreter la caracterisation des nanoparticules et le proces de separation.</description><description>Gel electrophoresis is conventionally used for sorting and separating macromolecules. More recently it has been adopted for nanoparticle sorting and characterization. While the theoretical interpretation of free-solution (without gel) nanoparticle electrophoresis is well developed, models for interpreting nanoparticle gel electrophoresis are new. Hill (2016) recently developed a generalized electrokinetic model that accounts for polarization and relaxation effects to calculate the gel electrophoretic mobilityof functionalized/soft spherical nanoparticles translating in charged and unchargedgels. The model captures hydrodynamic effects based on the Brinkman approximation for particles with arbitrary size, and includes pH charge regulation models. In this study, the model was applied to compare with independent calculations in the literature (including those undertaken using commercial nite-element software). It was also applied to interpret an experimental gel electrophoresis data for PEGylatednanoparticles with varying fraction of univalent PEG chains. The model accurately reproduced calculations in the literature, and extended the parameter space, now showing potential for quantitatively interpreting nanoparticle characterization and separation processes.</description><creator>Le, Liji</creator><contributor>Reghan James Hill (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Numerical calculation of gel electrophoretic mobility for "soft" spherical nanoparticles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z7771.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d252w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q874b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For the past 30 years, titanium implants have been used routinely to treat partial and complete dental edentulism. The clinical success of titanium implants relies on osseointegration, a process similar to bone healing. Successful osseointegration of titanium implant requires normal functioning of the biological events that occur during bone healing. Therefore, any factor that alters bone healing will jeopardise the success of titanium implant and might cause peri-implant complication or premature implant loss.Many people worldwide are exposed to long-term use of systemic medications. Many of these medications are known to interfere with bone accrual. Yet, little is known about the potential effect of these medications on titanium implant osseointegration. Selective Serotonin Re-uptake Inhibitors (SSRIs) are a group of anti-depressant drugs taken by more than 350 million patients worldwide; they inhibit the re-uptake of serotonin in the presynaptic clefts in the brain, giving the sensation of good mood. These drugs have been shown to decrease bone mineral density and increase the incidence of bone fracture. However, the potential effect of these drugs on bone healing and implant osseointegration has not been investigated yet. This thesis includes an in vivo study conducted to investigate the effect of SSRIs on bone healing and implant osseointegration. In this in vivo study, we have shown that SSRIs hinder bone healing and implant osseointegtration probably by altering the number and function of osteoblasts and osteoclasts, Moreover, we have demonstrated that SSRIs alter the immune response, causing changes in serum levels of many immunocytokines (i.e. IL-1β, INF-γ) involved in the inflammatory stage of the bone healing process. In this study, we provided the first scientific evidence on the negative effects of SSRIs on titanium implant osseointegration and bone healing. Consequently, SSRIs treatment should be taken into account by clinician upon patient selection, treatment planning, and maintenance for bone surgery and implant therapy. </description><description>Au cours des 30 dernières années, les implants en titane ont été utilisés couramment pour traiter l'édentorisme dentaire partiel et complet. Le succès clinique des implants de titane repose sur l'ostéointégration, un processus similiare à la guérison osseuse. L'ostéointégration réussie de l'implant de titane nécessite un fonctionnement normal des événements biologiques qui se produisent pendant la guérison osseuse. Par conséquent, tout facteur qui modifie la guérison osseuse compromettra le succès de l'implant de titane et pourrait entraîner une complication péri-implantaire ou une perte prématurée de l'implant.Beaucoup de personnes dans le monde sont exposées à long terme des médicaments systémiques. Il est convenu dans les littérature que beaucoup de ces médicaments interfèrent avec l'accumulation minérale dans les os. Pourtant, on connaît peu l'effet potentiel de ces médicaments sur l'ostéointégration des implant de titane. Les inhibiteurs sélectifs de réabsorption  de la sérotonine (ISRS) forment un groupe de médicaments antidépresseurs pris par plus de 350 millions de patients à travers le monde; Ils inhibent la ré-absorption de la sérotonine dans les fissures présynaptiques dans le cerveau, ce qui donne une sensation de bonne humeur. On a montré que ces médicaments diminuent la densité minérale osseuse et augmentent l'incidence de fractueres osseuses. Cependant, l'effet potentiel de ces médicaments sur la guérison osseuse et l'ostéointégration des implants n'a pas encore été étudié. Cette thèse comprend une étude in vivo menée pour étudier l'effet des ISRS sur la guérison osseuse et l'ostéointégration des implant. Dans cette étude in vivo, nous avons montré que les ISRS entravent la cicatrisation osseuse et l'osseointération des implants probablement en modifiant le nombre et la fonction des ostéoblastes et des ostéoclastes. En outre, nous avons démontré que les ISRS altèrent la réponse immunitaire, entraînant des changements dans les taux sériques de nombreuses immunocytokines (c'est à dire.  IL-1β, INF-γ) impliqués dans le stade inflammatoire du processus de guérison des os. Dans cette étude, nous avons fourni les premières preuves scientifiques sur les effets négatifs des ISRS sur l'ostéo-intégration de titane et la cicatrisation osseuse. Par conséquent, le traitment des ISRS doit être pris en compte par le clinicien lors de la sélection des patients du clinicien, la planification du traitement et la maintenance de la chirurgie osseuse et de la thérapie implantaire.</description><creator>Abu Nada, Lina</creator><contributor>Faleh Tamimi Marino (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Dentistry</subject><title>The effect of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors on bone healing and titanium implant osseointegration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt08s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q874b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161871m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There exists a prominent discrepancy between climate models and observations on thesign and magnitude of cloud radiative feedback during ENSO. Previous work, by Dessler(2013), showed that global climate models show a very strong, positive cloud feedback inthe central Pacific which is not present in observations. To better understand this discrep-ancy and the role of radiation in ENSO cycle, we use the radiation data from the CERES satellite dataset and atmospheric data from the ERA-interim reanalysis dataset to diagnosethe radiative energy budget. We extend the previous works by not only analyzing the TOA but also the surface and atmospheric radiation budgets, using a newly developed set ofradiation kernels. We find that cloud radiative feedback plays an interesting role duringthe ENSO cycle, helping the thermal anomalies to develop and sustain. It is important forthe global models to properly simulate the radiative energetic effects in order to improvetheir simulations of ENSO. Therefore, we draw comparisons to various prominent mod-els representative of the CMIP5 model ensemble. Through this comparison, we observethat the models, on average, exhibit a positive bias at TOA which is not completely dueto an overestimation of the longwave feedback, as previously thought, but also due to anunderestimation of shortwave feedback.</description><description>Il existe un écart important entre les modèles climatiques et les observations à proposdu signe et de l'amplitude de la rétroaction radiative des nuages pendant le cycle ENSO.Les travaux de Dessler (2013) montrent que les modèles climatiques globaux présententune rétroaction causée par les nuage très forte et de signe positif dans le Pacifique central,qui n'est toutefois pas présente dans les observations. Afin de mieux comprendre cet écartet le rôle de la radiation atmosphérique dans le cycle ENSO, nous utilisons les donnéesradiatives du satellite CERES et les données atmosphériques de la réanalyse ERA-interimpour faire un diagnostic du bilan radiatif. En effectuant une analyse du bilan radiatifà la surface et dans l'atmosphère, notre étude porte au-delà des travaux précédents quis'intéressent uniquement au sommet de l'atmosphère. Nous développons à cette fin unnouvel ensemble de kernels radiatifs. Nous trouvons que la rétroaction radiative des nu-ages joue un rôle clé durant le cycle ENSO en contribuant à la formation et au maintien desanomalies de température. Il est donc important pour les modèles de représenter correcte-ment les effets radiatifs afin d'améliorer les simulations d'ENSO. Dans cette perspective,nous établissons des comparaisons entre différents modèles représentatifs de l'ensemblemulti-modèles CMIP5. Nous trouvons que les modèles présentent en moyenne un biaispositif au sommet de l'atmosphère. Ce biais n'est cependant pas entièrement causé parune surestimation de la rétroaction du rayonnement aux ondes longues, comme supposéauparavant.</description><creator>Kolly, Allison</creator><contributor>Yi Huang (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</subject><title>Using El Niño to quantify cloud radiative feedback</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg250.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161871m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th94w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The incomplete spatial coverage of surface-water CO2 partial pressure (pCO2) data across estuary types represents a significant knowledge gap in current regional- and global-scale estimates of estuarine CO2 emissions. The Estuary and Gulf of St. Lawrence, at the southern limit of the subarctic region in eastern Canada, is the world's largest estuarine system and an excellent analogue of the more general coastal environment, yet no systematic study of its CO2 dynamics has been published to date. pH and total alkalinity measurements are used to calculate the pCO2 in the surface mixed layer that is in active contact with the atmosphere. On the basis of the available data, the area-averaged air-sea CO2 flux is estimated for the whole estuary. The key physical and biogeochemical processes controlling the spatial variability of surface-water pCO2 are then identified, using a further development of the extended optimum multiparameter (OMP) water mass analysis. In so doing, the physically- and biologically-induced changes of the inorganic carbon pool are differentiated.In late spring or early summer 2003–2016, the shallow, partially mixed, river-dominated Upper Estuary was a source of CO2 to the atmosphere due to microbial respiration of organic matter, whereas the deep, stratified, marine-dominated Lower Estuary was a sink of atmospheric CO2 due to net phytoplankton photosynthesis favored by the prevailing environmental conditions. Overall, the large subarctic St. Lawrence Estuary was a very weak source of CO2, with an area-averaged CO2 efflux of 0.98 to 2.02 mmol C m–2 d–1 (0.36 to 0.74 mol C m–2 yr–1) similar to that of strongly stratified and/or marine-dominated systems and Arctic estuaries.</description><description>La couverture spatiale éparse des mesures de pression partielle de CO2 dans les eaux de surface (pCO2) de différents types d'estuaires est une entrave à l'élaboration d'évaluations quantitatives des émissions de CO2 estuariennes à l'échelle régionale et mondiale. L'estuaire et le golfe du Saint-Laurent, à la limite inférieure de la région subarctique de l'est du Canada, est le plus grand système estuarien semi-fermé au monde. Pourtant, aucune étude systématique de la dynamique du CO2 dans ses eaux de surface n'a été publiée à ce jour. Des mesures du pH et d'alcalinité totale sont utilisées pour calculer la pCO2 dans la couche de mélange des eaux de surface en contact avec l'atmosphère sus-jacent. Sur la base des données disponibles, le flux de CO2 à l'interface mer-air est estimé pour l'ensemble de l'estuaire. Les processus physiques et biogéochimiques qui contrôlent la variabilité spatiale de la pCO2 en surface sont ensuite identifiés, en utilisant un nouveau développement de l'analyse multiparamétrique optimisée étendue (OMP). Ainsi, les changements de carbone inorganique induits par les processus physiques et biologiques sont identifiés.À la fin du printemps ou au début de l'été 2003–2016, l'estuaire supérieur, peu profond, partiellement mélangé et fluvial, représentait une source nette de CO2 à cause de la respiration microbienne de la matière organique allochthone ou autochthone, tandis que l'estuaire inférieur, plus profond, stratifié et maritime, constituait un puits net de CO2 en raison de la photosynthèse (conditions favorables à la croissance du phytoplancton). Globalement, le large estuaire subarctique du Saint-Laurent était une très faible source de CO2 vers l'atmosphère, avec un flux régional de CO2 de 0.98 à 2.02 mmol C m–2 j–1 (0.36 à 0.74 mol C m–2 yr–1) similaire à celui des systèmes fortement stratifiés et/ou maritimes et les estuaires arctiques.</description><creator>Dinauer, Ashley</creator><contributor>Alfonso Mucci (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Earth and Planetary Sciences</subject><title>Inorganic carbon dynamics in the Estuary and Gulf of St. Lawrence: a source or sink of atmospheric CO2 and factors that control the spatial variability in gas exchange</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v79j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th94w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v534m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Unique amongst surviving examples of Mosan metalwork, the London-Berlin Cross is the only Mosan enameled cross that preserves both its front and back plates. Yet, without its original core, scholarship has focused exclusively on questions of workshop style or iconographic developments in the twelfth century. Based on stylistic and iconographic similarities with other Mosan objects, most scholars hypothesize that the London-Berlin Cross once functioned as a reliquary for the True Cross. Iconography alone, however, does not provide strong enough evidence of its original function. This thesis offers a more extensive consideration of the London-Berlin Cross's liturgical role and its many potential uses. An examination into the material affordances of enamel and the artistic traditions from which it emerges, coupled with the roles of liturgical crosses in the twelfth century, reveal how objects such as the London-Berlin Cross effaced the boundaries that their modern titles often prescribe. Ultimately, this thesis demonstrates that the London-Berlin Cross was a polyvalent object that accommodated the manifold demands of the medieval liturgy.</description><description>Parmis les pièces d'art mosane ayant survécu au passage du temps, la croix Londres-Berlin est unique car c'est la seule croix émaillée dont les plaques d'avant et d'arrière sont encore existantes. Sans son corps originel, les chercheurs hésitent à examiner la croix Londres-Berlin au-delà de la citer comme exemple d'un style d'atelier d'art mosan ou du développement iconographique dans le XIIe siècle. Partageant des similarités iconographiques et étant basé stylistiquement avec d'autres objets contemporains, les chercheurs ont comme hypothèse que la croix Londres-Berlin aurait fonctionnée jadis comme un reliquaire pour la Vraie-Croix. Toutefois, cette thèse suggère un regard dans la fonction liturgique de la croix Londres-Berlin pour mieux considérer le potentiel de ses utilisations. Je considère comment les objets ont effacé les limites que leurs titres prescrivent souvent en considérant les propriétés matérielles de l'émail et les traditions artistiques dont il en émerge, associées aux rôles des croix liturgiques au XIIe siècle. Cette thèse démontre que la croix Londres-Berlin était un objet polyvalent qui accomodaient les multiples demandes de la liturgie médiévale.</description><creator>Corbett, Lindsay</creator><contributor>Hilsdale, Cecily (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Art History and Communications Studies</subject><title>Liturgical polyvalence and the potential of performance: reassessing the London-Berlin Cross</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w905.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v534m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95052939</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>According to the World Health Organization (World Health Organization, 2016), over one billion people, or 15% of the population, have some type of disability. In Canada, approximately 3.8 million people reported having a disability, and over three million adults (11%) reported having a physical disability (Statistics Canada, 2012a). People living with physical disabilities are at a higher risk of developing secondary physical and mental health conditions such as fatigue, obesity, and depression (Goodwin &amp; Compton, 2004; Heron, Kee, Cupples, &amp; Tully, 2015). The occurrence of secondary conditions has been associated with a lower quality of life and decreased independence for people with a physical disability (Motl &amp; McAuley, 2014). Physical activity is one way to decrease the severity and prevalence of these secondary conditions (Goodwin &amp; Compton, 2004). One type of physical activity is sport, which has been identified as a way of providing many psychological, physiological, and social benefits for people with a physical disability (Stephens, Neil, &amp; Smith, 2012). The largest sporting competition for elite athletes with a physical disability is the Paralympic Games and despite the exponential growth of the Games, the same growth and development has not occurred with empirical literature in this context, for either the coaches or the athletes participating in this event. Additionally, most of the samples in elite disability sport have been male only or mixed gender, most attributable to the small proportion of female athletes competing as a Paralympian. Thus, the purpose of the current study was to explore female Paralympic athlete preferences of effective coaching practices. Individual semi-structured interviews were conducted with eight female Paralympic athletes who each attended multiple Paralympic Games and achieved an average of eight combined Paralympic and Para Pan American medals. Interviews were transcribed verbatim and organized into themes and subthemes using thematic analysis, which provided the reader with a comprehensive understanding of each participants' experience (Braun &amp; Clarke, 2013; Sparkes &amp; Smith, 2014). Results from the analysis revealed that athletes preferred coaches who were able to adapt to the various needs of the individual, were knowledgeable of their sport, engaged in effective communication, and challenged athletes to reach their potential. Athletes also described negative coaching experiences and described coaches who insulted them based on their gender and disability, and engaged in selfish or manipulative behaviours. The athletes felt the coaches' behaviours impacted their satisfaction and success on both a personal and professional level. These results add to the small body of coaching knowledge in disability sport, and is one of the first studies to include an all-female sample of Paralympic athletes.  </description><description>D'après l'Organisme Mondiale de la Santé (World Health Organization, 2016), plus d'un milliard de personnes, ou 15% de la population, vivent avec un certain handicap. Au Canada, approximativement 3,8 millions de personnes ont déclarées avoir un handicap, et plus de trois million d'adultes (11%) ont déclarées avoir un handicap physique (Statistics Canada, 2012a). Les personnes vivantes avec un handicap physique sont à plus grand risques de développer des conditions secondaires, physiques et/ou mental, tel qu'épuisement, obésité, et dépression (Goodwin &amp; Compton, 2004 ; Heron, Kee, Cupples, &amp; Tully, 2015). L'apparition de conditions secondaires a été associée à une baisse de qualité de vie et une diminution de l'indépendance chez les personnes avec un handicap physique (Molt &amp; McAuley, 2014). L'activité physique est un moyen de diminuer la sévérité et la fréquence de ses conditions secondaires (Goodwin &amp; Compton, 2014). L'un des types d'activité physique est le sport, qui fournit de nombreux bénéfices psychologique, physiologique, et social pour les personnes avec un handicap physique (Stephens, Neil, &amp; Smith, 2012). Les Jeux Paralympiques sont la plus grande compétition sportive pour les athlètes atteint d'un handicap physique mais en dépit de la croissance exponentielle des Jeux, la même croissance n'a pas encore été observée pour la littérature empirique dans ce contexte, que ce soit pour les entraîneurs ou les athlètes participants à cet évènement. De plus, la majorité des échantillons ont été exclusivement masculins ou mixtes, en grande partie dû à la faible proportion d'athlètes Paralympique féminines. Par conséquent, l'objectif de cette étude était d'explorer les préférences de pratique d'entraînement efficace chez les athlètes Paralympique féminines. Des interviews individuelles semi-structurées  ont été conduites avec huit athlètes Paralympique féminines qui ont chacune participées à de multiples Jeux Paralympiques et ont chacune obtenue une moyenne combinées de huit médailles Paralympique et Para panaméricaines. Les interviews furent retranscrite verbatim et organisées en thèmes et sous-thèmes en utilisant une analyse thématique, ce qui fournit au lecteur une compréhension complète de l'expérience de chaque participantes (Braun &amp; Clarke, 2013 ; Sparkes &amp; Smith, 2014). Les résultats de l'analyse révélèrent que les athlètes ont eu une préférence envers les entraîneurs qui furent capable de s'adapter aux différents besoins de l'individu, étaient bien informés sur leur sport, qui ont contribués à une communication efficace, et qui ont stimulés leurs athlètes à atteindre leur potentiel. Les athlètes ont également décrites des expériences d'entraînement négatives et décrites des entraîneurs qui les ont insultés à cause de leur genres ou handicap, et qui ont adoptés un comportement égoïste ou manipulateur. Les athlètes ont ressenties que le comportement de leurs entraîneurs influencé leur satisfaction et leur succès sur un plan à la fois personnel et professionnel. Ses résultats s'ajoutent à la petite quantité de connaissances existant sur l'entraînement en handisport, et est parmi les premières études à inclure un échantillon d'athlètes Paralympique exclusivement féminin.</description><creator>Alexander, Danielle</creator><contributor>Gordon Bloom (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Female paralympic athlete preferences of effective coaching practices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m13p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052939</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p067r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette démonstration explore la conjoncture sous-théorisée de la pensée conservatrice en plaçant le travail politique de Joseph Schumpeter en dialogue avec les auteurs caractéristiques de la tradition conservatrice. Les similarités entre les conservateurs traditionnels, tels que Russell Kirk et Roger Scruton, et les conservateurs libéraux comme Friedrich Hayek et Michael Oakeshott sont d'abord débattues. Ces similitudes représentent une conception de la politique comme une association sans but, ainsi qu'une affirmation du scepticisme à travers le savoir et ses revendications politiques et sociales. Cet essai soutient que quand les conservateurs essaient de combiner les deux dimensions, ils privilégient continuellement l'absence de but sur le scepticisme épistémique et cela entraine des lacunes dans la théorisation du conservatisme. Pour rectifier ceci, cinq notions épistémiques sont extraites des travaux de Hayek et d'Oakeshott. Ces dernières sont aussi présentes dans l'ouvrage de Joseph Schumpeter. Cependant elles ne présentent pas le postulat ajouté sur l'absence de but. Ainsi, Schumpeter représente une nouvelle ouverture de la pensée conservatrice politique qui pourra être explorée dans le futur appelée « conservatisme épistémique ».</description><description>This essay explores an undertheorized juncture in conservative thought by putting Joseph Schumpeter's political thought in dialogue with authors representative of the conservative tradition. It begins by assessing the similarities between traditional conservatives such as Russell Kirk and Roger Scruton and liberal conservatives like Friedrich Hayek and Michael Oakeshott. These similarities are a conception of politics as a purposeless association, and an assertion of skepticism about social and political knowledge. The essay argues that when conservatives attempt to combine the two dimensions they consistently privilege the purposelessness over epistemic skepticism and that this has created a gap in theorizing conservatism. To rectify this, five epistemic ideas are extracted from the works of Hayek and Oakeshott and these are shown to also be present in the work of Joseph Schumpeter but without the added postulate of purposelessness. Schumpeter thus represents a new avenue in conservative political thought that can be explored in the future referred to as "epistemic conservatism". </description><creator>Schildroth, Eric</creator><contributor>Jacob Levy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Political Science</subject><title>Schumpeter's epistemic intervention in conservative thought</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc30k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p067r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n586v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We report on a search for Fast Radio Bursts (FRBs; bright, millisecond duration radio bursts of unknown origin) with the Green Bank Northern Celestial Cap (GBNCC) Pulsar Survey at 350 MHz. Pointings amounting to a total on-sky time of61 days were searched to a dispersion measure (DM; integrated column density of free electrons along the line of sight) of 3000 pc/cc while the rest (23 days; 29% of the total time) were searched to a DM of 500 pc/cc. No FRBs were detectedin the pointings observed through May 2016. We estimate a 95% confidence upper limit on the FRB rate of 3600 FRBs/sky/day above a peak flux density of 0.63 Jy at 350 MHz for an intrinsic pulse width of 5 ms. We place constraints onthe spectral index α by running Monte Carlo simulations for different astrophysical scenarios and cumulative flux densitydistributions of the FRB population. The non-detection with GBNCC is consistent with the 1.4-GHz rate estimate reported for the Parkes surveys for α &gt; +0.35 in the absence of scattering and free-free absorption and α &gt; −0.3 in the presence ofscattering, for a Euclidean flux distribution. The constraints imply that FRBs must exhibit either a flat spectrum or a spectral turnover at frequencies above 400 MHz. These constraints also allow us to estimate the number of bursts that can be detected with current and upcoming surveys. We predict that the Canadian Hydrogen Intensity Mapping Experiment (CHIME) may detect as many as 54 FRBs a day, making it well suited to obtain interesting constraints on spectral index, slope of the log N-log S function and pulse profile evolution across its bandwidth (400-800 MHz).</description><description>Dans ce mémoire, nous faisons état d'une investigation pour trouver des sursauts radio rapides (Fast Radio Bursts ; FRBs, de lumineux sursauts d'ondes radio ne durant qu'environ une milliseconde, dont l'origine est inconnue) avec le Green Bank Northern Celestial Cap (GBNCC), un relevé astronomique de pulsars opérant à 350 MHz. Au total, 61 jours de données ont été analysées jusqu'à une mesure de dispersion (dispersion measure ; DM, densité intégrée de la colonne d'électrons libres le long de la ligne de visée) de 3000 pc/cc, alors que 23 jours additionnels (29% du temps total d'observation) ont été analysés jusqu'à une mesure de dispersion de 500 pc/cc. Aucun FRBs n'ont été détectés dans les données collectées jusqu'en mai 2016. Nous estimons que 3600 FRBs/ciel/jour est la limite supérieure de la fréquence d'occurrence des FRBs, avec un interval de confiance de 95%, ayant une densité de flux d'au moins 0.63 Jy et une largeur intrinsèque de pulsation de 5 millisecondes, à 350 MHz. Nous plaçons des contraintes sur l'indice spectral α en conduisant des simulations de Monte Carlo pour différents scénarios astrophysiques et différentes distributions de densités de flux cumulatives de la population de FRBs. Le fait qu'aucune sources n'aient été détectées dans les données de GBNCC est consistent avec la fréquence d'occurrence à 1.4 GHz reportée par les relevés astronomiques de Parkes, pour α &gt; +0.35 dans l'absence de diffusion et d'absorption libre-libre, et α &gt; −0.3 avec la présence de diffusion pour une distribution euclidienne du flux. Ces contraintes impliquent que les FRBs doivent soit émettre un spectrum plat, ou bien il y a un changement dans l'émission à des fréquences plus élevées que 400 MHz. Nos résultats nous permettent également d'estimer le nombre de sursauts pouvant être détectés avec les relevés astronomiques présents et futurs. Nous prédisons que le Canadian Hydrogen Intensity Mapping Experiment (CHIME) pourra détecter jusqu'à 54 FRBs chaque jour, ce qui fera de CHIME l'expérience idéale pour obtenir des contraintes sur l'indice spectral des FRBs, sur la pente de la fonction log N-log S ainsi que sur l'évolution du profile de pulsation dans la bande passante du télescope (400-800 MHz).</description><creator>Chawla, Pragya</creator><contributor>Victoria Kaspi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>A search for fast radio bursts with the GBNCC pulsar survey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k984d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n586v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vr003</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse étudie la modélisation dynamique et le contrôle basé sur la passivité d'un système de câble à simple degré de liberté. Le modèle de câble à masse accumulée dèveloppé prend encompte les changements de masse de câble en raison de son enroulement et de son déroulement autour du treuil d'actionnement, avec la variation de masse répartie dans toutes les masses agglomérées. La rigidité des câbles varie également en fonction de la longueur de changement et est répartie sur toute la longueur du câble. Pour améliorer encore d'avantage le modèle dynamique, les limites de la méthode de masse groupée sont traitées à l'aide de la méthode Rayleigh-Ritz, avec un ensemble de fonctions basées sur l'état qui discutent des câbles de longueur variable. Une simplification du modéle basé sur l'énergie est proposée pour faciliter d'avantage la réduction de la charge de calcul lors de la simulation numérique impliquant le modéle proposé. Les réponses du système en boucle ouverte sont utilisées pour comparer l'effet de la simplification du modèle basé sur l'énergie. Les réponses en fréquence sont utiliséespour comparer l'influence du nombre de fonctions de base utilisées et fournir une comparaisonà un modèle de masse groupée. On constate que la troncature du modèle à base d'énergie préserve les fréquences naturelles du système tout en améliorant l'efficacité de calcul du modèle. L'hypothèse de charge utile massive est utilisée pour séparer la dynamique rigide et élastique dusystème. Un couple d'entrée et un débit de sortie modifiés sont utilisés pour développer une cartepassive d'entrée-sortie pour le système naturellement non localisé. Une loi de contrôle adaptatif basée sur la passivité est dérivée pour s'adapter dynamiquement aux changements dans les propriétés des câbles et l'inertie de la charge utile, et est testée en simulation. Le contrôleur est également conçu pour approximer les forces non linéaires agissant sur le câble et s'adapter aux incertitudes de l'inertie de la charge utile. L'effet de l'utilisation de différentes formes régressives est également analysé numériquement. Il est constaté que le contrôleur adaptatif estrobuste aux incertitudes du modèle et que les performances du contrôleur dépendent également des formes régressives sélectionnées. </description><description>This thesis investigates the dynamic modelling and passivity-based control of a single degree of freedom cable-actuated system. The lumped-mass cable model developed takes into account the changes in cable mass due to its winding and unwinding around the actuating winch, with the change in mass distributed throughout all the lumped masses. The stiffness of the cables is also varied according to the changing length and is distributed throughout the cable length. To improve the dynamic model further, the limitations of the lumped-mass method are addressed using the Rayleigh-Ritz method, with a set of state-dependent basis functions discretizing cables of varying length. A novel energy-based model simplification is proposed to further facilitate reduction in the computational load when performing numerical simulationsinvolving the Rayleigh-Ritz model. Open-loop system responses are used to compare the negligible differences between the energy-based model simplification and the full-order model. Frequency responses are used to compare the influence of the number of basis functions used and to provide a comparison to the lumped-mass model. It is found that the energy-based model truncation preserves the natural frequencies of the system, while improving the computational efficiency of the model. The massive payload assumption is used to decouple the rigid and elastic dynamics of the system, and a modified input torque and modified output rate are used to develop a passive input-output map for the naturally noncollocated system. A passivity-based adaptive control law is derived to dynamically adapt to changes in cable properties and payload inertia, and is tested in simulation. The controller is also designed to approximate thenonlinear forces acting on the cable and adapt to uncertainties in payload inertia. The effect of using different regressor forms in the adaptive control law is also analyzed numerically. It is found that the adaptive controller is robust to model uncertainties, and the performance of the controller depends on the selected regressor forms as well.</description><creator>Godbole, Harsh Atul</creator><contributor>James Forbes (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Dynamic modelling and control of cable-actuated systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fr371.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vr003</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm90j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude cherche à approfondir la compréhension des aspects sociaux de l'émotion en salle de classe au primaire. La collaboration et la conversation génèrent possiblement des émotions positives qui favorisent leur soutien progressif ainsi que la motivation scolaire (Jones and Isroff, 2005). Toutefois, ces mêmes conditions peuvent entraîner des émotions négatives et faire obstacle à la motivation lorsque les personnalités, objectifs et idées s'entrechoquent (Järvelä, Lehtinen, &amp; Salonen, 2000). S'il fut démontré que les émotions stimulent ou entravent les processus d'autorégulation pendant l'apprentissage (Muis et al., 2015), aucune étude n'a, à ce jour, cherché à expliquer comment les émotions sociales affectent la corégulation pendant l'apprentissage (Järvelä &amp; Hadwin, 2013). Cette recherche cible les émotions sociales surgissant pendant le processus collaboratif lors de l'apprentissage de notions complexes. Elle examine les antécédents (contrôle, valeur et besoins psychologiques de base) et les conséquences (processus corégulateurs et résultats de l'apprentissage) des émotions sociales émergeant chez des élèves qui collaborent pour résoudre un problème mathématique complexe. Vingt-neuf élèves de cinquième année du primaire, provenant de Montréal, furent placés en petits groupes pour résoudre une situation problème. Des données cernant la valeur de tâche, le contrôle pédagogique pour l'apprentissage mathématique et les besoins fondamentaux de satisfaction furent collectées. Les enregistrements audio des périodes furent transcrits et codés afin d'analyser les processus corégulateurs. Les résultats montrent que la valeur de tâche, le contrôle pédagogique pour l'apprentissage mathématique et les besoins fondamentaux de satisfaction constituent des antécédents significatifs aux émotions ressenties par les élèves impliqués dans un environnement social. Les émotions sociales suscitent des sentiments d'interrelation et des stratégies fonctionnelles de corégulation.</description><description>This study seeks to deepen the understanding of the social aspects of emotion in the classroom. Collaboration and conversation have the potential to generate positive emotions and foster motivation and support progressive communication and collaboration (Jones and Isroff, 2005). However, these same circumstances may bring about negative emotions and produce unique motivational barriers for students when personalities, objectives, and ideas clash (Järvelä, Lehtinen, &amp; Salonen, 2000). As researchers (Muis et al., 2015) have shown, emotions may facilitate or constrain self-regulatory processes during learning but, to date, no research has explored how social emotions may similarly affect the co-regulation of learning (Järvelä &amp; Hadwin, 2013), especially during learning of complex content. This study investigated the social emotions that arise during the collaborative process and explored the antecedents (control, value, and basic psychological needs) and consequences (co-regulatory processes and learning outcomes) of social emotions in the context of solving complex mathematics problems in a collaborative learning setting with elementary students. Twenty-nine, fifth grade students in the Montreal area were asked to solve a complex math problem in groups. Measures of task value, academic control for learning mathematics, and basic needs satisfaction in that group context were collected. Audio-recordings of the session were transcribed and coded to investigate co-regulatory processes. Results revealed that task value, control and basic needs were antecedents to the emotions that students experienced in the social context. Social emotions subsequently mediated relations between relatedness and functional co-regulatory strategies.</description><creator>Singh, Cara</creator><contributor>Krista Muis (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</subject><title>The role of social emotions and co-regulation of learning during complex math problem solving</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107155v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm90j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qm331</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:50:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stereotypy is one type of repetitive behavior observed in individuals with autism spectrum disorder (ASD). Researchers have found that engaging in stereotypic behaviors can impede opportunities for socialization and skill development (Ashburner et al., 2008; Cunningham &amp; Schreibman, 2008), and can inadvertently cause stress and stigma for families (Farrrugia, 2014; Guralnick, 2005). Luckily, early intervention (EI) has been found to improve certain ASD symptomology, such as deficits in communication and socialization (Cohen et al., 2006; Howard et al., 2005; Lovaas, 1987; Makrygianni &amp; Reed, 2010; Peters-Scheffer et al., 2011). Yet, only five publications to date have examined the effectiveness of EI (specifically early intensive behavioral intervention; EIBI) on stereotypic behaviors and although reductions have been noted, results have been overwhelming mixed (Ben-Itzchak &amp; Zachor, 2007; Dawson et al., 2010; MacDonald et al., 2014; McGarrell et al., 2009; O'Connor &amp; Healy, 2009). The present study aimed to contribute to the small body of literature in an effort to provide some insight into, if and, to what extent stereotypic engagement changes after EI. A quasi-experimental non-equivalent within-group design was conducted with a sample of children (N=20) with ASD, receiving either EIBI or a combination of the Carolina Curriculum and TEACCH models from EI centers in Montreal. A socio-demographic questionnaire and video recordings were administered at two time periods, at baseline and post-intervention, and data was collected on seven different forms of stereotypy. Results showed positive behavioral outcomes at post- intervention. Compared to baseline, two participants completely eliminated their stereotypy and 15 participants showed a 1% to 41% reduction in their engagement, regardless of the type of intervention received. EIBI group means specifically reduced from 24.7% at baseline to 17.7% at post-intervention. Participants who received less than one year or more than two years of EI were found to show the most reductions, both in terms of changes in the frequency and diversity of stereotypic engagement. Results are expected to contribute to the existing research literature and inform educators and service providers in the field early intervention. Keywords: autism spectrum disorder, stereotypy, early intervention, child outcomes</description><description>La stéréotypie est un type de comportement répétitif observé chez les personnes atteintes d'un trouble du spectre de l'autisme (TSA). Les chercheurs ont constaté que s'engager dans des comportements stéréotypés peut entraver les possibilités de socialisation et de développement des compétences (Ashburner et al., 2008; Cunningham &amp; Schreibman, 2008) et peut causer par inadvertance le stress et la stigmatisation pour les familles (Farrrugia, 2014, Guralnick, 2005). Heureusement, l'intervention précoce (IP) a été trouvée pour améliorer une certaine symptomatologie TSA, comme les déficits de communication et de socialisation (Cohen et al., 2006; Howard et al., 2005; Lovaas, 1987; Makrygianni &amp; Reed, 2010; Peters- Scheffer et al., 2011). Pourtant, seulement cinq publications, à ce jour, ont examiné l'efficacité de l'assurance- emploi (spécifiquement l'intervention comportementale intensive précoce, ICIP) sur les comportements stéréotypés et bien que des réductions aient été notées, les résultats ont été massifs (Ben-Itzchak &amp; Zachor, 2007; Dawson et Al., 2010; MacDonald et al., 2014; McGarrell et al., 2009; O'Connor &amp; Healy, 2009). La présente étude visait à contribuer à la petite littérature dans le but de donner un aperçu, si et dans quelle mesure l'engagement stéréotypé change après l'AE. Une conception quasi expérimentale non équivalente à l'intérieur des groupes a été menée avec un échantillon d'enfants (N = 20) avec TSA, soit ICIP, soit une combinaison du programme Carolina Curriculum et des modèles TEACCH des centres IP à Montréal. Un questionnaire sociodémographique et des enregistrements vidéo ont été administrés à deux périodes, à la ligne de base et après l'intervention, et les données ont été recueillies sur sept formes différentes de stéréotypie. Les résultats ont montré des résultats comportementaux positifs lors de la post- intervention. Par rapport à la ligne de base, deux participants ont complètement éliminé leur stéréotypie et 15 participants ont montré entre une réduction de 1% à 41% de leur engagement, quel que soit le type d'intervention reçue. Le groupe ICIP signifie spécifiquement réduit de 24,7% à la base à 17,7% à la post-intervention. Les participants qui ont reçu moins d'un an ou plus de deux ans d'assurance-emploi ont montré le plus de réductions, tant en termes de changements dans la fréquence que dans la diversité de l'engagement stéréotypé. Les résultats devraient contribuer à la littérature de recherche existante et informer les éducateurs et les prestataires de services dans le domaine de l'intervention précoce. Mots-clés: trouble du spectre de l'autisme, stéréotypie, intervention précoce, résultats des enfants</description><creator>Fernandez, Melissa</creator><contributor>Ingrid Sladeczek (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</subject><title>Stereotypic behaviors in children with Autism Spectrum Disorder: Observations of stereotypic engagement after receiving early intervention</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mz07m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qm331</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5800</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>