<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:35:18Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11950" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w788c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the course of a confidential War Research by another worker, it was found that a large excess of free hydroxylamine dissolved in pyridine caused the removal of approximately one mole of nitrate group per glucose unit from cellulose trinitrate, the nitrogen being nearly quantitatively recovered as such in the gaseous phase. Experimental evidence indicated that the removal of the nitrate group left an hydroxyl group in the cellulose portion and that this hydroxyl group was probably of a secondary alcohol type. All attempts to identify the secondary alcohol position from which the nitrate group had been removed were unsuccessful. In the present research the hydroxylamine - pyridine reaction was applied to crystalline, fully-nitrated methyl-α and β-glucosides in order to locate the nitrate group or groups attacked by the reagent. [...] It was found that the nitrate group in the fourth position (secondary alcohol) of the glucoside took part in the reaction and this fact permitted an easy preparation of crystalline methyl-4-methyl-β-D-glucoside. It is suggested that this compound, which possesses ether linkages at positions one and four, may prove to be valuable as a model substance for future studies of cellulose reactions.</description><creator>Hayward, Lloyd Douglas.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The denitration of sugar nitrates.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv073.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w788c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k837d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The well-known regulation of the electrolyte balance by the adrenal cortex has been attributed to its secretion of a hormone similar to, if not identical with, desoxycorticosterone. A deficiency of adrenocortical hormone lowers both serum chloride and sodium, and elevates potassium. Therapy with desoxycorticosterone rapidly restores these electrolyte levels to normal by markedly increasing the retention of sodium and chloride and reducing the renal retention of potassium. Therefore it seemed paradoxical to find that large doses of desoxycorticosterone acetate (DCA) can lower the serum chloride of both normal and adrenalectomized animals. At the outset of this research, the problem was to determine the mechanism by which DCA produced this hypochloremia, which has been observed by several investigators. It seemed probable that it was an overdosage effect related to the loss of potassium produced by DCA, and that this steroid must increase the urine chloride excretion, contrary to the available information indicating that it produces chloride retention.  These factors were investigated. Balance studies on chloride and potassium ions were performed to determine the relation between the chloride and potassium excretions in potassium deficiency. This problem of the effect of DCA and potassium deficiency on chloride balance forms the first part of this thesis.[...]</description><creator>Henrikson, Helen A.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Potassium deficiency and gastro-intestinal function.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s18s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k837d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg909</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>“Je tiens le discrédit actuel de Zola pour une monstrueuse injustice qui ne fait pas grand honneur aux critiques littéraires d’aujourd’hui.” 1 L’oeuvre de Zola est si “actuelle” et les remous qu’elle a provoqués encore si récents, et parfois si profonds, dans l’opinion publique française; l’auteur de Mes Haines a fait surgir tant de protestations passionnées, que l’appareil critique n’encombre pas encore l’étudiant qui s’attaque à un romancier de cette envergure. Il semble, en vérité, que c’est par l’oubli que la génération de 1900 se soit vengée de Zola et aucune réputation littéraire - sauf peut-être celle d’Anatole France vingt ans plus tard - n’a souffert une “déflation” plus rapide. Plus injuste aussi, comme Gide le constate dans son Journal. Car Zola est plus que le “romancier de masses” que proclament les manuels. C’est aussi un penseur - sans doute pas vin penseur très profond ni très subtil - mais aussi authentique dans son effort pour aller au fond des choses que Victor Hugo quand il s’essaie à la métaphysique.[...]</description><creator>Hepburn, Johnston Sumner.</creator><contributor>Launay, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Zola, Émile, 1840-1902 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>La religion du travail dans l’oeuvre d’Emile Zola.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq00d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg909</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m5086</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is an attempt to discover whether it is possible for the rat to learn anything about a simple maze problem by seeing it before actually being tested on it. While the results have not shown that this can happen, they are suggestive and seem to warrant further investigation of the problem. </description><creator>Heron, Woodburn.</creator><contributor>Hebb, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY, COMPARATIVE</subject><subject>RATS</subject><title>An investigation of perceptual latent learning in the rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q031z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m5086</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp149</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The centenary of Hopkins’s birth was celebrated in 1944. Many important books on the poet prepared at that time were restricted in scope or delayed in publication because of war-time conditions. Thus much material, including newly discovered manuscripts of Hopkins, has only recently (1948-49) been published. The work of W.H. Gardner is of special significance. In 1948 he edited the third edition of the Poems, which was enlarged to include many of Hopkins’ s early pieces. In 1949 he published the second volume of his Hopkins study, now the most complete and balanced examination of the poet. This scholarly activity favours a close investigation of the poetry.[...]</description><creator>Heuser, Alan.</creator><contributor>Anderson, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Hopkins, Gerard Manley, 1844-1889 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>An investigation of the poetic imagery of Gerard Manley Hopkins.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322h855.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp149</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p790g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies that have been conducted to compare the relative fungicidal value of Bordeaux mixture and Dithane spray have indicated that the two fungicides are about equally effective in controlling the diseases of the potato. Bordeaux mixture, however, as well as having fungicidal value also acts to some extent as an insecticide, and gives some control of flea beetles and leaf hoppers. [...]Bordeaux mixture is known to have an adverse effect on such physiological functions of the plant as photosynthesis, transpiration, and the rate of maturing and growth of the plant. No investigations have been conducted to determine the physiological effect of Dithane spray on plants, but the published results of several field tests reveal that where the insects controlled by Bordeaux are not important, and when there is no deficiency of copper in the soil, Dithane spray gives higher yields than Bordeaux mixture. The increased yield resulting from the use of Dithane spray suggested to the writer that Dithane spray was less toxic to the plant than Bordeaux, and in order to determine if this were so, investigations were conducted to compare the effect of the two fungicides on the foliage growth, rate of maturing, tuber development, and starch formation of the potato, and the cuticular transpiration of the tomato.</description><creator>Hodgson, William A.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>The effect of dithane sprays on some physiological functions of the plant.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418r516.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p790g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602416v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the beginning of mental testing, the concept of the normal distribution of human intelligence has influenced the theory of test construction to a great extent. This is understandable if intelligence itself is regarded in the light of the knowledge concerning other human properties, for there is then some justification to support the belief that it may be normally distributed in human beings. Unfortunately, however, the basic result of this concept in the field of mental test construction has been to effect the construction of tests which, owing to the properties of the normal curve, did not discriminate to the maximum possible extent amongst testees. Although the theory of test construction has been under consideration since the time of Bine’s original work in this field, during the past ten years or so a considerable amount of specialized work has been done on this subject. The concepts of discriminatory capacity and internal consistency of a test have emerged and have brought about a gradual change in the theory of mental test construction. The purpose of this work is to examine in an empirical manner, as accurately as possible, some of the newly-deduced theoretical assumptions in these same concepts.</description><creator>Holmes, Anthony Frederick.</creator><contributor>Ferguson, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY -- MENTAL TESTS</subject><title>On the properties of distributions of test scores.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n19z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602416v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999986t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A simple, portable instrument is described which employs the nuclear absorption method and the known value of the proton magnetic moment to determine magnetic field strength. No known fields and no geometrical calculations are required for calibration. The range covered by the present instrument is approximately 3000 to 19000 oersteds. No upper limit is inherent in the method. Homogeneity is required over a small cylindrical volume. Absolute accuracy of better than ± 0.2 percent is obtainable depending only on precise measurement of frequency. Higher accuracy is possible in comparing fields and in measuring field changes.</description><creator>Hopkins, Nigel John.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Magnetic fields accurately measured from proton magnetic moment.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg91k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999986t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hg30p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Parmi les écrivains français qui ont eu le plus de prise sur la jeunesse de l’entre-deux guerres, Jean Giono demeure un de ceux dont la lecture ne saurait nous laisser indifférents. Car Giono est le contraire même de l’écrivain froid: un vent de passion anime toute son oeuvre, et déploie, comme autant de drapeaux, les idées qui l’ont suscitée ou inspirée. L’intensité même des sentiments, leur profondeur, leur authenticité ne peuvent qu’émouvoir profondément ou inspirer une répulsion totale. Il faut “aimer” Giono, ou le “détester”. Ce prophète d’un monde meilleur et ce devin des forces sournoises des plateaux de Provence n’est pas pour “les tièdes”. A ceux qui aiment Giono, à ceux qui se laissent emporter par son souffle, à ceux qui s’abandonnent sans arrière-pensée à son offrande de générosité, de mystère et d’humain, l’adhésion tacite semble toute naturelle; il ne viendrait jamais à l’esprit de la discuter, de lui faire simplement subir l’examen de la raison raisonnante, de la passer au crible de la logique.[...]</description><creator>Howell, Helen Marie.</creator><contributor>Launay, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Giono, Jean, 1895-1970 -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Le monde de Jean Giono.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f18f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hg30p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913t05j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The combustion of hydrocarbon fuels is essentially the more or less complete oxidation of the hydrogen and carbon constituents. The theoretical heat content per pound of fuel may be calculated from the known heat of combustion of hydrogen and carbon. The process of obtaining energy from the burning of liquid (and gaseous) hydrocarbons applies to a great number and range of heat engines; from the common coal-oil heater through a variety of internal combustion reciprocating engines, up to the present day gas turbine. From oil heaters to reciprocating engines to gas turbines, we ascend in an order of increasing refinement of control of the process. There are certain fundamental requirements for efficient combustion: (1) Stoiciometric Air/Fuel ratio, (2) Thorough mixing of air and fuel vapor, (3) A sufficiently high localized temperature to sustain the ignition process, (4) Time and space to permit the process to go to completion. Regardless of how the energy of combustion may be used, the conditions outlined above must still be met to a greater or less degree as economy in dollars, weight, or size may dictate.[...]</description><creator>Howell, Allison Brant.</creator><contributor>Mordell, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>Use of a vaporizer and flame-tube combustor in studying combustion of hydrocarbon fuels.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193d10m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913t05j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh97g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to investigate the effects of electroconvulsive shocks on gestation and maternal behavior in the multiparous rat. In a recent study, Rosvold (13, 14) investigated the effects of electroconvulsive shocks on gestation and maternal behavior in the nulliparous white rat raised in the Stanford laboratory. It was shown that electroconvulsive shocks disrupt pregnancy and interfere with such components of maternal behavior as nest building, parturition, lactation, cleaning of the young, retrieving and maintenance of the nest. Further, the seriousness of the effect seemed to be related to the period of pregnancy - lactation cycle during which the shocks were administered. His results also indicated a rise in the body temperature of the animal during the period in which the shocks were administered. He concluded that the effects of electroccnvulsive shock on pregnancy and maternal behavior appeared to be greater than could be accounted for by known or hypothetical cortical damage. Hormonial dysfunction as a result of the shock was suggested as a basis for explaining the results.[...]</description><creator>Hoyt, Ruth.</creator><contributor>Rosvold, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY, COMPARATIVE</subject><subject>RATS</subject><title>The effects of electroconvulsive shocks on gestation and maternal behavior in the multiparous rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf206.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh97g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795b98h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When a suspension of cellulose fibres in water is shaken or stirred with sufficient violence to produce a uniform dispersion and allowed to come to rest, it is observed that the dispersion tends to become less uniform in distribution of fibres. This important but little understood phenomenon is termed “flocculation” by analogy to the coagulation of a colloidal dispersion. Flocculation is usually undesirable during certain stages in the process of paper making. If it occurs during or just prior to the forming of the sheet on the wire of the paper machine, the pulp fibres are distributed unevenly and a non-uniform sheet results. When a sheet has a very poor “formation”, the ink is not distributed uniformly over the surface of the paper during the printing process. This prohibits the use of the paper in services where good reproduction is required. The strength and general appearance of paper are also determined, in large measure, by the formation. It is therefore of extreme importance that the principles of cellulose fibre flocculation be determined so that they may be available to the paper maker. There are other instances in which a more thorough knowledge of the principles of flocculation would be of value. In fibre recovery systems it is desirable to promote flocculation. In producing dissolving-grade pulps of uniform permeability and swelling properties it is of considerable importance to have the fibres uniformly dispersed when the pulp sheets are formed.[...]</description><creator>Hubley, Charles Emerson.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Flocculation of cellulose fibre suspensions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w2974.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b98h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd376091g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of early learning has been of increasing interest to psychologists in recent years. It has become clear that investigation of the effects of early experience upon adult behaviour is essential to a comprehensive understanding of that behaviour. This emphasis on early experience arises from a consideration of numerous experimental findings, as well as from the Freudian theory of psycho-sexual development.* Although doubt has been east upon the acceptability of some of these psychoanalytic principles (Orlansky, 1949) they have nevertheless provided a Stimulus to fruitful experimentation. It was shown by Hunt (1941) that rats suffering feeding-frustration during infancy tended to display more hoarding behaviour after periods of starvation at maturity than rats that had not been so deprived during early life. A similar phenomenon occurred as a result of lack of satisfaction of sucking needs in puppies (Levy, 1947). These puppies in later life displayed a “perverted” type of continual sueking and oral behaviour. Wolf fs (1943) study is particularly interesting. One group of rats was temporarily blinded and a second temporarily deprived of audition during early life.[...]</description><creator>Hymovitch, Bernard.</creator><contributor>Hebb, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>ANIMAL INTELLIGENCE</subject><subject>PSYCHOLOGY, COMPARATIVE</subject><title>The effects of experiential variations on problem solving in the rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591c353.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd376091g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r52g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Macaroni is made from the coarse, ground middlings of the endosperm of durum wheat. This material is called semolina and closely resembles “cream of wheat” in appearance. The semolina is mixed with the minimum amount of water necessary to produce a homogeneous mass during the mixing stage. This mass then undergoes a kneading treatment, during which it becomes a smooth and cohesive dough. It is then extruded, under considerable pressure, through dies and is dried slowly under controlled temperature and humidity conditions. There are three principal criteria on which macaroni is judged. It must withstand prolonged boiling in water, retaining its shape, and leaving little residue in the water. It must stand up physically under packing, storage and transportation without cracking or breaking. It must have a smooth amber-yellow appearance. The first two of these criteria are largely functions of the quality and quantity of the protein present in the wheat from which semolina is made. The third criterion is a function of both the processing technique and the amount of yellow pigment remaining in the finished product. Almost all varieties of durum wheat grown in Canada yield macaroni which satisfies the first two of these criteria, although a number of varieties are not satisfactory from the standpoint of the third criterion. Hence the question of colour becomes of primary importance [...]in the development of new varieties of durum wheats.[...]</description><creator>Irvine, G. N.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>A kinetic study of the oxidation of carotenoid pigments during the processing of macaroni.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848t75w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r52g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v8901</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The crowning achievement of the experimental study of diabetes has, so far, been the isolation and purification of insulin. Through this agent we have at our disposal an effective means of controlling clinical cases of diabetes and thus considerably improving the prognosis of the disease. The task of the experimental investigation of the disease, however, is far from having been completed. Not only are many of its biochemical mechanisms still obscure, but even the morphological changes in the islets of Langerhans, which are probably of fundamental importance, are only poorly understood. More than seventy years after the first description of islet lesions we have to admit our inability to determine with certainty the presence or absence of diabetes by histological methods. [...]The prospect of finding a permanent cure for the disease, which must always remain the ultimate aim of medical research, does not appear to be as remote as in most other diseases of advanced age. The islet tissue of both human patients and experimental animals frequently shows marked regenerative activity which, however, appears clinically ineffective. It is one of the more immediate tasks at present confronting morphological research to relate the changes in the islets to the clinical state of the patient and to find criteria for the determination of the functional state of the islet cell. Only then can the cause of their occasional apparent inactivity be determined.[...]</description><creator>Jaffe, Frederick A.</creator><contributor>Duff, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Quantitative changes in the islets of Langerhans following alloxan.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666790j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v8901</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687m44x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our provisions for dependent groups in our communities are so conditioned by the moralistic philosophy of the past, and by our attitudes towards them as individuals, that it becomes necessary from time to time to evaluate our thinking in this connection. It is somewhat disconcerting to discover that many of our present provisions for dependents in our society continue to be based on the theories that were widely held as far back as the seventeenth century. We are all too familiar with the reaction that meets any new social welfare measure which aims at putting certain economic props under various dependent groups. It is constantly re-iterated that the government is encouraging laziness, sloth, and irresponsibility. An historical survey suggests that this philosophy seems to have its roots in Puritan beliefs and later, in the bourgeois conception that prosperity was synonymous with virtue and similarly, that poverty was synonymous with vice. It is implicit in this philosophy that, if a person were a thrifty, hard working person, he would never become a public charge - even in old age. Because our present day attitudes are tinged with century-old, moralistic thinking, many of our welfare provisions have been punitive and harsh in their administration.[...]</description><creator>Jewett, Marion Shiell.</creator><date>1949</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>An evaluation of the old age pension system in Canada: an analysis based on the socio-economic needs of one hundred aged clients of the Family Welfare Association of Montreal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s808w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687m44x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fv90v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From the defeat of Llewelyn by Mortimer in 1284 until the union with England in 1536 the Welsh had continued proudly to regard themselves as an independent nation. Conquered many times in battle, the Welsh chieftains had always withdrawn to their mountain retreats, where pursuit and decisive overthrow had been impossible. Even in defeat such a chieftain as Owen Glyndwr was able to communicate to his people a clear vision of their future as an independent nation. Indeed [...]these Welsh people regarded such a losing battle as a spiritual triumph, and they were never less united to England than in such defeat. The Act of Union was designed to eradicate this Welsh isolation, to transform Wales into a part of England for all political and administrative purposes. In spite of the failures of the past, the authors of the Act had reason to be confident of its success. The great Welsh landowners had already identified themselves with the cause of Henry Tudor, and had become thoroughly Anglicised. Some of them, like William Herbert, Earl of Pembroke, continued to use the Welsh language when speaking to their tenants, but for the most part they were English in thought and speech. The influence of such men was expected to bring about the easy overthrow of Welsh institutions. For a while, certainly, this apparent overthrow of the ideals of Welsh independence, seemed to have an atrophysing effect on Welsh poetry, which entered on one of the leanest periods in its history.[...]</description><creator>Jones, Taliesin.</creator><contributor>Duthie, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>WELSH LITERATURE -- HISTORY AND CRITICISM</subject><title>A survey of Anglo-Welsh poetry : the continuity between seventeenth and twentieth century Anglo-Welsh poets.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m723d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv90v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cp088</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Bourget map-area is bounded by latitudes 48030' N and 48°45' N and longitudes 71°15' W and 71°30' W, and includes Bourget Township, the larger part of Begin Township, as well as parts of the townships of Labrecque, Taché, Falardeau and Kenogami, all in Chicoutimi County, Quebec. Most parts of the area are readily accessible, being traversed by numerous gravelled roads connected with Chicoutimi, Jonquière, and St. Joseph d’Alma. These towns are connected by the Canadian National Railways with Quebec and Montreal. In addition, the Saguenay River is navigable up to Chicoutimi. Physiographically, the Bourget map-area lies within the belt of low country of the Lake St. John - Saguenay region, which is sharply contrasted to the more rugged adjacent parts. The geology of this region is noteworthy in that it is partly underlain by one of the largest, if not the largest, anorthosite massif in the world; and that it contains scattered outliers of paleozoic strata well within the Precambrian Shield. Furthermore, the lowland was flooded by the post-glacial Champlain Sea, which extended like a tongue between the adjacent higher regions.[...]</description><creator>Jooste, René François.</creator><contributor>Jolliffe, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Geology of the Bourget map-area Chicoutimi county, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193d11w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp088</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb83r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is concerned with certain emotional needs as manifested by a group of men hospitalized at the Allan Memorial Institute of Psychiatry. These needs we have called “Dependency Needs” because their distinguishing characteristic is that their satisfaction must be supplied by someone other than the individual, thus placing him in a dependent situation. [...]In the process of the individual’s growth and development, [...]. Some demands will be discarded, while others will receive satisfaction or suffer disappointment from the environment. Each experience of satisfaction and disappointment will mold these demands so that they tend to form a characteristic pattern in the individual’s emotional life. These demands may be roughly defined as a desire for freely given affection, for tolerant understanding and for protection by someone to whom the person may turn in times of particular emotional need. It will depend on the development of a given individual’s life experience with his environment whether he will have either an exaggerated need which cannot be met in normal adult life, whether he will have ordinary needs which can be met by normal conditions in the environment, or whether he will create elaborate defenses against his needs. If the last alternative develops, the individual’s own defenses will not allow him to seek positive satisfaction for his emotional needs.</description><creator>Smith, Joy R. Powels.</creator><date>1949</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>Dependency needs as manifested by twenty men hospitalized at the Allen Memorial Institute of Psychiatry and referred to social service.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30px01x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb83r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838374r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The minute size of the bacterial cell and the fact that the bacteria is unicellular has made the problem of liberating the bacterial nucleoproteins difficult, and has led to numerous devices and methods for breaking the cells. The methods for releasing bacterial intracellular proteins might be classified thus: I Mechanical II Sonic or Ultrasonic Vibration III Freezing and Thawing IV Chemical Treatments.[...]</description><creator>Kahnka, Mary J.</creator><contributor>MacPherson, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Bacteriology.</subject><title>Nucleoproteins of the Staphylococcus in connection with immunity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z1353.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838374r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q7499</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The immediate interest in the problem under investigation was aroused while the author was interning at the Children’s Memorial Hospital. In the course of following several cases of acute haematogenous osteomyelitis it was stated by one of the attending staff that it was his clinical impression that the appearance of lymphadenopathy did not occur until the infective process has spread beyond the confines of the bone involved to the surrounding soft tissues.[...] Certainly if the lymphatic glands do not become enlarged until the tissues about the involved bone become infected, lymphadenopathy would give some indication of the extent of the disease. This has become particularly important since the advent of chemotherapy, and the use of the antibiotics as a possible sole means of controlling the pathological process. Preliminary review of the standard texts of anatomy and pathology showed that there was no great stress placed upon the existence, or a function of a lymphatic system within the skeletal structure. The presence of such a lymphatic drainage would be of importance also in the ectogenous type of osteomyelitis that is found in compound fractures, or in infective processes lying close to bone.[...]The purpose of this investigation has been to determine whether there is a lymphatic distribution in bone, and if so what its relationship is to the general lymphatic structure.[...]</description><creator>Karn, Gordon M.</creator><contributor>Webster, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Lymphatic drainage of bone with special reference to osteomyelitis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj70t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q7499</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zb96k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present work is a continuation of an investigation initiated by Brown and Purves (1). They found that the nitrogen content of a cellulose nitrate from solventextracted cotton, linters could be varied by pre treatments of the starting material, using strictly physical methods which could promote no change in chemical composition. A mercerized sample of cotton linters which had a high nitration reactivity could be converted to a topochemical modification with a lower nitration reactivity by the simple operation of drying from water rather than through the solvent exchange series : water - methanol - benzene. It was the immediate purpose of the present work to examine in detail the dependency of the reactivity toward nitration on the pretreatment of cellulose, to increase or diminish the magnitude of the effect if possible, and to study the phenomenon in terms of a number of nitration variables. In a broader sense, therefore, the present work employed nitration as a means of studying the structure of cellulose in the range of magnitudes between the X-ray crystallites and the microscopically visible morphological building units. The main body of the work involved the preparation of several hundred samples of cellulose nitrates from cotton linters or from wood pulp variously treated prior to nitration and under various conditions of nitration.[...]</description><creator>Keays, John Lake.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The effect of various pretreatments on the nitration of cellulose.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193d125.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zb96k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts30g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Available evidence leads us to believe that all parasitic nematodes have been derived at one time or another, from free-living nematode ancestors. The assumption of a parasitic existence has probably occurred at different periods during the evolutionary history of these worms, and therefore no one group of the present free-living nematodes can be said to have given rise to all parasitic forms. In spite of modifications and adaptations due to a parasitic life, all nematodes, whether free-living or parasitic, seem to have originated from the same evolutionary stem. On the basis of morphological similarity Baylis and Daubney (1926) united both the freeliving and the parasitic nematodes which were hitherto treated separately. Filipjev (1934) and Chitwood (1937) later contributed to make that classification more natural. The parasitic nematodes have developed a number of morphological, physiological and biological modifications which not only help them to live in an unfamiliar environment inside the body of the host but also enable them to gain access to new hosts. If a study of the life-cycles of the parasitic forms is made, a number of evolutionary stages from the freeliving to a complete parasitic life can be traced.[...]</description><creator>Khan, M. Abdul Basir.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>The morphology and biology of Strongyloides Papillosus (Wedl, 1856).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wn523.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts30g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vf63n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At the outset the purpose of the present investigation was to fit another piece into the puzzle of cortical representation of autonomic function. This work is a part of a long term investigation aimed at the elucidation of the relation of the cerebral cortex to the physiology of visceration (Yakowlev). The particular facet of this problem upon which attention is focused is the cortical control of gastric function. The present paper is a continuation of work begun by Dr. T.J. Speakman in 1947. As seems inevitable in the field of play of autonomic physiology, lack of specificity, simultaneous firing of separate systems and the close peripheral interdependence of these systems have given an accumulation of non-gastric responses which cannot be excluded from a discussion of the particular problem at hand. For these reasons the results of all types of experiments will be divided into the following categories: 1) Gastric motor and secretory responses, 2) blood pressure effects, including changes in cardiac rate and “Traube-Hering” waves, and 3) respiratory, both diaphragmatic and thoracic. When the occasion demands, associated responses, such as salivation mastication and deglutition, will be included among the responses enumerated.[...]</description><creator>Kite, William C.</creator><contributor>Penfield, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery.</subject><title>The cortical representation of gastric motor function.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96024174.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf63n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dj809</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:11:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Kobernick, Sidney D.</creator><contributor>More, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Cardiac lesions produced in rabbits by foreign serum proteins and adjuvants and their relation to the cardiac lesions of human rheumatic fever.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb841.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj809</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11975</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>