<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:23:02Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33550" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429b99k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies have shown that the mitochondrial orf224/ atp6 gene region is correlated with the Polima (pol) cytoplasmic male sterility (CMS) of Brassica napus, and that the effects of nuclear fertility restoration on orf224/ atp6 transcripts co-segregate with the pol restorer gene Rfp in genetic crosses. Results presented in this thesis indicate that the pol CMS restorer gene Rfp acts in an organ-specific manner to promote the processing of primary, dicistronic orf224/atp6 transcripts into new restorer-specific, monocistronic transcripts. The single 1.1 kb atp6 transcript of nap cytoplasm and some orfB transcripts of nap and pol cytoplasm B. napus mitochondria are shown to arise by removal of sequences from the 5' end of a longer precursor. Specific endonucleolytic cleavage of a precursor RNA, followed by non-specific 3' to 5' exonuclease action, may thus represent a common mechanism for tailoring transcripts in plant mitochondria. Northern analysis of a segregating F2 population indicates that the recessive rfp allele at the restorer gene locus, or a very tightly linked gene, acts as a dominant gene designated Mmt (modifier of mitochondrial transcripts). Mmt controls the presence of additional, smaller transcripts of the nad4 and ccl1-like (ccl1-l) genes. These results suggest that Rfp/Mmt is a novel nuclear genetic locus that affects the expression of multiple mitochondrial gene regions, with different alleles or haplotypes exerting specific effects on different mitochondrial genes. One of these genes, ccl1-l, is split in the B. napus mitochondrial genome into two widely separated and independently transcribed parts, contrasting with the situation in other plants where this gene is present as an uninterrupted ORF. Although transcripts of both parts are edited, no "trans-spliced" transcripts spanning both parts of the split ORF, that could be translated into a full sized protein product, were detected. Moreover, an antiserum directed against the product of t</description><creator>Menassa, Rima.</creator><contributor>Brown, Gregory G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Cytoplasmic male sterility.</subject><subject>Rape (Plant) -- Cytogenetics.</subject><subject>Plant mitochondria.</subject><subject>Plant gene expression.</subject><title>Nuclear-mitochondrial gene interactions and mitochondrial gene expression in Brassica napus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s6521.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429b99k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278v96m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Almost seventy-five percent of India's one billion people live in villages. Until recently, most of the villages were fairly isolated from external media influence. As these villages continued to modernize and gain access to services once thought to be limited to an urban environment, basic human needs began to change. Television, which used to be thought of as a luxury, has in the past 10--15 years become perceived as a necessity. Rural Maharashtrian villages have suddenly been propelled into the electronic information age. These societies that used to be defined by their own oral traditions and stories are now more than ever being structured and reorganized through television. The research question centers on the role of television in rural life, and the influence it has had on the social, economic and political landscape of the village. Through in-depth interviews and participant observation a picture emerged of television's role in the process of social change at the village level. The physical presence of television and the content of the medium both contribute to the restructuring of human relationships within village life. The data suggest that television influences certain processes of social change, some of which include: consumerism, democratization, changing gender and age relations, linguistic hegemony, access to information and the entrepreneurial base. In addition, television has restructured the concept of time within the village community. The data also illustrate that village children are unaware of what life was like before the arrival of television. Villagers have become accustomed to their daily dosage of soap operas, movies, game shows and music programs. Rural Maharashtrians are increasingly becoming active participants in the "global village."</description><creator>Johnson, Kirk.</creator><contributor>Von Eschen, Donald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Television -- India -- Maharashtra -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Social change -- India -- Maharashtra.</subject><title>Television and social change in rural India : a study of two mountain villages in Western Maharashtra</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t882.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v96m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032474g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis contributes to knowledge in the field of medical anthropology, particularly in Egypt and the Middle East, in two specific ways. First, the thesis demonstrates how a limited focus on kinship and micro social relations precludes a full understanding of the life experiences of people, especially at times of illness. The thesis shows that these conceptual limitations stem from a romanticized view of Egyptian culture---a view that poorly corresponds to the contemporary Egyptian situation. The thesis proposes that social networks And the ground between micro and macro social associations need to be incorporated into future studies of medical anthropology in general, and in Egypt and the Middle East in particular. Second, the thesis demonstrates how cultural values linked to the diversity of social classes and unequal access to social and financial capital shape illness experience. It is argued that access to biomedical services is a social manifestation of culturally constructed subcultures where kinship, social networks, and social hierarchy produce the current inequalities in well-being among inhabitants of modern Egypt. A cultural and social analysis grounded in the history of Egyptian modernity is pursued here to better understand current inequality in social and physical well-being. Space, aesthetics, religion, network affiliation, and other factors constitute essential elements of this analysis. The thesis proposes integrating a study of the cultural manifestations of the production of social inequality into all future studies of illness in Egypt and the Middle East. It is concluded that a culture of social distinctions and discrimination prevails, and that such a culture shapes social relations and illness experience. Unless this culture is understood and addressed, there is little hope for an equal distribution of resources for well-being among Egyptians.</description><creator>Kamal, Montasser.</creator><contributor>Lolk, Margaret (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Social networks -- Egypt</subject><subject>Medical anthropology -- Egypt.</subject><subject>Egypt -- Social conditions -- 1952-</subject><subject>Social classes -- Egypt</subject><title>Affiliation, discrimination, and well-being in modern Egypt : cultural and social dimensions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9675375.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032474g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544br182</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chiral auxiliary 1,2-O-cyclopentylidene-5-deoxy-5-isopropylamino-alpha- D-xylofuranose 51 and its enantiomer 52 were synthesized from D-xylose and L-xylose respectively and treated with PC13 to form cyclic phosphochloridites 58 and 67, and then reacted with 5'-O- t-butyldimethylsilylthymidine to give diastereornerically pure cyclic phosphoramidites 60 and 68. They were coupled with 3'-O-t-butyldimethylsilylthymidine in the presence of 2-bromo-4,5-dicyanoimidazole 46 as catalyst, and then sulfurized with Beaucage's reagent to form protected dithymidine phosphorothioates 62 and 72 stereoselectively. After deprotection, Sp and Rp dithymidine phosphorothioates 65 and 66 were obtained respectively in 98% diastereomeric excess. The mechanism of the coupling reaction which involves only one inversion in the transformation of the phosphoramidites (60, 68) to the dithymidine phosphorothioates (65, 66) is discussed. The effect of the acidity of the catalyst on the stereoselectivity and the rate of the coupling reaction was studied. The synthesis and separation of diastereomers of protected dithymidine boranophosphates Sp-107 and Rp-108 gave the dimers Sp-109 and Rp-110 in a stereospecific manner. These dimers will be incorporated into oligonucleotides to synthesize mixed backbone oligonucleotides. To confirm the stereochemistry of the dimers Sp-109 and Rp-110, the free dithymidine boranophosphates Sp- 115 and Rp-116 were synthesized, the configurations at the phosphorus atom of which were assigned by comparison with spectral data from the literature. A stereoselective synthesis of a dinucleotide boranophosphate Sp- 115 with a de of &gt;98%, using (S)-3-hydroxyl-4-(2-indolyl)butyronitrile 28-(S) as chiral auxiliary, is described. The conversion of phosphite triester to boranophosphate by BH3-Me2S-proceeds with retention of configuration at the phosphorus atom. The procedure may be adaptable to the solid phase synthesis.</description><creator>Jin, Yi, 1963-</creator><contributor>Just, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>The stereoselective synthesis of antisense phosphorothioates and boranophosphates /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc850.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br182</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c226n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using interviewers' ratings of respondents' physical appearance this study examined the relationship between physical attractiveness and wages treating the former as marginal to a baseline, human-capital derived equation. To test the hypotheses about the consequences of physical attractiveness alone or conditioned by other factors on earnings and wage growth we estimated wage and wage growth equations using 3 cross-sectional and 3 panel data sets derived from the Canadian Quality of Life survey. The cross-sectional estimates indicated that the effect of physical attractiveness on earnings was a plausible one and likely to be conditioned by other characteristics such as firm size, occupation, union membership, frequency of on-the-job supervision, and level of formal schooling. The 'above average' rated workers received pay premia ranging from +2.2% to 6.1% while those 'below average' received pay penalties ranging from-2.7% to -13.0% relative to the grand mean. The 'average' rated workers received pay penalties ranging from -0.7% to -3.4%. The main source of these wage differentials appears to be discrimination based on looks. The results of panel specifications also provided some support for the notion that physical attractiveness ratings were associated with differential wage growth and that the relationship between physical attractiveness and wage growth might be moderated by other individual or institutional characteristics of the workers, especially before adjustments for the lagged effects of wages were made. Overall, these results provide a moderate level of support for the thesis that physical attractiveness plays a role in the wage determination process in modern labour markets.</description><creator>Kaczorowski, Janusz.</creator><contributor>Rytina, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>van den Berg, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Discrimination in employment.</subject><subject>Wage differentials.</subject><subject>Beauty, Personal -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Physical attractiveness and economic success</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn39v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c226n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xb294</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is an examination of the position of Catharina Regina von Greiffenberg (1633--1694) with regard to contemporary societal gender-paradigms, which were the conditions under which she produced her literary work; these same conditions are also reflected in her texts. The first chapter includes a methodological discussion and establishes the importance of applying a socio-historical approach in order to better understand the situation of women in the Baroque period, and of Greiffenberg in particular, in order to answer the question, how it was possible for the author to write and publish at a time that generally excluded women from such activities. The second chapter provides a brief biography of Greiffenberg and a review of secondary literature, with the main focus on the positioning of the poet within patriarchal society. The socio-historical framework includes the religious, social, and legal position of women. These include: the hierarchy of power based on gender-roles, definitions of women in marriage, educational paradigms, as well as characteristics typically attributed to women. An analysis of the moral and theological view of women, as outlined by Martin Luther and presented in sermons by Johann Michael Dilherr, evaluates the general conditions for women during the Baroque period and the specific position of Greiffenberg (chapter three). With a similar aim in mind, chapter four examines the genre of "Hatisvaterliteratur" through the example by Wolfgang Helmhard von Hohberg. This provides a framework for the investigation of Greiffenberg's expressions of her views regarding gender politics. She made the restrictions placed on women a topic in both her published and unpublished texts. She also developed strategies to overcome these restrictions. She found the courage to act against the proscribed role for women by defining her writing as God's will and thus based her profession on a higher authority. She also affirmed the gender-paradigms, while at the same time transgressing their boundaries, whereby she was able to negotiate the roles of both a woman and a publishing writer at a time when one identity conflicted with the other (chapters five and six).</description><creator>Falkner, Silke R.</creator><contributor>Daly, Peter M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Greiffenberg, Catharina Regina von, 1633-1694.</subject><subject>Women -- Social conditions -- History.</subject><title>Zur schreibenden Frau im Barock : Catharina Regina von Greiffenberg : sozialhistorische Produktionsbedingungen und ihre literarische Bewältigung</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c927v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb294</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs14q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rigid spargers are enjoying renewed interest in some flotation column applications such as de-inking of recycled paper and de-oiling of water. Sparger selection depends on the physical characteristics of the porous material, the liquid/slurry properties, and the dimensions of the column. There is no generally accepted method to select spargers for a given flotation column duty. A methodology for selecting stainless steel rigid spargers is proposed. The methodology is based on a target bubble size (db), gas holdup (epsilong), or bubble surface flux ( Sb). It combines two models: one for bubble formation at the sparger proposed by Kumar and Kuloor which relates bubble size to sparger characteristics, and drift flux analysis which relates mean bubble size, gas holdup, and gas rate. Prediction of bubble size by the Kumar and Kuloor model requires a knowledge of an equivalent pore diameter (De) of the sparger. A procedure to estimate De by fitting the predicted and measured epsilong - Jg relationships is developed. Comparison of bubble size measured photographically with that estimated from drift flux analysis, and predicted by the Kumar and Kuloor model shows acceptable agreement between the measured, estimated and predicted values. By combining db predicted with drift flux analysis, and allowing for column dimensions, both the gas holdup and the bubble surface flux were predicted. A maximum in sparger surface area was found above which the gas holdup and the bubble surface flux do not increase. Spargers were characterized according to their permeability (k ), by applying the Darcy law. Sparger homogeneity was established from this permeability measurement. A relationship between De and k was derived. For spargers with permeability up to 0.75 darcy (0.75 x 10-5 m2), the equivalent pore diameter was constant (De = 2 mum). For larger permeabilities De increased with permeability. Application of the sparger selection criteria in a pilot unit (0.5 m diameter column) showed epsilong and Sb can be predicted with acceptable accuracy.</description><creator>Escudero Garcia, Ramiro.</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Characterization of rigid spargers and their selection for flotation columns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j061s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs14q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s418w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Questions about the role of the "informal sector" color much of the discussion of urban economic development in poor countries. Why is there an informal sector (and how to define it)? Are informal businesses stagnant or dynamic, and can they contribute to development? In the small Bolivian city of Sucre, site of this study, there is no "informal sector"; rather, the entire economy demonstrates informal characteristics. With a handful of exceptions, businesses are all very small and household centered. Most manufacturing is done by hand or with simple machines, and informal labor and trade relationships predominate. This thesis describes Sucre's producers, especially chocolate-makers and carpenters, and the local organizations which work with them to promote business growth. Despite attempts by local NGOs, grassroots organizations, and business people, Sucre' businesses stay, small and informal. The reasons for this include: (A) the size and composition of the local market; (B) the problems of trust and contract enforcement which raise transaction costs (for hiring workers, contracting distributors and forming partnerships); (C) the inability to "catch up" with more efficient, mechanized competitors in neighboring countries; and (D) a tendency for households to diversify their investments as a response to risk and uncertain markets. The main problem impeding business growth in Sucre is not the businesses' informality (which is principally a result of their smallness), but the local social, economic and institutional environment in which they must work. This is an environment in which business owners have learned to survive and even, occasionally, prosper, but one which they have thus far been unable to change.</description><creator>Eversole, Robyn.</creator><contributor>Attwood, Donald W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Family-owned business enterprises -- Bolivia -- Sucre</subject><subject>Sucre (Bolivia) -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Informal sector (Economics) -- Bolivia -- Sucre</subject><title>Little business, big dreams : households, production and growth in a small Bolivian city</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064754h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s418w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d169v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An integrated experimental and theoretical study of the residual thermal stresses has been carried out. The final stress profiles along the thickness were measured in an amorphous and a semi-crystalline injection molded polymer using the layer removal technique. The two materials exhibited drastically distinct residual profiles. Furthermore, processing parameters such as melt and coolant temperatures, pressure history, and mold thickness were found to modify the profiles. In order to elucidate the findings, two models were derived. The two-dimensional free mold shrinkage model was developed to provide a rapid estimation of thermal stresses and the main features of their profile. A more complex model was developed by integrating the stress analysis with the simulation of the complete injection molding cycle by McKam. This model accounts for the fountain flow effect, the crystallization, and the PVT behavior of the material. With the help of the model predictions, explanations were provided for the occurrence of various regions in the residual stress profiles. Transitions or reversal of the regions under variable conditions or material properties were observed to be mainly determined by the ratio of the thermal to the pressure effects. Using these concepts, practical conclusions were drawn for controlling the residual stresses. As an alternative for optimization of injection molding with respect to residual stresses, inverse methods were developed to calculate the pressure history or the initial temperature distribution required to produce a prescribed residual stress distribution. These methods were tested using direct solutions with added errors and experimental stress data.</description><creator>Farhoudi, Yalda.</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><title>Measurement and computation of thermal stresses in injection molding of amorphous and crystalline polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc40h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d169v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z016p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of organometallic complexes involving manganese, bonded to silicon, tin, lead and phosphorus ligands, and nickel, bonded to various trialkylphosphine ligands, has been synthesized and their crystal structures, vibrational, and multinuclear magnetic resonance spectra have been obtained. The FT-IR and FT-Raman spectra of the manganese carbonyl compounds in the carbonyl region (2200--1850 cm--1) have been assigned. Solid-state, CP-MAS, 13C, 29Si, 31P, 117Sn, 119Sn and 207Pb NMR spectra of substituted pentacarbonylmanganese(I) and tetracarbonylmanganese(I) complexes feature asymmetric sextets, whereas those containing a group 14 (IVA) element bridging two pentacarbonylmanganese(I) moieties show asymmetric sextets. The uneven splitting arises from spin-spin coupling and second-order quadrupole-dipole effects, which are not eliminated by magic angle spinning. The solid-state NMR spectra of the manganese complexes have been analyzed to give the isotropic chemical shifts, the chemical shift tensors, one-bond spin-spin coupling constants, 55Mn nuclear quadrupole coupling constants, effective dipolar coupling constants and the anisotropies; in the spin-spin coupling for each complex. The results provide new insights into the relationship between spin-spin coupling and quadrupolar coupling in bimetallic complexes involving a quadrupole transition-metal and a spin-1/2 nucleus. For the para-substituted triaryltin complexes, the 13C, 55Mn and 119Sn chemical shifts and one-bond spin-spin constants in solution show excellent correlations with pairs of substituent constants (sigmaI, sigmaR). However, there is no correlation of the chemical shifts or spin-spin coupling with either Hammett (sigmaP) or Taft (sigmaP o) constants or the Mn-Sn bond lengths, rMn-Sn. The results obtained from dual substituent parameter (DSP) analysis indicate that both resonance effects (sigmaR) and inductive effects (sigma I) are important in determining the NMR parameters. Crystal structures and high-resolution solution and solid-state 31P NMR spectra were obtained for several dihalobis(trialkylphosphine)nickel(II) complexes. The crystal structures and NMR results indicate that these complexes are trans square-planar in the solid-state. The chemical shifts and shift tensors were obtained and found to vary with the electronic properties of the halogens. The 31P isotropic chemical shifts in the solution spectra of dibromo- and diiodiobis(tribenzylphosphine)nickel(II) are very different from those found for the solid-state, and chemical exchange effects were observed in all spectra. The mechanism of exchange appears to involve the formation of dimers with bridging halides.</description><creator>Christendat, Dharamdat.</creator><contributor>Gilson, Denis F. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Butler, Ian S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><title>Synthesis, structural and solid-state, multinuclear magnetic resonance studies of some manganese and nickel complexes containing silicon, tin, lead and phosphorus ligands</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft128.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z016p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v475n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chronic heart failure is an increasingly prevalent condition associated with high mortality and a heavy burden on patients, families, and society. Despite evidence that psychosocial variables are associated with the clinical evolution of other forms of cardiac disease, little is known about the prognostic impact of these factors for patients with asymptomatic left ventricular dysfunction (LVD) or overt heart failure. The purpose of this study was to evaluate social isolation, mood (anxiety, depression, and vigor), low socioeconomic status, non-White ethnicity (in U.S. patients), life stress, and poor self-rated health as possible correlates of health outcomes for patients with systolic LVD. A secondary analysis was performed on clinical and psychosocial data for 4991 (of 6797) American, Canadian and Belgian patients aged 21 to 80 with left ventricular ejection fractions ≤35% enrolled in the Studies of Left Ventricular Dysfunction (SOLVD) clinical trials. Psychosocial correlates of mortality, clinical deterioration, arrhythmias, hospitalizations, and quality of life (functional status, life satisfaction, and symptom levels) were examined using logistic and Cox proportional hazards model regressions, before and after adjustment for patient clinical characteristics. Results showed that some measures of social isolation (being unmarried, making visits to and receiving visits from others infrequently) were associated with the majority of the negative health outcomes studied. Contrary to expectations, neither high depression, nor high anxiety predicted risk of either cardiac-related mortality or ventricular arrhythmias. However, both depression and anxiety were linked with measures of clinical deterioration, hospitalizations for any cardiac cause, as well as poor quality of life at 1 year. Low vigor, low socioeconomic status, non-White ethnicity, and low self-rated health were all consistently associated with poor quality of life and heightened risk of all of the adverse events studied except arrhythmias. Psychosocial factors appear to be independent predictors of mortality and morbidity in advanced cardiac disease characterized by moderate to severe LVD. This suggests that it is worth evaluating these parameters in patients with, or at risk for, heart failure and tailoring clinical interventions to address the impacts these factors may have on different health outcomes.</description><creator>Clarke, Sean Patrick.</creator><contributor>Frasure-Smith, Nancy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Psychosocial correlates of mortality, cardiac events, health care utilization, and quality of life in patients with left ventricular dysfunction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv74b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v475n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng401</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this dissertation is to demonstrate the existence of a prophetic discourse in the work of the French writer J. M. G. (Jean-Marie-Gustave) Le Clezio. Within the period of his first books (1963--1973), from Le proces-verbal (The interrogation) to Les Geants (The Giants), Le Clezio systematically adopts a prophetic discourse conveying his personal view of the world. We intend to show that these works form a complete cycle within the broader scope of Le Clezio's writings. At the forefront of these earlier works we find a questioning on the nature of language and the process of writing, the latter being at times disputed and scorned, at others celebrated and inflated. We shall see the profound ambivalence that Le Clezio has towards language, the language being perceived both as a degradation of man's being as well as the sole mean to express the "adventure of being alive". The first chapter recaps succinctly the evolution of the prophetic terminology up to the modern times, in which it is no longer the pure domain of godly matters. In the following chapters, each of which pertains to a specific work according to their sequence, we aim to show that (1) the prophetic discourse in Le Clezio's earlier works operate as a set of literary devices---narrative strategies, addresses, invocations, sacred themes---and that (2) this discourse takes the shape of a trajectory. As for content, we win demonstrate that (3) Le Clezio's prophetic discourse is the expression of a phenomenological approach positing the individual's consciousness in face of the absolute. It is this threefold dynamic that we will analyze in the first works of Le Clezio and that we have gathered under the notion of prophetic discourse.</description><creator>Chung, Ook, 1963-</creator><contributor>Rivard, Yvon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Le Clézio, J.-M. G. (Jean-Marie Gustave), 1940- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Le discours prophétique dans l'oeuvre de J.M.G. Le Clézio /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n5033.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng401</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096885m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis has focused on the measurement of gas holdup in flotation systems, a variable not measured reliably to date. A sensor was designed using so-called flow conductivity cells. Their properties were studied and modelled, and their application in the design, construction, and operation of a gas holdup probe for use in flotation systems described. A flow cell is defined as one that allows a fluid or dispersion to flow through freely while the electrical conductivity is measured. One of the most important features of a flow cell is the so-called cell constant. Once the cell constant is determined, the cell can be used to measure liquid and dispersion conductivity. The cell constant depends mainly on cell dimensions, and is largely independent of the characteristics of the fluid. The addition of non conductive bodies to the fluid was studied. It was concluded that the cell constant is not affected by the presence of such bodies. These systems are described by Maxwell's model, which relates the fraction of non conductive phase (holdup) in the system to the conductivity of the continuous phase and the conductivity of the dispersion. It was demonstrated that the electromagnetic field associated with the flow cells can be solved using the MagNet 5.1 software. Predicted results for cell constant were in good agreement with the experimental. The model holds the potential for design of flow cells for particular applications in mineral processing. The gas holdup probe developed in this work applies the principle of separation of phases to fulfill the requirements of Maxwell's model. The probe consists of two flow cells. One, the open flow cell, measures the conductivity of the dispersion while the other, the syphon cell, measures the continuum conductivity. The test work, in both laboratory and industrial flotation columns, demonstrated that the probe gave accurate estimates of gas holdup. The probe satisfied the requirements of an industrial sensor, as it performs in-situ, on-line, in real-time, with no external measurements and no assumptions regarding properties of any phase. The gas holdup probe was used to explore operating flotation columns. It appears to hold great promise for diagnosis, readily detecting, for example, differences in gas holdup between sections of baffled columns. This success may make the probe a candidate sensor for process control, although this will require a significant in-plant effort to realize. As a first step, the probe offers an opportunity to study the relationship between gas holdup and metallurgy, at least in flotation columns.</description><creator>Tavera-Miranda, Francisco Javier.</creator><contributor>Finch, James A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Flow cells to measure electrical conductivity : use in estimating gas holdup in flotation systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g676x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096885m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj913</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ors8 is a mammalian autonomously replicating DNA sequence, previously isolated by extrusion of nascent CV-1 (monkey kidney cells) DNA from replication bubbles active at the onset of S phase. A panel of deletion mutants of ors8 have identified a fragment of 186 bp that is essential for the in vitro and in vivo replication of ors8 containing plasmid. This fragment, when subcloned into pBR322 and similarly tested, was capable of autonomous replication in vivo and in vitro (Todd et al., 1995). The objective of the research in this thesis is the purification and characterization of a mammalian factor(s) that specifically interact(s) with the 186 bp fragment of ors8, and is involved in DNA replication. Fractionation of HeLa cell extracts by chromatographic techniques have identified such a protein fraction. The OBA (Ors Binding Activity) enriched fraction is able to support the in vitro replication of ors8, and is also enriched for polymerases alpha and delta, replication protein A (RP-A) and topoisomerase II (Ruiz et al., 1995). OBA sediments at approximately 150 kDa in a glycerol gradient. Band-shift competition experiments demonstrate that a subfragment of 59 bp, from the 186 bp fragment of ors8, competes for OBA binding as efficiently as the 186 bp fragment itself. The 59 bp subfragment shares 85% homology with a 36 bp sequence (A3/4) generated by comparison of several mammalian replication origins, including the ors (origin rich sequences). The A3/4 sequence is able to compete efficiently for OBA binding. Furthermore, the addition of increasing amounts of the A3/4 oligonucleotide to the in vitro reaction inhibits the replication of 186 bp-containing plasmid. Band-shift elution of the A3/4-OBA complex, followed by Southwestern analysis showed that a band of approximately 92 kDa is involved in the interaction of OBA with the A3/4 sequence. Microsequencing analysis of this band revealed that it is identical to the 86 subunit of Ku antigen. Affinity purification of OBA by DNA sequence-specific chromatography demonstrated that both subunits of Ku antigen (p70 and p86) are present in this fraction. In addition, the affinity purified OBA (apOBA) fraction is also enriched in the DNA-dependent protein kinase catalytic subunit (DNA-PKcs). In vitro replication experiments using anti-Ku70, anti-Ku86, and anti-DNA-PKcs antibodies, resulted in the inhibition of p186 replication in vitro, suggesting the involvement of Ku in mammalian DNA replication.</description><creator>Ruiz Guerra, Marcia Teresa.</creator><contributor>Zannis-Hadjopoulos, Maria (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Purification and characterization of a mammalian Origin Binding Activity (OBA)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c229g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj913</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gj090</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This historical and conceptual thesis examines the cultural and socio-economic situatedness of education and development in the different epochs of South African history from the arrival of the first European settlers in 1652 up to the present post-apartheid era. The project assumes that cultural domination is utilized for the creation and long-term maintenance of systems of learning that are embedded in colonial and exploitative relationships. These relationships are generally defined by the socio-economic development of the dominant group at the expense of subordinated populations. Moreover, the thesis argues that colonial, and specifically apartheid education in the South African situation were deliberately designed and implemented for the purpose of assuring and perpetuating divergent and at times "opposing" schemes of development for the colonizing Europeans vis-a-vis the colonized populations. As evident from the examination of policy objectives and the resulting economic and social situations, therefore, the development of one group, i.e., the Europeans, was achieved at the relative underdevelopment of the indigenous population and other oppressed groups. With the establishment of these observations, the body of the thesis moves to critically examine the current educational and cultural situations of what is "romantically" being called the new South Africa. The still depressing educational and development character of the post-apartheid situation confirms the immensity of the current and potential social "problematic" that may be capable of derailing the present agreed-upon political enterprise. In conclusion, the thesis critically examines the case for a genuine multicultural development education that assures or, at least demonstrably promises a more just and equitable education for all South Africans. Hence, the project's main assertion that the formulation and implementation of this type of education is essential for the development of the hitherto dis</description><creator>Abdi, Ali A., 1955-</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Blacks -- Education -- South Africa -- History.</subject><subject>Segregation in education -- South Africa -- History.</subject><title>Culture, education and development in South Africa : a general theoretical analysis with emphasis on black education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268688g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj090</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544br19b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a monograph on the facade of the church of Santa Maria Novella in Florence, Italy. The present appearance of the facade is the result of three building campaigns effected over the period of two centuries (c1300--c1500), and two restorative campaigns conducted in the twentieth century. Each of the three major campaigns is considered in isolation, with attention to reconstructions, formal and comparative analyses, and extensive contextualization and discussion of patronage networks. The twentieth-century interventions are cursorily presented in an epilogue. Major themes developed and continued through the five chapters of the dissertation are: architecture and its projected meanings in late medieval and Renaissance Florence, urban organization, political structures, the Dominican order and the position of the Florentine chapter within local and international ecclesiastical, social and political structures.</description><creator>Roy, Brian E.</creator><contributor>Boker, Hans Josef (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Santa Maria Novella (Church : Florence, Italy)</subject><title>The façade of Santa Maria Novella : architecture, context, patronage and meaning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t375v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br19b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq504</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Wireless telephone service providers must deploy their cellular networks with two main criteria in mind: radio coverage and traffic density. All areas where users expect a service must be covered and enough channels must be provided to accommodate the users. This thesis explores the problem of radio coverage prediction for indoor systems. The indoor radio channel contains a large number and variety of obstacles which scatter and attenuate electromagnetic waves. A transmitted signal reaches a receiver via multiple propagation paths after undergoing a series of reflection, transmission and possibly diffraction effects along each path. The sum of all path contributions, each characterized by an [attenuation, delay, carrier phase shift] vector, is called the impulse response, from which various channel quality measures can be derived. Given an environment over which an indoor wireless cellular network has to operate and the location of a base station, one must evaluate, for every point in that environment, the channel quality and hence compute the impulse response. Since measurements are too slow, there is a need for a computer tool that could evaluate the coverage of a base station from a representation of the environment. Using a high frequency ray approximation of electromagnetic waves, the thesis first presents the two main ray tracing algorithms: ray shooting and the method of images. In both cases, the scene is represented as a series of panels with associated electromagnetic characteristics. Ray shooting consists of shooting rays in all directions from a transmitter location, tracking their interactions with obstacles until one or many reach a receiver location. The method of images reflects the transmitter about permutations of panels and checks which combinations lead to physically realizable reflection paths. Comparison with measurement results show good agreement in both cases although running times are high. Better running times are obtained by considering two alternatives. A software alternative in the form of a faster algorithm called the method of regions is described. Spatial coherence is used to discard a priori image combinations which are not feasible and finding grid locations which belong together. The environment is divided into reflection, transmission and optionally diffraction regions and it is checked in which regions the various grid points belong. A hardware alternative in the form of a parallel machine is also demonstrated. A Multiple Instructions Multiple Data stream machine can provide linear speed-ups over a large range of processor numbers. The concept of a low level massively parallel machine in the form of a threshold logic network is also described.</description><creator>Kimpe, Marc.</creator><contributor>Leib, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Computerized estimation of the indoor wideband radio channel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Marc Kimpe, 1998</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935471c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq504</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj032</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE) is a central nervous system (CNS) disease, with symptoms reminiscent of Multiple Sclerosis. During disease, the CNS is infiltrated by immune cells, with increased expression of MHC antigens and Th1 cytokines. We asked whether antigen presentation in the CNS controls the bias towards Th1 cytokine in mice. We examined the capability of microglia to act as antigen presenting cells. We found that they stimulated T cell responses in vitro, but supported increased production of Th1 cytokines only. We also found that IL-12 mRNA was upregulated during peak disease, produced by resident microglia. We therefore propose that microglia, through their production of IL-12, influence the cytokine response in the CNS to produce the observed Th1 bias. We investigated the effect of deletion of IFN-gamma on the ability to induce EAE in genetically-resistant (BALB/c) mice. IFN-gamma-/- mice were susceptible to induction of EAE, and cellular infiltrates in the CNS showed increases in message for CD3 and TNF-alpha. Therefore, IFN-gamma converts an otherwise EAE-susceptible mouse strain to become EAE-resistant. We examined whether the negative effect of IFN-gamma on generation of encephalitogenic T cells in the periphery might differ from its role in the CNS. We interbred IFN-gamma -/- mice to mice transgenically overexpressing IFN-gamma in the CNS. Levels of IFN-gamma in CNS of the resulting mice were insufficient to induce spontaneous disease. These mice will be useful tools for studying the role of IFN-gamma in CNS disease. During EAE, T cells of many specificities infiltrate the CNS. The function of those that do not recognize CNS antigens ("bystanders") is unclear. We transferred Ovalbumin-reactive (bystander) T cells to mice prior to EAE onset. Flow cytometry analysis showed that the vast majority of myelin basic protein-reactive T cells in the CNS were memory/effector cells, but only very few bystander T cells showed an activated/memory/effector phenotype. As a whole population, the bystander cells did not upregulate their expression of CD44 or IL-2Ralpha, or production of IFN-gamma, thus are probably not contributing to the ongoing immune response during disease.</description><creator>Krakowski, Michelle L.</creator><contributor>Owens, Trevor (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>T cell activation and cytokine production in experimental allergic encephalomyelitis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng42k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj032</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q326g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurotrophins are dimeric polypeptides responsible for the survival, differentiation and maintenance of specific neuronal populations that express cell surface receptors termed tropomyosin receptor kinases (Trks). Trks possess intrinsic tyrosine kinase activity and are thought to mediate most neurotrophic effects. Recently, non-neuronal cells as well as certain human neoplasias, such as neuroblastoma have also been shown to express Trks. The prototype neurotrophin, Nerve Growth Factor (NGF) binds to the first identified Trk, TrkA causing its dimerization, auto- and trans-phosphorylation and subsequent cascade of signaling events. NGF also binds to a receptor with less well characterized biological activity termed p75. The production of novel ligands which can either mimic or inhibit the signaling of the NGF-TrkA ligand-receptor system holds much promise for the development of therapeutics and diagnostics in pathologies ranging from neurodegenerative disease to cancer. Prior to this work no "artificial" ligands had been reported to bind the extracellular domain of TrkA and to sufficiently affect TrkA-mediated signaling. In my work, I designed and synthesized small peptidic cyclic analogs of NGF beta-turn regions. A competitive antagonist termed C(92-96) which structurally mimics NGF beta-turn C-D was obtained (LeSauteur et al., 1995). In addition, the monoclonal antibody (mAb) 5C3, a naturally dimeric molecule which is specific for human TrkA, was produced and characterized. MAb 5C3 is a structural and functional mimic of NGF and an artificial receptor agonist (LeSauteur et al., 1996a). The in vivo targeting efficacy of two novel ligands; the NGF analog C(92-96) and mAb 5C3, was evaluated and compared (LeSauteur et al. 1996b). Both TrkA ligands were radiolabelled with technicium and used to specifically image TrkA-expressing tumors. The pharmacokinetics of targeting was better for the NGF analog C(92-96) than for mAb 5C3. MAb 5C3 has been shown to be a useful diagnostic and prognostic factor for neuroblastoma (Kramer et al., 1996).</description><creator>LeSauteur, Lynne.</creator><contributor>Saragovi, H. U. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>TrkA ligands : development and uses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q36c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q326g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r7325</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to develop a new barotropic ocean model to study ocean dynamics. The model combines for the first time the flexible finite-element method and an accurate semi-Lagrangian advection scheme on unstructured triangular meshes. In the first part of the work, the semi-Lagrangian method is used for advection experiments on an irregular grid. A cosine hill is advected using a specified flow field corresponding to solid body rotation. A major difficulty is to find an interpolator which is at least fourth order accurate on an unstructured mesh. Such accuracy is needed for the treatment of slow Rossby waves in ocean models. We develop such a method using a kriging interpolating scheme. The results are better than fourth order accurate on an unstructured grid. Such accuracy is achieved at a reasonable computational cost due to the increased flexibility of unstructured meshes and accuracy of the kriging approach. The second part of the thesis examines the finite-element spatial discretization of the linear inviscid shallow-water equations with a semi-implicit temporal discretization on unstructured meshes. The finite-element velocity-pressure pair should ideally give noise-free results when solving geostrophic balance, and fulfill at the same time certain consistency conditions. We show most of the known finite-element pairs do not satisfy these two requirements simultaneously, except for an unconventional and unnamed low-order element pair. The latter gives good results for experiments on the propagation of gravity waves using the linear inviscid shallow-water equations. The last part of the thesis examines the coupling between semi-Lagrangian advection and semi-implicit treatment of the linear gravity wave terms on unstructured meshes. We use kriging as interpolator for semi-Lagrangian advection and the unconventional finite-element pair previously examined for the nonlinear shallow-water equations. The propagation of a typical oceanic eddy is simulated without forcing.</description><creator>Le Roux, Daniel Y.</creator><contributor>Lin, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>A semi-Lagrangian finite element barotropic ocean model /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw368.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r7325</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft153</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sulfur containing polymers are very important as rubbers, conducting materials, and high performance polymers. Examples are poly(aliphatic disulfide)s, poly(phenylene sulfide) (PPS), poly(sulfone), and polybenzothiazole. Several new polymerization reactions have been described in this thesis for the preparation of sulfur containing materials. The synthesis of a series of cyclic(arylene disulfide) oligomers was accomplished by catalytic oxidation of arylenedithiols with oxygen in the presence of a copper-amine catalyst. The cyclic(arylene disulfide) oligomers underwent a novel free radical ring-opening polymerization at elevated temperatures in the melt to form high molecular weight poly(arylene disulfide)s. Cyclic(arylene disulfide) oligomers were copolymerized with elemental sulfur at 250°C to form stable poly(arylene sulfane)s containing 3--7 sulfur linkages. They also copolymerized with diiodoaromatic compounds, or dibromoaromatic compounds, in the presence of potassium iodide at 270°C to give poly(thioaryiene)s with the formation of iodine as the coproduct in both cases. The novel self-polymerization of 4-bromobenzenethiol was realized at 270°C in m-terphenyl solution in the presence of a catalytic amount of free radical initiator. Hydrogen bromide is the sole side product. This novel reaction has also been extended to the synthesis of poly(thioarylene)s from arylenedithiols and dibromoaromatic compounds. Another novel polymerization reaction to prepare poly(arylene thioether)s has been realized by a one-pot reaction of bis(N,N'-dimethyl-S-carbamate)s with activated dihalocompounds in diphenylsulfone in the presence of a mixture of Cs2CO3/CaCO3. Bis(N,N'-dimethyl-S-carbamate)s can be conveniently prepared from dihydroxy compounds via the Newman-Kwart rearrangement reaction. This polymerization reaction opens a new route for the synthesis of new poly(arylene thioether)s and poly(arylene sulfone)s. A series of novel cyclic(arylene ether)s has also been synthesized and characterized. The ring-opening polymerization of these cyclic oligomers in the melt represents a new way to prepare high performance polymers.</description><creator>Ding, Yong.</creator><contributor>Hay, Allan S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>New polymerization reactions : sulfur containing cyclic oligomers and high performance polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h355d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft153</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx20z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Housekeeping is an important aspect of safety in the workplace. There have been only a limited number of studies assessing the impact on injury of housekeeping. In addition, measuring the state of housekeeping has posed continuous problems in these studies due to the lack of standardized and objective instrumentation. Objectives. The objectives of the first part of this thesis involved the development and evaluation of an instrument for measuring the state of housekeeping in industry. The second part examined the association between housekeeping and safety. Methods. This study began with the development of a checklist for evaluating housekeeping and proceeded to a fifteen-month prospective cohort study of fifty-seven companies in the transportation equipment and machinery manufacturing sector in Quebec, Canada, each employing between twenty and sixty workers. Companies were followed over 16 months to evaluate housekeeping levels. At the end of the study, information on compensable injuries that occurred during the study period was obtained. Results. Inter-observer reliability of the instrument was reasonably high (ICC 0.88, 95% CI 0.81--0.94) though test-retest reliability was less stable (ICC 0.73, 95% CI 0.68--0.78). In the second part of this study, housekeeping was found to be significantly associated with both injury rates (IRR 1.35, 95% CI 1.08--1.70) and rate of days lost (IRR 1.48, 95% CI 1.39--1.57), and trends were seen across categorical housekeeping levels. The association between cleanliness and safety was not as strong, nor was a trend found. Conclusions. The housekeeping checklist demonstrated high inter-observer reliability. The less stable test-retest reliability is partly due to changes in housekeeping between visits. Obstructions (lack of clutter, clear access to workstations, equipment and exits) and cleanliness components of housekeeping were more difficult, to measure and observers disagreed more when evaluating these components</description><creator>Dufort, Vincent.</creator><contributor>Infante-Rivard, Claire (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><title>Exploring the link between housekeeping and occupational injuries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161800n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx20z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z501</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The establishment and maintenance of the cardiac phenotype requires the activation of cardiac-specific as well as muscle-restricted genes in a tightly regulated spatial manner. This process is presumably governed by the combinatorial action of cell-restricted as well as ubiquitous transcriptional regulators. In order to unravel new cardiac transcriptional regulatory pathways and to characterize how they participate in the establishment of the cardiac transcriptional program, we used the atrial natriuretic factor (ANF) gene as a marker. This strategy led to the identification of a novel cardiac cis-element, the NKE, which is critical for the activity of the ANF promoter and which binds members of the cardiac NK2 family. The NKE is located in proximity to a critical GATA element and the phasing between these two elements is evolutionary conserved. Thus, we hypothesized that GATA-4 would functionally interact with Nkx2-5. Indeed, this work documents, for the first time, a molecular interaction between the essential cardiac proteins GATA-4 and Nkx2-5. Furthermore, this work provides a basis for GATA specificity in vitro and generates novel insights on how the cardiac genetic program is activated in early cardiogenesis. Finally, we report the cloning of a novel cardiac protein likely to have an important role in cardiogenesis, which was cloned in an effort to discover novel binding proteins that bind the critical CARE element required for high promoter activity in embryonic heart and postnatal atrium. This CARE-binding protein, CATF1, is a multifunctional helicase that defines a new family of DNA/RNA helicases. CATF1 is specifically expressed in the heart in neonates and is likely to be an activator of the ANF promoter. Collectively this work significantly furthers our knowledge on the establishment of cardiac- and chamber-specific transcription in the myocardium which is proposed here to occur via a combinatorial set of interactions among cardiac-restricted and ubiqu</description><creator>Durocher, Daniel.</creator><contributor>Nemer, Mona (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Combinatorial interactions controlling cardiac transcription</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b0544.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z501</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z714r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study combines qualitative and quantitative methodological approaches in a microanalytic examination of discourse features found in the instructional interactions of six Inuit first language, two Inuit second language, and six non-Inuit second language teachers of Inuit children in northern Quebec. In particular, the study analyzes the discourse features that contribute to the formulation of differing forms of communicative competence required for successful performance in the classrooms of Inuit versus non-Inuit teachers as well as the potential effects of these differences on the classroom participation of Inuit students. The quantitative results are integrated with findings taken from participant observation and ethnographic interviews conducted with all teacher participants. The study attempts to separate those effects that might be due to second language pedagogy from those likely to be the result of underlying cultural differences. Variation in discourse organization due to teaching experience is also examined. The study is situated within a dialogical framework of discourse organization whereby participants socially construct meanings and interpretations of talk through communicative interaction. Results of the study have implications for theories of syncretism and adapted pedagogy in minority educational contexts, demonstrating how instructional interactions can be influenced by and adapted toward the learner, resulting in teaching practices that reflect an amalgamation of cultures.</description><creator>Eriks-Brophy, Alice.</creator><contributor>Crago, Martha B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Education, Bilingual and Multicultural.</subject><subject>Education, Curriculum and Instruction.</subject><title>Instructional discourse of Inuit and non-Inuit teachers of Nunavik</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx196.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z714r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb61c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Apoptosis, a mechanism for modulating tissue growth, is triggered by signals (Fas ligand (FasL), tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-alpha)) derived from other cells as well as external factors such as ultraviolet radiation (UV). We have investigated the possibility that FasL, Fas, M-CSF and flt3/flk2 ligand are released on shed vesicles from HuT 78 cells, tumor cell lines (MIP-101 and CX-1), and Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cells transfected with cDNA encoding for M-CSF and flt3/flk2 ligand, respectively. Further, we examined the effects of UV-B irradiation on the capacity of CHO cells to shed vesicles per se, and on the capacity of CHO cells transfected with cDNA encoding flt3/flk2 ligand to express flt3/flk2 ligand on their cell surface. Vesicles and plasma membranes from CHO cells solubilized in N-octyl-beta-D-glycopyranoside, electrophoresed in polyacrylamide and reacted with anti-human M-CSF or anti-flt3/flk2 ligand antibody revealed bands of 90 and 45 kDal or 32 kDal bands, respectively. Following irradiation with UV-B (600 Joules/m2), CHO cells transfected with flt3/flk2 ligand cDNA failed to express the protein at their cell surface. When plasma membranes and shed vesicles collected from HuT 78 cells, solubilized, electrophoresed in polyacrylamide and reacted with anti-FasL IgG, immunoreactive FasL protein was detected in membranes and vesicles from HuT 78 cells. When exposed to FasL-bearing SVs 67.2 +/- 0.59% of Fas-expressing tumor cells survived as compared to cells treated with SVs derived from CX-1 cells (control), results which were comparable to the level of cell death observed following treatment with anti-Fas antibody (69.1 +/- 1.25%). Tumor cells treated with FasL- and Fas-bearing SVs simultaneously, exhibited 96.4 +/- 1.04% viability, indicating that FasL and Fas interact when expressed on SVs, in vitro. Our results suggest that diminished release of shed vesicles represents a potential early event in radiation-induced apoptosis occurring even pri</description><creator>Albanese, Joseph, 1964-</creator><contributor>Dainiak, Nicholas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Plasma membrane-derived shed vesicles bearing growth regulatory molecules induce cell proliferation or cell death : a potential mechanism for intraintercellular communication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b2815.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb61c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33575</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>