<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:55:39Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1225" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s451x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Guarino Guarini's SS. Sindone Chapel and its relic offer the occasion to contemplate the paradox of the Incarnation in architecture--a dialectic of presence and absence. The thesis begins with a return to the Gospel accounts of the Empty Tomb, and examines the tradition of reliquary and martyria which the Chapel is inscribed in. The Incarnation theme is then traced to the late seventeenth century context of the Chapel and is considered in the Counter-Reformation context of Turin. The architectural organization of the theme of presence and absence is then explored in the Chapel. In Part II, an examination of Architettura Civile, Guarini's treatise on architecture, seeks to understand the theory of parallel projection (ortografia) with regards to the Chapel's themes. In the last stage Guarini's philosophical treatise sheds some interesting light on ortografia--Presence and absence weave an architectural idea, a geometrical theory, a theological mystery.</description><creator>Debanné, Janine</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Incarnation</subject><subject>Cappella della SS. Sindone (Turin, Italy)</subject><subject>Architecture and religion</subject><subject>Guarini, Guarino, 1624-1683 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Guarino Guarini's SS. Sindone Chapel : between reliquary and cenotaph</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk19k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s451x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w446t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The conception of the unity of God in al-Juwayni, one of the latest thinkers in the early Islamic kalam, is the subject of this thesis. Al-Juwayni, though an Ash'arite thinker was quite often open to Mu'tazilite thought, particularly that of Abu Hashim al-Jubba'i. He was also influenced by the philosophers. With al-Juwayni the kalam's theory of the unity of God reached its ultimate resolution. That is to say, the theory of the unity of God was based on specific epistemological grounds, in the early period of the kalam. It had assumed its shape, and was therefore open to the possibility for establishing a new approach to the unity of God in the ontological sense. The first chapter deals with the long historical debate about the unity of God. It introduces many aspects of al-Juwayni's thought, and touches on how al-Juwayni proceeding from an Ash'arite background adopted many of the Mu'tazilite's themes, in its Basrian branch. The second chapter analyzes the theory of al-Juwayni on these issues and shows his contribution to the notion of the unity of God in his book al-Irshad. The third is a conclusion which throws light on the possibilities opened by al-Juwayni to approaching the unity of God from different ontological angles. Such possibilities had, infact, emerged in al-Juwaynis thinking when he began to use different concepts, particularly in his book al-'Aqidah al-Nizamiyah. Thus after he provided in al-Irshad that God is existence itself, he generally avoided using the terms atoms and accidents. Instead, he viewed the universe as two kinds, necessary Being and possible beings. In this context the attributes of God as aspects of His essence would play a different ontological role, comprehended in the term al-takhsid s.</description><creator>Ajhar, ʻAbd al-Ḥakīm.</creator><contributor>Ormsby, Eric (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>God -- Simplicity.</subject><subject>Imām al-Ḥaramayn al-Juwaynī, ʻAbd al-Malik ibn ʻAbd Allāh, 1028-1085</subject><title>The theory of the unity of God in al-Juwaynī's al-Irshād</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk85k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w446t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j7530</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to describe, apply and critique an assessment framework, namely, 'Student-Centred Assessment' based on concepts presented by Stiggins (1994). The theoretical basis is found in the literature dealing with multiculturalism and education, the forces promoting change in assessment, and the current status of assessment methods. The analysis of the 'Student-Centred Assessment' reveals that in such a framework there is a constant interaction between the student and the assessor leading to student engagement and that there is a need for changes in the assessment practices. Of the weaknesses noted, adapting tools for assessment is an ongoing challenge and the time needed to apply the framework effectively is a stressful problem. Based on these findings, various recommendations for practice and future research are made. The study examines the assessment of students in a regular grade three class, divided equally into a control and an experimental group randomly. Sources of data include documents, reports, and interviews with administrators, educators, and students. The control group is assessed by the classroom teacher according to norm-based tests. This teacher and the resource teacher then assess the experimental group by means of the methods outlined in the framework, to determine the inter-scorer reliability. Thereafter, the scores of the control group are compared to those of the experimental group to ensure internal validity and to analyze the framework. As well, interviews with school personnel ascertain the current status of assessment methods including sources for empowerment.</description><creator>Ahmad, Itrat</creator><contributor>Ghosh, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Multicultural education</subject><title>An assessment framework for empowering students in a multicultural society</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn521.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j7530</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f338v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative research employed the single case study approach to review the process by which service users and the staff of a food bank successfully broke through the bureaucratic resistance and secured new premises from the City of Montreal. This study explores the capacity of weaker parties to achieve their desired goal through strategic intervention on social exchange network despite the pre-existing asymmetric power relations. The conception of goal attainment, power relations and social exchange were discussed in order to develop the research questions. Case materials were collected from multiple sources: documentary research, in-depth interviews, and observation. The findings demonstrate that internal solidarity, potential uses of coalitions and expansion of resource networks are fundamental factors for members of a subordinate group to gain power and to achieve their goals. Implications for community organization practice were drawn from the overview of the empirical findings and theoretical concepts.</description><creator>Sin, Ricky W. C. (Ricky Wai-Chuen)</creator><contributor>Torczyner, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Community organization -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Power (Social sciences)</subject><subject>Social exchange.</subject><subject>Multi-Caf (Côte-des-Neiges, Montréal, Québec)</subject><title>Goal attainment, social exchange and power relations : a search for guiding principles for organizing strategy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ricky W. C. Sin, 1995</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr675.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f338v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nk224</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following thesis describes the experiences of a non-Native, female, social worker as a participant-observer among First Nations people. The setting was that of an Intensive Drug and Alcohol Abuse Prevention Program for male Aboriginal ex-offenders, held over a period of four months in 1993. The environment was a secluded camp site, situated to the North-East of Montreal. The material describes, in narrative form, the interactions between non-Native and Mohawk workers, and between non-Native worker and Native clients of various cultural backgrounds. Also considered are general issues which affect First Nations peoples, such as alcohol and drug abuse, grief and loss, sexual abuse and the resurgence of traditional Native spiritual practices. Implications of the work reflect on effective cross-cultural communication, and the importance of facilitating appropriate healing processes for First Nations peoples.</description><creator>Garwood, Nicki</creator><contributor>Leonard, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Social work with Indians -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Cross-cultural counseling.</subject><subject>Social work with alcoholics -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Social work with minorities -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>"Why do you want to help me? I've never even been to your home..." : a journey in cross-cultural social work with Aboriginal people</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz606.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk224</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw556</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The economic regulation of air transport is a field that was, in large part, left out from the Chicago Convention of 1944 drafted at the Chicago Conference, due to a lack of agreement amongst the participants. Since then, ICAO has made numerous unsuccessful attempts to fill this void. With the inclusion of air transport services in the General Agreement on Trade in Services of 1993, the subject has once again come to the forefront of the aviation liberalization efforts. This thesis describes the economic regulation of air transport since 1944 as set out in the Chicago Convention, its consequences and the liberalization efforts that have since been proposed. The principles of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) are presented as is the debate concerning their application to air transport services. The final text of the General Agreement on Trade in Services (GATS) and the Annex on air transport services is analyzed and its implications for the future regulation of air transport services are discussed. Finally, the question of the appropriate forum for the future regulation of such services is also examined.</description><creator>Kolivakis, Marie-Angélique</creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>The economic regulation of air transport : from the Chicago Convention to GATS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881p097.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw556</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bk23q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The constitutionality of the limit of liability in article 22(1) of the Warsaw Convention has never been fully considered by the Canadian courts. Article 22(1) limits the liability of air carriers in the case of injury or death of passengers. This study analyses the constitutionality of the limit of liability under the Constitution Act, 1867, ss. 6, 7 and 15 of the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms and s. 1(a) of the Canadian Bill of Rights. The author submits that the limit of liability is ultra vires the federal Parliament under the Constitution Act, 1867. The author also submits that the limit of liability infringes ss. 6 and 7 of the Charter and is not demonstrably justified under s. 1.</description><creator>Hatnay, Andrew J.</creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>The constitutionality of the limit of liability of the Warsaw Convention in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h297.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk23q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qf07x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to help the fight against organised crime, particularly drug dealing, the problem of money laundering has become more significant. The various techniques used by money launderers are also subject of this thesis. Through the many ways utilised to launder money, it shows how difficult it is to pinpoint what action is on the border of legality and what is not. These difficulties become more apparent when precise analysis is made of the law as applied in both Switzerland and the U.S.A. Neither approach has proven successful. On the contrary, the question of constitutionality of many rules becomes relevant. Many authors do not find the application of the laws easy from the point of view of constitutional law. The present thesis suggests to review the present laws and redefine them in a simpler manner which makes them acceptable internationally.</description><creator>Gerber, Thierry</creator><contributor>Glenn, H. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Sociology, Criminology and Penology.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Money laundering - a comparative study between the law in Switzerland and in the U.S.A.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f69z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qf07x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956h95f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is now common that amendments to the Chicago Convention are adopted unanimously, or almost unanimously, and at a relatively great speed by the General Assembly of the International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO). Unfortunately, the pace of their ratification by the member States is extremely slow and it delays considerably their entry into force. The first part of this thesis tries to identify, on the one hand, different mechanisms which could accelerate the process of ratification and therefore the entry into force of amendments and, on the other hand, describes the procedure that would maintain the unity and homogeneity of the legal framework of the Chicago Convention. ICAO is aware that several member States fail to notify differences between their own regulations and the annexes to the Chicago Convention and do not implement in their national legislation the international standards which they did not disapprove. This failure of the quasi-legislative function of ICAO may endanger the safety of the international civil aviation. The second part of this thesis describes various mechanisms of control which ICAO could adopt in order to identify the violations of international obligations by its member States and to urge them to observe its international standards. ICAO has to secure a high degree of uniformity in regulations between its member States. Otherwise, it may lose its role as leader in international civil aviation to regional organizations.</description><creator>Ducrest, Jacques</creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Une nouvelle dynamique des fonctions législatives et quasi-législatives de lórganisation de l'aviation civile internationale?</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm50k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h95f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dv21w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The telecommunications industry is being shaped by technological and market developments, and is moving into the 21st Century. The telecommunications technology of the future is integrated services digital networks. ISDN, which is the concept for a future digital telecommunications network for delivery of a wide range of innovative voice, data and video services through satellite systems and the national information highways being developed in several countries, will lead to a Global Information Infrastructure. ISDN development will pose challenges to traditional telecommunications regulation, lead to increased multimodal competition between ground and space-based transmission systems, and erode INTELSAT's market base since future digital ISDN systems will be interchangeable with satellite systems. This study begins in Chapter I with an examination of the emerging technologies and recent market trends which challenge traditional regulation, as well as the importance of upholding regulation in the emerging ISDN telecommunications environment. Chapter II discusses the recent market developments in Canada, the legal implications of emerging technologies for the current regulatory regime, and the need for comprehensive policy and regulation. Chapter III discusses the role of satellites in the emerging global ISDN environment, the mandate of INTELSAT in terms of spectrum/orbit resource management, the regulation of multimodal telecommunications under the INTELSAT Agreement, the challenges to INTELSAT represented by ISDN development, the role of the ITU in the regulation of the emerging global ISDN environment, and the future of INTELSAT in light of competition, technological progress, and regulatory trends. This is followed by a conclusion in Chapter IV.</description><creator>Correia, Rose Mary</creator><contributor>Jakhu, Ram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Information Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Legal aspects of multimodal telecommunications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s92k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dv21w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m50g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Commercial undertakings to arbitrate and arbitral awards are commonly recognized and enforced in both Canada and the United States. Chapter Eleven of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), Investor-State Arbitration, now gives new meaning to the established arbitral regime. For the first time in any trade pact in the world to date, the NAFTA provides a mechanism by which a private investor may submit a claim against NAFTA Party government to dispute resolution through "binding" arbitration. This system not only established an innovative solution to a bureaucratic quandary by raising the investor onto a level playing field with a government, but reaffirms the validity of commercial arbitration and demonstrates its adaptability to a changing political and economic environment. Investor-State "binding" arbitration is the only form of dispute resolution in existence which responds faster to the needs of North American investors than the courts or legislature. The influence of national laws and the jurisprudence of countries party to the NAFTA on the arbitral decision-making process not only will facilitate trade across North American borders, but will create a new body of transnational legal norms.</description><creator>Bogdanowicz, Kasia</creator><contributor>Brierley, John E. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Commercial arbitration between Canada and the United States and the effect of the NAFTA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv718.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m50g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp367</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Four fundamental principles constitute the basis of international regulations pertaining to the operational aspects of telecommunications, and communications satellites in particular. Firstly, provision of global distress and safety service should be provided globally on a priority basis. Secondly, global telecommunications coverage and connectivity should be achieved. Thirdly, basic telecommunications services should be established within every national jurisdiction, including developing areas, and should be accessible to all individuals. Finally, universal access to telecommunications services on a non-discriminatory basis should be guaranteed. At the outset, governments have not only chosen to foster and closely regulate the development and operations of communications satellites, but also to maintain management oversight by cooperatively establishing two unique consortia, namely Intelsat and Inmarsat. This international regulatory framework, which currently continues to oversee the operational aspects of global satellite services, is essentially comprised of the Intelsat and Inmarsat Agreements adhered to by numerous member states. This framework was established a few decades ago at the inception of commercial fixed and mobile satellite services, and has not been structurally reviewed despite the changing global environment. Considering that the prime objective of international agreements is to ensure that the world community adheres to the principles outlined above, this thesis examines the relevance of the current regulatory framework at the dawn of the information age. A growing number of governments may be rewriting their own role in the operational aspects of communication satellites for the future, as they review this framework to address the challenges of the emerging environment nearly three decades after the launching of the first commercial satellite, Early Bird. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Berdnikoff, Michel</creator><contributor>Jakhu, Ram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Information Science.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Three decades after early bird : global communications satellite services and emerging regulatory issues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r048r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp367</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h646</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The representativeness of North Atlantic cyclone activity is assessed for the 15 January-15 March 1992 period of the second Canadian Atlantic Storms Program (CASP II). Explosive cyclogenesis is found to shift northeastward to a locus east of the Canadian seaboard along a sustained anomalous cyclone track. Active (inactive) periods are defined as comprising the quarter of the study period with the strongest (weakest) cyclone deepening: Of 24 Atlantic bombs, 14 (1) occur(s) during active (inactive) periods. During active periods, storms develop along strong baroclinic zones on the leading edge of southeasterly advancing Arctic air masses, and lead low-frequency oscillations in the position of an intensified Atlantic jet stream. Cyclone deepening shows heightened response to 500 hPa vorticity advection during active periods. Maximum deepening positions of explosive (weak) cases are preconditioned by negative (positive) 1000-500 hPa thickness anomalies 36-12 h ahead of the developing cyclones.</description><creator>Wintels, Werner</creator><contributor>Gyakum, John R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A study of cyclone activity during CASP II</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x067.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h646</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b497</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Filter-feeding macrozooplankton were collected from 24 lakes in south-central Ontario to examine relationships between environmental factors and methyl mercury accumulation. Zooplankton methyl mercury levels ranged from 19 to 448 ng$ rm cdot g sp{-1}$ dry weight in the study lakes and were highest in zooplankton from acidic brownwater lakes. Water color and lake water pH were the best predictors of methyl mercury levels in zooplankton explaining 73% of the variation. Methyl mercury concentrations were positively correlated with water color and inversely correlated with lake water pH. Water color explained a greater portion of the overall variance in methyl mercury levels, indicating that the supply of mercury from the drainage basin plays a key role in determining methyl mercury concentrations in the lacustrine biota. Zooplankton methyl mercury levels were well correlated with mercury concentrations in smallmouth bass (Micropterus dolomieui) and largemouth bass (Micropterus salmoides) from 11 of the study lakes showing zooplankton to be good indicators of the relative bioavailability of mercury at the base of the food chain.</description><creator>Westcott, Kim</creator><contributor>Kalff, Jacob (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Freshwater zooplankton -- Ontario</subject><subject>Lake ecology -- Ontario</subject><subject>Methylmercury -- Bioaccumulation</subject><title>Environmental factors affecting methyl mercury accumulation in zooplankton</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935507j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b497</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gq31q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Parallelizing compilers are increasingly relying on accurate data dependence information to exploit parallelism. This thesis addresses the problem of array data-flow analysis which provides more accurate information than traditional scalar data-flow analysis and array data dependence analysis. We describe the design and implementation of an array data-flow analyzer which has been integrated into our HPC compiler. The HPC compiler automatically parallelizes programs written in the HPC language, an extension of the C language, and generates SPMD codes for distributed memory machines. Two other important parts of the compiler, the automatic data and computation decomposition tool and the SPMD code generator, use the array data-flow information. We introduce the array data-flow representation source tree which allows us to compute array data-flow information more effectively and efficiently. We perform array data-flow computation from the highest dependence level to the lowest dependence level and sequence the writes by lexicographical order in the presence of multiple writes. The check of a source tree against the coverage conditions allows us to avoid any further computation once the sources have been found. We introduce our global array data-flow analysis to compute array data-flow information beyond a single loop nest. This is useful for advanced program transformation and optimizations in the scope of a cluster of loop nests. We have investigated the pragmatic issues of applying Feautrier's method in the HPC compiler framework. We have performed experiments of both local array data-flow analysis and global array data-flow analysis on seven programs of the Perfect Benchmarks, under the platform of the HPC compiler. The experimental results show that our method has acceptable performances for analyzing scientific and engineering applications.</description><creator>Wen, Renhua</creator><contributor>Gao, G. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>The design and implementation of an accurate array data-flow analyzer in the HPC compiler</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws39j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq31q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967579p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The definition of the study population for a clinical trial via the criteria for trial eligibility has implications for the validity of the study and its applicability to clinical practice. Though issues of equity regarding the selection of subjects for research have long been a concern of ethicists, issues regarding the impact of subject selection on a trial's generalizability have only recently attracted ethical scrutiny. After a review of the history of the ethics of subject selection, I focus on three empirical questions regarding the generalizability of clinical trials. (1) What proportion of diseased populations are studied in clinical trials? (2) How are subjects selected for clinical trial participation (and what are the main barriers to participation)? (3) Are clinical trial participants comparable to non-participants? Finally, the role of the Institutional Review Board--Research Ethics Board in Canada--in assessing the generalizability of clinical research is discussed.</description><creator>Weijer, Charles</creator><contributor>Freedman, Benjamin (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Fuks, Abraham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Philosophy.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, General.</subject><title>Characterizing the population in clinical trials : barriers, comparability, and implications for review</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505246x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967579p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d6248</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The behaviour of captive mallards (Anas platyrhynchos) and black ducks (Anas rubripes) was studied from the end of March to mid-June in 1991 and 1992 to determine the extent of interspecific aggression exhibited and the effect of sympatry and allopatry on interactions between the two species. Mallards were more aggressive than black ducks regardless of sex and origin, though both species were equally attacked in both years, male ducks were more aggressive and more attacked than female ducks regardless of species and origin in both years, and ducks of sympatric origin were more aggressive than ducks of allopatric origin in 1991 regardless of sex and species while the opposite was true in 1992. Site attachment was observed in 7 of 9 experiments performed in 1992. In the experiments involving site attachment, almost all of the activity centered around the feeding stations, not around the nesting platforms.</description><creator>Tisdall, Carol</creator><contributor>Titman, Rodger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Mallard -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Captive wild birds.</subject><subject>Black duck -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Aggressive behavior in animals.</subject><title>Aggression among captive mallards and black ducks during the breeding season</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp48s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d6248</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f4627486</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dry Romano beans (Phaseolus vulgaris) were soaked and cooked at temperatures ranging from 70 to 100$ sp circ$C for different time intervals. The rate of texture softening associated with each temperature was found to be consistent with two simultaneous pseudo first-order kinetic mechanisms 1 and 2. Approximately 40% of the firmness of Romano beans was lost by the rapid softening mechanism 1. The remaining firmness loss was characterized by mechanism 2 which was found to be much slower ($ sim$1/50th of the former). The temperature dependence indicator (z value) of reaction rate constants were 30 and 24 C$ sp circ$, respectively for mechanisms 1 and 2 with associated activation energies of 82 kJ/mole and 103 kJ/mole, respectively. Turnip (Brassica napobbrassica) and beet roots (B. Vulgaris L.) were cooked at temperatures ranging from 70 to 100$ sp circ$C for different time intervals. Three textural properties (firmness, springiness, and stiffness) were found to follow the same trend of apparent first order kinetic theory with two substrates. Temperature dependence of softening (z value) was found to be within 27 and 35 C$ sp circ ,$ with activation energies in the range of 93 and 60 kJ/mole. Cylindrical turnip, beet root pieces and Romano beans were packed in thin profile plastic containers and cylindrical metal cans and thermally processed in the static and rotational modes. Through heat penetration testing, process times were adjusted to give an equivalent lethality of 10 min for each product. Thin profile packed vegetables, in all cases, were found to have a firmer and stiffer texture. On the other hand, for rotational processing, the result showed no significant improvement in textural properties (firmness, springiness and stiffness) over the still counterparts. It was found that previously determined kinetic data could be used to estimate texture retention.</description><creator>Taherian, Ali Reza</creator><contributor>Ramaswamy, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Food -- Effect of heat on.</subject><subject>Vegetables -- Preservation.</subject><title>Thermal softening kinetics and textural quality of thermally processed vegetables</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2687219.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4627486</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s93v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurogenic impotence is a clinical situation commonly resulting from major pelvic surgery. A detailed description of the neural pathways mediating erection has been lacking and this has been implicated as a major cause for the high incidence of post-operative impotence. Nitric oxide (NO) is a gaseous molecule believed to be an important mediator of erection. The synthesis of nitric oxide is regulated by the enzyme nitric oxide synthase. In the first part of this work, we studied the neuroanatomical pathways responsible for erection in the male lower urogenital tract. Using a histochemical staining technique able to localize a co-factor of nitric oxide synthase, NADPH, we traced the course of the cavernous nerve and its microscopic branch fibers from the pelvic plexus distally until the penile crura. Studies in a rat model and in man demonstrated multiple small nitric oxide releasing nerve fibers located on the anterior and lateral surfaces of the prostatic capsule. The physiologic importance of these fibers was shown in a rat model. Transection of these fibers resulted in a significant loss of intracavernosal pressure rise following cavernous nerve stimulation. The nitric oxide synthase enzyme is found in three isoforms: neuronal, endothelial, and inducible forms. The neuronal form is believed to be important in the neural regulation of erection as has been demonstrated in histological studies. Using a specific inhibitor of the neuronal form of nitric oxide synthase, 7-nitroindazole, we evaluated and showed the importance of the neuronal form in regulating erection in an animal model.</description><creator>Spiess, Philippe E. (Philippe Edouard)</creator><contributor>Dion, Stephane B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Nitric oxide : an important neural mediator of penile erection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8382606.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s93v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq882</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work proves the pathogenicity of four substitution mutations in the androgen-binding domain of the human androgen receptor (hAR) gene of four subjects with varying degrees of androgen insensitivity syndrome (AIS): complete (CAIS), partial (PAIS), or mild (MAIS). Of three unrelated CAIS subjects, two have Arg830Leu, the third has Arg830Gln. Their genital skin fibroblasts (GSF) have negligible androgen binding, but in overexpressing transfectants, the mutant androgen-binding activities have increased dissociation rates and decreased affinity for androgen. Owing to the instability of AR-androgen complexes, both mutants fail to transactivate a reporter gene. Glu771Ala and Arg870Gly caused PAIS and MAIS, respectively. Their normal levels of GSF androgen-binding activity have normal androgen affinity but increased dissociation rates. In transfectants, rates of dissociation resemble those in GSF, but the androgen affinities are questionably abnormal. Instability of Glu771Ala and Arg870Gly AR-androgen complexes caused subnormal transactivation of a reporter gene.</description><creator>Shkolny, Dana</creator><contributor>Pinsky, Leonard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>X chromosome -- Abnormalities</subject><subject>Androgens -- Receptors</subject><subject>Sex differentiation disorders</subject><title>Characterization of four point mutations in the androgen receptor gene of subjects with varying degrees of androgen insensitivity syndrome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c382.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq882</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m51r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The developmental profiles of mRNA and protein expression for ornithine decarboxylase (ODC), the Na$ sp+$-dependent glucose co-transporter (SGLT1), sucrase isomaltase (SI), and the Na$ rm sp+K sp+$ ATPase $ alpha sb1$ and $ beta sb1$ subunit isoforms in the postnatal rat small intestine, as well as the effects of exogenous spermidine on their precocious development, were examined. Postnatal age had a significant effect with all enzymes and the nutrient transporter maturing around weaning. Consecutive exposure to exogenous spermidine during suckling precociously induced ODC mRNA, SI protein, and SGLT1 gene expression in the proximal and distal small intestine. Levels of Na$ rm sp+K sp+$ ATPase $ alpha sb1$ and $ beta sb1$ subunit isoform mRNA were precociously induced in the proximal small intestine only. These findings show that exposure to exogenous spermidine can promote precocious alterations in intestinal enzyme and nutrient transporter expression; however, it appears that spermidine must be continuously supplied for these alterations to persist in suckling rats.</description><creator>Searles, Lynne E. (Lynne Elizabeth)</creator><contributor>Koski, Kristine G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Intestine, Small.</subject><subject>Ornithine decarboxylase.</subject><subject>Spermidine.</subject><subject>Sodium/potassium ATPase.</subject><subject>Sodium cotransport systems.</subject><subject>Gene expression.</subject><title>Effects of orally administered spermidine on absorptive enzyme and nutrient transporter gene expression in the rat small intestine during postnatal development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w948j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m51r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm51v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study evaluated the Aga Khan University Urban Primary Health Care Program's effectiveness, six years after implementation in lower-middle class Karachi. The study supplemented surveillance data which showed two-fold improvements in health indicators. One Program and one Comparison area were successfully matched post hoc on ethnicity and socioeconomic status. Study participants included women in both areas who had been pregnant in the last 5 years and resident for over 1 year. The Program achieved 88% community coverage: 85% with outreach visits and 65% with clinic-based services. Factors which potentially confounded the surveillance estimates included secular improvements in water, sanitation, and socioeconomic status, along with the utilization of other health-care providers and health education resources. The Program's unique services were community health worker outreach (home visits and educational meetings) and growth monitoring. The Program was found to be effective in improving most knowledge scores, some healthy behaviours, and no impacts. Positive results included: increased immunization and family planning knowledge scores by 5-10%, higher maternal-child immunization rates by 10-20%, and greater colostrum feeding practice by 10%. Negative results included: no additional diarrhea knowledge; no change in healthy behaviours towards diarrhea treatment, breast feeding, family planning or maternity care; and no health impact on fertility or childhood nutritional status. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Schokking, Ian David</creator><contributor>Tonssignant, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Effectiveness of outreach primary health care in Karachi, Pakistan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q92n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm51v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p024z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis reports two new methods developed to study the free ion activity of aluminum and copper. Both methods could be applied to the study of other metals. The first method measures the apparent solubility of aluminum and sulfate in a dynamic, leached system. This system is believed to give a good representation of the field situation where soils are continuously leached and never at equilibrium. This study was done under three sulfate concentrations. The part of the experiment using low sulfate concentrations showed aluminum solubility control by a gibbsite-like solid phase with a log K$ sp circ$ of 7.49. It was also shown, however, that under natural soil solution concentrations of sulfate in acidic forest soils, an interaction with sulfate controls aluminum activity rather than gibbsite solubility equilibria. This interaction is either, an aluminum-sulfate solid phase or, a stoichiometric ion-pair co-adsorption of aluminum and sulfate. The second method is a simple determination of free Cu$ sp{2+}$ in soils using a cupric ion-selective electrode. Free copper has been demonstrated to be the toxicity controlling component in aquatic studies and this study was undertaken to measure free copper activity in soils. The possible interference due to ionic strength variations or the presence of aluminum in the soil solution was checked and found to be negligible. The free activity of copper (pCu$ sp{2+}$) measured in a variety of pristine and contaminated soils varied between 6.33 to 12.20 pCu$ sp{2+}$ units. Total soil copper content and acidity were shown to strongly increase copper solubility and free Cu$ sp{2+}$ activity in the soil solution extracts. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Sauvé, Sébastien</creator><contributor>Hendershot, W. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Soil chemistry.</subject><subject>Soils -- Copper content.</subject><subject>Soils -- Aluminum content.</subject><subject>Soil solutions.</subject><title>Copper and aluminum free ion activity in soil solutions = L'activité inonique du cuivre et de l'aluminium dans des solutions de sols</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc75m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p024z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418q23t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the acknowledged importance of nutritional support for COPD patients, it is difficult to accomplish in acutely stressed individuals. A randomized trial of nutritional supplementation during an acute exacerbation was carried out in 16 hospitalized patients for a 2 week period. Six control patients consumed a standard diet supplying 1,951 $ pm$ 130 (mean $ pm$ SEM) kcal and 80 $ pm$ 6 g protein/d, while ten treatment patients, in addition to the usual diet received oral supplements (Ensure) or snacks, resulting in an intake of 2,516 $ pm$ 129 kcal (p = 0.012) and 99 $ pm$ 6 g protein/d (p = 0.059). Although the treatment subjects improved their intake over the control group, no significant improvement in nutritional status occurred in either group. Forced vital capacity (FVC % predicted) improved significantly over the study period in treated vs control subjects (+11.10 $ pm$ 4.63 vs $-$4.50 $ pm$ 2.14; p = 0.026). Nitrogen balances were calculated for 9 subjects, and all were in negative balance ($-$8.42 $ pm$ 1.74 g nitrogen/d) with no difference between groups. Because of the high doses of methylprednisolone administered (69.6 $ pm$ 8.3 mg/d), and their known catabolic effects, we examined whether the dose affected nitrogen balance and muscle strength. Both nitrogen balance (r = $-$0.73; p = 0.025) and grip strength (r = $-$0.76; p $&lt;$ 0.001) worsened with higher doses of steroids. The catabolic process may have resulted from elevated energy requirements, inadequate intake of protein and energy or been induced by high doses of steroids. Hospitalized COPD patients are highly stressed and catabolic, and the means to preventing protein wasting during an acute exacerbation of their disease remains to be established. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Saudny-Unterberger, Helga</creator><contributor>Gray-Donald, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Lungs -- Diseases, Obstructive -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Nutrition -- Evaluation.</subject><title>Impact of nutritional support on changes in functional status during an acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p241r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q23t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f340w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The prescription of R. M. Wald for determining a thermodynamic first law for stationary, axisymmetric, asymptotically flat black holes in general theories of gravity is applied to the effective Lagrangian for the bosonic sector of low-energy heterotic super-string theory. It is found that the presence of the gauge fields necessitates an alteration of the prescription. Specifically, the Lie derivatives with respect to the Killing vector of the gauge fields are non-vanishing. This introduces new terms which ensure gauge-invariance of the final result in a natural way.</description><creator>Roderick, Christopher</creator><contributor>Myers, Robert C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>The thermodynamic first law for black holes in low-energy string theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g361.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f340w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1250</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>