<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:28:14Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34750" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707959458</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clinical decision making is essential to clinical practice, yet research into the cognitive processes underlying clinical decision making is limited. The purpose of this study was to investigate the cognitive processes utilized by nurses in actual clinical decision making situations. Using a criterion sampling technique, eight experienced medical and surgical nurses from an acute care community hospital were selected as participants for in-depth interviews about clinical decision making in nursing practice. Actual clinical data documented by the eight nurses were obtained from a review of 100 randomly selected hospital records of patients discharged over a one year period. The study examined the influence of contextual factors (nursing subgroup, Problem Oriented Recording [POR] charting system and primary nursing system), task variables (complexity of clinical problems), and clinician characteristics (nursing expertise) on clinical decision making. The dependent variables included the accuracy of nursing diagnosis documentation and the utilization of specific thinking processes. Donald's model of thinking processes provided a framework for the analysis of the data. The results suggest that clinical decision making is a complex cognitive process requiring numerous thinking skills and operations. Five different categories of thinking skills and 14 different operations were identified in the narrative notes. The clinical situations were categorized into three types based on the complexity of clinical problems. Nurses from both hospital units documented a wider range of thinking skills and operations in situations of greater complexity. The findings also suggest that structured charting formats such as SOAP narrative notes encouraged the use of higher order thinking processes. The introduction of the primary nursing patient assignment system did not result in significant changes in the documentation of nursing diagnoses or thinking processes utilized by nurses. The nurses were grouped into two levels of expertise according to Benner's categories: expert and proficient, with differences more evident in the medical nurses. An important outcome of this study was the development of nursing exemplars and illustrations of thinking processes that can provide a working vocabulary to describe the underlying cognitive processes used in clinical decision making.</description><creator>Higuchi, Kathryn A. Smith.</creator><contributor>Donald, Janet G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Nursing -- Decision making.</subject><subject>Nursing -- Study and teaching.</subject><title>Professional nursing education : cognitive processes utilized in clinical decision making</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765372847.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707959458</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td90q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An understanding of the molecular structure-function relationships of diacyl phospholipids is demanded in fields of study such as drug delivery, therapeutics, metabolism and physiology. Of particular interest are the properties of lipid derivatives where one or both acyl chains contain a polar moiety. Phospholipid analogs of distearolyphosphatidylcholine (DSPC) bearing polar groups (SO2, SO, S and CO) in the acyl chain(s) were synthesized and characterized using differential scanning calorimetry (DISC) and the Langmuir film-balance technique (LFB). Through the development of a detailed structure-function relationship map we have endeavored to understand the effect of the functional group on lipid conformation, phase, morphology and stability. Many of the measured properties prove to be sensitive to the chemical nature of the specific functional group and its position in the acyl chain, and whether one (mono) or both (bis) acyl chains are derivatized. In the LFB experiment both surface pressure and surface potential isotherms provide a description of the properties of functionalised lipids at the air-water interface. A functional group position-dependent phase transition mechanism is revealed for phospholipids bearing SO2 and SO groups in their acyl chains. The monolayer critical temperature (Tc) is used as a diagnostic of the mechanism; T c corresponds to the bilayer phase transition temperature (Tm) in the former case, but not in the latter. Surface dipole experiments permit direct observation of the conformation of the functionalised lipid chain due to the presence of the polar groups in the chain. A methodology which normalizes the temperature-dependent isotherms of structurally-related materials for the purpose of their direct comparison is also presented. The LFB technique is used to determine the interaction of the enzyme protein tyrosine phosphatase (PTPase, SHP-1) with lipid monolayers. The LFB technique in conjunction with fluorescence resonance energy transfer experiments (FRET) were used to directly monitor the interaction of protein with lipid interfaces. Studies on the effect of headgroup structure, lipid surface density, and SHP-1 subphase concentration supports a self consistent model in which cohesive protein-lipid interactions control a first order penetration mechanism. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Heitner, Tara.</creator><contributor>Lennox, R. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biophysics, General.</subject><title>Bi- and tripolar phospholipid interfaces : characterization and interaction with proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh30n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td90q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053h846</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Brief episodes of ischemia followed by reperfusion render the heart more resistant to injury from a subsequent prolonged ischemia. This endogenous and highly protective phenomenon is known as ischemic preconditioning. Although the phenomenon has been demonstrated virtually in all species tested including nun, the mechanism of ischemic preconditioning is incompletely understood. Early studies showed that both adenosine A1 receptors and K ATP channels appeared to mediate the effects of preconditioning in most species, but not in the rat. Therefore, we first investigated the signal transduction mechanisms involved in ischemic preconditioning against post-ischemic contractile dysfunction in isolated Langendorff-perfused rat hearts. We found that ischemic preconditioning in the rat heart is due to stimulation of alpha1B-adrenoceptors by release of endogenous catecholamines, resulting in acfivation of a pertussis toxin-sensitive guanine nucleotide binding (G) protein which enhances protein kinase C (PKC) activity. The results support the hypothesis that G protein-dependent PKC activation may be the common mechanism in signal transduction pathways of ischemic preconditioning among species. Accumulating evidence suggests that ATP-sensitive K+ channel (KATP channel) activation plays an important protective role in ischemic preconditioning. We hypothesized that PKC stimulation in ischemic preconditioning may produce cardioprotection by modulating KATP channel function, and studied further the modulation of the KATP channel by PKC-mediated phosphorylation, in rabbit and human ventricular myocytes, using voltage clamp techniques. We found that PKC activation stimulates KATP-induced opening at reduced intracellular ATP concentrations by reducing KATP channel sensitivity to intracellular ATP. In order to determine whether membrane-bound PKC could explain previously-described adenosine-induced KATP channel activation in excised membrane patches, we studied KATP channel function</description><creator>Hu, Keli.</creator><contributor>Nattel, Stanley (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Signal transduction systems involved in ischemic preconditioning and ATP-sensitive K+ channels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r733f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h846</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw21c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Susceptibility to infection with Salmonella varies in different chicken lines suggesting the involvement of host genetic factors. Segregation analysis using Salmonella-resistant and Salmonella-susceptible chickens has shown that early resistance to infection is fully dominant, not sex-linked or associated with the major histocompatibility complex (MHC). In mice, natural resistance to infection with Salmonella typhimurium is controlled by two major loci, Nramp1 and Lps, that exert pleiotropic effects and contribute to cytostatic/cytocidal activities of the macrophage. We have tested the candidacy of the chicken homologs of Nramp1 and Tnc (a locus closely linked to Lps ) in the differential resistance of chicken inbred lines to infection with Salmonella typhimurium. We first mapped chicken NRAMP1 gene to chromosome 7q13 within a conserved synteny to mouse chromosome 1 and human chromosome 2q. We have analyzed six inbred chicken lines that were Salmonella -resistant or Salmonella-susceptible for the presence of sequence variation within NRAMP1. Sequence analysis has revealed 11 nucleotide variations within the coding portion of NRAMP1 10 of these sequence variation represent either silent mutations or conservative changes. We have investigated the effect of NRAMP1 and the chromosomal region surrounding LPS on resistance to infection with S. typhimurium in 425 (CXWI)F1XC chicken progeny. Together, NRAMP1 and TNC explain 33% of the early differential resistance to infection with S. typhimurium of parental lines C and Wl. The data established that both NRAMP1 and TNC contributed to the resistance of chicken to infection with Salmonella typhimurium, and demonstrated that comparative mapping is valuable in identifying Salmonella-resistance genes in the chicken. Furthermore, the results are consistent with the fact that resistance to salmonellosis in chicken is inherited as a complex trait. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Hu, Jinxin.</creator><contributor>Malo, Danielle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Agriculture, Food Science and Technology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Molecular and genetic studies of resistance to infection with Salmonella typhimurium in chickens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd42d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw21c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc22b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reactive amyloidosis characterized by the tissue deposition of insoluble AA amyloid (AA), is a potentially serious complication of certain chronic infections and recurrent inflammatory diseases. AA is derived from the amyloidogenic serum amyloid A (SAA), an acute phase protein whose plasma concentration may increase up to 1000-fold in response to tissue trauma. Chronic elevation of SAA in conjugation with inflammation-related host factors is believed to induce conversion of SAA to AA. One such host factor, called amyloid enhancing factor (AEF), has recently been identified as ubiquitin (UB). However, the molecular pathogenesis of AA amyloidosis in vivo is not well understood. Prior studies in our laboratory using alveolar hydatid cyst infected mouse model of AA amyloidosis (AHC-mouse) has demonstrated that (a) SAA and UB co-deposit in the splenic perifollicular areas prior to AA deposition, (b) both SAA and UB co-localize to endosomes-lysosomes (ELs) inflammatory macrophages (MA) and splenic reticuloendothelial (RE) cells, and (c) UB binds to the tissue AA deposits. My working hypothesis is that EL-mediated physiological degradation of SAA may serve as the primary clearance mechanism for exogenous SAA. As a secondary consequence, incessant overloading of ELs with ubiquitin-associated SAA during chronic inflammation may alter the rate or the extent of proteolysis leading to prolonged retention of SAA derivatives and the formation of "nascent" AA fibrils in ELs. The objectives of the present study are the following: (a) to establish intra-macrophage topographical relationship between murine SAA3, which is synthesized by activated MA and RE cells, and two precursors of AA, SAM and SAA2, that are endocytosed by MA and RE cells, (b) to immunochemically and chemically analyze the MA-derived degradation products of SAA in order to establish whether they could be potentially amyloidogenic and (c) to seek functional clues regarding the role of ubiquitin in SAA processing and in AA formation. Both the in vivo and in vitro experiments were carried out to pursue these objectives. I have shown that (a) murine SAA1/SAA2 localize exclusively to ELs whereas SAM occupies the cytoplasmic compartment in MAs, (b) the lysates derived from MA contain at least four AA-sized potentially amyloidogenic N-terminally intact SAM and SAA2 derivatives and (c) AA amyloid purified from AHC-mice is derived from both SAA2 and SAA1. As to the role of UB in SAA processing, I have shown that (a) UB binds avidly but non-covalently to both SAA1 and SAA2, (b) UB binds to ELs containing both immature and mature AA fibrils and (c) UB dissociated and purified from the tissue AA deposits retains its AEF activity in vivo. Collectively, these data show for the first time a direct relationship between the localization of SAA1 and SAA2 to ELs in MAs and the intracellular generation of potentially amyloidogenic N-terminally intact SAM and SAA2 derivatives which may polymerize into "nascent" AA fibrils in ELs. We believe, as has also been proposed by others, that these "nascent" AA fibrils either after exocytosis or cell death may act as nucleation sites for extracellular AA deposition. As to the role of UB in SAA processing, we suggest that non-covalent binding of UB to SAA1 and SAA2 may (a) structurally alter theses substrates, thereby rendering them susceptible to phagocytosis by MA/RE-cells, and (b) interfere with their complete degradation culminating in the formation of UB-associated AA found in the EL. Non-covalent linkage of UB has been shown to induce structural alterations in other substrate proteins rendering them susceptible to phagocytosis.</description><creator>Chan, Sic L.</creator><contributor>Ali-Khan, Z. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Lysosome-related generation of potentially amyloidogenic serum amyloid A polypeptides in activated murine macrophages and the potential role of ubiquitin in this process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx19f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc22b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc893</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In searching for genetically-programmed responses to arsenic oxyanion exposure in plasmid-free bacterial strains, an arsenate-inducible Escherichia coli chromosomal operon was identified using a Mud I (lac Apr) transposable bacteriophage. The operon is induced by cellular exposure to arsenic and antimony oxyanions. The operon contains three cistrons that are homologous to the arsR , arsB, and arsC genes of plasmid-borne ars operons, coding for an arsenite/antimonite-inducible repressor, an inner membrane arsenite transporter, and an arsenate reductase, respectively. The E. coli chromosomal ars operon is functional in protection against arsenic toxicity, as mutants of this operon are hypersensitive to arsenic. To elucidate regulation of ars operon expression, two luciferase gene fusions, arsR::luxAB and arsB::luxAB , were constructed and analysed. The E. coli chromosomal ars operon was demonstrated to be regulated by the trans -acting repressor, ArsR, in a manner similar to that of the plasmid R773 ars operon. The operon is transcribed as a single transcription unit, and regulated by arsenic mainly though not exclusively, at the mRNA level. The individual gene products of the operon were visualized in both in vivo and in vitro expression systems. The chromosomal ars operon is conserved in the chromosomes of a number of Gram-negative bacterial species. To monitor the toxicity and bioavailability of arsenic compounds, the potential of the E. coli arsB::luxAB fusion strain as a bacterial biosensor has been evaluated. This luciferase gene fusion strain was shown to selectively detect the presence of arsenic in a mixed wood preservative, chromated copper arsenate (CCA). To further elucidate the evolutionary relationship of chromosomal ars operons between different bacterial species, a Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1 chromosomal ars operon homolog was cloned and found to confer resistance to arsenite and antimonite, and to a lesser extent, to arsenate, in an E. coli ars -- mutant strain. Three cistrons were identified that share homology with the arsR, arsB, and arsC genes of other known ars operons. Expression of the P. aeruginosa ars operon is induced by arsenite as shown by RNA dot blots. Homologous sequences of this operon, have also been detected in other strains and species of the genus Pseudomonas.</description><creator>Cai, Jie.</creator><contributor>DuBow, Michael S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Identification and characterization of a chromosomal arsenicantimony inducible operon in gram-negative bacteria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh764.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc893</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526f03m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the fundamental relationship between a continuous-time system and its discrete-time models. This involves a study of the conditions that the state space realization of a model must satisfy in order to be valid. While such a study has been performed for models whose order equals that of the continuous-time system, this thesis also includes "higher order discrete-time models", that is, models whose order is higher than the continuous-time system. A strict mathematical definition for models is presented based upon the convergence in a certain sense of the time responses of the continuous-time system and its model. Theorems are also presented which can be used to prove the validity of models, and shown are that many common discretization techniques, such as mapping models and hold equivalent models, are valid. Using these theorems some of these discretization techniques can be generalized. However, the aim of this thesis is not to prove the validity of common discretization techniques, but to understand the conditions which a model must satisfy in order to be valid. Common discretization techniques simply provide convenient examples for this understanding. The definition of models is later expanded to consider discrete-time time-varying and multi-rate system. It is with multi-rate systems that the importance of higher order models becomes particularly apparent. Depending on the particular ratio of sampling rates between the plant input and output, some multi-rate systems must include inherently discrete-time operations, resulting in a higher order, for these systems to be considered valid. Also shown is that it is possible for a discrete-time periodically-time-varying system to model a time-invariant continuous-time system. Finally, using the developed model concept, the practical problem of the multi-rate implementation of an analogue control system is considered. The method presented is an extension of the plant input mapping method which is the only method capable of guaranteeing the stability of the digital closed-loop system provided the sampling period is nonpathological. Simulation examples illustrate the effectiveness of the proposed methods, even for very slow sampling periods.</description><creator>Comeau, A. Raymond (André Raymond)</creator><contributor>Hori, Noriyuki (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, System Science.</subject><title>Higher order discrete-time models with applications to multi-rate control</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs150.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526f03m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n038r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis concerns parallel, platform mechanisms, consisting of two distal links that are connected to each other by a set of open kinematic chains, called legs. Particularly, mechanisms with redundant loops, kinematically quite challenging, are investigated. Existing methods of analysis and their shortcomings are outlined and alternatives which help to overcome them are developed. Definitions and analyses of platform mechanisms, mobility and degree-of-freedom are reviewed. Kinematic analysis and workspace determination of platform mechanisms are thoroughly investigated. An algebraic method, based on the functional matrix of mechanisms, as defined by Freudenstein, is applied to determine their degree of freedom (DOF). It is shown with examples that this method unambiguously yields the DOF for mechanisms where other methods fail. The effects of extra legs, and hence, redundant loops, are discussed. The statics, differential and positional kinematics of these mechanisms are investigated. Kinematic-mapping techniques are used to analyze the constraints applied by individual legs to the platform. Current methods of workspace analysis of platform mechanisms are reviewed. A novel technique, which contains both position and orientation information, is introduced. It is shown that this method successfully treats platform mechanisms, with or without redundant loops. However, it may be computationally expensive for some mechanisms, such as spherical wrist mechanisms. An alternative technique, based on the Euler-Rodrigues parameters of a rotation, is also introduced for spherical mechanisms, of both serial and platform types. The features of some of the methods introduced here are applied to a novel mechanism introduced elsewhere, namely, the double-tetrahedral mechanism (DTM), which it is a paradigm of closed-loop mechanisms with redundant loops.</description><creator>Bulca, Ferhan.</creator><contributor>Angeles, Jorge (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Zsombor-Murray, Paul J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>The kinematics and workspace analysis of platform mechanisms /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd457.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n038r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sc01b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>General methodologies are elaborated for the modification of residual vinyl groups resulting from the polymerization of technical grade divinylbenzene to obtain polymer supported reagents, catalysts, protecting groups, separation media and chemosensors. These residual vinyl groups undergo anti-Markovnikov addition reactions via free-radical mechanisms to give polymer supported halides, sulfides, phosphines, phophonates, amines, silanes, carboxylic acid derivatives such as amides, amidines, esters and also b -diketones, crown ethers or acetals. Reaction of these pendant styryl units via electrophilic or nucleophilc mechanisms also give useful polymeric products. Diels-Alder reactions of the pendant styryl units are also investigated, showing that these may react as dienophiles or, with the participation of the aromatic group, as a diene. Thus, one mole of diene such as hexachlorocyclopentadiene or 3,6-dipyridyl-1,2,4,5 tetrazine add per mole of alkene, or two moles of dienophile such as maleic acid derivatives add in a fashion analogous to the Wagner-Jauregg reaction. Transition metal catalysed hydrosilylation of the substrate (vinyl)polystyrene using Co2(CO)8 gives exclusively dimethylene linked polymer supported dialkylchlorosilanes. These may be used to selectively protect primary hydroxyls in the presence of secondary or tertiary hydroxyls. Cleavage of the silyl ethers can be effected with aqueous acid, base or more conveniently with fluoride ions which then could be regenerated back to the polymeric silylchlorides using BCl3/CH2Cl2. Resins bearing amino acid functionalities, obtained by free-radical addition of cysteine, may be converted to polymer supported azlactones which smoothly immobilize enzymes such as lipase, and retain their hydrolytic activity. Functional polymer particles of nanometer dimensions bearing fluorescent molecular imprinted sites are obtained using a core-shell polymerization approach in conjunction with technique described above. The resulting clear particle dispersions show some ability to distinguish between molecules and even between enantiomers through weak interactions, as shown by fluorescence spectroscopy. Small molecule fluorescent probes based on dimethylaminostyrylpyridinium salts are demonstrated to be useful fluorescent probes due to their great sensitivity to solution microviscosity. Caged derivatives are applied in microbial and cell cultures.</description><creator>Stranix, Brent R.</creator><contributor>Chin, B. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Darling, G. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Functional polymers from (vinyl)polystyrene : solid-phase reagents, catalysts, supports and fluorescent sensors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn06p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc01b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b055d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research investigated children's awareness of the shared constituent feature of relative clause sentences prior to mastery of the grammatical structure. Performance predictions based on linguistic and cognitive-pragmatic language acquisition theories were evaluated. Three experiments were conducted to explore comprehension strategies used by normally developing, preschool-aged children (ND), and by children who vary in the cognitive or pragmatic abilities: children with intellectual impairment (II), and children with severe speech and physical impairment (SSPI). Comprehension of one type of relative clause structure, the subject relative, was targeted using a picture-choice task. The task was designed so that response patterns consistent with use of one of three strategies could be identified. Use of the Participant strategy was interpreted as evidence of awareness of the shared constituent feature, consistent with linguistic theory predictions. Use of the Agent or Patient strategies suggested no awareness of the shared constituent feature, consistent with cognitive-pragmatic theory predictions. The performance of the ND subjects in Experiment One was best predicted by the Participant strategy. A relationship was observed between use of this strategy and subject age. The II subjects in Experiment Two and the SSPI subjects in Experiment Three primarily demonstrated response patterns similar to those of the ND subjects, although the Agent strategy was used by a minority of subjects. Different associations between strategy use and language growth were suggested by the data for the two impaired populations. The findings of the three experiments are most consistent with linguistic theory predictions that children are aware of the shared constituent feature prior to mastery of relative clause structures, and that similar comprehension strategies are used by children who differ in cognitive-pragmatic abilities. The results suggest that the development of relative clause comprehension differs from the views expressed in the literature to date, and may be at least a two step process. The relationship of strategy use and the language growth suggested by these studies warrants further investigation.</description><creator>Sutton, Ann Elizabeth Colquhoun.</creator><contributor>Gallagher, Tanya (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Psychology, Cognitive.</subject><subject>Psychology, Developmental.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology.</subject><subject>Language, Linguistics.</subject><title>Children's comprehension performance prior to mastery of relative clauses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p6470.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b055d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz40q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oncogenically transnformed mammalian cells irrespective of their origin synthesize and secrete osteopontin (OPN), a sialic acid rich, adhesive, phosphoglycoprotein, not only in excessive amounts but also in different molecular forms, as compared to their non-transformed counterparts. It has been postulated that OPN has important functional roles in oncogenesis, but its mechanism of action remains obscure. In the present study this question was addressed by using Rat-1 cells transformed by a temperature-sensitive mutant of Rous sarcoma virus (tsB77 cells) which secrete two discrete molecular forms of OPN, a 69-kDa OPN at the non-permissive temperature (41°C and a 62-kDa form at the permissive temperature (34°C). Investigations were aimed to determine how the two isoforms of OPN secreted by transformed and non-transformed cells originate, whether the two forms have different functional properties, and the effects of specific inhibition of OPN synthesis on the transformed state of the cells. The latter was achieved by transfecting tsB77 cells with antisense OPN cDNA at the permissive temperature. Immunoprecipitation, V8 protease mapping, tryptic peptide analysis, and thrombin digestion confirmed that 62-kDa and 69-kDa proteins are two isoforms of OPN. It was also observed that tsB77 cells at both temperatures transcribe a single 1.6 kb OPN mRNA and contain only the 69-kDa OPN intracellularly, suggesting that 69-kDa OPN is modified to its 62-kDa form prior to or immediately after secretion by cells at 34ºC. Proteolytic cleavage, differential phosphorylation, or lack of N- or O-linked carbohydrates as the possible mechanism for the generation of 62-kDa OPN were ruled out, but it was observed that 62-kDa OPN contains significantly reduced levels of sialic acid residues, as compared to its 69-kDa form. The binding assays using 32P-labeled OPN revealed that only the 69-kDa OPN, not its 62-kDa form, undergoes receptor-mediated localization on the cell surface,</description><creator>Shanmugam, Vijayalakshmi.</creator><contributor>Mukherjee, Barid B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Phosphoproteins -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Osteopontin</subject><subject>Cell transformation.</subject><title>Characterization of osteopontin in RSV transformed rat-1 cells and its role in cell transformation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784n46x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz40q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161801x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The enzyme mechanism, nucleotide interactions and active site residues in the Vibrio harveyi aldehyde dehydrogenase (Vh.ALDH) have been examined. The Vh.ALDH gene encodes a polypeptide of 510 amino acids with molecular mass of 54 kDa. The recombinant Vh.ALDH was purified in a single step using 2', 5' ADP Sepharose affinity chromatography. It was shown that NAD+ and NADP+ bound to the same site and that saturation of Vh.ALDH with NADP+ occurred with a Michaelis constant (Km) of 1.4 m M with dodecanal. The specificity for aldehydes of longer chain length was shown to be reflected in a decrease in (Km). The identification of a catalytic conserved cysteine in Vh.ALDH (Cys289) indicated that a highly related mechanism and structure have been retained among ALDHs. Two glutamic acid residues, Glu253 and Glu377, which are highly conserved in ALDHs, were investigated by site directed mutagenesis. It was shown that Glu253 is involved in the acylation step possibly assisting in the deprotonation of the was found to be involved in a cysteine nucleophile. Glu377 step affecting hydride transfer. Glycine 229 was found to be critical for dinucleotide binding and ALDH function, perhaps through interaction with the 2',5 ' ADP part of NAD(P)+. Glycine 234 on the other hand was not critical in ALDH activity and dinucleotide binding. It was also shown that Vh.ALDH does not have a classical nucleotide binding domain found in most dehydrogenases.</description><creator>Vedadi, Masoud.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Structural and functional studies of fatty aldehyde dehydrogenase from the bioluminescent bacterium, Vibrio harveyi</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x47x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161801x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gj10r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to identify a homologue of the cell division cycle regulatory kinase P34cdc2 that may function in the nervous system, a mouse brain cDNA library was screened at low stringency using a cdc2 cDNA probe. A 2.5 kb cDNA was isolated that contains a 423-amino acid open reading frame encoding a novel cdc2-related protein kinase that was named PFTAIRE, because of the consensus PSTAIRE-like motif (single letter amino acid code) characteristic of cdc2 kinase family. The novel PFTAIRE is most homologous to the PCTAIRE class of cdc2-related kinases because of similar N- and C-terminal extensions lacking in many other cdc2-related kinases. Restriction fragment length polymorphisms were used to determine that the PFTAIRE gene (Pftk1) is positioned close to the centromere of mouse chromosome 5, proximal to the cdk5 gene. PFTAIRE cDNA probes hybridize to a single mRNA transcript of approximately 6.0 kb, which is expressed predominantly in the nervous tissue of postnatal and adult mice. I have demonstrated by in situ hybridization and by indirect immunofluorescence that several discrete populations of terminally differentiated neurons and some glia express PFTAIRE mRNA and protein. In neurons, the PFTAIRE protein is localized primarily in the nucleus and cytoplasm of coli bodies but some populations of neurons also contain PFTAIRE in axons. The anatomical, cellular and ontogenic patterns of PFTAIRE expression in the nervous system differ from those of p34cdc2 and cdk5 PFTAIRE may be the first member of the cdc2 kinase family identified to date that is so specifically localized to the mammalian nervous system. When, immunoprecipitated from cytosolic protein preparations of adult mouse brain and transfected cells, PFTAIRE forms a complex with proteins of approximately 58--60 kDa that were specifically co-precipitated. These proteins also appear to be major endogenous targets of this kinase activity. The phosphorylation of these proteins was reduced in the presence of a PFTAIRE dominant negative mutant, generated by site-directed mutagenesis of a residue required for the phosphate transfer reaction. The biochemical characterization of PFTAIRE has also revealed that PFTAIRE itself is phosphorylated by a protein kinase in brain extract and that PFTAIRE may also autophosphorylate. To address the possible function of PFTAIRE, PFTAIRE plasmids were transfected transiently in several proliferating fibroblast cell lines that expressed little or no endogenous PFTAIRE protein. Low transfection efficiencies and decreased cell viability were consistently observed. Cells overexpressing PFTAIRE showed morphological changes including decreased call size, irregularly shaped nuclei, multiple or fragmented nucleoli and changes in the distribution of nuclear lamin proteins resembling that of cells arrested in the early G 1 phase of the cell cycle or cells undergoing apoptotic death. These results suggest that inappropriate expression of PFTAIRE may interfere with cell cycle progression. Thus the function of PFTAIRE in postmitotic neurons may be related to specialized properties acquired by cells that no longer progress through the cell cycle. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lazzaro-Albert, Maribeth A.</creator><contributor>Julien, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of a novel cdc2-related kinase expressed in the nervous system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f564.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj10r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qn789</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of agricultural chemicals often results in water pollution. This research, comprising three parts, was designed to investigate the role of soil and grass strips and water table management in reducing pesticide and nitrate residues in drainage waters. The first part of the research was made on lysimeters to investigate the effects of soil and grass cover under two water table management regimes. Four treatments were involved: subsurface drainage, controlled drainage, grass cover, and bare soil. Each treatment consisted of three replicates. Contaminated water containing atrazine, metolachlor, and metribuzin residues was applied to the lysimeters and samples of drain effluent were collected. Significant reductions in pesticide concentrations were found in all treatments. In the first year (1993), herbicide levels were reduced significantly, from an average of 250 mug/L to less than 10 mug/L. In the second year (1995), water polluted at a concentration of 50 mug/L, was applied to the lysimeters, and herbicide residues were reduced significantly to less than 1 mug/L. Subsurface drainage and grass cover lysimeters (SDG treatment) reduced herbicide concentration levels to a greater extent than the other treatments and the controlled drainage lysimeters reduced nitrate concentration levels to a greater extent than the free drainage lysimeters. The second part of the research was a field study that reports the development and testing of an on-farm pollution control system using soil as a biological filter for trapping herbicide residues. A field site with four shallow surface ditches, underlain with four perforated drain pipes, was used to carry-out field measurements. Polluted water with concentration levels of 30 mg/L of nitrate and 100 mug/L of three commonly-used herbicides was applied to the ditches for 10 days continuously; and no water was applied for the following ten days. This cycle was repeated three times. Water samples were collected both before application and after the water came out of the drains. Herbicide levels were reduced significantly in drainage waters. The average concentration level of nitrate in drainage water was found to be 17 mg/L in comparison to 30 mg/L in applied water. Also, the bio-degradation of herbicide residues in the soil was found to occur between water applications. Thus, it appears that the system would be self-sustainable in the long term. The third part of the research utilizes a water table model, DRAINMOD, for simulating drainage waters from agricultural land and a solute transport model, PRZM2, for simulating pesticide concentrations in the drain effluent coming out of the grass filter area. DRAINMOD was used to estimate the daily drain outflows that would occur in a 100 ha subsurface drained field in the for a 1-in-20 year annual rainfall period. It was found that 6% of the farm area could be used to bring down the concentrations in drainage water from 50 mug/L to less than 1 mug/L for the three herbicides. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Liaghat, Abdolmajid.</creator><contributor>Prasher, S. O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Nitrates -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Drainage.</subject><subject>Water -- Pollution.</subject><subject>Pesticides -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>Use of soil and vegetative filter strips for reducing pesticide and nitrate pollution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs17j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn789</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903165q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Progressive myoclonus epilepsy type 1 (EPM1), also known as Unverricht-Lundborg disease, is one of the rare forms of epilepsy that shows a clear pattern of autosomal recessive inheritance. The gene defective in this disease was linked to the distal tip of chromosome 21, in band q22.3. In this study, we have collected 93 samples from 15 EPM1 families and 5 affected individuals as the basis for identifying the EPM1 gene. We have also constructed a 770 kb cosmid and bacterial artificial chromosome contig covering the candidate EPM1 region, and have isolated expressed sequences from this contig. For three of the genes that we isolated (GT335, GT334, and PWP2), we have identified and sequenced a full-length cDNA, identified the putative protein, assessed the expression pattern of the gene by Northern blot, determined the exon/intron structure of the gene, characterized basepair polymorphisms within each gene, and finally excluded each of these genes as the one defective in EPM1 patients. Using these new polymorphisms, and others that were available and that we had identified, we were able to construct detailed haplotypes on each of the affected EPM1 chromosomes, to help pinpoint, the location of the EPM1 gene, and help estimate the number of different mutations we might have in our collection. While these studies were underway, another group identified the cystatin B (STFB) gene as that defective in EPM1. This allowed us to directly test this gene for mutations in our collection of EPM1 patients. We could identify four different mutations in the STFB gene, the most common of which consisted of a variable length insertion in the 5 ' flanking region of the gene, and which was previously undescribed. This mutation, which is found in 78% of unrelated EPM1 chromosomes we studied, showed some level of meiotic instability, and mapped to a polymorphic 12-bp GC-rich repeat. Using a combination of PCR and Southern blotting assays, we could accurately diagnose nearly 100% of all EPM1 patients. This represents a significant step forward in our ability to diagnose this disease at the molecular level, and should allow a more precise definition of the progressive myoclonus epilepsies, as a whole.</description><creator>Lafrenière, Ronald G.</creator><contributor>Rouleau, G. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Myoclonus -- Molecular aspects.</subject><subject>Myoclonus -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Molecular and genetic studies of progressive myoclonus epilepsy type 1 (EPM1)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg797.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903165q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk55v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Amyloid deposition in cortical plaques and around cerebral vessels is a hallmark of Alzheimer's disease (AD). Amyloid also accumulates, to a lesser degree, in some nondemented elderly individuals, in the cerebral cortex and in the choroid plexus (CP), a tissue in the cerebral ventricles which produces cerebrospinal fluid (CSF). The cortical amyloid is composed mainly of aggregates of a neurotoxic peptide called amyloid-beta (Abeta), of which there are two main variants, Abeta42 and Abeta40, but the composition of CP amyloid has not been determined, nor is it known if there is a relationship between amyloid deposition in these two locations. This thesis characterizes amyloid deposition in the CP and cortex of normal individuals, and investigates the effects of aging and Abeta on the levels of proteins that may modulate Abeta neurotoxicity and amyloid formation in these locations. Immunohistochemistry identified Abeta and its associated proteins, apolipoprotein (apo) E, apoJ and transthyretin in the CP of normal and AD subjects. However, Western blot analysis revealed that apoE, not Abeta, is the major protein component of the CP amyloid. Soluble forms of Abeta and apoE were identified in the CP and CSF. The concentrations of Abeta42, apoE and transthyretin in the CSF remained constant with age, indicating that the reduced levels of these proteins reported in the CSF of AD patients is not age-related. In addition, we found that the levels of Abeta40 declined, suggesting a change in metabolism of the Abeta precursor with age. In the cerebral cortex, the ratio of Abeta42- to Abeta40-positive plaques remained constant with age at 2.6, but was reduced to 1.6 in AD brains. ApoE, apoJ and transthyretin were present in a small minority of plaques in normal and AD brains, indicating that these proteins do not play a central role in modulating Abeta neurotoxicity in plaques. However, apoE was strongly associated with cerebrovascular amyloid in normal individuals, while Abet</description><creator>Kunicki, Suzanne.</creator><contributor>Zorychta, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>The effect of age on the accumulation of amyloidogenic peptides in the human brain and cerebrospinal fluid /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074x00v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk55v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jg611</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although the letter purports to represent fact, it cannot avoid having a partly or potentially fictive status, turning as it does on the complex interplay between the real and the imagined. Consequently, the main critical approach of this paper is to consider the interactions between conflicting modes of expression in eighteenth- and nineteenth-century epistolary fiction. The rhetorical and conceptual contrarieties that I examine are broadly characterized by the contradiction between the implied spontaneity of the familiar letter and the inevitable artifice of its form. Working with familiar letters by four writers between the years 1740 and 1825, I specifically address various narrative patterns by which each turns to the act of communication to draw upon the experience of an isolated self. Against a background which explores the main developments in epistolary fiction and a historical progression of the uses and significance of letter-writing, I investigate epistolary texts by Lady Mary Wortley Montagu, Lord Byron, John Keats, and William Hazlitt. In turning to letters by each author, I explore the literary, theoretical and especially the psychological implications of the tenuous divisions between fact and fiction. In particular, my analysis stresses that letter-writing is an authorial act in which writing about the self can be understood as a literary form of self-portraiture or creative expression. I examine this claim---and the metaphors defining it---in two ways. First, by focusing on selected letters, I foreground each writer's language as an agent of internal conflict. In so doing, I am able to formulate distinctive questions regarding the potential of epistolary narratives to transform emotional or psychological schisms into fictions which become explicitly creative texts. Secondly, I analyze the changing nature of the fictions which emerge through this process. My findings conclude that authors' letters must be read, at least very often, as a constituent part of their literary work and as interpretive models of a shifting dynamic of psychological expression.</description><creator>Shannon, Josephine E.</creator><contributor>Hensley, David C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>English literature -- 19th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>English literature -- 18th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Epistolary fiction -- History and criticism.</subject><title>From discourse to the couch : the obscured self in eighteenth- and nineteenth-century epistolary narrative</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w788.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jg611</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp796</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Because of the centrality of Christ, truly God and truly human, Christian theology regards the understanding of the human as one of its essential tasks. In the wake of environmental concerns, however, the dominant self-understanding of the human is presently being challenged and rethought by Christians. This study is an attempt to contribute to this larger effort of examining the role of the human in Christian theological responses to the ecological "crisis," a question that is surfacing as a paramount concern in this emergent literature. In this work I examine how the role of the human is an inherent problematic in Christian ecological literature. I review some of the principal categories or paradigms of Christian ecological literature, such as Gaia theory, process theology, new cosmology, ecofeminism, and liberation theology. All these approaches, I contend, make important contributions to a renewed understanding of human interaction with nature. Yet each model, on its own, seems somewhat incomplete in its portrait of the human. On the one hand, a certain segment of this religious and theological literature diminishes or undervalues the role of the human in our ecological destiny. On the other hand, much of this literature neglects to examine seriously humanity's historical context, which includes economic, political, and social dimensions. Through a study of these paradigms for approaching the environmental crisis, this work explores the idea that only a theology that views the human agent as a principal actor in both the devastation and reclamation of the life systems of the planet is a viable ecological theology. Such a theology views the human agent in terms of social, economic, political, cultural, moral, as well as ecological transformation in order to confront comprehensively the threats to the planet's ecosystems. With the reading assistance of liberation theology from Latin America, with its emphasis on solidarity, a preferential option for the destitute, and societal transformation, this work raises the possibility of a political theology of the environment, outlining several salient horizons for such a theology.</description><creator>Scharper, Stephen B.</creator><contributor>Baum, Gregory (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Theological anthropology -- Christianity -- History of doctrines -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Human ecology -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.</subject><title>The role of the human in Christian ecological literature /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r42j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp796</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp78x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to examine the anti-Semitic propaganda of Social Credit movement in the 1930s and 1940s and its impact on organized Canadian Jewry. During World War Two, the Alberta Social Credit government and its provincial land national parties engaged in the dissemination of anti-Semitic propaganda, which greatly concerned the Canadian Jewish Congress, the national representative organization for Canadian Jewry. The Canadian Jewish Congress responded by attempting to confront and end this propaganda; however, it lacked a public relations philosophy effective and assertive enough to do so. Eventually the Social Credit movement realized the political liabilities of engaging in anti-Semitic propaganda; yet despite Congress's years of efforts, it could take little credit for Social Credit's purge of anti-Semitism. An examination of the relationship between the Canadian Jewish Congress and the Social Credit movement adds a new perspective on the history of both organizations, and reveals much about ethnic organization in Canada and the nation's political culture of intolerance. The sources for this thesis come from the Canadian Jewish Congress National Archives in Montreal, the National Archives of Canada in Ottawa, the Provincial Archives of Manitoba in Winnipeg, the Glenbow Archives-Institute in Calgary, and the Provincial Archives of Alberta in Edmonton. The Canadian Social Crediter, Vers Demain, and other Canadian newspapers were used extensively. The sources on the Social Credit movement held at the Canadian Jewish Congress National Archives have not been used before, which makes this thesis a significant departure from previous works.</description><creator>Stingel, Janine.</creator><contributor>Zucchi, Juhn (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Alberta Social Credit Party.</subject><subject>Antisemitism -- Alberta.</subject><subject>Social credit -- Alberta.</subject><subject>Canadian Jewish Congress.</subject><title>Social Credit and the Jews : anti-Semitism in the Alberta Social Credit movement and the response of the Canadian Jewish Congress, 1935-1949</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d170m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp78x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx15k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Crying Wave is a twenty minute music composition for an amplified ensemble of fifteen instruments combined with a prerecorded electroacoustic audio component and live signal processing. The composition explores the use of fundamental electroacoustic music techniques such as additive, subtractive, and granular synthesis as models for the creation and manipulation of materials and structure in both the instrumental and electroacoustic aspects of the work. Two series of harmonies underlie the piece and serve as both harmonic and melodic resources. Procedures including additive/subtractive durations, palindrome and canon, the Fibonacci series, and antiphonal alternation of instrumental groups are used throughout the composition to provide structural coherence. The MIDI data processing software Max is employed to control a number of aspects of the work during performance, including playback of prerecorded electroacoustic audio segments on compact disc, changes of effects algorithms for digital signal processing modules, and the generation of a click track for synchronization. The following dissertation presents an analysis of the work in terms of the aforementioned concepts and techniques.</description><creator>Radford, Laurie, 1958-</creator><contributor>Rea, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Electronic music.</subject><subject>Computer music.</subject><subject>Instrumental ensembles -- Scores.</subject><title>The crying wave : (1996)</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw21m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx15k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n967x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We examined the hypothesis that maturation ameloblasts degrade enamel matrix in a manner analogous to bone matrix degradation mediated by osteoclasts. Thus, we assessed the distribution of the cation-independent mannose 6-phosphate receptor (MRP) and lysosomal enzymes in the enamel organ and in the alveolar bone surrounding the rat incisor. The MPR was observed on the ruffled border of the ruffle-ended ameloblast (RA) but not on the distal call membrane of the smooth-ended ameloblast (SA), although both cells demonstrated strong immunoreactivity in the Golgi region. Immunogold localization of cathepsin B showed more labelling on the distal end of RA than SA, indicating that the source of the extracellular cathepsin B was likely the RA. Since MPR and lysosomal enzymes were also detected on the ruffled border of osteoclasts, our immunocytochemical approach provides strong evidence for a similarity between the maturation of enamel, as mediated by RAs, and bone matrix degradation by osteoclasts. We also examined the nature of the basement membrane-like structure between maturation ameloblasts and the surface of enamel, and the possible role it may play in the maturation of enamel. We used high resolution electron microscopy combined with immunohistochemical localization of laminin, heparan sulfate proteoglycan (HSPG) and type IV collagen. Our results indicated that this structure was a highly specialized basement membrane unusually rich in HSPG. The cord network was replaced by a network of fine filaments, identified as core filaments of cords containing type IV collagen. A proposed role for this basement membrane is likely to be mediation of firm attachment of maturation ameloblasts to the surface of the enamel. Since integrins play an essential role in cell-substratum interactions, we investigated the distribution of the integrin beta1 subunit on osteoclasts and ameloblasts. Immunocytochemistry showed significant concentrations of beta1 integrin at the ruffled border of osteoclasts, and negligible staining at the sealing zone. Since beta1 integrin localization was higher in the RA than the SA, we suggest that beta1 may have a role in the cell modulations. This role is likely to be recognition of extracellular matrix components and consequent interaction of RA with that matrix. The findings that the ruffled border of both RAs and osteoclasts display the most intense labelling for beta1 integrin, further supports our hypothesis that these cells are functionally similar.</description><creator>Al Kawas, Sausan.</creator><contributor>Warshawsky, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>A comparative study of maturation processes in enamel and bone in the rat /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj546.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n967x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bg800</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aims of the present studies were to determine the magnitude of iron deficiency anemia among preschool children in Northern Ethiopia and to evaluate different control strategies. The cross-sectional study showed that anemia was highly prevalent (42%) and that iron deficiency was the commonest cause of anemia. However, the iron deficiency was not due to lack of iron in the diet but to its poor availability and to other non-dietary risk factors. Unsafe water, mother's illness, older child (24--60 months), family not having food reserves and family income below poverty-line were predictors of anemia. Hookworm and malaria were rare and did not account for the anemia. In the iron pot study three types of Ethiopian foods were cooked in three types of pots (iron, aluminum and clay) and assessed for their total and available iron. After adjusting for cooking time and moisture, there were significantly higher total and available iron in all the three types of foods when cooked in iron pots compared to the aluminum or clay pots. The study also showed that the hemoglobin status and length of children improved significantly when they consumed food cooked in iron pots. In the third study, a randomized, placebo-controlled, and double-blind trial, both iron and vitamin A supplemented children showed increased hemoglobin levels. Combined iron and vitamin A supplementation showed the highest rise. Iron-supplemented children showed increase in length, but no increase in weight. They also showed lower rates of c-reactive protein positivity and decreases in the prevalence and frequency of diarrhea. A single dose of vitamin A did not result in any increase in length or weight but a decrease in the prevalence and frequency of diarrhea was observed. Children supplemented with iron only or vitamin A only showed higher ARI rates, but those children who received combined iron and vitamin A showed significantly lower ARI rates. Iron supplementation did not have any effect on either zinc</description><creator>Adish, Abdulaziz A.</creator><contributor>Johns, Timothy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Iron deficiency diseases in children -- Ethiopia.</subject><subject>Iron deficiency diseases in infants -- Ethiopia.</subject><subject>Iron deficiency anemia in children -- Ethiopia.</subject><title>Risk factors and an assessment of control strategies for iron deficiency anemia in children in northern Ethiopia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666632f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg800</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g10w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fullerenes, the family of large, all-carbon, cage-like molecules, promise to launch an array of new products. However, the development of such products is hindered due to unavailability of large quantities of fullerenes and the present high cost of production. Fullerenes are produced commercially via the arc vaporization of graphite, a method which is limited to low production rates and low scale-up potential. In this work, a new process was developed in which fullerenes are produced via the thermal plasma dissociation of hydrocarbons. The process is attractive due to its potential for large scale fullerene production. Tetrachloroethylene (C2Cl4) was selected as the carbon source for fullerene synthesis, due to the instability of C-Cl bonds in the high temperature zone predicted for fullerene formation. The effect of input electrical power, C2Cl4 feed rate and reactor pressure on fullerene formation and collection was studied. The temperature profile and its effect on the residence time of reactive species in the temperature zone required for fullerene formation was found to play a critical role in the production of fullerenes. With the present reactor configuration, an input power in excess of 55 kW was required for the treatment of up to 0.54 mol/min of C2Cl4. High C2Cl 4 feed rates resulted in a lower conversion of C2Cl 4 to fullerenes. Lower reactor pressures (200 and 300 torr) resulted in higher fullerene yields as compared to results obtained at 400 torr. The maximum concentration of fullerenes in soot was 5.3% and the maximum conversion of C2Cl4 to fullerenes was 2.8%, based on carbon input. Fullerenes produced by the process were purified using conventional extractive and chromatographic techniques. Although successful, purification by chromatography proved to be difficult due to the presence of perchlorinated, aromatic by-products. Some of these perchlorinated aromatic by-products were identified and were found to have structures reminiscent of fullerene precursors, and thus, may provide clues as to how fullerenes form in this plasma process.</description><creator>Alexakis, Theodora.</creator><contributor>Meunier, J. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Tsantrizos, Peter G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The production of fullernes via the thermal plasma dissociation of C2Cl4 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px76q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g10w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nn10h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Psychological stress may be a risk factor for essential hypertension. While several variables have been implicated as mediators or moderators of the relationship between stress and high blood pressure, their exact roles and level of importance remain to be elucidated. A key moderating variable may be family history of hypertension. A series of five studies examined the cardiovascular and emotional reactions to stress of normotensive individuals with and without a parental history of hypertension. In an attempt to facilitate the generalizability of the results, the studies used stressors with greater ecological validity than those used in most previous studies of this topic. This aspect of the research aided the examination of a possible mediator of group differences in cardiovascular reactivity, i.e., emotionality. Several studies observed significant group differences in cardiovascular reactivity to stress, suggesting that stress may be more likely to contribute to the development of hypertension in those with a genetic predisposition for the disorder. However, the exaggerated cardiovascular responsivity of individuals with a parental history of hypertension did not appear to be mediated by greater trait or state emotionality.</description><creator>Adler, Perry S. J.</creator><contributor>Ditto, Blaine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Stress (Psychology) -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Hypertension -- Risk factors.</subject><title>Cardiovascular and emotional reactivity to stress in offspring of hypertensives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f5290.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn10h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h6314</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study involves an examination of Anglo-American relations between the years 1933 and 1938 through the policies of U.S. Secretary of State, Cordell Hull, and British Foreign Secretary, Anthony Eden. It is based on the thesis that both of these foreign ministers believed strongly in the need to establish a "special relationship" between Great Britain and the United States as a means to counter the growing world economic and political crisis that developed during the 1930s, but that in spite of these sentiments, they failed in this effort. This work explores the reasons for this failure. The study begins by noting the widespread expectation, following the 1932 election of Franklin D. Roosevelt, that the onset of a new American Administration under the leadership of Roosevelt and Hull would lead to closer transatlantic ties. It then goes on to explore Eden and Hull's efforts to establish a new economic and security relationship between the two powers through the workings of the World Economic Conference, the Geneva Disarmament Talks, the London Naval Conference, and the negotiation of an Anglo-American trade agreement. It then traces Eden and Hull's reaction to the outbreak of hostilities in Abyssinia, Spain and China, and notes how the increasing likelihood of a world war led to an intensification of their efforts to find a vehicle of cooperation. The work then closes by examining the circumstances which led to Eden's resignation, and the successful negotiation of the Anglo-American Trade Agreement. In the latter case, however, it is argued that the trade agreement had little effect on the behavior of the fascist states, and hence proved ineffective as a means to stop the drift towards war. The study then concludes by reiterating the argument that both men shared in the belief that it was in their respective country's best interests to pursue closer transatlantic ties. It also concludes that they each carried certain idealistic notions about the benefits which might accrue from such a pursuit, as each felt that even the mere appearance of Anglo-American solidarity would give serious pause to the dictators and thus further advance the cause of peace. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Woolner, David B.</creator><contributor>McKercher, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.</subject><subject>United States -- Foreign relations -- Great Britain.</subject><subject>Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon, 1897-</subject><subject>Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- United States.</subject><title>The frustrated idealists: Cordell Hull, Anthony Eden and the search for Anglo-American cooperation, 1933-1938 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d171w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h6314</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34775</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>