<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:23:44Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33700" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q25v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis seeks to determine the nature and character of Canada's foreign policy towards Vietnam. Dependent upon Southeast Asian stability for strategic resources, a merchandise surplus and the expansion of the American economy, Canada also benefitted directly through increased exports of staple goods, automotive parts and war material. Ottawa's record on the International Control Commissions was characterized by partisan voting, complicity in the violation of the Geneva and Paris Agreements and the rationalization of Washington's strategy. Canadian aid, dispensed only to Saigon, was a co-ordinated part of American pacification programs. The purpose of Ottawa's policy was to ensure the permanent division of Vietnam while the ultimate intention and consequence was to legitimate the U.S. intervention. Underlying Ottawa's decision-making was Canada's integration into the world market system and the unequal, albeit voluntary, alliance between the economic elites of Canada and the United States.</description><creator>Levant, Victor</creator><contributor>Noumoff, Sam (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1981</date><subject>Canada -- Politics and government -- 1945-1980</subject><subject>Canada -- Foreign relations -- Vietnam</subject><subject>Vietnam -- Foreign relations -- Canada</subject><title>The political economy of Canadian foreign policy in Vietnam</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t7932.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q25v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73px63n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les premiers romans étaient des romans d'aventures. L'Iliade est un roman d'aventures guerrières et l'Odyssée est un roman d'aventures maritimes, peu importe s'ils soient en vers; la prose n'a commencé vraiment qu'avec l'imprimerie quand on pouvait s'adresser à un seul lecteur en particulier. Donc, le roman est aussi vieux que la littérature elle-même. Cependant, le roman, le genre littéraire qui raconte une histoire où les personnages semblent vivre, a subi des transformations complexes et inattendues à travers les siècles selon les événements et les caprices politiques, scientifiques, et religieux. </description><creator>Allard, Wilfred Philip</creator><date>1941</date><subject>Martet, Jean, 1886-1940.</subject><title>Le roman d'aventures humoristique de Jean Martet</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q311v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px63n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj4306394</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multiple Organ Dysfunction Syndrome (MODS) is the leading cause of mortality in Intensive Care Unit (ICU) patients. Although essential for host defense, the polymorphonuclear neutrophil (PMN) contributes to endothelial cell and end organ injury in disease states such as MODS. PMN chemotaxis and apoptosis are principally involved in neutrophil delivery and clearance, and their evaluation is performed with the goal of developing effective therapeutic intervention that would attenuate neutrophil mediated host injury. To investigate the role of neutrophil membrane receptor expression in the regulation of neutrophil apoptosis and chemotaxis, human circulating PMN (venipuncture, healthy controls), exudate PMN (skin window skin blister) and septic PMN (venipuncture, patients with sepsis) were evaluated for apoptosis rates (flow cytometry), chemotactic function (Boyden chambers), and receptor expression (flow cytometry - Fas, FasL, TNFRI, TNFRII, IL-8RA, IL-8RB, C5aR). Experiments were coupled with a theoretical evaluation of the assumptions and clinical implications inherent to analytical research of the host response. Following transmigration, exudate neutrophils demonstrate delayed constitutive and induced (TNF-alpha &amp; Fas Ab) apoptosis. Decreased binding to TNF-alpha (not receptor expression) was found in association with decreased TNF-alpha induced apoptosis in exudate PMN. In contrast to circulating PMN, inhibition of protein synthesis in exudate PMN does not augment apoptosis; NF-kappaB does not mediate this effect as inhibition of NF-kappaB augments apoptosis in circulating and exudate PMN. Evaluation of chemoattractant receptors and chemotactic function revealed the following: exudate PMN displayed increased C5a receptors &amp; C5a chemotaxis and reduced Interleukin-8 receptors (both IL-8RA &amp; IL-8RB) &amp; IL-8 chemotaxis. Septic PMN displayed reduced C5a &amp; IL-8 receptors, and decreased C5a chemotaxis. These results suggest that alteration in chemoattractant receptor expression serves to regulate PMN chemotaxis in vivo, exudate PMN chemotaxis depends more on C5a than IL-8, and diminished chemoattractant receptors and chemotaxis in septic PMN may explain decreased PMN delivery in these patients. Therapeutic interventions for patients with complex inflammatory disease states such as MODS remains elusive despite immense growth in understanding the mechanisms involved in the host response. To complement analytical research, the systemic host response to trauma, shock or sepsis may be evaluated as a complex system. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Seely, Andrew J. E.</creator><contributor>Christou, Nicolas V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Neutrophil apoptosis &amp; chemotaxis and the complex systemic host response</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hd79q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj4306394</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h22p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The liquid-liquid extraction of biomolecules using a reverse micellar system has been studied in literature as a simple and easily scalable purification method that can be used in fermentation industry. The recovery of proteins from the reverse micellar phase has shown a low efficiency (less than 20%) making the technique unfavorable in industrial practice. In addition, the modeling is often complicated due to the complex interactions among surfactants, cosurfactants, electrolytes and charged biomolecules. Thus, this work was aimed to examine the solubilization behavior of lysozyme into four different reverse micellar systems, in order to better understand the extraction mechanism. The water uptake and the concentration of lysozyme obtained in the organic phase were measured. The recovery of lysozyme from the reverse micellar phase was attempted using a second aqueous phase with pH and ion strength adjustments, a conventional method used in literature. The best extraction was obtained with aerosol-OT, but low recoveries were obtained with all three anionic and one cationic surfactants tested. During these experiments, the formation of a white precipitate at the aqueous-organic interface was observed, and this observation provided the basis for an understanding of the extraction mechanism and a proposal of a novel separation method. A novel purification method is proposed to extract lysozyme from an aqueous solution using surfactants and recover it as a solid. In this method, the surfactant is directly added to the aqueous solution containing lysozyme, instead of using a liquid-liquid extraction mechanism. Upon contact, the lysozyme forms an insoluble lysozyme-ligand complex. The insoluble compound was then dissolved in acetone, and the surfactant-free lysozyme was recovered as a solid. An overall recovery efficiency of up to 70% was obtained, and the lysozyme was found to retain its original enzymatic activity. A simple mathematical model is suggested to describe the formation of lysozyme-surfactant complex. The model was also used to better understand, the extraction mechanism of lysozyme into a reverse micellar phase.</description><creator>Shin, Youn-Ok, 1971-</creator><contributor>Vera, Juan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Extraction of lysozyme using surfactants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j0487.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h22p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d33x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>X-linked hypophosphatemia (XLH), the most prevalent form of inherited rickets in humans, is caused by mutations in the PHEX gene, which encodes a protein with high homology to the M13 family of type-II integral membrane zinc metallopeptidases. We created an online mutation database, PHEXdb (http://data.mch.mcgill.ca/phexdb), to catalogue PHEX mutations identified in XLH patients, and found that missense mutations account for 22% of the 157 mutations reported to date. We also undertook to examine the effects of eight missense mutations (C85R, D237G, Y317F, G579R, G579V, S711R, A720T, and F731Y) on synthesis, glycosylation, cellular trafficking, and catalytic activity of the recombinant proteins using several approaches. The wild-type protein was resistant to endoglycosidase H (endo H), indicating that it is fully glycosylated. In addition, biotinylation and immunofluorescence studies revealed that the wild-type protein resides at the cell surface. The D237G, Y317F and F731Y mutant PHEX proteins were also endo H resistant and thus terminally glycosylated. In contrast, endo H digestion demonstrated that C85R, G579R, G579V, S711R and A720T were not terminally glycosylated. Furthermore, immunofluorescence showed that C85R, G579R and S711R were sequestered in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). A secreted form of wild-type and mutant PHEX (secPHEX) proteins was generated to examine catalytic activity, using a synthetic fluorogenic peptide substrate. For this purpose, rescue of ER-trapped mutant proteins was attempted by growing transfected cells at 26°C. Low temperature was able to rescue three of the five trapped mutant proteins (G579V, S711R and A720T). Residual catalytic activity was observed with four mutant proteins (D237G, Y317F, A720T and F731Y) relative to the wild-type. However, the rescued S711R mutant was devoid of catalytic activity. Finally, limited proteolysis with trypsin and endoproteinase Glu-c revealed that the mutations D237G and F731Y induce conform</description><creator>Sabbagh, Yves</creator><contributor>Tenenhouse, Harriet S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Hypophosphatemia, Familial</subject><subject>Genetic polymorphisms</subject><subject>Sodium cotransport systems</subject><title>Impact of disease-causing missense mutations on the structure and function of PHEX</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq20c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d33x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cm62n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is widely recognized that differences in both prosodic complexity and position-sensitive contrasts exist both within and across languages. In contemporary phonological theory, these differences are often attributed to differences between heads and non-heads and the asymmetries in licensing potential that exist between such positions. In this thesis, the consequences of such differences for the second language (L2) acquisition of prosodic complexity and position-sensitive contrasts are explored. It is argued that an explanatorily adequate account of L2 syllabification must include highly-structured representations as well as a theory of licensing, which distinguishes between the licensing of a given position and the licensing of featural content in such a position. Using data drawn primarily from a number of studies that investigate the acquisition of French by native speakers of English and Mandarin, it is demonstrated that the widely-attested interlanguage (IL) syllable-structure-modification processes of deletion, epenthesis, and feature change have a common source. Specifically, all three processes result from the IL grammar's inability to license a syllable position or (some of) the featural content present in such a position in the target representation. Within Optimality theory, the framework adopted, this is formalized through the competition between Faithfulness constraints and Markedness constraints, which evaluate the wellformedness of the licensing relationships. Finally, it is argued that Prosodic Licensing and the principle of Licensing Inheritance from Harris (1997) work together to encode prosodic markedness in representation, as they create a series of head-dependent asymmetries in which heads are strong licensors vis-a-vis their dependents.</description><creator>Steele, Jeffrey, 1972-</creator><contributor>Goad, Heather (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Prosodic analysis (Linguistics)</subject><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Syllable</subject><subject>Language transfer (Language learning)</subject><title>Representation and phonological licensing in the L2 acquisition of prosodic structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd17b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm62n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225c66w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sorace (1993) suggests that competence at the final stage of non-native acquisition falls into qualitatively distinct categories: (1) incomplete grammar, which lacks a representation for a part of the target system; (2) divergent grammar, which has the target distinctions with non-target instantiations. She captures the general nature of the two systems but leaves their contents undefined. This study adopts her proposal and investigates non-native grammars with respect to acquisition of the Polish aspects: completive, pofective and perfective, in an attempt to define the properties of incomplete or divergent knowledge in the domain of aspect. According to the account of the aspectual system of Polish proposed in this thesis, acquisition of this system requires knowledge of the following semantic and morpho-syntactic properties: (1) aspectual interpretations, which depend on the semantic features of a VP; (2) the semantic features carried by the aspects; (3) the distinct feature context required for each aspectual interpretation; (4) restriction on feature composition with respect to the syntactic domain of derivation, namely l(exical)-syntax vs. s(syntactic)-syntax. The learners' competence, therefore, must contain information about which feature context yields which interpretation, which interpretations are unrealizable in these contexts, and which aspectual structures are allowed by virtue of their syntactic vs. lexical feature character. The Polish aspectual system involves many elements of knowledge that must be acquired for the L2 end-state to be complete. It also provides a wide range of properties whose nontarget status would lead to a divergent grammar. Experimental data were elicited from two groups of English speakers who were advanced or near-native learners of Polish in a series of tests (grammaticality judgments, semantic and end-state compatibility tasks, and picture selection) each addressing separate sets of restrictions governing the system. Results were compared to native speaker adult and child controls. Although the results reveal two types of competence, these cannot be categorically defined as either complete or divergent. While the near-natives' knowledge manifests a complete representation of the elements of the target grammar and native-like distinctions between the aspects, it also bears some characteristics of an incomplete system. The advanced learners manifest a system that is both divergent and incomplete. The study shows that the classification proposed by Sorace (1993) is only appropriate with reference to individual properties of grammar, as a single system of knowledge may show the characteristics of complete, incomplete, divergent and, possibly, non-divergent competence.</description><creator>Kozłowska-Macgregor, Martyna</creator><contributor>White, Lydia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Polish language -- Aspect</subject><subject>Second language acquisition</subject><title>The state of near-native grammar : a study of aspect in L2 Polish</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x305x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c66w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc308</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The control of milk protein production was investigated utilising two different approaches. The first model is one of intravenous infusion of atropine. Atropine, which decreases milk protein yield, has been theorised to act either by decreasing blood somatotropin (ST) concentration or by decreasing blood amino acid (AA) concentration. Thus, the first experiment was designed to test which mechanism, or both, is responsible for the effects on milk protein yield. Five lactating dairy cows were assigned to the following treatments which were administered intravenously: Saline (CONT), atropine (ATR), ATR + ST, ATR + AAs, and ATR + ST + AAs. Atropine treatment failed to decrease plasma ST concentration but did decrease plasma alpha-amino nitrogen concentration. Atropine treatment decreased milk protein yield but neither ST, AAs, nor ST + AAs were able to maintain milk protein yield at the CONT level when infused with ATR. It is clear that the treatments tested are not directly responsible for the decrease in milk protein yield due to ATR. Therefore, neither ST, AAs, nor ST + AAs appear to have direct control of milk protein production. Plasma insulin (INS) concentration was decreased and plasma IGF-I concentration was not decreased by ATR treatment. Insulin, therefore, presents itself as a candidate for direct control over milk protein synthesis. The second model is one of monitoring endocrine response to abomasal infusion of AAs mimicking the profile of milk protein with selective deletion of certain AAs. Six lactating dairy cows were subjected to the following treatments: Saline (negative control, NC), AAs (positive control, PC), PC minus methionine (PC-Met), PC minus lysine (PC-Lys), PC minus histidine (PC-His), and PC minus the branched-chain AAs (PC-BCAAs). All endocrine factors studied (ST, INS, glucagon &amp; IGF-I) were affected by treatment. Plasma IGF-I concentration responded similarly, except for the PC-Met treatment, to milk protein yield (Weekes and Cant, 200</description><creator>Luimes, Paul Hendrik</creator><contributor>Zhao, Xin (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Petitclerc, Denis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Milk proteins.</subject><subject>Milk yield.</subject><title>An examination of endocrine and nutrient controls of milk protein production /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sb93v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc308</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz14x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>After ejaculation, spermatozoa undergo a series of transformation in the female genital tract, named capacitation, that enables them to bind to the zona pellucida, initiate the acrosome reaction and fertilize the egg. Mammalian sperm motility, capacitation and acrosome reaction are regulated by signal transduction systems involving cAMP and cAMP-dependent protein kinase A (PKA). Intracellular levels of cAMP are regulated by adenylyl cyclase (AC) and phosphodiesterases (PDEs), responsible for its production and degradation, respectively. Of the 11 PDE families that exist, calmodulin (CaM)-dependent PDE (PDE1) and cAMP-specific PDE (PDE4) activities were previously identified in human spermatozoa. The aims of the present study were to evaluate the role played by some PDEs in human sperm function, to determine which PDEs are present and to evaluate the changes in cAMP, PDE and PKA activities during sperm capacitation and acrosome reaction. PDE activity did not change during either capacitation or acrosome reaction while PKA activity was increased in both phenomena. Moreover, sperm PDEs were associated with the membrane (50--60%) as well as with the particulate fraction (30--50%) and had much more affinity for cAMP than cGMP as substrate. Type-specific PDE inhibitors such as EHNA for cGMP-stimulated PDE (PDE2), milrinone for cGMP-inhibited PDE (PDE3) and rolipram for PDE4 but not sildenafil for cGMP-specific PDE (PDE5), decreased sperm PDE activity suggesting that PDE2, PDE3 and PDE4 but not PDE5 were present both in membrane and particulate fractions. Moreover, EHNA and rolipram increased sperm capacitation while milrinone increased sperm cAMP. Anti-PDE1A and anti-PDE3A antibodies recognized proteins of 67 kDa (PDE1A) and 97 kDa (PDE3A). Immunolocalization indicated that PDE1A was present on the equatorial segment of the sperm head as well as on the mid- and principal pieces of the flagellum and that PDE3A was present on the post-acrosomal segment of the head. Furth</description><creator>Lefièvre, Linda</creator><contributor>Gagnon, Claude (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Studies on phosphodiesterase activities in human spermatozoa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr31s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz14x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x3066</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transposons are a diverse collection of mobile genetic elements and are important components of nearly every genome. Because of their mobile and repetitive nature, transposons can have considerable effects on host gene expression, genome organization and evolution. The recent availability of genomic sequence information has expedited the discovery and study of transposons, as exemplified in this thesis by the complete genome analysis of the model plant system Arabidopsis thaliana. Data mining in Arabidopsis has revealed a rich diversity of transposons, of which Basho and Terminal-repeat Retrotransposons In Miniature (TRIM) elements were previously unknown types. The identification of Related to Empty Sites (RESites) provide evidence for past transposition events. Examples of elements contributing to coding regions, acquiring cellular sequences, along with in-depth analysis of the insertions, their target sites and their distribution illustrate the impact of transposons on gene and genome structures. Computer-based searches of genomic sequences has also improved our understanding of previously identified transposon families, such as the origin, classification and mobilization of Tourist elements. In addition, information on transposons gathered from in silico analysis of genomic sequences has served to design in vivo experiments. In a whole genome strategy, Transposon Display was used to investigate transposition and regulation of mobility of Tourist-like elements in A. thaliana and in the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans.</description><creator>Le, Quang Hien, 1972-</creator><contributor>Bureau, Thomas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Molecular genetics</subject><subject>Transposons</subject><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Molecular genetics</subject><title>Diversity and mobility of transposons in Arabidopsis thaliana</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n824.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3066</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n024d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conceptual rainfall runoff (CRR) models are popular among hydrologists owing to their modest input data requirements, their simple structure and therefore their modest computational requirements. The realisation that CRR model calibration is more akin to a global optimisation problem, not a local optimisation one, was a significant development. The subsequent applications of global optimisation methods (GOM) have solved a major difficulty for estimating model parameters. Further improvement in parameter estimation may follow if constraints that help to limit the number of feasible parameter values can be developed. This study has proposed a methodology for formulating constraints related to the CRR model structure and the hydrologic data available for calibration. For developing this methodology, the research examined the capabilities of three GOMs for calibration, namely, the Shuffled Complex Evolution (SCE) method, a genetic algorithm (GA) and a simulated annealing procedure (SA), and one local optimisation method, the downhill simplex method (DSM). The GOMs all performed better than the DSM. The SCE displayed superior accuracy and robustness for synthetic data applications, being able to find all (five) selected sets of parameter values with almost 100% accuracy. However, the GA performed better than the SCE method with real data and perhaps reflects some weakness in the SCE to find global optimal points under difficult calibration conditions. The SA was inferior to the others with both types of data applications. The importance of selection of parameter ranges is currently given little attention in the calibration process, but even with the superior search capability of GOMs, inflated search spaces can frustrate their searches and may lead to inferior parameter estimation. Several inequalities relating model parameters with the hydrologic data were developed, which when coupled with the SCE method, significantly improved the GOM performance. This modified SCE method appeared less sensitive to the problem of parameter range specification. A method for formulating these constraints was demonstrated on synthetic data and a procedure for its application to real data was done using data from two tropical watersheds.</description><creator>Cooper, Vincent A.</creator><contributor>Nicell, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Hydrology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>On automatic calibration of conceptual rainfall runoff models using optimisation techniques</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt661.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n024d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375z00n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An integrated system providing dynamic control of sound source azimuth, distance and proximity to a room boundary within a simulated acoustic space is proposed for use in multichannel music and film sound production. The system has been investigated, implemented, and psychoacoustically tested within the ITU-R BS.775 recommended five-channel (3/2) loudspeaker layout. The work brings together physical and perceptual models of room simulation to allow dynamic placement of virtual sound sources at any location of a simulated space within the horizontal plane. The control system incorporates a number of modules including simulated room modes, "fuzzy" sources, and tracking early reflections, whose parameters are dynamically changed according to sound source location within the simulated space. The control functions of the basic elements, derived from theories of perception of a source in a real room, have been carefully tuned to provide efficient, effective, and intuitive control of a sound source's perceived location. Seven formal listening tests were conducted to evaluate the effectiveness of the algorithm design choices. The tests evaluated: (1) loudness calibration of multichannel sound images; (2) the effectiveness of distance control; (3) the resolution of distance control provided by the system; (4) the effectiveness of the proposed system when compared to a commercially available multichannel room simulation system in terms of control of source distance and proximity to a room boundary; (5) the role of tracking early reflection patterns on the perception of sound source distance; (6) the role of tracking early reflection patterns on the perception of lateral phantom images. The listening tests confirm the effectiveness of the system for control of perceived sound source distance, proximity to room boundaries, and azimuth, through fine, dynamic adjustment of parameters according to source location. All of the parameters are grouped and controlled together to create a perceptually strong impression of source location and movement within a simulated space.</description><creator>Corey, Jason Andrew</creator><contributor>Levitin, Daniel (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Woszczyk, Wieslaw (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Surround-sound systems</subject><subject>Sound</subject><subject>Music -- Acoustics and physics</subject><title>An integrated system for dynamic control of auditory perspective in a multichannel sound field /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj25m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z00n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dn992</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to obtain some insight into the deformation behavior of the dispersed phase in the various flows and to evaluate the effects of various variables such as concentration of the dispersed phase and viscosity ratio, affine deformation equations were derived for some stratified shear and elongational flows. It was shown by the derived deformation equations that the volume fraction of the dispersed phase is a factor affecting the deformation of the dispersed phase, and the effect depends on viscosity ratio. The results from the stratified simple shear flow model predict that, for viscosity ratio &gt;1, the deformation rate increases with the volume fraction, and the shear stress also increases, leading to the increase of the breakup time. Therefore, the total deformation of the dispersed phase, before breakup, increases with the increase of the volume fraction, resulting in the decrease of the size of the dispersed phase particles. The prediction was verified experimentally, in both the Haake batch mixer and the Couette flow mixer, using polyethylene/polyamide-6 blends compatibilized by adding maleic anhydride grafted polyethylene, when coalescence was suppressed. In the analysis of particle size data for the verification of the volume fraction effect, an effort was made to identify the contribution of coalescence. The experimental results of particle sizes in 1 wt% blends of the Haake mixer are in reasonable agreement with the transient deformation and breakup theory for simple shear flow. This suggests that the dominant flow in the mixer was shear flow. In some reactively compatibilized blends, at high shear rate, the particle sizes showed a maximum when either the weight fraction or the shear rate was increased. This behavior may be explained by coalescence effects related to the redistribution of the produced copolymers at the interface. It was shown experimentally that, for very high viscosity ratio (&gt;3.5~4), the deformation of large drops between gaps i</description><creator>Cho, Yong Gyun, 1965-</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The effect of concentration of the dispersed phase on morphology evolution in high viscosity ratio polymer blends /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc79v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn992</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9998311</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Under what conditions did conservative governments of the major industrial countries commit themselves to building domestic institutional frameworks for embedded liberalism as an international economic subsystem? As a way of answering the question, this study looks into informal and formal institutional arrangements for domestic compromise among classes and sectors. During the 1950s, governments in the United States, Britain, France, and West Germany sought to accommodate working-class demands and achieve a stable domestic economy within the institutional limits set by the prior experiences dating back to the interwar years. At the informal level, organized labor and business community in each country interacted with each other to produce varying forms of labor-management conflict resolution mechanism. At the formal level, political parties became more centrist in the domestic economic policy areas in order to maximize votes in an era of catch-all party politics. National outcomes varied from the semi-privatized welfare state in the United States to the liberal Keynesian welfare state in Britain to the dirigiste interventionist state in France to the social market economy in West Germany. Although those nationally distinct institutional arrangements reduced international policy coordination, embedded liberalism could work as long as participating countries shared the social purpose that domestic stability and international liberalization should not be incompatible.</description><creator>Cho, Chansoo, 1968-</creator><contributor>Brawley, Mark R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Liberalism</subject><subject>Free enterprise</subject><subject>Economic policy</subject><title>Making embedded liberalism work : domestic sources of the postwar liberal subsystem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn118.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998311</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1070797</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-1) is a polypeptide trophic factor playing an important role in the survival and differentiation of both neuronal and non-neuronal cells. The biological functions of IGF-1 are mediated by the IGF-1 receptor, a tyrosine kinase receptor expressed in most tissues including the central nervous system. IGF-1 possesses trophic effects in neuronal cells including in hippocampal neurons. However, the intracellular signaling pathways activated by IGF-1 receptors in these cells remain to be fully established. The main objective of the thesis was to investigate the activation and regulation of survival kinases such as Akt and one of its downstream targets the Forkhead family transcription factor FKHRL1 (a proapoptotic protein), as well to establish the role of these events in IGF-1 induced neuroprotection in PC12 cells and hippocampal neurons. Our results show that IGF-1 stimulates tyrosine phosphorylation of the IGF-1 receptor, as well as of IRS-1 and IRS-2, and their association with PI3 kinase, leading to the activation of Akt in PC12 cells and hippocampal neurons. The activation of Akt by IGF-1 is mediated by the PI3 kinase as only PI3 kinase inhibitors such as wortmannin and LY294002 but not the MAP kinase pathway inhibitor PD89059 or the S6p70 kinase pathway inhibitor rapamycin blocked the action of IGF-1. IGF-1 also increases the phosphorylation of FKHRL1 in PC12 cells and hippocampal neurons via the activation of Akt as evidenced by the use of various kinase inhibitors, an in vitro kinase assay and the expression of different forms of Akt. Interestingly, the phosphorylation of Akt and FKHRL1 induced by IGF-1 is attenuated by the stimulation of protein kinase C which modulates IGF-1 receptor signaling at various levels including IRS-1 and Akt in PC12 cells. As in PC12 cells, IGF-1 activates the IGF-1 receptor/IRS-1/PI3K/Akt/FKHRL1 pathway in hippocampal neurons, and the phosphorylation of FKHRL1 is mediated by PI3K/Akt kinase. Functionally, cell survival assay with kinase inhibitors and transfection of different forms of Akt suggest that the PI3K/Akt/FKHRL1 pathway plays a role in IGF-1-promoted survival in neuronal cells. Interestingly, similar results were obtained for neurotrophins such as NGF and BDNF suggesting that neurotrophins induce the activation of this pathway to promote cell survival. Taken together, these finding support the hypothesis that the survival promoting effects of IGF-1 in neuronal cells are mediated, at least in part, by the PI3K/Akt/FKHRL1 pathway.</description><creator>Zheng, WenHua, 1962-</creator><contributor>Kar, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Quirion, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Intracellular signaling of insulin-like growth factor receptors in neuronal cells : activation and regulation of AKT kinase pathway and the forkhead family transcription factor FKHRL1, and their role in cell survival</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp00m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1070797</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp59q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Firstly, that all normativity constitutes law. Thus, law can no more be defined by formal criteria than it can be conditioned by determinisms. Its substance must be found in the ontology of regulation. All manifestations of normativity must therefore be considered as relevant to the jurist. Secondly, that identity is at once complex, fragmented, interwoven and in flux. We are all inhabited by multiple and often contradictory relationships, allegiances and sensibilities whose overlaps define our identity. It is the constant arbitration with which identity confronts us that predisposes us to develop the empathy necessary to interaction and coexistence. Thirdly, that normativity is a subjective experience that reflects the nature of our identity. The law cannot be viewed as an externality. It can only be actualized through the reciprocal interpellation it implies. The norm is a contested and fragmented space that implies prehension through a reflexive process and retroaction through its inscription within interaction. This thesis explores the foundations and the articulations of norms. Firstly, the study of the sources of legal pluralism reveals the location of radical legal pluralism within a context which called for its emergence. The acknowledgment of the localization of normativity within a complex universe then serves as a foundation for the development of a typology which accounts for the whole scope of the normative domain. It is upon this ontological foundation that we can then acknowledge that the instrumental potential of normative phenomena is overestimated and its symbolic potential is underestimated. This foundation then allows us to contemplate the complexity and the interrelated character of both the emergence and the legitimization of norms. Hence, the mobilization of our shared character as normative agents is the only criterion that can serve as a basis for a radical pluralist conception of law. Radical legal pluralism then represents both a metaphor which describes the wealth of the human condition through the legal experience and an emancipatory heuristic which enables a reappropriation of the law by those who, often without knowing, are its principal crafters.</description><creator>Lebel-Grenier, Sebastien.</creator><contributor>Macdonal, Roderick A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Pour un pluralisme juridique radical</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k4294.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp59q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988m703</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the context of globalization, the idea of place is reputed to be losing its footing. This thesis explores the implications of these developments with respect to the way that place is constructed in law by focusing on tensions between the concept of jurisdiction and the ways that the contexts of law overspill it, threatening to engulf comparative analysis. Central to the idea that jurisdiction is losing its familiar moorings is the implication that other forms of thinking about legal normativity are emerging as more commonsensical alternatives to the state-based idea of jurisdiction that emerged in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. The thesis explores this hypothesis by bringing elements of the discipline of comparative law (conventionally state based) into play with elements of the discipline of legal anthropology (conventionally culture based). The focus for this theoretical intrigue is an Gitano population in the South of Spain that served as the fieldwork locale for seven months of ethnographic fieldwork carried out in 1995. Investigations are centered on the theme of family law. Familiar notions of state and culture, and the legal sensibilities associated with each, are examined through exploring the interplay between local expressions of Gitanitude in Jerez de la Frontera and regional, national, international, and global forces that structure legal sensibilities in the area. The first chapter explores the interplay by focusing on the context surrounding Spain's reforms to family law in the 1980s. The familiar frontiers of the state are prodded through this analysis. The second chapter then explores the frontiers of culture through an examination of a variety of expressions of Gitanitude in Spain. The third chapter brings modified versions of state and culture together in a reconceptualisation of family law. As a whole, the thesis suggests a new way of approaching the problematic relationship between context and the disciplines of comparative law an</description><creator>Drummond, Susan G. (Susan Gay), 1959-</creator><contributor>Baker, Blaine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Romanies -- Legal status. laws, etc. -- Spain.</subject><subject>Domestic relations -- Spain.</subject><subject>Andalusia (Spain) -- Social life and customs.</subject><subject>Law and anthropology.</subject><title>Legal itineraries through Spanish Gitano family law : a comparative law ethnography</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h117t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m703</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw11c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The theory of the autonomy of the will plays a central structuring role in Quebec's positive law. It has given rise to a conception of contractual justice that has contributed to the transformation of the role played by equality in contract and influenced the treatment of unfair contract by positive law in Quebec. It cannot however serve as an analytical framework for explaining the entire juridical regime applicable to contract. Based on the theory of the autonomy of the will, positive law states the principle according to which lesion does not vitiate consent, but it also provides for numerous exceptions based on ideas that proceed from another conception of contractual justice. Moreover, although the Civil Code does not set forth any rule destined to ensure equality in contract the idea according to which contracts may not lead to the exploitation of a party by the other and must respect some sense of fairness can be put forward. A look at the body of rules in positive law pertaining to equality in contract shows that this idea plays an important role in Quebec's positive law.</description><creator>Charpentier, Elise M., 1965-</creator><contributor>Crepeau, Paul-Andre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Contracts -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Contracts</subject><title>L'équilibre des prestations : une condition de reconnaissance de la force obligatoire du contrat?</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n496w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw11c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv65c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Na+/H+ exchangers (NHE) are transmembrane proteins that mediate the electroneutral exchange of Na+ and proton across the plasma membrane. There are seven mammalian isoforms of the gene family identified to date. The recently cloned isoform NHE5 seems to be the most highly cell type-specific being probably expressed only in neurons. The objective of my research was to describe the basic biochemical and some of the regulatory characteristics of NHE5 in an effort to understand its in vivo function. To this end, the full-length cDNA of NHE5 was reconstructed and transfected into the NHE-deficient Chinese hamster ovary cell line AP1. Pharmacological analyses demonstrated that H+ i-activated 22Na+ influx mediated by NHE5 was inhibited by several classes of drugs at half-maximal concentrations that were intermediate to those determined for the high-affinity NHE1 and the low-affinity NHE3 isoforms. Kinetic analyses showed that the extracellular Na+-dependence of NHE5 activity followed a simple hyperbolic relationship and, unlike other NHE isoforms, the intracellular H+-dependence also exhibited first-order kinetics. Extracellular monovalent cations, such as H+ and Li+, but not K+, acted as effective competitive inhibitors of 22Na+ influx by NHE5. To find novel interacting proteins that are involved in NHE5 regulation, a yeast two-hybrid screen of human brain cDNA library was conducted using NHE5 as bait. A clone encoding the AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) alpha2 subunit was further analyzed. AMPK is a serine/threonine kinase that is activated by elevated ratios of [AMP]/[ATP], regulating various biological processes in response to hypoxia or exercise. AMPK alpha2 binds NHE5 in vitro and in vivo, and directly phosphorylates it in vitro. Activation of endogenous AMPK by AICAR, a membrane permeable AMP analogue, as well as heterologous expression of the full-length and constitutive active forms of alpha2 subunit increased the transporter activity measured by 22Na+ influx. The regulatory protein arrestin3 was also found to interact with NHE5 in the yeast two-hybrid screen. Arrestins were previously shown to associate with and regulate transmembrane proteins of the G protein-coupled receptor family. We demonstrate that NHE5 binds arrestin3 both in vitro and in vivo; and the binding is phosphorylation-dependent. When co-expressed in CHO cells, arrestin3 and NHE5 co-localize, and arrestin3 expression seems to attenuate the basal activity of the transporter. The data presented in this thesis reveals new aspects of both NHE regulation, and AMPK and arrestin function.</description><creator>Szabo, Elod Zala.</creator><contributor>Orlowski, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Molecular and cellular properties of the human brain Na+H+ exchanger isoform 5</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c675.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv65c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544br07j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There has during a rapid growth of third sector organizations (TSOs) in the third world during the 1990s. Such growth has occurred during a period of severe cutbacks in state investment as well as rapid globalization of trade. Social activists have often organized TSOs in these countries as an alternative to private and public organizations. However the question of how leaders and managers of these TSOs sustain their activities remains important. Their dilemma of help is the focus of this study. Through a study of strategy formation in three third sector organizations in the third world, this study focuses on how TSOs can be sustainable yet effective change agents. It develops a typology of TSOs with particular attention to type of third sector activity (operating, support, community), type of organizational form (Grassroots initiatives, Grassroots Organizations, Grassroots Federations, Development Support Organizations and International Development Support Organizations) and dominant strategy approach (domain, distinctiveness, and design). This study argues that attention to these three aspects needs to be complemented by exploring the processes through which strategies form in these organizations. Accordingly the strategy process in three TSOs in South India was examined, in particular the origin of the strategy, tactics of consensus, and interests of participants. Examining the strategy process in TSOs revealed that strategies originated in intent or event, promoters' consensus-tactics were conceived or improvised and participant's interests were fixed or shifting. These findings on strategy process show varied origins, interests and consensus tactics in TSOs. They also seem to be associated with particular capacities in these organizations to perform their chosen activities, as well as with changes in mission. The study concludes with a discussion of the significance of these findings and a call for bridging the literatures on good management and effective social change, for further researching capacity building in TSOs, and encouraging initiatives for cross sector learning.</description><creator>Srinivas, Nidhi.</creator><contributor>Jorgensen, Jan (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Mintzberg, Henry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Non-governmental organizations -- India.</subject><subject>Cooperation -- India</subject><subject>Nonprofit organizations -- India.</subject><title>Crafting consensus in the third world : strategy formation in the third sector</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q72d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br07j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt62m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The removal of multiple substrates in a defined mixed culture process was investigated in the treatment of brewery wastewater. The study was conducted using both batch and a semi-continuous reactor system called self-cycling fermentation. Batch experiments were conducted using a synthetic brewery wastewater containing glucose, ethanol and maltose. Activated sludge from a municipal wastewater treatment plant was acclimatized in the synthetic brewery wastewater. The microbes capable of degrading this wastewater were analyzed by a combination of microscopy, spread plating, and Polymerase Chain Reaction-Denaturing Gradient Gel Electrophoresis (PCR-DGGE) and identified as Acinetobacter sp., Enterobacter sp. and Candida sp. From the pure culture batch experiments, it was determined that Enterobacter could degrade glucose and maltose but no ethanol, while Acinetobacter and Candida could degrade all three carbon sources. In mixed culture batch experiments, Enterobacter was dominant in degrading the sugar concentrations to levels permissible for Acinetobacter to degrade ethanol. PCR-DGGE was found to be effective in identifying the dominant species but selective carbon source plating was required to determine viability and track the population dynamics. Kinetic experiments were carried out in a semi-continuous, self-cycling fermentation process using the defined mixed culture in media containing glucose and various initial concentrations of ethanol and maltose. The overall rate of substrate removal was attributable to both the suspended culture and the biofilm formed during the process. A rate expression was developed for this system for the range of substrate concentrations tested. The data indicated that substrate removal by the suspended culture was a function of only the biomass concentration. However, substrate removal by the biofilm was found to be limited to the surface cells and determined to be a function of substrate concentration only.</description><creator>Tam, Kawai, 1969-</creator><contributor>Sheppard, J. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Bioreactors.</subject><subject>Water -- Purification -- Biological treatment.</subject><subject>Brewery waste.</subject><subject>Fermentation.</subject><title>Removal of multiple substrates in a mixed culture process for the treatment of brewery wastewater</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v953t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt62m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sv38x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this dissertation is to explain the meaning of concordia surveying the historical context in which it emerged. The thesis concentrates on the period 63--43 B.C. because it is in this crucial period that the concept achieves its most articulate and influential defence by the Roman orator, statesman, and philosopher, Marcus Tullius Cicero. My intention is to review the important writings and speeches of Cicero and to situate them in the political struggles in which he was implicated. By placing the concept of concordia in this political context, a clearer picture emerges than is available in the current literature about how Cicero promoted, defended, and skillfully redefined the concept of concordia in order to achieve his political aims. What emerges are three identifiable meanings of the concept of concordia . The first is the longstanding conventional Roman republican idea of concordia as unity, friendship, and agreement. The second is what Cicero called the concordia ordinum, an innovative idea of concordia as a harmony or coalition of the two Roman orders of the senate and equites. The third is the idea of concordia as a consensus omnium bonorum---what Cicero called concordia civium or concordia civitatis . This idea represents an important shift in the thinking of the Roman orator who began to see the survival of the republic as depending on a consensus that went beyond the coalition of the senate and equites.</description><creator>Temelini, Mark A.</creator><contributor>Richardson, T. Wade (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Rome -- History -- Republic, 265-30 B.C.</subject><subject>Concord</subject><subject>Harmony (Philosophy)</subject><subject>Cicero, Marcus Tullius</subject><title>Cicero's concordia : the promotion of a political concept in the late Roman republic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh885.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv38x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w138r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation argues that Isaiah Berlin and John Rawls can be seen as seminal contributors to two quite distinct revivals of political theory in the latter half of the twentieth century. It suggests that coming to grips with the different underlying character of these revivals and writers is important to understanding political theory and liberalism today. However, while the importance Berlin's of Berlin's work is increasingly recognized, there remain puzzling controversies concerning its overall character and import and in particular concerning its relationship to the dominant forms of American political thought, and Rawls' work in particular. This dissertation offers a novel interpretation of Berlin's political thought and liberalism, and a preliminary exploration of its relationship with Rawls' political thought. The reading of Berlin develops the following principal themes: (1) Berlin was a moderate but consistent historicist primarily concerned with the interpretive self-understanding of his own form of life; (2) Berlin was a strong but distinctive pluralist who argued for a limited but open-ended range of recognizable and rivalrous ultimate values and for an agitated equilibrium of these values in public life; (3) Berlin focused the bulk of his critical energy on defending an internally pluralistic range of traditionally liberal values within this agitated equilibrium, with an emphasis on liberty and pluralism. He nonetheless recognized that there were other equally ultimate values, not distinctively liberal, which were legitimate and deserving of consideration and even defense. Berlin's essential insight is into the contemporary rivalry of equally ultimate values revealed by the historicist exercise of the sympathetic imagination. This interpretation of Berlin's thought suggests some deep points of dispute with Rawls' Political Liberalism, in particular over the regulative role of Rawls' political conception of justice in public reason. This dissertation argues that, when explored, these points of disagreement reveal two very different approaches to contemporary political thought, Berlin's grounded in an embrace of strong moral and political pluralism as the basis of political theory, and Rawls' grounded in an effort to tame such "simple" pluralism through the elaboration of a consensual normative framework of public life.</description><creator>Plaw, Avery.</creator><contributor>Patten, Alan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Berlin, Isaiah, Sir.</subject><subject>Liberalism.</subject><subject>Rawls, John, 1921-2002.</subject><subject>Cultural pluralism.</subject><title>Isaiah Berlin's pluralist thought and liberalism : a re-reading and contrast with John Rawls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b271x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w138r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc31j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neurotrophins support survival of many different classes of neurons during development of the nervous system. Appropriate neuronal numbers are generated as developing neurons compete for adequate amounts of neurotrophin and those that are unsuccessful die by a process of apoptosis. In addition to survival, the neurotrophins have recently been shown to regulate apoptosis by activating the p75 neurotrophin receptor at the cell surface. Therefore, the decision to live or die depends on the interplay between survival and death signals, but the underlying mechanisms mediating these events are only beginning to be elucidated. The following chapters highlight the function of two related proteins, p53 and p73, and their opposing roles in neuronal apoptosis and survival. The first chapter demonstrates that the endogenous p53 tumor suppressor protein is essential for naturally occurring death of sympathetic neurons. Blocking the function of p53 either by targeted deletion in mice or viral inhibitors can rescue sympathetic neurons from apoptosis. These results are consistent with the role of p53 following injury in postmitotic neurons, however, they also demonstrate a novel function for p53 during nervous system development. The next experiments define a role for the p53 related protein, p73, in sympathetic neuron development. P73 exists as both pro and anti-apoptotic isoforms with the latter being predominantly expressed in the nervous system. Here I report that the anti-apoptotic p73 protein (DeltaNp73) is essential for sympathetic neuron survival during development and that one of its main targets is p53. The final section examines the role of DeltaNp73 in the CNS. Cortical neurons die at a rapid and continuous rate in the absence of DeltaNp73. We also identify p73 at a position downstream of PI3 kinase, a major survival protein important for many types of neurons. Finally, we demonstrate that p73 overexpression can protect neurons from DNA damage induced death. Together these studies have identified novel and opposing roles for the p53 family members in developing and mature neurons of the central and peripheral nervous systems.</description><creator>Pozniak, Christine D.</creator><contributor>Miller, Freda D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The related p53 and p73 proteins have opposing roles in neuronal survival and apoptosis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x5614.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc31j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q794m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:40:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Timbre is a multidimensional attribute of sound and depends to a large extent on its spectral content. The evaluation and control of timbre is a task commonly performed by sound engineers, loudspeaker designers, and subjects participating in listening tests on the quality of transmitted and reproduced sound. Such listening tasks require specific listening abilities. This dissertation presents a training method that aims at developing memory for timbre, sensitivity to timbre changes, and listening strategies involving disciplined auditory attention and efficiency. The physical timbre space is divided into categories defined by the center frequency of standard octave and third-octave resonances. This simplification of the physical timbre space allows the memorization of a limited set of perceptual timbre categories or references that can be used to evaluate other timbres. The proposed method combines the use of computer software for the presentation and evaluation of exercises and individual tutoring sessions with an instructor. The software monitors the actions of listeners during equalization adjustment tasks and allows data to be collected on the sequence of problem solving operators that are used. Performance indicators can thus be compiled and used for the assessment of skill level achieved by the listeners. A global performance index is proposed. A listening test involving the adjustment of multiple peaks and dips in a sound's spectrum is presented, in which the performance of a group of experienced professionals involved in sound recording and audio post-production was compared with a group of student subjects with comparatively little listening experience but who were trained with the method described in the present work for a period of 6 months. Results indicate that overall the experimental student group outperformed the control group of professionals. Suggestions for further improvement of the training method and performance level assessment are proposed.</description><creator>Quesnel, René.</creator><contributor>Levitin, Daniel (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Woszczyk, Wieslaw (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Tone color (Music) -- Computer-assisted instruction.</subject><subject>Auditory perception -- Computer-assisted instruction.</subject><title>A computer-assisted method for training and researching timbre memory and evaluation skills /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c14r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q794m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33725</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>