<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:32Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kv72q" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kv72q</identifier><datestamp>2020-05-06T20:00:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Among the different theories of translation, the work of critic Antoine Berman is most remarkable. In Pour une critique des traductions: John Donne, published in 1994, Berman suggests, in the segment entitled "Le projet d'une critique 'productive'", a critical method of translation that is not a "model", but a possible analytical process. By following the steps devised by Berman, we will endeavor to apply this method to a translation of several short stories by the American writer Raymond Carver, chosen from the collection Will You Please Be Quiet Please?, first published by McGraw-Hill in 1976. The work has only been translated into French once, by Francois Lasquin in 1987. Our analysis will be based on this version. The creative component of our Master's Thesis will consist in a new translated versions of the selected short stories from Carver's collection, namely: Fat, They're Not Your Husband, Are You A Doctor?, Nobody Said Anything, Night School, The Student's Wife and Bicycles, Muscles, Cigarets . Subsequent to the applications of the possible analytical process , we will compare the version presented in the first part of this Thesis with Francois Lasquin's, using the tools proposed by Berman. This comparison will be based on the deformation tendencies theory found in Berman's essay: "La traduction et la lettre ou l'auberge du lointain", published in 1985 in les tours de babel. Finally, we will re-emphasize the recurrent changes suggested in the version we are presenting. This analysis leads us to a discussion of our own conceptions of translation, and the elements that motivate and justify our choices concerning translation and translating.</description><creator>Ouellet, Annie.</creator><contributor>Chapdelaine, Annick (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Carver, Raymond, 1938-1988</subject><subject>Literature, Comparative.</subject><subject>Literature, American.</subject><title>Veux-tu te taire, s'il te plat? : critique de la traduction de Carver</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq40m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv72q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>