<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:00:57Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15225" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk940</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Classical methodologies for carbon-carbon bond formation often require stoichiometric amount of reagent to prefunctionalize a C-H bond. Such methods generate a lot of waste and are therefore not atom-efficient. On the other hand, the use of catalysts for the direct use of C-H bond without prior functionalization is a more desirable approach for carbon-carbon formation. For example, an overall addition reaction is 100% atom economical. This thesis focuses on the catalytic addition of the three types of C-H bonds (Csp-H, Csp2-H and Csp3-H) to unsaturated molecules such as conjugated dienes, imines and carbon dioxide to form heterocycles. The first chapter describes the direct single addition of 1,3-diketones (Csp3- H bond) to conjugated dienes and enol ethers catalyzed by gold(III) chloride and silver(I) trifluoromethanesulfonate. The reaction is highly regioselective, although the overall yields are modest (up to 70%) due to the oxidative nature of the catalysts. Under certain conditions, the addition product undergoes a subsequent cyclization to form dihydrofurans. This tandem addition/cyclization reaction is catalyzed by trifluoromethanesulfonic acid and is discussed in the second part of the chapter. The second chapter deals with the addition of phenol derivatives (C sp2-H bond) to conjugated dienes catalyzed by gold(III) chloride and silver(I) trifluoromethanesulfonate. The reaction affords dihydrobenzofurans via an intramolecular O-H cyclization. Investigation into the sequence of the reaction shows that the C-C bond is formed before the C-O bond. The third chapter presents the addition of terminal alkynes (Csp-H bond) to imines catalyzed by cheap copper(I) iodide salt via a three-component coupling of salicylaldehyde derivatives, secondary amines and alkynes. Microwave irradiation is used which considerably shortens the reaction time and eliminate the use of solvents. Dihydrobenzofurans with an exocylic double bond are formed via an intramolecular O-H cyclization. The use of aliphatic alkynes molecules containing a heteroatom is critical to the success of the reaction. Finally, in the last chapter, the addition of terminal alkynes (C sp-H bond) to carbon dioxide (catalyzed by gold(I) chlorotriphenylphosphine and silver trifluoromethanesulfonate) is applied to the synthesis of arynaphthalene lactones via a multicomponent coupling of phenylacetylene, CO2 and 3-bromo-1-phenyl-1-propyne.</description><creator>Nguyen, René-Viet, 1981-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Alkynes.</subject><subject>Phenols.</subject><subject>Ketones.</subject><subject>Heterocyclic compounds -- Synthesis.</subject><title>Catalytic tandem nucleophilic addition for the synthesis of heterocycles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945v37x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk940</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cp45d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite growing recognition that impulsivity is associated with pathological gambling (PG), three methodological concerns continue to prevent a meaningful examination of how impulsivity is specifically associated with PG. First, the lack of studies specifically comparing PGs to less severe gamblers leaves the question of whether impulsivity was not also associated with less severe gamblers unexamined. Second, the inadequate control of confounding variables in most studies raises concerns about whether findings that impulsivity is associated with PG may be spurious. Third, many findings that impulsivity is associated with PG are based on unrelated definitions of impulsivity, and are therefore relatively uninformative. The present series of studies is the first attempt to address all of these concerns at the same time. In terms of appropriate comparison groups, study 1 compared PGs to at-risk gamblers and social gamblers, and study 2 compared severe PGs to moderately severe PGs and social gamblers. In terms of adequate controls, both studies examined PGs who were not in treatment and representative in terms of comorbid drug use. In addition, both studies controlled for age, gender, education, socioeconomic status, psychiatric comorbidity, and general cognitive function. Study 2 furthermore controlled for depression, trait anxiety, aggression, and criminality. In terms of improving how impulsivity is examined, study 1 elaborated a neuroanatomically-based definition of impulsivity and examined how three hypothesized neuroanatomical components of impulsivity were associated with PG. In study 2, different operationalizations of impulsivity, based on the same definition of impulsivity, were examined regarding their association with PG. Every measure that was directly related to the present definition of impulsivity was significantly associated with severe PGs, and only severe PGs, suggesting that severe PGs may comprise a distinct group of gamblers. Measures which were not directly related to this definition of impulsivity were not significantly different between severe PGs (or PGs in study 1) and less severe gamblers. Severe PGs performed as well or better than social gamblers on retention capacity and attention control measures of working memory. In conclusion, the inability to inhibit inappropriate reward-seeking is argued to be a primary deficit of severe PGs in our sample.</description><creator>Leiserson, Victor.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Reward (Psychology)</subject><subject>Compulsive gamblers -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Impulsive personality.</subject><title>A controlled examination of impulsivity in terms of the inability to inhibit inappropriate reward-seeking in non-treatment-seeking, non-abstinent pathological gamblers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk75s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp45d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z4409</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cerebral ischemia is the principal cause of morbidity and mortality worldwide. In addition to neuronal loss associated with hypoxic-ischemic damage, cerebral ischemia is characterized by a neuromicrovascular injury. Nitrative stress and lipid peroxidation increase in hypoxic-ischemic damages and play an essential role in neuromicrovascular injury leading to cerebral ischemia. We hypothesized that newly described lipid peroxidation products, termed trans-arachidonic acids (TAA), could be implicated in the pathogenesis of hypoxia-ischemia by affecting the cerebral vasomotricity and microvascular integrity. The effects of TAA on neuromicrovascular tone were tested ex vivo by monitoring the changes in vascular diameter of rat cerebral pial microvessels. Four isomers of TAA, namely 5 E-AA, 8E-AA, IIE-AA and 14 E-AA induced an endothelium-dependent vasorelaxation. Possible mechanisms involved in TAA-induced vasorelaxation were thoroughly investigated. Collectively, data enclosed revealed that TAA induce cerebral vasorelaxation through the interactive activation of BKCa channels with heme oxygenase-2. This interaction leads to generation of carbon monoxide which in turn activates soluble guanylate cyclase and triggers vasorelaxation. Chronic effects of TAA on microvascular integrity were examined by generating a unilateral hypoxic-ischemic (HI) model of cerebral ischemia on newborn rat pups. Our HI model showed microvascular degeneration as early as 24h post-HI, preceded by an increase in cerebral TAA levels. HI-induced microvascular lesions were dependent on nitric oxide synthase activation and ensued TAA formation. Although the molecular mechanisms leading to TAA-induced microvascular degeneration were, in part uncovered for the retina, the primary site of action of TAA remains unknown. We demonstrated that TAA binds and activates GPR40 receptor, a newly described free fatty acid receptor. Importantly, GPR40 receptor knock-out prevents TAA-induced reduction in cerebral microvascular density and limits HI-induced brain infarct.</description><creator>Kooli, Amna.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Brain Ischemia -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Rats, Sprague-Dawley.</subject><subject>Hypoxia-Ischemia, Brain -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Arachidonic Acids -- pharmacology.</subject><subject>Cerebrovascular Circulation -- drug effects.</subject><subject>Rats.</subject><subject>Receptors, G-Protein-Coupled -- physiology.</subject><title>Uncovering the mechanisms of trans-arachidonic acids : function and implications for cerebral ischemia and beyond</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bx85n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z4409</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623h07c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Grain corn (Zea mays L.) production occupies more farmland than any other annual crop in Quebec and is expanding demand from the livestock sector and the emerging bioethanol industry. Corn production requires high nutrient inputs and intensive tillage (IT). Many producers have thus switched to conservation tillage systems like ridge-tillage (RT) to overcome soil compaction and erosion problems that are common in IT systems. However, fertilizer guidelines developed for IT soils are used in RT although RT adoption greatly modifies phosphorus (P) dynamics. Lower fertilizer P requirements are expected because arbuscular mycorrhizal (AM) symbiosis known to enhance plant P nutrition are minimally disrupted under RT, compared to IT systems. A two-year study was conducted on a commercial farm in the Monteregie region (Quebec, Canada) to investigate the effects of P fertilizer rates and soil P-saturation status on corn early growth, nutrition and yield. Surface soil plant-available P was monitored in situ with anionic exchange membranes (P AEM) from seeding to the end of July. The effects of indigenous AM fungi on corn parameters and rhizosphere soil P pools were also investigated in untreated (AMNI) or AM-inhibited fungicide-treated (AMI) soils. Quebec's P fertilizer guidelines underestimated the soil P fertility in studied soils. Adding inorganic P (Pi) did not improve the early corn P nutrition, growth or yield, and had little impact soil PAEM. Variations in PAEM were better explained by climatic variables. AMNI corn had similar early development and high yield, regardless of whether P fertilizer was applied, whereas AMI plants needed P fertilizer to produce optimal yield. AMNI corn had reduced dependence on Pi inputs due to more efficient uptake of soil solution P i in surface and rhizosphere soils during the first 22 days after seeding (DAS), In the rhizosphere, available-Pi pool appeared to be used first to replenish the resin-P pool, but over the longer term, AM symbiosis also enhanced NaHCO3-Po mobilization through a mechanism that remains unclear. Deeper understanding of the mechanisms by which AM fungi alter soil P dynamics will contribute to the development of more sustainable P fertilizer programs for RT systems.</description><creator>Landry, Christine.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Corn -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Phosphatic fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Corn -- Yields -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Ridge-till -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Phosphorus fertilization and mycorrhizae influence soil phosphorus dynamics, corn nutrition and yield under reduced-tillage practices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c6071.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623h07c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182p62b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis focused on the spatiotemporal patterning of classical excitatory and inhibitory synaptic contacts accounting for the majority of cerebral cortical connections, in relation to ageing and cognitive status. These investigations tested the hypothesis that higher CNS functions depend on the balance between excitatory and inhibitory synaptic connections. Glutamatergic and GABAergic presynaptic bouton densities were determined in aged animals segregated according to their cognitive status into aged and cognitively unimpaired (AU) and aged and cognitively impaired (AI), using the Morris water maze. These two groups were compared in terms of behaviour and the pattern of excitatory and inhibitory synapses. It was evident that an excitatory and inhibitory presynaptic decline is associated with age-related cognitive impairments; whereby both glutamatergic and GABAergic boutons gradually diminish from young to AU to AI. Nevertheless, the balance between excitatory and inhibitory presynaptic inputs was maintained. To determine whether postsynaptic sites differed with respect to ageing and cognitive impairments, excitatory and inhibitory postsynaptic scaffold proteins were investigated in the same cohort of segregated aged animals. There was an imbalance in density ratio between immunoreactive sites of excitatory versus inhibitory postsynaptic scaffold proteins in AI animals. This resulted from a marked decrease in the density of excitatory postsynaptic sites. To further investigate ultrastructural aspects of excitatory synapses I carried out electron microscopical studies of cerebral cortex to measure the abundance of NR2 receptor subunits of the NMDA receptor- a receptor site directly associated with excitatory postsynaptic scaffold proteins. This study revealed that NR2 immunoreactive sites were largely preserved during age-related cognitive decline with an uneven profile distribution. Finally, protein expression of specific receptor subunits and key proteins representative of excitatory and inhibitory postsynaptic sites was investigated by semi-quantitative Western blot analyses in selected cortical areas. It was clear that many of these postsynaptic proteins are affected by age and cognitive status. The most striking change was a marked up-regulation in neuroligin-1 in AI animals, which may affect the delicate balance between excitatory versus inhibitory synaptic inputs. Another notable finding was the down-regulated expression of GluR2 receptor subunits in AI animals, which should have implications for neuronal Ca2+ regulation. In conclusion, we have demonstrated the greater vulnerability of excitatory postsynaptic sites in aged and cognitively impaired animals.</description><creator>Majdi, Maryam.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Aging -- physiology.</subject><subject>Synapses -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Gene Expression Regulation -- physiology.</subject><subject>Cognition Disorders -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Rats.</subject><subject>Cerebral Cortex -- metabolism.</subject><title>Brain ageing : cognitive status and cortical synapses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v197b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182p62b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fc747</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerical analysis of the electromagnetic fields in large, complex structures is very challenging due to the high computational overhead. Recently, it has been shown that a new method called Trefftz-FLAME ( Flexible Local Approximation MEthod) is suitable for problems where there exist a large number of similar structures. This thesis develops Trefftz-FLAME in two areas. First, a novel 2D Trefftz-FLAME method incorporates the modal analysis and port boundary condition that are essential to an accurate calculation of reflection and transmission coefficients for photonic crystal devices. The new technique outperforms existing methods in both accuracy and computational cost. The second area pertains to the 3D, vector problem of electromagnetic wave scattering by aggregates of identical dielectric particles. A methodology for the development of local basis functions is introduced, applicable to particles of any shape and composition. Boundary conditions on the surface of the finite FLAME domain are described, capable of representing the incident wave and absorbing the outgoing radiation. A series of problems involving dielectric spheres is solved to validate the new method. Comparison with exact solutions is possible in some cases and shows that the method is able to produce accurate near-field results even when the computational grid spacing is equal to the radius of the spheres.</description><creator>Pinheiro, Helder Fleury, 1967-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Electromagnetic waves -- Scattering -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Photonic crystals.</subject><subject>Optoelectronic devices -- Design and construction.</subject><subject>Optical wave guides -- Design and construction.</subject><title>The application of Trefftz-FLAME to electromagnetic wave problems /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd488.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc747</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f954x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pain requiring treatment is experienced by many cancer patients at the end of life. When these patients stay at home, family caregivers are often directly implicated in pain management. There are few studies that examine the process that these family caregivers engage in when they take on the responsibility of pain management. This means we need information on whether or not these family caregivers are prepared for management to ensure proper support and optimal pain control. The purpose of this qualitative study was to study the process used by family caregivers at home to manage the pain of palliative cancer patients using a grounded theory approach. A total of 24 family caregivers with differing relationships to the patient and differing lengths of caregiver experience participated. Family caregivers were recruited using purposeful then theoretical sampling. The data sources were taped, transcribed (semi-structured) interviews, field notes, and memos. Data analysis used Strauss &amp; Corbin's (1998) suggestions for substantive coding: open, axial, and selective coding. The results lead to the proposition of an explanatory theory titled "the puzzle of pain management," which include: 1) a frame of the process of "drawing on past experiences"; 2) puzzle pieces representing the process "strategizing a game plan" which include the sub-processes of "accepting responsibility," "seeking information," and "establishing a pain management relationship"; 3) puzzle pieces representing the process of "striving to respond to pain" which include the sub-processes of "determining the characteristics of pain," "implementing a strategy for pain relief," and "verifying if pain relief strategies were successful; and 4) "gauging the best fit," a decision-making process that joins the two pieces of the puzzle. The realization that family caregivers assemble a puzzle of processes indicates that there are factors that nurses must be aware of before creating, teaching, and implementing interventions for pain management. Furthermore, the results provide information to create and subsequently administer interventions based on caregivers' existing knowledge, identified needs for information and support, and current pain management regimens. The puzzle of pain management must be validated by further studies using this theory, in part, to help create interventions that will allow us to know how useful the theory is in practice. </description><creator>Mehta, Anita, 1973-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Pain -- therapy.</subject><subject>Caregivers -- psychology.</subject><subject>Neoplasms -- complications.</subject><subject>Palliative Care -- psychology.</subject><subject>Home Nursing -- psychology.</subject><title>Family caregivers of palliative cancer patients at home : the puzzle of pain management</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw30r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f954x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kx368</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Myelin and oligodendrocytes (OLGs) are the apparent targets of the immune-mediated injury that underlies the development of multiple sclerosis (M8). Recovery from M8 clinical relapses likely reflects remyelination attributed to recruitment and differentiation of oligodendrocyte progenitor cells (OPCs), rather than to new process formation by previously myelinating OLGs. Newly emerging M8-directed immuno-modulatory therapies (statins and FTY720) can readily cross the blood-brain barrier and have been shown to impact signaling pathways implicated in cytoskeletal regulation, differentiation, migration, and survival; these are cellular events presumably important for myelin integrity and remyelination. Statins inhibit the production of cholesterol (concentrated in the myelin membrane) and isoprenoids (post-translational attachments regulating the functions of proteins such as the Rho GTPases). We showed that treatment of human and rodent-derived OPCs with lipophilic statins induced an initial process extension associated with enhanced differentiation and impaired spontaneous migration, whereas prolonged treatment induced process retraction and cell death. Rodent and human mature OLGs demonstrated similar cytoskeletal and survival responses. Chronic simvastatin therapy of mice inhibited remyelination following demyelination induced by the OLG toxin, cuprizone, attributed to a block in OPC differentiation and consequent decrease in mature OLGs. Even fully myelinated animals treated with simvastatin over the long-term demonstrated a decrease in myelin in the brain by maintaining oligodendroglial cells in the pre-OLG state and preventing continual replacement of mature OLGs. FTY720 is an agonist of G-protein-coupled receptors S1P1, 3, 4, and 5, that are associated with distinct receptor isotype-selective activation of Rho GTPases. In human OPCs, FTY720 could induce initial S1P3/5-dependent process retraction associated with an inhibition of differentiation, and subsequent S1P1-dependent process extension. Mature OLGs showed a dose-dependent cyclic modulation of process extension and retraction was observed over time. Both human OPCs and OLGs were rescued by FTY720 under death-promoting environments. Both cell types also demonstrated a cyclic and reciprocal modulation of S1P1 and S1P5 mRNA levels, reflected in the recurring receptor isotype-dependent functional responses over time. Studies using organotypic cerebellar slice cultures demonstrated that FTY720 did not impact myelin integrity under basal conditions, yet accelerated remyelination following lysolecithin-induced demyelination. Both treatment regimens were associated with an extension of OPC and mature OLG processes. Our observations demonstrate that drug concentrations used to modulate immune function can have differential dose and time-dependent effects on OPCs, OLGs, as well as on myelin and remyelination processes. Our findings indicate the need to monitor the effects of putative immuno-modulatory therapies on myelin-related processes in MS patients.</description><creator>Miron, Veronique.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Immunosuppressive Agents -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Multiple Sclerosis -- drug therapy.</subject><subject>Propylene Glycols -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Immunosuppressive Agents -- adverse effects.</subject><subject>Propylene Glycols -- adverse effects.</subject><subject>Central Nervous System -- drug effects.</subject><title>The effects of CNS-accessible multiple sclerosis-directed immuno-modulatory therapies on oligodendroglial lineage cells, myelin maintenance, and remyelination /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn92w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx368</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b26m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mechanisms of post-transcriptional control are critical to deploy RNAs and proteins asymmetrically to a discrete region of cytoplasm at the posterior of the Drosophila oocyte and embryo, called the pole plasm and thus allow differentiation of the germline. Research presented in this thesis investigates the post-transcriptional control of Drosophila pole plasm component germ cell-less (gcl ). Maternal gcl activity is required for germ cell specification and gcl RNA and protein accumulate asymmetrically in the pole plasm. gcl RNA, but not Gcl protein, is also detected in somatic regions of the embryo, and ectopic expression of Gcl in the soma causes repression of somatic patterning genes suggesting that gcl RNA is subject to translational control. I find that Gcl is expressed during oogenesis, where its expression is regulated by translational repressor Bruno (Bru). Increased levels of Gcl are observed in the oocyte when Bru is reduced (i.e., in an arrest heterozygote) and Bru overexpression reduces the amount of Gcl. Consistent with this, reduction of the maternal dosage of Bru leads to ectopic Gcl expression in the embryo, which, in turn, causes repression of anterior huckebein RNA expression. Bruno binds directly to the gcl3'UTR in vitro, but surprisingly, this binding is largely independent of a Bruno Response Element (BRE) in the gcl 3'UTR and depends upon a novel site. Furthermore, the gcl BRE-like region is not required to repress Gcl expression during oogenesis or embryogenesis. I concluded that Bru regulates gcl translation in a BRE-independent manner. In addition, I established the role of the gcl 3'UTR in gcl RNA localization and translation using transgenes that replace the endogenous 3'UTR with the alpha-tubulin 3'UTR or place it in tandem to the bicoid 3'UTR. I find that accumulation of gcl RNA in the embryonic pole plasm requires the gcl 3'UTR. Moreover, Gel is restricted to the pole plasm by translational repression mediated by the gcl 3'UTR and a limiting pool of trans-acting translational repressors. The phenotypic consequences of loss of this translational control are relatively mild, suggesting that gcl translation does not require stringent repression in the soma.</description><creator>Moore, Jocelyn.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Embryology.</subject><subject>Gene Expression Regulation, Developmental.</subject><subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- Morphogenesis -- Molecular aspects.</subject><subject>RNA-Binding Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Nuclear Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Drosophila Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><title>Post-transcriptional control of Drosophila pole plasm component, germ cell-less</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d762w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b26m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj27w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Inflammation of the central nervous system (CNS) is important in many human diseases, and is regulated by a multitude of factors, including the cytokine interferon-gamma (IFNgamma). The importance of IFNgamma is highlighted in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE), an animal model of CNS inflammation. Mice lacking IFNgamma show exaggerated disease, with a different pattern of chemokine expression than the wild-type. We administered IFNgamma to the CNS using intrathecal injection of a replication-defective adenoviral vector to ask about direct actions of IFNgamma on chemokine expression without the confounding factors present during CNS inflammation. AdIFNgamma induced expression of CXCL10 and CCL5, two chemokines strikingly absent in Ifng-/- EAE. Chemokine expression was not associated with inflammation, though when an infectious stimulus was administered, an influx of immune cells to the CNS was seen. Using AdIFNgamma to restore IFNgamma to Ifng-/- mice with EAE had a disease-limiting effect. We used vectors encoding CXCL10 or CCL5, to replace these chemokines which are absent during Ifng-/- EAE, attempting to modulate the disease into a form resembling that of the wild-type. AdCCL5 treatment showed a mild reduction in EAE severity in the Ifng-/-, though AdCXCL10 treatment had no effect. A principal inducer of IFNgamma is interleukin-18 (IL 18), and IFNgamma induces IL18-binding protein (IL18bp) which inhibits IL18, establishing a negative feedback loop. We found that ILl8bp expression is upregulated in wild-type mice with EAE, but not in the Ifng-/-, suggesting that the exaggerated disease of the Ifng -/- may be due in part to unrestrained actions of ILI8. Treatment with a vector encoding IL18bp (AdIL18bp) significantly inhibited EAE, without restricting immune cell entry to the CNS. Cytokine expression was shifted away from a pattern favouring Th17 development. AdIL18bp treatment inhibited EAE in Ifng-/- mice, indicating that IFNgamma was not required for this activity. We used a vector encoding M3, a chemokine-binding protein derived from MHV-68, to reduce EAE severity, showing the first use of a viral chemokine-binding protein in EAE.</description><creator>Millward, Jason Michael, 1976-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Nervous System Diseases -- immunology.</subject><subject>Interferon Type II -- biosynthesis.</subject><subject>Encephalomyelitis, Autoimmune, Experimental -- pathology.</subject><title>Interferon-gamma and the regulation of neuroinflammation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc75h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj27w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r886p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Development of a suitable animal model of AIDS is much needed in AIDS research to study infection and pathogenesis as well as to evaluate methods of prevention and treatment of HIV infection. Small animals such as rodents are attractive candidates for AIDS research due to the availability of various inbred and genetically engineered strains, extensive knowledge or their immune system, especially in mice, and the relative ease of breeding and maintaining animal colonies. Transgenic small animal models carrying entire HIV genome or selected genes have been instrumental to understand functions of HIV genes in vivo and their role in HIV pathogenesis. The type of cells in which HIV genes are expressed seems to be an import prerequisite for the study of HIV gene functions in transgenic mice. Mice constitutively expressing the entire HIV-1 genome or HIV-1 nef gene in CD4 + T cells and in the cells of macrophage/dendritic lineage develop an AIDS-like disease very similar to AIDS disease in humans. Similarly, expression of Nef in adult mice, using inducible system, results in the AIDS-like disease. This disease is characterized by thymic atrophy, impaired thymocyte maturation, loss of CD4+ T cells, increased activation and turnover of T cells, which can occur in the absence of lymphypenia, and non-lymphoid organ disease involving the lungs and kidneys. Susceptibility of adult mice to the pathological effects of Nef suggests that the AIDS-like disease in the constitutively expressing Nef Tg mice is not due to developmental defects caused by early expression of Nef. This model highlights the important role of Nef in HIV-1 pathogenesis. The high similarity in the disease in these Tg mice with human AIDS strongly suggest that these mice are a relevant model to study AIDS. This study further evidence that mouse cells can support functions of Nef and these Tg mice represent a unique model to study Nef functions in vivo in the context of the primary immune system. Moreover, the inducible Nef Tg model has given us the ability to control the level and time of expression of Nef which was impossible to do in the previously reported constitutive Nef Tg mouse models. These mice will be useful to study immune reconstitution since Nef expression can be turned off after withdrawal from dox.</description><creator>Rahim, Mir Munir Ahmed, 1975-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>HIV-1 -- growth &amp; development.</subject><subject>Mice, Transgenic.</subject><subject>CD4-Positive T-Lymphocytes -- immunology.</subject><subject>Disease Models, Animal.</subject><subject>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome -- immunology.</subject><subject>nef Gene Products, Human Immunodeficiency Virus -- physiology.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><title>Pathogenesis of HIV-1 nef in adult mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66347128.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r886p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92gb790</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The instabilities of shallow shear flows are analyzed to study exchanges processes across shear flows in inland and coastal waters, coastal and ocean currents, and winds across the thermal-and-moisture fronts. These shear flows observed in nature are driven by gravity and governed by the shallow water equations (SWE). A highly accurate, and robust, computational scheme has been developed to solve these SWE. Time integration of the SWE was carried out using the fourth-order Runge-Kutta scheme. A third-order upwind bias finite difference approximation known as QUICK (Quadratic Upstream Interpolation of Convective Kinematics) was employed for the spatial discretization. The numerical oscillations were controlled using flux limiters for Total Variation Diminishing (TVD). Direct numerical simulations (DNS) were conducted for the base flow with the TANH velocity profile, and the base flow in the form of a jet with the SECH velocity profile. The depth across the base flows was selected for the' balance of the driving forces. In the rotating flow simulation, the Coriolis force in the lateral direction was perfectly in balance with the pressure gradient across the shear flow during the simulation. The development of instabilities in the shear flows was considered for a range of convective Froude number, friction number, and Rossby number. The DNS of the SWE has produced linear results that are consistent with classical stability analyses based on the normal mode approach, and new results that had not been determined by the classical method. The formation of eddies, and the generation of shocklets subsequent to the linear instabilities were computed as part of the DNS. Without modelling the small scales, the simulation was able to produce the correct turbulent spreading rate in agreement with the experimental observations. The simulations have identified radiation damping, in addition to friction damping, as a primary factor of influence on the instability of the shear flows admissible to waves. A convective Froude number correlated the energy lost due to radiation damping. The friction number determined the energy lost due to friction. A significant fraction of available energy produced by the shear flow is lost due the radiation of waves at high convective Froude number. This radiation of gravity waves in shallow gravity-stratified shear flow, and its dependence on the convective Froude number, is shown to be analogous to the Mach-number effect in compressible flow. Furthermore, and most significantly, is the discovery from the simulation the crucial role of the radiation damping in the development of shear flows in the rotating earth. Rings and eddies were produced by the rotating-flow simulations in a range of Rossby numbers, as they were observed in the Gulf Stream of the Atlantic, Jet Stream in the atmosphere, and various fronts across currents in coastal waters.</description><creator>Pinilla, Camilo Ernesto.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Shear flow -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Wave equation -- Numerical solutions.</subject><subject>Hydrodynamics -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Water waves -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Shear waves -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Numerical simulation of shear instability in shallow shear flows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8384048.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb790</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gr78t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Understanding the stratigraphic architecture of geologically complex reservoirs, such as the heavy oil deposits of Western Canada, is essential to achieve an efficient hydrocarbon recovery. Borehole and 3-D seismic data were integrated to define the stratigraphic architecture and generate 3-dimensional geological models of the Mannville Group in Saskatchewan. The Mannville is a stratigraphically complex unit formed of fluvial to marine deposits. Two areas in west-central and southern Saskatchewan were examined in this study. In west-central Saskatchewan, the area corresponds to a stratigraphically controlled heavy oil reservoir with production from the undifferentiated Dina-Cummings Members of the Lower Cretaceous Mannville Group. The southern area, although non-prospective for hydrocarbons, shares many similarities with time-equivalent strata in areas of heavy oil production. Seismic sequence stratigraphic principles together with log signatures permitted the subdivision of the Mannville into different packages. An initial geological model was generated integrating seismic and well-log data Multiattribute analysis and neural networks were used to generate a pseudo-lithology or gamma-ray volume. The incorporation of borehole core data to the model and the subsequent integration with the lithological prediction were crucial to capture the distribution of reservoir and non-reservoir deposits in the study area. The ability to visualize the 3-D seismic data in a variety of ways, including arbitrary lines and stratal or horizon slicing techniques helped the definition of stratigraphic features such as channels and scroll bars that affect fluid flow in hydrocarbon producing areas. Small-scale heterogeneities in the reservoir were not resolved due to the resolution of the seismic data. Although not undertaken in this study, the resulting stratigraphic framework could be used to help construct a static reservoir model. Because of the small size of the 3-D seismic surveys, horizontal slices through the data volume generally imaged only small portions of the paleogeomorphologic features thought to be present in this area. As such, it was only through the integration of datasets that the geological models were established.</description><creator>Sarzalejo de Bauduhin, Sabrina, 1955-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Seismic prospecting -- Saskatchewan.</subject><subject>Geology -- Saskatchewan.</subject><subject>Hydrocarbon reservoirs -- Saskatchewan.</subject><subject>Petroleum -- Prospecting -- Saskatchewan.</subject><subject>Geology, Stratigraphic -- Cretaceous.</subject><title>Integration of borehole and seismic data to unravel complex stratigraphy : case studies from the Mannville Group, western Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds973.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gr78t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s109t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reverse transcription in HIV-1 (human immunodeficiency virus type 1) is initiated from a tRNA, tRNALys3, that is annealed to the primer binding site (PBS) in the 5' region of viral RNA. This tRNA, along with the other major tRNALys isoacceptors, tRNALys1,2 , is selectively packaged into HIV-1 during its assembly. The formation of a tRNALys packaging/annealing complex is believed to involve the interaction between a Gag/GagPol/viral complex with a lysyl-tRNA synthetase (LysRS)/tRNALys complex, with Gag interacting specifically with LysRS, and GagPol interacting with both Gag and tRNALys. In fact, Gag particles alone will package LysRS, but GagPol, which binds tRNA Lys, is also required for incorporation of the tRNALys. The model we propose for the tRNALys packaging/annealing complex predicts a possible interaction between LysRS and Pol sequences in GagPol, which might facilitate transfer of tRNALys3 from LysRS to the reverse transcriptase (RT) thumb domain where tRNALys3 binds. In this work, we demonstrate that, in addition to its interaction with Gag, LysRS also interacts with sequences within the connection/RNaseH domains in RT. Since these RT domains are not required for tRNALys packaging into HIV-1, the LysRS/Pol interaction is probably not involved in the transfer of tRNALys3 to RT. The LysRS/Pol interaction may instead be involved in tRNALys3 annealing since the connection domain in RT has been found to be required for this process. Also, since an interaction has been reported between Gag and Pol sequences in GagPol, we also investigated whether the Gag/LysRS/Pol interaction played an important role in stabilizing the Gag/Pol interaction, and found, using siRNA to LysRS, that it did not. tRNALys3 annealing to viral RNA is promoted by nucleocapsid sequences in Gag and by mature NCp7, and we have examined the roles of Gag and NCp7 in this process. Gag- and NC-facilitated tRNALys3 annealing to HIV-1 RNA were measured both in vivo and in vitro, indirectly by the ability of annealed tRNALys3 to prime reverse transcription, and directly by measuring the occupancy of the PBS by tRNALys3. While tRNALys3 annealing can be carried out by both Gag and NCp7, exposure (in vivo or in vitro) of the tRNALys3/viral RNA complex to NCp7 is required for optimum placement of the tRNALys3. This is indicated by 1) tRNALys3's reduced ability to incorporate the first dNTP, dCTP, and 2) its more ready displacement from the PBS by DNA synthesized from a downstream primer. It has been previously demonstrated that APOBEC3G (A3G) can inhibit tRNA Lys3 annealing to viral RNA, and we have used A3G to further dissect the roles of Gag and NCp7 in annealing, both in vitro and in vivo. Experiments studying how APOBEC3G (A3G) inhibits tRNA Lys3 annealing indicate that in protease-positive viruses, Gag-facilitated tRNALys3 annealing may only playa minor role. In vivo and in vitro, A3G only inhibits NCp7-facilitated annealing, and not Gag-facilitated annealing. Nevertheless, while Gag is able to show 70-80% of the annealing efficiency of NCp7 in a protease-negative virus, A3G can reduce annealing efficiency in protease-positive viruses to 40%. This appears to be due to the fact that, in vitro, the presence of NCp7 makes prior Gag-facilitated annealing susceptible to A3G. This suggests that in wild type viruses, any Gag-facilitated annealing of tRNALys3 to viral RNA that does occur is altered through an A3G-susceptible re-annealing by NCp7.</description><creator>Saadatmand, Jenan.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>RNA, Transfer, Lys -- chemistry.</subject><subject>RNA, Viral -- chemistry.</subject><subject>HIV-1 -- genetics.</subject><title>The packaging and annealing of primer tRNALys3 in HIV-1 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wc080.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s109t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q777g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of uniformity of heat transfer with respect to the effect of heat treatment was investigated by correlating engineering parameters with the quantified heat treatment effects. Differences in treatment effect in terms of quality, anti-pathogen and chilling injury (CI) control properties among commodities was studied by exposing them to different target temperatures. Similar effects were also evaluated and quantified within an individual commodity by a custom-designed device. This device, whose design parameters were based on a heat transfer simulation, insured that one hemisphere of a tomato was exposed to air at 39°C and 0.24 m s-1; while the other hemisphere was exposed to air at a lower temperature with a velocity of0.24 m s-1 or 0.12 m s-1. Single-temperature heat treatment was most effective in limiting pathogen development and varied according to the parameter measured: 38°C for hypersensitive response (HR), 36°C for tissue breakdown, 36°C, 38°C or 39°C for mycelium abundance, and 38°C or 39°C for lesion size. Bilateral differences in temperature across the fruit significantly affected disease control: decreasing temperature differences significantly improved the uniformity of disease control. Some of the effects of heat treatment on tomato quality, such as color development and resistance to CI, appear to be localized. A significant difference in redness was identified between heated parts and unheated parts of tomato fruits immediately after treatment; and the differences persisted during storage. Differences in lightness and chroma were noted on day 4. Delay in ripening caused by heat treatment was confirmed through the higher TA and TSS values of heated tomatoes or heated portion of partially heated tomatoes. The heated parts of tomatoes showed a stronger resistance to chilling injury. The effective temperature control range for CI was wide, but temperatures higher than 39.5°C for 23 h hot air treatment could lead to adverse effects. Differences in physiological effects between hemispheres in two chambers was reduced by directly decreasing the temperature difference between upper and lower chambers or relatively increasing the heating air flow rate, highlighting the importance of improving the uniformity of air flow around each individual treated fruit.</description><creator>Lu, Jianbo.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Tomatoes -- Postharvest losses -- Prevention.</subject><subject>Tomatoes -- Postharvest diseases and injuries.</subject><subject>Hot-air heating.</subject><title>Quantifying non-uniformity in hot air treatment using tomato as a test material for postharvest quality and disease control</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741w19w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q777g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72pb88g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interactions between the retinoic acid receptor alpha (RARalpha) and coregulators play a key role in coordinating gene transcription and myeloid differentiation. In acute promyelocytic leukemia (APL), RARalpha is fused with the promyelocytic leukemia (PML) gene, resulting in the expression of the fusion protein PML/RARalpha. Here, I report that topoisomerase II beta (topoIIbeta) associates with and negatively modulates PML/RARalpha and RARalpha transcriptional activity, and increased levels and association of topoIIbeta cause resistance to retinoic acid (RA) in APL cell lines. Knock down of topoIIbeta was able to overcome resistance by permitting RA-induced differentiation and increased RA-gene expression. Overexpression of topoIIbeta, in clones from an RA-sensitive cell line, conferred resistance by a reduction in RA-induced expression of target genes and differentiation. Chromatin immunoprecipitation assays indicate that topoIIbeta is bound to an RA-response element, and inhibition of topoIIbeta causes hyper-acetylation of histone 3 at lysine 9 and activation of transcription. These results identify a novel mechanism of resistance in APL and provide further insights to the role of topoIIbeta in gene regulation and differentiation. Studies to determine the mechanism by which topoIIbeta protein is regulated found that levels of protein kinase C delta (PKCdelta) correlated with topoIIbeta protein expression. Moreover, activation of PKCdelta, by RA or PMA, led to an increase of topoIIbeta protein levels. Most notably, in NB4-MR2 cells, we observed increased phosphorylation levels of threonine 505 on PKCdelta, a marker of activation. Inhibition of PKCdelta was able to overcome the topoIIbeta repressive effects on RA-target genes. In addition, the combination of RA and PKCdelta inhibition led to increased expression of the granulocytic marker, CD11c, in NB4 and NB4-MR2 cells. These results suggest that PKCdelta regulates topoIIbeta expression, and a constitutively active PKCdelta in the NB4-MR2 cell line leads to overexpression of topoIIbeta. In conclusion, these studies demonstrate that topoIIbeta associates with RARalpha, binds to RAREs and plays a critical role in RA dependent transcriptional regulation and granulocytic differentiation. In addition, I show that topoIIbeta overexpression leads to RA resistance and provide evidence that topoIIbeta protein levels are regulated via a mechanism involving the PKCdelta pathway. This work has contributed to an enhanced understanding of the role of topoIIbeta in gene regulation and brings novel perspectives in the treatment of RA-resistance in APL.</description><creator>McNamara, Suzan.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Leukemia, Promyelocytic, Acute -- pathology.</subject><subject>DNA Topoisomerases, Type II -- physiology.</subject><subject>Drug Resistance, Neoplasm -- physiology.</subject><subject>Antineoplastic Agents -- pharmacology.</subject><subject>Neoplasm Proteins -- physiology.</subject><subject>Oncogene Proteins, Fusion -- drug effects.</subject><subject>Tretinoin -- pharmacology.</subject><title>Topoisomerase II beta negatively modulates retinoic acid receptor alpha function : a novel mechanism of retinoic acid resistance in acute promyelocytic leukemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k16z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pb88g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494c79x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation presents solid-state NMR studies that probe the dynamic and conformational properties of polymers adsorbed on solid surfaces in the dry state. The systems studied include a series of ethylene based random copolymers where the binding group is modified, and two diblock copolymer systems where the blocks have different intrinsic mobilities and surface interactions. The thesis begins by looking at the structures formed by the adsorption of poly (ethylene-co-acrylic acid) (PEA), poly (ethylene- co-vinyl alcohol) (EVOH), poly (ethylene-co-vinyl acetate) (EVA), and polyethylene (PE) on metal oxide powders (zirconia and alumina). NMR spectroscopy, FTIR-PAS, and TGA were used to characterize the surface behaviour of the systems with comparisons made between the bulk and adsorbed copolymers. 13C CPMAS, 1H and T 1 relaxation measurements were all recorded with the aim of correlating the microscopic structure of the surface with changes in NMR data. The chain conformation of adsorbed ethylene copolymers was found to strongly depend on the binding strength of the polar sticker groups with the substrates. The chain dynamics of adsorbed diblock copolymers in the dry state are reported for the first time. Poly (styrene)-b-poly ( t-butyl acrylate) (PS-PtButA) and poly (styrene)-b-poly (acrylic acid) (PS-PAA) were selected to vary both the block size and the binding strength. Once again the primary surface characterization methods are NMR spectroscopy, FTIR-PAS, and TGA. 13C CPMAS, 1H, T1, and T1rho relaxation measurements were all recorded with the aim of correlating the surface structures with changes in NMR data. For the most part, the observed trends in the chain mobilities of the anchor (PAA) and buoy (PS) blocks with block size can be correlated with the predicted mushroom, intermediate and extended brush structures which collapse upon removal of the solvent. However, the chain mobility of the PS buoys decreases with increasing anchor block size. Although the chain mobility of the PS buoys are moderately enhanced relative to the bulk state, the mobility is sufficiently restricted to comfirm the picture of a thin glassy layer with adhesive properties similar to the surface of bulk polystyrene. The diblock copolymers poly (2-vinylpyridine), poly (isoprene)- b-poly (2--vinylpyridine), (PI-P2VP) and poly (isoprene)- b-poly (4-vinylpyridine) (PI-P4VP) were selected to complement the PS-PAA system as both systems have been studied by surface force microscopy. The large contrast in chain mobilities of the PI and PVP blocks allowed spectral editing through variation of the 13C cross polarization parameters. The trends in mobility with block size differ from that of PS-PAA in that the segmental mobility of the buoys increases with anchor block size as expected. The chain mobility of the collapsed PI brushes is significantly enhanced as compared to the bulk state, again supporting the interpretation of surface microscopy studies which require an entropically unfavorable flattened, yet rubbery, surface structure.</description><creator>McAlduff, Michael.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Polystyrene.</subject><subject>Block copolymers.</subject><subject>Metallic oxides -- Surfaces.</subject><subject>Nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Copolymers.</subject><subject>Polyethylene.</subject><title>Solid-state NMR studies of polymer adsorption onto metal oxide surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gk958.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c79x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vs06z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carbon (C) biogeochemical cycling studies in northern peatlands, in particular the production, consumption, storage and emission of C gases (CO2 and CH4) over space and time between different peatland landforms can help in understanding their current and future role in the global C cycle. In some peatlands, a distinct surface patterning of vegetation, interspersed with open water pools, controls the spatial and temporal variability in CO 2 and CH4 exchange to atmosphere. These open water pools initially develop from shallow, flooded hollows to deeper water bodies and at some point reach a limit in their depth. Observations link pool size to age and spatial location on the peatland surface and over time the proportional cover of pools increases, playing an important role in the long-term peatland C balance. The processes responsible for the production of CO2 and CH 4 in pools remain unexplored. In particular, the contribution of pools to the peatland C balance over the timeframe of the development of a pool complex is not explained and pools are not incorporated into current peatland models. A field study was carried out to examine the exchange of CO2 and CH4 from pools to atmosphere and to explore the spatial and temporal dynamics in CO2, CH4 and DOC storage in pools of different size and spatial location. This was undertaken to improve the understanding of the processes responsible for the generation of CO 2 and CH4 over the timescale of pool development. The empirical study was carried out during spring, summer and fall over two years in an ombrotrophic, raised bog, Quebec, Canada. A modelling component was carried out to examine the contribution of pools to the long-term peatland C balance. Measurements of dissolved concentrations and emissions of CO2 and CH4 from pool surfaces to atmosphere were different among pools of different sizes and spatial location. Shallow pools had consistently higher emissions of both CO2 and CH4 and higher water column dissolved CO2 and DOC concentrations. Deeper pools had greater concentrations of sediment CH4. Dissolved organic carbon in pools was allochthonous, with a greater concentrations and proportion from higher plant materials in shallow pools, likely contributing to the observed water column CO2 concentrations and greater CO2 emissions. All pools were supersaturated with dissolved CO2 and CH 4 at the time of sampling, with shallow pools up to eight times atmospheric equilibrium concentrations for CO2 and concentrations were up to one hundred times greater than CH4, comparable to findings in other global freshwater systems. Results suggest that greater decomposition is occurring in shallow pools due to warmer water and basal sediment temperatures and increased light penetration and dissolved oxygen (00) and that greater CH4 production and oxidation accounts for some of the differences reaching a limit at 0.7 m deep. Even though this range of pools are not as deep as pools found on other northern peatlands, the results provide evidence for the potential processes responsible for the generation of CO2 and CH4 emissions to atmosphere and demonstrate that pools have a significant role in the short and long-term peatland C balance. Modelling the hypothesised processes responsible for the generation of CO2 and CH4 shows that if sediment decomposition is the major source of these gases then the dynamical link between pool sediments, C gas production and pool growth has been demonstrated. Ultimately their role as source or sink is largely determined by their size (depth), the proportional cover on the landscape and their rates of C storage in sediments versus rates of C uptake and exchange.</description><creator>McEnroe, Nicola A., 1973-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry) -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry) -- James Bay Region.</subject><subject>Greenhouse gases -- James Bay Region.</subject><subject>Greenhouse gases -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Peat bogs -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Peat bogs -- James Bay Region.</subject><title>Carbon biogeochemistry of open water pools on an ombrotrophic raised bog, James Bay, Québec, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268879x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vs06z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602447v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stearoyl-CoA desaturase1 (SCD1) catalyzes the synthesis of conjugated linoleic acid (CLA) and mono-unsaturated fatty acids (MUFA) in the mammary gland of ruminant animals. We hypothesized that single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in the coding region, 5' and 3' untranslted regions (UTRs) of the SCD1 gene would influence the activity of SCD1 enzyme and consequently account for some within-breed variations in milk CLA and MUFA. Sequence analysis of the coding region of the SCD1 gene of Jerseys and Holsteins revealed c.702A→G, c.762T→C and c.878C→T SNPs in exon 5 in both breeds and c.435G→A in exon 3 in Holsteins. The SNPs resulted in: A (G435A702T 762C878), A1 (A435A702T 762C878), B (G435G702C 762T878) and B1 (A435G702C 762T878) coding variants in Holsteins and only variants A and B in Jerseys. Only SNP 878C→T resulted in a non-synonymous codon change resulting in p.293Ala and p.293Val protein variants or alleles at the SCD1 locus. Subsequent association studies found significantly higher C10 index, C12 index and C14 index and consequently higher concentrations of C10:1 and C12:1 in p.293AA cows compared to the p.293VV cows in both breeds. The SCD1 genotype had no influence on concentrations of C141, C16:1, C18:1 and CLA in both breeds. Sequence analysis of the 5' and 3' UTRs revealed no SNPs in the 5'UTR and a total of 14 SNPs in the 3'UTR of both breeds. The SNPs were in complete linkage disequilibrium resulting in 3 haplotypes or regulatory variants: H1 (G1571G1644C1763C2053A2584 A3007C3107G3208 T3290G 3497G3682A4399C4533G4881), H2 (G1571G1644A1763C2053A 2584G3007 C3107G3208T3290G3497G 3682A4399C4533G4881) and H3 (T 1571C1644A1763 T2053G2584G3007T 3107A3208C3290A3497A3682T 4399T4533A4881) in Holsteins and only H1 and H3 variants in Jerseys. A subsequent association study involving 862 Holstein cows, found the H1 regulatory variant to be associated with higher C10 and C12 desaturase indices and consequently with higher concentrations of C10:1 and C12:1 compared with the H3 variant. The effects of the H2 variant were intermediate to those of H1 and H3. 3'UTR genotype had no influence on the concentrations of C14:1, C16:1, C18:1 and CLA. The concentrations of C10:1 and C12:1 in milk fat could therefore be due to effects of SNPs in the open reading frame and the 3'UTR regions of the SCD1 gene. These results indicate that SNPs in the coding and 3'UTR regions of the SCD1 gene could be used as markers for genetic selection for increased C10:1 and C12:1 contents of milk.</description><creator>Kgwatalala, Patrick M., 1973-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Stearoyl-CoA Desaturase -- genetics.</subject><subject>Fatty Acids, Monounsaturated.</subject><subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Cattle -- genetics.</subject><subject>Linoleic acid.</subject><subject>Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide -- genetics.</subject><subject>Unsaturated fatty acids.</subject><subject>Milk.</subject><subject>Jersey cattle -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Linoleic Acids, Conjugated.</subject><subject>Milkfat -- Composition.</subject><title>Genetic polymorphisms in the stearoyl-CoA desaturase1 (SCD1) gene and their influence on the conjugated linoleic acid (CLA) and monounsaturated fatty acids (MUFA) content of milk fat of Canadian Holstein and Jersey cows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g6082.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602447v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r887z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:45:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Epidemiological evidence linking dietary folate deficiency and risk for colorectal cancer is conflicting. Studies using animal models indicate that timing, dose and presence of pre-malignant lesions will influence whether folate deficiency prevents or promotes tumor formation. In this thesis a new model of spontaneous tumor formation due to long-term dietary folate deficiency alone, in non-transgenic mice and without carcinogen induction, is developed. The mechanisms by which folate deficiency might influence cancer risk are also examined. BALB/c mice, with or without a null allele in a key folate-metabolizing enzyme, Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (Mthfr ), develop intestinal tumors due to dietary folate deficiency alone. On folate-deficient (FD) diets, 12.5% of Mthfr+/+ mice and 28.1% of Mthfr+/- mice developed tumors; mice on control diet (CD) did not. C57B1/6 mice (a strain resistant to other methods of tumor induction) placed on the same diets for the same amount of time did not develop any tumors. To investigate possible mechanisms the levels of DNA damage (dUTP/dTTP ratio and p-H2AX staining) and DNA methylation (thin layer chromatography) were examined. FD BALB/c, but not C57B1/6 mice, had a trend towards increased dUTP/dTTP and DNA double-strand breaks and decreased global DNA methylation compared to CD mice. To determine why the FD diet affects the BALB/c and not the C57Bl/6 strain, the expression of genes involved in folate metabolism was examined. Several changes in gene expression were observed. In particular, BALB/c mice had increased Mthfr expression and MTHFR activity compared to C57Bl/6 mice. Increased MTHFR activity may deplete 5,10-methylenetetrahydrofolate supplies for the dTMP synthesis, increasing the dUMP levels and, possibly, DNA damage. The levels of several DNA repair genes were also examined. Two genes involved in base excision repair, Thymine DNA glycosylase (Tdg) and Apurinic/apyrimidinic endonuclease 1 (Apex1), were increased in FD C57B1/6 compared to FD BALB/c mice suggesting increased DNA repair capacity. These results support the evidence that dietary folate deficiency promotes intestinal tumor formation possibly through increased DNA damage, with subsequent defects in DNA repair.</description><creator>Knock, Erin Heather, 1981-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred C57BL.</subject><subject>Colorectal Neoplasms -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Folic Acid Deficiency -- complications.</subject><subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate Reductase (NADPH2) -- deficiency.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred BALB C.</subject><title>Long-term dietary folate deficiency and intestinal tumor development in mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bs900.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r887z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz8063576</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:46:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cell adhesion is essential to cell motility and tissue integrity and is regulated by the Integrin family of transmembrane receptors. Integrin binds to ligand extracellularly and provide anchor to the intracellular cytoskeleton via adhesion scaffolding proteins. In order to link cell to the surrounding matrix Integrin needs to be activated. Intracellular activation signals induce perturbations in Integrin cytoplasmic domain that are translated into a conformational change in extracellular region for high affinity ligand binding. Integrin engagement by matrix, in turn, triggers the assembly of adhesion complexes. Such early adhesions promote cytoskeletal organization with subsequent contractile activity that exerts forces against initial Integrin-matrix adhesions. In response to force, Integrin strengthens the interaction with matrix through its clustering and successive recruitment of additional adhesion components. These bidirectional regulatory loops mediated by such interactions are largely dependent on the unique function of Integrin adhesion components. We demonstrate a novel role for the PDZ/LIM domain protein Zasp as a core component of Integrin adhesions. Specifically, Zasp colocalizes with Integrins at focal adhesion in cultured cells and myotendinous junctions in Drosophila embryos. In both cases elimination of Zasp modifies Integrin function causing consequently defects in cell spreading and muscle attachment. Zasp supports Integrin adhesion to the extracellular matrix that is required to withstand tensile forces exerted during cell spreading and muscle contraction. Furthermore, we found that the distribution of Zasp in muscle Z-lines is essential to orchestrate the cross-linking of alpha-Actinin and Actin filaments. Disruption of Zasp leads to loss of muscle cytoarchitecture, pointing to a larger role for Zasp in sarcomere assembly. Finally, we demonstrate that Zasp, in addition to alpha-Actinin, physically interacts with the Integrin- and Actin-bound cytoskeletal protein Talin. Collectively, our results point to a dual role for Zasp as a structural scaffold. First it regulates Integrin adhesion to the extracellular matrix by interacting with the head domain of Talin at the myotendinous junctions. Second, Zasp controls sarcomere assembly by tethering the presarcomeric alpha-Actinin component to the tail domain of Talin. Zasp finding as a crucial adhesion component provides further insights on the mechanism underlying Integrin-mediated adhesion.</description><creator>Jani, Klodiana.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Integrins -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Adaptor Proteins, Signal Transducing -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Integrins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Carrier Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Muscle, Skeletal -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Drosophila Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Striated muscle -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Cell Adhesion -- physiology.</subject><subject>Cell adhesion.</subject><title>The role of integrin-dependent cell matrix adhesion in muscle development /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j244j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8063576</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tc75p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:46:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transposons, also known as transposable elements (TEs), are genetic elements capable of changing their location in the genome and amplifying in number. Because of their ability to cause mutations in the host genome, often with detrimental consequences to the host, yet avoid being eliminated by natural selection, transposons have been labeled selfish elements or genomic parasites. However, the advent of genomics has allowed the identification of numerous instances where transposons have played a crucial role in host genome evolution. In this thesis, I evaluate the extent to which transposons have influenced the genomes of their hosts, with an emphasis on plant genomes. I review the present knowledge of different mechanisms by which this is achieved and provide examples to illustrate them. Next, I tackle the problem of annotating transposons in the completed genomic sequence of domestic rice by comparing RepeatMasker, the standard approach used in transposon annotation, with an alternative approach employing hidden Markov models. In addition, I perform a genome-wide analysis of gene fragment capture by rice Mutator-like transposons. I conclude that, while this is a widespread phenomenon in rice, it is unlikely to represent a major force in generating novel protein-coding genes. Nevertheless, the duplicated gene fragments that are transcribed may playa role in the regulation of host genes they arose from via an RNAi-like mechanism. Finally, I conduct an in silico analysis of a gene family derived from a domesticated Mutator-like transposase, called MUSTANG (MUG), in conjunction with an experimental characterization of the MUG family in Arabidopsis. The results of the study indicate that the MUG family arose in a common ancestor of flowering plants and that the Arabidopsis genes AtMUG1 and/or AtMUG2 may act as global regulators of mitochondrial function. I conclude that our appreciation of the role of transposons in host function and evolution will undoubtedly continue to grow as our understanding of these processes deepens.</description><creator>Juretic, Nikoleta.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Transposons.</subject><subject>Plant genomes.</subject><subject>Arabidopsis -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Rice -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>The role of transposons in shaping plant genomes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dk12c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc75p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v629z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:46:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oligodendrocyte progenitors are highly sensitive to oxidative insults. Among the factors postulated to contribute to this susceptibility are high levels of intracellular iron and low antioxidant content. During ischemia, the neurotransmitter dopamine (DA) is released and may contribute to oxidative stress and oligodendrocyte injury in the hypomyelinating disorder, periventricular leucomalacia (PVL). In this thesis, I investigated the role of iron in DA-induced toxicity in primary cultures of oligodendrocyte progenitors, and assessed the contribution of the antioxidant defenses (glutathione (GSH), glutathione peroxidase (GPx) and superoxide dismutase (SOD)) and other survival factors (heat shock proteins and the protein kinase Akt) in determining the response of the cells to DA. Addition of iron to cultures increased DA-induced expression of the stress protein heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1), and toxicity as assessed by mitochondrial activity, cellular release of lactate dehydrogenase, nuclear condensation and caspase-3 activation. In contrast, an iron chelator reduced these events. Furthermore, DA induced accumulation of superoxide, which was also reduced by the iron chelator. Surprisingly, a mimetic of the superoxide detoxifying enzyme, SOD potentiated DA toxicity, suggesting that generation of hydrogen peroxide via superoxide dismutation may be contributing to toxicity. Both a mimetic of the peroxide-scavenging enzyme, GPx and a GSH analog blocked DA-induced superoxide accumulation, HO-1 expression and caspase-3 activation. In addition, the GPx mimetic blocked caspase-3 activation induced by the combination of DA with iron. In contrast, an inhibitor of glutathione synthesis potentiated DA-induced HO-1 expression and cell death. Finally, in further examining the cellular defense mechanisms, I found that various heat shock proteins increased in expression levels during oligodendroglial differentiation, however only heat shock protein-90 (HSP-90) was detected in oligodendrocyte progenitors. An HSP-90 inhibitor decreased activated Akt levels, induced caspase-3 activation, increased nuclear condensation, reduced oligodendrocyte progenitor viability, and potentiated DA-induced apoptosis. In addition, an Akt inhibitor alone exacerbated DA toxicity and in combination with the HSP-90 inhibitor caused synergistic potentiation of DA toxicity by enhancing caspase-3 activation. In conclusion, elevated levels of iron, superoxide, deficient detoxification of peroxides by glutathione peroxidase and inadequate defense by glutathione contribute to the susceptibility of oligodendrocyte progenitors to DA-induced toxicity. On the other hand, HSP-90 alone or in concert with Akt play important roles in oligodendrocyte progenitors survival following an insult that produces oxidative stress.</description><creator>Hemdan, Sandy, 1977-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Proto-Oncogene Proteins c-akt -- antagonists &amp; inhibitors.</subject><subject>Oligodendroglia -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Dopamine -- toxicity.</subject><subject>HSP90 Heat-Shock Proteins -- antagonists &amp; inhibitors.</subject><title>Mechanisms of dopamine toxicity in oligodendrocytes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s839w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v629z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm92b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:46:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cross-flow past a pair of equal-diameter circular cylinders, arranged in a staggered configuration, was investigated experimentally in a closed-circuit water tunnel at Reynolds numbers, based on the mean-flow velocity and the cylinder diameter, within the lower subcritical range. The wake formation process was studied employing dye-injection flow visualization and hot-film measurements. The main emphasis was placed on acquiring a physical understanding of the mechanisms leading to vortex shedding, and particularly on the effect of a forced oscillation transverse to the flow direction of either of the two cylinders. For comparison purposes, investigations were also carried out with both cylinders stationary. Experimental results showed that, for a reasonably large angle of incidence, the flow in the wake of a stationary cylinder pair could be characterized by two distinct periodicities, each of which was dominant on one side of the wake. Furthermore, for lower Reynolds numbers (Re &lt; 1.0x10 4), there was an integral relationship between the two Strouhal numbers, but this integral relationship was no longer maintained for Re &gt; 1.0x10 4. On the other hand, the flow around stationary cylinders for a small angle of incidence was characterized by a single Strouhal number, which remained approximately constant over the entire Reynolds number range. For all the cylinder configurations investigated the wake flow patterns remained essentially the same as those of the corresponding static cases, when either of the two cylinders was forced to oscillate with a nondimensional forcing frequency less than approximately 0.10. However, beyond this value, the wake underwent considerable modification vis-a-vis when the cylinders were stationary, and the flow pattern within the wake was strongly dependent on the value of the forcing frequency. In particular, there were distinct regions of synchronization between the dominant wake periodicities and the cylinder oscillation; these synchronization regions involved sub- and superharmonics as well as fundamental synchronizations. With either upstream or downstream cylinder oscillation, the wake on the mean-flow side of the downstream cylinder synchronized with the shear layers separated from its outer surface, whereas synchronizations on the mean-flow side of the upstream cylinder were caused by the periodicities formed from the interaction of the other three shear layers. The flow phenomena associated with the synchronizations were described in detail via flow visualization. The organization of the wake was strongly dependent on whether it was the upstream or downstream cylinder which was oscillating. The synchronized wake on the mean-flow side of the downstream cylinder at both lower and higher oscillation frequencies for upstream cylinder oscillation was observed to form either by the shedding of independent vortices or by the coalescence of two or more vortices. However, for downstream cylinder oscillation, although the synchronizations on this side of the wake at lower oscillation frequencies were caused by the shedding of independent vortices or by the coalescence of vortices, those at higher oscillation frequencies were the consequence of the coalescence of vortices only. For large incidence angles, the number of shear layers separated from the downstream cylinder which interacted with those separated from the upstream cylinder was critical in causing the synchronizations on the mean-flow side of the upstream cylinder. In most cases, the flow for all the cylinder configurations traversed between the same patterns as those obtained when the cylinders were placed stationary at their minimum and maximum transverse spacings; but there were also some situations where the oscillation of either cylinder pushed the flow outside the regimes associated with the stationary configurations. The synchronization ranges obtained when the upstream or downstream cylinder was oscillating were different from each other, and these ranges were much wider than the corresponding synchronization ranges for a single oscillating cylinder. For two cylinders, an analysis of the fundamental synchronization showed that the frequency range over which this occurred was much broader for upstream cylinder oscillation than for downstream cylinder oscillation. Also, the fundamental synchronization ranges for downstream cylinder oscillation were closer to those for single cylinder oscillation in comparison to those for upstream cylinder oscillation.</description><creator>Hayder, Mir Mohammad Abu, 1976-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Cylinders -- Vibration.</subject><subject>Structural dynamics.</subject><subject>Fluid dynamics -- Congresses.</subject><title>Cross-flow past oscillating circular cylinders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wk58m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm92b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67317541</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:46:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clathrin-mediated endocytosis (CME) plays a central role in the regulation of multiple cellular processes such as uptake of nutrients, recycling of housekeeping receptors and transporters, as well as for cell surface removal and downregulation of signaling receptors. Once endocytosed, cargo passes through early endosomes where sorting mechanisms traffic the cargo to the recycling pathway or to degradation in the lysosome. The general objectives of this doctoral research were to identify and characterize new players of the clathrin-mediated trafficking pathway to reveal differences between the abundant components of the trafficking machinery in two tissues, and to examine the mechanisms of endosomal sorting. We used subcellular proteomics to reveal the differences in components of clathrin-coated vesicles (CCVs) isolated from brain and liver and to identify new molecules participating in clathrin trafficking. We demonstrated that the ratio between the clathrin adaptor proteins AP-1 and AP-2 is different in brain and liver, which indicates differential functions between the two tissues. We also discovered that clathrin-light chains, which have been proposed for many years to be regulatory proteins in the assembly of CCVs, were less abundant relative to clathrin-heavy chain in liver and in non-brain tissues compared to brain. We identified a new DnaJ domain-containing protein, receptor-mediated endocytosis protein 8 (RME-8) that was detected in liver CCVs specifically. Further characterization revealed that the RME-8 DnaJ domain binds to the chaperone heat-shock cognate 70 (Hsc70) in an ATP-dependent manner. RME-8 is a ubiquitously expressed protein that tightly associates with endosomes, and its depletion causes intracellular trafficking defects. Moreover, we demonstrated that RME-8 depletion also leads to a decrease in levels of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), as a result of an increase in EGFR degradation. RME-8 knock-down causes decreased EGFR levels even in cancer cells lines where EGFR is generally protected from degradation. Globally this doctoral project revealed new insights on specialized functions for c1athrin-mediated trafficking in different tissues and allowed the identification and characterization of a novel protein implicated in sorting decisions occurring on endosomes.</description><creator>Girard, Martine.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Molecular Chaperones -- physiology.</subject><subject>Clathrin -- chemistry.</subject><subject>Proteomics.</subject><subject>Endosomes -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Rats.</subject><title>Proteomic analysis of clathrin-coated vesicles and functional characterization of the mammalian DnaJ domain-containing protein receptor-mediated endocytosis 8</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dw833.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67317541</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15250</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>