<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:16:42Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm01p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Based primarily on notarized farm leases, this thesis examines approaches to agriculture on the island of Montreal from 1780 to 1820. This source permits us to establish the crucial relationship between people and farms and to then link them to differences in capital investment, production and farming techniques. By understanding the common, day-to-day farming operations, we can address ourselves to the larger questions of what contributed to the state of Lower Canadian agriculture, a subject of contentious debate in Quebec historiography. The island of Montreal, already favoured by the geographic circumstances of climate, soil and location, was also a crucible for two profound changes which were occurring in Quebec society during this period--the beginning of a wave of English-speaking immigrants who would permanently alter the ethnic composition of the province's population, and the development of a significant urban market. In the 564 notarized farm leases passed in this forty-year period, half of the lessors were merchants and professionals, most of whom resided in the city and suburbs of Montreal. The farms of the urban bourgeoisie were on average larger and better-stocked than the farms of habitants, artisans and other proprietors. Most attempts at agricultural innovation and more intensive cultivation occurred on the farms of this elite, not on the lands owned by those with less capital resources: capital, not ethnicity, directed the approach taken to farming.</description><creator>Waywell, Jennifer L.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Farm tenancy -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</subject><subject>Land tenure -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region</subject><subject>Agriculture -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region -- History</subject><title>Farm leases and agriculture on the Island of Montreal, 1780-1820</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d601.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm01p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967489q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis argues that desire is a major theme in Samuel Beckett's dramatic works. Central to our analysis is Jacques Lacan's concept of the Desire for the Other, as the outcome of the human subject's division. We will investigate how desire is expressed at the level of Beckett's characters' utterance. The characters' attempts at and inability to achieve a reconciliation with their speech correlate with the impossibility of reunifying Lacan's split subject. The first part of our discussion focuses upon desire-as-paradox--the lack of will to desire and the continuation of desire--in Not I, Footfalls and Krapp's Last Tape, whereas Rockaby and That Time are indicative of the regression of desire leading toward the characters' death. The second part emphasizes the dramatic presentation of these plays, except for Footfalls. It will become clear that desire affects the performance and the audience, thus preventing them from attaining a unified perception of self and other.</description><creator>Wulf, Catharina</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Desire in literature.</subject><subject>Beckett, Samuel, 1906-1989 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Lacan, Jacques, 1901-1981.</subject><title>Desire in Beckett : a Lacanian approach to Samuel Beckett's plays Krapp's last tape, Not I, That time, Footfalls and Rockaby</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c01t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967489q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042v10s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Physical analogs to the statistical properties of a theoretical flicker noise model are extracted from published accounts of the character of the record. Analogies are drawn between the temporal scales of variability of sedimentary processes, and the spatial scales of acoustic impedance variability. A linear model is proposed as a first approximation. It is consistent with both impedance characteristics and the dual, cyclic spatial and episodic temporal, nature of the sedimentary record. This model consists of the superposition of independent random processes having logarithmically distributed correlation times. Processes occurring over some discrete frequency range define distinct scales of 'stability' in the evolution of sedimentary environments. The contribution which a range of frequencies makes towards the character of the impedance spectra is a reflection of the continuity of conditions favouring the deposition of a particular lithology. The magnitude of change at a particular scale is a reflection of the recurrence interval of effective processes.</description><creator>Agapeew, George</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>Geological justification of fractal acoustic impedance models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860814d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v10s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b5919512</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research attempted to examine the reasons why children and youths disclose their sexual victimization, as well as the manner of their disclosure, specific to the school setting. An original questionnaire was developed, and given out to all the school social workers from one social service agency. Each worker chose, non-randomly one case of sexual abuse disclosure. It was hypothesized that if a child or youth had decided to disclose their sexual victimization in the school setting they would do so in a planned and overt manner, choosing an adult with whom they had a close, positive and trusting relationship; a positive authority figure. Both hypotheses were borne out, although the strongest predictors of planned disclosure in this study, were that the victim had a positive relationship with the adult they told, knew them fairly well, and that they were being abused by their natural father or live-in father-figure.</description><creator>Barbeau, Andrée Yvonne</creator><date>1990</date><subject>School children -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Sexually abused children</subject><title>Childhood sexual abuse : disclosure in the school setting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nf791.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b5919512</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x254n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Large-area ICs require adequate defect-tolerance to achieve a reasonable yield. One concern is that the power distribution network is shared by a number of modules, and any single short between the supply (V$ sb{dd}$) and ground can disable all these modules. The object of this thesis is to evaluate the feasibility of incorporating circuit breakers in large area ICs, which provide protection against such defects by disconnecting the defective modules from the array. A critical analysis and comparison of MOS transistors and parasitic bipolar transistors as circuit breakers are carried out. It is shown that MOS transistors offer a better and a more practical solution than their bipolar counterparts. Several rules applicable to a MOS circuit breaker in a bulk CMOS process are defined and discussed. These rules, if strictly adhered to, are predicted to result in a design which is defect-tolerant, latch-up free and optimal in size. The design of a large MOS transistor, based on the Manhattan style of "waffle-iron" design is described. Results of two test chips provide the experimental validation of this design. The peak instantaneous current through the modules has to be known in order to realize a circuit breaker of optimal size. A preliminary analysis of a possible technique to estimate the magnitude of this worst case peak current for a CMOS combinational block is carried out. Finally a short discussion on the defect sensitivity of the power switch is presented.</description><creator>Madhyastha, Sadhana</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Design of circuit breakers for large area CMOS VLSI circuits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3656245.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x254n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n4533</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This project consists of two parts. The first part is a composition for orchestra of approximately thirteen minutes in duration. The second part, an analysis of the work, describes the music in terms of its form, harmony, rhythm and orchestration. The piece can be considered as a free rondo in the sense that it does not necessarily follow the usual plan of the classical rondo. This particular composition sometimes displays two verses in a row, thus trying to introduce some new ideas into this very old type of musical form. In terms of harmony, the work deals with two basic categories of chords. First, some chords are designed as to show different ways of combining together the two whole-tone scales. Second, the chords sometimes mimic the behaviour of the harmonic series by using a decreasing sequence of harmonic intervals from the lower register to the upper register. The rhythms of the piece mainly follow Olivier Messiaen's theory of added durations. Finally, the orchestration aspect basically shows examples of chords which are held still in a certain number of voices while they are slightly ornamented by other voices in the orchestra. This device has simply been named the technique of "simmering sound".</description><creator>Desjardins, Jacques A., 1962-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Orchestral music -- Scores.</subject><title>Les Chemins de Milarepa /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h865.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n4533</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf17c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this investigation was to determine, the difference in selected kinematic variables of the shuttle-racquet head interaction for players of different ability levels executing the badminton overhead forehand clear. These variables included, (1) resultant velocity of the racquet head at contact, and (2) time between peak velocity and contact. This study also examined the total horizontal displacement of the shuttle after contact, the angle of deviation of the shuttle, the time of flight of the shuttle, the angle of projection of the shuttle after contact, and the shuttle velocity after contact. Six volunteer male subjects were divided equally into three groups corresponding to their ability; novice, intermediate, and advanced. Data were collected using a high speed motion picture camera. The data did not establish significant differences between the three groups with respect to the racquet head velocity at contact, or for the time differences between peak velocity and contact time. However, it was found that the angle of projection of the shuttle as well as the flight time of the shuttle decreased with ability.</description><creator>Currie, Gary</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Kinesiology</subject><subject>Badminton (Game) -- Coaching</subject><title>Optimizing racquethead-shuttle interaction for an effective overhead forehand clear in badminton</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c95q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf17c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666568m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various methods of synthesizing the novel, highly congested bis(tris(trimethylsilyl)methyl) disulfide (2) were investigated. It was found that the oxidation of tris(trimethylsilyl)methyl mercaptan (1) with iodine in the presence of sodium methoxide affords a product whose $ sp{13}$C, $ sp1$H and combustion data are consistent with its structure being that of 2. In another attempt at the preparation of 2, tris(trimethylsilyl) methane with methyl lithium, elemental sulfur and iodine gave rise to 2 unanticipated products, believed to be bis(trimethylsilyl)methyl, tris(trimethylsilyl)methyl disulfide (3a) and bis(tris(trimethylsilyl)methyl) trisulfide (3c). Furthermore, trisulfide 3c was subsequently prepared by the sulfuration of 1 using SCl$ sb2$ or N,N-thiobisbenzimidazole. In addition to thiol 1, both 3c and 2 exhibited unanticipated multiplicity of $ sp{13}$C NMR peaks in the silyl region of the spectrum. As a result, efforts were made to explain these results by molecular mechanics calculations on the thiol, trisulfide and disulfide structures.</description><creator>Maher, Denise C. (Denise Christine)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Studies towards the synthesis of superhindered polysulfides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf47b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666568m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n53p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new ion plating deposition technique, known as vacuum arc deposition, was tested for the first time using a graphite cathode in low-pressure hydrogen and led to the formation of diamondlike, graphitic and amorphous carbon thin films. The angular distribution of the ionic flux was measured in vacuum as well as under hydrogen pressures. The flux J was found to follow an exponential function of the solid angle $ Omega$ subtended by a cone normal to the cathode surface: J = J$ sb{ rm o}$ exp ($- Omega sp2$ / k$ sp2$). Another angular distribution of the ionic flux which can be associated with the effusion of a gas from an enclosure by an orifice is J = J$ sb{ rm o}$ cos ($ theta$), where $ theta$ is the angle from the cathode surface normal. This distribution was tested but agrees less with experimental measurements. The ionic flux is attenuated with distance R to the cathode and gas density n according to J = J$ sb{ rm o}$ e $ rm sp{- n sigma R}$ where $ sigma$ is the cross-section of the carbon ions-hydrogen molecules interaction. The obtained values of the cross-section for a wide range of pressures are in the order of 10$ sp{-17}$ cm$ sp{-2}$. The analysis of the time delays taken by the ions to reach electrostatic probes proved that the attenuation of the ionic flux by the background gas was not due to the photoionization of the hydrogen by radiation emitted from the cathode spots.</description><creator>Douyon de Azevedo, Mario</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Etude du dépôt par arc dans le vide de couches minces de carbone sous pression réduite d'hydrogène</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g8657.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n53p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g632v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the problem of registration, merging and viewing medical images from multiple modalities for stereotactic surgery planning. A technique is presented, using volumetric rendering of tomographic data, to create anatomical perspective projections that can be easily merged with vascular projections. The geometry of the digital subtraction angiogram (DSA) projection is reproduced by the rendering process to enable registration between the DSA radiograph and the volumetric projection. The viewing parameters are calculated from the location of fiducial markers in the image. Each angiogram is overlayed onto a translucent volumetric projection of computed tomography (CT) or magnetric resonance (MR) data, rendered to give a matched view. Until recently, rendered medical volumes have been used qualitatively in the diagnostic and surgical planning process. Since the volumetric projections are matched to the DSA images, the complete set of stereotactic surgery planning tools can be used to identify points and measure distances in the rendered images. A point spread function of the rendering process is derived to establish a theoretical limit on the accuracy of the technique and is verified by experimentation.</description><creator>Collins, Donald Louis</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Volumetric rendering of medical data : applications to stereotactic neurosurgery planning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k833q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g632v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zr95v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purposes of this thesis are to examine experimental results obtained with subsurface irrigation of maize in 1988, and to provide preliminary plans and an economic analysis for the subsurface irrigation of maize in Richelieu County, Quebec. A mean increase in maize yield of 3.7 % was observed in 1988 on experimental plots with subsurface irrigation at the Charbonneau farm. However, a review of results obtained at the same experimental site from 1982 to 1988 indicated that the mean increase in maize yield with subsurface irrigation was 29 %. Plans for two possible water supply systems designed to provide 180 mm a year of irrigation water for the subsurface irrigation of 1,250 ha in Richelieu County were considered. An economic analysis indicates that subsurface irrigation using groundwater has the greatest net benefits with an internal rate of return of 22.92 % and benefit to cost ratios of 1.90, 1.72 and 1.56 for discount rates of 8 %, 10 % and 12 % respectively. However, much of the groundwater in this region is saline and its use for irrigation may need to be restricted. Subsurface Irrigation using surface water from the Yamaska River was also profitable with an internal rate of return of 17.31 % and benefit to cost ratios of 1.66, 1.46 and 1.30 for the same discount rates.</description><creator>Drouet, Marc Philippe</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Corn -- Irrigation -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Irrigation farming -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Subirrigation -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>An economic analysis for subsurface irrigation of maize in Quebec /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc44r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr95v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dd61h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work furthers the study of "Non-Governmental Organizations" (NGOs). It examines alternative Third World development strategies employed by them and the internal and external variables that may influence the formation or implementation of NGO strategies. A history of the growth and differentiation of NGOs follows an outline of the major channels for development assistance. The Canadian Catholic Organization for Development and Peace (CCODP), a major Religious NGO (RNGO), serves as the focus of this study. Four five-year stages are studied to determine how factors such as government, church, Third World recipients, and staff influenced the evolution of CCODP's development strategy. Case studies from Senegal, India, and Brazil show that CCODP has yet to be able to fully employ its development strategy. The principal hypothesis is that Church teachings and initiatives were more influential than other variables in determining CCODP's development strategy. This proposition was confirmed by this study.</description><creator>Dougherty, Michael Dennis</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Non-governmental organizations -- Canada</subject><subject>Economic assistance -- Developing countries</subject><subject>Canadian Catholic Organization for Development and Peace</subject><title>The Canadian Catholic Organization for Development and Peace : the shaping of an NGO strategy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q270t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dd61h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c8695</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Adult articular cartilage of many species including humans has a limited capacity for repair following injury. The hypothesis that this might be related to a lack of responsiveness to growth factors involved in growth was investigated. Cartilage explants from 4 child and 5 adult human donors were cultured in the presence of various growth factors. Incorporation of $ sp{35}$SO$ sb4$ into proteoglycans and $ sp3$H-thymidine into deoxyribonucleic acid used as measures of the biosynthetic response of cartilage. Young cartilage showed the ability to behave in an autocrine or paracrine manner to stimulate its basal biosynthetic rate. Immature chondrocytes respond well to somatomedin C (insulin-like growth factor, IGF-I) and insulin but there was no significant stimulation in old cartilage. This data suggests a specific loss of responsiveness to IGF-I in mature cartilage. However, adult cartilage was stimulated by IGF-I and insulin after prolonged incubation times. Adult cartilage could also be stimulated by the addition of fetal calf serum and to some degree by platelet derived growth factor, indicating that adult chondrocytes still have the capacity to respond to external stimuli. The relevance of these results is discussed.</description><creator>Benaroch, Thierry Ezer</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Biosynthetic response of young and adult human articular cartilage to growth factors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064705k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c8695</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gp553</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>McGill management certificates are credit continuing education programs. Perceptions of the benefits achieved through participation were investigated, surveying 1424 students in four cohorts: entrants, graduates, alumni and withdrawn. Goals of entrants factored into six categories: career development, gaining knowledge, fulfiling external requirements, personal development, personal fulfilment and networking. In almost all areas achievements matched expectations. Graduates reported significant improvement in career status, although somewhat less than desired. Irrespective of prior education, they were particularly appreciative of knowledge gained. In other areas, graduates without prior university education perceived more benefit than those with degrees. Women, though equally satisfied with the program's contribution to career development, reported slower progress in their careers than men. They experienced more personal development than men. Work experience and certainty of goals affected outcomes. Many withdrawn students attained their objectives without completing. Academic achievement did not correlate with career development or with graduates' perception of knowledge gained.</description><creator>Clark, Fiona</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Management -- Study and teaching (Continuing education) -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Continuing education -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Benefits adults attribute to their participation in a university continuing education management certificate program</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bc84q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gp553</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cm23z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a psychoanalytical study of the novel A l'ombre des jeunes filles en fleurs. It is specifically concerned with identifying the subconscious mechanisms that engage the creative process in the Proustian hero. The main character's belligerent relations with the real world augment his passivity and sense of powerlessness. As the story unfolds, the young Marcel's desirous nature is expressed though his private fantasy world, providing a revealing glimpse of the great literary works to come. The character's sado-masochistic and oedipal tendencies act as a catalyst for his creative energies, leading him to use his pen, as the ultimate instrument of his brilliant revenge on the cruel realities of life. The young Proustian protagonist's literary project is above all a magnificent attempt at domination that achieves the perfect metaphorical transposition, in the true sense of the word, i.e. transporting language into the all-powerful kingdom of creation.</description><creator>Berrouard, Sylvie</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922. A l'ombre des jeunes filles en fleurs</subject><title>La thématique du désir proustien ou le décodage d'une métaphor /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d103r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm23z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sx01d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent developments in CAD for electromagnetic devices have utilized knowledge-based programming techniques to simplify the task of design process automation. The ultimate goal is to duplicate the role an expert designer performs in synthesizing devices such as transformers, motors, and actuators. A missing quality from these CAD systems is a convenient representation of design space. Interval mathematics is proposed as a means of dealing with this elusive representation. The present work details an interval mathematics package that allows the user to put practical limits on certain parameters enabling the program to deduce the valid design space of the device. This facility permits the system to recognize and eliminate impossible designs and to guide the novice designer through the true search space. Intervals may also be used in other types of expert knowledge such as if-then rules and heuristic "rules of thumb" derived from years of design experience.</description><creator>Brett, Craig, 1965-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>An interval mathematics package for computer-aided design in electromagnetics /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763813w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sx01d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429b440</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to analyze the frequency distributions of alleles at the 3$ sp prime$HVR (hypervariable region) and 5$ sp prime$HVR, two highly polymorphic regions on chromosome 16p. About 300 DNA samples from individuals of East Asian, French Canadian, Greek, Italian, Jewish and Middle Eastern origin were analyzed by hybridization to probes for the 3$ sp prime$HVR and 5$ sp prime$HVR. The distributions of alleles at both loci are skewed with the long tail towards the larger alleles. The observed heterozygosity at the 3$ sp prime$HVR locus for 281 individuals was 0.91, ranging from 0.85 in the Jewish group to 1.00 among French Canadians and East Asians. Statistical analysis demonstrated significant variation among some of the ethnic groups. The observed heterozygosity at the 5$ sp prime$HVR locus in 225 individuals was 0.75. Heterozygosity varied from 0.91 in East Asians to 0.61 of Middle Eastern samples studied. 28% of samples also display a RsaI site polymorphism near the 5$ sp prime$HVR locus. Genetic distance analysis demonstrated that the largest distance at these two loci exists between the Jews and East Asians (D = 0.119). Both the 3$ sp prime$HVR and the 5$ sp prime$HVR are extremely variable in all the populations studied, and thus will serve as informative markers for chromosome 16p for clinical as well as population studies.</description><creator>Marshall-Shapiro, Adele H.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Human population genetics -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Human genetics -- Variation.</subject><subject>Human chromosomes.</subject><title>Variation at two hypervariable loci on chromosome 16p in the multicultural population of Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt29w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429b440</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472x56j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Effects of acute and chronic cocaine on the respiratory pattern, and ventilatory responses to hypoxia and hypercapnia, were studied in awake and anesthetized adult rats. In addition, effects of the drug on vagal reflexes, respiratory mechanics and gas exchange were investigated in anesthetized animals. Acute cocaine elicited rapid and shallow breathing in awake rats. Ventilatory excitation, but not tachypnea, was present in anesthetized animals. In untreated rats, respiratory rate (f) increased during 10% O$ sb2$ and 5% CO$ sb2$ exposures; f decreased after cocaine, but in absolute terms, it was still higher after than before treatment. In anesthetized animals, augmentation of minute ventilation and f recorded in response to low O$ sb2$ and high CO$ sb2$ were higher with than without acute cocaine. Chronic cocaine depressed ventilatory responses to both stimuli in awake, but not in the anesthetized chronic rats. Neither acute nor chronic cocaine affected respiratory mechanics and diffusion capacity of the lungs. Finally, strength of the expiratory-promoting reflex increased following acute cocaine. The data suggest that while acute cocaine acts as ventilatory stimulant triggering behavioral polypnea, it depresses ventilation in chronically treated rats.</description><creator>Kelly, Gisèle</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Effects of acute and chronic cocaine on the breathing pattern and chemosensitivity in the adult awake and anesthetized rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm22k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472x56j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w336</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study surveyed the sexual behaviors and knowledge of Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS) among 117 undergraduate students from McGill University, Montreal. The sample consisted of 32 men and 85 women ranging from 18 up to 24 years of age. The total sample was split into three knowledge groups, Low, Medium, and High, based on answers provided to questions about AIDS. The data were analyzed separately for the total sample, men, women, and the three knowledge groups. The findings indicated that these students were relatively knowledgeable about AIDS (73.23% correct responses out of 21 items), but were engaging in high risk sexual activities. It appears that personal concern about contracting AIDS, not knowledge of this disease, is related to behavior change among undergraduate students. It was recommended that AIDS education programs focus more on increasing the personal concern than the AIDS knowledge of adolescents.</description><creator>Khehra, Nina</creator><date>1989</date><subject>College students -- Sexual behavior -- Case studies</subject><subject>Safe sex in AIDS prevention -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Sexual behaviors and knowledge of AIDS among undergraduate students</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf709.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w336</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf69j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose was to examine the effect of body mass and body composition on the mean power output in the 30 second Wingate cycling test at five resistance settings. Forty females (X = 22 years), were divided into four groups based on body mass and the sum of five skinfolds. The Wingate test was performed at the resistance settings of 0.075, 0.080, 0.085, 0.090, and 0.095 kp/kg body weight. A 3-way ANOVA (mass, skinfolds, resistance settings) indicated that: (1) mean power (W/kg) was similar for low and high mass groups; (2) the low sum of skinfolds group had a significantly higher (p $&lt;$ 0.02) mean power output than the high sum of skinfolds group; and (3) at resistance settings of 0.080, 0.085, 0.090, and 0.095 (kp/kg) the low sum of skinfolds group had a higher (p $&lt;$ 0.05) mean power score than the high sum of skinfolds group at equivalent resistance settings.</description><creator>Lopato, Marisza</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Body composition</subject><subject>Physical fitness -- Testing</subject><subject>Cycling -- Physiological aspects</subject><title>The effect of body mass and body composition on mean power output in the 30 second Wingate test at five resistance settings /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs12j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf69j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs13t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to explore the relationship between divergent thinking and Schmidt's schema theory of motor learning in a population of first year University physical education students. Problem solving teaching methodology was used as the intervention program in this study and the main sources of data were the Torrance Tests of Creative Thinking and tests of Schmidt's schema theory designed by the researcher. Descriptive data were used to explain the intervention program. A mixed model analysis of variance was used to compare the pre-test and post-test performance on Torrance Tests of Creative Thinking (TTCT), and the Pearson product-moment correlation technique was used to compare the results of the TTCT post-test and the Schmidt test. Results showed minimal differences attributable to the intervention and no relationships between the two tests. Analysis of the descriptive data suggests several limitations to the intervention program and some suggestions for further research are offered.</description><creator>Hodge, H. Jane F.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Motor learning</subject><subject>Problem solving</subject><subject>Physical education teachers -- Training of.</subject><subject>Methodology</subject><title>Divergent thinking and Sschmidt's schema theory as a function of problem solving methodology in physical education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d7776.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs13t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36tz79t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The rule-following problem can be condensed into the paradox that a rule cannot determine any course of action because every course of action can be made to accord with that rule. In his Wittgenstein on Rules and Private Language, Saul Kripke sees this paradox as potentially leading to a radical semantic scepticism that renders meaning itself meaningless, and attributes a sceptical solution of the problem to Wittgenstein. After a critical examination of Kripke's work, I conclude that this solution fails on account of allowing neither for a normativity beyond the subjection of the individual to correction by others in her community, nor for a non-interpretive conception of the understanding. Finally, I propose an alternative solution that incorporates the notion of communal background understanding into that of a form of life and thus preserves the normativity of rule-following and of language.</description><creator>Fultner, Barbara</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Wittgenstein, Ludwig, 1889-1951</subject><subject>Language and languages -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Kripke, Saul A., 1940- Wittgenstein on rules and private language</subject><title>Rules in context : a critique of Kripke's interpretation of Wittgenstein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x49w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tz79t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x255x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Lesch-Nyhan disease, concentrations of hypoxanthine are elevated especially in the brain and cerebrospinal fluid; dopamine and its metabolites are reduced in the caudate and putamen. Hence we investigated the possibility that hypoxanthine has direct effects on dopamine neurons. Hypoxanthine, adenine or allopurinol was delivered unilaterally into the rat brain. Behavioural effects were monitored by apomorphine-induced rotation; ipsilateral turning was time and dose-dependent. Turning was competitively blocked by a non-specific DA antagonist, suggesting that dopamine neurons were altered. In hypoxanthine treated animals, a D1 antagonist specifically blocked rotation; catalepsy occurred after caffeine administration. After two or three weeks treatment all groups had elevated purine levels in the caudate nuclei, while catecholamine levels were variably altered.</description><creator>Heshka, Timothy William</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><title>Effects of hypoxanthine upon dopamine neurons : an animal model for Lesch-Nyhan disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h21x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x255x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s599q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis examines the Canadian policy and law affecting those services sectors affected by the provisions of the Canada - U.S. Free Trade Agreement which relate to telecommunications, enhanced network services, and computer/information services. In particular, constitutional law and administrative law in telecommunications matters are examined. Also examined in detail are those provisions of the Free Trade Agreement which affect the regulatory measures relating to the telecommunications transport sector and regulatory measures relating to other services which extensively utilize telecommunications, computer and information services.</description><creator>Frits, Paul K.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Measures affecting domestic and foreign competition in the Canadian computer-telecommunications sector</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860815p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s599q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r4277</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:29:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite significant differences in the why, how and what of their interpretations of religious, our three authors (Muhammad Abu Zahrah, 'Abd-Allah Diraz and Ahmad Shalabi) understand religions, and in Diraz's case the religious phenomenon in general, through categories specific to an Islamic worldview. Their use of Western scientific methods to apprehend the study of religion is not systematic. It varies from Abu Zahrah's limited use to Shalabi's exuberant use, both being highly subservient to polemical intentions. Only Diraz shows familiarity and appreciation for scientific methods, without however subscribing to the epistemology of science which underlies them. The resulting relationship between the scientific study of religion and the Islamic study of religion, as epitomized in the fusion of my own commitments to the former and my authors' commitments to the latter, proves ultimately irreconcilable. Our respective epistemologies remain answerable to different centres of authority; the subjective self in the first instance and the objectified God, Allah, in the second.</description><creator>Brodeur, Patrice C.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Religions -- Relations</subject><subject>Abū Zahrah, Muḥammad.</subject><subject>Dirāz, ʻAbd Allāh, 1894-1958</subject><subject>Shalabī, Aḥmad</subject><subject>Islam -- Relations</subject><title>Contemporary Muslim approaches to the study of religion : a comparative analysis of three Egyptian authors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x04m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r4277</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>