<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:58:51Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):14600" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b215v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present the first year-long climatology of a new real-time global Lagrangian diagnostic system for stratosphere-troposphere exchange. This Environment Canada data set has been producing and archiving daily data since July 20th, 2010. A set of trajectories are calculated every day starting at 00:00UTC using the operational global forecast. They are seeded every 5 hPa between 600 and 10 hPa over the entire globe with even horizontal spacing of 55 km. We examine the mass fluxes across i) the dynamical tropopause,which is taken to be the 2 PVU iso-surface, and ii) the 380K temperature surface. Pole-ward of approximately 20o these two surfaces form a wedge called the Lowermost Stratosphere (LMS). The dynamics responsible for the transport across these two surfaces are very different. Mass flux across 380K, the upper surface, is driven by diabatic effects associated with the Brewer-Dobson circulation. Transport across the dynamical tropopause is dominated by quasi-isentropic mixing associated with baroclinic wave activity. The details of the transport across these two surfaces is known to determine the rate of injection of stratospheric ozone into the troposphere. This transport process is still today one of the major causes of uncertainty concerning the tropospheric ozone budget. Here we present the first one-year climatology of high-resolution global mass transport in the LMS, including geographical distributions and the Northern Hemispheric mass budgets, and will compare our results with previous studies.</description><description>Nous présentons la première année de la climatologie en temps réel d'un nouveau système diagnostique lagrangien étudiant les échanges entre la stratosphère et la troposphère. Ce système d'acquisition, en fonction tous les jours à Environnement Canada, de données produit et archive quotidiennement les données depuis le 20 juillet 2010. Un ensemble de trajectoires est calculé chaque jour commençant à 00:00 UTC utilisant les prévisions météorologiques déterminées par Environnement Canada. Ils sont dispersées chaque 5 hPa entre 600 et 10 hPa également autour du globe avec un espacement horizontal de 55 km. Nous examinons le flux de masse i) entre la stratosphère et la troposphère, i.e. au travers de la tropopause dynamique (2PVU iso-surface), et ii) à travers la surface à température de 380K. Dans les extra-tropiques, les deux surfaces se forment un region qu'on appele la haute troposphère et la basse stratosphère. Les dynamiques responsable pour le transport à travers ces deux surfaces sont très différentes. Le flux de masse à 380K, donc la surface supérieure, est déterminé par les effets diabatiques due à la circulation de Brewer-Dobson; alors que le transport à travers la tropopause dynamique est largement dominé par un mélange quasi-isentropique accompagné d'une activité de vagues baroclines. Les détails du transport entre ces deux surfaces sont connus pour déterminer le taux d'injection d'ozone stratosphérique dans la troposphère. Ce processus de transport est encore aujourd'hui une des causes majeures de l'incertitude concernant le budget de l'ozone troposphérique. Dans cette thèse, nous présenterons la première d'une année en climatologie sur le transport de masse global entre la haute troposphère et la basse stratosphère, incluant les distributions géographiques et les budgets de masse de l'hémisphère nord, et nous comparerons nos résultats avec de précédentes études.</description><creator>Paull, Georgina</creator><contributor>Michel Bourqui (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>David N Straub (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>A new one-year global lagrangian climatology of mass transport in the lowermost stratosphere</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2677019b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b215v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kx31w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Breast cancer is the most common form of cancer in women in the Western world and the second most fatal after lung cancer. Estrogens play a crucial role in normal breast development, but also contribute to mammary tumorigenesis. Estrogen signaling is mediated by intracellular estrogen receptors (ERα and ERβ), with ERα being a common target in breast cancer therapeutics. Two classes of competitive estrogen inhibitors have been investigated and proved to be useful for breast cancer treatment: full antiestrogens (FAE's) and selective estrogen receptor modulators (SERM's). A novel platform, FORECASTER, was developed in the Moitessier laboratory with the aim of integrating computational, medicinal and combinatorial chemistry. The successful validation of FORECASTER as a computer-aided drug design platform is described. In our quest for potent SERMs, this platform was used to build virtual combinatorial libraries and to filter and extract a highly diverse library from the NCI database. The virtual screening of a diverse library seeded with known active compounds followed by a search for analogs yielded a high enrichment factor. Moreover, the virtual screening of a designed virtual combinatorial library that included known actives resulted in a highly discriminative process. The laboratory of Dr. Sylvie Mader at University of Montreal showed that only FAE's induce a strong and fast SUMOylation of ERα in a variety of cell lines, strongly suggesting that SUMOylation is a general property related to full antiestrogenicity. A collaboration between the Gleason and Mader laboratories resulted in an SAR study of ERα ligands with different side chain lengths that revealed a specific side chain length of 15 to 19 atoms was necessary to differentiate SERM's from FAE's through the induction of SUMOylation. Histone deacetylase inhibitors (HDACi's) have emerged as a new and growing class of anticancer agents. Recent findings have shown that co-treatment of SERM's or FAE's with HDACi's can significantly decrease the growth of breast cancer cells. Inspired by the success of the vitamin D/HDACi hybrids developed within our group, and taking advantage of structural features of both kinds of molecules, we developed a new family of antiestrogen/HDACi hybrids. A first generation set of hybrids were designed by replacing the tertiary amide of FAE ICI-164,384 with three different zinc binding groups: hydroxamic acid, o-aminoanilide and N-butylhydroxamate. Both the hydroxamic acid and the o-aminoanilide hybrids displayed both antiestrogenic and HDAC inhibitory activities whereas N-butylhydroxamate hybrid displayed antiestrogenic activity but a poor HDAC inhibition profile. All hybrids inhibited MCF-7 cell proliferation and validated the proof of concept regarding the formation of this class of hybrids. However, none of the hybrids showed an improved profile compared to known antiestrogens or HDACi's. A second generation set of hybrids exploiting the same zinc binding groups with SERM- and FAE-like side chains were developed in an effort to balance the activity of our hybrids. Hydroxamic acids showed a consistent inhibition of HDAC's while displaying poor antiestrogenic activity in most cases. Ortho-amino anilides showed modest HDAC inhibition activity and only aliphatic-based o-amino-anilides behaved as antiestrogens. N-Butyl-hydroxamates showed a reduced potency to inhibit HDAC's compared to their hydroxamic acid counterparts but retained antiestrogenic behaviour. Overall, our second-generation hybrids did not show equal or improved HDAC inhibition and antiestrogenic activities relative to known antiestrogens and HDACi's. </description><description>Le cancer du sein est la forme la plus courante de cancer chez les femmes en Occident et la deuxième plus mortelle après le cancer du poumon. Les œstrogènes jouent un rôle crucial dans le développement mammaire normal, mais aussi contribuent à la tumorigénèse mammaire. La signalisation des œstrogènes est permise grâce à des récepteurs d'œstrogènes (ERα et ERβ), avec ERα étant une cible courante dans la recherche thérapeutique du cancer du sein. Deux classes d'inhibiteurs compétitifs d'œstrogène ont été étudiées. Certains se sont révélés utiles pour le traitement du cancer du sein dont les anti-œstrogènes complets (FEA) et les modulateurs sélectifs des récepteurs d'œstrogènes (SERM). Une nouvelle plate-forme, FORECASTER, a été développée dans le laboratoire Moitessier dans le but d'intégrer la chimie computationnelle, médicinale et combinatoire. La validation réussie de FORECASTER comme plate-forme pour la conception assistée par ordinateur de médicaments est décrite. Dans notre quête pour la découverte de SERM puissants, cette plate-forme a été utilisée pour construire des bibliothèques combinatoires virtuelles et pour filtrer et extraire de la base de données NCI une bibliothèque de composés très diversifiée. Un facteur d'enrichissement élevé a été obtenu par le criblage virtuel d'une bibliothèque diversifiée et ensemencée avec des molécules actives connues suivi d'une recherche d'analogues.Le laboratoire du Dr Sylvie Mader à l'Université de Montréal a montré que seulement les FAE provoquent une SUMOylation forte et rapide des ERα dans une variété de lignées cellulaires, suggérant fortement que la SUMOylation est une propriété générale liée à antiestrogénicité complète. Une collaboration entre les laboratoires Gleason et Mader est à la base d'une étude de relations structure-activité  de ligands ERα de différentes longueurs de chaînes latérales qui a révélé qu'une longueur de chaîne latérale spécifique de 15 à 19 atomes était nécessaire pour différencier les SERM des FAE à travers l'induction de la SUMOylation. Les inhibiteurs de l'histone déacétylase (HDACi) ont émergé comme une nouvelle et croissante classe d'agents anticancéreux. Des découvertes récentes ont montré que le co-traitement utilisant des SERM ou des FAE avec des HDACi peut réduire de façon significative la croissance des cellules cancéreuses du sein. Inspirés par le succès des hybrides vitamine D - HDACi développés au sein de notre groupe, et profitant des caractéristiques structurelles des deux types de molécules, nous avons développé une nouvelle famille d'hybrides antiestrogènes - HDACi. Un ensemble d'hybrides de première génération ont été conçus par remplacement de l'amide tertiaire des FAE ICI-164,384 avec trois différents groupes capables de se lier au zinc : le groupe acide hydroxamique,  le groupe o-aminoanilide et le groupe N-butylhydroxamate. Les hybrides acide hydroxamique et o-aminoanilide ont montré à la fois des activités anti-œstrogénique et inhibitrices des HDAC, alors que l'hybride N-butylhydroxamate a affiché une activité anti-œstrogénique mais une piètre inhibition des HDAC. Tous les hybrides ont inhibé la prolifération des cellules MCF-7 et ont ainsi validé l'hypothèse en ce qui concerne la formation de cette classe d'hybrides. Un ensemble d'hybrides de deuxième génération exploitant les mêmes groupes se liant au zinc, mais avec des chaînes latérales ressemblant à celles des SERM et des FAE, ont été développé. Les acides hydroxamiques ont montré une inhibition importante de la HDAC tout en étant de mauvais anti-oestrogènes dans la plupart des cas. Les hybrides o-aminoanilide montré une modeste activité inhibitoire des HDAC et seulement les o-aminoanilides aliphatiques se sont comportés comme des anti-œstrogènes. Les hydrides N-butylhydroxamates ont montré une activité d'inhibition des HDAC réduite comparée à celle de leurs homologues d'acides hydroxamiques, mais ont conservé un comportement anti-œstrogénique. </description><creator>Mendoza Sánchez, Rodrigo</creator><contributor>Nicolas Moitessier (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>James L Gleason (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Design, synthesis, and biological evaluation of novel antiestrogens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gk90w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx31w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741w10d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les plastifiants sont des adjuvants ajoutés aux formulations de plastiques pour les rendre plus flexibles et plus faciles à manipuler. Malheureusement, étant donné leur tendance à migrer de la matrice polymère et leur utilisation répandue, ils sont devenus des contaminants environnementaux omniprésents. Des études ont corrélé la hausse de certaines maladies à l'exposition chronique à ces composés et évoquent leurs risques en tant que potentiels carcinogènes et perturbateurs endocriniens. Notamment, il y a évidence qu'ils perturbent la formation de certains stéroïdes dont la testostérone et ainsi, agissent comme des anti-androgènes. L'importance de ce sujet a incité les chercheurs à développer des plastifiants ‘verts' pour éviter les effets négatifs associés à ces composés. Dans cette thèse, des composés alternatifs ont été testés pour leur effet anti-androgène in vitro avec la lignée cellulaire tumorale interstitielle du testicule de souris, les cellules MA-10. Des concentrations optimales de solvant et plastifiants ainsi qu'une durée optimale d'exposition ont été déterminées afin d'assurer la viabilité des cellules au cours des expériences. En employant les conditions optimales établies, des composés sélectionnés en tant que potentiels plastifiants verts, incluant les dibenzoates de 1,3-propanediol (C3), de 1,4-butanediol (C4), de 1,5-pentanediol (C5) et de 1,6-hexanediol (C6), ont été étudiés en mesurant l'impact sur la synthèse de progestérone. Les résultats de cette étude, appuyés par d'autres résultats de notre groupe, démontrent le potentiel du C4 en tant que potentiel plastifiant vert. </description><description>Plasticizers are additives to plastics that impart flexibility and the ability to process polymers. Unfortunately, due to their leaching potential and widespread use, they have become ubiquitous contaminants in the environment. Studies have correlated the rise of many health issues to the chronic exposure to these compounds and have suggested them as potential carcinogens and endocrine-disruptors. In particular, available evidence indicates that they disturb steroid production such as testosterone production and therefore, behave as anti-androgens. The seriousness of this issue has prompted researchers to develop "green" plasticizers to avoid adverse effects. In this thesis, a series of potential alternative plasticizers were screened for their anti-androgenic potential in vitro using a mouse Leydig tumor cell line, the MA-10 cells. Optimal solvent and plasticizer concentrations and time frame conditions were determined to ensure viability of the cells for the duration of the experiments. Using these optimized testing conditions, potential green plasticizers, including the 1,3-propanediol (C3), 1,4-butanediol (C4), 1,5-pentanediol (C5) and 1,6-hexanediol (C6) dibenzoates, were studied by monitoring their effects on progesterone synthesis. Based on these results and those of others from our group, the candidature of C4 is supported as a potential green plasticizer. </description><creator>Vanlian, Marie</creator><contributor>Viviane Yargeau (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Richard L Leask (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Assessment of anti-androgenic potential of candidate "green" dibenzoate plasticizers in mammalian MA-10 cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b6862.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741w10d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042x530</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le “spliced-leader” (SL) trans-épissage est un processus dépendant du spliceseome dont l'éxtremité 5' de divers ARNms sont remplacés par une séquence commune dérivant d'un SL ARN donneur spécialisé. À cause de sa répartition phylogénétique compliquée et sa découverte récente dans le tunicier Ciona intestinalis, un deutérostomiens, il existe deux possibilités d'évolution plausible pour le SL trans-épissage. Le SL trans-épissage est soit; un caractère ancestral qui s'est perdu plusieurs fois dans différentes lignées où il s'est inventé de novo dans différentes lignées, y compris les tuniciers. Une des fonctions connues du SL trans-épissage est la résolution de transcrits polycistroniques, cependant sa fonction concernant les transcrits monocistroniques est moins évidente. Il existe plusieurs hypothèses en ce qui concerne la fonction du SL trans-épissage de gènes monocistroniques, une d'entre-elles est l'assainissement des régions 5' non-traduit (5'-UTR). Mes travaux de recherche ont portés sur la répartition phylogénétique de SL trans-épissage dans les deutérostomiens et sa fonction en tant d'assainissement de la région 5' non-traduite pour le gène troponine I (CiTnI) de Ciona. J'ai créé des banques d'ADNc 5'-RACE coiffés d'oligonucleotide pour bien étudier les séquences à l'extrémité 5' de différents ARNms et ainsi découvrir un motif SL commun dans le Branchiostoma céphalochordé, le Saccoglossus hemichordate et le Strongylocentrotus échinodermes. Après avoir éliminé les courtes séquences reliées à l'amorce qui se sont crée au cours de la réaction de coiffe des ARNs et qui étaient apparemment cachées sous forme de complexes hétéroduplexes, les banques d'ADNc ont été soumises au séquençage 454 ultra à haut débit. La présence des séquences 5'-TOP sur les ARNms des proteines ribosomique et gènes de facteurs de traduction était un des indicateurs confirmant que les banques comprenaient des extrémités 5' de ARNm de qualité. Des extrémités 5' en communs, qui pourraient représenter des séquences SL, n'ont pas été observées dans les organismes examinés. Ce résultat appuie fortement l'évolution indépendante de SL trans-épissage dans les tuniciers.Pour examiner davantage le rôle d'élimination des séquences néfastes de la 5'-UTR postulé pour le SL trans-épissage, j'ai produit et utilisé un contrôle interne de transfection. Ce contrôle a été construit afin de valider des résultats obtenus il y a quelques années dans notre laboratoire, qu'un rapporteur expérimental de CiTnI qui contient un outron-5'-UTR non-épissé a une faible activité du gène rapporteur lorsqu'électroporé dans des embryons de Ciona. Ensuite, j'ai créé un nouveau rapporteur CiTnI pour évaluer la présence possible d'un élément néfaste dans la séquence du 5'-UTR. Mes résultats indiquent qu'il n'y a aucun élément néfaste spécifique, mais que la longueur du outron-5'-UTR retenu, en soi, mène à la faible expression du rapporteur TnI. </description><description>Spliced-leader (SL) trans-splicing is a splicesomal process by which the 5'-ends of diverse mRNAs are replaced by a common sequence originating from a specialized SL donor RNA. The patchy phylogenetic distribution of SL trans-splicing, including its recent discovery in the deuterostomes in the tunicate Ciona intestinalis presents two equally possible evolutionary histories. Either it is an ancestral eukaryotic trait that has been lost in multiple lineages, or, it was invented de novo in various lineages including the tunicates. SL trans-splicing has a known function in the resolution of polycistronic operons. However, for monocistronic transcripts there are many proposed but not substantiated functions, including the 5'-untranslated region (5'-UTR) sanitization hypothesis. I investigated the phylogenetic distribution of SL trans-splicing in the deuterostomes and its possible function as a 5'-UTR sanitization mechanism in the monocistronic troponin I gene (CiTnI) in Ciona. I produced oligo-capped 5'-RACE cDNA libraries to survey mRNA 5'-end sequences for common candidate SL sequences in the cephalochordate Branchiostoma, the hemichordate Saccoglossus and the echinoderm Strongylocentrotus. Following steps taken to eliminate short primer-related sequences created during the 5' oligo-capping reaction, and apparently hidden in the form of heteroduplex complexes, the cDNA libraries were subjected to 454 ultra high-throughput sequencing. Several indicators, including the presence of 5'-TOP sequences at the 5'-termini of mRNAs encoding ribosomal proteins and translation factors showed that the 5'-RACE libraries effectively represented the extreme 5'-termini of mRNAs. No common 5'-ends that could represent SL sequences were observed in any of the species examined. This result strongly supports the independent evolution of SL trans-splicing in the tunicates. To further examine the postulated functional role of SL trans-splicing in removing deleterious sequences from the 5'-UTR, I made and used an internal transfection control construct to validate the observation, previously made in our lab, that an experimental CiTnI reporter construct with a long retained-outron 5'-UTR showed low reporter gene activity when electroporated in Ciona embryos. I then created a new CiTnI construct to directly assess the possible presence of a specific deleterious element in the long retained-outron 5'-UTR. My results clearly indicated that there is no specific deleterious element, but that it is the length of the retained-outron 5'-UTR, per se, that leads to low TnI reporter construct expression. </description><creator>Levasseur, Liane</creator><contributor>Kenneth E M Hastings (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Evolution of pre-mRNA spliced-leader (SL) trans- splicing in the deuterostomes and its role in monocistronic gene expression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h788g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x530</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vv33q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Force and centre of pressure (COP) were measured during a forward skating task on ice using a standard hockey skate and a modified skate with an altered tendon guard and eyelet configuration which allows for increased dorsiflexion and plantarflexion. The objective of this study was to determine if those skate design changes would result in biomechanical changes in the skaters during forward skating. Both left and right skates were instrumented with a calibrated strain gauge force transducer system to measure forces and with an insole system used to measure the COP during the forward skating task. The modified skate showed a reduction of 14.5-24.3 mm in total anterior-posterior COP excursion (p &lt; .05). This suggests that the modified skate changes the biomechanics of the skaters. However, a full body kinematic study might be needed in order to study the exact biomechanical changes.</description><description>La force et le centre de poussée (CDP) ont été mesurés pendant le patinage sur glace en ligne droite en utilisant des patins de hockey standards et des patins de hockey modifiés avec un protecteur du tendon d'Achille plus flexible et une configuration différente des oeillets pour lacets permettant une plus grande dorsiflexion et flexion plantaire de la cheville. Le but de cette étude était de déterminer si ces changements de construction de patins ont une influence sur le mouvement biomécanique des patineurs pendant le patinage sur glace en ligne  droite. Les patins gauches et droites ont été instrumentés avec un système d'estimation de la force calibré et avec un système de capteurs de pression en dessous de la semelle pour mesurer le CDP. L'utilisation du patin modifié s'est manifestée par une réduction de 14.5 à 24.3 mm du déplacement total du CDP dans la direction antéro-postérieure (p &lt; .05). Celà suggère que l'utilisation du patin modifié a un effet sur la biomécanique des patineurs. Cependant, une étude cinématique du corps au complet serait peut-être nécéssaire afin d'étudier les changements biomécaniques exacts.</description><creator>Le Ngoc, Chau</creator><contributor>Rene A Turcotte (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>David J Pearsall (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Force and centre of pressure measurements during ice hockey skating with a regular and a modfied ice hockey skate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3014877.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vv33q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n630</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il est estimé que les changements climatiques auront une incidence profonde sur la distribution des espèces animales. Déjà, les impacts sont observés chez certains vecteurs de maladies qui migrent vers de nouveaux territoires, ayant des conséquences sur le risque de transmission des maladies chez les humains. Dans cette thèse, j'étudie le cas de la souris à pattes blanches (Peromyscus leucopus), dont le nombre de sites de présence augmente au sud de la province de Québec depuis les dernières années. La souris à pattes blanches est un acteur important dans le processus de transmission des pathogènes de la maladie de Lyme (Borrelia burgdorferi) de la tique à pattes noires (Ixodes scapularis) à l'humain.Les résultats obtenus fournissent donc des informations essentielles afin de guider les activités de prévention de la maladie de Lyme, et cibler les cites de surveillance. Je révise tout d'abord par une revue de la litterature, les facteurs potentiels environnementaux, géographiques et climatiques qui influencent la distribution de l'espèce à la limite nord de sa distribution. Je performe ensuite une analyse factorielle de la niche afin de mieux comprendre l'influence potentielle de variables climatiques sur la distribution de la souris à pattes blanches au Québec. Finalement, je modélise la niche fondamentale de l'espèce pour le temps présent en utilisant une combinaison de modèles de niche construite dans BIOMOD, et estime son expansion future selon trois scénarios de projections de changements climatiques. J'évalue, à partir de mes résultats, une expansion potentielle de la distribution de la souris à pattes blanches dans l'ensemble de la province du Québec d'ici 2050;un phénomène principalement lié à des hivers plus cléments et plus courts. </description><description>It is expected that climate change will influence the distribution of a number of species. As some of these species are disease vectors, changes are also expected to occur in the distribution of disease risk areas, which influence the disease transmission risk to human populations. In this thesis I describe the potential influence of climate change on the white-footed mouse distribution (Peromscus leucopus), a range that is expanding within Québec. The white-footed mouse is an important zoonotic reservoir for the Lyme disease pathogen (Borrelia burgdorferi) and is a vector of the disease's principal host: the black-legged tick (Ixodes scapularis). My results provide information to guide intervention activities and to target sites for disease surveillance. I first characterize, based on published literature, the environmental, geographical, and climatic determinants of the current range of the mouse. I then use Ecological Niche Factor Analysis to explore the influence of climate on the distribution of the white-footed mouse in Québec. Finally, I model the mouse's current fundamental niche at its northeastern range limit, using a combination of habitat-niche models from BIOMOD, and estimate its future expansion along three scenarios of projected climate change. I conclude by,predicting a potential expansion of the range of the white-footed mouse into most of the province of Québec by 2050, as a result of warmer and shorter winters.</description><creator>Roy-Dufresne, Émilie</creator><contributor>Gail L Chmura (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Virginie Millien (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Temporal evolution of the ecological niche of the white- footed mouse (Peromyscus leucopus) and its relation with the emergence of Lyme disease in Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mg34j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n630</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w319z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Worldwide CO2 generation is estimated to range between 25 and 30 gigatonne per year. Environmental specialists and legislators suggest that preventing even a small percentage of this CO2 from entering the atmosphere can help alleviate the emission-induced climatic changes. It is estimated that for the cement industry, each tonne of cement clinker generates approximately 0.8 tonne of CO2. Therefore, the mitigation of carbon dioxide has become a collective global challenge, where legislative efforts in many countries seek to mandate the recovery of flue gas CO2 in the near future. The concept of Carbon Capture and Utilization (CCU) presents a valid means towards the effective containment of CO2 in the cement industry and its long-term fixation through utilization in the concrete industry. Carbonation curing meets the criteria of less emissions and energy consumption by presenting proactive efforts towards sustainable construction practices in the cement and concrete industries. In this study, the basic concept of CCU in cement and concrete industry will be adapted to model cradle-to-grave scenarios for carbonation curing of concrete products, which are then compared to conventional steam curing to investigate the economic, technical, and environmental benefits. The energy consumption related to the different components of CCU, which include CO2 capture, compression, transportation and utilization, were optimized to yield the lowest cost of carbonation curing scenario. Given CCU's economic benefits and strength attributes, it is possible for cement and concrete industry to attain the levied regulated emission reductions, justify its environmental contribution and keep economical competitiveness. </description><description>La production mondiale annuelle de CO2 est estimée être entre 25 et 30 gigatonnes. Les spécialistes de l'environnement et les législateurs suggèrent que la prévention d'un pourcentage minime de ce CO2 relâché dans l'atmosphère peut contribuer à atténuer les changements climatiques induits par ces émissions. Il est considéré que pour l'industrie du ciment, chaque tonne de scorie de ciment produite émet environ 0.8 tonne de CO2. Par conséquent, l'atténuation de dioxyde de carbone est devenue un défi collectif mondial, d'où les efforts législatifs dans de nombreux pays cherchent à imposer la récupération des gaz de combustion du CO2 dans un avenir proche. Le concept de la capture du carbone et de son utilisation (CCU) présente un moyen valable afin de confiner efficacement le CO2 dans l'industrie du ciment ainsi qu'à  sa fixation permanente grâce à son utilisation dans le béton. Le durcissement du béton par carbonatation présente un moyen proactif pour réduire les émissions ainsi qu'à diminuer la consommation d'énergie dans la production de  produits de béton durables. Dans cette étude, la CCU dans l'industrie du ciment et du béton sera adapté à des scenarios pour modéliser le concept du berceau à la tombe  pour le durcissement de carbonatation de produits en béton. Ces scénarios seront ensuite comparés à la vapeur conventionnel durcissement pour enquêter sur les avantages économiques, techniques et environnementaux. La consommation d'énergie liée aux différentes étapes de la CCU, qui comprennent la capture, la compression, le transport et l'utilisation, ont été optimisés pour obtenir le coût le plus bas dans le scénario de durcissement de carbonatation. Compte tenu des avantages économiques du CCU et la résistance mécaniques des produits carbonatés, il est possible pour le ciment et l'industrie du béton à atteindre les réductions d'émissions réglementés, justifier sa contribution à l'environnement et  maintenir sa compétitivité économique.</description><creator>Tayara, Lana</creator><contributor>Yixin Shao (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Feasibility analysis for carbon capture and utilization in cement-concrete industries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn871.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w319z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mt32q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microresonators are crucial components of microelectromechanical systems (MEMS) used for communicating and sensing. One of the main objectives while designing microresonators is to minimize all sources of energy dissipation leading to damping. This thesis focuses primarily on dissipation at the points of attachment of the microresonator to the larger supporting frame, package, and test setup. The sources of such attachment losses include stress-wave radiation at the supports and stick-slip friction at the clamps. In the absence of accurate models for all such sources, it becomes necessary to analyze attachment losses by using the limits of thermoelastic damping for calibration. The implementation of this approach is illustrated by analyzing damping in single-crystal silicon microcantilever resonators that were previously micromachined and characterized. By examining the dependence of attachment losses on frequency and beam geometry, and using estimates for support losses, it is concluded that clamping losses are the primary source of attachment losses in these structures. Finally, to eliminate attachment losses, a new resonator design based on the concept of free-free beams is proposed and the microfabrication of the first prototype is presented.</description><description>Les micro-résonateurs sont des composants essentiels des microsystèmes électromécaniques et sont utilisés pour la communication et la perception. L'un des principaux objectifs  lors de la conception de micro-résonateurs est de minimiser toute source de dissipation d'énergie entraînant de l'amortissement. Cette thèse se concentre principalement sur la dissipation au niveau des points d'attache du micro-résonateur sur le support de dimensions supérieures et sur l'installation expérimentale. Les sources de pertes d'énergie dues aux fixations comprennent la radiation des ondes de contraintes au niveau des supports et les frottements de type 'stick-slip' au niveau des dispositifs de serrage. En l'absence de modèles précis pour ces sources, il apparaît nécessaire d'analyser les pertes au niveau des points d'attache en utilisant une calibration reposant sur les limites théoriques de l'amortissement thermoélastique. La mise en œuvre de cette approche est illustrée par l'analyse de l'amortissement dans des résonateurs en silicium monocristallin de type micro-poutre en porte-à-faux qui ont été micro-usinés et caractérisés à l'avance. En examinant la dépendance des pertes de fixation par rapport à la fréquence et à la géométrie de la poutre, et en utilisant des estimations pour les pertes au niveau des supports, il a été démontré que les pertes au niveau du dispositif de serrage sont les principales sources de pertes dues aux fixations dans ces structures. Enfin, pour éliminer les pertes au niveau des fixations, un nouveau modèle de résonateur reposant sur le concept de poutre à double porte-à-faux est proposé, et la fabrication du premier prototype est présentée.</description><creator>Hung, Sherman</creator><contributor>Srikar Vengallatore (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Damping due to attachment losses in microresonators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xw40h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mt32q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm137</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude examine la criminalisation de la dissidence qui se produit à travers le discours officiel anti-terroriste (et des politiques associées) au Canada. Même s'il existe beaucoup de travaux de recherche sur le terrorisme et sur les campagnes  contre le terrorisme, la recherche sur le discours du terrorisme et de l'anti-terrorisme devient une nécessité urgente, étant donné que le discours est un moyen de pouvoir et de contrôle. Actuellement, il existe peu de recherches sur les lois anti-terroristes et la criminalisation des dissidences au Canada. En examinant le contexte canadien et en se concentrant en grande partie sur les lois anti-terrorisme, cette thèse ajoute deux dimensions importantes à l'étude critique de la guerre sur le terrorisme. S'appuyant sur une analyse critique du discours – une méthodologie conçue pour exposer les effets idéologiques du discours – cette étude révèle le pouvoir dissimulé derrière le discours anti-terrorisme au Canada, et les processus par lesquels il est voilé et renforcé. Se fondant sur divers textes, l'analyse critique du discours des documents officiels anti-terrorisme (discours parlementaires, lois d'anti-terrorisme, et documents publics de police sur le terrorisme), cette recherche montre comment ces documents, soi-disant destinés à combattre le terrorisme, servent à criminaliser certains types particuliers de la dissidence et d'opposition en les traitant/ confondant avec le terrorisme et/ou la violence due aux actes terroristes. En déconstruisant ces diverses pratiques discursives (c.-à-d., textes canadiens anti-terrorisme), cette étude met en évidence les contextes et les intérêts socio-historiques qui influencent ces pratiques. L'étude utilise la méthode analytique tripartite de Fairclough Norman (description, interprétation, analyse) pour établir une base analytique descriptive, qui est ainsi employée pour établir et informer les deux autres niveaux de l'analyse. Le nouveau cadre  d'analyse développé dans ce travail – celui de la menace et de ces victimes – applique les différentes étapes d'analyse employées par Fairclough sur un corpus varié. En examinant de façon critique qui et ce que les textes considèrent comme menaçant et menacé (c.-à-d., comme vilain ou victime), et comment chaque catégorie est construite, l'étude dévoile le pouvoir et les intérêts derrière le discours canadien anti-terrorisme. L'opposition entre la menace et l'objet de la menace constitue un motif puissant qui pourrait être employé d'une manière descriptive, explicative et analytique. En dévoilant qui et ce qu'est la cible des textes anti-terrorisme, la recherche démontre qui et ce qu'ils servent réellement à protéger. En somme, cette thèse montre que le discours canadien anti-terrorisme et les politiques associées protègent en réalité la puissance et les structures du capitalisme mondial, visant et criminalisant particulièrement toute opposition et/ou résistance. Ceci a des implications sérieuses pour les libertés civiles et la participation à la vie politique au Canada.De plus, cette étude aura une importante contribution en matière d'éducation en permettant d'y inclure les fonctions idéologiques des lois sociales. Les lois anti-terrorisme et les discours associés illustrent la façon dans laquelle l'état canadien est engagé dans un plus large projet éducatif visant à façonner l'esprit des individus et à influencer leur interprétation et compréhension de ce qui est considéré comme terrorisme. Un des objectifs du discours et des politiques anti-terrorisme semble être la normalisation d'une manière particulière de penser le terrorisme et la résistance comme étant identique, et ainsi encourager le soutien public dans la guerre contre le terrorisme à l'étranger et dans  la répression de la dissidence domestique. </description><description>This study examines the criminalization of dissent that is occurring through official anti-terrorism discourse (and associated policies) in Canada. While there is vast scholarly work on the war on terrorism and attendant anti-terrorism campaigns, research on the discourse of terrorism and anti-terrorism is urgently needed, not least because discourse is a key medium of power and social control. To date, very little research exists on Canadian anti-terrorism laws and the criminalization of dissent. By examining the Canadian context and focusing largely on policies, this dissertation adds two important dimensions to the critical study of the war on terrorism. Employing Critical Discourse Analysis, a methodology designed to expose the ideological effects of discourse, the study reveals the hidden power at work behind anti-terrorism discourse in Canada, and the processes by which it hides and reinforces itself. Through a multi-text, critical discourse analysis of official anti-terrorism documents (parliamentary speeches, anti-terrorism laws, and public police documents on terrorism), the research demonstrates how these documents, purportedly aimed at combating terrorism, discursively serve to criminalize particular types of dissent and opposition by conflating it with terrorism and/or terrorist violence. By deconstructing various discursive practices (i.e., Canadian anti-terrorism texts), the study's critical analysis uncovered the larger socio-historical practices, contexts, and interests that inform and guide these practices. The study employs leading CDA scholar Norman Fairclough's three-part analytic method (description, interpretation, analysis) to build a descriptive analytic base, which is then used to build and inform the other two levels of analysis. The novel analytic framework developed—that of threat and threatened—unifies the different texts as well as Fairclough's different stages of analysis. By critically examining who/what the texts construct as a threat and as threatened (i.e., as villain or victim), and how each category is constructed, the study sheds light on the power and interests behind Canadian anti-terrorism discourse. Analytically, the duality of threat and threatened constitutes a powerful motif that can be used descriptively, interpretively, and for larger explanation and social analysis. By uncovering who and what the anti-terrorism texts target, the research reveals who and what it actually serves to protect. Overall, the dissertation demonstrates that Canadian anti-terrorism discourse and associated policies ultimately protect the power and relations of global capitalism, by specifically targeting and criminalizing opposition and/or resistance to it. This has serious implications for civil liberties and political participation in Canada.In addition, the study is related to and informs the field of Educational Studies insofar as it expands the notion of "education" to include the ideological functions of public policy. The anti-terrorism laws and associated discourses illustrate the manner in which the Canadian State is engaged in a broader educational project aimed at shaping individuals' hearts and minds over how to interpret and understand what constitutes terrorism. One intention of anti-terrorism discourse and policy appears to be to "normalize" a particular way of thinking about both terrorism and dissent (in a manner that conflates the two), and thus promote public support for the war on terror abroad and war on dissent at home. </description><creator>Chehade, Ghada</creator><contributor>Anthony W Pare (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Steve Jordan (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Education - Sociology of</subject><title>Anti-terrorism discourse and the war on dissent: a critical analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn889.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm137</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dz70v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les patients souffrant de la maladie rénale chronique et de la maladie hépatique peuvent exiger de la filtration sanguine extracorporelle pour éliminer les toxines de leur sang. Des matériaux absorbants sont utilisés dans des dispositifs d'hémodialyse recirculation et les dispositifs hemoperfusion, mais ils peuvent être coûteux à fabriquer. Des sphères actuelle et de particules en formé de matériaux absorbants créer de grandes chutes de pression quand ils sont soumis à un fluide passent. Pour résoudre ces problèmes, un nouveau matériau absorbant a été développé dans cette thèse en déposant de carbone activé et de l'alginate sur un treillis d'acier inoxydable en utilisant un dépôt électrophorétique. Un dispositif a d'abord été créé pour effectuer le dépôt électrophorétique et pour caractériser le processus tel qu'il est appliqué à trois niveaux différents de l'alginate. Les propriétés des gels obtenus ont été comparées, et l'alginate de viscosité moyenne a été sélectionné pour être utilisé dans le matériau sorbant. Les propriétés physiques du treillis sorbant ont été caractérisées. Le processus a été analysé dans le contexte de l'optimisation dimensionnelle. Le rendement des sorbants du matériel a été évalué pour l'urée, l'acide urique, l'ammoniac et de la créatinine, et il a été comparé à d'autres techniques d'immobilisations de carbone activées de la littérature. Le matériel a déjà été démonstré pour être prometteur comme une toxine du sang absorbant. Le processus décrit dans cette thèse est très polyvalent, peu coûteux, peut facilement être réalisé à l'échelle industrielle, et pourrait facilement être adapté pour une large gamme d'applications biomédicales. </description><description>Patients suffering from chronic renal disease and acute liver failure may require extracorporeal blood filtration to clear toxins from their blood. Sorbent materials are used in re-circulating hemodialysis devices and hemoperfusion devices, but they can be expensive to manufacture. Current sphere and particle shaped sorbent materials create large pressure drops when subjected to a passing fluid, further reducing the practicality of their use. To address these problems, a novel sorbent material was developed in this thesis by co-depositing alginate and activated carbon onto a steel wire mesh using electrophoretic deposition. A device was first created to perform electrophoretic deposition and to characterize the process as applied to three different grades of alginate. The properties of the resultant gels were compared, and the medium viscosity grade alginate was selected as the sorbent matrix. Alginate and activated carbon were co-deposited onto steel wire mesh to create a novel sorbent material. The sorbent gel physical properties were characterized. The process was analysed in context of dimensional optimization. A solution consisting of urea, uric acid, ammonia and creatinine was used to evaluate the sorbent performance of the material which was compared to other activated carbon immobilization techniques from literature. The material was shown to have promise as a blood toxin absorbent. The process outlines in this thesis is highly versatile, inexpensive, can easily be performed on an industrial scale, and could easily be adapted for a wide range of biomedical applications. </description><creator>Jackson, Christopher</creator><contributor>Satya Prakash (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Design and in-vitro characterisation of novel sorbent device for extracorporeal blood filtration and other applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074z49h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz70v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892f442</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Older adults display slower walking speeds, which could be attributed to an altered perception of optic flow (OF) speed. It has been previously demonstrated that older adults exhibit altered speed discriminations when exposed to expanding OFs. Whether these perceptual impairments explain slower and less context-adapted gait speeds in older adults remains unknown. The purpose of this study was to contrast speed discrimination thresholds and gait speed adaptations in young-old vs. younger adults. I also sought to determine whether speed discrimination and walking speed modulation abilities were related in older adults. Twelve young adults (23.0 ± 2.4 years) and twelve young-old adults (68.8 ± 4.4 years) participated in a speed discrimination experiment and two walking experiments. In the speed discrimination experiment, participants wore a head-mounted display (HMD) that displayed a virtual reality (VR) scenario depicting self-motion along a corridor. Participants were asked to choose which of two scenes that were played sequentially, moved faster. Speed discrimination thresholds were determined as the geometric mean of the last eight reversals. In the walking tasks, participants walked on a self-paced treadmill while wearing the HMD and viewing the VR scene showing OF speeds ranging from 0.25 to 2 times their comfortable speed. In the first walking paradigm, participants were instructed to walk the corridor distance of each test trial, which displayed different OF speeds, within the same time as during a preceding control trial that presented an OF matching their comfortable gait speed. In the second walking paradigm, participants were instructed to match their gait speed to the speed of the OF shown in the virtual environment. Walking speed modulation was measured as the slope between walking speed changes and OF speed changes (walking paradigm 1), and as the absolute error in walking speed with respect to the target speed (walking paradigm 2). Older adults showed larger speed discrimination thresholds, more attenuated slopes and larger errors in speed compared to their younger counterpart. Within the older group, speed discrimination thresholds were not significantly related to speed modulation abilities, as measured by the slopes and absolute errors in speed. These findings indicate that older age affects both the ability to perceive speed information from OF and to modulate walking speed in response to OF speed changes. It is suggested that poor visual motion perception may be one of the contributing factors leading to a mobility decline in older adults.</description><description>Les gens âgés ont une démarche plus lente, ce qui peut être attribué à une perception fautive de la vitesse du flux optique (FO). Il a déjà été démontré que les personnes âgées ont une capacité altérée à discriminer la vitesse de stimuli visuels décrivant des FO à différentes vitesses. On ne sait toujours pas si cette perception déficiente explique que leur vitesse de marche soit plus lente et que leur démarche soit moins adaptée aux demandes contextuelles. Le but de cette étude était de comparer le seuil de discrimination de la vitesse et l'adaptation de la vitesse de marche chez des jeunes personnes et des personnes âgées en bonne santé. J'ai aussi examiné la relation entre la perception de la vitesse et l'habilité à contrôler la vitesse de marche. Douze jeunes adultes (23.0 ± 2.4 ans) et douze adultes plus âgées (68.8 ± 4.4 ans) ont participé à une évaluation de la perception de la vitesse et à deux évaluations de la démarche. Lors de l'expérience de perception de la vitesse, les participants étaient en position assise et portaient un casque de réalité virtuelle illustrant leur déplacement le long d'un corridor à différentes vitesses. Ensuite, les participants devaient identifier laquelle des deux scènes présentées était la plus rapide. Les seuils de perception de la vitesse ont été mesurés par la moyenne géométrique des huit derniers changements de vitesse. Lors des tâches de marche, les participants marchaient sur un tapis roulant auto-rythmé en portant un casque de réalité virtuelle montrant des scènes présentées à des vitesses de FO variant de 0,25 à 2 fois leur vitesse de marche confortable. Lors du premier test de marche, les participants devaient marcher la longueur du corridor qui décrivaient des vitesses variées de FO (condition expérimentale) et ce, durant la même période de temps qu'un essai précédent illustrant un FO équivalant à leur vitesse confortable de marche (condition contrôle). Lors de la deuxième session, on a demandé aux participants de marcher à une vitesse équivalente à la vitesse du FO présentée dans l'environnement virtuel. La modulation de la vitesse de marche a été mesurée selon la pente entre les changements de vitesse de marche et les changements de vitesses du FO (premier test de marche) et avec les erreurs absolues de vitesse de marche par rapport à la vitesse cible (deuxième test de marche). Les adultes plus âgés ont démontré des seuils plus élevés de discrimination des vitesses, des pentes plus atténuées et de plus grandes marges d'erreurs de vitesse lorsque comparés aux jeunes adultes. Parmi le groupe plus âgé, les seuils de discrimination des vitesses n'étaient pas reliés de façon significative aux habiletés à moduler la vitesse de marche, tel que mesurés par les pentes et les erreurs de vitesse. Ces résultats indiquent que le vieillissement affecte autant l'habileté à percevoir les vitesses du FO que celle à moduler sa vitesse de marche en réponse aux changements de vitesse de FO. Ces observations suggèrent qu'une mauvaise perception de mouvements visuels pourrait être un des facteurs contribuant au déclin de la mobilité chez les personnes âgées.</description><creator>Lalonde-Parsi, Marie-Jasmine</creator><contributor>Anouk Lamontagne (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Physical Therapy</subject><title>Perception of self-motion &amp; regulation of walking speed in older adults in comparison to young adults</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c135.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892f442</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x269j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Poly(vinyl chloride) (PVC) requires the addition of large quantities of plasticizers in order to improve the flexibility and processability of the polymer. Since the plasticizer is not bound to the PVC polymer matrix, there is a tendency of the plasticizer to migrate into the surroundings. The most commonly used PVC plasticizer, di-2-ethylhexyl phthalate (DEHP), has become a ubiquitous environmental contaminant. As with other plasticizers, it may either accumulate or lead to the formation of metabolites, which resist further degradation and can themselves be toxic. Accordingly, there is incentive for the development of a 'green' plasticizer as a replacement to DEHP in order to minimize the environmental impact of PVC production and use. In this study, a method was developed to quantify the degradation of plasticizers used in PVC formulation or proposed as alternatives. The method is based on derivatization in order to lower the boiling points of the compounds and allow for analysis by gas chromatography (GC). Using this developed method, the biodegradation of two different families of potential 'green' plasticizers was considered. The biodegradation was assessed using Rhodococcus rhodochrous and evaluated based on the rate and completeness as well as the toxicity and stability of any observed metabolites. It was found that the poly([ε]-caprolactone)-based plasticizers containing octanoate-terminal groups degraded much more rapidly and completely than the benzoate-terminated ones. Furthermore, no metabolites were observed during the degradation of octanoate-terminated plasticizers while the benzoate-terminated plasticizers gave rise to metabolites which contributed substantial toxicity to the culture media. Under ideal conditions, these metabolites were shown to be biodegraded themselves. The methodology and data presented in this thesis can be used as a tool in selecting a 'green' plasticizer based on the degradation criteria, and aid in the selection of alternative plasticizers to DEHP.</description><description>Le polychlorure de vinyle (PVC) requiert l'ajout important de plastifiant afin d'obtenir un polymère flexible et plus facile à mettre en forme. Comme ces plastifiants ne sont pas chimiquement liés à la matrice, ils ont toutefois tendance à migrer dans le milieu environnant. Le phtalate de diéthylhéxyle (DEHP) est le plastifiant le plus couramment utilisé et est maintenant un contaminant omniprésent. Tout comme d'autres plastifiants, il peut s'accumuler dans l'environnement ou se biodégrader et former des métabolites qui peuvent résister à la biodégradation et être potentiellement toxiques. Cette situation inquiétante a susciter l'intérêt envers le développement de plastifiants verts offrant une alternative au DEHP et permettant de minimiser l'impact environnemental de la production et de l'utilisation du PVC.Dans le cadre de l'étude présentée dans cette thèse, une méthodologie a été développée afin de permettre la quantification et le suivi de la biodégradation de plastifiants utilisé pour le PVC ou proposés comme alternatives. Cette méthode basée sur le dérivatisation permet la diminution du point d'ébullition des composés et l'analyse par chromatographie en phase gazeuse (GC). Cette méthode a été utilisée ici afin d'étudier la biodégradation de deux familles de composés proposés comme plastifiants verts. La biodégradation a été étudiée à l'aide de la bactérie Rhodococcus rhodochrous et évaluée en fonction de la cinétique et l'étendue de la dégradation ainsi que selon la formation de métabolites et la toxicité résiduelle. Les résultats ont démontré que les plastifiants à base de poly([ε]-caprolactone ayant des groupes terminaux octanoïque se biodégradent plus rapidement et que ceux ayant des groupes terminaux benzoïque. De plus, aucun métabolite n'a été détecté lors de la dégradation des plastifiants octanoïque alors que les plastifiants benzoïques ont formés des métabolites et engendré une toxicité résiduelle du milieu de culture. Dans des conditions idéales de biodégradation, les métabolites se sont dégradés. La méthodologie développée et les résultats présentés dans cette thèse seront utiles à la sélection de plastifiants verts offrant une alternative au DEHP.</description><creator>Fontaine, Adam</creator><contributor>David G Cooper (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Viviane Yargeau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Degradation of poly(ε-caprolactone)-based 'green' plasticizers for poly(vinyl chloride)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623h01q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x269j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sh05z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) is defined as glucose intolerance (hyperglycemia) first recognized during pregnancy, and affects approximately 7% of all pregnancies – over 135 000 cases per year in the United States alone. Estimates suggest that gestational diabetes prevalence has increased by 10-100% during the past 20 years, particularly among certain ethnic groups and individuals with low socioeconomic status (SES), yet only five studies have analyzed the influence of sociodemographic conditions on this disease. There is evidence that age, obesity, parity, ethnicity and family history are risk factors for GDM. Efforts to reduce the risk of GDM have been focused on clinical and behavioural factors and largely ignored the social and spatial patterning of this disease. I conducted a retrospective patient chart review of 538 women treated for GDM at the Toronto East General Hospital, living in 307 geographic areas to assess the role of sociodemographic marginalization in severity of hyperglycemia at diagnosis, glycemic management and adverse perinatal outcomes. Sociodemographic marginalization was found to be associated with more severe GDM diagnostic test values and poor glycemic management after controlling for known risk factors (age, parity, GDM in previous pregnancy and family history). Severity of hyperglycemia at GDM diagnosis was also associated with approximately 35% increased likelihood of poor glycemic management outcomes and poor glycemic control contributed an additional 65%-69% increased risk for a traumatic birth event. Results indicate that severity of hyperglycemia at GDM diagnosis and glycemic management is patterned by sociodemographic disparity, which have practical implications for a focus on pre-, peri- and post-natal care amongst residents of lower socioeconomic geographies in Canada.</description><description>Le diabète gestationnel est défini comme un état d'intolérance au glucose qui apparaît au cours de la grossesse. Ceci concerne environ 7% des grossesses, plus de 135,000 cas aux Etats-Unis par an. Les évaluations suggèrent que pendant les vingt dernières années, la fréquence a augmenté de 10-100%, notamment chez certains groupes ethniques ainsi que chez les individus des catégories sociales défavorisées. Il y a cependant cinq études qui ont analysé l'effet des conditions sociodémographiques sur cette maladie. Il y a des indications que l'age, l'obésité, la parité, l'origine ethnique et l'histoire de la famille sont tous des facteurs qu'il faut considérer. Les efforts pour réduire le risque du diabète gestationnel se sont concentrés sur les facteurs cliniques et comportementaux en négligeant la constance des influences sociales et environnementales. J'ai dirigé une analyse rétrospective des cas de 538 femmes qui ont été traitées pour le diabète gestationnel au Toronto East General Hospital (Hôpital Général de l'Est de Toronto). Ces tests ont été menés sur des femmes habitant 307 régions différentes dans le but d'évaluer le rôle de la marginalisation sociodémographique en ce qui concerne la sévérité du diagnostic de l'hyperglycémie, la prise en charge de la maladie et de ses conséquences sur la période périnatale. Une fois pris en compte les facteurs connus de risques (l'age, l'obésité, la parité, l'origine ethnique et l'histoire de la famille) on a pu constater que les cas de diagnostics les plus sévères devaient être mis en relation avec la marginalisation socioéconomique et la prise en charge défectueuse des malades. Dans 35% des cas, une mauvaise prise en charge était à l'origine de la sévérité du diagnostic. Par ailleurs, l'insuffisance du contrôle glycémique augmentait de 65-69% les naissances à risque.Les résultats indiquent que la gravité du diabète gestationnel et sa prise en charge dépendent essentiellement des inégalités sociodémographiques qui ont des implications en ce qui concerne les soins donnés avant, pendant et après la naissance aux familles les plus défavorisées du Canada.</description><creator>Sampson Riden, Lorna</creator><contributor>Nancy Ross (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Social Sciences - Geography </subject><title>Gestational diabetes: the influence of sociodemographic marginalization on severity of hyperglycemia at diagnosis, glycemic management and perinatal outcomes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795c302.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sh05z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p823t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Monolinguals harness language-specific prosodic cues for the purpose of segmenting out words from the speech stream. However, if and how bilinguals are able to do so in both their languages is less certain. 41 adult English-French bilinguals heard streams of both English- and French- accented nonsense syllables, and then performed a recognition task for syllable sequences. There was no difference between the performance of English- and French- dominant bilinguals, nor between simultaneous versus sequential bilinguals. As a group, English-French bilinguals did show evidence of different segmentation strategies between the English and French language streams. It is therefore concluded that in certain conditions, bilinguals appear to be able to switch stress-based segmentation strategies between their languages. The use of the Hearing in Noise Test (HINT) as a promising new method for measuring language dominance is also discussed.</description><description>Les monolingues utilisent les indices prosodiques  spécifiques à la langue afin de pouvoir extraire les mots du flot de la parole continue. Toutefois, on n'est pas encore parvenu à expliquer si et comment les bilingues réussissent cette tâche perceptuelle dans leurs deux langues. 41 adultes bilingues anglais-français ont entendu deux flots de parole continue, composés de syllabes dépourvues de sens: un flot était énoncé avec une prononciation anglophone, l'autre avec une prononciation francophone. Ensuite, les participants ont subi une tâche de récognition pour des séquences de syllabes. La dominance d'une langue et l'âge d'acquisition de la deuxième langue n'influençaient point comment les adultes bilingues réagissaient à la tâche. Comme groupe, les bilingues anglais-français semblent alterner leur stratégie de segmentation selon la langue entendue . Nous concluons donc que les bilingues ne traitent pas leurs deux langues de façon identique, du moins dans certaines conditions. L'utilité du Hearing in Noise Test (HINT) comme une mesure nouvelle et prometteuse pour établir la langue dominante est également discutée. </description><creator>Spring, Meghan</creator><contributor>Polka, Linda (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013-01</date><subject>Health Sciences - Speech Pathology</subject><title>Speech segmentation in adult French-English bilinguals: The role of prosody</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx91s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p823t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mq907</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cell physiology and survival critically depend on mechanisms that regulate the development and maintenance of polarity, which is manifested by the asymmetric distribution of proteins or organelles to specific sub-cellular compartments. A prime example of this is observed in mammalian photoreceptor cells, where the proteins involved in the phototransduction cascade are housed exclusively in a specialized primary cilium called the outer segment (OS). Despite the importance of polarized protein trafficking in photoreceptor physiology and disease, the mechanisms regulating this process remain largely unknown. Recent studies have shown that Numb, an endocytic adapter protein, is an essential regulator of directional protein trafficking in migrating cells and neurons, raising the possibility that it might be involved in OS protein sorting. Consistent with this idea, we find that Numb is expressed in the inner segment (IS) of rod photoreceptors, where proteins involved in phototransduction are synthesized. To study the role of Numb in photoreceptors, we used the Cre/lox system to generate double conditional knockout (dcKO) mouse in which the Numb and Numblike (Nbl, a homolog of Numb) genes are specifically inactivated in postmitotic rod photoreceptors. While rod OS disk membrane proteins traffick normally in Numb Nbl dcKO photoreceptors, the cyclic nucleotide-gated channel (CNGC), which normally localizes to the plasma membrane of rod OS, was also found localized to the IS plasma membrane. Since CNGC was also observed in this region in wildtype rod photoreceptors, albeit at much reduced levels, these results suggest a model in which the Numb/Nbl-mediated endocytosis of CNGC promotes trafficking to the OS. Consistent with this possibility, we found that Numb and CNGC physically interact both in vitro and in vivo, and that overexpressing Numb in a heterologous cell culture assay increases the pool of CNGC trafficked to early endosomes. Together, these results support a new model implicating polarized endocytosis in OS plasma membrane protein sorting in mouse rod photoreceptor cells. CNGC is critical for  photoreceptor function in the retina and in addition, since Numb Nbl dcKO photoreceptors ultimately undergo progressive degeneration, our findings could have important implications in our understanding of the pathophysiology leading to retinal degeneration in humans.</description><description>Le fonctionnement et la survie de la cellule dépendent de mécanismes régulant le développement et le maintien de la polarité, laquelle se définit par la distribution asymétrique des protéines ou organelles à des compartiments cellulaires précis. Un excellent exemple de ceci peut être observé dans les photorécepteurs des mammifères. En effet, les protéines impliquées dans la cascade de phototransduction, qui est un processus essentiel à la vision, se retrouvent exclusivement dans un cilium primaire spécialisé nommé « segment externe ».  Malgré son importance physiologique et son implication dans les troubles de la vision, les mécanismes contrôlant le triage directionnel et la polarisation des protéines demeurent peu connus. Toutefois, de récentes études ont démontré que Numb, une protéine adaptatrice endocytique, joue un rôle dans le contrôle directionnel du trafic des protéines dans les cellules en migration et les neurones, d'où l'idée qu'elle pourrait aussi être impliquée dans le triage des protéines du segment externe. Conformément à cette idée, nous avons trouvé que Numb est exprimée dans les segments internes des bâtonnets - un type de photorécepteurs – où les protéines impliquées dans la phototransduction sont synthétisées. Afin d'étudier le rôle de la protéine Numb dans les photorécepteurs, nous avons utilisé le système Cre/lox afin de produire une souris transgénique (conditional knock-out ou cKo) chez laquelle le gène Numb a été spécifiquement déplété dans les bâtonnets. Nos résultats démontrent que la vaste majorité des protéines membranaires du segment externe se déplacent normalement dans les bâtonnets de la souris Numb cKo. Toutefois, on dénote une accumulation de la protéine CNGC (cyclic nucleotide-gated channel, i.e. le canal à fonctionnement contrôlé par les nucléotides cycliques) au niveau du segment interne. Fait à noter, CNGC localise normalement au niveau de la membrane plasmique du segment externe des bâtonnets. Étant donné que le CNGC a aussi été observé - bien qu'à des niveaux largement réduits - dans cette région dans les bâtonnets des souris de type sauvages, ces résultats suggèrent l'existence d'un modèle selon lequel l'endocytose de CNGC par Numb pourrait favoriser le trafic vers le segment externe. Conformément à cette possibilité, nous avons trouvé que Numb et CNGC interagissent in vitro et in vivo, et que la surexpression de Numb dans un dosage de culture de cellules hétérologues augmente le niveau de CNGC situé dans les endosomes précoces. Conséquemment, ces résultats soutiennent un nouveau modèle selon lequel Numb régulerait la polarisation cellulaire via l'endocytose et le triage directionnel des protéines de la membrane plasmique des segments externe des bâtonnets des souris. Par ailleurs, puisque les photorécepteurs des souris Numb cKo subissent ultimement une dégénérescence progressive, cette étude pourrait avoir un impact important sur notre compréhension de la pathophysiologie menant à la dégénérescence maculaire chez l'humain.</description><creator>Ramamurthy, Vasanth</creator><contributor>Michel Cayouette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Polarized sorting of ion channels to the light-sensing cilia of mouse photoreceptor cells requires the endocytic protein Numb</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h070d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq907</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd920</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Voués à limiter les risques d'incendies, les retardateurs de flammes bromés (BFRs) sont des composés dotés de propriétés physicochimiques qui réduisent l'inflammabilité d'une large gamme de produits de consommation. Relargués dans l'environnement, les BFRs s'accrochent aux particules de poussière d'où résulte une contamination par les BFRs, s'effectuant principalement par ingestion. Un accroissement important de la charge corporelle en BFRs suscitent une inquiétude majeure en raison de leur persistance dans l'environnement et de leurs propriétés lipophiliques et bioaccumulables.En effet, des taux élevés en BFRs détectés chez l'humain ont été associé à une perturbation du système endocrinien, du développement des organes reproducteurs mâles et de la fertilité masculine. Des études menées chez les rongeurs ont mis en évidence des résultats similaires. Cependant, ces études caractérisent les effets d'un congénère ou d'une mixture de BFRs et ne reflètent pas ce qui est mesuré dans l'environnement. Ainsi, l'objectif de cette thèse était de déterminer si une exposition chronique à une mixture de BFRs détectée dans la poussière domestique Nord-américaine, à l'âge adulte ou durant la gestation affectait la structure des organes reproducteurs et leur fonction à l'âge adulte ou, le développement fœtal des gonades, chez le mâle. Des mâles et femelles rats Sprague-Dawley adultes ont été exposé à la mixture de BFRs via leur nourriture pendant 70 jours pour les mâles et pendant la période de pré accouplement et la gestation chez les femelles. Afin d'investiguer les associations cellulaires et l'intégrité des tissus, des coupes histologiques de testicules ont été analysé. L'expression de gènes clés a été quantifié afin d'évaluer la fonction testiculaire et l'activité stéroidogenique. Chez le mâle adulte, aucuns effets induits par l'exposition aux BFRs ont été observés sur l'histologie des testicules ou l'expression de gènes marqueurs. Cependant, la morphologie et le nombre de cellules dans les testicules fœtal à 20 jours de gestation étaient affectés par une exposition in utero aux BFRs. Non seulement la morphologie des cellules de Sertoli et des gonocytes était anormale, mais également le nombre de cellules de Sertoli et, le ratio du nombre de cellules de Sertoli et de gonocytes. Par conséquent, une exposition aux BFRs, à des doses reflétant celles mesurées dans l'environnement, n'affecte pas la structure et la fonction du système reproducteur mâle adulte mais est associée à des conséquences néfastes sur le développement des gonades mâles, suggérant une sensibilité accrue aux BFRs lors de la période de différenciation des gonades mâles.</description><description>Brominated flame retardants (BFRs) are a group of industrially important chemicals that are incorporated into a wide variety of consumer products in order to increase their flame ignition resistance. These BFRs are readily released into the immediate environment through a multitude of routes, whereupon an appreciable level can be detected in household dust. The ingestion of contaminated dust is the major source of exposure for humans. Rising body burdens of BFRs over the last decades have led to major concern because of the persistence of BFR in the environment, their bioaccumlative and lipophilic properties, and their implication as endocrine disruptors. Elevated levels in humans have been positively correlated with dysregulation of the endocrine system and disruptions of male reproductive function and development. Animal studies have identified similar effects; however, these studies have characterized the consequences of exposure to single BFR congeners or to technical mixtures but not to an environmentally relevant mixture. Therefore, the aim of this thesis was to determine if chronic exposure to a representative mixture of the BFRs found in North American household dust during adulthood or gestation disrupts male adult or fetal gonadal structure or function and development. The BFR mixture was delivered to adult male and female Sprague-Dawley rats through their diet for 70 days in the males and for the duration of a premating and gestation period in the females. Male testicular histology was examined to determine effects on cellular associations and tissue integrity; the expression of key genes was assessed to reflect any effect on testicular function and steroidogenic capacity. Neither testicular histology nor the expression of marker genes was affected by BFR exposure in the adult males. However, alterations in testicular cell morphology and count were observed in testes from fetuses on gestation day 20 after in utero exposure to BFRs. Specifically, BFR exposure affected Sertoli cell and gonocyte morphology, as well as Sertoli cell counts and the ratio of Sertoli cells to gonocytes. Therefore, an environmentally relevant BFR mixture that did not affect the structure or function of the adult male gonad did adversely affect gonad development, suggesting that these chemicals target critical events during differentiation of the male gonad. </description><creator>Ma, Yiqian</creator><contributor>Barbara F Hales (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Toxicology</subject><title>Understanding the effects of exposure to an environmentally relevant mixture of brominated flame retardant congeners on the function and development of the male gonad</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k66p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd920</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r74h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse se situe dans le contexte d'un cadre largement utilisé pour formaliser les méchanismes autonomes de décision, à savoir les processus de décision markoviens (MDP). L'un des principaux problèmes qui se posent dans les MDP est celui de l'évaluation d'une stratégie de prise de décision, généralement appelée une politique. C'est souvent le cas qu'obtenir des données recueillies dans le cadre de la politique qu'on souhaite évaluer est difficile, ou même impossible. Dans ce cas, des données recueillies sous une autre politique doivent être utilisées, une situation appelée "évaluation hors-politique". L'objectif principal de cette thèse est de proposer un nouvel éclairage sur les propriétés des méthodes pour l'évaluation hors-politique. Ce résultat est obtenu grâce à une série de nouveaux résultats théoriques et illustrations empiriques. La première série de résultats concerne des problèmes de type bandit (des MDP avec un seul état et une seule étape de décision). Dans cette configuration, le biais et la variance de divers estimateurs hors-politique peuvent être calculés sous forme fermée sans avoir recours à des approximations. Nous comparons également le compromis biais-variance pour les différents estimateurs, du point de vue théorique et empirique. Dans le cadre séquentiel (plus d'une étape de décision), une étude empirique comparative des différents estimateurs hors-politique pour les MDP avec des états et des actions discrètes est menée. Les méthodes comparées sont trois estimateurs existants, ainsi que deux nouveaux proposés dans cette thèse. Tous ces estimateurs se sont avérés convergents et asymptotiquement normaux. L'étude empirique montre comment le comportement relatif des estimateurs est affecté par des changements aux paramètres du problème. L'analyse des MDP discrets est complétée par des formules récursives pour le biais et la variance pour l'estimateur basé sur le modèle. Ce sont les premières formules analytiques pour les MDP à horizon fini, et on montre qu'ils produisent des résultats plus précis que les estimations "bootstrap".La contribution finale consiste à introduire un nouveau cadre pour délimiter le retour d'une politique. Le cadre peut être utilisé chaque fois que des bornes sur le prochain état et la récompense sont disponibles, indépendamment du fait que les espaces d'état et d'action soient discrètes ou continues. Si les limites du prochain état sont calculées en supposant la continuité Lipschitz de la fonction de transition et en utilisant un échantillon de transitions, notre cadre peut conduire à des bornes plus strictes que celles qui sont proposées dans des travaux antérieurs.Tout au long de cette thèse, la performance empirique des estimateurs étudiés est illustrée sur plusieurs problèmes de durabilité: un modèle de calcul des émissions de gaz à effet de serre associées à la consommation de nourriture, un modèle dynamique de la population des mallards, et un domaine de gestion de la pêche.</description><description>This dissertation is set in the context of a widely used framework for formalizing autonomous decision-making, namely Markov decision processes (MDPs). One of the key problems that arise in MDPs is that of evaluating a decision-making strategy, typically called a policy. It is often the case that data collected under the policy one wishes to evaluate is difficult or even impossible to obtain. In this case, data collected under some other policy needs to be used, a setting known as off-policy evaluation. The main goal of this dissertation is to offer new insights into the properties of methods for off-policy evaluation. This is achieved through a series of novel theoretical results and empirical illustrations. The first set of results concerns the bandit setting (single state, single decision step MDPs). In this basic setting, the bias and variance of various off-policy estimators can be computed in closed form without resorting to approximations. We also compare the bias-variance trade-offs for the different estimators, both theoretically and empirically. In the sequential setting (more than one decision step), a comparative empirical study of different off-policy estimators for MDPs with discrete state and action spaces is conducted. The methods compared include three existing estimators, and two new ones proposed in this dissertation. All of these estimators are shown to be consistent and asymptotically normal. The empirical study illustrates how the relative behaviour of the estimators is affected by changes in problem parameters. The analysis for discrete MDPs is completed by recursive bias and variance formulas for the commonly used model-based estimator. These are the first analytic formulas for finite-horizon MDPs, and are shown to produce more accurate results than bootstrap estimates. The final contribution consists of introducing a new framework for bounding the return of a policy. The framework can be used whenever bounds on the next state and reward are available, regardless of whether the state and action spaces are discrete or continuous. If the next-state bounds are computed by assuming Lipschitz continuity of the transition function and using a batch of sampled transitions, then our framework can lead to tighter bounds than those proposed in previous work. Throughout this dissertation, the empirical performance of the estimators being studied is illustrated on several computational sustainability problems: a model of food-related greenhouse gas emissions, a mallard population dynamics model, and a fishery management domain.</description><creator>Paduraru, Cosmin</creator><contributor>Doina Precup (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Joelle Pineau (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Off-policy evaluation in Markov decision processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq12v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r74h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x2709</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation sets out to offer a renewed perspective on the participation of Shakespeare's theatre in the secularization of early modern England. It engages with current theories of secularization, in which the pluralization of beliefs is recognized as fuelling secularizing processes, as opposed to longstanding subtraction theories of secularization, which have mistakenly charted a comprehensive decline of belief. While this study acknowledges the historical reality of Shakespeare's involvement in the secularization of the religious landscape of early modernity, it also resists the common reception of his plays as prescient anticipations of much later secularisms. I argue that these retroactive secularist interpretations of the plays have tended to elide the profoundly conflicted responses to secularization in Shakespeare's drama. This dissertation's historical investigation of tolerance, demonism, blasphemy, and love in the plays reveals that while Shakespeare's dramas do often convey an implicit recognition of the possible opportunities that secularization presented, they also represent it as a development that could render humans vulnerable to social and to supernatural harm. The introductory chapter provides an overview of current secularization theory, focusing particularly on Charles Taylor, the most influential proponent of recent developments in our understanding of secularizing processes. In cooperation with other theorists, Taylor has reanimated the idea of secularization by reconceiving of it as an unpredictable and dynamic process, largely driven by the pluralization of beliefs over time. I take up this hypothesis by demonstrating its potential for analyzing tolerance in several of Shakespeare's comedies, as well as more generally as a means of furthering critical debate on Shakespeare and religion. Chapter one is devoted to Shakespeare's theatricalization in Othello of the idea that the devil could make use of the discordant processes of the Reformation, as well as of the innovations of humanism, both pluralizing engines of secularization in the period, in order to infiltrate weakened spiritual communities. Chapter two investigates Shakespeare's response in Macbeth to legislation that prohibited blasphemous swearing in public entertainments. Shakespeare appears to have been inspired by the new bill to write Macbeth in a way that superficially complied with the law, but which nonetheless engaged profoundly with the dispersion of the post-Reformation idea of blasphemy into a secularizing plurality of beliefs, a fragmentation that is enacted in the play with an ambiguous mixture of approval and disapproval. In the final chapter, I consider how in Romeo and Juliet, Shakespeare recuperates the radicalism of the Franciscan Order's societal and poetic ideals of relational and spiritual love in ways that initially appear to support, but which then ultimately subvert, English Protestantism's tentative investment in matrimonial love as the principal means by which the fraying bonds of the religious and the secular dimensions of Reformed society might be restored. Instead of celebrating a unified representation of Catholic or of Protestant aspirations for marriage, the play concludes by evoking a secularizing plurality of options for belief in matrimony, an impetus which has contributed to the currently widespread, albeit variously experienced, belief in wedded love as the cornerstone of the modern social imaginary.</description><description>Cette thèse propose une perspective renouvelée sur la participation du théâtre de Shakespeare dans la sécularisation de l'Angleterre pendant la Renaissance. Elle utilise les théories actuelles de la sécularisation, selon lesquelles la pluralisation des croyances est reconnue pour avoir alimenté les processus de sécularisation, contrairement aux théories dites « de soustraction » qui attribuent ceux-ci à une diminution globale de la croyance religieuse. Bien que cette étude reconnaisse la réalité historique de l'implication de Shakespeare dans la sécularisation du climat religieux de la Renaissance, elle résiste également à l'idée populaire que ses pièces anticipaient de façon presciente la laïcité moderne. Je soutiens que ces interprétations rétroactives des pièces de Shakespeare ont eu tendance à élider les réponses en conflit à la sécularisation contenu dans le drame de Shakespeare. Cette enquête historique de la tolérance, du démonisme, de blasphème, et d'amour dans les pièces de Shakespeare révèle que ses drames véhiculaient non seulement la reconnaissance implicite des opportunités que la sécularisation présentait, mais aussi d'un développement capable de rendre les humains plus vulnérables à l'endommagement social et surnaturel. Le chapitre d'introduction fournit une vue d'ensemble de la théorie de la sécularisation actuelle, en se concentrant particulièrement sur Charles Taylor, le partisan le plus influent des développements récents dans notre compréhension des processus de sécularisation. Avec d'autres théoriciens, Taylor a ravivé l'idée de sécularisation en la présentant comme un processus imprévisible et dynamique, conduit principalement par la pluralisation des croyances au fil du temps. J'applique cette hypothèse en démontrant son potentiel pour l'analyse de la tolérance dans plusieurs comédies de Shakespeare, ainsi que plus généralement comme un moyen de faire progresser le débat critique sur Shakespeare et la religion. Le premier chapitre est consacré à Othello où Shakespeare théâtralise l'idée que le diable peut faire usage des processus discordants de la réforme protestante, ainsi que des innovations de l'humanisme, deux instigateurs de la pluralisation séculaire durant cette période, afin d'infiltrer une communauté spirituelle affaiblie. Le deuxième chapitre étudie la réponse de Shakespeare dans Macbeth à la législation interdisant le langage blasphématoire dans les spectacles publics. Ici, Shakespeare décrie le nouveau projet de loi en écrivant d'une manière conforme seulement en apparence à la loi, mais qui en réalité promulgue une dispersion de l'idée post-réforme du blasphème en une pluralité séculaire de croyances, une fragmentation qui est jouée dans la pièce par le biais d'un mélange ambigu d'approbation et de désapprobation. Dans le dernier chapitre, je considère comment, dans Romeo and Juliet, Shakespeare s'appuie sur le radicalisme des idéaux sociaux et poétiques de l'ordre Franciscain, particulièrement ceux concernant l'amour relationnel et spirituel, d'une manière qui apparait initialement à le soutenir, mais qui finalement s'insurge contre l'investissement du protestantisme anglais dans l'amour matrimonial comme principal moyen de restauration des dimensions religieuses et séculaires de la société réformée. Au lieu de célébrer une représentation unifiée des aspirations catholiques ou protestantes du mariage, la pièce se termine en évoquant une pluralité d'options pour séculariser la croyance dans le mariage, un élan qui a contribué à faire aujourd'hui de l'amour conjugal, sous toutes ses formes, une fondation de l'imaginaire social moderne. </description><creator>Morris, Robert Blair</creator><contributor>Paul Edward Yachnin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Literature - English</subject><title>Shakespearean secularizations: endangering beliefs on the early modern stage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt87p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x2709</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02871049j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Neotropical knifefish Brachyhypopomus occidentalis is one of the few species of the highly diverse group of gymnotiform weakly electric fish that successfully colonized the freshwater basins of Central America, more specifically of Panama. Here, we inferred the phylogenetic relationships between populations of B. occidentalis in Panama to understand this species' evolutionary dynamics and resolve the timing and the mode of its colonization of the Central American Isthmus. We identified a highly divergent lineage composed solely of specimens from westernmost Atlantic Panama (Bocas del Toro drainages), which is the only relict of an early dispersal event from South America in the late Miocene. All other individuals distributed in Panama and northwestern Colombia drainages formed a second lineage. We found that recent, rapid, and major expansion events in the Late Pliocene most likely facilitated by the final closure of the Isthmus led to the establishment and diversification of B. occidentalis in Central and Eastern drainages of Panama.Like all gymnotiforms, B. occidentalis produces weak electric organ discharges (EOD) in the surrounding water, used for communication and navigation. EOD properties vary widely across species, and electrocommunication thus provides a good opportunity to study signal variation and evolution. We determined the pattern of signal waveform and genetic variation among five isolated B. occidentalis populations in Panama and used this pattern to identify evolutionary processes shaping signal divergence. We found that signal, genetic, and geographic distances were correlated in B. occidentalis, suggesting that genetic drift contributed to shaping signal variation among allopatric populations of this species. Nonetheless, high intra-drainage signal distances between specimens of the same drainage with low levels of genetic differentiation indicate that selective forces may also play a role in generating signal differences.  </description><description>Brachyhypopomus occidentalis, un poisson couteau néotropical, est l'une des quelques espèces du groupe très diversifié des poissons gymnotes faiblement électriques, qui a pu coloniser les bassins d'eau douce d'Amérique Centrale et plus spécifiquement du Panama. Dans cette étude, nous avons inféré les relations phylogénétiques entre les populations de B. occidentalis au Panama pour comprendre les dynamiques évolutionnaires de cette espèce ainsi que pour déterminer le patron de sa colonisation de l'isthme d'Amérique Centrale. Nous avons identifié une lignée extrêmement divergente composée uniquement de spécimens distribués dans la partie ouest atlantique du Panama (les rivières de Bocas del Toro), qui reste le seul vestige d'un ancien évènement de colonisation  provenant d'Amérique du sud à la fin du Miocène. Tous les autres individus distribués dans les rivières du Panama et du nord-ouest de la Colombie formaient une deuxième lignée. Nous avons trouvé que des évènements d'expansion récents et rapides ayant eu lieu à la fin du Pliocène, facilités par la fermeture finale de l'isthme, ont conduit à l'implantation et à la diversification de B. occidentalis dans les rivières du centre et de l'est du Panama.Comme tous les gymnotes, B. occidentalis produit de faibles décharges électriques dans l'eau environnante, utilisées pour la communication et la navigation. Les propriétés des décharges varient de manière importante selon les espèces et l'électrocommunication fournit par conséquent une bonne opportunité pour étudier la variation et l'évolution des signaux de communication. Nous avons déterminé le patron de variation génétique et de la forme du signal parmi cinq populations isolées de B. occidentalis au Panama. Nous avons utilisé ce patron pour identifier le processus évolutionnaire dans la divergence du signal. Nous avons mis en évidence que les distances du signal électrique, les distances génétiques, et les distances géographiques étaient corrélées pour B. occidentalis, suggérant que la dérive génétique contribue à la variation du signal parmi les populations allopatriques de cette espèce. Néanmoins, de grandes distances de signal entre des poissons venant du même bassin d'eau douce et montrant de faibles distances génétiques indique que des forces sélectives peuvent également jouer un rôle sur la divergence des signaux électriques de cette éspèce.</description><creator>Picq, Sophie</creator><contributor>Eldredge Bermingham (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Rudiger Krahe (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Zoology </subject><title>Phylogeography and signal evolution in one species of neotropical weakly electric fish, brachyhypopomus occidentalis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c749.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871049j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z156v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>   Use of composite non-uniform radiation fields, which consist of a multitude of small fields, is very common in modern radiotherapy techniques. The conventional reference dosimetry protocols, however, use a 10 × 10 cm2 field as the reference machine calibration condition. The purpose of this work is to develop new, direct absorbed dose calibration methods for modern radiotherapy techniques that use static and composite nonstandard fields.   An IAEA-AAPM international working group [Med. Phys. 35:5179–5186 (2008)] proposed a new formalism and introduced two intermediate fields, machine specific reference (msr) field fmsr and plan-class specific reference (pcsr) field fpcsr, for reference dosimetry of static and composite nonstandard fields, respectively. In the new formalism, correction factors which account for the difference in chamber calibration conditions between the reference field and msr field k^fmsr,fref_Qmsr,Q , pcsr field k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q or clinical field k^fclin,fref_Qclin,Q were defined. This thesis focuses on the characterization of these correction factors.   The dosimetry techniques to accurately measure the absorbed dose to water in nonstandard fields were established using four different radiation detectors, for which collecting volumes are radiologically water-equivalent. The characteristics of each radiation detector response were thoroughly investigated. Dose measurementin a nonstandard field normalized to that in the reference 10 × 10 cm2 field can be performed with an uncertainty of 0.2–0.3% when the dose distribution in the reference measurement region is homogeneous. Correction factors k^fmsr,fref_Qmsr,Q and k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q were measured for one static nonstandard field and two different composite nonstandard fields, respectively, using different types of air-filled ionization chambers.   Using the established dosimetry techniques, the k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q were measured for different composite nonstandard fields which deliver various dose distributions in the reference measurement region. This work proved that the values of k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q depend on the dose heterogeneity over the chamber collecting volume. Based on the measurement results, guidelines were suggested to select a new intermediate field for reference dosimetry of composite nonstandard fields.   Finally, the IAEA-AAPM new formalism with values of k^fclin,fref_Qclin,Q obtained by experiments and MC methods was applied to reference dose measurement of clinical composite nonstandard fields using a calibrated air-filled ionization chamber. The corrected measured dose for each clinical field was compared with dose calculated using clinical treatment planning software or Monte Carlo methods. It was found that the accurate positioning of the reference detector and air-filled ionization chamber becomes more important when the dose heterogeneity in the reference measurement region increases.   In conclusion, this thesis provides a method for accurate dose measurements in static and composite nonstandard fields. This work will help pave the way to improve the dosimetric consistency in these dynamic modern radiotherapy techniques.</description><description>   L'utilisation de champs de rayonnement composes non uniformes, qui consistent en une multitude de petits champs, est tres commune dans les techniques modernes de radiotherapie. Cependant, les protocoles de dosimetrie de reference conventionnels utilisent un champ standard de 10×10 cm2 pour calibrer les appareils. Le but de ce travail est de developper de nouvelles methodes de calibration de la dose absorbee pour des techniques modernes de radiotherapie, ce en utilisant autant des champs statiques que des champs composes non standards.   Le groupe de travail AIEA-AAPM a propose un nouveau formalisme qui introduit deux champs intermediaires, soient le champ specifique a l'appareil (fmsr) et le champ specifique au plan de traitement (fpcsr), ce pour la dosimetrie de reference des champs statiques et des champs composes non standards, respectivement. Dans ce nouveau formalisme, des facteurs de corrections ontete definis afin de tenir compte des conditions de calibration de la chambre qui different entre le champ de reference et les champs fmsr, fpcsr ainsi que les champs cliniques (fclin). Ces facteurs sont respectivement d´efinis ainsi: k^fmsr,fref_Qmsr,Q , k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q et k^fclin,fref_Qclin,Q . Cette these comporte sur la caracterisation exprimentale de ces facteurs de correction.   Les techniques de dosimetrie visant a mesurer precisement la dose absorbe dans l'eau pour des champs non standards ont ete etablies en utilisant quatre differents detecteurs de radiation, chacun ayant un volume sensible radiologiquement equivalent a l'eau. Les caracteristiques de chaque detecteur ont ete approfondies. Les mesures de dose dans un champ non standard normalise a un champ de reference de 10×10 cm2 peuvent etre obtenues avec une incertitude de 0.2-0.3% lorsque la distribution de dose dans la region de mesure de reference est homogene. Les facteurs de correction k^fmsr,fref_Qmsr,Q et k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q ont ete mesures pour un champ statique non standard et pour deux differents champs composes non standards, respectivement, en utilisant differents types de chambres d'ionisation a air.   En utilisant les techniques de dosimetries etablies, les k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q ont ete mesures pour plusieurs champs composes non standards qui produisent diff´erentes distributions de dose dans la region de mesure de reference. Ce travail demontre que les valeurs de k^fpcsr,fref_Qpcsr,Q d´ependent de l'heterogeneite de la dose dans le volume sensible de la chambre. Base sur les resultats des mesures, des lignes de conduite sont suggereespour determiner un champ intermediaire necessaire a la dosimetrie de reference des champs composes non standards.   Finalement, le nouveau formalisme de l'AIEA-AAPM a ete applique a des mesures de dose de reference de champs composes non standards cliniques avec les valeurs k^fclin,fref_Qclin,Q obtenues experimentalement et avec des methodes Monte Carlo pour une chambre d'ionisation a air etalonnee. La dose mesuree et corrigee pourchacun des champs a ete comparee avec la dose calculee en utilisant un logiciel de planification de traitement ou des methodes Monte Carlo. Il a ete determine que la precision du positionnement du detecteur de reference ainsi que celui de la chambre d'ionisation a air devient plus important lorsque l'heterogeneite de dose dans la regionde mesure augmente.   En conclusion, cette these fournit une methode precise de mesure de la dose absorbee pour des champs statiques et des champs compose non standards. Ce travail aidera a ameliorer la coherence des methodes dosimetrique appliquables aux techniques modernes de radiotherapie.</description><creator>Chung, Eunah</creator><contributor>Jan Peter Frans Seuntjens (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Physics - Radiation </subject><title>Development of radiation dosimetry techniques for non-standard beam radiotherapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fm64x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z156v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z869j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bien que la médecine s'intéresse aux modèles biologiques de la maladie depuis bien longtemps, elle a tendance à ignorer les dimensions psychologiques associées à ces modèles.  Cette perspective incomplète s'est amplifiée au cours des dernières années avec l'expansion des recherche dans le domaine génétique.  Malgré les plus francs efforts des chercheurs et des cliniciens, cependant, certaines maladies considérées comme essentiellement biologiques demeurent difficiles à comprendre et à contrôler.  Défendant l'importance des facteurs psychologiques associés à de telles conditions, la présente thèse vise à comprendre le rôle des facteurs psychologiques dans l'intolérance au lactose et l'urticaire spontanée chronique.Les résultats de l'étude 1 ainsi que du projet pilote associé suggèrent que les attentes jouent un rôle clef dans l'intolérance au lactose.  Plus spécifiquement, manipuler les attentes des participants intolérants au lactose suffirait à déclencher des symptômes typiques de cette condition (ballonnements, douleur abdominale et flatulences).  Les résultats de l'étude 2, quant-à-eux, révèlent que des facteurs psychosociaux seraient impliqués dans la génération et le développement de l'urticaire spontanée chronique.Ensemble, ces résultats nous mènent à considérer de nouvelles interventions psychosociales pouvant potentiellement réduire les symptômes de l'intolérance au lactose (en manipulant les attentes) et de l'urticaire spontanée chronique (en désactivant les processus de pensée négative tel qu'illustré dans la Réponse Commentaire 1 [Commentary Response 1]). Enfin, la présente thèse examine les dilemmes éthiques générés par les traitements visant la manipulation des aspect psychosociaux liés à ces conditions et suggère un moyen d'employer de telles déceptions d'une manière éthique pour le bénéfice des patients.</description><description>Historically, medicine has emphasized biological models of illness, while ignoring their psychological dimensions. This outlook has been emphasized further in the recent era of genetic research. In spite of our best efforts, however, certain conditions that clinicians consider exclusively rooted in biology have remained difficult to manage. In order to demonstrate the importance of psychological factors in such conditions, this thesis examines the role that psychological factors play in lactose intolerance and chronic spontaneous urticaria. Findings from Study 1 and its corresponding pilot project suggest that expectancies are a key mechanism in lactose intolerance. Specifically, expectancy manipulations led self-reported lactose intolerant individuals to develop common intolerance symptoms (bloating, abdominal pain, and flatulence). Findings from Study 2 reveal that psychosocial factors appear to be implicated in the onset and development of chronic spontaneous urticaria. These results may lead to the development of new psychological interventions to alleviate lactose intolerance (through expectancy-manipulation) and chronic spontaneous urticaria (through negative thought process de-automatization, as outlined in Commentary Response 1). Finally, this thesis addresses the ethical dilemmas which may accompany psychologically-targeted treatments, and suggests a method through which deceptive practices may be ethically employed to benefit patients.</description><creator>Blinderman, Ilia</creator><contributor>Amir Raz (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Psychology - General</subject><title>Mind over matter in biological conditions: the role of psychological processes in lactose intolerance and chronic spontaneous urticaria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r8844.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z869j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000003467</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydroxyurea is commonly used to treat myeloproliferative diseases and sickle cell anemia. It is also a potent teratogen, inducing severe developmental malformations in many animal models after in utero exposure. The administration of hydroxyurea to CD1 mice during organogenesis causes predominantly hindlimb, tail, and neural tube defects. Hydroxyurea inactivates ribonucleotide reductase, inhibiting DNA replication and leading to DNA replication stress and cell death. Hydroxyurea exposure during embryo development also induces oxidative stress and p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase (p38 MAPK) signaling. My goal was to test the hypothesis that hydroxyurea-induced p38 MAPK activation, DNA damage, and cell death are spatially related to the malformations observed in organogenesis-stage embryos.Hydroxyurea (400 or 600 mg/kg) or saline was given intraperitoneally to CD1 mice on gestation day 9. Dams were euthanized and whole embryos collected at 0.5, 3 and 6 hours post-treatment. Whole embryo protein extracts were used to examine the protein expression and activation levels of the p38 MAPK pathway using Western blots. Five regions of the embryos, including the rostral and caudal neuroepithelium, neural tube, somites and heart, were selected to determine the localization of proteins and DNA damage, using immunofluorescence and confocal microscopy. Subsequently, quantification of protein expression and DNA damage in the embryo at the subcellular level was determined using 3D imaging software. Hydroxyurea treatment (400 or 600 mg/kg) induced the activation of mitogen-activated protein kinase kinases 3/6 (MEK-3/6), upstream MAP2K3 kinases; phospho-MEK-3/6 immunoreactivity was widespread throughout the embryo after hydroxyurea exposure. Downstream phospho-p38 MAPK was increased in the rostral and caudal neuroepithelium and the neural tube, but not in the somites or heart. Nuclear translocation of phospho-p38 MAPK was significantly elevated in the rostral and caudal regions of embryos 3 hours after hydroxyurea treatment.  Hydroxyurea exposure increased DNA damage, as assessed by the formation of γ-H2AX foci, throughout the embryo; the volume of γH2AX foci peaked in the caudal neuroepithelium 3 hours post-treatment with hydroxyurea. Pyknotic nuclei and cell fragmentation increased 3 and 6 hours following hydroxyurea exposure in all regions of the embryo except the heart. These data suggest that the p38 MAPK nuclear signaling and DNA damage response triggered by hydroxyurea exposure play key roles in mediating the caudal malformations that are observed. Further work is needed to evaluate these two stress response pathways in order to elucidate the mechanism of embryonic responses to a teratogenic insult. </description><description>L'hydroxyurée est un médicament couramment utilisé pour traiter les maladies myéloprolifératives et l'anémie falciforme. Il a cependant un puissant effet tératogène, causant de graves malformations congénitales chez de nombreux modèles animaux lorsqu'administré durant la grossesse. Le traitement de souris CD1 avec de l'hydroxyurée pendant la période de  l'organogenèse provoque principalement des malformations au niveau des membres postérieurs, de la queue et des anomalies du tube neural. L'hydroxyurée inactive la ribonucléotide réductase ce qui diminue la réplication de l'ADN, et mène à la mort cellulaire. Une exposition à l'hydroxyurée au cours du développement embryonnaire induit également un stress oxydatif et active  la voie de signalisation p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK p38). Mon objectif était de tester l'hypothèse selon laquelle les malformations observées suite à une exposition à l'hydroxyurée lors de l'organogénèse sont colocalisées avec une activation de MAPK p38, des dommages crées à l'ADN et une mort cellulaire.Au jour 9 de la gestation, des souris CD1 ont été injectées avec de l''hydroxyurée (400 ou 600 mg / kg) ou une solution saline par voie intrapéritonéale. Les mères  ont été euthanasiés et les embryons prélevés à 0,5, 3 et 6 heures post-traitement. L'expression de protéines et des niveaux d'activation de la voie de signalisation MAPK p38 ont été quantifiée par par western blot réalisé sur des extraits protéiques entiers de l'embryon. Les protéines et les dommages crées à l'ADN ont été localisés par microscopie confocale et immunofluorescence dans cinq régions de l'embryon comprenant le neuroépithélium rostrale et caudale, le tube neural, les somites et le cœur. Leur localisation au niveau subcellulaire a ensuite été déterminée en utilisant un logiciel d'imagerie 3D.L'hydroxyurée (400 ou 600 mg / kg) induit l'activation des kinases activées par les mitogen-activated protein kinase kinase 3/6 (MEK-3/6) de la catégorie des MAP2K3 kinases; Les embryons provenant des groupes traités à l'hydroxyurée démontrent une immunoréactivité positive de phospho-MEK-3/6 détectée dans les cinq régions analysées de l'embryon. L'expression de phospho-p38 MAPK, la cible cellulaire de MEK-3/6,  est élevée dans le neuroépithélium rostrale et caudale et le tube neural, mais pas dans les somites ou les cellules cardiaques. De plus, une translocation nucléaire de phospho-p38 MAPK est significativement induite dans les régions rostrales et caudales des embryons collectés 3 heures après le traitement à l'hydroxyurée. L'exposition à l'hydroxyurée est associée avec une augmentation des dommages crées à l'ADN, telle que démontrée par la formation de foyers de γH2AX  dans les cinq régions étudiées de l'embryon. . Le nombre maximal de foyers γH2AX est observé dans le neuroépithélium caudale, 3 heures après l'exposition à l'hydroxyurée. Une augmentation du nombre de noyaux pycnotiques et de cellules avec une ADN fragmentée est détectée 3 à 6 heures après l'exposition à l'hydroxyurée dans toutes les régions de l'embryon à l'exception du cœur. Ces données suggèrent que l'activation de la voie de  signalisation MAPK p38 nucléaire et  les conséquences des dommages crées à l'ADN  provoquées par une exposition à l'hydroxyurée jouent un rôle clé dans l'induction des malformations caudales observées. Des études supplémentaires sont néanmoins nécessaires afin d'investiguer ces deux voies de réponse au stress et ce, dans un but d'élucider les mécanismes de défenses embryonnaire face à un tératogène.</description><creator>Banh, Serena</creator><contributor>Barbara F Hales (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</subject><title>Role of p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase signaling and the DNA damage response in the developmental toxicity induced by Hydroxyurea</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tz68k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000003467</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xg31q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les cellules olfactives engainantes (COE) sont une classe unique de cellules gliales dans le système olfactif. Elles possèdent certaines caractéristiques antigéniques et fonctionnelles des deux grandes classes de cellules gliales, soit les cellules de Schwann et les astrocytes. De plus, elles peuvent traverser la frontière entre le système nerveux central (SNC) et périphérique (SNP). Les contributions indispensables des COE à la régénération continuelle du système olfactif tout au long de la vie adulte font de ces cellules des candidats extrêmement prometteurs pour les thérapies de transplantation cellulaire pour la régénération du SNC. Toutefois, les études préliminaires ont généré des résultats variables, ce qui remet en question l'utilité thérapeutique des COE. Une telle variation dans les résultats pourrait être causée par l'hétérogénéité des COE. Cette explication est fondée sur l'hypothèse que seules certaines sous-populations de COE auraient le potentiel de régénérer et d'engainer les axones. Cependant, notre compréhension des fonctions et des propriétés moléculaires spécifiques aux sous-populations de COE est limitée, ce qui restreint l'exploitation de leur potentiel. Nous avons déjà établi que le facteur de transcription Runx1 est exprimé spécifiquement dans une population de cellules que nous croyons être les COE dans le bulbe olfactif. Ici, nous montrons que Runx1 est exprimé dans une sous-population de COE dans la région interne de la couche du nerf olfactif (CNO) et nous présentons une caractérisation moléculaire de ces cellules. Nous montrons aussi qu'une diminution du niveau de la protéine Runx1 chez la souris augmente de façon significative la prolifération des COE présomptives et des précurseurs de COE. De plus, nous montrons qu'il y a une diminution concomitante dans le nombre de COE qui ont atteint la maturité développementale. Finalement, nous présentons des évidences initiales qui suggèrent que Runx1 est impliqué dans l'organisation topologique des COE qui expriment Runx1 dans la région interne du CNO. Ces résultats soulèvent la possibilité que Runx1 est impliqué dans la spécification du destin cellulaire des COE. Nous fournissons donc une avenue pour l'exploration future des mécanismes moléculaires qui contrôlent l'acquisition de l'identité, la spécification et la fonction des sous-populations spécifiques de COE.</description><description>Olfactory ensheathing cells (OECs) are a unique class of glia in the olfactory system. They exhibit characteristics of both Schwann cells and astrocytes and have the ability to cross the boundary between central (CNS) and peripheral (PNS) nervous systems. The indispensible contributions of OECs to the lifelong regeneration of the olfactory system has identified these cells as promising candidates for cell transplantation therapies to repair CNS injuries. However, initial studies have yielded highly variable results on the suitability of OECs for CNS regeneration strategies. The inherent heterogeneity of OECs is believed to underlie this problem, as only a subpopulation of OECs is thought to have axonal ensheathing properties. Learning how to harness the potential of the right subpopulation has been hindered by the lack of information regarding their specific functions and molecular properties. In this regard, we have previously shown that a particular transcription factor, termed Runx1, is expressed in cells thought to correspond to a subpopulation of OECs in the olfactory bulb (OB) and have set forth to explore its expression pattern and role in this region. We demonstrate Runx1 is preferentially expressed in OECs of the inner olfactory nerve layer (ONL) and molecularly characterization of this subset of cells. Additionally, we show that Runx1 knockdown in vivo perturbs the proliferation of presumptive OEC precursors and leads to an increase in Runx1-expressing OEC precursors, with a parallel decrease in the number of more developmentally mature OECs. Finally, we provide initial evidence suggesting that Runx1 might be involved in the topological organization of Runx1-expressing OECs within the inner ONL of the OB. These results raise the possibility that Runx1 might be involved in OEC fate specification and provide an avenue for further exploration into the molecular mechanisms underlying OEC subpopulation identity, specification and function.</description><creator>Murthy, Manjari</creator><contributor>Stefano Stifani (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Regulation of olfactory ensheathing cell development by the transcription factor Runx1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q059n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xg31q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sn78g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Visceral glomerular epithelial cells (GEC), also known as podocytes, are essential components of the kidney glomerulus, and play a pivotal role in maintaining normal glomerular permselectivity. The regulation of the actin cytoskeleton is central to podocyte morphology and function. In the rat model of membranous nephropathy, passive Heymann nephritis (PHN), heterologous antibody binds to GEC antigens. Following immune complex formation the complement system is activated with the assembly of the C5b-9 membrane attack complex. In GEC, C5b-9 induces sublytic injury associated with morphological changes and proteinuria. We have previously reported that complement activates RhoA, member of the Rho family of small GTPases, in vitro and in vivo. The current study addresses the role of GEF-H1, a Rho GEF protein, in complement-mediated RhoA activation in GEC injury. In glomeruli from rats with PHN and cultured GEC, complement stimulation increased GEF-H1 activity, in a parallel fashion with RhoA activation. Activation of GEF-H1 by complement was at least partially dependent on the extracellular signal-regulated kinases (ERK) pathway, but not on the epidermal growth factor (EGF) receptor, or Src-family kinases, or microtubules. To address the functional effects of GEF-H1, GEC were transduced with lentivirus-mediated shRNA of GEF-H1, to knockdown the expression. GEC transduced with shRNA of GEF-H1 significantly blocked RhoA activation and augmented cytotoxicity in response to complement stimulation, implicating a cytoprotective effect of GEF-H1 on GEC in complement-mediated injury.</description><description>Les cellules glomérulaires épithéliales viscérales (CGE), ou podocytes, sont des composantes essentielles du glomérule du rein, et jouent un rôle important dans le maintien de la permsélectivité glomérulaire. La régulation du cytosquelette d'actine est à la base du fonctionnement normal du podocyte, ainsi qu'à sa morphologie. Dans le modèle de rat de la néphropathie membraneuse, passive Heymann nephritis (PHN), les anticorps hétérologues se lient aux antigènes des podocytes. Après formation de complexes immuns, le système du complément est activé avec l'assemblage du complexe d'attaque membranaire C5b-9. Dans les CGE, C5b-9 induit des effets sublytiques associés à des modifications morphologiques et à la protéinurie. Nous avons déjà signalé que le complément active RhoA, membre de la famille Rho des petites GTPases, in vitro et in vivo. La présente étude porte sur le rôle de GEF-H1, une protéine de la famille des Rho GEF, dans l'activation de RhoA dans les CGE méditée par le complément. Dans les glomérules de rats avec PHN et dans les CGE cultivés in vitro, la stimulation du complément a augmenté l'activité de GEF-H1, d'une façon parallèle avec l'activation de RhoA. L'activation du GEF-H1 par le complément a été au moins partiellement dépendante de l'extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK), mais pas du facteur de croissance épidermique (EGF), de la famille des kinases Src, ou des microtubules. Pour faire face aux effets fonctionnels de GEF-H1, CGE ont été infectées par des lentivirus contenants un petit ARN en épingle à cheveu, pour réduire l'expression de GEF-H1. Les CGE infectées par les lentivirus ont bloqué de manière significative l'activation de RhoA et ont augmenté la toxicité en réponse à la stimulation du complément, impliquant un effet protecteur de GEF-H1 sur les CGE.</description><creator>Mouawad, Flaviana</creator><contributor>Tomoko Takano (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Role of guanine nucleotide exchange factor-H1 in complement- mediated RhoA activation in glomerular epithelial cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw083.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sn78g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80j002v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:25:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Turning Over is a 13-minute composition for 13 instruments, piano, electronic piano and pre-recorded electronics. A strong emphasis on harmony, representing the result of two years of research into various intonation theories of the 17th, 18th and 20th centuries, is reflected in the subtle variations in intonation between the equal-tempered acoustic instruments and the just-intonation tuning of the electronics as well as the electronic piano. The musical discourse reflects philosophical concerns regarding the concept of essence in music and its illusive nature – this translates into a musical form that is in a constant state of transformation.</description><description>Turning Over ('ressasser') est une composition pour 13 instruments, piano, piano électronique et sons électroniques d'une durée de 13 minutes. Un fort accent sur l'harmonie, qui est le résultat de deux années de recherche sur les théories du tempérament musical du 17e, 18e et 20e siècle, est reflété dans les variations subtiles de tempérament entre les instruments acoustiques et les éléments électroniques. Le discours musical reflète des préoccupations philosophiques concernant le concept de l'essence dans la musique et de sa nature illusoire – ceci se traduit dans une forme musicale qui est toujours en état de transformation.</description><creator>Flanagan, Beavan</creator><contributor>John Rea (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Turning over, for 13 instruments, piano, electronic microtonal piano and electronics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gh31m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j002v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):14625</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>