<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:49:22Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rh81n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines one facet of the nineteenth-century territorial expansion of French Canada. It analyzes the principal features of the settlement history of the northern coast of the Gaspe Peninsula where colonization did not begin in earnest until the 1830s when the expansion of the Jersey cod fishery encouraged many Baie des Chaleurs residents to move permanently to the easternmost outports of the study area. Between 1840 and 1880, a much larger contingent of landless French-Canadians from parishes located between Levis and Matane, on the southern shore of the St. Lawrence River, settled the remainder of the Gaspe north coast. Successful permanent settlement on the Gaspe coast hinged on the colon's ability to exploit a full array of maritime, littoral and terrestrial resources. This resulted in a clearly-defined annual cycle of subsistence and commercial activities and in the rise of a plural economy. The family and kin group played an instrumental role in this cycle of resource exploitation as well as in the migration process itself. In contrast, the French-Canadian clergy and politicians played only a minor role, despite the elite's many statements on the nineteenth-century colonization movement and notwithstanding the widespread impression that fervent Catholicism and a strong sense of nationalism dominated traditional French-Canadian society.</description><creator>Remiggi, Frank William.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Land settlement -- Québec (Province) -- Gaspé Peninsula.</subject><subject>Migration, Internal -- Québec (Province) -- Gaspé Peninsula.</subject><title>Nineteenth-century settlement and colonization on the Gaspé north coast : an historical - geographical interpretation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k802q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh81n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z608d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to determine the role of biogenic monoamines in the control of pancreatic secretion, the metabolism and disposition of 5-hydroxytryptamine (5-HT) and dopamine in rat exocrine pancreas was studied. Pancreatic acinar cells contained 5-HT which was located exclusively in the zymogen granule fraction. Aromatic amino acid decarboxylase activity was located exclusively in the cytosol of acinar cells and was substrate specific for the L-isomers of hydroxylated aromatic amino acids 3,4-dihydroxyphenylalanine(L-DOPA) and 5-hydroxytryptophan (L-5-HTP). Each substrate competitively inhibited the decarboxylation of the other. When incubated with {('14)C}5-HT dispersed acinar cells took up the amine and concentrated it in zymogen granules. These cells also took up {('14)C}5-HTP, decarboxylated it and stored the {('14)C}5-HT produced in zymogen granules. 5-HTP decarboxylation and 5-HT concentration into zymogen granules occurred in the pancreas, but not in the parotid gland. When pancreatic acinar cells pre-labelled with {('14)C}5-HT and {('3)H}Leucine were stimulated with caerulein, there was a synchronous increase in secretion of amylase activity, {('14)C}5-HT and {('3)H}protein. Pancreatic acinar cells took up L-DOPA, decarboxylated it but the dopamine was not retained by the granules and dopamine secretion from the cells incubated with caerulein could not be demonstrated. The results indicate that (1) in the acinar cell of rat pancreas 5-HT is a normal component of zymogen granule; (2) pancreatic acinar cells possess a single aromatic amino acid decarboxylase specific for DOPA and 5-HTP; (3) zymogen granule 5-HT and zymogen granule protein are released together when the cells are stimulated to secrete protein.</description><creator>Yu,Edward Wing-Tung.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>5-hydroxytryptamine in rat pancreatic acinar cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n411k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z608d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nm21t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The idea of an operational category over A generalizes the notions of tripleable and equational category over A, and also the dual notions of cotripleable and coequational category. An operational category, U:D (---&gt;) A is given by a presentation ((theta),H) (UNFORMATTED TABLE FOLLOWS) D C('T) C('(theta)) A C('B) H*(TABLE ENDS) where (theta) is a functor bijective on objects and D is a specified pullback. R:Op(A) (---&gt;) Cat/A is defined as the category of operational categories (and functors) with given presentations. Another category, Op(,o)(A) over Cat/A of operational categories with standard presentations is also defined. There is a fixed theory (theta)(,o), employed in every standard presentation. Op(,o)(A) is a retract of Op(A) over Cat/A: (UNFORMATTED TABLE FOLLOWS) i Op(,o)(A) Op(A) s R(,o) R Cat/A(TABLE ENDS) i.e. every operational category (and functor) has a standard presentation (but not s(REVTURNST)i!). Also R(,o) has a left adjoint L(,o) and Op(,o)(A) is complete. Finally, there is a category of algebras, S(,*)-Alg over Cat/A such that Op(,o)(A) (DBLTURN) S(,*)-Alg over Cat/A. Thus, the operational categories can be determined by their internal structure, without reference to any presentation. Some properties of operational categories and some special cases are also examined.</description><creator>Lardner-Cornett, R. Jack.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Water -- Dissolved oxygen.</subject><subject>Limnology -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Prediction and interpretation of rates of hypolimnetic oxygen depletion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k983.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm21t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fs08g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the extrusion blow molding process the shape and thickness distribution of the finished container depend on the dimensions of the parison at the time of inflation. In particular, the processes of swell and sag act to cause a variation of parison dimensions between the time the melt emerges from the die and the moment of inflation. In the present study the effects of die geometry, extrusion velocity and the rheological properties of the resin on parison behavior were studied. Four annular dies (a straight, a diverging and two converging dies) and three high density polyethylene resins were used. To study the individual contributions of swell and sag to the overall parison behavior, two types of experiments were carried out. First, swell was studied in the absence of sag by extruding the parison into an isothermal oil bath. Both diameter and thickness swells were measured as functions of time. Then combined effect of swell and sag was studied by extruding the parison into an isothermal air oven. A simple lumped parameter model was developed to predict the length of the parison using the swell data, storage modulus and process variables.</description><creator>Orbey, Neṣe.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Extrusion process.</subject><subject>Plastics -- Molding.</subject><title>Sag and swell of extrudate from annular dies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290b23h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fs08g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fs09r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Efficient allocation of scarce resources to health programs involves measuring the economic benefits of life saving and/or improvement in health status. While several attempts have been made to quantify individual preferences for life, only a few, if any, have attempted to measure individual preferences for quality of life. In this thesis, we develop a methodology based on the estimation of individual preference functions to arrive at monetary measures of the value of marginal improvements in health status. The first chapter reviews conventional methodologies for estimating the value of human life, and points out many theoretical and empirical propositions related to our own concerns. The second chapter analyzes various procedures used to quantify variations in health status. We distinguish non-monetary procedures, which combine recent psychometric techniques and research on health level scaling to obtain estimates of the relative desirability of a state of health, and monetary procedures which, we conclude, still need to be developed. The third chapter presents a new methodology based on the direct estimation of bivariate welfare function of income and level of health. The theoretical basis of our approach and the data source are described in this chapter. Various functional forms were tried but we have finally retained the log-normal specification to derive estimates of the monetary value of a marginal change in the state of health for different subgroups of individuals. We conclude with critical discussion of our results. Some improvements over the approach used are suggested in the fifth chapter.</description><creator>Bastien, Michel.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Public health -- Evaluation.</subject><subject>Public health -- Research.</subject><subject>Health surveys -- Statistical methods.</subject><title>Valeur monétaire de modifications permanentes au niveau de santé : un essai d'estimation basé sur les fonctions de bien-être individuelles</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d978c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fs09r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sb02d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Eight experiments tested priming in short-term memory as a model for latent inhibition and habituation. The model postulates that the two phenomena result from reduced processing when a representation of the target stimulus is already active (primed) in short-term memory at the time of its presentation. Priming is assumed to depend on the integrity of an association formed between the contextual stimuli and the conditional stimulus (CS) during exposure. Using a procedure that should have overshadowed the context, Experiment 1 found that latent inhibition and habituation were nevertheless maintained when a second CS of either equal or shorter duration overlapped with the target during exposure. Experiment 2 found no support for the priming of a configural stimulus when simultaneous compounds were preexposed. Experiment 3 ruled out sensitization and/or pseudoconditioning as an alternative explanation of latent inhibition. Experiments 4, 5 and 6 showed that sensory preconditioning as well as habituation and latent inhibition were obtained with compound exposure, providing evidence that the added CS was indeed processed along with the target. In Experiment 7, sequential pairings produced as much latent inhibition as compounds but less sensory preconditioning. Experiment 8 showed that retardation of conditioned inhibition was not attenuated by compound exposure. These results are interpreted as consistent with a correlational approach to classical conditioning.</description><creator>Mercier, Pierre</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Inhibition.</subject><subject>Conditioned response.</subject><subject>Short-term memory.</subject><subject>Habituation (Neuropsychology)</subject><subject>Classical conditioning.</subject><title>Latent inhibition and habituation during sensory preconditioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh84s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sb02d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343s96j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A general method for the formation of acetals using chlorotrimethylsilane has been developed. Dioxolanes are formed from most carbonyl groups whereas methyl acetals are only formed from electron-poor carbonyl groups. The intermediacy of a silicon-bound carbonyl species is discussed. The method has been extended to the formation of esters. In a solution of the alcohol to be esterified, methyl, ethyl, benzyl and 2-trimethylsilylethyl esters are readily formed in the presence of chlorotrimethylsilane. Using ('29)Si-N.M.R., a trimethylsilyl ester has been shown to be an intermediate in the reaction. The Lewis acid catalyzed condensation of 1,3-bis-trimethylsiloxy-1-methoxy-1,3-butadiene with a variety of dielectrophiles, in a 1,2 relationship, has been investigated. The relative order of electrophilic reactivity towards this compound has been found to be; RR'C(Cl)SC(,6)H(,5) &gt; ArCOCHO &gt; ArCOCHO &gt; RC(OCH(,3))(,2),RC(OCH(,3))SC(,6)H(,5) &gt; RCHCl(,2). The dialkylation of 1,3-bis-trimethylsiloxy-1-methoxy-1,3-butadiene has been shown to lead to hydroxycyclopentenones with the same substitution pattern as the prostaglandins skeleton. Using ('29)Si-N.M.R., the mechanism of this reaction has been shown to proceed in two sequential steps; reaction of the (gamma)-position takes place first to give a titanium-bound intermediate, the thus formed intermediate then undergoes (alpha)-alkylation to give the cyclopentenone compound.</description><creator>Brook, Michael Adrian.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Silicon.</subject><subject>Organosilicon compounds.</subject><subject>Trimethylsilyl.</subject><title>The trimethylsilyl group in organic synthesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t269h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s96j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vp32z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The psychological significance of recurrent dreams was explored in a multivariate comparison of recurrent, previously-recurrent and non-recurrent dreamers on core psychological well-being and recalled dream content dimensions. Analytical psychology dream theory was employed to generate hypotheses concerning the relationship between recurrent dreams and psychological distress or neuroticism, and the psychological health value held to associate with the resolution of a recurrent dream. Sixty-seven individuals twice completed measures assessing core psychological well-being dimensions and collected a fourteen day time-sample of their remembered dreams. Multivariate and discriminant analyses revealed the clear separability of the comparison groups in the directions predicted by Jung. Recurrent dreamers achieved significantly less adaptive scores on the psychological well-being measures and reported significantly more conflicted and dysphoric dream content. Previously-recurrent dreamers achieved significantly higher psychological well-being scores and reported more thematically and affectively balanced dream content. The results are discussed in terms of insights afforded into the experience (and resolution) of recurrent dreams, and the support generated for core assertions of analytical psychology dream theory concerning the relationship between dreaming and psychological adaptation (individuation).</description><creator>Brown, Ronald James.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Psychoanalysis.</subject><subject>Dreams.</subject><title>An enquiry into the psychological meaning of recurrent dreams employing analytical psychology dream theory /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r6494.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp32z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jv351</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This exploratory study was designed to identify a range of variables distinguishing long-term unattached (LTU) from long-term committed (LTC) adults between the ages of 30 and 50. Specifically, it attempted to identify explanations for, and consequences of, long-term unattachment. LTU subjects selected were those who had not been in a committed, intimate relationship for eight or more years; LTC subjects selected were those who had been in a marital, or equivalent, relationship for eight or more years. The study was done in two parts. The preliminary study was qualitative and consisted of interviews of 14 subjects--seven LTUs and seven LTCs. LTU and LTC subjects were closely matched on demographic and socioeconomic variables. Emerging themes were added to the range of ideas from the review of literature. A questionnaire was developed from the comprehensive list of ideas. The final study was quantitative; 77 subjects were administered the questionnaire designed for the study, as well as the Millon Clinical Multiaxial Inventory (MCMI). LTUs' responses to the questionnaire and scores on the MCMI were compared with those of LTC subjects. All variables were subjected to discriminant function analysis, and univariate analysis. The results showed that: (a) LTUs came from families characterized by significant separations and losses, distant relationships with parents, and little communication within the family; (b) LTUs felt significantly more alienated from others as children and adults than LTCs; (c) LTUs were significantly higher than LTCs on MCMI scales schizoid, avoidant, passive-aggressive, schizotypal, and borderline, i.e., scales of personalities characterized by problems with intimate, committed relationships; (d) LTUs were not significantly more influenced than LTCs by sociocultural changes such as the human potential movement, the women's liberation movement, and the emphasis on romance in our culture; and (e) LTUs suffered significantly more than LTCs from despair and lack of meaning in their lives, and lacked satisfying ways of meeting others with whom they would like to be involved. Implications, limitations of the study, and suggestions for future research are proffered.</description><creator>Siegal, Marilyn G.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Attachment behavior</subject><subject>Interpersonal relations</subject><subject>Family</subject><subject>Social isolation</subject><title>Exploratory study of the long-term unattached</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n976.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jv351</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t073</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human type I interferons offer a relevant system to examine cell-specific inducible gene expression. Interferon genes are transcriptionally activated in a variety of cell types following induction by synthetic double-stranded RNA (poly I:C) and viruses. A transient expression system was developed which permits regulated expression of different IFN-CAT (chloramphenicol acetyltransferase) hybrid genes in human cells. Using this system in vivo competition assays identified positive and negative cellular factors interacting with the IFN-$ beta$ promoter. A factor that recognizes negative upstream regulatory sequences was also identified in uninduced myeloid cell extracts. Complementary studies demonstrated that transcription of the IFN-$ beta$ gene in vitro could be inhibited by a 44 bp synthetic oligonucleotide corresponding to the interferon regulatory element (IRE). This element is comprised of two genetically distinct positive regulatory domains, PRDI and PRDII, that are essential for maximal induction by virus or poly I:C. Binding and competition analysis showed that the PRDI element interacts with a factor(s) present in uninduced and virus-induced Hela extracts. The DNA-binding specificity of the PRDI factor(s) is characteristic of proteins recently shown to be involved in IFN-stimulated gene transcription. The PRDII domain is unrelated to PRDI, but shares 80% nucleotide homology with the NF-$ kappa$B binding site in the immunoglobulin kappa enhancer. PRDII was found to interact with an NF-$ kappa$B-like activity in both lymphoid and non-lymphoid cell extracts. An HIV-1 enhancer oligonucleotide containing two repeated $ kappa$B elements was interchangeable with PRDII in the gel retardation assay. UV-crosslinking analysis further revealed that several distinct inducible and constitutive proteins bind specifically to PRDII in different cell types, and suggests that multiple factors may interact with this element to regulate IFN-$ beta$ transcription. Taken togeth</description><creator>Xanthoudakis, Steven</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Interferons.</subject><title>Regulation of the human interferon-b promoter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq078.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t073</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88ch201</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research programme employed a combination of qualitative and quantitative methodologies to address the question of the effects of cooperative learning on kindergarten children's perspective-taking ability and prosocial behaviour. In an observational study, the kindergarten classes of two teachers who had the reputation for using small-group cooperative activities with their students were observed for one month at the beginning of the school year. Very few cooperative activities were employed during the observation period, making it impossible to determine the effects of engaging in such activities. An analysis of the qualitative observations elucidated techniques that these teachers used to create a smoothly functioning class. A quasi-experimental study was conducted involving kindergarten students working for six weeks in either an individualistic or cooperative programme. Both qualitative and quantitative observations indicate that students who engaged in cooperative learning activities displayed a higher number of instances of prosocial behaviour than those in the individualistic programme. The results revealed that participation in the cooperative programme positively correlated with increases in affective perspective taking.</description><creator>Chambers, Bette</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Group work in education</subject><subject>Interaction analysis in education</subject><subject>Child development</subject><subject>Cooperativeness</subject><title>The influence of cooperative learning activities on the perspective-taking ability and prosocial behaviour of kindergarten students /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c48b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch201</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m010f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pseudomonas pictorum can deplete serum cholesterol. Cholesterol depleted includes free cholesterol, esterified cholesterol and cholesterol bound to different lipoproteins. Temporarily accumulated cholestenone was metabolized as reaction continued. The reaction kinetics controls the global cholesterol depletion rate during the initial part of the fermentation. Then, mass transfer takes control. In the latter, the global rate was first order with respect to the cholesterol concentration and zero order with respect to the bacterial concentration. The half time was 330 min. The activation energy was 83 kJ/mol. These results are consistent with the aqueous cholesterol diffusion model. P. pictorum was immobilized in alginate beads, polylysine microcapsules and open pore agar beads. The latter depleted serum cholesterol. The depletion rates were similar to those of free P. pictorum, suggesting a barrier free mass transfer. The matrix effect diffusivity for lipoproteins at 37$ sp circ$C was 6.7 $ times$ 10$ sp{-11}$ m$ sp2$/s. The beads effectively retained P. pictorum. No leakage was detected.</description><creator>Garofalo, Flavio A. (Flavio Alberto)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Serum cholesterol depletion using immobilized pseudomonas pictorum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc03r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m010f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343s88v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines mother-daughter relationships in six novels written by German speaking women authors in the decade after the "Year of the Woman." Three novels depict positive mother-daughter relations: Ausflug mit der Mutter (1976), by Gabriele Wohmann, Gestern war Heute (1979), by Ingeborg Drewitz, Die dreizehnte Fee (1983), by Katja Behrens. Three others portray a negative mother-daughter relationship: Die Eisheiligen (1979), by Helga Novak, Die Zuchtigung (1985), by Waltraud Anna Mitgutsch, and Die Klavierspielerin (1983), by Elfriede Jelinek. Common to all novels is a strong autobiographical tendency and the central importance of the mother in the development of the daughter's self-identity. The complexity and problems of mother-daughter relationships are analyzed as an outcome of female socialization within a patriarchal society. Chapter I deals with historical, economic and psychological oppression of women. The resulting internalization of the role of inferiority and dependency leads to the subsequent repression of their own daughters. Chapter II discusses new contributions in the fields of psychology and sociology to the understanding of female identity formation through relationships. Chapter III provides a two-pronged analysis of each novel by describing the individual mother-daughter relationship in comparison with the outcomes of Chapters I and II, and by addressing the narrator's process of putting the experience into a unique literary form and thus contributing to women's literature. Themes that are unique in each novel are: the emotional stress of the adult daughter trying to redefine her relationship with her widowed mother (Ausflug mit der Mutter), the dichotomy of woman in her nurturing role as mother and in her quest for self-realization (Gestern war Heute), the difficulty of breaking the repetitive cycle of the female role of dependency (Die dreizehnte Fee). All of the following novels assess the damaged self-identity of the daughter caused by a destructive mother. While the daughters survive due to fierce resistance (Die Eisheiligen) or escape into the world of art (Die Zuchtigung) there is no hope for the daughter in Die Klavierspielerin due to her identification with the oppressor.</description><creator>Aulls, Katharina</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Mothers and daughters in literature</subject><subject>German fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism</subject><title>Mutter-Tochter Beziehungen in deutschsprachigen Romanen im Jahrzehnt nach dem "Jahr der Frau"</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d7199.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s88v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b6784</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We consider a nonlinear mathematical program, with twice continuously differentiable functions. If a point x$ sb0$ does not satisfy a certain Second Order Sufficient Condition (SOS) for optimality (that does not require any constraint qualification, see, e.g., BEN-ISRAEL, BEN-TAL and ZLOBEC (81)), then we prove that the knowledge of the second order properties (derivative, Hessian) of the functions is not enough to conclude that the point is optimal. When the functions are continuously perturbed, what is the local behavior of an optimal solution x$ sb0$ and of the associate optimal value? The stability and sensitivity of the mathematical model are addressed. We present a new method for solving this problem. Our approach does not rely on the classical Lagrangian coefficients (which cannot be always defined) but rather on power series expansions because we use the primal formulations of optimality. In the regular case, when Strict complementarity slackness holds, we recover Fiacco's results (FIACCO (83)). On the other hand, when Strict complementarity slackness does not hold, we extensively generalize Shapiro's Theorems (SHAPIRO (85)) since we do not assume Robinson's second order condition (ROBINSON (80)) but the SOS condition. In the non-regular case, no general algorithm for computing the derivative of the optimizing point with respect to the parameters had been presented up to now. The approach is extended to analyze the evolution of the set of Pareto minima of a multiobjective nonlinear program. In particular, we define the derivative of a point-to-set map. Our notion seems more adequate than the contingent derivative (AUBIN (81)), though the latter can easily be deduced from the former. This allows to get information about the sensitivity of the set of Pareto minima. A real-life example shows the usefulness and the simplicity of our results. Also, an application of our method to industry planning (within a general framework of Input Optimization) is made in the ideal case of a linear model.</description><creator>Nahum, Carole</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Second order sensitivity analysis in mathematical programming</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx74t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b6784</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vc05b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reactions $ gamma gamma$ $ to$ 2$ pi sp+2 pi sp-2 pi sp0$ and $ gamma gamma to pi sp+ pi sp- pi sp0 pi sp0$ have been studied by using the ARGUS detector at the $e sp+e sp-$ storage ring DORIS II at DESY. In the $2 pi sp+2 pi sp-2 pi sp0$ final state the production of $ omega$-mesons is observed and in particular the reaction $ gamma gamma$ $ to$ $ omega omega$ is seen for the first time. The cross section for $ gamma gamma to omega omega$ is found to have an enhancement at $ sim$1.9GeV/c$ sp2$ of about 12 nb. The topological cross sections for the reactions $ gamma gamma$ $ to$ 2$ pi sp+2 pi sp-2 pi sp0$ and $ gamma gamma$ $ to$ $ omega pi sp+ pi sp- pi sp0$ are also measured. The production of charged $ rho$-mesons is observed in the $ pi sp+ pi sp- pi sp0 pi sp0$ final state. The cross section for the reaction $ gamma gamma$ $ to$ $ rho sp+ rho sp-$ is measured for the first time. The cross section did not show a threshold enhancement similar to that found in the reaction $ gamma gamma$ $ to$ $ rho sp0 rho sp0$ and is about a factor of four smaller. A spin parity analysis of the $ rho sp+ rho sp-$ system shows that the cross section is dominated by the two amplitudes $J sp{P}$ = 0$ sp+$ and $J sp{P}$ = 2$ sp+$ with helicity 2.</description><creator>Tsipolitis, George</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Omega omega] and [rho]+[rho- production in two photon interactions at ARGUS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354f94m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vc05b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f190p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Observations consist of n sample path segments each coming from one of m possible point processes. The object is to classify each segment as having arisen from one of the m processes. The problem is an extension of the classical clustering problem where the classification is into groups having the same distribution. Poisson processes receive special attention so that the clusters consist of those sample path segments with the same intensity. In the parametric case both Bayesian and maximum likelihood methods are used to determine criteria for clustering while in the non-parametric setting only the classification likelihood approach is employed. The methods are applied to a data set from a group of patients with epilepsy.</description><creator>Zieliński, Jan M. (Jan Miroslaw)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Clustering procedures for sample paths from poisson processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xj36p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f190p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j97q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents for the first time direct structural measurements of both reversible and irreversible structural relaxation and the glass transition in the metal-metalloid glass Pd$ sb{40}$Ni$ sb{40}$P$ sb{20}$. The techniques have been x-ray diffraction and Mossbauer spectroscopy, and a new analysis method for changes of amorphous diffraction patterns was developed. It is found that irreversible relaxation proceeds by many local shear-type motions involving the metal atoms, and that it is accompanied by a small densification. Reversible relaxation at high annealing temperatures entails the same microscopic processes, but it does not change the density of the glass. The type of atomic processes changes continuously as the annealing temperature is lowered, and at sufficiently low temperatures the distribution of metal atoms remains constant, so that reversible relaxation then proceeds via rearrangement of the metalloid atoms. This rearrangement leads to more ordered, but less isotropic atomic sites. The second part of the thesis is concerned with the motion of the atoms in a metallic glass below and above the glass transition. Mossbauer spectroscopy allows the direct measurement of vibrational and diffusional motion. The increase of the amplitude of atomic vibration has the same temperature dependence as the increase in volume that marks the glass transition, thus the two processes are governed by the same mechanism. The directly measured diffusional motion is in agreement with macroscopic measurements of diffusion.</description><creator>Brüning, Ralf</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Structural relaxation and the glass transition in metallic glasses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r171f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j97q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zv03g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A description and analysis of the outcomes of an experiment with Kohlberg's Just Community Approach in the development of moral judgements of francophone delinquents is examined. Data were collected from 12 adolescents ranging in age from 17 to 18 years and from 8 adult educators involved in the Just Community Program at Boscoville Center (Montreal, Qc.) which was implemented between October 1987-October 1988. Kohlberg's Structural Issue Moral Judgement Interview and several questionnaires were administered and journals kept by the educators and the researcher. Analysis of these data allowed us to describe how the program was implemented and showed that the intervention appreciably increased the stage of moral judgement of participants and improved the "moral atmosphere" of the program. In comparison to previous evaluations of the Just Community Approach, this program had more impact on these outcomes. It is suggested that the effects of the program could be strengthened by more intensive training of educators.</description><creator>Dionne, Jacques</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Moral development -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Juvenile delinquents -- Rehabilitation -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Evaluation de la mise en oeuvre d'une intervention de Communauté juste avec des adolescents délinquants</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cd95s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zv03g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p1034</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since women's entry into the workforce has constituted such a tremendous social change, its political consequences deserve further study. This investigation uses the 1977 Quality of Life Survey to assess the political impact of both objective and subjective features of women's work on political involvement. Results demonstrate that mere employment fails to politicize women, but either higher salaries or professional positions can act as political catalysts. In addition, jobs that are perceived to be "good", or that possess a number of positive qualities, may also be politically beneficial. Manual labor, on the other hand, actually discourages political involvement, and unions are not politically helpful. More research should be conducted into the family context which contributes to the "double burden" of working women (the dual set of responsibilities shouldered by women--at home and on the job). Furthermore, the still limited political and employment opportunities realistically available to women merit greater scholarly attention.</description><creator>Deller, Joanne Elizabeth</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Women -- Employment</subject><subject>Wages -- Women</subject><subject>Women in politics.</subject><title>The impact of employment : the blossoming of politically motivated women?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q967t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p1034</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722h960p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sexual 'arousal' in Helix aspersa can be divided into 2 components, sexual proclivity (the tendency of a snail to respond to conspecific contact with courtship) and sexual arousal (the intensity with which the snail courts). Sexual proclivity and sexual arousal have different effects on feeding and locomotion and are differentially affected by sexual isolation, daily conspecific contact, and by a courtship pheromone found in the digitiform gland mucus. Therefore sexual arousal and sexual proclivity are probably mediated by 2 separate physiological mechanisms. Behavioural state, or the animal's general level of activity, correlates positively with mating behaviour. However, although a central system controlling behavioural state probably exists, it has no direct effect on either sexual proclivity or sexual arousal. Confusion over the term 'arousal', which impedes neuroethological research in this area, would be decreased by the adoption of the terms used in this thesis.</description><creator>Adamo, Shelley A. (Shelley Anne)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Brown garden snail -- Sexual behavior.</subject><subject>Brown garden snail -- Reproduction.</subject><title>An examination of the concept of arousal within the context of the sexual behaviour of the snail, Helix aspersa /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k626.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722h960p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zh515</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of various steroid hormones on human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) production and placental viability were investigated using an explant culture model of human placenta. Placental hCG production was assessed using two different methods: (a) hCG concentrations in media recovered from cultures were measured by radioimmunoassay and (b) tissue levels of hCG in cultured placentae were determined immunohistochemically; both were evaluated before and after exposure to steroid hormones. In first trimester placentae, progesterone and dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA) increased hCG concentrations both in collected medium and levels in cultured placentae. Estradiol increased the levels of hCG in tissues but not in media. Cortisol increased concentrations in media but did not alter tissue levels. Testosterone decreased hCG levels in media, but had no effect on hCG placental content. In third trimester cultures, progesterone and DHEA were the only hormones studied which increased concentrations of hCG in media; estradiol, cortisol and testosterone had no effect. Progesterone, estradiol and DHEA, alone or in combination, extended the viability of first trimester placental explant cultures from approximately 7 to 30 days. There was a significant relationship between placental viability and tissue hCG levels (r = 0.73, P $&lt;$ 0.001). The concentrations of hCG, progesterone and estradiol in human placentae were determined at various times through gestation. These studies suggest that a temporal relationship exists between the placental levels of hCG and these steroids, and that they may be significant determinants of growth and differentiation of the placenta in vivo. Furthermore, these investigations support the hypothesis that hCG production by the placenta is subject to paracrine regulation by steroid hormones.</description><creator>Ahmed, Najma Ayesha</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Studies on the regulation of chorionic gonadotropin production in explant cultures of human placenta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj419.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh515</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r637b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The potential of granular zeolites as a heating medium for drying corn was evaluated in a batch type experimental dryer. At temperatures from 150-250$ sp circ$C and residence times of 3-8 minutes, synthetic zeolites (4A and 13X) removed 9-18 percentage points from the initial moisture of corn. These values were about double those of sand, the most commonly used particulate medium. Using an adiabatic dryer, the kinetics of moisture sorption in corn-zeolite mixtures was investigated. The heating medium in this part of the study was a natural zeolite (chabazite) and the corn was yellow dent type. Diffusivity values for corn were 1.012 $ times$ 10$ sp{-5}$ $-$ 3.127 $ times$ 10$ sp{-5}$ cm$ sp2$/s with zeolite at temperatures of 140-220$ sp circ$C. These values are much smaller than those for zeolite. Therefore, it is believed that the diffusion of moisture in corn itself is the main resistance to the transfer of moisture. The heat transfer coefficient between corn and zeolite was found to be in the range of 50-312 W/m$ sp2 cdot$K. Luikov's model for simultaneous heat and mass transfer was applied to corn-zeolite mixtures and the equations were solved by the Numerical Method of Lines (NMOL). These numerical solutions agreed closely with the experimental data. The processed corn was subjected to in vivo and chemical analyses. Results of feeding experiments using laboratory rats did not indicate that the nutritive quality of the processed corn was adversely affected. Similarly, the acid detergent fibre analysis did not show a significant reduction in the availability of corn protein.</description><creator>Alikhani, Zaman</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Zeolites.</subject><subject>Corn -- Drying.</subject><title>Zeolites as particulate medium for contact heating and drying of corn</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv729.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r637b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s3228</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phenoxyacetyl group was investigated as a base protecting group in oligoribonucleotide synthesis using the phosphoramidite coupling procedure. The N-phenoxyacetyl protected ribonucleoside methylphosphoramidites were prepared and they were evaluated in the synthesis of a number of oligoribonucleotides, including a 75-unit-long molecule whose base sequence is related to the yeast formylmethionine initiator tRNA. A side reaction leading to some cleavage of the assembled oligoribonucleotide chain was observed in oligoribonucleotide synthesis, following the standard procedure. The nature of this side reaction was identified and a procedure to eliminate it was developed. An extensive study has been carried out to prove the fidelity of alkylsilyl groups as the 2$ sp prime$-hydroxyl protecting group in oligoribonucleotide synthesis. A series of natural dinucleotides were prepared. The corresponding dinucleotides with the unnatural 2$ sp prime$-5$ sp prime$ phosphate linkage were also synthesized. The products from the synthesis as well as the intermediates during the synthesis were characterized by $ sp1$H and $ sp{31}$P NMR and HPLC. Unambiguous chemical evidence of the stability of the phosphate linkages in synthetic oligoribonucleotides was provided. Several ribozymes and their substrates were chemically synthesized. A general procedure to prepare novel mixed DNA-RNA polymers was developed. The usefulness of this type of molecule in molecular biology has been demonstrated in the study of the mechanism of ribozyme catalysis.</description><creator>Wu, Taifeng</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the chemical synthesis of natural and novel oligoribonucleotides using alkylsilyl protecting groups</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f191z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s3228</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407x98f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The larvae of Tenebrio molitor Linne and Alphitobius diaperinus (Panzer) both aggregated upon substrates treated with aqueous extracts of conspecific larval frass. Lactic acid is a pheromone in the frass of both species. Alphitobius larvae were attracted to lactic acid, while lactic acid caused Tenebrio larvae to arrest. Propionic acid is a repellent pheromone present in Tenebrio frass, but the lactic acid-induced response is dominant. The role of these chemical factors in population orientation of the larvae of these mealworm species is discussed. The cuticular lipids of the larvae of both species contained close-range attractants that had a role in aggregate formation. The Tenebrio cuticular lipid pheromone is predominately 8,9-pentacosanediol. The Alphitobius cuticular pheromone is a mixture of at least two compounds. The ecological preferences of these larvae suggested that these aggregation pheromones increased the density of individuals per unit volume. This increased density had varying effects on the physiological development of Tenebrio individuals.</description><creator>Weaver, David K. (David Keith)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Insects -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Insect pests</subject><subject>Pheromones.</subject><subject>Tenebrionidae.</subject><title>The role of selected frass chemicals and cuticular lipid components in the orientation of certain larval Tenebrionidae /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm48m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x98f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t263v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:10:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bernard Lonergan's economic writings have not been fully evaluated by economists although two recent papers by Burley (1989a, 1989b) show that work has begun. The purpose of this dissertation, therefore, is to situate Lonergan's (1944) economics essay, Circulation Analysis, in the history of economic thought of the period as well as to present a Lonerganian cycle model. Circulation Analysis examines fundamental macrodynamic processes to explain fluctuations. It was written in the early 1940s following a period of controversy and debate that led to the current paradigms of economic dynamics. The two sides of the debate are exemplified by Harrod (1936) and Hayek (1933 (1928), 1939), in particular. The controversy ended with World War II and the emerging hegemony of the Anglo-American approach, which separated macrodynamics into growth theory (long-run supply problems), and stabilization theory (short-run demand problems). This dissertation argues that this dichotomy is unsatisfactory and proposes Lonergan's pure cycle as an alternative paradigm. Lonergan's pure cycle restores the importance of supply-side dynamics in the short-run, without denying the primacy of demand issues in the analysis of deviations. A Lonerganian approach views demand shocks as essentially monetary, but also contends that the distribution of nominal income can cause shocks, if it is not synchronized with changes in real variables. In this thesis a Lonerganian model is presented that uses a Kydland-Prescott (1982) type of "time-to-build" technology. The model is subjected to permanent productivity shocks to investment, which explain, with a lag, equilibrium output. The monetary and distributional shocks to demand, which are temporary, can then explain the deviation of actual output from its equilibrium value. The model uses a Beveridge and Nelson (1981) approach, which specifies changes in growth rates of variables as a function of permanent and temporary shocks. The shocks are identified because the model is recursive: first, the productivity shock determines investment and equilibrium output; then, the monetary shock determines prices and sales of consumer goods. Simulation results are presented.</description><creator>De Neeve, Eileen O'Brien</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Lonergan, Bernard J. F.</subject><subject>Macroeconomics -- Mathematical models</subject><title>Bernard Lonergan's "Circulation analysis" and macrodynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj42k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t263v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>