<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:38:46Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38975" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k06989451</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mammalian prosomatostatin (PSS) is cleaved at an Arg-Lys doublet in order to produce somatostatin-14 (SS-14), and at two singlets, Arg and Lys, in order to release SS-28 and PSS$ sb{ lbrack 1{-}10 rbrack}$ respectively. Furin, PC1, and PC2 are three recently cloned mammalian endoproteases, associated with the Golgi (furin) or targeted towards the secretory granules of the regulated pathway (PC1 and PC2). In order to determine the enzymes involved in the proteolytic processing of PSS and localize the endoproteolytic reactions in specific compartments of the secretory pathway, I compared PSS processing in endocrine (AtT-20, GH3, and GH4C1 pituitary cells) or nonendocrine tumor cell lines (COS-7 kidney cells, PC 12 pheochromocytoma, LoVo colon adenocarcinoma cells). The efficiency of PSS processing to SS-14, SS-28, and PSS$ sb{ lbrack 1{-}10 rbrack}$ was correlated with: (i) secretion through the constitutive or regulated pathway, (ii) mRNA expression for furin, PC1 and PC2, and (iii) exogenous expression of furin, PC1, and PC2 in cells deficient in these proteinases. Coexpression of PC1 and PC2 with rat PSS was accomplished by transient (COS-7 cells) or stable (GH4C1 cells) cotransfections of their cDNAs in the respective cell lines. In the case of furin, recombinant vaccinia viruses expressing human furin or rat PSS were used to coinfect COS-7 or LoVo cells. Furthermore, I examined the effect of granules on the expression of PC2 and on PSS processing, by incubating GH4C1 cells with insulin, EGF, and $ beta$-estradiol, a treatment known to induce granule formation. Cell extracts and secretion media were further analyzed by HPLC and somatostatin specific RIAs. Conclusions. (i) PSS is capable of monobasic processing within the constitutive secretory pathway. (ii) Such cleavages may be effected by furin or related endoproteases but are relatively inefficient. (iii) PC1 is capable of dibasic cleavage of PSS to SS-14 in both constitutive or regulated secretory cells. (iv) PC2 mediates SS-14 conversion only if expressed in regulated secretory cells. (v) The milieu of secretory cells, and not the granules, is required for PC2 activity. (vi) Furin is a mammalian SS-28 convertase, but not the unique one. (vii) A yet unknown endoprotease is responsible for PSS$ sb{ lbrack 1{-}10 rbrack}$ cleavage.</description><creator>Galanopoulou, Aristea S.</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Elucidation of the role of the mammalian endoproteases furin, PC1, and PC2 in rat prosomatostatin processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0969129.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06989451</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw45g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to reduce the test development cost and guarantee testable designs, it is essential to have synthesis transformations that are testability and test-set preserving. In this thesis, we study testability preservation of transformations that form the basis of existing state-of-the-art logic synthesis and optimization techniques. We show that the concurrent decomposition and factorization transformations, except dual-extraction of multiplexor structures, preserve testablility and test-set under several testing constraints. Furthermore, we provide sufficient conditions for test-set preservation under the algebraic resubstitution with complement transformation that cover a larger class of complementary expressions than was known previously. Experimental results show that dual-extraction of multiplexor structures is utilized in only 2 out of 50 benchmark circuits. We demonstrate that while disabling this transformation has negligible effect on area, it results in an efficient test-set preserving multilevel logic synthesis algorithm. Recently, it has been shown that retiming has a very strong impact on the run time of sequential, structural automatic test pattern generators (ATPGs), as well as the levels of fault coverage and fault efficiency attained. We show that retiming preserves testability with respect to a single stuck-at fault test set by adding a prefix sequence of a pre-determined number of arbitrary input vectors. Furthermore, we show that a new circuit attribute, termed density of encoding, is the main reason for high test generation time. We also propose a novel approach for reducing test pattern generation cost based on test-set preserving transformations. Experimental results show that high fault coverages can be achieved on high performance circuits optimized by retiming with a much less CPU time (a reduction of two orders of magnitude in several instances) than if ATPG is attempted directly on those circuits.</description><creator>El-Maleh, Aiman H.</creator><contributor>Rajski, Janusz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Testability preservation of combinational and sequential logic synthesis transformations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw392.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw45g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r58f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Airfoils with structural nonlinearities subject to two-dimensional subsonic flow may undergo aeroelastic instabilities even below the linear flutter boundary. This thesis studies the aeroelastic behaviour of airfoils accounting for structural nonlinearities. The feasibility and potential of a modern nonlinear dynamics approach to the understanding of the underlying dynamics is investigated. Extensive numerical simulations were performed for a two-degree-of-freedom air-foil with a freeplay nonlinearity in the structural pitch moment and subject to two-dimensional incompressible inviscid flow. Different types of attractors were identified well below the linear flutter speed via numerical simulations of the system, and the existence of chaotic attractors was verified. Basins of attraction and bifurcation diagrams were constructed showing rather complex dynamics of the system below the divergent flutter boundary. In some cases physical explanations are given for the air-foil's behaviour. Effects of the airfoil and nonlinearity parameters, airfoil camber and angle of attack and the compressibility of the fluid on the results are also presented, and it is shown that the system response is very sensitive to many parameters. Similar investigations are presented for an airfoil with either cubic, bilinear or hysteretic nonlinearities. In many cases, most notably where the airfoil is subject to small preload, small central stiffness and small hysteresis, chaotic motions are detected for a considerable range of speed. A period doubling route to chaos is obtained for the particular case of cubic nonlinearity. Numerical simulations were also performed for an airfoil-aileron combination and an airfoil with active flutter control accounting for freeplay structural nonlinearities in the pitch or flap hinge moment. More complex dynamics and chaotic oscillations were obtained for these three-degree-of-freedom systems. For the case of a freeplay in the aileron hinge moment a quasi-periodic route to chaos was identified. Various numerical methods were employed to solve the equations of motion. Similar results were obtained in terms of the bifurcations and the amplitude of oscillations for all the numerical methods, so verifying to some extent the different numerical methods employed. The systematic investigation of the aeroelastic response of airfoils with structural nonlinearities showed the existence of complex dynamics, and for velocities well below the linear flutter boundary it was demonstrated that the motion can be stable or that the airfoil can oscillate in a periodic or chaotic manner. The aeroelastic response was shown to be highly dependent on the initial conditions and numerous airfoil, nonlinearity and flow parameters. The results suggest that for aeroelastic analyses of aerosurfaces a nonlinear investigation of precise models is necessary.</description><creator>Alighanbari, Hekmatollah</creator><contributor>Price, S. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Flutter analysis and chaotic response of an airfoil accounting for structural nonlinearities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd96m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r58f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57ns92h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ceramic fibers are one of the most important categories of reinforcements for composite materials. This study deals with a novel melt extraction system which has been developed to produce fine oxide ceramic fibers. Four oxide compounds were selected for the production of fibers and characterization of the extraction system. These compounds were CaO-$ rm Al sb2O sb3$ (CA), ZrO$ sb2$-$ rm Al sb2O sb3$ (ZA), ZrO$ sb2$-$ rm Al sb2O sb3$-SiO$ sb2$ (ZAS), and ZrO$ sb2$-$ rm Al sb2O sb3$-TiO$ sb2$ (ZAT). Using a 150 W CO$ sb2$ laser, these materials were melted to obtain a small molten drop, and through shallow contact with a sharpened and bevelled molybdenum wheel, fibers were extracted at various wheel velocities. At low speeds (v  000$ sp circ$C) was measured using a novel technique. Various parameters such as laser power (temperature), wheel tip radius and feed rate have been studied and their effects on the extracted fiber dimensions were investigated. It is suggested that momentum transfer controls the extracted layer thickness and fiber dimensions. The viscosity of the liquid ceramics is a crucial factor in the system, and is estimated to be $&lt;$0.5 poise (0.05 Pa$ cdot$s) at ${ approx}2400 sp circ$C. Due to the fine fiber dimensions and strong conductive cooling of the molybdenum wheel, the extracted liquid layer was rapidly solidified, and fibers with amorphous, partially crystalline and/or metastable phases were formed. Uniform diameter fibers were amorphous, transparent, flexible and exhibited excellent tensile properties. Fine fibers with a diameter of ${ approx}$10 $ mu$m showed tensile strengths up to 3300 MPa, however, only moderate elastic moduli were achieved (95-143 GPa) due to the amorphous nature of the fibers. The rapidly solidified fibers were thermodynamically metastable, and as shown by differential thermal analysis (DTA), they devitrified in the temperature range of 930-980$ sp circ$C. Heating the fibers at higher temperatures resulted in the formation of various crystalline phases and the development of different grain morphologies.</description><creator>Allahverdi, Mehdi</creator><contributor>Drew, Robin A. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Melt extraction of oxide ceramic fibers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n29v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57ns92h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh547</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation argues that a pervasive ethical vision underlies the work of Friedrich Nietzsche (1844-1900): a concern for the possibility of human flourishing, in the modern world. Notwithstanding Nietzsche's celebrated claim to be "beyond good and evil", and against the standard interpretation of his "perspectivism", it is argued that Nietzsche makes qualitative, normative distinctions between higher, admirable modes of human existence and lower, contemptible ones, and that he wishes through his writings to foster the former and discourage the latter. Furthermore, it is argued that Nietzsche believes human excellence to be the property of a small minority of "higher" human beings, and that he identifies the project of encouraging human excellence with a political imperative of cultivating this gifted elite. The dissertation also argues that Nietzsche's picture of the fully flourishing human life suffers from a number of inconsistencies that may be traced back to his vacillation between two incompatible moral discourses: an Aristotelian discourse emphasising the importance of certain "external goods" (e.g. friendship, recognition, community) in a fully flourishing life, and a rival, Stoic-influenced discourse stressing the virtuous individual's total self-sufficiency. An examination is made of Nietzsche's stance towards the following key concepts and questions: truth, morality, virtue, instinct and "bodily" knowledge, nature, creativity, rationality, discipline and self-mastery, freedom, solitude and sociability, friendship, community, pity, breeding and heredity, women and gender relations, and domination.</description><creator>Appel, Fredrick</creator><contributor>Taylor, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1844-1900 -- Political and social views.</subject><subject>Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1844-1900 -- Contributions in ethics.</subject><title>Nietzsche's ethical vision : an examination of the moral and political philosophy of Friedrich Nietzsche</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw91q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh547</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bk07b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A group of 21 HIV-positive gay or bisexual men was compared with a matched group of 22 HIV-negative individuals. All subjects were sexually active gay or bisexual males matched for age, as well as age at first intercourse with males. Subjects completed a detailed sexual history questionnaire as well as a series of standardized measures of psychosocial functioning. Results indicated that subjects engaged in a wide range of unsafe sexual behaviours, and frequently combined drugs with sex. Scores on the Michigan Alcoholism Screening Test (MAST) were significantly correlated with lifetime condom use. Social support was also found to be significantly associated with the lifetime number of homosexual partners. Regression analysis revealed a significant negative association between MAST scores and social support and a positive relationship between social support and CD-4 cell count. The groups were found to be similar in terms of clinical levels of anxiety and depression, self-esteem in interpersonal situations, and risk-taking personality.</description><creator>Abracen, Jeffrey</creator><contributor>Talley, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Risk factors</subject><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects</subject><subject>Risk-taking (Psychology)</subject><title>Psychosocial risk factors for HIV infection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db893.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk07b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wf70m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of these studies was the identification and characterization of the micro-heterogeneity present within the joining peptide fragment of POMC. The joining peptide (JP) from various animal species was resolved into major and minor components by RP-HPLC and characterized in terms of amino acid composition. Amino acid analyses revealed that no apparent sequence variations occur in any of the JP forms, indicating that post-translational modifications were responsible for the heterogeneity. Using a combination of biochemical and analytical techniques, including RP-HPLC, mass spectrometry, Edman sequencing, peptide mapping and an in vitro methylation assay, we were able to identify the nature of the modifications. Within the mouse and porcine JP, we were able to show the occurrence of an isomerization reaction at an -Asp-Gly- sequence leading to the formation of isoaspartyl, aspartyl, and succinimide containing forms of JP. This reaction was also shown to occur in pro-ANF purified from rat atria. Biosynthetic studies in the mouse revealed that the reaction was occurring in the secretory granule. The kinetics of the reaction indicated that it was being promoted by some means, and steps were taken to identify the driving force. It was determined that neither carboxyl-methylation nor calcium ion concentration had any effect on the rate of isomerization; however, the reaction was promoted at higher pH levels. Additional modifications to which JP is subject were also characterized. We were able to determine that mouse JP is modified at both its amino- and carboxyl-termini, leading to the production of acetylated and amidated forms of JP. Each these forms was resolved by RP-HPLC and characterized using several mass spectrometry techniques.</description><creator>Toney, Karen, 1967-</creator><contributor>Bennett, H. P. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of post-translationally modified forms of the joining peptide fragment of pro-opiomelanocortin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g9335.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf70m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb73z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fluid flow and filtration phenomena associated with filtration of liquid aluminum using reticulated ceramic filters were systematically investigated. It was found that fluid flow through this type of filter could be described by Darcy's Law up to a Reynolds number of 8, and the permeability of this type of filter ranged from about $9 times10 sp{-3}$ to $4 times10 sp{-2} rm mm sp2$. Parameters affecting filtration processes during the initial period were identified, some of which could be quantified numerically using a 2-D computational domain. According to these numerical analyses, the clean filter coefficient for this type of filter was linearly dependent on the dimensionless Stokes velocity of the suspended particles, had a $-$0.96 power dependence on the Peclet number, a $-$6.93 power dependence on the effective porosity of the filter, and exhibited only a weak dependence on the Reynolds number, in the Darcy velocity regime. The dynamic behaviour of this type of filter was analyzed theoretically and simulated numerically using newly proposed correlations relating the filter coefficient and the pressure drop to the amount of particles captured within the filter (the specific deposit), and a model describing the morphology of captured particles. The simulated results showed that the filtration efficiency and the pressure drop increased with inlet particle concentration and filtration time; these increases were however, insignificant when the inlet particle concentration was less than 1 ppm for filtration periods of two hours, however, when the inlet concentration (initial and continued) reached 10 ppm, the change became appreciable. Experimental data, obtained from liquid aluminum filtration tests conducted by the author in both laboratory and industrial settings, compared favourably with the numerical results.</description><creator>Tian, Chenguo</creator><contributor>Guthrie, R. I. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Filtration of liquid aluminum with reticulated ceramic filters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d1903.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb73z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95052301</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many of the problems faced in magnetic resonance imaging and angiography are due to hardware limitations of the scanners used. The use of multidimensional excitation pulses, and new, fast acquisition sequences such as echo-planar and spiral imaging, put demands on the gradient systems and although technology is progressing in these areas, performance must be carefully monitored to ensure artefact-free images. This thesis deals with four distinct aspects of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). A simple hardware modification to decrease the minimum achievable echo-time of our MRI scanner was designed, built, programmed and tested and was found to improve the quality of inflow angiograms significantly. Further improvements were demonstrated with the use of on-resonance (binomial) magnetization transfer saturation contrast enhancement pulses. A method for measuring the k-space trajectories of gradient waveforms was adopted, modified, validated and used to measure the k-space trajectories of gradient waveforms used for selective excitation and spiral image acquisition. Distortion was observed even when gradient waveforms were designed within specifications of the manufacturer. The literature reports the application of the k-space model, usually associated with image acquisition, to the design of multidimensional selective excitation pulses. This thesis demonstrates theoretically and experimentally the modification of the design procedure to compensate RF envelopes for distortion of the k-space trajectories of the accompanying gradient waveforms by using measured k-space data. The correction of spiral image reconstruction algorithms to compensate for k-space trajectory distortion was also demonstrated theoretically and experimentally.</description><creator>Takahashi, Atsushi M. (Atsushi Mark)</creator><contributor>Peters, T. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Rapid data acquisition and selective excitation in magnetic resonance imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b526d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052301</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd39c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the notion of partnership as an approach to long-term sustainable development in Africa, by examining relationships Canadian non-governmental organizations (NGOs) forge with their donors and with counterpart NGOs in developing countries. A case study methodology was used to examine how Canadian NGOs in general, and CARE Canada in particular, work in partnership with the Canadian International Development Agency (CIDA), and Kenyan local NGOs. The findings indicate that the development themes and agendas of the past three development decades are reflected in the activities and programs of Canadian NGOs. However, very little was learned about the contribution of partnership to African development. CARE Canada's partnership relations seem to be guided by the development priorities of funding agencies such as CIDA, which dictate how CARE relates to its Kenyan partners. Partnership seems only to facilitate an environment for dialogue between organizations, concerning needs, constraints and fiscal accountability. The study proposes that further research on the concept of development partnerships needs to be carried out in-depth to determine how this model can be used in building capacities of African organizations.</description><creator>Kambites Mukebezi, Sarah</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Canadian International Development Agency</subject><subject>Economic assistance, Canadian -- Kenya</subject><subject>Non-governmental organizations -- Canada</subject><title>Non-governmental organizations as partnering agencies : a case study of the relationship between Canadian NGOs with CIDA and Kenyan local groups</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1676.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd39c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c013g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cyclophosphamide is a bifunctional alkylating agent. Administration of low doses of cyclophosphamide to male rats produces severe effects on the outcome of their progeny. The studies in this thesis show that one week treatment with cyclophosphamide can produce about 30% post-implantation loss. This indicates that post-testicular spermatozoa are sensitive to alkylating agents. Previous studies have shown that six weeks treatment caused more than 95% post-implantation loss. The effects of cyclophosphamide treatment on rat spermatozoal nuclei in the testis and epididymis were also addressed in this thesis. Rat cauda epididymal spermatozoa collected after one week of cyclophosphamide treatment showed no change in decondensation pattern in vitro; while samples obtained from rats treated for six weeks showed a slowed chromatin elongation and dispersion pattern. Iodoacetamide binding revealed that there was about a 30% decrease in the amount of free sulfhydryls in spermatozoal nuclei from six weeks treated samples, while there was no detectable change in one week treated samples. DNA single strand breakage was detected in one week treated samples only in the presence of proteinase K in the lysis solution, while significant amounts of both DNA single strand breakage and DNA cross-links were detected in six weeks treated samples. Using a DNA synthesis in vitro system, it was found that six weeks treatment decreased spermatozoal template function, while one week treatment did not result in any significant difference in DNA template function when compared with the control. It is proposed that as the mele germ cells undergo the chromatin transition processes, the chromatin is in an open dynamic status, which expresses many vulnerable sites of the genome to aklylating agent. Since there is no DNA repair system, the alkylation of the genome is cumulative and causes severe damage to the germ cell nuclei; this would lead to early embryo death. Furthermore it is hypothesized that</description><creator>Qiu, Jianping, 1953-</creator><contributor>Robaire, Bernard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology.</subject><title>Effects of cyclophosphamide exposure of male rats on progeny outcome and site of action on male germ cell nuclei in the testis and epididymis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg35r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c013g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z030h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During long-term EEG monitoring of epileptic patients, seizure detection assists in selecting information important for diagnosis. We present a new generation of detection methods with self-adapting, more specifically patient-adapting, algorithms for two functions: (1) Reduction of false seizure detections (FSDs), thus increasing the sensitivity of detection. (2) Detection of seizure onset, thus providing a warning which is useful to patient and observers, allowing appropriate precautions and observations. The self-adapting algorithm for reducing FSDs utilizes FSDs from one baseline monitoring session as template patterns. In subsequent sessions, events having a pattern similar to any template pattern are eliminated from the detection. A unique "similarity" measure was used to reflect the relation between two muitichannel EEG patterns. An extensive test was done on twenty patients with 2600 hours of monitoring. Results show an average reduction in FSDs by 61% with a risk of missing seizures of 2.7%, comparing to the most commonly used method. The self-adapting algorithm for seizure onset detection assumes one seizure has been recorded and uses that seizure and one set of non-seizure EEG to train a patient-specific classifier. By using special features and a modified nearest-neighbor classifier, this algorithm reached an onset detection rate of 100% with an average delay of 9.6 seconds after onset. The average false alarm rate was only 0.21/hour, making it an acceptable warning device. This test was done on 17 patients with 77 seizures. In conclusion, our self-adapting algorithms make seizure detection more accurate and effective than was possible before. They are also efficient, practical and capable to work in real time.</description><creator>Qu, Hao</creator><contributor>Gotman, Jean (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Self-adapting algorithms for seizure detection during EEG monitoring</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v88p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z030h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b310d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several approaches to sample preconcentration combined with sample introduction by Direct Sample Insertion (DSI) into the Inductively Coupled Plasma (ICP) for ultra trace elemental analysis have been developed. A microcolumn based flow injection (FI) manifold was used with ICP Mass Spectrometry (MS) but performance was adversely affected by high and variable blank levels. Physical preconcentration by depositing the sample as an aerosol into an inductively heated graphite DSI probe yielded detection limit improvements of over two orders of magnitude for ICP Atomic Emission Spectrometry (AES). Instrumentation was developed to automate the aerosol deposition preconcentration process, and this apparatus was used in conjunction with ICP-MS. Several of the aerosol deposition, DSI, and ICP parameters that impact on the performance of the technique were studied. Detection limit improvements averaged two orders of magnitude, and analysis of a river water reference material for 10 elements gave good results even at the part per trillion (pg ml$ sp{-1}$) level. Investigations into direct analysis of the analyte-laden chelating resin by DSI-ICP-AES were carried out. It was clearly demonstrated that the determination of volatile elements was adversely affected by the effect of the pyrolysis products of the resin on the plasma excitation conditions.</description><creator>Rattray, V. Robin (Vaughn Robin)</creator><contributor>Salin, Eric (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><title>Sample preconcentration and analysis by direct sample insertion inductively coupled plasma spectrometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc16z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b310d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623f52s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Superparamagnetic cellulosics were prepared by the in situ synthesis of nanoscale ferrites. The internal reaction volume of cellulosic matrices served as compartments for the controlled precipitation of iron oxides, biomimicking magnetic bacteria such as Aquispirillum magnetotacticum. Nanocomposites were prepared from a range of materials, both ionic and nonionic. The ionics were sulfonated thermomechanical wood pulp (TMP), sodium carboxymethylcellulose (CMC), calcium alginate fibres and chemically modified rayon tirecord, in addition to a model synthetic system which consisted of a Nafion$ sp circler$ 117 ion-exchange membrane. Two never-dried, water-swollen, nonionic cellulose gels were also used as substrates for in situ synthesis: a bacterial cellulose membrane and a wet-spun model cellulose filament. Characterization of the resulting magnetic materials was performed using transmission electron microscopy (TEM), electron diffraction, vibrating sample magnetometry (VSM) and Mossbauer spectroscopy. The ionic substrates produced a non-uniform distribution of fine ferrites. However, the water-swollen, neutral cellulose gels yielded a uniform distribution of ferrites which, in turn, were used to propose a model for matrix-mediated synthesis of superparamagnetic cellulosics.</description><creator>Raymond, Louise M. (Louise Margaret)</creator><contributor>Marchessault, R. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Nanocomposite cellulosics prepared by the in situ synthesis of ferrites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r968p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f52s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nd02f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two natural soils from Bahrain were used in this study to investigate the feasibility of using Arabian oil residue as a means to stabilize collapsible saline soils. Since the presence of oil residue in soils can pose an environmental threat, the high oil retention capability of the stabilized soils is critical to its application. The behavior of the stabilized soils has been experimentally investigated in the laboratory. This study has concentrated on the evaluation of the mechanical properties of the stabilized soils, the oil retention characteristics and its bonding mechanisms, and the leaching and migration behaviors of oil residue from the stabilized soils. The geotechnical investigation results indicated that the addition of 4% oil residue, by weight, was sufficient to significantly enhance the strength performance of the tested soils. The geochemical tests showed that the bonds formed between the oil and the soil surfaces were predominantly Van der Waal's attraction, weak hydrogen bonding, and cation and water bridging. These bonds were found to be relatively weak but stable and insensitive to leaching forces. The geo-environmental results revealed good oil retention in these samples, with less than 3% of the oil residue by weight leached from the stabilized soils after 40 days of leaching in distilled water. The migration of oil from the stabilized soils has also been theoretically evaluated. The theoretical study utilizes the model developed by Yong et al. (1992) with a few modifications made to accommodate this particular situation. The model was solved using an explicit finite difference method, Powell's optimization technique, and experimental results. The predicted oil migration profiles were found to be slightly over-estimated as compared to the experimental profiles.</description><creator>Mohammed, Lamya F. (Lamya Faisal)</creator><contributor>Yong, R. N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Agriculture, Soil Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Petroleum.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><title>Assessment of saline soil stabilization via oil residue and its geo-environmental implications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c9437.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd02f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr1720205</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Peter Paul Rubens' creative genius, as expressed with consummate mastery in his paintings, is but one of the many elements that have compounded to establish his fame. He is also renowned as a man of immense erudition. Indeed, his reputation is such that it is taken for granted that his great learning informed all aspects of his art in a fundamental way. In accordance with this kind of thinking, current scholarship on Rubens accepts, as a matter of course, that the artist, whilst creating his painted works, followed the dictates of a colour theory, as we would know it today. In fact, on the basis of circumstantial evidence, it has been accepted that Rubens invented a colour theory that may be seen as innovative for his time. This thesis assesses the evidence which has led researchers to formulate such a conclusion. As a consequence, it investigates the circumstances of Rubens association with Francois de Aguilon during the final stages of the latter's publication of his book on optics, the Opticorum libri sex. ... As well, the artist's correspondence with his friend, Nicolas Fabri de Peiresc, which contains allusions to an autograph manuscript purported to contain Rubens' thoughts on colour, is re-examined. Indeed, this very correspondence reveals that Rubens did not consider himself particularly knowledgeable about the theoretical aspects colour. On the basis of a thorough review of these existing documents; an investigation into relevant biographical circumstances; and an examination of the artist's technique, it is here proposed that Rubens did not consciously apply theoretical principles to his craft, but rather, that any of the discernable elements of what is considered to be modern colour theory are in the paintings only because the demands of the painter's craft serendipitously parallel art historians' theoretical hindsight.</description><creator>Meyer, Rüdiger</creator><contributor>Glen, T. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Color in art</subject><subject>Rubens, Peter Paul, Sir, 1577-1640 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Peter Paul Rubens and colour theory : an assessment of the evidence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk742.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1720205</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s4348</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The formation of patterns of functionally appropriate chemical synapses is one of the key aspects of nervous system development. I have investigated the cellular interactions that culminate in the formation of an inhibitory synapse between the R and P neurons of the leech. These neurons may be isolated and maintained in culture, where they reform synaptic connections under easily manipulable conditions. An early event in the formation of this synapse is the loss from sites of contact in the postsynaptic P cell of an excitatory response to the transmitter serotonin. The loss of this response was triggered specifically by contact with the presynaptic R neuron, and not by contact with other leech neurons, including other serotonergic neurons. Furthermore, contact with the R neurons of the reproductive ganglia, which do not innervate P cells, was also ineffective in causing the loss of response. This highly specific cellular interaction was prevented by treatment of the R cell surface with the proteolytic enzyme trypsin or with the lectin wheat germ agglutinin (WGA), suggesting involvement of an R cell surface glycoprotein. WGA blocked not only the loss of the excitatory response, but also prevented the formation of the R-P synapse. An antibody library against the R cell generated using a novel phage-display system produced antibodies which bound to subsets of leech neurons, including the R neurons, but none of these was specific for the R cells. I conclude that an early event in the formation of the R-P synapse is the recognition by the P cell of its correct synaptic partner through an R cell-specific surface molecule.</description><creator>Merz, David C. (David Christian)</creator><contributor>Drapean, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Neurons -- Growth</subject><subject>Synapses</subject><subject>Leeches -- Physiology</subject><title>Synapse formation between identified leech neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b800n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s4348</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c249z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is devoted to the kinematic synthesis of parallel manipulators at large, special attention being given to three versions of a novel class of mainpulators, named double-triangular. These are conceived in planar, spherical and spatial double-triangular varieties. The treatment of planar and spherical manipulators needs only planar and spherical trigonometry, a fact that inductively leads to the successful treatment of spatial varieties with methods of spatial trigonometry, wherein the relationships are cast in the form of dual-number algebraic expressions. Using the foregoing tools, the direct kinematics of the three types of double-triangular manipulators is formulated and resolved. Moreover, a general three-group classification, to deal with singularities encountered in parallel manipulators, is proposed. The classification scheme relies on the properties of Jacobian matrices of parallel manipulators. It is shown that all singularities, within the workspaces of the manipulators of interest, are readily identified if their Jacobian matrices are formulated in an invariant form. Finally, the optimal design of the manipulators is studied. These designs minimize the roundoff-error amplification effects due to the numerical inversion of the underlying Jacobian matrices. Such designs are called isotropic. Based on this concept the multi-dimensional isotropic design continua of several manipulators are derived.</description><creator>Mohammadi Daniali, Hamid Reza</creator><contributor>Zsombor-Murray, Paul J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Contributions to the kinematic synthesis of parallel manipulators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v89z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c249z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79408013q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rh hemolytic disease of the newborn, once a major cause of perinatal mortality and long-term disability, is rarely seen in developed countries today. This drastic reduction in the frequency of disease occurrence has followed the widespread postpartum use of Rh immunoglobulin. However, more than half the world's population does not have access to this health care technology. The objective of this thesis was to study the epidemiology of Rh disease in developed country settings and specifically to quantify the magnitude of Rh disease reduction that occurred secondary to Rh prophylaxis, and to changes in birth order, the quality of medical care and other Rh disease determinants. Another objective was to identify feasible and cost-effective options for Rh disease control in developing countries. Study methods include Poisson regression modeling of surveillance data from Manitoba, Nova Scotia, Canada and the United States and a model based on conditional probabilities obtained from the medical literature and vital statistics publications. Outcomes considered in these analyses include maternal Rh sensitization, Rh hemolytic disease of the newborn, perinatal deaths from Rh disease and infant deaths from hemolytic disease of the newborn. The results show that besides Rh prophylaxis, changes in other determinants of Rh disease were responsible for significant reductions in the disease over the last four decades. Changes in the birth order resulted in a 35% reduction in Rh sensitizations, while changes in the quality of medical care were responsible for about 80% of the reduction in perinatal deaths from Rh disease. Rh prophylaxis was found to be responsible for reducing the rate of maternal Rh sensitization (both Rh D and Rh non-D) by 60-69% and the rate of perinatal and infant deaths by 80-90% (estimated effects are independent but not mutually exclusive). Effects of other Rh disease determinants, such as abortion rates, racial composition, race and Rh type-specific blood transfusions, were also quantified. Finally, a decision analysis of various Rh prophylaxis options was modeled with a view to optimizing cost-effectiveness and minimizing cost. The option of administering Rh prophylaxis to first births was found to be the most cost-effective and feasible option. It is recommended as a first step for Rh disease control in countries like India.</description><creator>Kuruthukulangare, Joseph Sebastian</creator><contributor>Kramer, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Prevention of Rh-hemolytic disease of the newborn : an evaluation of competing strategies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn67n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408013q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r038h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of turbulence in the process of collision and coalescence of small cloud droplets is still an outstanding problem in the area of cloud physics. In particular, the growth of droplets in the radius range for 10 to 15 $ mu$m is not well understood. The present research has been motivated by the curiosity whether or not turbulence affects the growth rate of such small drops. We developed a method to calculate collision rates of small hydrodynamically interacting drops embedded in an external flow field; we call it the flux method. Then, the method was tested for simple cases of laminar flows such as linear shear and a two-dimensional deformation field. The tests were designed not only to validate the method but also to examine the mechanisms associated with the simplified types of external flows which may be equally important for real turbulent flows. In order to obtain estimates of collision rates for turbulent flows, the flux method was used in conjunction with a probabilistic approach. Numerous simulations of trajectories of two hydrodynamically interacting droplets in a turbulent field were carried out. The ratio of the number of collisions to the total number of simulations gave the probability of collision for different relative positions of the drops. Because the Reynolds number of the flow around droplets (based on the drop radius and terminal velocity) is small, the trajectories were calculated with the help of a model based on the linear Stokes hydrodynamics. Turbulence was modelled in the form of random Fourier modes with both the space and the time spectrum prescribed. Both spectra were characterized by Kolmogorov scaling. The space spectrum was modelled in the inertial and dissipation subranges. On the basis of scale analysis, only small scale time variations were allowed, and, the so called Eulerian-Lagrangrian time spectrum was applied. The results show that most collision rates increase moderately in a turbulent flow characterized by a rate of energy dissipation of the order of 1, 10, and 100 cm$ sp2$ sec$ sp{-3}.$ The estimated increase in collision efficiencies, however, is not uniform, and a rather complicated relation between the increase in the collision efficiency and the parameters--the drop radii, and the rate of energy dissipation--can be observed.</description><creator>Koziol, Anna S. (Anna Sophia)</creator><contributor>Leighton, Henry G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>The effect of turbulence on the collision rates of small cloud drops</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r752n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r038h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t112g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Composite material tendons are considered in this thesis as interior ground support for underground excavations. The physical and mechanical properties of composite tendons critical to mining requirements were identified. Preliminary laboratory investigations were also undertaken to evaluate their performance as fully grouted reinforcing tendons. Arapree, a flexible tendon, and Weldgrip, a solid tendon, are the two patented composite tendons found to be superior in pull out testing. Their load carrying capacity and ductility in the elastic range is similar to that of existing steel supports, although their post peak performance is different. Rigid composite bolts have more load sustaining capacity than their steel counterparts, while flexible composite tendons have less capacity than conventional seven wire flexible steel cable. The shear capacity of fully grouted Weldgrip bolts was found to be in the range of 100 kN. As part of studies of flexible tendons, conventional steel cable was also used to investigate other parameters, since it was found to be identical in pull out behaviour to composite flexible cable. It was found that the effect of grout strength and modulus, radial confinement and host medium strength and stiffness is significant in controlling the performance of steel cable. The laboratory investigation also found that different grouting materials, such as conventional to high strength cement grout and polyester resin grout greatly influence the pull out performance of both steel and composite tendons.</description><creator>Khan, Umar</creator><contributor>Mitri, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hassani, F. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Laboratory investigation of the steel cables and composite material tendons for ground support</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67315875.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t112g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967565b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hypertension is associated with a reduction in sensitivity to pain in both animals and humans. Changes in nociception pre-date elevations in blood pressure in animals genetically predisposed to hypertension, and preliminary findings with male offspring of hypertensives indicate that genetic risk for hypertension is related to decreased pain sensitivity in humans. Sensitivity to naturalistic and laboratory pain stimuli was compared in normotensive females with and without a parental history of hypertension in three studies. Genetic risk for hypertension was associated with decreased sensitivity for blood donation venipuncture pain and electric shock, but not for menstrual pain or the cold pressor test. These findings provide modest support for the notion that hypoalgesia is present in females at risk for hypertension. Issues for future research include extension of these findings to other pain stimuli, use of multiple indices of risk, assessment of the effects of cyclic hormonal changes on the relationship between pain sensitivity and risk for hypertension, and further study of the mechanisms and pathophysiological implications of this effect.</description><creator>Krywiak, Janis L. (Janis Lori)</creator><contributor>Ditto, Blaine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Pain -- Susceptibility.</subject><subject>Hypertension -- Risk factors.</subject><subject>Women -- Physiology.</subject><title>Pain sensitivity in females at risk for hypertension</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f546n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967565b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r293p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sclerotinia sclerotiorum is a widespread plant pathogen that produces structures known as sclerotia. When sclerotia germinate they give rise to infective hyphae, myceliogenic germination, or they produce ascocarps, carpogenic germination. Biological control has usually targeted sclerotia or ascospores. The main objectives of the research presented herein were to observe the effect of a mycoparasite and fungus gnats (Bradysia coprophila) on the survival of sclerotia in vitro and in field conditions, and to study the enzymatic activity of the mycoparasite when in contact with sclerotia damaged by fungus gnats. In this research several mycoparasites were evaluated for their efficacy to degrade sclerotia in soil. From these tests, an isolate of Trichoderma hamatum, TMCS 3 proved to be the most effective. Larvae of fungus gnats have also been reported to feed on sclerotia. When both organisms were combined in laboratory tests, fewer sclerotia survived than when the organisms acted alone. Sclerotia recovered from this treatment contained fewer viable cells when compared to sclerotia recovered from treatments with TMCS 3 or fungus gnats alone. The results obtained from field trials showed that TMCS 3 was effective at degrading sclerotia. Unfortunately environmental conditions were not always optimal for the establishment of high populations of fungus gnats. Few larvae were observed feeding on sclerotia and no significant differences were found among treatments. Growth of TMCS 3 was studied using different carbon sources as substrates, including sclerotia of S. sclerotiorum. Biomass obtained from this latter treatment was significantly larger than on the other carbon sources tested. Enzymatic activity was also induced by the presence of sclerotia. In many cases, sclerotial exudates from mechanically damaged sclerotia or sclerotia damaged by larval feeding showed that the concentration of amino acids, carbohydrates, and electrolytes was increased as damage to the sclerotia has increased. Exudation of protein was not different when damaged and undamaged sclerotia were compared. Exudates from sclerotia with the melanized rind completely removed by fungus gnats feeding accelerated the germination of conidia of TMCS 3. These heavily damaged sclerotia also enhanced the growth of TMCS 3 when both organisms were grown together. However enzymatic (i.e. glucanase and chitinase) activity of TMCS 3 was not increased by the damage to the sclerotia. When damaged sclerotia were buried in soil infested with TMCS 3 they were degraded faster when the medulla of sclerotia was completely uncovered by larval feeding.</description><creator>Gracia, Javier</creator><contributor>Paulitz, T. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Trichoderma.</subject><subject>Sclerotinia sclerotiorum -- Biological control.</subject><subject>Mycetophilidae.</subject><title>Evaluation of fungus gnats (Bradysia coprophila) and Trichoderma spp. as biocontrol agents of the plant pathogen Sclerotinia sclerotiorum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr92n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r293p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397b17g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the context of the choice of treatment for end-stage renal disease, three approaches to utility assessment were examined to determine which captures prospective patients' values best. The standard gamble (SG), time tradeoff (TTO) and visual analogue scale (VAS) were compared for their test-retest reliability and convergent validity. The study population consisted of patients who attended nephrology clinics at one of three teaching hospitals in the city of Montreal. Sixty-six patients were interviewed three times by one of two interviewers. They were taught about the treatments using an information package developed expressly for the study and a video produced by a pharmaceutical company for use in this decision context. Utilities for treatment were measured on two occasions about one week apart. Patients differed widely in the utilities provided (responses ranged from 0 to 100) but mean utilities were similar across the treatments assessed. Because of the wide variation among subjects, the intraclass correlation coefficients for test-retest reliability were high to moderate: 0.87 for SG, 0.73 for TTO and 0.64 for VAS. However, the precision of the methods, as measured by the standard deviation of the measure from one occasion to the next within subjects, was low with SD's of 10 for SG, 14 for TTO and 13 for VAS assessments. The use of correlation coefficients as a measure of reliability and convergence in this context was challenged. SG and TTO utilities and SG and VAS utilities (when anchoring effects were controlled) were unbiased estimates of one another, but the degree of agreement between each pair was low. The VAS assessments produced higher values than the TTO assessments. Both SG and VAS were susceptible to strong anchoring effects; in other words, the utilities obtained were different when the best and worst outcomes used to anchor the ends of the scale were changed from full health and death to full health and the worst treatment. Subject characteristics and study factors were investigated for associations with reliability and with convergence and with the absolute level of utility. The standard gamble approach was strongly associated with many of the factors, while the time trade-off and the visual analogue utilities were associated with fewer. The poor reliability of the methods raises questions about their use in decision aids for individuals. The lack of agreement among the methods indicates that the methods cannot be used interchangeably.</description><creator>Groome, Patti A.</creator><contributor>Hutchinson, Tom A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Measuring prospective-patients' values for treatments for end-stage renal disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f233.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b17g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g209r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The proximal promoter of the rat carbamyl phosphate synthetase I gene contains 4 cis-acting regulatory regions, designated sites GAC, I, II, and III. Transient transfection assays revealed that the GAG element functions as the main activator element, whereas sites I and III bind repressor proteins and site II binds an anti-repressor. We propose that sites I and III repress the CPS I promoter either by quenching the sole activator(s) bound to the GAG element, or by directly repressing the basal transcription apparatus. Footprint analyses of the promoter with and without a mutation within site II suggested that the site II-anti-repressor may interfere with the site I and site III repressors by a similar quenching mechanism. Although the elements within the proximal promoter exhibit the potential for complex regulation, they are unable to confer tissue-specific promoter activity when analyzed either by in vitro transcription employing nuclear extracts from tissues that do not express the endogenous gene (i.e. brain, kidney, and spleen), or by transient transfection assays in non-CPS I-expressing cells (i.e. Rat1 and C6). However, we identified a cell-type specific enhancer that lies 10 kb upstream of the promoter. Unexpectedly, the enhancer functions as well in a gene-specific manner because enhancer-stimulated promoter activity was exclusively dependent on the GAG element within the CPS I proximal promoter. As a result, the GAG element is required to couple enhancer activity to the proximal promoter and exemplifies an efficient method whereby enhancers can be constrained to activate only their cognate promoters.</description><creator>Goping, Ing Swie</creator><contributor>Shore, Gordon C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Mechanisms of transcriptional regulation for the rat carbamyl phosphate synthetase I gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv73h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g209r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39000</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>