<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:29:14Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34975" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s642s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) is common and fatal X-linked genetic disorder. The overall objective of this thesis was to carry out a prospective study for dystrophin gene therapy in dystrophic muscles, using the X-linked muscular dystrophy (mdx) mouse model. Recombinant adenovirus (AdV) is presently the vehicle of choice for gene therapy for a number of diseases including DMD. However AdV possess two major limitations when utilized as vectors in skeletal muscles: (i) the maturation-dependency of AdV-infectivity in skeletal muscles, (ii) the host immune response against adenoviral proteins as well as the transgene product. Thus, the work presented in this thesis addresses these two major limiting factors. By modifying either the host or the vectors, we have attempted to optimize AdV-mediated therapeutic gene transfer in dystrophic muscle. Our strategy has consisted firstly to evaluate the regenerative response of dystrophic muscle with advanced disease after experimentally-induced regeneration, in an attempt to recapitulate the myogenic program. We report that mdx mice with severe dystrophic pathology can still show a substantial level of muscle repair with attendant generation of immature myofibers. Secondly, by taking advantage of this level of regeneration and the concomitant generation of immature myofibers, we have upregulated expression of the coxsackie adenovirus receptor (CAR) present in mdx muscles. We have delivered AdV containing a dystrophin gene (AdV-Dys) at a period corresponding to this peak level of CAR expression and we have reported a significant increase of the number of dystrophin expressing myofibers with a net trend toward muscle function amelioration. The work of this thesis also reports that the combined blockade of calcineurin and CD28 signaling, two key and distinct elements needed for an effective immune response, effectively blunted the immune-mediated destruction of dystrophin expressing myofibers expressed after AdV-Dys delivery. As an alternative to host modification (regeneration and immunosuppression) that can be associated with potential toxic effects, we have explored a strategy where by the recombinant AdV vector contains a less immunogenic transgene utrophin. We report that overexpression of utrophin and dystrophin by AdV-mediated gene transfer in adult immunocompetent mdx mice produces differential effects on muscle cell function in adult immunocompetent (mdx) mice. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Guibinga, Ghiabe H.</creator><contributor>Petrof, B. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Molecular therapeutic interventioan for dystrophin-deficient muscles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v7115.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s642s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t68b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Researchers have found that children with behaviour disorders inflate their self-perceptions (e.g., Hughes, Cavell, &amp; Grossman, 1997). This study investigated the self-perceptions of depressed and nondepressed children with behavioural difficulties relative to significant others' perceptions (i.e., parents, teachers, and behaviour aides) with reference to Cole's (1990; 1991a, 1991b) interpersonal feedback theory. Cole's theory argues that what children believe about themselves results from their perception and internalization of others' judgments. This study involved a quantitative phase and a qualitative phase of data collection conducted one year apart. The quantitative phase consisted of evaluating the congruence in children's (mean age = 10.9 years) and others' (parents, teachers, and behaviour aides) perceptions in depressed and nondepressed children with behavioural difficulties. Perceptions were of the children's general behavioural conduct, problem behaviour, mood, and the raters' general satisfaction with the children. The following measures were used: the Children's Depression Inventory (Kovacs, 1992), a modified Self Perception Profile for Children (Harter, 1985), and the Child Behaviour Interview (Grinberg, 1997). Parallel forms were used with the parents, teachers, and behaviour aides. In addition, the Direct Observation Form-Revised Edition (Achenbach, 1986) was used to assess actual behaviour. Results suggest that children with behavioural difficulties inflate their competencies. Further, the other raters' perceptions did not differ for the depressed and nondepressed groups. The depressed children rated their competence in behavioural conduct to be significantly lower than the nondepressed children with behavioural difficulties. Also, differences across raters' perceptions were found for the nondepressed group but not the depressed group. Five children from the original sample and their behaviour aides were interviewed for the qualitative study. Qu</description><creator>Grinberg, Daisy I.</creator><contributor>Heath, N. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Self-perception in children.</subject><subject>Behavior disorders in children.</subject><subject>Depression in children.</subject><title>Perceptions of depressed and nondepressed children with behavioural difficulties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng34w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t68b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s1800</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This cross-cultural inquiry focuses on the involvement of mothers in their children's education and the ways in which motherhood impacts the personal identities of mothers. The Second-wave feminism started thirty years ago and questioned the role and position of mothers in society. The objective of this movement was to free women from the exclusive responsibility of childcare. However, three decades later women are still the primary caregivers for their children. The study involves 36 middle-class mothers, 12 each from Canada, India and Mexico. Irrespective of their cultural backgrounds, these mothers participated actively in the domestic work related to childcare and in their children's schoolwork. Participants in this study expressed their views about intensive mothering and how they sought their personal identities from the work of mothering. The majority regarded motherhood as a unique and rewarding role, and wished to continue mothering despite the frustrations and stresses they experienced. The findings concerning the childcare strategies of mothers from Canada, India and Mexico highlight some cultural differences. These cultural differences also had an impact on how these mothers perceived their roles and identities.</description><creator>Gupta, Meenakshi, 1970-</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Women -- Mexico -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Women -- India -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Mother and child -- Cross-cultural studies</subject><subject>Women -- Canada -- Social conditions</subject><title>Mothers' involvement in their children's education : a comparative study of mothers from Canada, India and Mexico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462716x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s1800</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx44z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The research field of this thesis is framed by the major political and legal women's movement campaigns from the 1840s to the 1870s: the debates over the Married Women's Property Act; over philanthropy and methods of addressing social ills; the campaign for professional opportunities for women, and the arguments surrounding women's suffrage. I address how these issues are considered and contextualised in major works of Victorian fiction: Anne Bronte's The Tenant of Wildfell Hall (1848), Elizabeth Gaskell's North and South (1855), Charlotte Bronte's Villette (1853), and George Eliot's Middlemarch (1871--2). In works of fiction by women, concepts of social justice were not constrained by layers of legal abstraction and the obligatory political vocabulary of "disinterest." Contemporary fiction by women could thus offer some of the most developed articulations of women's changing expectations. This thesis demonstrates that the Victorian novel provides a distinct synthesis of, and contribution to, arguments grouped under the rubric of the "woman question." The novel offers a perspective on feminist politics in which conflicting social interests and demands can be played out, where ethical questions meet everyday life, and human relations have philosophical weight. Given women's traditional exclusion from the domain of legitimate (authoritative) speech, the novels of Gaskell, the Bronte's, and Eliot, traditionally admired for their portrayal of moral character, play a special role in giving voice to the key political issues of women's rights, entitlements, and interests. Evidence for the political content and efficacy of these novels is drawn from archival sources which have been little used in literary studies (including unpublished materials), as well as contemporary periodicals. Central among these is the English Woman's Journal. Conceived as the mouthpiece of the early women's movement, the journal offers a valuable record of the feminist activity of the period. Though it has not been widely exploited, particularly in literary studies, detailed study of the journal reveals close parallels between the ideological commitments and concerns of the women's movement and novels by mid-Victorian women.</description><creator>Dredge, Sarah.</creator><contributor>Wihl, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>English literature -- 19th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Feminism -- Great Britain -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Women novelists, English.</subject><title>Accommodating feminism : Victorian fiction and the nineteenth-century women's movement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn407.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx44z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h3480</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines Christian experientialist epistemology as articulated of late by Alvin Plantinga especially and also William Alston. It situates their approach to the epistemic status of Christian belief claims within the overall outlook they have respectively developed on what features generally legitimate beliefs as being rationally responsible or even qualify some true beliefs as constituting knowledge. First to be taken up is Plantinga's journey from considering the deontological justification for basic belief in God to making his own externalist proposal for warranted belief at large. Next up for consideration is Alston's accent on adequate grounds and reliable process, attending as well to his stance on perceptual immediacy and belief-forming or doxastic practices in general. The study then looks at his case for Christian mystical practice as a dependable perceptual doxastic habit. Also treated is Alston's support for the process of forming Christian beliefs on testimony and his contention that these practices are realist and partly amenable to evaluation drawing on standards used also outside them. Then comes extended analysis of Plantinga's recent lengthy claim that, courtesy of special divine provisions, core Christian convictions can enjoy warrant even in the face of frequently alleged defeaters. While Alston's reliabilist epistemology is not as strong as Plantinga's package on appropriate proper function, his appreciation for the communal contribution to second-level knowledge is an important supplement. He offers more perspective on the status of Christian belief overall. Plantinga's model suffers from some internal tensions which admit better resolution than he has yet supplied. His response to religious pluralism is a solid one within his framework. Like Alston, Plantinga unabashedly appeals to theology to indicate doxastic propriety, but could do so in a way more sensitive to hermeneutical challenges. Yet Plantinga's and Alston's realism is an attempt to honor the distance between God's knowledge and that of believers.</description><creator>Dyck, Timothy Lee.</creator><contributor>Boutin, Maurice (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Plantinga, Alvin.</subject><subject>Experience (Religion)</subject><subject>Alston, William P.</subject><subject>Knowledge, Theory of (Religion)</subject><title>Experientialist epistemology : Plantinga and Alston on Christian knowledge</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq19c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h3480</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp664</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis provides a general framework for the manual teleoperation of kinematically redundant space-based manipulators. It is proposed to break down the task of controlling the motion of a redundant manipulator into a sequence of manageable sub-tasks of lower dimension by imposing constraints on the motion of intermediate bodies of the manipulator. This implies that the manipulator then becomes a non-redundant kinematic chain and the operator only controls a reduced number of degrees of freedom at any time. However, by appropriately changing the imposed constraints, the operator can use the full capability of the manipulator throughout the task. Also, by not restricting the point of teleoperation to the end effector but effectively allowing direct control of intermediate bodies of the robot, it is possible to teleoperate a redundant robot of arbitrary kinematic architecture over its entire configuration space in a predictable and natural fashion. It is rigourously proven that this approach will always work for any kinematically redundant serial manipulator regardless of its topology, geometry and of the number of its excess degrees-of-freedom. Furthermore, a methodology is provided for the selection of task and constraint coordinates to ensure the absence of algorithmic rank-deficiencies. Two novel algorithms are provided for the symbolic determination of the rank-deficiency locus of rectangular Jacobian matrices: the Singular Vector Algorithm and the Recursive Sub-Determinant Algorithm. These algorithms are complementary to each other: the former being more computationally efficient and the latter more robust. The application of the methodology to sample cases of varying complexity has demonstrated its power and limitations: It has been shown to be powerful enough to generate complete sets of task/constraint coordinate pairs for realistic examples such as the Space Station Remote Manipulator System and a simplified version of the Special Purpose Dexterous Manipulator.</description><creator>Dupuis, Erick.</creator><contributor>Hayward, Vincent (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Papadopoulos, Evangelos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>A general framework for the manual teleoperation of kinematically redundant space-based manipulators /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df239.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp664</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237ht44r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation studies the origin of new organisational forms. It focuses on organisations that challenge existing institutional boundaries, specifically the boundaries between for profit and not for profit providers of financial services. It builds on research on the origins of the microfinance industry in Bolivia; and particularly on the creation and development of BancoSol and Los Andes, the two pioneering organisations. This research involved in-depth interviews and analysis of industry-specific documents and newspaper files. The study builds on three research streams: collective strategy, institutional theory, and evolutionary entrepreneurship. It proposes an overarching process-model that bridges these three bodies of work and advances our understanding of three key dynamics in the creation of new organisational forms: (1) the combination of hitherto unconnected principles and practices; (2) the leverage of support and acceptance for new organisational forms; and (3) the development of endurance for the new form. The study argues that these three dynamics occur within a nonlinear process that includes three overlying stages. The first stage involves the creation of an entrepreneurial team to launch the organisations. This team includes individuals from fields with divergent principles and practices (e.g. for profit and not for profit). The second stage involves negotiations with institutional actors to leverage support and acceptance for the novel organisational form. The third stage involves decisions, actions, and interactions that promote internal coalescence and defend the organisations from external challenges. I have labeled this process-model social entrepreneurship. The process is predominantly social as the three dynamics are defined by the social assets and relations of actors. It is predominantly entrepreneurial as it destroys existing boundaries across fields and generates an enduring combination of principles and practices previously unconnected.</description><creator>Dorado-Banacloche, Silvia.</creator><contributor>Westley, Frances (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Bolivia -- Economic conditions -- 1982-</subject><subject>Microfinance -- Bolivia.</subject><title>Social entrepreneurship : the process of creation of microfinance organisations in Bolivia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc35n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht44r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r03f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research investigated the impact of "embedded teaching" and "learner-controlled" instruction on student learning of algebra in a controlled computer-tutoring environment. Three versions of a computer tutor were developed to establish three experimental conditions. Condition 1 corresponds to a conventional "lecture-demonstration-practice" in which conceptual knowledge is presented by the computer tutor as a coherent entity prior to engagement in problem-solving activities (Lecture-Demonstration-Practice). Condition 2 reflects "embedded teaching" in which before students begin practice, the computer tutor uses examples to demonstrate problem-solving processes, introducing concepts and principles, as they become relevant (Embedded-Teaching Condition). Condition 3 is a "learner-controlled" instruction in which students engage directly in problem-solving activities without receiving any prior formal instruction, but in which they are provided with instructional assistance and demonstrations upon request (Learner-Controlled Instruction). Twenty-seven high-school students participated in the experiment over a 1-month period. Students were divided into three groups based on their pre-test scores, each group was then assigned randomly to one of the three experimental conditions. The computer tutor was used as the sole source of instruction. Pre- and posttests were administered to measure the changes in students' algebraic abilities. A multivariate analysis of the pre- and posttest results indicates that overall student performance in all three conditions improved significantly over time, as measured by the ability to construct algebraic representations and the ability to made estimates using the various representations ( F (2, 23) = 46.6, p &lt; 0.01). In particular, students in Lecture-Demonstration-Practice Condition demonstrated a higher level of accuracy (89.51%) than students in the Embedded-Teaching and Learner-Controlled Instruction did (61.1% and 63.3% respectively). Moreover, all students in Lecture-Demonstration-Practice Condition completed the posttest successfully, whereas only 56% of students in the other two conditions passed the posttest. This research demonstrates that students learn more effectively from instruction that emphasizes the coherent representations of the symbol system of algebra. It is postulated that such coherent representations enable students to make sense of the subsequent examples to be studied and the problems to be solved thus leading to better problem-solving performance. This research has implications for the development of instructional theories and educational computer applications.</description><creator>Chen, Mei, 1962-</creator><contributor>Frederiksen, Carl (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Breuleux, Alain (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Education -- Data processing.</subject><subject>Algebra -- Study and teaching (Secondary) -- Data processing.</subject><title>The impact of three instructional modes of computer tutoring on student learning in algebra /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s22n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r03f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107083t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Exposure to methyl mercury (MeHg) is a global concern. Increased chronic exposure to MeHg among fish and marine mammal consuming populations will increase the risk of prenatal exposure and as a result, the risk of infant brain damage and neurotoxcity. It is therefore important to understand the role of environmental factors, such as nutrition, in determining susceptibility to MeHg toxicity. Three nutrients (selenium (Se), vitamin C and vitamin E) were selected for examination of their interactions with the mechanisms of McHg cytotoxicity in vitro. Two hybrid neural cell lines (M03.13 and NSC-34) were evaluated for their usefulness in the study of MeHg cytotoxicity. Sixteen toxic endpoints were selected for investigation of growth, viability, structure and biochemistry. Both cell lines responded to MeHg exposure in a dose dependent manner for the majority of endpoints suggesting that both MO3.13 and NSC-34 cells undergo structural and biochemical changes during exposure to McHg, but that MO3.13 cells are more sensitive to DNA, mitochondria) membrane damage and glutathione (GSH) depletion and that NSC-34 cells are more sensitive to protein damage and apoptosis. Se exposure lessened the MeHg-induced decrease in DNA and GSH concentrations in both cell lines. In NSC-34 cells, Se also increased F-actin concentrations and prevented an increase in caspase-3 activity. Se may alter the mechanism of cell death by preventing McHg disruption of DNA replication thus maintaining the production and function of peptides (GSH) and protein (polymerized actin) that aid in MeHg detoxification and neural function. In NSC-34 cells, vitamin C prevented the induction of caspase-3 activity and lessened DNA damage and GSH depletion. Vitamin E lessened GSH depletion and lessened G-actin depletion. Both vitamin C and E improved GSH status, but vitamin C also delayed McHg damage of DNA and prevented early signs of apoptosis suggesting these two vitamins interfere with MeHg metabolism by diffe</description><creator>Chapman, Laurie A.</creator><contributor>Chan, H. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Neurotoxicology.</subject><subject>Vitamin C -- Health aspects.</subject><subject>Methylmercury -- Toxicology.</subject><subject>Toxicity testing -- In vitro.</subject><subject>Selenium in human nutrition.</subject><subject>Vitamin E -- Health aspects.</subject><title>Interactions of nutrients on methyl mercury toxicity in neuron X spinal chord hybrid cells (NSC-34) and human oligodendrocyte X rhabdomyosarcoma cells (MO3.13)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v023b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107083t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707959394</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gap junctional intercellular communication (GJIC) allows for the transport of small signaling molecules between adjacent cells. Gap junctions and their constituents, connexins, are often impaired in cancer. Restoration of connexins and GJIC in cancer cells leads to reversal of the transformed phenotype, reduction of the rate of cell growth, and inhibition of in vivo tumorigenicity. In addition, restoration of connexin43 (Cx43), one of the most abundant connexins that is often reduced in cancer, allows for the transfer of chemotherapeutic agents among neighboring cells, a phenomenon known as the "Bystander Effect". In chapter 2, I'm reporting evidence that induction of Cx43 and GJIC with cyclic-AMP (cAMP) can enhance the cytotoxic effect of the prodrug ganciclovir following infection of breast cancer cells with an adenovirus expressing the ganciclovir-activating enzyme viral thymidine kinase (vTK). This induction may provide a therapeutic advantage in suicide gene therapy due to the bystander effect when a small proportion of the cell population is expressing vTK. In chapter 3, I'm reporting that breast tumor tissue samples from patients had low to undetectable Cx43 levels, in contrast to their matched normal tissues. In addition, Cx43 protein and RNA levels were undetectable in a panel of human breast cancer lines and in rat breast tumors induced by the carcinogen dimethylbenz[a]anthracene. Together, these observations indicate that the loss of Cx43 is a common marker of cancer cells. In chapter 4, I examined the hypothesis that Cx43 downregulation occurs primarily at the transcriptional level. To determine the mechanisms behind the transcriptional regulation of Cx43, the human Cx43 promoter was investigated. Overexpression of the H-Ras oncogene in NIH3T3 cells leads to the induction of the human Cx43 promoter activity, as well as Cx43 RNA and protein levels. This stimulation involves the MEK-ERK pathway downstream of H-Ras. The promoter sequence responsible for</description><creator>Carystinos, George D.</creator><contributor>Batist, Gerald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Molecular studies on the therapeutic implications and regulation of connexin 43</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397986p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707959394</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr31s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Luminescence is a secondary metabolic process that can be detected and assayed in a non-disruptive, in vivo, and real-time manner. As such the Vibrio harveyi luminescence (lux) system constitutes a model system that can be used to delineate the relatively complex transcriptional control mechanisms that are inherent to secondary metabolic processes. Molecular insights into the control of luminescence induction in V. harveyi is limited to the two-component quorum-sensing system and LuxR. While the quorum-sensing system is thought to facilitate luminescence induction through a mechanism of derepression, LuxR has been shown to be an essential activator of the process by virtue of the absence of luminescence in a luxR null mutant. Additionally, it has been suggested that LuxR activates its own expression. Data presented here demonstrates that LuxR is involved in autorepression. Moreover, it is argued that LuxR may not be a typical activator in that it may mediate activation of lux gene expression through a mechanism of repression. An implication of this proposal is that a second unidentified activator is required for luminescence induction to occur. The search of candidates to fill this proposed activation role focused on two highly conserved and extensively studied activators, MetR and CRP. Both are involved in nutrient dependent pathways as MetR is an activator of methionine biosynthesis genes and CRP is implicated in the regulation of metabolic pathways in response to the presence of preferred carbohydrates. In the specific case of the V. harveyi lux system, MetR is shown to act as a repressor, while CRP is shown to be a critical activator of luminescence induction. The evolutionary and ecological implications of these findings are discussed.</description><creator>Chatterjee, Jaidip.</creator><contributor>Meighen, Edward A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The luminescence induction point of Vibrio harveyi is an integration of multiple regulatory controls : LuxR, MetR, and CRP</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg59v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr31s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b055</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A melt extraction process with a new approach to making ceramic fibers was used to produce amorphous fibers in the Y2O3-Al 2O3 system within the 20--30 micron size range. Three different compositions were studied, E1, Y3A5 and E2 with 79, 62.5 and 57.5 mol% Al2O3, respectively. Such fibers were X-ray amorphous and transparent, regardless of composition in the as-produced state, and showed all the principal characteristics of the fibers made by this process: a cross section which is almost circular, a line of contact with the wheel and a clean and defect-free surface. However, the quality of the fibers was controlled by the wheel edge and rotational speed, with both having a significant effect on fiber diameter and avoidance of irregularities and instabilities along the fiber length. Moreover, compositional distribution analysis showed that the melt-extracted fibers were chemically homogeneous between the core and the edge of the fiber and, in addition, were very close to theoretical stoichiometry. Thermal analysis was performed in order to determine the glass transition, crystallization and phase transformation temperatures. E1 fibers showed two exothermic peaks at 949 and 1040째C that correspond to the crystallization of YAG and delta-Al2O3 phases, respectively, and one small exothermic peak at 1300째C due to the phase transformation of delta-Al 2O3 to alpha-Al2O3. In the case of Y3A5 and E2 fibers, both showed one single exothermic peak at 942 and 939째C due to the crystallization of YAG and YAP cubic phases, respectively. YAP orthorhombic and YAG phases appeared in E2 fibers after heat-treating at 1400째C for 1h with no identifiable exothermic peak in the DTA scan. Differential thermal analysis was used to study the crystallization phenomena in the as-extracted fibers. The activation energy values were calculated using both Kissinger and Augis-Bennett equations by measuring the variation of the peak temperature in the differential thermal scans with heating rate, and the crystallization mode was identified using the Ozawa analysis. After crystallization, there was a conversion of the transparent glass fiber to an opaque polycrystalline material and both E1 and Y3A5 fibers had a nanocrystalline microstructure with a grain size typically of 100--500 nm. In the case of E2, the grain size was 1--2 mum. Tensile strengths and elastic moduli of the fibers in the glassy state varied from 606 to 776 MPa and from 95 to 121 GPa, respectively. Furthermore, fibers exhibited brittle fracture initiated from flaws on the fibers surface.</description><creator>Aguilar Reyes, Ena Athenea.</creator><contributor>Drew, Robin A. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Preparation and characterization of rapid solidified yttria-alumina fibers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk84s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b055</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n286h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this study is to present the empirical results of a design experiment that validates the Integrated Learning Model (ILM). The study also explores the contribution of multiple Web-tools that facilitate specific learning outcomes. Using a multiple paradigmatic approach that blends the best of both cognitive and situative perspectives in an open-learning constructivist environment, three broad constructs were used to identify variables that influence learning. These constructs include (1) knowledge acquisition strategies ; (2) cognitive tools that support practice and (3) assessment components that capture artifacts of learning. In addition, the ILM uses expertise, pedagogical content knowledge and self-regulation as principles that anchor instructional designs. While these principles have traditionally been operationalized separately in classroom settings, they have not been implemented simultaneously to constitute the core elements of an open-learning model. The ILM represents such a synthesis. Data were collected from 338 students using various tools online, as well as from four surveys administered throughout the semester. Sixty percent of the participants were male with an average age of 21 years. They spent approximately six hours per week on the course. Print material, interactive practice tests and online information were the most frequently used tools. Other tools such as videos and communication software were also positively rated. The majority preferred a mixture of discovery learning and guided instruction. From the fifteen online items, three extracted factors explained 69% of the total variance and loadings were above the 0.7 threshold. These factors correspond to the three broad constructs identified above. Given these dimensions and the latent construct (learning), Structural Equation Modeling techniques were applied to confirm the ILM. The ELM is introduced to encourage designers of Web-based instruction to engineer appropriate knowledge acquisition strategies and to practice opportunities and appropriate assessment methods that are theoretically driven and constructively aligned in an open learning environment. Such Web-designs open new doors to faculty, administrators, employers, and learners. They help to explain why participants learn meaningfully and what might enable them to create knowledge.</description><creator>Ahmad, Arshad.</creator><contributor>Lajoie, Susanne P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Distance education.</subject><subject>Learning.</subject><title>Validating a theory-based design for online instruction : the integrated learning model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh20d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n286h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wr98h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study is a comparative analysis of the development of two networks of nongovernmental organizations (NGOs) in the Mexican states of Oaxaca and Jalisco and their contribution to the strengthening of the political capacities of NGOs. A new view of civil society is introduced that emphasizes its multiple functions and forms the basis for disaggregating capacity into three dimensions: defensive, propositional and infrastructural. A political process approach draws from social movement theory for understanding the emergence and activities of NGO networks. The development of NGOs in Mexico from the 1960s through the 1990s is analyzed as the result of mobilization in response to political opportunities arising from transformations to the political and social policy regimes of the Mexican state. The study compares the national pattern with the experience of two regional NGO networks: Foro de Organismos Civiles de Oaxaca (FOCO) and Foro de Organismos Civiles de Jalisco (FOCIV). Each network emerged in response to state-level defensive and propositional opportunities. Comparative historical case studies and a latitudinal analysis of linkage development reveal the contribution of these two networks to capacity-building. Increased communication between member organizations was an positive result of the network activities. However, neither network strengthened linkages of NGOs with popular movements, political parties, or the state. The study confirms earlier research findings that these types of networks contribute to the development of pluralism in civil society, but reveals the defence of NGO autonomy to be a barrier to greater linkage development. The focus on autonomy can distance NGOs from other important political actors and their struggles, hinder coordination with other actors, and thus reduce the political effectiveness of the networks. The two cases also illustrate the important role of third-order NGOs to the development of the sector as a whole, and suggest that linkages tend to be stronger in networks where third-order NGOs promote network development.</description><creator>Ainsworth, David, 1968-</creator><contributor>Oxhorn, Philip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Mexico -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Democracy -- Mexico.</subject><subject>Non-governmental organizations -- Mexico.</subject><subject>Mexico -- Social conditions.</subject><title>Capacity building in civil society : NGO networks in the regions of Mexico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t48x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr98h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214q803</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation deals with Ibn Taymiyya's theory of the unity of God and of creation, or, as Muslim philosophers have posited the question, the relation between the oneness of God and the diversity that has come out of it. Indeed, Ibn Taymiyya (d. 728/1328) responded to the same ontological question that earlier Muslim philosophers were concerned to answer. Although Ibn Taymiyya was a theologian, he did not encounter quite the same questions as the early kalam theologian whose concern it was to prove the existence of God. The dissertation discusses the forms this question took. The introduction reviews Ibn Taymiyya's life, works and historical circumstances. The first chapter deals with Ibn Taymiyya's concept of God which is that of a real and actual being. God, for him, is not abstract in the way some Muslim theologians, philosophers and mystics had affirmed. The second chapter discusses two great Muslim thinkers: al-Ghazali, who attempted to reconcile kalam with Ibn Sina's philosophy, and Ibn Rushd, who criticized both al-Ghazali and Ibn Sina and established a new philosophical approach to the notion of God and the process of creation. In this chapter we touch on the later development of both kalam and philosophy in Islam and show how Ibn Taymiyya, while pursuing the same goal as al-Ghazali in reconciling kalam and philosophy, drew benefit from these developments. The third chapter goes to the core of Ibn Taymiyya's theory of diversity issuing from the oneness of God. This chapter shows the bold notions that Ibn Taymiyya believed represent the only possible answers to the question of creation: the essence of God as a substrate of generation; the eternity of the world; and God's attributes as species and genera, actualized in our concrete world. The conclusion illustrates the differences between Ibn Taymiyya and other Muslim philosophers and theologians, as well as his adoption of certain of their ideas.</description><creator>Ajhar, 軻Abd al-搔ak카m.</creator><contributor>Ormsby, Eric (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Ibn Taym카yah, A搔mad ibn 軻Abd al-搔al카m, 1263-1328.</subject><subject>Philosophy, Islamic.</subject><subject>God (Islam)</subject><title>The metaphysics of the idea of God in ibn Taymiyya's thought /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365690r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q803</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td821</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This manuscript-based thesis explores the relationship between learning and development. The first manuscript reviews the important empirical regularities identified in human discrimination shift learning, including a qualitative age-related change in performance observed in childhood. Leading theoretical accounts of the empirical data are discussed, suggesting that none provides a comprehensive interpretation. The manuscript presents the novel, spontaneous overtraining interpretation. It hypothesizes that age-related changes in human shift learning stem from differences in amount of processing. Successful neural network simulations of the reversal and nonreversal shift tasks and of the optional shift task are reported as tests of the hypothesis. The second manuscript reports simulations of additional discrimination shift tasks. These are the intradimensional and extradimensional shift tasks, in which novel stimuli are introduced in the relearning phase. Preschoolers and adults exhibit the same pattern of behavior in this variant of shift learning. Simulation results show that the spontaneous overtraining hypothesis captures this effect. The third chapter reports an empirical validation of the shift learning model. If the shift learning performance of adults is a consequence of more extensive processing, it follows that adults in whom such processing is prevented should perform as preschoolers. Sixty adults took part in a shift learning experiment with a Brown-Peterson task as a cognitive load. Results mirror those observed with preschoolers. As a control, 40 adults performed the shift learning experiment without the cognitive load. These results replicate the typical adult performance. Overall, these experiments lend additional support to the model developed in Manuscript 1. The final manuscript is a theoretical discussion of the relationship between learning and development. Two classes of neural networks are discussed, and their underlying assumptions about learning and development are highlighted. These are static architecture and generative architecture networks. It is argued that only generative algorithms, such as used in the shift learning simulations, qualify as developmental models. Both classes of networks are further contrasted with respect to innateness. The comparison suggests that only generative networks can acquire genuinely new representations. The manuscript proposes a novel formulation of Piaget's constructivism from the generative neural network perspective.</description><creator>Sirois, Sylvain.</creator><contributor>Shultz, Thomas R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Innateness hypothesis (Linguistics)</subject><subject>Cognition.</subject><subject>Psycholinguistics.</subject><subject>Neural networks (Neurobiology)</subject><title>A neural network perspective on learning and development /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dh46s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td821</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bz931</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The application of Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy in the assessment of oil quality and stability and the determination of the degree and type (cis or trans) of unsaturation of fats and oils was investigated. FTIR spectroscopy was shown to provide a rapid means of monitoring changes in oils undergoing oxidation or subjected to thermal stress. Absorption bands associated with common primary and secondary oxidation products were identified by relating them to those of spectroscopically representative reference compounds, and a quantitative approach based on the use of oils spiked with these reference compounds as calibration standards was proposed. A sample-handling accessory based on a heated 25-mum transmission flow cell and heated input and output lines was developed to facilitate the rapid analysis of oils and premelted fats in their neat form. Using this system, an FTIR edible oil analysis package was developed to simultaneously analyze for trans content, cis content, iodine value (IV), and saponification number (SN) of neat fats and oils, using partial-least-squares (PLS) calibrations based on pure triglycerides. An automated transmission-based peak height method for isolated trans isomer determination using the characteristic trans absorption band at 967 cm -1 in the spectrum of a neat fat or oil, ratioed against the spectrum of a trans-free oil, was also developed. A subsequent validation study involving the analysis of more than 100 oil samples demonstrated concurrence between the trans data obtained by the PLS and peak height FTIR methods as well as between IV results obtained by FTIR analysis and gas chromatography. In addition, the internal consistency of the IV, cis, and trans FTIR predictions provided strong experimental evidence that the FTIR edible oil analysis package measures all three parameters accurately. A PLS-based IV/trans method was developed for a heated single-bounce horizontal attenuated total reflectance (SB-HATR) sample-</description><creator>Sedman, Jacqueline.</creator><contributor>van de Voort, F. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Oils and fats, Edible.</subject><title>Application of Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy in the analysis of edible fats and oil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp68p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bz931</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kp77w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During embryogenesis, patterning is one of the key processes by which the body plan of the embryo becomes established. Patterning of the A-P axis is accomplished by the products of the Hox gene family. In mammals, there are 39 genes in the Hox family that have been grouped into four clusters (A-D) by virtue of their chromosome location. Cross-species studies have confirmed the conservation of the Hox genes during evolution. In vivo, the products of the Hox genes function as transcription factors. The genes have a highly conserved sequence called the homeobox, which translates into a 60 amino acid homeodomain. The homeodomain is a DNA-binding domain made up of three alpha helices and an N-terminal arm which precedes helix 1. Since most HOX homeodomains bind a common core sequence (TAAT), the mechanism by which these proteins achieve specificity in target gene regulation was unknown for some years. This was resolved by the identification of extradenticle (exd). Genetic analysis of zygotic and maternal effect mutations of exd demonstrated that it is a required cofactor for the Drosophila Hox gene products. Examination of exd mutations showed posterior and anterior transformations with alteration in segmental identities. These transformations were similar to those caused by Hox genes. Further analysis of the Hox and exd mutations in vivo, substantiated by in vitro biochemical evidence showed that exd acts in concert with homeotic gene products by cooperatively binding DNA. The mammalian homologue of exd is PBX. PBX functions analogously to its Drosophila counterpart by modulating the DNA-binding specificity of HOX proteins. In mammals, PBX interacts with members of the first 10 paralog group HOX proteins. A second cofactor, MEIS with a high degree of homology to PBX was identified very recently. Both PBX and MEIS belong to the three amino acid loop extension (TALE) family of homeodomain proteins. The homeodomain of these proteins differ from the HOX homeodomains in t</description><creator>Shanmugam, Kandavel.</creator><contributor>Featherstone, M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Molecular interactions between homeodomain proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm66r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp77w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nc78k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acute promyelocytic leukemia (APL) is characterized by reciprocal chromosomal translocations invariably involving the retinoic acid receptor alpha (RARalpha) gene on chromosome 17. In the vast majority of APL cases, the RARalpha gene is fused to the PML gene on chromosome 15, generating the fusion PML-RARalpha. The chimeric PML-RARalpha protein plays a critical role in APL leukemogenesis. Retinoic acid (RA) can overcome the differentiation block conferred by PML-RARalpha and induce APL cells to terminally maturate into granulocytes. However, resistance to RA develops both in vitro and in patients. We have developed RA-resistant subclones derived from the human APL cell line, NB4. These resistant subclones display altered RA-binding and reduced transactivation of retinoid response elements (RAREs) upon RA treatment. In the subclone R4, we identified a point mutation changing a leucine to praline in the ligand binding domain of the fusion PML-RARalpha protein that causes a loss of ligand binding. The mutant PML-RARalpha protein retains its ability to heterodimerize with RXRalpha and bind to RAREs. Thus, it functions as a dominant negative transcriptional inhibitor of the coexpressed wild-type RARalpha. The mutant PML-RARalpha has impaired RA-dependent interaction with receptor coregulatory factors, SMRT and ACTR. Histone deacetylase inhibitor, Trichostatin A (TSA), in combination with RA can overcome the dominant negative activity of the mutant PML-RARalpha in R4 and relieve transcriptional inhibition on RAREs. Further, TSA potentiates and partially restores RA-induced differentiation of NB4 and R4 cells respectively. When we examined the interaction of specific cofactors with retinoid receptors in NB4 cells compared to that in RA-resistant cell lines, we isolated the DRIP/TRAP protein complex. The ligand-inducible interaction between the DRIP/TRAP complex and retinoid receptors is independent of RA sensitivity and the expression of PML-RARalpha, supporting the glo</description><creator>Shao, Wenlin, 1973-</creator><contributor>Miller, Wilson H., Jr. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Retinoic acid responsiveness and resistance in acute promyelocytic leukemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096877x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc78k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xd41j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three related studies were performed to better characterize the intracellular process of protein S-acylation in mammalian cells. The first study focused on the use of cysteinyl-containing fluorescent lipopeptides which mimic the N-terminal of various S-acylable intracellular regulatory proteins. These lipopeptides diffuse rapidly between membranes and are efficiently S-acylated by a variety of mammalian cells. S-acylation appears to be enzymatic by various criteria and is highly selective for cysteinyl as opposed to serinyl residues. Fluorescence microscopy revealed that the plasma membrane is the predominant site for intracellular S-acylation but that a second potential site localized to the Golgi apparatus may also exist. The second study examined the intracellular S-acylation of lipopeptides which mimic the carboxy-terminus of N-ras. S-acylation of lipopeptides was again specific for cysteinyl residues as opposed to serinyl residues. The exact structure of the attached prenyl group, for example the farnesyl versus geranyl group, does not affect the ability of the lipopeptide to undergo S-acylation, however, an attached moiety with sufficient hydrophobicity to promote high affinity but rapidly reversible interactions with membranes is required for efficient S-acylation. Fluorescence microscopy suggests that S-acylation of these peptides and likely N-ras protein itself occurs at the plasma membrane of mammalian cells. The third study examined the hypothesis that proteins of different sequences may be S-acylated by distinct S-acyltransferases. Lipopeptides bearing sequences mimicking the N-termini of src-like nonreceptor protein tyrosine kinases or heterotrimeric G-protein alpha-subunits, incorporate similar ratios of [3H]palmitate/[3H]stearate following incubation of lipopeptide with cells and equal activities of [3H]palmitate and [3H]stearate. In contrast, lipopeptides which mimic the C-terminus of N-ras exhibit ratios which are significantly different from the ratios for those lipopeptides described above. These results suggest that these two groups of structurally-different lipopeptides are S-acylated by distinct S-acyltransferases within the plasma membrane. Further, lipopeptides bearing nonphysiological sequences which are preferentially S-acylated in the Golgi, incorporate radiolabeled fatty acids in ratios which are significantly different from those determined for most lipopeptides S-acylated at the plasma membrane, suggesting that distinct S-acyltransferases may exist in the plasma membrane and Golgi apparatus of mammalian cells.</description><creator>Schroeder, Hans R.</creator><contributor>Silvius, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>S-acylation and intracellular targeting of lipid-modified proteins and model lipopeptides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw21w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd41j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w92c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In polymer extrusion, a melt instability called gross melt fracture is often observed when the extrusion rate is increased beyond a critical value. Because gross melt fracture limits the production rate, much attention has been devoted to predicting when it will occur. However, there is still no general understanding of the origin of this phenomenon. Several criteria have been proposed for the onset of gross melt fracture (OGMF), but these depend on the procedure used for measuring them and thus are not material properties. The use of a critical extensional stress (CES) is proposed here as a criterion for OGMF. This stress is estimated using the entrance pressure drop analyses proposed by Cogswell and by Binding. Orifice dies were used to eliminate the complication arising from the presence of a capillary. The entrance angle and contraction ratio were varied to study the effect of die geometry. Various materials including conventional linear low and high density polyethylene and new polyethylenes produced by metallocene and constrained geometry catalysts were used in a study of the effect of molecular structure on OGMF. The latter materials are of special interest, because they have very well-defined molecular structure in terms of molecular weight (MW), molecular weight distribution (MWD), and long chain branching (LCB). In addition, the effect of particulate additives (boron nitride and carbon black) was investigated. It was found that CES is independent of the die, contraction ratio, and entrance angle, as long as the angle is equal to or greater than 90 degrees. This result suggests that CES is, indeed, a material property. The CES was found to be independent of additive content up to a level of 0.5 wt%. Further, it was found that while CES is independent of MW, increasing levels of LCB and broadening MWD increase CES. Finally, brittle fracture at the entrance of the die is proposed as the cause of gross melt fracture.</description><creator>Kim, Seungoh, 1966-</creator><contributor>Dealy, J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>A criterion for gross melt fracture of polyolefins and its relationship with molecular structure /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h55g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w92c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qd80q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Breast cancer is the second most frequent cancer in middle-aged women. Control of this disease requires identification of the various factors involved in the invasive-metastatic cascade, facilitating the subsequent development of relevant blocking compounds. Tumor cell invasion is a complex sequence of events where cell adhesion molecules exert determinant roles. CD44 is a family of cell adhesion glycoproteins generated by alternative splicing of up to ten variant exons. Discrete CD44 isoforms are overexpressed in different human cancers, including breast cancer. CD44 is expressed on the plasma membrane of cells and binds mainly to hyaluronan. Hyaluronan is a negatively charged high-molecular-weight glycosaminoglycan conspicuously present in the extracellular matrix ant its concentration is increased at sites of tissue remodeling. This study tested the hypothesis that CD44 and its main ligand, hyaluronan participate in the invasive properties of breast cancer cells. The hypothesis is based on the following rationale: the previously documented upregulation of CD44 expression in human breast cancer tumors, the role of CD44 in the invasive properties of nonepithelial cells in vitro, and the high concentrations of hyaluronan present in human breast cancer tumors. The experiments were performed with different human breast cancer cell lines. In one cell line, CD44 and its v6 variant isoform participate directly in tumor cell invasion in vitro. Moreover, hyaluronan alters cell behavior in vitro, mainly by changing CD44 expression, adhesion and motility of breast cancer cells with high CD44 expression. In addition, it is shown that intratumoral injection of hyaluronan reduces the volume of tumors produced by orthotopically xenotransplanted breast cancer cells. The contribution of these studies to the advance of knowledge in breast cancer is based on a role of CD44 and hyaluronan in the interactions between tumor cells and the extracellular matrix, offering an opportunity to develop a new therapeutic strategy.</description><creator>Herrera-Gayol, Andrea.</creator><contributor>Jothy, Serge (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Role of CD44 and its main ligand, hyaluronan, in breast cancer invasion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558f88t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd80q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns0647473</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nucleophilic sulfonation of decyl halides and benzyl halides was carried out at 298.2 K in batches in o/w microemulsions and emulsions formed with the two-tailed cationic surfactants dioctyldimethylammomum chloride, R2(Me)2N +Cl-, or bromide, R2(Me) 2N+Br-. The effects of mixing, surfactant concentration and counterion, and reactant concentrations on the conversion of the halide were investigated. At the concentrations employed, phase separation occurred in most of the samples. Mixing did not affect the sulfonation of decyl halides, while it governed the sulfonation rate of benzyl halides. Chloride as the surfactant counterion reacted with the bromide and iodide halides to form an intermediate, decyl chloride, and a side product, benzyl chloride. At a fixed time, the conversion to the final product versus surfactant concentration displayed a broad maximum. The tendency of sodium decyl sulfonate to remain at the interface resulted in lower conversion with increasing decyl halide concentration, while the formation of a separate benzyl halide phase produced the same effect. Increasing the mole ratio sodium sulfite/halide reactant increased the conversion to the final product in a manner that supports the mechanisms of ion exchange with the surfactant counterions and a second order nucleophilic substitution. A single-pseudophase and a three-pseudophase model described the sulfonation of decyl halides and benzyl halides, respectively. The three new assumptions employed in the model are: (1) the volume of the interfacial region varies only with the amount of surfactant added, (2) the oil-soluble reactant may be unavailable for reaction if there is insufficient surfactant to bind all of the decyl halide to the interface, or insufficient mixing to eliminate the benzyl halide phase, and (3) a single ion exchange constant accounts for the exchange of three different anions at the interface.</description><creator>Husein, Maen.</creator><contributor>Vera, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Weber, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Nucleophilic sulfonation in microemulsions and emulsions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn16n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647473</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kp785</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Why do some regimes enjoy more autonomy than others when taking foreign policy and alignment choices? How does the organization of state-society relations constrain or enable a regime's freedom to take foreign policy and alignment choices? What explains the overlap between the domestic and external security spheres of some states, but not others? Finally, how do the foreign policy and alignment choices of some regimes have domestic political origins, uses, and implications? This study explores these theoretical questions through a comparative examination of the impact of the organization of state-society relations (the independent variable) on regime autonomy in taking foreign policy and alignment choices (the dependent variable) in King Hussein's Jordan and Hafiz al-Asad's Syria. In contrast to Jordan's overlapping security terrains, and the domestic political origins, uses, and implications of many of the Hashemite regime's foreign policy and alignment choices, in Asad's Syria these choices are responses to shifts in the external geopolitical environment. This study offers an explanation of the discrepancy between the Syrian regime's ability to ignore domestic constraints on foreign policy and alignment choices, due to its preoccupation with external sources of threat, compared to its Jordanian counterpart's inability to do so and, consequently, its preoccupation on many occasions with strictly domestic sources of threat. This study bridges comparative politics and international relations theorizing, inviting a methodological shift away from the hitherto dominant neorealist tendency in the latter field, which anchors foreign policy and alignment choices in primarily external considerations and objectives. Borrowing from the literature on corporatism, populism, and historical institutionalism, this study also supplies a more rigorous methodology for investigating the relationship between the domestic structures of nondemocratic states and their foreign policy and alignment choices. More than a revision of neorealist theorizing, and in contrast to idiosyncratic, domestic structure, or constructivist approaches to the study of state behavior, this study contends that a contextual and historical analysis of the organization of state-society relations explains why regime autonomy to take foreign policy and alignment choices may be constrained in some states but not in others. Furthermore, and against neorealism's insistence on the external origins of foreign policy and alignment choices, this study also argues that on many occasions these choices have domestic political origins, uses, and implications. The implications of these conclusions on the study of Arab politics, and on the quest for a first-cut theory of state behavior, are also assessed.</description><creator>Salloukh, Bassel Fawzi.</creator><contributor>Bryner, Rex (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Jordan -- Foreign relations.</subject><subject>International relations -- Political aspects.</subject><subject>Syria -- Foreign relations.</subject><subject>Syria -- Politics and government.</subject><subject>Jordan -- Politics and government.</subject><title>Organizing politics in the Arab world : state-society relations and foreign policy choices in Jordan and Syria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px699.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp785</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt688</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Museum of Modern Art's television project sponsored by the Rockefeller Brother's Fund between 1952 and 1955 was designed to educate a democratic and cultured citizenry through the principles and practices of modern art and liberal humanism. Through a close reading of four television programs, related policy documents and exhibitions, as well as critical, educational and promotional literature, this study will show how within the context of the MoMA's mandate and history, the television project was a decisive, yet highly troubled attempt to forge cultural citizenship through the burgeoning media of modern art and television. This exploration will establish how the television project was an integral aspect of the MoMA's efforts since World War II to situate modern art as essential to the formation of an international polity shaped around the promise of universality, yet dependent on upholding the primacy of free and creative individuals. In addressing such a challenge, this dissertation will contend that television was not necessarily antithetical to modernism, rather it was just one among an array of struggling forces falling within the rubric of the modern. Moreover, this analysis will consider the importance of culture in logics of liberal governance. In order to elucidate the dimensions of cultural democracy as they emerged through the MoMA's television project, this study will be shaped around a discussion of three components crucial to the formation and maintenance of citizenly conduct---civic education, democratic cultural communications, and cross-cultural governance. To these ends, a range of sources from the disciplines of Communications, Cultural Studies and Critical Artistic Studies will be drawn on in order to investigate the provisional links forged between modern art, media pedagogy, and cultural citizenship in the Cold War period.</description><creator>Shaw, Nancy (Nancy Alison), 1962-</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Art museums -- United States -- Educational aspects.</subject><subject>Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.)</subject><subject>Television -- Social aspects -- United States.</subject><subject>Arts -- Political aspects -- United States.</subject><title>Modern art, media pedagogy and cultural citizenship : the Museum of Modern Art's television project, 1952-1955</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn43s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt688</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35000</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>