<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:34:04Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11575" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pt78g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’analyse spectrale a été utilisée pour étudier les composantes périodiques des taux de croissance relatifs (en masse et en longueur) et de la consommation de nourriture journalière chez la truite mouchetée Salvelinus fontinalis, selon un plan expérimental en mesures répétées dans le temps. L’analyse du périodogramme multi-fréquentiel et la procédure pas à pas croissante qui l’accompagne ont révélé la présence de composantes infradiennes de 4 to 10 j dans les taux de croissance relatifs et de 6 to 19 j dans la consommation de nourriture journalière, qui expliquaient conjointement une large proportion (80 to 90%) de la variation totale. L’analyse de variance de la transformée de Fourier finie a démontré la répétabilité des rythmes dans les taux de croissance relatifs. [...] Finalement, un modèle à espace d’états a été développé pour la série chronologique vectorielle des probabilités d’être dans les six états étudiés de manière à décrire et prédire à court terme la dynamique comportementale de la truite mouchetée; le R2 calculé entre les valeurs prédites et observées variait de 0.32 et 0.83 avant la remise de nourriture et de 0.40 à 0.89 après celle-ci.</description><description>Spectral analysis was used to investigate the periodic components of relative growth rates (on a mass and length basis) and of daily food intake in young-of-the-year brook trout Salve linus fontinalis, according to a temporal repeated measures design. The analysis of the multi-frequential periodogram and the companion stepwise procedure revealed the presence of infradian components of about 4 to 10 d in the growth rates and of 6 to 19 d in the daily food intake, which jointly explained a high proportion (80 to 90%) of the total variation. The analysis of variance of the finite Fourier transform showed the relative growth rate rhythms were repeatable and the characteristics of those rhythms were not modified by handling, stocking density (1.52 vs 0.76 kg·m-3) or ration level (1.25 vs 2.5%). On the other hand, periodicities in the daily food intake were mainly modified by the ration level. Trigonometric models were built on the periodicities detected by the multifrequential periodogram, with temporally autocorrelated random errors when required. These models described and predicted at short term the variation in the relative growth rates and daily food intake of brook trout, with the R2pred ranging between 73 and 93%. [...] The model described and predicted very well the behavioral dynamics of brook trout at short term; the R2 computed between the observed and the predicted values ranged between 0.32 and 0.83 before feeding and between 0.40 and 0.89 after feeding.</description><creator>Aboul Hosn, Wafa.</creator><contributor>Dutilleul, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Brook trout -- Food.</subject><subject>Time-series analysis.</subject><subject>Biological rhythms.</subject><subject>Brook trout -- Growth -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Brook trout -- Behavior -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Analysis of growth rhythms and activity patterns of brook trout Salvelinus fontinalis, based on replicated time series and time-dependent transition probabilities.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js035.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt78g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634689p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les mutations dans le recepteur androgene humain (hAR) causent, ou du moins predisposent, it differentes maladies telles que le syndrome d’insensibilire aux androgenes (AIS), l’atrophie musculaire spinobulbaire (SBMA), une maladie neurodegenerative ainsi que le cancer de la prostate. Ma recherche a porte sur le mecanisme de pathogenese de trois mutations dans le hAR. La premiere mutation etant une expansion de l’insert poly-glutamine (poIyQ) dans le premier exon qui cause le SBMA; les 2 autres mutations sont dans l’exon 5 (Asn727Lys) et dans l’exon 8 (Met886Val) du do maine de liaison du ligand (LBD) qui causent l’infertilite d’origine oligospermique. [...]Ni la mutation Met886Val, ni la mutation Asn727Lys ne reduisent la liaison de l’androgene dans les cellules COS transfectees ou dans les fibroblastes cutanees d’origine genitale. Cependant, les deux mutations reduisent le taux de transactivation de 40% ce qui se reflete dans la reduction de la liaison de l’hAR avec l’element de reponse dependant des steroides. A notre connaissance, ces deux mutations sont les premieres dans le AR LBD qui affectent la liaison avec l’ADN et c’est probablement a travers un changement dans l’activite du recepteur d’androgene que ces deux mutations causent une diminution de la fertilitite chez les males. [...]</description><description>hAR mutations cause, or predispose to, androgen insensitivity syndrome (AIS), spinobulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA, a motor neuronodegenerative disease), and prostate cancer. I investigated the pathogenic mechanism of three AR mutations: expansion of the trinucleotide repeat (CAG)n coding for the polymorphic poly glutamine (polyGln) tract in exon 1 of the AR which causes SBMA, and mutations in exon 5 (Asn727Lys) and exon 8 (Met886Val) of the AR ligand-binding domain (LBD) each of which causes oligospermic infertility. [...]Neither the Met886Vai nor the Asn727Lys mutation affects androgen binding in genital skin fibroblasts or transfected COS cells. However, both reduce transactivation by -40%, a result paralleled by A-R binding to a steroid response element. To my knowledge, these are the first AR LBD mutations that impair DNA binding. Mesterolone normalized spermatogenesis in Asn727Lys subject. Interestingly, the Asn727Lys AR is 50% hypertransactive with mesterolone at 37°C but not at 34°C, and trypsinolysis indicates that it is conformationally normal with mesterolone but not with 5α-DHT.</description><creator>Abdullah, Abdullah A. Rasool.</creator><contributor>Pinsky, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Infertility, Male -- Pathogenesis.</subject><subject>Muscular atrophy -- Pathogenesis.</subject><subject>Androgens -- Receptors.</subject><title>Molecular analysis of human androgen receptor mutations causing motor neuronopathy or infertility.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g98v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634689p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc956</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The overall objective of this research was to identify forage legumes and grasses, which competed sufficiently with weeds developing after tillage, to provide acceptable weed control in grain corn, without, however reducing corn growth, and to obtain a better understanding of the physiological aspects of competition, particularly light and nitrogen. Corn yields were not affected by forage seeding date (10 and 20 days after corn emergence), however yields were affected by the type of forage species used as an intercrop. Cultivation reduced weed populations in corn and the inclusion of cover crops provided some additional control (up to 10%). Crimson clover was able to establish and suppress weeds well, however, it caused yield reductions in grain corn. A system of injecting solutions into stems of soybean plants proved to be successful for administering substantial amounts of dilute and concentrated solutions over long periods of time. [...] Plants placed under 75% shade senesced approximately two weeks earlier than unshaded plants. Soybean plants injected with sucrose or sucrose plus nitrogen senesced later than those receiving only nitrogen or distilled water, demonstrating that carbon availability plays a more important role than nitrogen in the senescence of soybean plants.</description><description>L’objectif de cette recherche était d’identifier l’espèce fourragère qui peut achever un bon contrôle des mauvaises herbes qui se développent après un sarclage, sans pour autant faire la compétition au maïs-grain, et de mieux comprendre l’aspect physiologique de la compétition surtout pour la lumière et l’azote. Le rendement du maïs-grain a été affecté par les espèces fourragères intercalaires et non par leurs dates de semis (10 et 20 jours après l’émergence du maïs). Le sarclage a réduit les populations des mauvaises herbes et les intercalaires ont fourni un contrôle supplémentaire Gusqu’à 10% ). Le trèfle incarnat s’est bien établi et a bien contrôlé les mauvaises herbes, cependant il a causé des réductions du rendement du maïs. Un système d’injection de solutions dans les tiges des plants de soja a prouvé être efficace pour administrer aux plantes différentes quantités de solutés pendant de longues durées. [...] Les plants placés dans des conditions de 75% d’ombre ont sénescé à peu près deux semaines plus tôt que ceux qui ne l’étaient pas. Les plants recevant du sucrose ou du sucrose + N ont sénescé plus tard que ceux qui ont reçu de l’N seulement ou de l’eau distillée. Ceci démontre que la disponibilité du C joue un rôle plus important dans la sénescence des plants de soja que l’N.</description><creator>Abdin, Omar A. K.</creator><contributor>Smith, D. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Intercropping.</subject><subject>Cover crops.</subject><subject>Corn -- Yields.</subject><subject>Corn -- Weed control.</subject><title>Aspects of the physiology and agronomy of competition in crop plants.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj68h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc956</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rx80r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mieux faire connaître le riche héritage de Hans-Joachim Iwand aux milieux théologiques nord-américains qui, à ce jour, sont fort peu sensibilisés à la contribution de cette figure de proue de la pensée protestante du XX° siècle, tel est le but de cette étude. Celle-ci soulève entre autres le fait que le principe du theologische Existenz avancé par Iwand permet d’envisager la théologie chrétienne dans le contexte de la «contextualité» qui anime en grande partie la pensée théologique contemporaine en Amérique du Nord. [...] La réflexion théologique d’Iwand constitue ainsi une source pertinente pour aider la communauté chrétienne à poursuivre plus avant sa réflexion sur la foi biblique. Interprète moderne de Luther, Iwand s’est joint au nombre des ardents défenseurs de la paix entre l’Est et l’Ouest alors qu’illuttait pour renouveler la pensée théologique et la proclamation de l’Église en Allemagne au lendemain de la Seconde Guerre mondiale. Les pages qui suivent démontrent comment ce professeur vénéré par nombre de théologiens allemands contemporains, y compris Jürgen Moltmann, a vécu sa foi dans un siècle où l’histoire occidentale vivait ses plus sombres années. Cette étude porte sur l’interprétation d’Iwand au sujet des événements qui ont conduit à la chute de l’Allemagne et aux difficultés de l’après guerre.[...]</description><description>The intention of this study is to make the legacy of Hans-Joachim Iwand accessible to the North American theological community, which to date has had little if any awareness of the contribution of this important figure to twentieth century Protestant thought. It is argued, in particular, that Iwand’s concept of theologische Existenz constitutes an approach to Christian theology reminiscent of the concern for “contextuality” present in much contemporary North American theology, and therefore an historical model from which the latter may draw inspiration and insight. Iwand’s theology offers itself as a relevant source for the Christian community engaged in rethinking the biblical faith. A noted modem interpreter of Luther, Iwand became an ardent advocate of peace between East and West as he struggled to renew theology and the proclamation of the church in post-War Germany. The dissertation demonstrates the manner in which this revered teacher of many present-day German theologians, including Jürgen Moltmann, lived out his confession of the faith in the midst of this century’s most devastating period of Western history. The study discusses Iwand’s interpretation of the developments that led to Germany’s collapse and the problems of the aftermath of World War II. His thought is compared with that of a number of his contemporaries and today’s scholars in both Europe and North America.</description><creator>Aach, Inge.</creator><contributor>Hall, D. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Iwand, Hans Joachim, 1899-1960.</subject><subject>Theology -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>The contextuality and unity of the theology of Hans-Joachim Iwand : an introduction for North American Protestants.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278x52z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rx80r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qn04s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The access of commercial farm workers in Zimbabwe to resources such as wages and land has been strongly influenced by the spatial inscriptions of modernity in state administrative practices that emerged along with the international concerns of “development” in the 1940s. Marginalized by the dominant narratives of modernization within colonial development policies that focused on “African peasants” and “urban African workers,” farm workers were officially viewed less as a Government responsibility and more as a domestic responsibility of white farmers. In this thesis, I discuss this form of governance on commercial farms which I call “domestic government” - “domestic” in the double-sense of officially promoting the “private” over “public” domain and of administratively valuing proper paternalistic family and family-like relations between male workers and their families and between commercial farmers and “their” workers. The tobacco farms of Hurungwe District in northwestern Zimbabwe provide the setting to trace the spatially inscribed power relations, strategies, negotiations, and transgressions within what may be called the “traditions” of domesticity in “modern” Zimbabwean politics. </description><description>L’accès des travailleurs agricoles commerciaux du Zimbabwe à des ressources telles que les salaires et la terre a reposé dans une large mesure sur l’inscription spatiale de la modernité dans les formalités administratives de l’État qui ont vu jour en même temps que les préoccupations internationales touchant le «développement» dans les années 1940. Marginalisés dans les récits prédominants de la modernisation inscrits dans les politiques sur le développement colonial qui mettaient l’accent sur les «paysans africains» et les «travailleurs africains urbains», les travailleurs agricoles étaient officiellement considérés moins comme une responsabilité du gouvernement que comme une responsabilité domestique des agriculteurs blancs. Dans la présente thèse, je traite de cette forme de gérance des agriculteurs commerciaux que je qualifie de «gouvernement domestique», l’adjectif «domestique» ayant un double sens, d’abord, la promotion officielle du domaine «privé» aux dépens du domaine «public», ensuite, l’importance que l’administration accorde aux bonnes relations paternalistes familiales et quasi-familiales entre les travailleurs de sexe masculin et leur famille et celles entre les agriculteurs commerciaux et «leurs» travailleurs. Les plantations de tabac dans le district de Hurungwe, au nord-ouest du Zimbabwe, sont les endroits où l’on peut constater les relations, stratégies, négociations [...]</description><creator>Rutherford, Blair A.</creator><contributor>Galaty, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Rural development -- Government policy -- Zimbabwe.</subject><subject>Agricultural laborers -- Zimbabwe -- Hurungwe District.</subject><subject>Hurungwe District (Zimbabwe) -- Rural conditions.</subject><subject>Rural development -- Zimbabwe -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>"Traditions" of domesticity in "modern" Zimbabwean politics : race, gender, and class in the government of commercial farm workers in Hurungwe district.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb48r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qn04s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63t010z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A novel approach whereby one can use genetically engineered cells for various applications is presented in this thesis. The concept of artificial cell has been used for the purpose. Artificial cells containing genetically engineered bacteria E. coli DH5 cells for the removal of urea and ammonia are taken as an example to establish the feasibility of this approach. Further, this example of removal of urea and ammonia is selected as presently we do not have an efficient and cost effective method to use during kidney failure, liver failure and other diseases when elevated levels of urea and ammonia are commonly experienced. [...]For these studies, alginate-polylysine-alginate microcapsules were used. Process parameters for E. coil DH5 cell microencapsulation, using the drop technique, have been optimized and presented. [...]Results show, only a very small dosage of artificial cells is required to lower systemic urea and ammonia. Thus, this approach can overcome problems related to the use of free bacterial cells. The efficiency of microencapsulated genetically engineered bacteria was found to be several times greater compared to standard oxystarch and urease-zirconium phosphate methods. This study has shown the primary feasibility of this new approach. The possibility of extending this approach of using artificial cells for the use of other types of genetically engineered cells for various clinical, biotechnological and biomedical applications is, therefore, potent.</description><description>Une nouvelle approche par laquelle des cellules programmées génétiquement peuvent être utilisées lors diverses applications est presentée dans cette thèse. Le concept de cellule artificielle est utilisé à ce propos. Des cellules artificielles enrobant les cellules bacteriénnes E. coli DHS, programmées génétiquement, sont prises comme exemple afin d’établir la praticabilité de cette approche. De plus l’élimination d’urée et d’ammoniaque est choisie, car présentement nous ne possédons une méthode efficace et rentable, applicable lors de l’échéances rénale, hépatique et d’autres maladies, où on rencontre très souvent des niveaux élèves d’urée et d’ammoniaque. [...] Pour ces études les microcapsules alginate-polylysine-alginate étaient utilisées. Les paramètres du procédé de microencapsulation des cellules E. coli DHS, utilisant la technique de goutte, ont été optimises et présentés. [...]Les resultats montrent qu’il suffit d’un petit dosage de cellules artificielles pour baisser les niveaux systémiques d’uree et d’ammoniaque. Ainsi cette approche peut surmonter les problèmes associés à l’utilisation des cellules bactériennes libres. [...]Cette étude a demontré la praticabilité primaire de cette nouvelle approche. Ainsi, la projection de microencapsulation d’autres cellules programmées génétiquement pour diverses applications cliniques, biotechnologiques et biomédicales semble réaliste.</description><creator>Prakash, Satya, 1962-</creator><contributor>Chang, T. M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biomedical Engineering.</subject><title>A novel biomedical approach based on artificial cells microencapsulated genetically engineered bacterial cells : using E. coli DH5 cells for urea and ammonia removal as an example.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x241v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t010z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214s423</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La conception des réseaux de transport CA/CC est un problème complexe nécessitant un temps de calcul très long. Bien qu’une variété d’outils d’analyse de réseaux soient disponibles à cette fin, les ingénieurs de planification comptent encore fortement sur leur expérience pour déterminer quelles conceptions alternatives de réseau sont les plus appropriées. Ceci est particulièrement vrai quand des critères multiples comme le coût, la fiabilité et d’autres critères techniques doivent faire face à des considérations environnementales ou socio-économiques. Les techniques actuelles de conception reposent principalement sur des outils d’analyse détaillée qui consomment beaucoup de temps et de ce fait, elles sont restrictives sur le nombre de conceptions qui peuvent être raisonnablement analysées. De plus, la plus grande partie de l’expertise disponible en conception se retrouve disséminée dans nombreuses sources, particulièrement dans l’expérience de nombreux experts de ce domaine.Dans cette thèse, un nouvel logiciel appelé TIDE ( Environnement intelligent de conception pour réseau de transport: « Transmission Intelligent Design Environnement «) a été développé et fournit à l’ingenieur de conception un environnement intelligent intégré et rapide pour la conception préliminaire de réseaux de transport point à point.[...]</description><description>The design of AC/DC power transmission networks is a complex, time-consuming problem. Although a variety of power system analysis tools are available for this purpose, planning engineers still rely heavily on their experience to determine which alternative network designs are the most suitable. [...] The present design practices rely mainly on time-consuming detailed analysis tools thereby restricting the number of designs that can be reasonably processed. [...] In this thesis, a new software tool called TIDE (Transmission Intelligent Design Environment) has been developed which provides the design engineer with a fast, integrated and intelligent environment for the preliminary design of point-to-point transmission systems. The goals of this environment were to identify, model and preserve design expertise in a computerized user-friendly environment, to integrate this expertise with the main network analysis tools (load flow, transient stability, reliability and costing) and to automate the transmission design process. These goals are achieved through an integrated system made up of complementary expert system modules, databases and classical simulation techniques. The expert system modules are particularly appropriate to capture basic design knowledge since design is mainly conceptual, creative and nonalgorithmic. A hybrid expert system using object structures and rules was developed for this purpose. [...]</description><creator>Loud, Lester.</creator><contributor>Galiana, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>An intelligent environment for the preliminary design of power transmission networks.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514np57m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214s423</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nc05b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il existe aujourd’hui un intérêt croissant sur l’usage des poudres de cuivre pour rem placer les poudres de métaux précieux dans des applications telles que les couches épaisses. Des poudres de cuivre ayant une taille de particule élémentaire de moins de 5 µm, une distribution granulométrique étroite, une forme de particule sphéroïdale et une faible teneur en oxygène (poudres de haute pureté) sont nécessaire pour des applications ou une forte conductivité électrique est d’une importance critique.Dans cette recherche, une nouvelle méthode de production de poudre de cuivre ayant les caracteristiques requises a été étudiée. Cette méthode implique la précipitation de la poudre de cuivre par réduction avec le gaz hydrogène sous pression, à partir d’un médium organique. Le médium organique -composé de Kelex 100, de décanol et de kérosène -a la composition d‘un des solvents organiques utilisés dans l’extraction par solvant. Ce travail a été divisé en deux parties. En première partie, les paramètres influant la précipitation de la poudre de cuivre ont été étudiés.[...]</description><description>Today, there is growing interest in using copper powders for thick film application in the place of precious metals. Copper powders with particle size less than 5 μm, narrow size distribution, spheroidal shape and very low oxygen content (high purity) are required for this kind of application where high electrical conductivity is of primary consideration. In this work a novel method of preparing copper powder having the above requirements was investigated. This method involves the precipitation of copper powder from an organic medium by hydrogen reduction under pressure. The organic medium used, Kelex 100* -decanol -kerosene, is one of the solvent mixtures used in solvent extraction of metals. The work was conducted in two parts. In part (I), all the parameters affecting the precipitation of copper were studied. The parameters studied were temperature (473 -573 K), hydrogen pressure (1.03 -3.79 MPa), time, use of additives, solvent composition, etc. In particular, the investigation focused on the underlying correlation between the reduction kinetic parameters of the system and the physical properties of the powder. [...]</description><creator>Sarraf-Mamoory, Rasoul.</creator><contributor>Demopoulos, G. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Drew, R. A. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Mining and Metallurgical Engineering.</subject><title>Preparation and processing of fine copper powders from organic media.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f6784.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nc05b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f9203</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The origin of the alkaline igneous rocks and the related carbonatites (carbonate bodies that appear to be intrusive plugs of dykes) has long been debated. The crux of this debate is whether the carbonate rocks are the product of differentiation of an alkaline magma or the cause in the first place of the alkaline magma through the assimilation of country rock limestone by a “normal” magma. The object of this thesis is to investigate this association of alkaline igneous bodies with carbonate rocks with special reference to the Monteregian plutons. Since carbonate rocks were known to be associated with alkaline igneous rocks in both the Oka area and on Mount St-Hilaire, these two areas were selected for study. Not only are they less than 50 miles apart and conveniently located to the west and east of Montreal respectively, but drill cores from both areas are available.</description><creator>Gold, David Percy.</creator><contributor>Kranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The relationship between the limestones and the alkaline igneous rocks of Oka and St.-Hilaire, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bf908.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f9203</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92gb40s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acetylcholine storage, release and synthesis have been studied in ganglia perfused with solutions containing varied concentrations of sodium, potassium, and calcium ions. Ganglia perfused with sodium free Locke spontaneously lose their ACh store with time, and this process is accelerated by simultaneous withdrawal of calcium ions. Ganglia perfused with solutions containing high concentrations of potassium ions release acetylcholine at a high initial rate even in the absence of sodium ions. Their synthesis of acetylcholine is dependent on the sodium ion concentration in the perfusion fluid; in 100 mM sodium synthesis is inhibited by 20% and in 40 mM sodium by 75%. In low sodium release of acetylcholine becomes relatively impaired within a few minutes. It is suggested that influx of sodium ions into nerve endings during activity plays a part in stimulating ACh synthesis and ACh mobilization.</description><creator>Quastel, David M.</creator><contributor>Birks, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>The role of sodium ions in acetylcholine metabolism in sympathetic ganglia.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042x28n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb40s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts29q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Temiscouata region is here defined as the area encompassed by the National Topographic Series maps of Squateck, the western half of the Cabane sheet, and part of the Wild Goose sheet ( see maps 1 and 2). Specifically, the region is bounded by the following geographical coordinates: Latitudes 47°30’ and 47°45’, combined with longitudes 69°00’ and 68°45’ (Cabane West half sheet) Latitudes 47°45’ and 48°00’, combined with longitudes 69°00’ and 68°15’30’’ (Squateck sheet and part of the Wild Goose sheet) The area thus enclosed is an L, and is 730 square miles. Approximately half of this area is underlain by Silurian and Devonian rocks, and the remainder is underlain by Quebec group rocks (Cambrian and Ordovician). The Temiscouata region is situated for the most part within Temiscouata county, although it also includes important parts of Riviere du Loup and Rimouski counties. Parts or the whole of the following townships are included within the Temiscouata region: Ange, Asselin, Auclair, Bedard, Begon, Biencourt, Cabane, Hocquart, Madawaska (Lac Temiscouata) seigniory, Packington, Raudot, Robitaille, Rouillard, and some undivided land northeast of the Horton River.</description><creator>Lespérance, P. J.</creator><contributor>Stearn, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1961</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The silurian and devonian rocks of the Temiscouata region, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dw477.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts29q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fp979</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a report on an investigation into the origins of the modern seaport of Montreal. [...] The present study is concerned primarily with the specific measures taken to open up the channel to ocean shipping in the years 1805 to 1865. 1805 was the date of creation of Trinity House, Quebec, which marked the inception of officially controlled pilotage and navigation in the modern sense. By 1865, channel improvement had provided a channel three hundred feet wide and twenty feet deep. Subsequent deepenings belong to the modern era, and are excluded from this study. No attempt is made to examine either the economic consequences of channel improvement, or the pressures that led to its attainment. Emphasis bas been laid on the physical aspects of the operation because they have, on the whole, been neglected in the previous literature by comparison with the social and economic implications.</description><creator>Corley, Nora Teresa.</creator><contributor>Hare, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1961</date><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- History.</subject><subject>Saint Lawrence River.</subject><subject>Harbors -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>The Montreal ship channel, 1805-1865.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182p281.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fp979</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg86q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Scientifically, the peninsula of Quebec-Labrador is a new land. The establishment of the mining town at Knob Lake has served to open up to scientific exploration a piece of country of great interest to all field scientists, but especially to the glacial geomorphologists. Since the early days of the acceptance of the Glacial Theory, Labrador has been considered to have been a region of prime importance in the development of the North American ice-sheet. It has also been implied that the final remnants of the ice-sheet wasted away in the Labrador peninsula. [...]The morphological effects produced by waning ice-sheets can be interpreted to indicate the precise course of events at the time of the deglaciation. The morphological evidence is both widespread and well preserved in the central portion of Quebec-Labrador and the first results of a study of it are presented in this thesis. Fluvioglacial erosion, or erosion effected by waters issuing from and flowing marginally and beneath a mass of glacial ice, results in the cutting of valleys which today are mainly unoccupied by streams and which constitute a relatively precise means by which the behaviour and condition of past ice-sheets and glaciers can be assessed. Glacial drainage channels, the significance of which was first fully appreciated by Kendall at the turn of the century, are sensitive indicators of the position and condition of formerly ice-covered terrain.</description><creator>Derbyshire, Edward D.</creator><contributor>Bird, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1960</date><subject>Glacial erosion -- Québec (Province) -- Nord-du-Québec.</subject><subject>Glacial erosion -- Newfoundland and Labrador -- Labrador.</subject><title>Fluvioglacial erosion in central Quebec-Labrador.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rs03c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg86q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2688453</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work gives the results of the study of the geology of the Eastman-Orford Lake area in the Eastern Townships or Quebec. This area has previously been mapped on a large scale by a number of well-known geologists under the auspices of the Geological Survey and the Quebec Department of Mines. In 1956 and 1957, the writer was directed by the Quebec Mineral Deposits Branch to undertake a detailed study of the structural relations and stratigraphy of the above area with the view to investigate possible exploitable mineral deposits. Two preliminary reports, summarizing these field studies, have been published by the Quebec Department of Mines in 1957 and 1958. Additional information pertinent to this survey was gathered by the writer in the field in 1958 and 1959 as a supplement to previously collected field-data.</description><creator>De Römer, H. S., 1926-</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1960</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Geology of the Eastman-Orford Lake area, Eastern Townships, Province of Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nc06m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2688453</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v599f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Seal Lake area described covers over 1,500 square miles in Central Labrador. This sedimentary basin is composed of a succession of Precambrian sediments, volcanic flows and diabase sills which have an estimated thickness of at least 30,000 feet. These rocks represent a typical geosynclinal sequence of sedimentation. Fluctuating shallow water conditions were prevalent throughout the deposition of most of the sequence, but the younger members of the succession are of terrestrial origin. The basin bas been extensively folded and overturned to the north with prominent thrust-faulting along the southern margin of the syncline. Low grade metamorphism increases slightly towards the southern thrust-faulted granite contact. More than 250 small copper occurrences have been recorded from the younger members of the Seal Lake succession but the mineralization is erratic. Low-grade niobium-thorium-rare earth deposits were discovered in the older Letitia Lake rocks to the southwest.</description><creator>Mann, Ernest Leigh.</creator><date>1959</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The geology of the Seal Lake area, central Labrador.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d570085t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v599f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp106</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is based on a study of the geology and mineralogy of a prospect area, including a copper deposit, near Goshen, New Brunswick. The prospect area included 38 claims on which the writer directed an exploration program for Oakwood Mines Limited during the summer of 1955. The field studies were carried out chiefly on this claim group. Soma information was collected from the surrounding region in order to obtain a broader geological picture of the prospect area. The laboratory investigations were done at McGill University.[...]</description><creator>Hawkins, William Maxwell.</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The geology of the Goshen copper prospect, Goshen, New Brunswick.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172134q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp106</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741v726</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A detailed study of the calcareous layera within the Lorraine group and the Waynesville member of the Richmond group has been attempted in this thesis. Not only have these rooks been studied on the basis of their chemioal composition, as is suggested by the title of this thesis, but hand specimens, insoluble residues, thin sections and polished sections were also examined. Furthermore, a chapter conoerning the changes which occurred within the oaloareous rooks during diagenesis has been included and an appendix on the use of the X-ray speotrometer has been provided.[...]</description><creator>Dean, Ronald Samuel.</creator><contributor>Webber, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject>Sedimentary rocks</subject><title>A compositional study of calcareous Lorraine sedimentary rocks.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bx60s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741v726</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mg04t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is based on research into the nature and controls on the geochemical patterns resulting from the dispersion in humus and moss, of zinc, nickel, copper and lead from Precambrien rocks. The results have justified certain conclusions which the writer believes will be of practical use to the rapidly expanding science of applied geochemistry. The dispersion patterns studied are the result of weathering and dispersion in mineral soils and ground water, of primary minerals, either related to zones of sulphide mineralization or occurring in trace amounts in unmineralized rock. The metals forming these secondary dispersion patterns have entered the biogeochemical cycle and been concentrated in the organs of plants, which upon death and decay have formed humus. There has been a leaching away of the more soluble elements in the humus and concentration of the less soluble ones. The behaviour of a given element in the exogenic geochemical cycle depends on its mobility which is governed by a vast complex of physical, chemical and biological factors. In this thesis an attempt is made to evaluate the influence of some of the factors that control the dispersion, and/or concentration of zinc, nickel, copper and lead in the humus and topmost peat horizons. [...]</description><creator>Berrangé, Jevan P.</creator><contributor>Riddell, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Dispersion in humus and moss, of zinc, copper, nickel and lead, from a glaciated Precambrian terrain.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sg82v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mg04t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hz768</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The structure and petrology of an area of 602 square miles in Northwestern Q.uebec is described. The region is between the Timiskaming and Grenville petrological provinces and is known as the belt of banded gneisses or Ottawa mountains. The area is between Val-d’Or and Malartic and is 15 miles south of the Canadian National line from Quebec to Cochrane. About 70 per cent of the area is covered by lacustrine clay through which project northeast-trending ranges of hills or isolated outcrops consisting mainly of granite or pegmatite. All the consolidated rocks are Precambrian in age. The oldest rocks are metamorphosed equivalents of clastic feldspathic sediments, the Pontiac group, represented by biotite schists and gneisses belonging to the biotite-chlorite subfacies of the green-schist facies. In parts migmatites are formed with granite and pegmatite, and locally porphyroblasts of potash or sodic feldspar develop. Staurolite and sillimanite schists form bands in the lower grade biotite schist. The development of the high-grade metamorphic minerals is probably due to initial chemical composition rather than higher metamorphic grade. [...]Foliation is common and is parallel to original bedding. The original sediments were probably deposited in a marine geosyncline adjacent to mountains during a cold climate. It appears that the Pontiac group and the Grenville series may be gradational into each other through the belt of banded gneisses [...]</description><creator>Freeman, Peter Verner.</creator><contributor>Kranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1957</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Geology of the Beraud-Mazerac area, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jh685.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hz768</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp11g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An apparatus of original design based on scattering of light by smoke was constructed to measure the penetration of smoke filters. Methods of obtaining a suitable testing cloud for use tn the e.pparatus were investigated. Various carbon smokes were investigated and the effects of several factors, involved in the production of these smokes, on the penetretion of' the filters were determined. An oleic acid smoke generator was constructed which yielded smokes of homogeneous particle size. The stabilty of various filters to this smoke was investigated. The optimum conditions for the Manufacture of rayon-asbestos filters were determined.</description><creator>Yaffe, Leo.</creator><contributor>Campbell, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1943</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on aerosol filtration.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913t01f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp11g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vm16q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Activated Morden Bentonite has been investigated as a vapour-phase catalyst for the decomposition of three butanediols and butanediol-2,3 diacetate. Butanediol-2,3 at low temperatures gave 85 per cent yields of butanone-2, with isobutyraldehyde and the isobutyral of butanediol-2,3 as by-products. At high temperatures, gaseous decomposition occurred producing small yields of butadiene increasing to 14.9 per cent in the presence or water vapour. Butanedlol-2,3 diacetate gave chiefly acetic acid, butanone-2, and butadiene. Highest yields (57.5 per cent) of the diene were obtained at low temperatures and at fast feed-rates. Butanediol-1,4 at low temperatures gave practically theoretical yields of tetrahydrofuran. At high temperatures, propene, butene and formaldehyde were formed with a small amount of n-butyraldehyde and condensation products. Butanediol-1,3 gave butadiene (maximum yield 28.8 per cent), propene and butene. Increase in temperature and dilution with water increased gaseous decomposition but decreased the butadiene content of the gas. n-Butyraldehyde, 1-butenol-4, n-butyral of butanediol-1,3 and formaldehyde were also formed.</description><creator>Bourns, Arthur Newcombe.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1944</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The vapour-phase dehydration of butanediols.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v73g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm16q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mj69s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A kinetic study of the alkaline hydrolysis of RDX and RMX permitted the establishment of a method for routine analysis of HMX in RDX(B), the accuracy of the method being +/- O.2 percent HMX. The yields of RDX, in a Bachmann reaction, are decreased by dilution, by decrease of temperature, by use of deficiencies of any of the reagents and by excesses of nitric acid. The optimal conditions in RDX production are different for each temperature and concentration. The rates of RDX formation are increased with increase of temperature, decrease of dilution, and increase of concentrations of aoetio anhydride and ammonium nitrate. The nitric acid optimal is the same for both yields and rates of formation of RDX.</description><creator>Epstein, Samuel.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1944</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The relation between RDX and HMX production in the Bachmann reaction.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr1721350.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mj69s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm54x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The protection of wet and dry S.B.T. charcoals towards phosgene has been shown to improve at reduced temperatures. The nature of adsorption of nitrogen, butane and water on a series of charcoals of varying degrees of activation has been studied by determinations of adsorption isotherms and surface areas. Calculations of charcoal pore radius, pore volume and surface wetted by adsorbed water have been made. The extent of surface and the configuration of the capillaries have been found to be the principal criteria in determining the adsorptive capacity of a charcoal. A steric factor, dependent upon the dimensions of these capillaries, is postulated as limiting the accessibility of large molecules to the pores. A theory of water adsorption is proposed which suggests that about sixty percent of the charcoal surface is contained in pores of less than twelve Angstrom units in radius and is inaccessible to water molecules.</description><creator>Fineman, Manuel Nathan.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1944</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Influence of structural factors on the adsorption of gases by charcoal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f921c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm54x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623g759</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] The rates of transition of &lt;X H.M.X. and B H.M.x. have been studied between 25°C. and 145°C. in several solvents. The transition temperature has been found to lie between l00°C. and ll5°C. The rate and direction of polymorphic transition depend on the temperature; at constant terJ.perature the rate depends on the solvent employed, and the presence or absence of certain salt catalysts. Spontaneous initiation of a polymorphia change may take place only in a limited number of liquids, which are not necessarily the best solvents for H.M.X.[...] </description><creator>Gilpin, Victor.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1944</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Thermal decomposition of rossite and picrite in aqueous media : B.) Rate of transition of H.M.X. polymorphs. C.) Thermochemistry of the R.D.X. reactions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d55x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g759</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz326</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:06:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A more thorough investigation or the density or charcoal by liquid displacement than any reported to date has been undertaken, employing a wider variety or liquids and a series or charcoals of varying activity. Social precautions have been taken to remove adsorbed gases from the liquids and the charcoals and to insure that all values of density were true equilibrium values. A steric hindrance by the charcoal to the penetration of the liquid has been noted and correlated with the activity of the sample. The disagreement between other investigators has been explained in the basis of this steric effect. The wetting of the charcoal by liquids has been considered and an explanation of Stuart's relationship based upon these considerations has been attempted.[...]</description><creator>Guest, Rex McLean.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1944</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The apparent density and internal structure of activated charcoal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r6317.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz326</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11600</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>