<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:32:53Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11225" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h035t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acrylamide disc electrophoresis was employed to characterize the isoenzymes of creatine phosphokinase. Three main isoenzyme bands were demonstrated. A specific antiserum against skeletal muscle creatine phosphokinase (CPK) has been obtained. The antiserum was organ rather than species specific. A technique was developed to visualize CPK in precipitin lines. In solution the antiserum inhibited the enzymatic activity of muscle CPK. By means of the immunofluoresence technique, CPK was localized in the intermyofibrillary space of normal human skeletal muscle fibers. A higher concentration of the enzyme was found in fibers which have primarily an anaerobic enzyme profile (type II fibers).</description><creator>Bulcke, Jan Andre</creator><contributor>Sherwin, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery.</subject><title>Immunochemical studies of creatine phosphokinase isoenzymes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9999805.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h035t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445ch46g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une revue assez étendue de. différents problèmes soulevés par les réactions secondaires aux médicaments a été entreprise. La littérature spécialisée a été revue et critiquée suivant un schéma d'étude épidémiolocique. Une enquête rétrospective menée dans deux hôpitaux universitaires de Montréal a éprouvé un nouveau système de détection des réactions secondaires aux medicaments. Des méthodes et des résultats des plus importantes études épidémiologiques sur le sujet ont été compares. En conclusion, certains aspects du problème des reactions médicamenteuses ont été nouvellement identifiés et certaines suggestions pour l'amélioration des procédés de recherché ont été avancés.</description><creator>Boelen, Charles L.</creator><contributor>Horowitz, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Epidemiology and Health.</subject><title>Les réactions secondaires aux médicaments: approche épidemiologique et critique d’enquêtes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g97k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445ch46g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g572w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A faster, more efficient method has been developed for preparation of a copper-protein similar to Mann and Keilin's hepatocuprein. Beef liver is homogenized in glass-distilled water. The water-soluble fraction, prepared by centrifugation at 105,000 g, is heated at 50° for 10 minutes and recentrifuged. Residual soluble protein is precipitated with acetone. On redissolving in 0.005M K-phosphate buffer, pH 7.0, the material is passed through Sephadex G-75 and fractions with a high copper:protein ratio are pooled. These fractions are colorless. They contain three protein components (electrophoresis in acrylamide gel at pH 8.9) which appear to have molecular weights (gel filtration) of around 18,000 and to contain a variable per cent copper. The copper does not react directly with zinc dibenzyldithiocaxbamate. The copper-protein bond is stable to freezing and thawing but is cleaved in 3N HCl or 2.5N NaOH. The protein accounts for at least 1.5% of the total liver copper.</description><creator>Bloomer, Linda C.</creator><contributor>Sourkes, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Isolation of a bovine hepatic cuproprotein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d53c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g572w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386n730</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Serial arterial blood gas studies and pulmonary diffusing capacity measurements were made in 43 patients admitted with fractures to detect subclinical fat embolism. The values were correlated with chest radiographs, coagulation factors and serum lipid fractions. Eight patients developed fat embolism, with all but one of them having multiple fractures. Significant arterial hypoxemia developed in all of the patients with fat embolism and was detected early following injury. The other tests were of limited value. Fat embolism is primarily a pulmonary disease and occurs most frequently following multiple fractures. Serial arterial blood gas determinations should be obtained during the 72 hours following major fractures. If the arterial oxygen tension remains above 50 to 55 mm. Hg. pulmonary (and therefore, systemic) fat embolism has probably not occurred and is unlikely to do so. This degree of hypoxemia is much less specific in the presence of chronic pulmonary disease cr major thoracic trauma.</description><creator>Benoit, Paul R.</creator><contributor>Hampson, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Respiratory gas exchange following fractures: the role of fat embolism as a cause of arterial hypoxaemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j43r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n730</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bx523</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Methods of isolation of IgD from D-myeloma and normal sera have been explored as has a sensitive method to quantitate low levels of IgD. DEAE-cellulose chromatography of a 30-45% saturated ammonium sulfate fraction of D-myeloma serum, yielded an IgD rich fraction in which IgG contamination did not exceed 20-25%. This was fractionated on G-200 Sephadex and IgD was eluted free of IgG in the ascending half of the first protein peak. Specific antisera to IgD were insolubilized by copolymerization and by coupling to an insoluble carrier and were used to specifically adsorb IgD from normal sera. IgD was eluted from the immunoadsorbant with solutions of high molarity. Other fractions containing IgG and IgD were purified by removing IgG vnth specific anti-IgG immunoadsorbants. IgD levels of less than 0.1 mg/ml were quantitated by a radioimmunosorbent method which depends on the competition between IgD in an unknown and 125-labelled IgD in binding to an insolubilized antiserum to IgD. Levels in excess of 0.1 mg/ml were quantitated in Cudin tubes.</description><creator>Behelak, Youssef</creator><contributor>Rose, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Methods for the purification and quantitation of IgD</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v87k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx523</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g322h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Merrifield method of Solid Phase peptide synthesis has been applied to a study of the evolution of the neurohypophysial hormones. This work was carried out in an attempt to establish the identity of a principle designated EOP 1 (elasmobranch oxytocin-like principle 1) which had been isolated from the pituitary gland of the spiny dogfish (Squalus acanthias), and to test hypotheses on possible evolutionary intermediates. Three new analogues, 8-glutamine-oxytocin, 8-phenylalanine-oxytocin and 4-proline 8-glutamine-oxytocin were synthesized while a fourth, 8-valineoxytocin, previously synthesized by classical methods was synthesized for the first time by solid phase. Each analogue was synthesized on the Merrifield resin by the stepwise addition of the appropriate BOC and CBZ protected amino acids. Cleavage From the resin, giving the protected nonapeptide amide intermediates was accomplished by ammonolysis. Reduction of the intermediates with sodium in liquid ammonia and subsequent oxidation of the sulfhydryl groups with ferricyanide to form cyclic disulfides yielded the crude peptides in each case. Each analogue was then isolated in highly purified form by gel filtration on Sephadex G-15. The peptides were then evaluated pharmacologically and the results compared with those of EOP 1. While none of the analogues synthesized appeared to be EOP 1 it is possible that one or more of them could exist in nature.</description><creator>Baxter, John W.</creator><contributor>Manning, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Solid phase synthesis of some possible evolutionary intermediates of the neurohypophysial hormones</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612r76j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g322h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903306z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with the consequences of the thought of Pierre Teilhard de Chardin for Christian social philosophy. Teilhard de Chardin, a Jesuit paleontologist, has of late gained the attention of the academic community because of his reformulation of the traditional Christian understanding of the meaning of existence. This reinterpretation of the meaning of existence is expressed in terms of Teilhard de Chardin's ideas concerning the physical evolution of life towards a transcendent teleological principle; or if you will, it is also transmitted in terms of his advocacy of a phenomenology of history not unlike the Hegelian philosophy of history. Moreover, Teilhard retains a dimension to his thought that is entirely personal, and beyond the permissibility of public intervention. Therefore, he guards against "the totalitarian threat". Finally, it might be said that Teilhard does not violate orthodox Christian doctrine in elaborating his position. In the reworking of the Christian world-view, he makes the doctrine more meaningful for modern man.</description><creator>Poirier, Maben W.</creator><contributor>Shingler, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Political Science.</subject><title>The political and philosophical implications of Pierre Teilhard de Chardin’s thought</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jv330.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903306z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bx53c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The incremental-pragmatic world-view offers an approach to political development in the Third World. The analytical orientation of the approach is determined by an underlying value-system. An empirical investigation of India historically and sociologically contradicts the theoretical analysis of this approach. The latter is apparently unable to produce a meaningful understanding of Indian socio-political forces because underlying values distort empirical evidence. The contemporary Indian liberal-democratic political system represents the practical application of the theoretical analysis. For related and similar reasons the practical dimension of the incremental pragmatic approach is evidently unsuccessful. The revolutionary-dialectic approach offers a theoretical analysis that more accurately comprehends the data and information which an empirical investigation of India uncovers.</description><creator>August, Arnold</creator><contributor>Shingler, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Political Science.</subject><title>The incremental-pragmatic and the revolutionary-dialectic approaches to Third World change: the case of India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k44n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx53c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mt01q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On a beaucoup écrit sur les tragédies et les théories dramatiques de Voltaire pendant la période suivant sa mort jusqu'à nos jours. Sans essayer de contredire Lion ni Ridgway nous allons dans cet exercice sur "le drame chez Voltaire" mener, à la fois, une étude plus générale et plus précise sur Voltaire, car nous nous proposons d'examiner son oeuvre dramatique complète (tragédies, comédies attendrissantes, "pieces dramatiques"), autant qu'il importe, pour voir en quoi le théâtre de Voltaire, par sa théorie et par sa pratique, ressemble au drame du dix-huitième siècle, en quoi il s'en éloigne et jusqu'à quel point il y a contradiction .entre la théorie et la pratique dramatique de Voltaire.</description><creator>Stewart, Brinsley E.</creator><date>1969</date><subject>French.</subject><title>Le drame chez Voltaire – theorie et pratique</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb49s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mt01q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wt65c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Varying degrees of panlobular emphysema were produced in 10 dogs by intratracheal injection of papain. Pulmonary function was studied before and after the development of emphysema. The production of emphysema led to an increase in ERC, RV and TIC of 23%, 24%, and 16% respectively. The arterial oxygen saturation decreased by 8% and the PaCO2 by 19 mmHg. There was no significant effect on the PaCO2 pH and bicarbonate. Steady state diffusing capacity was reduced by 55%, compliance increased by 63% and there was a shift in the static pressure volume curve of the lung upward and to the left. The relationship between pulmonary resistance, RL, and lung volume was not significantly changed. However, following excision of the lungs, RL was partitioned by the retrograde catheter technique and the peripheral resistance was abnormally high accounting for 33 to 84% of RL. There was a decrease in the resistance of the central airways explaining the preservation of a normal RL. Trivial to moderate panlobular emphysema was found in the animals and was usually fairly localized in extent. Mean linear intercept ranged from 0.124 to 0.258 (normal 0.009 - 0.149). The alveolar surface area at a standard lung volume was reduced to 33.0 - 57.0 m^2 (normal 59 - 71 m^2). With the exception of FRC there was no significant correlation between any of the function tests and the degree of emphysema.</description><creator>Pushpakom, Rungsun</creator><contributor>Macklem, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Experimental pulmonary emphysema in dogs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g323s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt65c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712mb031</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In designing square or rectangular slabs stiffened with edge beams it sometimes becomes desirable that the edge beams be tensioned to a higher pre-stress than the slab itself. This paper examines the variation of prestress throughout the slab corresponding to the application of known levels of prestress around the boundary. The method involves taking an imaginary cut so as to separate the slab from the edge beams. So far as the slab is concerned an Airy stress function is proposed, so that stresses throughout the slab may be obtained direct1y as derivatives of this function. The stress function is adjusted so that the movements of the slab and the edge beams are the corners of the slab and at the mid points of its sides. A theory is developed for an ideal elastic material. The application of the theory is carried out on concrete slabs. Experimental and theoretical results are compared and a design procedure is proposed. However, the creep of concrete is important, the theory applies just after the prestress is transferred.</description><creator>Pang, Shui-Hin</creator><contributor>Jaeger, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Redistribution of prestress in concrete slabs reinforced with edge beams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w09k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712mb031</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bx54n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Among the many methods for measurement of frequency, there is a bridge circuit devised by Kennelly and Velander. The circuit of this bridge is shown in Figure 2. The advantage of this bridge over others involving Mutual Inductance, Self Inductance, Capacitance, and Resistance, is that the behaviour of this circuit is independent of impurities in capacitance. Furthermore, this bridge is particularly well adapted to use at low frequencies. However, it has one outstanding disadvantage in that it has a following balance condition. There is another point, too, which limits its practical usefulness. This is the presence of a self-inductance in the circuit, which is a disadvantage because accurate self inductors are more difficult to construct than resistors or capacitors of comparable accuracy. The purpose of this thesis then is to indicate how the Kennelly and Velander Bridge may be modified to remove the following balance condition, and to replace the self inductance by a resistance. Incidental to this work, all frequency bridges are carefully classified in a manner more comprehensive than has yet appeared in the literature on the subject. As a result of this classification, several new circuits are proposed.</description><creator>Berry, Verne Harrington.</creator><contributor>Watson, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>A modified Kennelly-Velander bridge for the measurement of low frequencies.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fv81w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx54n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fv825</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The most disturbing paradox in the world today is war. All men desire to live, yet every so often large sections of mankind strive to destroy each other in deadly combat. Although the causes for this unfortunate dilemma are manifold, and stem from various directions, I believe that among the most preponderant causes are those pertaining to irrational elements in man’s thinking and acting. In this thesis I have not ventured to consider any absolute criteria of what is rational and what is irrational, but have rather relied upon a comparison of certain relative merits of two systems of human adherence. These two systems are, respectively, magic, mysticism, and religion on the one hand, and science on the other. The former are here designated collectively as systematized unreason, while the latter is examined in its various aspects as the “scientific system.” [...]</description><creator>Black, Percy.</creator><contributor>Kellogg, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>Systematized unreason and science: a socio-psychological interpretation of magic, mysticism, religion, and science.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b189f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv825</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp474</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study, the properties of the logistic curve [equation in text] as a mathematical model for quantal response data are investigated. When k = 2, the logistic function is often appropriate as a response curve in bio-assay. With this in mind, maximum likelihood, minimum X^2 and generalized minimum X^2 estimates of β0 and β1 are discussed. When k &gt; 2 the logistic function is sometimes useful in representing situations involving factorial tables and estimates of the parameters β0, β1,…, βk are often desired.</description><creator>Horowitz, Eva</creator><contributor>Seshadri, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>The logistic curve and biological applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s067h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp474</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b653h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis the problem of wide-band matching will be discussed with special attention to antenna matching in the U.V.F. range. A method of attack is suggested and several examples worked out. The author does not claim to have produced anything original and unknown heretofore in circuit analysis. He can declare, however, that the bulk of the material was developed by himself and is neither a resume or a summary of previous work, treated somewhere else, unless this is explicitly stated and references are given. It seems to the author that he merely took the obvious step from single frequency matching to broadband matching. That he had to do this himself is due to the lack of literature on the subject. In spite of a thorough search in English and German technical papers, only very few were found with direct bearing on the problem. [...] The theoretical possibility of a perfect match over a band of frequencies has interested the author greatly, and an attempt at the most general solution is made at the end of the thesis, in Chapter V. [...]</description><creator>Bott, Raoul.</creator><contributor>Howes, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>The design of wide-band matching networks for U.H.F. antennae.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq67f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b653h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rm47z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies of the effects of jet fuel spillage on samples of bituminous concrete pavements are reported. Test samples were made from binders of asphalt, tar and blends of asphalt and tar. All binders were rubberized by adding varying quantities of nitrile, styrene and natural rubber. Changes in Marshall stability and flow values resulting from exposure to fuel were measured, relative to unexposed control specimens. Tar concrete mixes proved to be the most resistant to jet fuel attack, while the temperature history of the test specimens was shown to be an important factor. Measured glass transition temperatures obtained from DTA studies of some of the blended binders gave evidence that the blends were physical, or two-phase. The results of this study give quantitative support to the observed behaviour of prototype bituminous pavements subjected to jet fuel spillage.</description><creator>Elquesny, Moustafa M.</creator><contributor>Yong, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>The deterioration of bituminous concrete pavement due to jet fuel spillage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t247s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm47z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sk47b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When the isolated heart is perfused with a constant flow, the perfusion pressure (PI) can be considered to be the sum of those pressures required to overcome autoregulation (PA), critical closure (PCC) and the resistance of the relaxed vascular bed (PO). PA can be estimated from the difference between PI and the pressure obtained 10 seconds following a 30 second period of stop flow (PR). PA increases from 0 to 50 mm Hg with increasing flow. PR was found to be linearly related to flow with a positive pressure intercept on the pressure axis. This intercept was interpreted as PCC and varied between 10 and 25 mm Hg. PO = (PR – PCC), also increased with flow and the slope of this line is interpreted as the resistance of the vascular bed (RO) in the absence of autoregulation and critical closure; this line went essentially through the origin. It was found that when a square wave flow change was imposed, the ratio of the change in pressure to the change in flow correspond well to Ra. It is concluded that Ra is small and that in the physiological range PA predominates and prevents overperfusion of the heart. At lower flows PCC becomes significant and critical closure leads to an apparent increase in resistance.</description><creator>Yudin, Howard S.</creator><contributor>Palmer, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>The components of coronary vascular resistance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dw44d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sk47b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032618j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La plupart des gens connaissent Maurice Constantin-Weyer comme l’auteur d’Un homme se penche sur son passé. C’est ce livre qui lui valut le Prix Goncourt en 1928. A part ce livre dont l’histoire se déroule dans l’ouest du Canada, Constantin-Weyer a écrit une trentaine de livres. Parmi eux, il y a une quinzaine où le lecteur se trouve dans un milieu canadien. De ces livres l’auteur a consacré sept à l’histoire du Canada. Le premier livre historique à paraître fut Vers l’Ouest en 1922, suivi en 1925 de La Bourrasque et en 1927 de Cavelier de ua Salle. Les autres livres historiques qui parurent après le Prix Goncourt sont Champlain. Du sang sur la neige. Le voyage de Leif l’heureux, et La Croisière du jour sans fin. Partout dans ses livres canadiens l’écrivain témoigne son amour pour la nature. il aime surtout la neige, le froid, la lutte, avec les éléments. Pour lui. c’est l’action, le courage, et l’énergie qui comptent.[...]</description><creator>Bradford, Florence Emily.</creator><contributor>Woodhead, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>CONSTANTIN-WEYER, MAURICE, 1881-</subject><title>L’histoire du Canada dans l’oeuvre de Maurice Constantin-Weyer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn45x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032618j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs77b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Data from nine smoke sampling stations in the Montreal area showed high smoke concentration (~2 Coh) for 5-15% of the time during three winter months. A tenth station in the central downtown area showed highconcentrations 50% of the tille, with a mean value of 2.2 Coh. In this downtown area, the rate of smoke production often appeared more daminant than the meteorological conditions in detennining the pollution level.[...]</description><creator>Yap, David</creator><contributor>Gunn, K. L. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>meteorlogy</subject><title>Air pollution and vertical temperature distribution over Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fv83f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs77b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827f84c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The absolute auditory intensity threshold of the cat was determined using a two-lever operant tracking procedure. In this procedure, developed by D. S. Blough, the S responds according to whether or not the stimulus is perceived, and depending on the response, the stimulus intensity is increased or decreased. Thus, S charts his own threshold. The method, which has several advantages over other procedures, proved to be successful in this study.</description><creator>Wise, Shirley M.</creator><contributor>Gannon, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Human Communications Disorders.</subject><title>The determination of auditory thresholds in cats by an operant tracking procedure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg802.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827f84c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752m01g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work reported in this thesis was part of the general wartime plan to investigate unexploited sources of vegetable oil in Canada. In spite of a potential supply of 2000 tons annually, according to an estimate for Canada in 1943, very little effort has been devoted to Canadian tall oil. This oil is a by-product of sulfate pulp mills and of the seven such mills in Canada only one or two are making an attempt to market tall oil. Its use is discouraged by its complex nature and in the unrefined grades the color and odour are additional handicaps. [...] However, the oil has a variable nature and there is a need for evaluating present and possible Canadian tall oils by a careful investigation of their properties and composition. The constituents of tall oil are divided into three main groups, fatty acids, resin acids and unsaponifiable materials. In order to get a broad view of Canadian tall oils it was decided to determine the ratio of these components along with other common chemical data. This information would provide a means for a rough comparison with the oils produced elsewhere and possibly give some indication of the utility of the Canadian oils. As a second objective, a preliminary investigation of the fatty acids was selected. [...]</description><creator>Burch, George Nelson Blair.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Canadian tall oils and their fatty acids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w18s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752m01g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nv074</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When an individual lands from a step to the ground, his antigravity muscles must oppose and terminate his downwards movement. It is often assumed that lengthening of involved postural muscles generates functional stretch reflexes that automatically match the strength of contraction of these muscles with the loads imposed. This contention was examined in the gastrocnemius and soleus muscles. The latency of the functional stretch reflex, as described by Hammond, Merton, and Sutton (1956) in the arm, was first determined in the gastrocnemius - soleus muscles. Electromyographic activity in these muscles, and the forces exerted by the foot, were then examined during steps to the ground, repetitive hops, and sudden, unexpected falls.</description><creator>Watt, Douglas G.</creator><contributor>Jones, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Modes of control in some antigravity muscles in man</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt020.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nv074</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dz472</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Historical background of the measuring, partitioning and correlating of resistance was reviewed, and the theory behind the indirect estimation of upstream resistance explained. The oscillator with volume plethysmograph enabled study of volume history effect on lower (obtained from a tracheal catheter) and total pulmonary resistance. An adaptation of the upstream resistance estimation was used. Each study was done both pre and post atropine. Each test showed inflation resistance greater than deflation. This hysteresis was greatly reduced after atropine. It was considered due to bronchomotor tone. Lower pulmonary resistance was found to be very low and much more sensitive to airway change than total pulmonary resistance, and showed an increase at TLC. Inflation partial expiratory flow volume curves were considered the best indicators of bronchodilation particularly due to their simplicity. All tests showed that airway calibre depended on the balance between elastic recoil pressure and smooth muscle tone.</description><creator>Vincent, Norma J.</creator><contributor>Macklem, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Influence of tracheobronchial smooth muscle on the mechanical properties of the lung in normal man</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c1513.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz472</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dq366</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Maxwell used conjugate functions to solve problems in electrostatics. His method depended on a guessing of the suitable complex transformation for any given problem. In 1867 Christoffel, and in 1869 Schwarz discussed a general theorem in Transformations which became finally known as the Schwarz-Christoffel Theorem. [...] In this paper the essential elements of the function theory and the required electrostatics background are briefly developed or discussed and it is shown why and how the one may be applied to the other. Proofs of the invariance of charge, equipotentials, and lines of force under complex transformation, which are not usually found in the texts, have been supplied. A number of problems illustrating the use of the complex potential and the complex transformation are solved. The Schwarz-Christoffel Theorem is stated and a fairly detailed discussion of its application made, after which problems illustrating its use are worked out. Lastly methods of extending the solution to sylinders of curved cross-section as occur in papers by the authors quoted above are considered. The whole subject has been well known for many years and no attempt to add anything new has been undertaken. However, the solutions and treatment of a number of the problems are the writers own.</description><creator>Burrow, Martin D.</creator><contributor>Rosenthall, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>TRANSFORMATIONS (IN MATHEMATICS)</subject><subject>ELECTROSTATICS.</subject><title>The application of conformal mapping to the solution of electrostatic problems.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb56h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dq366</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602409f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments were carried out to determine the effect of factors, other than vitamin C, on the development of odontoblast cells in the guinea pig incisor tooth. Using the “odontoblast” method of vitamin C bioassay, it was shown that guinea pigs may be assigned to experiment at a fixed initial age or a fixed initial weight, the odontoblast development remaining unaffected. Odontoblast development was not different whether the guinea pigs were penned and fed individually or in groups of two. A natural, an artificial and a fortified source of vitamin C were assayed simultaneously by the “odontoblast” and by the “increase in weight” methods of vitamin C bioassay. The “odontoblast” method was found to afford a bioassay accuracy greater than that afforded by the “increase in weight” method. Evidence was produced to support the belief that natural food sources of vitamin C are superior to synthetic vitamin C in the stimulation of odontoblast development.</description><creator>Burton, Barbara W.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>Some factors affecting the bioassay of vitamin C by the odontoblast method.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sw98k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602409f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11250</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>