<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:22:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pf64z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A three-dimensional, phenomenological, tensorial, isotropic, damage model is developed in the framework of continuum damage mechanics for materials whose behavior is governed by elastic deformation coupled with damage. The model was then extended to include isotropic damage for anisotropic materials, as well as rate-dependency behavior caused by damage evolution. The shortcomings of the commonly used scalar variable, as representative of isotropic damage are discussed. It is shown that isotropic damage is best represented by an isotropic tensor of rank four. The damage evolution equations are postulated using strain tensor invariants, based on decomposition of strain energy. The model simulates well the results of static and dynamic uniaxial tension tests on quasiisotropic laminated graphite-epoxy obtained in this study and results, from literature, of uniaxial compression tests on quartzite rock. To determine the material parameters used in the model and to validate the model, a set of material and structural tests, testing a laminate containing a hole, were performed under static and dynamic loading conditions. A tensile version of the Hopkinson bar, suitable for testing of laminated composite materials, is developed to perform dynamic tests. A pulse duration of 200--250 microseconds and peak strain rates of up to 350 s--1 are obtained. Tests performed on a quasi-isotropic lay-up of graphite-epoxy show good repeatability. Comparison of Hopkinson bar tests results with results of tests performed at a quasi-static rate on a hydraulic test machine shows the rate-dependency of this lay-up of graphite-epoxy. Tensile strength and fracture strain are found to be higher for dynamic testing. The model was evaluated for structural analysis, by implementing the model into a finite element code and analysing a laminate containing a hole. Two techniques are investigated in evaluating the model for structural analysis: stress limiter and mesh limiter. The model is found to be objective with respect to the mesh size. The predicted failure loads using both techniques conform well to the experiments and to the results obtained using one of the existing models.</description><creator>Eskandari, H. (Hamid)</creator><contributor>Nemes, James A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Rate-dependent continuum damage modeling of composite materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw350.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pf64z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021g975</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is made of two parts. In the first part, we study the rheology and nonequilibrium structure of fluids using the nonequilibrium ensemble method and a computational framework is laid toward a theory of steady state. The grand canonical partition function is computed analytically and used to study a gas mixture under shear. The dependence of the viscometric functions on the shear rate is presented and an exact constitutive relation between the kinetic-stress and the generalized potentials is obtained. The system was found to exhibit a shear thinning behavior. The Monte Carlo method in combination with generalized hydrodynamics was used to study the shear rate dependence of viscosity and the nonequilibrium structure of simple liquids. The fluid exhibited shear thinning, and a generalization of the Ree-Eyring equation was derived. This formula accurately fits the results of nonequilibrium molecular dynamics results and the relaxation time is computed from the theory. A set of self consistent integral equations is proposed for polyatomic fluids, which could be used for studying equilibrium and nonequilibrium molecular fluids. The prediction of these equations compared positively with simulation results for a number of molecular models. In the second part of this thesis, a kinetic theory for granular material is formulated. It is shown that the concept of excluded volume in phase space is crucial in explaining granular behavior. A thermodynamic formalism for fluidized granular matter was developed and the concept of granular temperature was elucidated and an equation of state was developed which gives the correct observed behavior. The density profile of a granular medium under tapping is computed and compared with experimental results. The viscosity computed in the theory also exhibits qualitatively correct behavior when compared with the viscosity of granular matter in that it remains almost constant over a density interval and then steeply increases with the density. The present theory also predicts that granular matter is dilatant as experimentally known.</description><creator>Farhat, Hikmat.</creator><contributor>Eu, Byung Chan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Studies in computational methods for statistical mechanics of fluids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k854.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g975</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb13g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies the human rights philosophy presented during the first productions of Shakespeare's plays, putting it in touch with that reflected in United Nations human rights law and the political theory of John Rawls. Its opening chapter discusses twentieth-century scholarship exemplary of the criticism relevant to human rights ideas in Shakespeare. The sixteenth-century historical context, so emphatically identified by historians with the institution of modern freedom, is kept in sight throughout, and provides, with the cultural context (especially the semantic context), the key to detailed explications, of four plays: King John, Much Ado About Nothing, Hamlet and All's Well That Ends Well. Interpreted by these means, the first two plays are seen to have enacted, at the time of their first performances, the religious strife that ironically gave birth both to the ideal of freedom of conscience and ideological complications restricting its implementation. The latter plays unfolded arguments concerning the relationship between epistemology and freedom of conscience. The questions addressed in these four plays range from the relationship between social stability, moral values, and the practicability of freedom of conscience to the criteria whereby coercion and abuse of freedom of conscience may be distinguished from legitimate exercise of freedom of expression. The characteristics of epistemologies enhancing the implementation of freedom of conscience and the educational process that promotes the moral attributes and social conditions necessary for the adoption of these are delineated. The freedom of conscience theory the plays proposed for those members of their first audiences attuned to its metaphoric language is remarkably thought-provoking as regards current challenges in human rights philosophy and law, and reinforces the argument that literature, and in particular theatre, have vital roles in social change and intellectual development.</description><creator>Earnshaw, Felicity.</creator><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Human rights in literature.</subject><title>Shakespeare and freedom of conscience</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt471.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb13g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161797j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The malignant phenotype, by definition, is composed of two facets, consisting of the tumor's ability to proliferate as well as its ability to invade the surrounding normal tissue. We propose that in malignant gliomas the protein kinase C (PKC) family of enzymes, which has been shown to be overexpressed in these tumours, plays a pivotal role in both their proliferative and invasive capacity. In the first genes of experiments where the expression of the alpha isoform of PKC was significantly decreased following antisense oligonucleotide treatment, we were able to report the novel finding that this inhibition not only inhibits glioma proliferation in a dose-dependent manner but that this inhibition of growth was the consequence of programmed cell death (1). In the second focus of this thesis, we addressed the postulate that the high PKC activity present in glioblastoma cells may also contribute to the invasive nature of this tumor by modulating the expression of proteolytic enzymes, the matrix metalloproteinases, (MMPs). In contrast to previous studies implicating MMP-9, our data demonstrated that MMP-2 was the metalloproteinase most closely associated with glioma invasion. Furthermore, we were also able to report that the regulation of MMP-2, and thus glioma invasion, could be modulated by PKC (2). In summary, this work presents evidence to support a role for PKC in both the proliferative and invasive phenotypes which characterize malignant gliomas. The translational nature of this research is readily illustrated by the emergence of clinical trials in which PKC and MMPs constitute the principal chemotherapeutic targets.</description><creator>Dooley, Nora P.</creator><contributor>Yong, Voon Wee (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>The proliferative &amp; invasive phenotypes of malignant gliomas : regulation by protein kinase C (PKC)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n03q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161797j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj07f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis concerns the cultural construction and mechanics of violence, domination, and survival under a Southeast Asian totalitarian regime. It entails an examination of the modern character of violence and domination in Myanmar (Burma) through the inscription of State power upon the bodies of Burmans and via the ramifications of the regime's alliance with the drug lords upon the urban struggle for survival. At times of extreme domination, fear, and degradation, very little space exists for psychological and physical resistance. Burmans seek escape from this situation by withdrawing into domains characterized by denial, numbness, and temporary madness. My concern is with the lived experience of totalitarianism, the way that individuals respond differently according to a prior series of lived experiences, and the particular idioms drawn upon to construct survival strategies. An important culturally constructed strategy of survival in Myanmar entails the detaching of agency from the body while the mind "flies" to freedom. This strategy has a long history not only in Burmese, but also in other Southeast Asian histories, myths, and legends. Just as Burmese wizards fly to a mythical landscape in the foothills of the Himalayas when released from their physical bodies, so too do heroin addicts, prostitutes, psychiatric patients, and the urban poor flee to Burmese fantasylands to escape the domination of the military regime. This strategy, one of many adopted by urban residents, denies the State the final prize it so desperately craves: the willing participation of Burmans in a military society, the complete internalization of totalitarian ideology such that no other ideologies can exist and no space is left for their creation and negotiation. In the conclusion I argue that the regime is aware that it has faded in this task. I also examine the possibility that the existence of multiple Burmese worlds or realities, in conjunction with a strong belief in the miraculous may offer new ground for research into the trauma of survivors of violence and terror. The construction of madness, death, and reanimation in Burmese culture, grounds particular survival strategies in logical, hopeful, and perhaps curative, rationalities.</description><creator>Skidmore, Monique.</creator><contributor>Lock, Margaret (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Burma -- Politics and government -- 1988-</subject><subject>Violence -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Burma -- Social conditions.</subject><subject>Totalitarianism -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Medical anthropology -- Burma.</subject><title>Flying through a skyful of lies : survival strategies and the politics of fear in urban Myanmar (Burma)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx49b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj07f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526d997</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of the mechanical energy budget is analyzed in relation to the small viscosity behaviour of an idealized model of the wind-driven circulation. This is addressed theoretically and numerically in part one. In part two the connection to the real ocean is made through an analysis of the energy source with real data. The theoretical arguments based on the QG energy equation show that, with the assumption that the maximum velocities occur at inertial length scales or smaller, a Sverdrup interior is consistent with the small Rossby number assumption only when the frictional parameters exceed critical values. For frictional parameters smaller than these values, valid solutions must decrease the energy source. This is possible for non-Sverdrup solutions since the energy source is dependent on the solution. The numerical study is focused on insensitivity to frictional parameters in the nonlinear Stommel-Munk model. Dependence of the multiple solutions of the steady state model on the boundary layer Reynolds number, Re, are investigated by varying the eddy viscosity for fixed wind forcing. An important finding is the tendency to decrease the energy source for solutions that are nonsymmetric about the centre latitude. Antisymmetric solutions display the opposite behaviour, and diverge more quickly with increasing Re. Also interesting is the tendency for the total energy and transport to become less sensitive to eddy viscosity with increasing Re. The robustness of the results to dynamic boundary condition, symmetry and strength of wind stress, time dependence and bottom friction are tested. A significant, though not surprising, result is that the no slip condition leads to high Rossby number in the boundary layer at much lower Re than for the free slip condition. It is demonstrated that recent advances in altimetry measurements allow for a reasonable estimate of the rate of mechanical energy transfer from the atmospheric winds to the surface geostrophic velocity integrated over large regions. (Local values are highly uncertain due to the very large uncertainty in the marine geoid undulation field.) The feasibility and methodology of a quantitative uncertainty estimate is also demonstrated. The estimate of the energy source term allows comparison of the theoretical and numerical results with the real ocean.</description><creator>Scott, Robert Bruce, 1965-</creator><contributor>Straub, David N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Geostrophic energetics and the small viscosity behaviour of an idealized ocean circulation model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h03k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d997</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz38p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In vitro culture techniques are widely used in potato for rapid production of specific pathogen tested plantlets and microtubers, which are essential for seed certification programs. The limited calcium (Ca) uptake in vitro promotes physiological disorders in many micropropagated species including potato. Factors that may affect Ca uptake by potato plantlets, including cations, osmotic potential, and boron (B) were examined. The possibility of improving microtuber yield by low pH shock or successive harvests, which stimulated greenhouse potato production, were also investigated. Ca uptake by cvs. Norland and Bintje potato plantlets grown on modified Murashige and Skoog (MS, 1962) media was enhanced by diluting the total macroelements in the nutrient medium, except Ca. Increasing Ca:specific cation ratios, by lowering either NH 4, Mg or K, had little effect on Ca uptake by Norland plantlets. At equivalent Ca:total cation, Ca uptake was promoted further when the total macroelement concentration was reduced by half than when the Ca level was doubled (from 3 to 6 mM). This suggested that the increase in the osmotic potential of the medium had a great impact on Ca uptake, probably by affecting the root pressure. B contamination from impurities in the nutrient chemical components always occurred. The addition of the recommended H3BO 3 level of 0.1 mM (1.08 ppm) or more (0.3 mM) to the medium decreased Ca content of leaves and shoots in Norland but not Bintje, while addition of only 25% of this level was sufficient to provide plantlets with adequate B tissue concentration without compromising normal growth. Macroelement dilution along with Ca addition, and lower B levels than commonly used in MS (0.1 mM) are recommended for optimal Ca uptake in potato and possibly other plant species. Microtuber yield was not improved by a low pH shock. Adjusting microtuberization medium pH to less than 5.7 (3.5, 4.3 or 5.2), prior to autoclaving, reduced microtuber number and/or weight</description><creator>Abdulnour, Jihad.</creator><contributor>Barthakur, N. N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Calcium.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Micropropagation.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Nutrient manipulation in potato plantlets and microtubers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430646j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz38p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sx61v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spatiotemporal processes occur in many areas of earth sciences and engineering. However, most of the available theoretical tools and techniques of space-time daft processing have been designed to operate exclusively in time or in space, and the importance of spatiotemporal variability was not fully appreciated until recently. To address this problem, a systematic framework of spatiotemporal random field (S/TRF) models for geoscience/engineering applications is presented and developed in this thesis. The space-tune continuity characterization is one of the most important aspects in S/TRF modelling, where the space-time continuity is displayed with experimental spatiotemporal variograms, summarized in terms of space-time continuity hypotheses, and modelled using spatiotemporal variogram functions. Permissible spatiotemporal covariance/variogram models are addressed through permissibility criteria appropriate to spatiotemporal processes. The estimation of spatiotemporal processes is developed in terms of spatiotemporal kriging techniques. Particular emphasis is given to the singularity analysis of spatiotemporal kriging systems. The impacts of covariance, functions, trend forms, and data configurations on the singularity of spatiotemporal kriging systems are discussed. In addition, the tensorial invariance of universal spatiotemporal kriging systems is investigated in terms of the space-time trend. The conditional simulation of spatiotemporal processes is proposed with the development of the sequential group Gaussian simulation techniques (SGGS), which is actually a series of sequential simulation algorithms associated with different group sizes. The simulation error is analyzed with different covariance models and simulation grids. The simulated annealing technique honoring experimental variograms, is also proposed, providing a way of conditional simulation without the covariance model fitting which is prerequisite for most simulation algorithms. The proposed techniques were first applied for modelling of the pressure system in a carbonate reservoir, and then applied for modelling of springwater contents in the Dyle watershed. The results of these case studies as well as the theory suggest that these techniques are realistic and feasible.</description><creator>Luo, Xiaochun.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><subject>Hydrology.</subject><title>Spatiotemporal stochastic models for earth science and engineering applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc38g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sx61v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x432</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Weak organic acids and/or their salts were tested as soil washing or flushing agents for the ex- or in-situ remediation of soils polluted by heavy metals. Three soils naturally with heavy metals were used for the tea. The three soils were characterized as a clay loam, loam and sandy clay loam. Their organic matter, pH, saturated hydraulic conductivity, cation exchange capacity, particle density and heavy metal contents were also characterized. The different retention forms of heavy metals in all 3 soils were studied by sequential extraction. The clay loam was contaminated with Cr, Hg, Mn and Pb while the loam and sandy clay loam were contaminated with Cd, Pb, Cu and Zn. Weak organic adds and/or their salts and chelating agents (EDTA and DTPA) were used at different pH, levels of concentration and leaching time in batch experiments to establish optimum conditions for maximum removal of heavy metals from the three soils. Citrate and tartarate were found to be quite effective, in leaching heavy metals from these soils. The rate of leaching of heavy metals from soils with citrate, tartarate and EDTA was modeled using two-reaction model at a constant pH and temperature. Three contaminated soils of different textures were flushed in a column at optimum pH with a salt of weak organic acids, namely, citrate, tartarate, citrate+oxalate or a chelating agent such as EDTA and DTPA. The citrate and tartarate (ammonium salts) were found to be quite effective in removing heavy metals from the three contaminated soils while leaching little macronutrients and improving the soil's structure. An in-situ soil remediation simulation was also successfully tested using the sandy clay loam at large scale level in a tub (plastic container) using citrate as a flushing liquid. EDTA and DTPA were effective in removing the heavy metals except for Hg, but these strong chelating agents extracted important quantities of macronutrients from the soil. These chelating agents are also known to pollute the soil by being adsorbed on the soil particles. A bioremediation process was developed using the fungus Aspergillus niger to produce weak organic acids (mainly citrate and partly oxalate depending on pH) for the leaching of heavy metals from contaminated soils. The fungus was cultivated on the surface of the three contaminated soils for 15 days at 30°C and a pH ≤ 4 to enhance the production of citric acid rather than oxalic acid which hinders Pb leaching. By extrapolating the result, the three contaminated soils were expected to be sufficiently remediated to meet the A category (Quebec clean up criteria for cleaning soils contaminated by heavy metals) after 20 to 25 days of leaching using this technique. Finally, the leachate, collected following the soil remediation using weak organic acids and/or their salts, EDTA and DTPA was treated effectively using granular activated carbon.</description><creator>Wasay, Syed A.</creator><contributor>Barrington, Suzelle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Soil pollution.</subject><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Heavy metals -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Bioremediation.</subject><title>Bioremediation of soils polluted by heavy metals using organic acids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd810.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x432</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj090</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis is to develop a binocular controller for artificial vision systems, based on principles used in biological binocular control. The controller is a symmetrical, two-sided system utilizing feedback across the midline. In spite of its simple topology, the controller allows for the integration of various aspects of eye movements, which are often modelled as independent systems. In addition, the controller topology naturally lends itself to sensory-fusion. The controller was applied to an artificial vision system and its 3-D tracking performance was evaluated. Eye (camera) movements consist of an appropriate mix of slow (tracking) and rapid (reorienting) motions. This is the first implementation of an artificial vision control system which: (1) Controls two eyes independently, in 2-D, for target motion in one plane. (2) Provides integrated conjugate and vergence coordination. (3) Provides integrated slow and fast operating modalities. (4) Has the intrinsic ability to hold gaze in the absence of a target. The controller is also well suited for extensions to coordinate multiple platforms (e.g. eyes on mobile head) using a conceptually simple motor-error control scheme. Its sensory-fusion properties make the controller receptive to the inclusion of a VOR system, essential in mobile robots.</description><creator>Wagner, Ross.</creator><contributor>Galiana, H. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Binocular coordination : providing stable tracking and rapid reorientation using a bilateral controller inspired by nature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v643.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj090</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv35b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The diastereoselective synthesis of phosphorothioates and methylphosphonates has been investigated. It has been found that indole is a good leaving group, and that it can form a stable indolephosphorine and can be stereospecifically substituted by a nucleoside in the presence of DBU. Chiral indole-oxazaphosphorines 31, 39, 44, 56 were synthesized and their reactivities were investigated. The cyano derivative 56 turned out to be a good chiral precursor in the diastereoselective synthesis of a T-T phosphorothioate dimer 65, with a diastereomeric excess larger than 96%. The reaction of cyano, monomer 63 on solid support was investigated. It was found that alkylphosphonate 64 was obtained as the major product, rather than the expected phosphorothioate 65.* A novel internucleoside coupling reagent 87 was developed for the synthesis of methylphosphonates, in which the indole group can be replaced by a nucleoside within several minutes in the presence of DBU. Several chiral auxiliaries were tested for the stereoselective synthesis of methylphosphonates. A diastereomerically enriched monoester 104 (66% de) was synthesized.* *Please refer to dissertation for diagrams.</description><creator>Wang, Jian-Chao, 1966-</creator><contributor>Just, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>The stereoselective synthesis of phosphorothioates and methylphosphonates /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c74k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv35b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h35r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A major contribution of research in workplace literacy has been to explore the part that writing plays in the knowledge-making practices of various professional groups. While such enquiry has revealed that writing is essential to the creation and use of specialized knowledge in the professions, it also points to the need to see writing as part of a larger network of symbolic activity. Researchers have shown that practitioners in certain professions---for example, engineering and architecture---do not produce knowledge solely through the social negotiations of language; rather, acts of writing and reading merge with other symbol-based practices in larger processes of knowledge-making. A promising area for further research in this regard is the field of economics, where knowledge is constituted through a discourse combining language, mathematics, and visual forms such as graphs. The study reported here examines a particular site of such knowledge-making: the Ottawa head office of the Bank of Canada. Employing an ethnographic methodology that included interviews, informal conversations, on-site observations, reading protocols, tape-recorded meetings, and text analysis, the study examines an ongoing, writing-intensive activity known in the Bank as the "monetary policy process," in which the institution's economists generate knowledge about Present and probable future conditions in the Canadian economy and use this knowledge in formulating and implementing policy. The central question guiding the study is this: what is the nature of the intellectual collaboration that enables the Bank's economists to transform large amounts of statistical data into focused written knowledge about the Canadian economy and then use this knowledge in making decisions about monetary policy? The study shows that the "monetary policy process" can be viewed as a communal activity in which the economists employ a set of written genres in combination with mathematical models---most importantly, the computer-run Quarterly Projection Model---to carry out their work. The joint, intermeshed use of writing and modelling gives rise to a distinctive pattern of social interaction and a style of collective thinking that allow the economists to produce specialized knowledge about the economy and apply this knowledge to decision-making.</description><creator>Smart, Graham.</creator><contributor>Dias, Patrick (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Business writing -- Research.</subject><subject>Monetary policy -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Bank of Canada.</subject><title>An ethnographic study of knowledge-making in a central bank : the interplay of writing and economic modelling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s1843.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h35r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623f329</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research in several domains has revealed that when individuals are asked to estimate the probability that their judgments are correct, they reveal an overconfidence effect. Judgments produced in decision environments such as psychodiagnosis, which are by their nature ambiguous and complex, appear to be most vulnerable to overconfidence. By implication, this phenomenon threatens the validity of clinical judgment and subjects clients to risks of flawed diagnoses and unsuitable treatments. In an effort to identify variables implicated in judgment confidence and overconfidence, this study examined the relationship between four different inferential biases (dispositionalism, confirmationism, truncated data search, and narrow problem formulation) and diagnostic confidence in the context of a psychological assessment task. A second aspect of this study examined the effect of clinical experience on psychodiagnostic confidence. Thirty-six clinicians (18 experienced professionals and 18 clinical trainees) were individually presented a written client casefile, which was segmented and serially presented, to read and clinically interpret aloud. Analyses of participants' verbal protocols revealed that one of the four inferential biases studied (i.e., dispositionalism) accounted for a significant proportion of the variance in psychodiagnostic confidence scores. The author concludes that other clinician variables likely moderate the relationship between particular heuristics and judgment confidence. Regarding the second hypothesis, the data revealed no difference between experienced clinicians and clinical trainees in the degrees of psychodiagnostic confidence manifested in their verbal protocols. The author proposes that effective remedies to overconfidence begin in training programs that lead students through problem-solving experiences that can invalidate facile, premature, and dubious diagnostic judgments. The author delineates a number of strategies that may be used by educators to achieve this end.</description><creator>Smith, J. David.</creator><contributor>Dumont, Frank (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Clinical psychology.</subject><subject>Mental illness -- Diagnosis.</subject><title>Confidence in psychodiagnosis : a study of clinicians' judgement confidence in a psychological assessment task as a function of reliance on four inferential heuristics and clinical experience</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn51g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f329</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hd928</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conventional computer speech recognition systems use models of speech acoustics and the language of the recognition task in order to perform recognition. For all but trivial recognition tasks, sub-word units are modeled, typically phonemes. Recognizing words then requires a pronunciation dictionary ( PD) to specify how each word is pronounced in terms of the units modeled. Even if the acoustic modeling component is perfect, the recognizer will still be prone to misrecognition, most often because the speaker can use a pronunciation other than that in the PD. This different pronunciation may be due to the speaker being a non-native speaker of the language being recognized, having 'mispronounced' the word, coarticulatory effects, recognizer errors in phoneme hypothesization, or any combination of these. One way to overcome these misrecognitions is to use a dynamic PD, able to acquire new pronunciations for words as they are encountered and misrecognized. The thesis examines the following questions: can automated methods be found that produce reliable alternate pronunciations? If so, does augmenting a PD (which originally contains only canonical pronunciations) with these alternate pronunciations lead to improved recognizer performance? It shows that using even simple methods, average reductions in word error rate of at least 45% are possible, even with speakers who are not native speakers of the recognition task language.</description><creator>Snow, Charles.</creator><contributor>De Mori, Renato (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Improving continuous speech recognition with automatic multiple pronunciation support</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv49f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hd928</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053h782</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A parameterization that describes in-cloud oxidation of S(IV) by hydrogen peroxide and ozone, has been developed for use in large scale models. This parameterization, which is based on the reaction rate equations and basic cloud characteristics, is an explicit function of the concentration of ambient chemical species and some gross cloud parameters. Comparisons of the parameterization scheme with a well-established three-dimensional cloud chemistry model, and also with the cloud chemistry module of a regional model have been used to formulate and test this parameterization scheme. Results show that the parameterization agrees with the 3-D chemistry model very well and that the parameterization holds considerable potential for application in large-scale models. Preliminary application in a regional climate model confirms that the parameterization is able to improve the agreement of the mass budget and spectrum distribution of sulphate aerosol with observations.</description><creator>Song, Qingyuan.</creator><contributor>Leighton, Henry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A parameterization of in-cloud sulphate production /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg60r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h782</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v35g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The evolution of a long-lived mesovortex and its transformation into a tropical storm are studied by a three dimensional mesoscale model. The major aspects of the work are: (1) to demonstrate the mesoscale predictability of a long-lived mesoscale convective system (MCS) from a mid-level vortex over land to a tropical storm over ocean, (2) to understand the processes involved in the transformation of a mid-level continental vortex into a tropical storm, and (3) to perform sensitivity experiments to assess the impact of model physics on an idealized simulation. The major conclusions are: The 90-h real-data simulation shows that the mesoscale model reproduces very well much of the meso-beta-structures and the evolution of the long-lived MCS. These include the development and dissipation of the continental mesovortex, the initiation of a new MCS both in time and in space, the genesis of a surface mesolow over the warm Gulf Stream water, the track and the deepening of the surface cyclone into a "tropical storm", the maintenance of a mid-level mesovortex system, and the propagation of a large-scale cold front with respect to the surface cyclone. The simulation also shows that the mid-level mesovortex provides persistent convergence at its southern periphery for the continued convective development, whereas the convectively enhanced low-level flow increases surface energy fluxes over the warm water causing further conditional instability. Such feedback processes lead to the rapid deepening of the "tropical storm". An idealized simulation was performed to eliminate the possible influence of the cold frontal system on the genesis of the tropical storm. The initial conditions resemble the basic structure of the subtropical high in the real-data case, but without the embedded frontal system. The simulation reproduces almost all of the essential features in the real-data simulation. In particular, the eye-like warm core structure of the tropical storm is well simulated. By decomposing the vertical relative vorticity into the curvature vorticity and the shear vorticity, it is shown that the amplification of a low-level vortex after 36 h arises mainly from the increase of curvature vorticity. The quasi-Lagrangian theta budget calculation shows that the descending motion in the center of the surface cyclone contributes to the formation of the warm core at 800 hPa. The results of sensitivity experiments demonstrate the impact of model physics on the idealized simulation. Using the Betts-Miller scheme, we showed that the model fails to simulate the multiple-episodes of convective activity which are present in observational studies of tropical cyclogenesis and in the simulation using the Kain-Fritsch scheme. We further found that the surface latent heat fluxes represent a dominant factor in the production of CAPE to maintain the persistent convection. Finally, we discussed the cumulative cooling effect by long-wave radiation on the destabilization of the environment of the storm.</description><creator>Bao, Ning, 1961-</creator><contributor>Zhang, Da-Lin (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Yau, M. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A numerical investigation of the transformation of a long-lived mesovortex into a tropical storm /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795943q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v35g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m837f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High output of prostaglandins (PGs) are the hallmark of inflammatory and immune reactions. A rate-limiting step in the production of PGs is the presence of the enzyme cyclooxygenase (COX). COX exists as two isoforms: COX-1 which is constitutively expressed in most cells and COX-2 which is inducible by LPS, proinflammatory cytokines and other stimuli in cells involved in inflammation. The objective of this study was to determine the effect of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs and proinflammatory cytokines on COX-2 expression in human macrophages. COX-2 specific (NS-398) and non-specific (aspirin, indomethacin and naproxen) inhibitors showed no effect on COX mRNA and protein expression induced by LPS. In contrast, the drugs markedly inhibited COX activity as measured by the accumulation of PGE2. The induction of COX-2 mRNA expression by LPS was rapid and sustained. However, LPS only transiently stimulated the transcription of COX-2 gene and activation of the transcription factor NF-kappaB. LPS stimulated the release of IL-1beta and TNF-alpha but these cytokines had no autocrine effect on the transcriptional or post-transcriptional regulation of COX-2. The presence of LPS was essential for the maintenance of high levels of long-lived COX-2 mRNA. As IFN-gamma is a major macrophage activating factor, we determined the role of this cytokine on COX-2 expression induced by exogenous IL-1beta. IFN-gamma-primed macrophages showed significantly lower levels of COX-2 mRNA, protein and PGE2 production compared to non-primed cells. IFN-gamma specifically decreased the transcriptional activation of COX-2 gene by IL-1beta but not by LPS without affecting the rate of mRNA decay. These results demonstrate that sustained production of PGE2 by macrophages in an inflammatory milieu can occur through the stabilization of COX-2 mRNA and revealed a role for IFN-gamma as an anti-inflammatory cytokine counteracting the expression of COX-2. A better understanding of COX-2 regulation will</description><creator>Barrios-Rodiles, Miriam.</creator><contributor>Chadee, Kris (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Rheumatoid arthritis -- Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>Cyclooxygenase 2 -- Inhibitors.</subject><subject>Macrophages.</subject><subject>Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory agents.</subject><title>Regulation of Cyclooxygenase-2 expression in human macrophages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z115.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m837f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk67w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Apolipoproteins play a central role in controlling the plasma metabolism of cholesterol- and triglyceride-rich lipoproteins, and in regulating their levels. Plasma concentrations of apolipoproteins, as well as their relative distribution on different lipoprotein fractions are determined by their rates of production and catabolism. In order to investigate the plasma kinetics of these proteins in normolipidemic and dyslipidemic individuals, an endogenous labeling procedure was set up, in which a primed constant (12 h) infusion of deuterium-labeled leucine is administered to fasted study subjects. Fractional rate of appearance of newly-synthesized, stable isotope-enriched, apolipoprotein in plasma pools is determined by gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS). Residence times (RT) are derived from tracer to tracee ratios using SAAM II computer software, and transport rates (TR) are calculated from residence times and pool sizes (measured by ELISAs). Two kinetic studies were conducted using this procedure. In the first, plasma kinetics of apolipoprotein (apo) C-III and apoE were simultaneously investigated in normolipidemic (NL) subjects (n = 5), hypertriglyceridemic (HTG) patients (pts.) (n = 5) and in pts. (n = 2) with type III (TypIII) hyperlipoproteinemia (both groups of patients having reduced catabolism of very low-density lipoprotein (VLDL) apoB-100). Elevated total plasma and VLDL apoC-III concentrations in HTG and TypIII pts., although associated with lower rates of apoC-III catabolism, were mainly due to significantly increased rates of apoC-III production (plasma apoC-III TR (mean +/- SE): (NL) 2.05 +/- 0.22, (HTG) 4.90 +/- 0.81 ( P &lt; 0.01), and (TypIII) 8.78 mg.kg-1.d -1; VLDL apoC-III TR: (NL) 1.35 +/- 0.23, (HTG) 5.35 +/- 0.85 (P &lt; 0.01), and (TypIII) 7.40 mg.kg-1 .d-1). Elevated total plasma and VLDL apoE concentrations in HTG and particularly in TypIII pts. were associated with increased VLDL apoE RT (0.21 +/- 0.02, 0.46 +/- 0.05, and 1.21</description><creator>Batal, Rami.</creator><contributor>Davignon, Jean (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Kinetics of apolipoproteins in plasma of normolipidemic and dyslipidemic subjects : an endogenous labeling study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t3739.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk67w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9998397</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In today's competitive environment, it is necessary to deliver products on time and within budget. Unfortunately, design projects have been plagued by severe cost and schedule overruns. This problem persists in spite of the significant advances that have been made in design technology over the last two decades. In most of the cases, the problem of overruns is due to poor estimation. The search for a solution has become even more pressing in the present era of shrinking product cycle times. Driven primarily by this need, this thesis presents new effort estimation models. Unlike existing estimation techniques that are based on work breakdown structures with respect to process or product, the proposed models are based on a new metric for estimating product complexity, which is based on product functional decomposition. The validity of the metric as a good predictor of design effort was tested using data obtained from an experiment involving simple design tasks, and empirically using historical data collected for 32 projects from 3 companies. The performance of the new effort estimation models was tested in terms of a number of objective criteria. The results indicated that the average estimation error of the models ranged from 12% to 15%. The improvement in estimation accuracy accomplished by the models ranged from 52% to 64% compared to estimates originally made by the companies which had errors from 27% to 41%. Moreover, models for estimating cost and duration, as well as updating the estimates during project execution, were derived. The applications of the derived models are described through demonstrative examples. Thus, a complete methodology is given for the estimation of project effort and duration.</description><creator>Bashir, Hamdi A.</creator><contributor>Thomson, Vince (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><title>Models for estimating design effort</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f768v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998397</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd21x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of multidrug resistance (MDR) in tumour cells to a wide range of anticancer drugs has become a major obstacle in the chemotherapeutic treatment of cancer. Molecular characterization of MDR tumour cells has led to the identification of several cell-based genetic alterations including the overexpression of a membrane protein, P-glycoprotein (P-gp). P-gp is a ATP dependent drug efflux pump and P-gp ATPase activity has been demonstrated to be essential in drug transport. In an effort to understand how P-gp ATPase activity is coupled to drug binding and transport, we examined the effects of N-ethylmaleimide (NEM), a potent inhibitor of P-gp ATPase, on P-gp drug binding and transport. Our results show that short term treatment of MDR cells with NEM led to a concentration-dependent increase in P-gp drug binding and phosphorylation. In addition, NEM increases [3H]-vinblastine accumulation in drug resistant cells but not in sensitive cells. Our study suggests that inhibition of P-gp ATPase activity, and not increased phosphorylation of P-gp by NEM, is responsible for the observed increase in P-gp-drug binding. Selection of tumour cell lines in vitro has led to multiple cellular changes that may mediate drug resistance to anticancer drugs. The role of other mechanisms, in addition to P-gp and multidrug resistance protein (MRP) in drug resistance, is supported by evidence from studies with tumour cell lines and clinical tumours. In an effort to identify other cellular changes that may be important in tumour drug resistance to anticancer drugs, we have used a differential immunodot blot method to isolate monoclonal antibodies that bind to proteins in drug resistant but not in drug sensitive cells. By using the immunodot blot method, we have isolated a monoclonal antibody (IPM96) which recognized a 40 kDa protein (P-40) in several MDR cell lines. The expression of P-40 is concurrent with the level of drug resistance. Biochemical characterization showed P-40 to be associated with the cell membrane and in the soluble fraction. Molecular cloning of P40 cDNA revealed that P-40 is identical to annexin I, a substrate for the epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase. The observed increase in P-40 (or annexin I) protein levels in drug resistant cells is due to the elevation of P-40 transcripts. The pharmacological characterization of P-40 cDNA transfectants (P-40-MCF-7) has demonstrated that overexpression of P-40 in drug sensitive cells is capable of conferring drug resistance to adriamycin, actinomycin D, Taxol and cisplatin. Taken together, our study provides convincing evidence that annexin I is important in the development of drug resistance in cancer cells. In addition, it suggests a novel mechanism of drug resistance that is different from the ATP-dependent drug efflux pumps that mediate P-gp- and MRP-associated MDR.</description><creator>Wang, Ying, 1958-</creator><contributor>Georges, Elias (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Multidrug resistance.</subject><subject>Cancer -- Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>P-glycoprotein.</subject><title>Identification and characterization of a novel mechanism of multidrug resistance in tumour cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh99p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd21x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz94h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) is a glycosylphosphatidylinositol (GPI)-Iinked cell surface glycoprotein which is overexpressed in several human cancers. CEA, and the CEA family members, non-specific crossreacting antigen (NCA) and biliary glycoprotein (BGP) are members of the immunoglobulin superfamily and all mediate homotypic adhesion. Ectopic expression of CEA in rat L6 and mouse C2 myoblasts can completely block myogenic differentiation. It is demonstrated here that CEA alone and in cooperation with avian v-Myc and human Bcl-2, can result in malignant cellular transformation, effects which are dependent on CEA's differentiation-blocking activity. Ectopic expression of v-Myc and c-Myc proteins in L6 transfectant cells were shown to induce programmed cell death (apoptosis) and surprisingly, myogenic differentiation, a novel function for Myc proteins. Induction of both of these cellular programs required the highly conserved subdomain, Myc homology box 2, in the Myc transactivation domain. L6 cells expressing v-Myc and Bcl-2 displayed reduced apoptosis, yet were limited in their transformation capacity owing to the persistence of v-Myc-induced differentiation. Cells expressing v-Myc Bcl-2, and CEA in combination were completely inhibited in executing their differentiation program, displayed an increased capacity to grow when deprived of anchorage to a substratum, and rapidly formed tumours in nude mice. Significantly, the critical prerequisite for the generation of transformed cells was the presence of CEA. The structural requirements for the differentiation blocking activity of CEA were also investigated. Like CEA, GPI-linked NCA also inhibits myogenic differentiation, whereas a transmembrane family member, biliary glycoprotein, BGP has no effect. Using cDNA constructs encoding chimeric proteins of CEA, BGP, and a GPI-linked musclespecific isoform of human neural cell adhesion molecule, which accelerates differentiation, it is demonstrated that the differentiation-blocking activity of CEA absolutely requires the 32 C-terminal amino acid residues of CEA which form the signal sequence for GPI-membrane attachment.</description><creator>Screaton, Robert A.</creator><contributor>Stanners, C. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Effects of carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) and MYC on cell state transitions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m109w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz94h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj461</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the CNS, one of the neurotrophin family members, brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF), plays an important role in neuronal survival and synaptic plasticity. However, the underlying mechanisms mediating these events are less clear. One approach to identify potential mechanisms is to better characterize the localization of endogenous BDNF protein in the CNS. This thesis has explored the subcellular localization of endogenous BDNF protein in the adult rat CNS, and the functional consequences of this localization. First, we show that endogenous BDNF protein can accumulate in microvesicles isolated from brain synaptosomes. Consistent with this localization, immunocytochemical data reveals a punctate staining pattern in hippocampal mossy fiber terminals. Further, increasing basal levels of activity throughout the CNS, using either kainic acid or specific noradrenergic antagonists, induces a rapid increase in the phosphorylation state of the TrkB neurotrophin receptor, consistent with the activity-dependent release of endogenous BDNF. Together, the first two studies are consistent with BDNF being anterogradely transported in CNS axons. The next two chapters have focused on potential functions of anterogradely transported BDNF. BDNF in noradrenergic fibers regulates the development of the neocortex, and the axotomy induced survival of facial motor neurons, both noradrenergic: targets, suggesting anterogradely transported BDNF may play a role in development. Finally, we show that BDNF transported in catecholaminergic fibers can regulate the levels of calbindin in the septum. Overexpression of BDNF in noradrenergic axons increases the expression of calbindin protein in the septum. Further, selective destruction of catecholaminergic fibers, coursing through the medial forebrain bundle (MFB), leads to a decrease in calbindin expression in the septum. Addition of exogenous BDNF protein to cultured septal neurons induced calbindin expression without affecting the proliferation or survival of calbindin-containing neurons. Together, these data suggest a novel localization and delivery mechanism for endogenous BDNF protein in the adult CNS.</description><creator>Fawcett, James P.</creator><contributor>Murphy, Richard A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The subcellar localization and function of endogenous BDNF in the adult rat CNS /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq26s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj461</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q797f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the fundamental problems in signal processing is to enhance a signal which has been corrupted by an additive noise. In this thesis, the problem of alleviating the effects of camera noise corrupting the dialog of a film soundtrack is examined. Two methods of noise reduction are investigated: adaptive noise cancellation with a synthesized reference signal, and spectral subtraction. It is found that, due to the relatively low correlation between successive camera noise pulses, the adaptive noise cancellation approach is not effective at reducing camera noise. The spectral subtraction method is shown to reduce camera noise, but the process creates audible artifacts which can be very disturbing to the listener. To overcome this, new methods are proposed for reducing musical noise and time aliasing effects. The use of subbands and sub-frames is shown to significantly improve the performance of the spectral subtraction algorithm by providing a better match of the noise reduction process to the noise. The performance is further improved by incorporating a perceptual model into the spectral subtraction algorithm. The use of subbands, sub-frames, and a perceptual model allows the amount of processing applied to the signal to be minimized which in turn reduces the level of any artifacts which may result from the noise reduction process. The results of a formal subjective test demonstrate the improved performance of the new noise reduction algorithm.</description><creator>Soulodre, Gilbert A.</creator><contributor>Kabal, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Adaptive methods for removing camera noise from film soundtracks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js91g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q797f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k33z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Adenoviruses have proven to be particularly helpful in unraveling the intricacies of cell growth regulation and apoptosis, greatly increasing our understanding of oncogenesis. At the onset of this work, adenoviruses were thought to induce apoptosis via a p53-dependent cell death pathway exclusively, and we set out to develop an assay system to study the ability of viral proteins to inhibit p53-induced apoptosis. We started using the p53-null human Saos-2 osteogenic carcinoma cells when we found that p53 expression led to rapid cell death. The morphology of these cells by electron microscopy confirmed that death was by apoptosis and this death was significantly reduced with Bcl-2 overexpression. We then demonstrated that the E1B-55K protein of human adenovirus type 5 (Ad5), which was known to bind and repress p53 transcriptional activity, blocks cell death following p53 expression. These results directly show that E1B-55K is able to inhibit p53-induced apoptosis. This ability is important for adenovirus replication because alone, the 289-residue (289R) and 243R E1A products of Ad5 induce p53-dependent apoptosis which would inhibit progeny production. During the course of this work, we also found that the 289R E1A protein is able to induce p53-independent apoptosis, and the remainder of this thesis work is focused on that question. Preliminary results suggested that p53-independent cell death required expression of additional Ad5 early gene products. We found that E1B-19kDa and Bcl-2 inhibited this p53-independent killing. Neither early regions E2 or E3 were necessary for cell death, but analysis of a series of E1A mutants indicated that mutations disrupting transactivation of E4 gene expression abolished killing. Furthermore, Saos-2 cells infected with an E1B +/E4- viral mutant remained viable for considerably longer times than those infected with wt Ad5. In addition, an E1-/E4- adenovirus vector was unable to induce cell killing in E1A-expressing cell lines, indicating that an E4 product is essential for E1A-induced p53-independent apoptosis. To identify which E4 products are involved, studies were conducted in p53-deficient human Saos-2 cells infected with various Ad5 E4 mutants. An E4orf6-deficient mutant was defective in cell killing whereas another which expressed only E4orf6 and E4orf4 killed like wt virus, suggesting that E4orf6 may be responsible for cytotoxicity; however, a mutant expressing only E4orf4 induced high levels of cell death, indicating that this E4 product may also be cytotoxic. To define the E4 cell death-inducing functions more precisely, cDNAs encoding individual E4 products were introduced into cells by DNA transfection together with a cDNA encoding firefly luciferase. Enzymatic activity was high in all cases except with E4orf4 where levels were less than 20% of controls. In addition, drug selection of cells following transfection with a puromycin-containing retroviral vector encoding individual E4 products yielded a high number of cell colonies except when E4orf4 was expressed. These data demonstrated that E4orf4 is the only E4 product capable of independent cell killing. Death was due to apoptosis, as evidenced by the morphology of DAPI stained cell nuclei. This identification of a p53-independent apoptosis pathway has offered considerable insight into how the virus may ultimately be killing the host cell. Additionally, it has directed us to another cellular apoptosis pathway which will contribute to our understanding of the life and death balance in the cell.</description><creator>Marcellus, Richard Charles.</creator><contributor>Branton, Philip E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Regulation of apoptosis by adenovirus type 5</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz28p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k33z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb05m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:39:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The distribution of fluidization flow of a variable speed 3-in (7.5 cm) Knelson centrifugal concentrator was first studied. Its performance was then investigated for different types of synthetic ores, and the effect of rotation speed, fluidizing water, gangue density and size distribution, and feed rate determined. To obtain some fundamental information relative to the recovery mechanisms of the Knelson Concentrator, the percolation or migration of dense particles in a gangue bed was investigated in the gravitational field, using a fluidization column. The equations for determining the instantaneous radial settling velocity of a spherical particle in the dilute zone of the inner bowl were derived for the Stokes' Law region. Recovery of tungsten from magnetite and silica gangues and recovery of magnetite from silica gangue were studied. Results indicate that rotating speed of the Knelson Concentrator affected both the movement of mineral particles and fluidization of the separation zone, which in turn affected KC performance. For all types of feeds studied, the fluidizing water flow rate needed to achieve a maximum recovery increased with increasing rotating speed. The study of capture kinetics showed that tungsten recovery from silica decreased gradually and almost linearly as the feed rate increased from 0.5 to 5 kg/min; this decrease became smaller with increasing Gs. However, the recovery drop (or the corresponding capture rate constant) was small for coarse (&gt;106 mum) tungsten and moderate for fine (&lt;106 mum) tungsten, suggesting that for typical applications of gold recovery from the circulating load of a grinding circuit, feed rate should be maximized. Further, accelerations of 30 to 60 Gs were adequate for very good recovery of tungsten above 25 mum. The recovery of magnetite from a -425 mum silica gangue was limited to a d 50c of 40 mum. Rotation velocity had little impact on how fine magnetite could be recovered, especially above the velocity corresponding to 60 Gs. At 1 Gs (i.e. in the gravitational field), an optimum fluidization flow was also observed for all systems studied. High density gangue, especially when coarse, had a detrimental effect on percolation and migration. Particles of high density percolated or migrated faster than those of lower density. When the gangue bed was well fluidized, the migration rate of coarse particles was higher than the percolation rate of fines. These observations are basically consistent with the effect of fluidization water, gangue size distribution and density on Knelson performance.</description><creator>Ling, Jinghong, 1948-</creator><contributor>Laplante, Andre R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>A study of a variable speed 3-in Knelson concentrator /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp849.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb05m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>