<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:19:31Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32750" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z24d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a contribution to the study of the interpretation of the concept of bodhicitta. This concept is a technical term of frequent occurrence in Buddhist Sanskrit literature. Within the Mahayana Buddhist tradition, bodhicitta is closely related to the spiritual practices of the Buddhist aspirant to enlightenment. Specifically researched is Santideva's use of this concept in his Bodhicaryavatara, a text known to have been composed around the 8th century. The form of this study is as follows: first, a survey of the various interpretations of the concept of bodhicitta suggested so far; secondly, an analysis of its possible functions in the context of the spiritual path of the aspirant to enlightenment; thirdly, a discussion of what I believe to be an appropriate understanding of bodhicitta. An argument will be made that the path to realization consists in cultivating an awareness of the reality described by the concept of bodhicitta. Such cultivation should bring one to the realization that what is described by it is indeed the only possible reality. This means that bodhicitta is the means to as well as the description of the goal to attain.</description><creator>Brassard, Francis, 1961-</creator><contributor>Hayes, Richard P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Śāntideva, 7th cent. Bodhicaryāvatāra.</subject><subject>Bodhicitta (Buddhism)</subject><title>The concept of bodhicitta in Śāntideva's Bodhicaryāvatāra /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x293b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z24d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cf85r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The process parameters that affect the anisotropy of mechanical properties of two Nb microalloyed linepipe steels (grades X-70 and X-80) were examined by controlled rolling and accelerated cooling on a pilot mill. The rolling schedules were first simulated by multi-pass torsion testing so as to determine the critical temperatures, such as T$ sb{ rm nr}$ and Ar$ sb3.$ Using the torsion test results, two finish rolling temperatures were chosen so as to be above and below the A$ sb3$ (in the $ gamma$ + $ alpha$ region). Two reheat temperatures were selected to study the effect of prior austenite grain size. The properties of air cooled samples are compared with those of specimens cooled at two different rates; in each case, cooling was interrupted at one of three different temperatures. The textures were measured by x-ray diffractometry and are presented in the form of ODF plots and skeleton lines. The yield strengths were measured by carrying out tensile tests along directions inclined at increasing angles to the rolling direction. The state of the pancaked austenite before transformation was characterized in terms of the effective interfacial area. It is shown that this parameter determines the sharpness of the transformation texture because it accounts for both the amount of pancaking strain applied to the austenite before transformation and the austenite grain size. Another important factor affecting texture development during transformation is the rate of cooling, as it determines the dislocation density present on each active slip system. The results of hardness testing, texture measurement, and mechanical testing showed that a moderate cooling rate and a medium cooling interruption temperature lead to the best combination of a fine microstructure and a desirable texture. It is shown that accelerated cooling increases both the yield strength and the planar anisotropy of the yield strength, the latter property rising to a maximum in the samples associated with the lowest cooling interruption temperature. Comparison between the experimental results and model predictions of the yield strength ratio indicates that the pancake and lath models are in the best agreement with the measured values.</description><creator>Akbarzadeh, Abbas.</creator><contributor>Jonas, J. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Effect of thermomechanical processing on microstructure, texture, and anisotropy in two Nb microalloyed steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm98x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cf85r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935451w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is made of two parts. In the first part, we study pattern formations and dissipation of energy and matter by using hyperbolic reaction-diffusion equations for reacting systems. Two-dimensional hyperbolic reaction-diffusion equations are numerically solved for the Selkov model and the Brusselator. It is shown that the evolution equations used can give rise to various kinds of patterns such as hexagonal structures, stripes, maze structures, chaotic structures, etc., depending on the values of the reaction-diffusion number and the initial and boundary conditions. The values of the entropy production computed indicate that the system maintains the particular organized local structures at the expense of energy and matter. However, when the system produces a chaotic pattern, the entropy production is lower than the locally organized structures. The phase speed of travelling oscillating chemical waves can be obtained from the linearized hyperbolic reaction-diffusion equations. The Luther-type speed formula is obtained in the lowest order approximation in the case of the Brusselator. The two-dimensional power spectra computed for chaotic patterns still preserve some kind of symmetry. In the second part of this thesis, the generalized hydrodynamics is applied to calculate the shock profiles, shock widths, and calortropy production for a Maxwell gas. Shock solutions are shown to exist for all Mach numbers. This is in contrast to the Grad moment equation method which does not admit shock solution for $N sb{M} ge 1.65$ and to the method of Anile and Majorana which breaks down for $N sb{M} ge 2.09.$ The energy dissipation in the shock is shown to increase with the Mach number as a power law of the form $(N sb{M} - a) sp{ alpha}$ where a and $ alpha$ are real constants.</description><creator>Al-Ghoul, Mazen.</creator><contributor>Eu, Byung Chen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Studies in generalized hydrodynamics for chemical reactions and shock waves</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv53k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935451w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j699d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hemopoietic microenvironment of the bone marrow is an essential regulator of in vivo hemopoiesis. In addition to supporting the growth of normal blood cells, it also influences the growth of leukemia. This thesis describes the use of a rat model to examine three aspects of the function of the hemopoietic microenvironment. First, using a myeloid leukemia cell line (BNML), we showed that the pattern of growth of these cells differed in the bone marrow and spleen, that their presence was associated with a relocalization of normal hemopoietic stem cells from marrow to spleen, and that factors (yet to be defined) released from spleen cells altered the pattern, possibly to create a more permissive environment. Second, we showed that the "ST3" marker of marrow fibroblasts was associated with the Thy-1 molecule, and either directly or indirectly contributed to the in vitro adhesion reaction between marrow fibroblastoid cells and normal and leukemic myeloid precursors. Third, we showed that ectopic bony ossicles induced by subcutaneous implantation of recombinant human bone morphogenetic protein-2 contained marrow expressing the full range of hemopoiesis, including stem cells with a potential for long-term repopulation (demonstrated using a rat Y-chromosome specific DNA probe that we developed), and contained fibroblastoid cells differentiated to express the ST3 antigen in a manner similar to those from femoral bone marrow. These results provide further evidence for, although not final proof of, the hypothesis that the ST3 antigen participates in the function of the rat hemopoietic microenvironment, and points the way to future experiments on the interactions between stromal elements and normal and leukemic myeloid precursors.</description><creator>An, Jing, 1962-</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Microenvironmental influences on the growth of normal and leukemic myeloid cells in the rat bone marrow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311q924.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j699d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354g78f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation investigates transitivity alternations, with particular reference to Amharic. The lexical-semantic and morphosyntactic properties of morphological causatives, experiencer predicates, applicative constructions and complex predicates formed by light verbs are examined in detail. It is claimed that transitivity alternations are an artefact of Event-type alternations and follow from universal principles such as Event Headedness. It is argued that the valency difference between various verb classes reduces to whether the Root of the verb is specified or underspecified for Event Headedness. Two levels of phrase structure, l-syntax and s-syntax, are recognized in the study. It is argued that productive causatives are generated in s-syntax, whereas morphological causatives which are sensitive to the Event-type of the Root are generated in l-syntax. A unified structural analysis is given for a number of superficially unrelated constructions including Subject Experiencer predicates, perception verbs and possessive predicates. It is argued that the quirky Case and agreement properties of such predicates can be handled by motivating inherent Case assignment. This analysis is further extended to account for the benefactive applicative of unaccusatives. The role of light verbs in transitivity alternation is explored in detail. It is shown that light verbs are independent verbs that spell-out Event-types. The study argues that the polysemous relationship between predicates is best accounted for by a single argument structure rather than by positing multiple lexical entries.</description><creator>Amberber, Mengistu.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Transitivity.</subject><subject>Amharic language -- Causatives.</subject><subject>Amharic language -- Transitivity.</subject><title>Transitivity alternations, event-types and light verbs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b73f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g78f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz09g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nonlinear viscoelastic properties of a series of blends of linear polyethylene were studied using the McGill sliding plate rheometer. A more reliable and sensitive shear stress transducer for this rheometer was designed, built and used in this work. The molecular weight dependence of a variety of nonlinear viscoelastic properties was investigated. It was determined that, as with steady state properties, the sensitivity of such properties to molecular weight diminishes with increasing shear rate. The behavior of these materials in large amplitude oscillatory shear (LAOS) was also studied. By using harmonic analysis, the frequency content of the nonlinear stress response to the sinusoidal strain was studied as a function of molecular weight, strain amplitude and frequency. The predictive abilities of the Wagner model in LAOS, exponential shear, start-up and cessation of steady shear and interrupted shear, at high shear rates were evaluated. Qualitative trends were well predicted by the model for a variety of sigmoidal and exponential damping function forms. For the first time, it has been shown that Wagner model predictions for molten thermoplastics are insensitive to the damping function form. The damping functions in simple shear and planar extension were obtained for a branched low density polyethylene (LDPE). Simple shear is similar to planar extension in a rotated reference frame and thus the two flows should have similar damping functions. It was found that the damping functions that fitted these two flows are, in fact, quite different. Thus we have shown that the contribution of kinematics cannot be simply described.</description><creator>Samurkas, Tony</creator><contributor>Dealy, J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><title>Nonlinear viscoelastic behaviour of linear polyethylene : molecular weight effects and constitutive equation evaluations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q55r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz09g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bz76c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the dynamics of German Turks' practices and life-styles and their relationship with Turkey in the context of the possibilities brought into their lives by their particular type of dislocation. Turkish migrants' "culture" and life-styles are explored in the context of their complex social space, rather than within a framework encapsulated in a reified ethnicity and/or immutable "Turkish culture". Chapter I discusses concepts of ethnicity, culture and identity and presents a critical account of the literature on German Turks in this respect. Chapter II focuses on the ambiguities and insecurities of German Turks' legal, political and social status in both Turkey and Germany, and traces the consequences of these conditions on Turkish migrants' complex sense of place. The discussion of German Turks' "myths of return" in the context of their liminality and the impact these have on their self-image and their visions about their lives constitute the focus of chapters III and IV respectively. Chapter V explores the changing nature of Turkish migrants' interpersonal relationships. Chapter VI concentrates on the anomalies of the social space occupied by German Turks in German society and discusses their life-styles, practices and emergent cultural forms in the context of social mobility.</description><creator>Simsek-Caglar, Ayse</creator><contributor>Rousseau, Jerome (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Turks -- Germany -- Social life and customs</subject><subject>Alien labor, Turkish -- Germany -- Social life and customs</subject><title>German Turks in Berlin : migration and their quest for social mobility</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924d257.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bz76c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb284</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coffee production in Costa Rica has brought prosperity to many small farmers, but conflicts of interest with the companies which process and market coffee are still a problem. In addition, producers and processors are plagued by the periodic market cycles of agricultural commodities. Various agencies have promoted cooperatives to help small farmers deal with these problems, but they often fail due to poor management and lack of participation. This thesis, a multi-layered study of coffee production, processing, and marketing, examines how household producers manage the constraints and opportunities posed by the international market, the Costa Rican state, and the coffee tree itself. A comparative analysis between cooperative and private coffee processors; between two rural communities; and among households in these communities provides the ethnographic context in which the effectiveness of cooperatives as mediating institutions between producers and the world market is analyzed.</description><creator>Sick, Deborah, 1956-</creator><contributor>Bossen, Laurel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Coffee industry -- Costa Rica.</subject><subject>Family farms -- Costa Rica.</subject><subject>Coffee growers -- Costa Rica.</subject><subject>Agriculture, Cooperative -- Costa Rica.</subject><title>The golden bean : coffee, cooperatives and small-farmer decision making in Costa Rica</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w392q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb284</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720f35c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The developmental potential of mammalian oocytes cryopreserved with procedures similar to those used for embryos has been limited, inasmuch as oocytes differ from embryos in advanced stages of development, both physiologically and morphologically. The objective of this work was to elucidate the precise nature of freeze-thaw damage with the expectation that identification of specific targets will enable devising optimal procedures for cryopreservation of bovine oocytes to prevent specific damage and minimize the loss of developmental capacity. In the first series of experiments, bovine oocytes were vitrified (V-oocytes) or frozen slowly (S-oocytes) at the germinal vesicle (GV) stage or after maturation in vitro (IVM). Survival was assessed morphologically and also by in vitro fertilization (IVF) and culture (IVC). Morphological integrity and developmental capacity were greater in S-oocytes than in V-oocytes (P $&lt;$ 0.05). Transfer of four embryos (2 morulae and 2 blastocysts) derived from post-IVM S-oocytes into a recipient heifer resulted in the birth of twin calves. In the second series of experiments, oocytes (GV and IVM) were exposed to a cryoprotectant solution (DAP213: 2M DMSO, 1M acetamide, 3M propanediol) for 1.5 or 5 min and viability assessed by IVM-IVF-IVC. Oocytes were also examined by transmission electron microscopy (TEM) before (control) or after exposure to the cryoprotectant. DAP213 induced profound premature cortical granule (CG) release and vesiculation. These changes were less pronounced in oocytes exposed to DAP213 only after IVM. The results suggest that: (1) the extrusion of CG is one of the important cytological events affected by the treatment of oocytes with DAP213; (2) GV oocytes are more sensitive to the cryoprotectant than IVM oocytes. In the third series of experiments, GV and IVM oocytes were vitrified with DAP213. On rewarming, DAP213 was removed by a one- or three-step dilution procedure and survival assessed by development after IVM-IVF-IVC. Morphology was assessed by TEM study immediately following DAP213 removal. Both assessments indicated that: (1) IVM oocytes are more tolerant to vitrification than are GV oocytes; (2) the three-step dilution is less damaging than the one-step procedure; (3) changes in the zona pellucida (loss of plasticity) of IVM oocytes following vitrification may result from the premature release of cortical granules.</description><creator>Fuku, Eiji</creator><contributor>Downey, Bruce R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Cattle -- Eggs.</subject><subject>Cryopreservation of organs, tissues, etc.</subject><title>Studies on the cryopreservation of immature and in vitro matured bovine - oocytes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903147s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f35c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z238v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stereoanalogues of choline (R and S, $ alpha$- or $ beta$-methylcholine), hemicholinium-3 and choline mustard aziridinium ion were used as tools to investigate the structure and function of the high-affinity choline transporter. Three studies are presented. In the first, the methylcholines were used to study the stereoselective properties of the high-affinity choline transporter. The recognition of the methylcholines by the choline carrier was stereoselective, while their transport was stereospecific. This difference was interpreted as indicating that recognition and transport might represent distinct and dissociable components of the choline transporter. In a second study, the methylcholines were used to examine the stereoselectivity of ($ sp3$H) hemicholinium-3 binding to determine how this compared to the interaction of the methylcholines with choline uptake. The ability of these compounds to inhibit stereoselectively ($ sp3$H) hemicholinium-3 binding indicates that binding is to the substrate recognition site of the choline carrier. However, this site can assume two configurations, as defined by changes in its stereoselectivity for the methylcholines and affinity for hemicholinium-3. The conformational change of the substrate recognition site likely plays a role in initiating the substrate translocation process, since locking it in its high-affinity ($ sp3$H) hemicholinium-3 binding state reduces the rate of choline transport. In a third study, choline mustard aziridinium ion and hemicholinium-3 were used to investigate the mechanism by which activity regulates the velocity of choline transport. These studies indicate that the mechanism involves the changed activity of transport sites that are available to the mustard, and presumably choline, but not hemicholinium-3 prior to stimulation. In addition, two pools of basal transport sites have been identified on the basis of their sensitivity to choline mustard, as well as their ability to transport choline and b</description><creator>Ferguson, Stephen S. G. (Stephen Sean Gilbert)</creator><contributor>Collier, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Studies upon the rat brain high-affinity choline transporter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v68f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z238v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sb84w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objectives of this Thesis were the determination of the reaction kinetics of the dissolution of zinc-ferrite particles ((Zn$ sb{1-x}$, Fe$ sbsp{x}{2+}$)$ rm Fe sbsp{2}{3+}O sb4$, x $ le$ 0.4) in hot aqueous solutions of sulphuric acid, and the development of a mathematical model for the prediction of the performance of a series of continuous stirred-tank reactors where zinc ferrite is leached. Well-characterised, porous zinc-ferrite particles of industrial origin were subjected to controlled leaching experiments at temperatures close to 373 K in sulphuric acid solutions of concentration higher than 0.25mol L$ sp{-1}$. The dissolution process was found to be described most adequately by the grain model with surface reaction being the rate-controlling step. After analysing the experimental results through this model, a unique rate equation for zinc-ferrite dissolution as a function of temperature and solution composition, was obtained. Based on this rate equation, a mathematical framework was built for the analysis of the start-up and the steady-state of reactor cascades where zinc ferrite is continuously leached. This framework consisted of population-balance and mass-balance equations, which were solved analytically or numerically. Computer simulation results, which were obtained by this reactor model, showed very good agreement with actual industrial data.</description><creator>Filippou, Dimitrios</creator><contributor>Demopoulos, George P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Reaction kinetics and reactor modelling of zinc-ferrite hot-acid leaching</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht34h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sb84w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n778</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two problems in nuclear physics are investigated using microscopic semi-classical models. The first model, developed to study heavy ion collisions, is based on the Boltzmann-Uehling-Uhlenbeck theory and has been extended to include one-body fluctuations. It has been successfully applied at low and intermediate energies and a comparison between simulations and an experiment done at the Michigan State University cyclotron facility has yielded very good agreement. The second is a nuclear structure model based on the Thomas-Fermi theory and describes nuclear rotations. It has been used to calculate nuclear shapes and limiting angular momenta across the periodic table. It has been found that it breaches the gap between classical Liquid Drop calculations and quantum Hartree-Fock calculations. Agreement with experimental results is satisfactory.</description><creator>Gallego, Juan</creator><contributor>DasGupta, Subal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>Two specific applications of semi-classical theories in nuclear physics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f278m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n778</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng15p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The eukaryotic mRNA 5$ sp prime$ cap structure m$ sp7$GpppX (where X is any nucleotide) is of crucial importance in translation initiation and protects messenger RNAs (mRNAs) against exonucleolytic degradation. L-A and L-BC are double-stranded RNA viruses which are persistently maintained in the cytoplasm of many Saccharomyces cerevisiae strains. Unexpectedly, their coat proteins exhibited a strong cap-binding activity. Unlike any other cap-binding protein, the coat protein (gag) of the L-A virus was shown to attach covalently to the cap structure of mRNAs, resulting in the cleavage of the cap structure and in the capture of m$ sp7$Gp. The linkage was determined to be a phosphoroimidazole bond between the $ alpha$ phosphate of the cap structure and a nitrogen ($N sp1$ or $N sp3$) in the gag His154 imidazole side-chain. Mutation of His154 abrogated the ability of gag to covalently link to the cap structure, without affecting cap recognition, viral particle formation from an L-A cDNA clone in vivo, or specific binding and replication of (+) single-stranded RNA in vitro. However, genetic analysis demonstrated that His154 was essential for the expression of viral proteins, possibly because efficient translation of the viral mRNA requires capping of the initially ppG-terminated viral transcripts by transfer of the m$ sp7$Gp captured by gag.</description><creator>Blanc, Antony</creator><contributor>Sonenberg, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Capture of eukaryotic mRNA cap structures by the coat protein of the yeast L-A dsRNA virus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37638501.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng15p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz11h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines how cultural understandings are generated and transmitted in a Canadian multicultural teaching hospital. It explores how issues of 'culture' are addressed formally and informally in the experiences of patients and practitioners. Using the approach of an institutional ethnography, emphasis is placed upon informal strategies of cultural care as a taken-for-granted practice in clinical life. It illuminates how pressure to learn culturally sensitive care seeps into the fabric of daily clinical life, and how cultural practices are constructed within a complex set of organized social practices. The study concludes that advocacy of multicultural policies, must consider the dominance of existing western health care paradigms. It advocates culturally responsive care as a parallel force that can collaborate with the regimes of formal health practices. It argues that providing effective health care to all segments of Canadian society requires structural changes in health education which need to address existing disjunctures between 'effective ideals' and ideological knowledge, in order that all are ensured optimum health care.</description><creator>Boston, Patricia Helen</creator><contributor>Jackson, Nancy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Multiculturalism -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Teaching hospitals -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Caring and culture : the practice of multiculturalism in a Canadian university hospital</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505204d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz11h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr992</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The production of contrastive stress was studied in normal-hearing and severely and profoundly hearing-impaired children. A picture description task was used to elicit utterances. Contrastive stress was assigned by changing one element in the second and third pictures in sets of three pictures. Stress production was assessed perceptually and acoustically. The normal-hearing and the severely hearing-impaired children were judged to have consistently stressed the element that was changed in the pictures. Some of the profoundly hearing-impaired subjects were judged to have stressed the changed element more often than chance but some did not perform above chance. Acoustic measurements indicated that only the normal-hearing speakers significantly varied both duration and fundamental frequency when stressing words while some of the hearing-impaired children varied only duration. These findings were interpreted as indicating that profoundly hearing-impaired speakers had difficulty producing recognizable contrastive stress and showed deviations in the duration and fundamental frequency of their utterances.</description><creator>Fitzgerald, Michèle Bordeleau</creator><contributor>Doehring, Donald G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology.</subject><title>The production of contrastive stress by hearing-impaired children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x0537.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr992</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472z03q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This history of the Tver (Kalinin) province of Russia, with particular emphasis on the years: 1945-1953, uses primary sources from archives of the Party and Soviet State, oral interviews, and readings of Russian, French, English, and German publications. The first chapters discuss the socio-economic and political effects of the events prior to 1945. Subsequently, the post-war role of Communist Party, Soviet government, security organs, and Komsomol and the results of Communist policies in agriculture and industry are analysed. The province's demographic losses between 1929 and 1945 and their consequences in Stalin's final years are assessed. The life of male and female kolkhozniks, workers, and intelligentsia, and their relationship with the authorities are depicted. Post-1953 changes are appreciated in the last chapter. Four maps, forty-seven tables, and four appendices are included.</description><creator>Boterbloem, Cornelis N.</creator><contributor>Boss, U. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Tverskai︠a︡ oblastʹ (Russia) -- History</subject><title>Communists and the Russians : the Kalinin Province under Stalin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b478z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z03q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666610d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Most mouse strains express either NK1.1 or NK2.1 NK-specific antigens. We have produced and characterized a mAb, 4LO3311, detecting the NK2.1 antigen expressed in most mouse strains. Strain-dependent variations in the frequency of splenic NK2.1$ sp+$ cells and in the cell surface density of NK2.1 were observed by flow cytometry, suggesting that 4LO3311 mAb actually detects a subset rather than all NK cells. In confirmation of this hypothesis, treatment of mice with 4LO3311 mAb had little effect on splenic NK cell activity although NK2.1$ sp+$ cells were no longer detected. Moreover, remaining NK cells in mAb-treated mice were totally resistant to further in vitro mAb plus complement treatment. Evidence of the high heterogeneity of the NK cell population was obtained in B6C3F$ sb1$ hybrid mice in which a relatively large subset of NK1.1$ sp-$ NK2.1$ sp-$ cells was detected in addition to those expressing either NK1.1, NK2.1, or both antigens. On the basis of the expression of several NK-specific and non-specific markers, NK2.1$ sp+$ cells appear themselves heterogeneous. Interestingly, immobilized 4LO3311 mAb induces granule exocytosis from IL-2-stimulated NK cells, thus identifying the NK2.1 antigen as a putative triggering structure. The capacity of NK cells to lyse anti-NK2.1 producing hybridoma cells is inhibited in the presence of soluble 4LO3311 mAb, whereas lysis of NK-susceptible targets is increased. The activation of the lytic activity through 4LO3311 mAb binding is Fc-independent and does not even require bivalency of the mAb. These findings are consistent with the NK2.1 antigen being involved in NK cell signaling. On the basis of the lytic activity of NK and related MHC non-restricted cells in selected Recombinant Inbred mouse strains of the AXB/BXA series and of the expression of NK-specific markers on their spleen cells, we finally established that, in this system, the lytic activity level of NK cells depends on variable combinations of at least 3 ef</description><creator>Morelli, Lidia</creator><contributor>Lemieux, Suzanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Phenotypes and properties of murine natural killer cell subsets</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq88g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666610d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj261</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments involving the random insertion of foreign DNA constructs into the genome have frequently had unanticipated but informative consequences. In the Tg4 line of transgenic mice, an hsp68-lacZ transgene caused an insertional mutation of the dystonia musculorum (dt) locus. In the same line, the transgene gained an ectopic expression pattern in the neural tube floor plate. The co-occurence of these events suggested that the dt phenotype of postnatal sensory neuropathy might arise from a primary defect expressed in floor plate cells. To test this hypothesis, the cellular target of the dt mutation was determined by analyzing $dt/dt leftrightarrow +/+$ chimeras, in which wild type neurons and their axons were identified by their expression of a human neurofilament transgene. In these chimeras, axonal pathology was confined to the axons of mutant neurons, thus defining an intrinsic neuronal dt defect, and ruling out an extrinsic influence of floor plate cells. The expression of $ beta$-galactosidase in the Tg4 line was further used to examine, using histochemical staining, the morphology of floor plate cells, which play a role in the guidance of commissural axons. Floor plate cells were found to possess a number of morphological specializations which appeared to establish a high degree of membrane apposition with commissural axons. Unexpectedly, $ beta$-galactosidase activity was also detected adjacent to stained floor plate cells in profiles that could not be distinguished from midline axon segments, suggesting that a process of macromolecular transfer may normally operate between floor plate cells and commissural axons.</description><creator>Campbell, Robert M. (Robert McLean)</creator><contributor>Peterson, Alan C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Investigation of an hsp68-lacZ transgene inserted at the dystonia musculorum locus and expressed in the neural tube floor plate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t803.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj261</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x295w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The localisation of B lymphocyte precursor cells in mouse bone marrow and their associations with stromal reticular cells and macrophages have been investigated by in vivo radioimmunolabeling combined with light and electron microscope radioautography. Many early B lineage cells expressing the B220 glycoprotein prior to the expression of surface immunoglobulin and those regenerating after sub-lethal $ gamma$-irradiation, were located in bone-associated regions of femoral marrow. Labeled B220$ sp*$ lymphoid cells of undifferentiated morphology were closely associated with complex cytoplasmic processes of stromal reticular cells. The binding of a monoclonal antibody raised against a B lymphocyte-supportive stromal cell line (mAb KMI6), was highly restricted to the interface between stromal cells and undifferentiated lymphoid cells. The VCAM-1 specific mAb M/K-2, labeled electron-dense stromal cells that contacted lymphoid cells and a variety of other hemopoietic cell lineages. Within the bone marrow of normal mice there was evidence of death of B220$ sp+$ B lineage cells by apoptosis and their removal by macrophages. Cell loss, apoptosis and macrophage deletion of B precursor cells were greatly enhanced in E$ mu$-myc transgenic mice. The results reveal a complex in vivo microenvironmental organisation of B lymphocytopoiesis characterised by intimate interactions with stromal reticular cells and macrophages which regulate the development of precursor B cells and determine the ultimate output of B lymphocytes from the bone marrow.</description><creator>Jacobsen, Karen Ann</creator><contributor>Osmond, Dennis G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Microenvironmental organization of B lymphopoiesis in mouse bone marrow : in vivo localisation of B lymphocyte precursors, molecular-interactions with stromal reticular cells, and macrophage-mediated deletion of apoptotic forms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js69z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x295w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988m57j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An alignment/phylogeny of the papain superfamily of cysteine proteases was created from which the existence of at least 11 families of mammalian cysteine proteases was inferred, including two as yet uncharacterized ones. Character weighting increased the average speed of maximum parsimony phylogenetic searches two- to three-fold. To study a sequence motif in pro-cysteine proteases and mammalian cystatins, cystatin C, a cysteine protease inhibitor, was expressed and purified using a new affinity method giving $&gt;$99% purity. Methionine oxidation to the sulfoxide occurring during protein production was eliminated. Reduced stability caused by Met14 oxidation was demonstrated. No function for the sequence motif was found, however cystatin C underwent a conformational change at acidic pH that rendered the His86-Asp87 peptide bond labile to proteolysis. This could constitute a mechanism for clearing inappropriately localized cystatins from the acid environment of lysosomes and explain differences between the X-ray and NMR structures of the homologous chicken cystatin.</description><creator>Berti, Paul J. (Paul Joseph)</creator><contributor>Storer, Andrew C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Cysteine proteases : interaction with cystatin C and sequence to structure-function relationships</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg08z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m57j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988m614</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The transition from deflagration to detonation is studied by focusing on the actual final process, i.e. the onset of detonation itself. The high speed deflagration prior to transition is obtained by suppressing the oscillatory structure of a detonation first. A theoretical model is developed to analyze the resulting deflagration complex which shows that it propagates close to half the CJ detonation velocity with the deflagration slowly separating from the leading shock. These high speed deflagrations thus obtained just prior to transition to detonation as well as the highly turbulent fast deflagrations that have been observed prior to transition in earlier studies are shown to be CJ deflagrations where the propagation velocities are governed by energetics rather than the flow structure. To understand how the nonsteady behavior of detonations may affect the transition process, the one-dimensional pulsating detonation is analyzed by computational studies. The time averaged solution of the non-overdriven detonation over a cycle is found to recover the steady CJ solution and the independence of the far rearward boundary condition is demonstrated for the activation energies studied. The self-oscillatory nature of the detonation also plays a key role in the maintenance, failure, and re-establishment of the detonation structure. To study the onset of detonation, the high speed deflagration obtained by failing the detonation is subsequently perturbed with periodic disturbances to stimulate transition. The numerical simulations show that the perturbations undergo a frequency selective amplification process to accelerate transition where the optimal frequency is related to the chemical reaction time of the detonation. The existence of optimal perturbation frequencies to stimulate transition is also observed in the experimental investigation carried out, although its value appears to depend on the channel dimension. Based on the oscillatory and frequency selective nature of the detonation phenomena, an oscillator model is proposed. An equation that has the basic features of a mechanical oscillator has been derived for the pulsating detonation. The proposed oscillator concept indicates the need to examine detonation phenomena from the point of view of a resonant oscillator.</description><creator>Chue, Randy Shek-Ming</creator><contributor>Lee, John H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>High speed deflagration and its transition to detonation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh016.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m614</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bq967</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hydrolytic depolymerization of poly(ethylene terephthalate), or PET, in excess water was studied at high temperatures in a 2 L pressure reactor. At an initial water/PET loading (w/w) of 5.1 or greater, essentially complete depolymerization was obtained at 265$ sp circ$C. The yield of terephthalic acid monomer was 97% of the theoretical value. The yield of ethylene glycol monomer was lower, 91%, due in part to a dimerization side reaction. An end-group analysis method was developed involving the titration of carboxyl groups of hydrolysate samples dissolved in one of two solvent systems, dimethylphenol:chloroform or dimethylsulphoxide, depending on reaction extent. A kinetic model was developed and found to provide a good fit with experimental data and with equilibrium concentrations. The activation energy of hydrolysis was calculated to be 56 kJ/mol. Zn$ sp{+2}$ catalysts increased the hydrolysis rate constant by about 20% at the same reaction temperature. PET glycolysis was studied at the same conditions of temperature and initial reactor loading as for hydrolysis using a method based on the removal of unreacted ethylene glycol from the product mixture through careful drying. The activation energy of glycolysis was found to be 102 kJ/mol. Glycolysis rate constants were about 7 times greater than the corresponding hydrolysis rate constants. The difference between the sets of rate constants is attributed largely to the morphology of the respective reaction mixtures (solution/emulsion).</description><creator>Campanelli, John R. (John Richard)</creator><contributor>Copper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The kinetics of hydrolysis and glycolysis of poly(ethylene terephthalate) melts at high temperatures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m80v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bq967</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687j91w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated nonverbal communication patterns in siblings in the prosocial, neutral, and agonistic conditions. Sixty-four children aged 3 years 3 months to 9 years 6 months (16 same-gender and 16 mixed-gender sibling dyads) participated. All children's behaviors were coded using the system for Identifying Affect Expressions by Holistic Judgments (AFFEX, facial expressions) and the Behavioral Coding System (BCS) for behaviors. The major finding was that all children were as likely to imitate positive facial expressions in the prosocial as in the aggressive conditions. However, they were more likely to imitate positive behaviors in the prosocial condition and negative behaviors in the aggressive condition. Age within the dyad was the most important subject factor affecting imitation of positive facial expressions and positive and negative behaviors. Younger children tended to imitate their older siblings more than the reverse. Gazing at the older siblings' nonverbal behaviors (NVBs) was an important precursor during both prosocial and aggressive play situations. Of paradigmatic importance is the finding on dyad-gender effects that all-female dyads imitated positive facial expressions as part of their communication during aggressive play.</description><creator>Babins, Leonard H. (Leonard Howard)</creator><contributor>Derevensky, Jeffery L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Nonverbal communication in children</subject><title>Nonverbal communication patterns in siblings during prosocial and agonistic conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407z76m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j91w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t785c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this dissertation I apply the literary and cultural theory of Fredric Jameson to some biblical texts. In the first chapter I present Jameson's theory as a complex relationship between an effort to account for the pluralism of methods and interpretations (metacommentary) and a specific Marxist method, comprising three phases of interpretation. In chapter two I apply metacommentary and the Marxist method to 1 Kings 11-14, moving from a formal and ideological analysis to questions of class and economics in an imperial context. In chapter three the method is similarly applied to two reinterpretations of the Kings passage: 3 Reigns 11-14 and 2 Chronicles 10-13. Here I argue that while the Reigns text is formally and ideologically concerned with moving away from a Judean focus, by contrast the Chronicles text constructs a utopian community in Judea. The conclusion considers the implications of these results.</description><creator>Boer, Roland, 1961-</creator><contributor>Culley, Robert C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</subject><title>Jameson and Jeroboam : a Marxist reading of 1 Kings 11-14, 3 Eeigns 11-14 and 2 Chronicles 10-13</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r20h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t785c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v0108</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:34:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The in situ, equimolar, trimethylaluminum/H$ sb2$O catalyst was used for the ring opening polymerization of racemic $ beta$-butyrolactone, $ beta$-heptanolactone and $ beta$-nonanolactone to form synthetic analogues of the naturally occurring family of biodegradable poly((R) -$ beta$-hydroxyalkanoate) polymers. This catalyst was found to produce both a better yield and a higher molecular weight of a high isotactic, primarily crystalline fraction of poly($ beta$-(R,S) -hydroxybutyrate) than the conventional in situ, equimolar triethylaluminum/H$ sb2$O catalyst. A mechanically tougher, less isotactic and less crystalline fraction of lower molecular weight and a largely amorphous fraction of even lower molecular weight were also isolated and characterized. Biodegradation of solid films of synthetic poly($ beta$-(R,S) -hydroxybutyrate) in the presence of an "extracellular" poly($ beta$-(R) -hydroxybutyrate) depolymerase was found to be dependent on accessibility of the enzyme to the (R) linkages along the polymer chain. The semicrystalline fraction was the most susceptible to degradation whereas the high crystallinity fraction showed little degradation and the low crystallinity fraction only showed limited degradation early in the incubation period. Synthetic poly($ beta$-(R,S) -hydroxyheptanoate) and poly($ beta$-(R,S) -hydroxynonanoate) polyesters were prepared for the first time and the whole product was predominantly isotactic. It was found to have comparable physical properties as the biosynthetic materials, which are only available as terpolymers. Evidence for paracrystalline ordering relating to the organization of the side chains and formation of liquid crystalline-like phases was observed.</description><creator>Jesudason, Jeyarajan Joseph</creator><contributor>Marchessault, R. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Synthetic analogues of bacterial polyesters : preparation and properties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb3979755.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v0108</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32775</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>