<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:17:59Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7100" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666741m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'appariement méiotique suivi de la synapse qui maintiennent les chromosomes homologues ensemble pour que le brassage de matériel génétique puisse avoir lieu sont au cœur de la méiose. Chez le nématode Caenorhabditis elegans, HTP-3 tient un rôle essentiel dans l'assemblage du complexe synaptonémal (synapton) qui polymérise sur toute la longueur des homologues lors de la synapse. HTP-3 possède des rôles établis dans l'appariement et la synapse, mais aussi dans la formation de cassures double brin, une première étape nécessaire pour l'échange de matériel génétique mentionné ci-dessus. HTP-3 contient un domaine appelé HORMA, qui est un domaine d'interaction protéine-protéine conservé parmi des protéines dont les rôles vont de l'apoptose a une fonction dans le point de contrôle d'assemblage des fuseaux (Aravind, 1998; Jao, 2013). Nous savons que HTP-3 joue un rôle central dans le processus de la méiose, mais le mécanisme moléculaire par lequel il exerce ses fonctions est encore inconnu parce que la protéine est impliquée dans de nombreuses étapes. Caractérisation de htp-3(vc79), qui contient une mutation dans le domaine HORMA conservé de HTP-3, m'a permis de disséquer les fonctions spécifiques de ce domaine. Le chargement de HTP-3 sur le synapton est abrogé dans le mutant htp-3(vc79); des agrégats de HTP-3 sont observés a la place dans les noyaux de pachytènes. L'analyse de ce mutant a révélé qu'un domaine HORMA intact est nécessaire pour la coordination du chargement de HTP-3 avec REC-8 sur l'axe, un composant des complexes de cohésion qui maintiennent les chromatides sœurs ensemble jusqu'à la méiose II. Cependant, des cassures double brin se produisent encore dans le mutant indiquant que son domaine HORMA n'est pas nécessaire pour cette fonction particulière. Des expériences futures vont étudier comment la mutation dans htp-3(vc79) affecte le paysage des partenaires de liaison de HTP-3 afin de faire la lumière sur les processus de la méiose, tels que l'appariement, la synapse et la formation de cassures double brins.</description><description>The stereotyped meiotic pairing and the subsequent synapsis that keeps the homologous chromosomes together for the shuffling of genetic material to take place is central to meiosis. In the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans, HTP-3 holds a vital role in the assembly of the synaptonemal complex (SC) that polymerizes throughout the length of the homologs during synapsis. HTP-3 has established roles in pairing and synapsis, but also in double strand break (DSB) formation, a necessary first step in the aforementioned exchange of genetic material. HTP-3 contains a HORMA domain, which is a protein-protein interaction domain conserved amongst proteins with roles ranging from apoptosis to the spindle assembly checkpoint (Aravind, 1998; Jao, 2013). We know that HTP-3 has a central role in meiosis, but the molecular mechanism by which it performs its functions is unclear because the protein is involved in so many processes. Characterization of the htp-3(vc79) allele, which contains a mutation in the conserved HORMA domain of HTP-3, has allowed me to dissect the functions specifically of the HORMA domain regarding the numerous roles of HTP-3. HTP-3 loading on the SC is abrogated in the htp-3(vc79) mutant, where instead meiotic aggregates of HTP-3 can be observed in pachytene nuclei. Analysis of this mutant uncovered that an intact HORMA domain in HTP-3 is necessary for its co-loading on the axis with REC-8, a component of the cohesion complexes that keep the sister chromatids together until meiosis II. However, DSBs still occur in the mutant indicating that its HORMA domain is dispensable for this particular function. Further experiments could investigate how the mutation in htp-3(vc79) affects the binding partner landscape of HTP-3 in order to shine light on meiotic processes such as pairing, synapsis and DSB formation.</description><creator>Delouche, Camille</creator><contributor>Monique Zetka (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>Characterization of a novel htp-3(vc79) mutant in «Caenorhabditis elegans»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq64s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666741m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bh717</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Computational fluid dynamics (CFD) is playing a rapidly growing role in the aero-icing certification process. However, three-dimensional (3D) viscous turbulent CFD-icing simulations of complete aircraft are prohibitive, in particular parametric studies where the cost of repeated calculations could become overwhelming. A reduced-order modeling (ROM) approach is proposed to explore the complete icing envelopes, with comparable accuracy to CFD.The ROM approach uses a limited, but strategically selected, number of snapshots (solutions obtained at various operating conditions) of the complex icing problem, and extracts a basis of vectors (or modes) that represent its most fundamental physical features. Proper orthogonal decomposition (POD) is adopted to extract modes from the snapshots. A linear combination of the POD modes can be subsequently used to obtain solutions for conditions different than the snapshots, with coefficients obtained via multi-dimensional interpolation. In regard to the continuous and intermittent maximum icing envelopes, a local POD approach, using machine learning algorithms, is developed. It clusters similar snapshots and delimits ice-type regions within the envelope, such that distinct physical features can be extracted separately. An error-driven iterative sampling method combining a greedy approach and a centroidal Voronoi tessellation sampling technique is developed to position additional snapshots in the regions of high nonlinearity, finding a good balance between accuracy and the total number of snapshots. The proposed ROM framework and iterative sampling methodology is first assessed on an airfoil. It is demonstrated that the continuous and intermittent maximum icing envelopes can be explored via ROM in terms of both shape/mass of ice and the associated lift coefficient curves. The methodology is then applied, for the first time to the best knowledge of the author, to a detailed aero-icing study of a regional jet, in terms of: 1) the "complete" exploration of the continuous maximum icing conditions for the shape/mass of ice, and 2) its aerodynamic degradation (changes in lift, drag and pitching moment) due to ice contamination during holding around an airport, and the consequent effect during descent and aborted landing. The results strongly support the drive to incorporate more CFD information into in-flight icing certification procedures as well as pilot training programs, leading to increased aviation safety.</description><description>La mécanique des fluides numérique (CFD) joue un rôle de plus en plus important lors du processus de certification du givrage en vol. Toutefois, la prédiction du cumul de glace sur un aéronef entier est trop coûteuse, particulièrement lors d'analyses paramétriques pour lesquelles le coût de calculs répétitifs peut devenir prohibitif. Un modèle d'ordre réduit (MOR; ROM en anglais) est proposé pour balayer à coût modeste la plage entière de l'enveloppe de certification, tout en offrant une précision comparable à la CFD. La méthode MOR utilise un nombre limité mais stratégiquement sélectionné de solutions, dites prises ou snapshots, obtenues à différentes conditions opérationnelles du problème et en extrait une base de valeurs propres (ou modes) représentant les caractéristiques physiques fondamentales du système. Une décomposition orthogonale propre (POD) est adoptée pour extraire les modes de ces prises. Une combinaison linéaire des modes est par la suite utilisée pour obtenir des solutions à des conditions autres que celles des prises, par interpolation multidimensionnelle. En ce qui concerne les domaines de givrage maximaux continus et intermittents, une décomposition orthogonale propre locale, utilisant des algorithmes d'apprentissage automatique, est développée. Cette méthodologie permet la partition de prises similaires et la délimitation de différentes régions selon le type de glace, de telle sorte que leurs caractéristiques physiques distinctes peuvent être traitées séparément. Une méthode d'échantillonnage itératif combinant un algorithme glouton (dit greedy en anglais), et une technique de partition d'échantillonnage de type centroïde de Voronoï, sont développées pour finement positionner des prises additionnelles dans les régions de forte non-linéarité, tout en  maintenant un juste équilibre entre la précision et le nombre total de prises.L'approche ROM et la méthodologie d'échantillonnage itératif sont d'abord évaluées pour un profil aérodynamique, et il est démontré que les enveloppes de givrage maximum-continu et intermittent peuvent être explorées via ROM pour prédire la forme et la masse de glace, ainsi que la portance. La méthode est par la suite appliquée, pour la première fois au meilleur des connaissances de l'auteur, à l'étude détaillée de l'aéro-givrage d'un jet régional, en termes de: 1) l'exploration "complète" des conditions de givrage maximales continues pour la forme/masse de glace et 2) la dégradation aérodynamique (changement de portance, de traînée et de moment de tangage) en raison de l'accumulation de glace lors de survol prolongé d'un aéroport, de descente et d'atterrissage avorté. Le niveau de précision atteint démontre la pertinence d'incorporer plus d'informations CFD dans les programmes de certification pour le givrage en vol, ainsi que lors de la formation de pilotes, avec pour but d'améliorer la sécurité aérienne.</description><creator>Zhan, Zhao</creator><contributor>Wagdi George Habashi (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Marco Fossati (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Towards real-time CFD simulation of in-flight icing via reduced-order modeling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d696h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh717</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rx170</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plus de 20% de la population mondiale adulte souffre de douleur chronique. Les évidences prouvent que la transition de la douleur aiguë à la douleur chronique dépend de la neuroplasticité dans la corne dorsale de la moelle épinière (CDME). Bien que les molécules responsables de l'initiation de la mémoire à long terme dans la CDME ont été identifiées, peu est connu sur le maintien de sa plasticité synaptique à long terme. La protéine kinase Mζ (PKMζ) est une kinase active de manière persistante qui contribue uniquement au maintien de la potentialisation à long terme (PLT) et au stockage de la mémoire dans l'hippocampe. Cependant, il est intéressant de noter que PKMζ est régulée à la hausse dans la CDME après une nociception persistante, et son inhibition en utilisant l'inhibiteur de peptide pseudosubstrate-myristoylée ζ (IPZ) dans le cerveau ou la moelle épinière inverse la nociception. Toutefois, le rôle du IPZ et l'action de PKMζ pendant la douleur persistante, et sa régulation exacte dans la moelle épinière sont inconnus. Nous déterminons ici le rôle de PKMζ dans des modèles de douleur persistante de longue durée.Résultats. L'inhibition pharmacologique de PKMζ chez le rat n'a eu aucun effet sur les seuils de retrait de la patte ipsilatérale (SRP) réduits observés chez les rats épargnés de lésion nerveuse (ELN), mais a transitoirement élevé les SRPs contralatérales, qui ont été réduits plusieurs semaines après la blessure. Aucun changement dans les SRPs réduits après l'inflammation de la patte arrière induite par l'adjuvant complet de Freund (ACF), n'a été observé après le traitement par IPZ ou scrIPZ. IPZ a réduit la phase tardive de la nociception induite par le formol 2% mais a affecté seulement partiellement les réponses nociceptives à 3,5 % de formol, et n'a pas affecté les réponses nociceptives à 5 % de formol. IPZ, mais pas scrIPZ, ni NPC15437, a inversé l'allodynie mécanique induite par l'injection de solution saline acide post-induction de douleur. Le pré-traitement et post-traitement par IPZ ont évité et renversé l'allodynie mécanique induite par la capsaïcine intracolonique (CAPi.c.). Surtout, nous démontrons pour la première fois que IPZ a inversé l'allodynie durable établie tant après l'amorçage que les injections CAPi.c. La délétion génétique de prkcz a soutenu les conclusions pharmacologiques ci-dessus. En outre, nous avons aussi évalué le rôle de plusieurs éléments régulateurs de PKMζ, identifiés dans des études de l'hippocampe. Nous démontrons ici que l'inhibition de PIN1 dans la moelle utilisant juglone (5-hydroxynaphtho-quinone) a exacerbé l'allodynie induite par l'injection i.t. de NMDA. L'amélioration de cette allodynie a été associée à une diminution des niveaux de PIN1, et d'une augmentation particulière de PKMζ, mais pas de la forme longue de la protéine PKCζ. En plus, l'inhibition de PDK1 utilisant GSK-2334470 a réduit significativement la phosphorylation de PKMζ, mais pas les niveaux de PKMζ totale. Le prétraitement par GSK-2334470 a empêché le développement de l'allodynie induite par le NMDA. De même, le prétraitement par pep2m, un inhibiteur de l'interaction entre la protéine de fusion sensible à N-éthylmaléimide (FSN) et le sous-type 2 de récepteur de glutamate (GluR2), a empêché l'allodynie induite par le NMDA. Ces données suggèrent que PIN1, PDK1 et l'interaction FSN-GluR2 sont nécessaires pour la mise en place de l'hyperalgésie induite par le NMDA dépendante de PKMζ.Signification. Avec sa structure et sa fonction uniques, PKMζ promet d'être une cible clé pour le traitement de la douleur chronique qui dépend de la neuroplasticité. Comprendre la neuroplasticité vertébrale est essentiel pour le développement de médicaments, pour le bénéfice des patients qui actuellement ne peuvent pas être traités de façon optimale avec des analgésiques de pointe.</description><description>Background. More than 20% of the world adult population suffers from chronic pain. Evidence shows that transition from acute to chronic pain depends on neuroplasticity in the spinal cord dorsal horn (SCDH). Although molecules responsible for the initiation of long-term memory in the SCDH have been identified, little is known about the maintenance of its long-term synaptic plasticity. PKMζ is a persistently active kinase that contributes uniquely to the maintenance of LTP and memory storage in the hippocampus. Interestingly, PKMζ is upregulated in SCDH after persistent nociception, and its inhibition using the myristoylated ζ-pseudosubstrate inhibitory peptide (ZIP) in the brain or spinal cord alleviates nociception. However, the role of ZIP and PKMζ action during persistent pain, and its exact regulation in the spinal cord are unknown. Here, we determine the role of PKMζ in models of persistent, long-lasting pain. Results. Pharmacological inhibition of PKMζ had no effect on the reduced ipsilateral PWTs observed in rats with spared nerve injury (SNI), but transiently elevated contralateral PWTs, which were reduced several weeks after the injury. No change in reduced PWTs following hind paw inflammation induced by CFA was observed after i.t. ZIP or scrZIP treatment. ZIP reduced the late phase of nociception induced by 2% formalin, but only partially affected nociceptive responses to 3.5% formalin, and did not affect nociceptive responses to 5% formalin. ZIP pretreatment, and post-treatment prevented and reversed, respectively, i.c. capsaicin-induced remote allodynia, and ZIP post-treatment persistently reduced i.m. acidic saline-induced remote allodynia, while no pain relieving effect was observed following i.t. scrZIP or full-length PKC inhibitor NPC15437, suggesting PKMζ may be responsible for the maintenance of remote allodynia. Moreover, ZIP prevented, and reversed long-lasting persistent mechanical allodynia in a modified hyperalgesic priming model using either i.c. or i.pl. capsaicin. Importantly, we show for the first time that ZIP reversed long-lasting established allodynia following both priming and challenging i.c. capsaicin injections. Genetic deletion of prkcz supported the above pharmacological findings. Thus, prkcz-/-, but not prkcz+/- or WT mice displayed attenuated responses in remote allodynia models, but not SNI-induced neuropathic pain. Importantly, these pain attenuation effects of prkcz KO were significantly more pronounced in male than in female mice.I.t. injection of 10 nmol NMDA produced a significant decrease in PWTs for 24 - 48 h that was reversed by i.t. ZIP. Concordantly, a significant increase in PKMζ protein levels was observed 60 min post i.t. NMDA.  Further, we assessed the role of several PKMζ regulatory elements identified in hippocampal studies. Spinal inhibition of PIN1 using juglone (5-hydroxynaphtho-quinone), which decreased PIN1 and increased PKMζ, but not full-length PKCζ, exacerbated i.t. NMDA-induced allodynia. Additionally, inhibition of PDK1 using GSK-2334470, which significantly reduced PKMζ phosphorylation, but not total PKMζ levels, prevented the development of NMDA-induced allodynia. Likewise, pretreatment with pep2m, an inhibitor of the interaction between N-ethylmaleimide-sensitive fusion protein (NSF) and the glutamate receptor subtype 2 (GluR2), prevented NMDA-induced allodynia. These data suggest PIN1, PDK1 and an NSF-GluR2 interaction are required for the establishment of PKMζ-dependent NMDA-induced hyperalgesia. Significance. PKMζ promises to be a key target for the treatment of chronic pain that depends on neuroplasticity. These studies have provided a detailed cellular and systems level analysis of the role of PKMζ in the maintenance of maladaptive neuroplasticity contributing to persistent pain. Understanding spinal neuroplasticity is essential for drug development benefiting patients that currently cannot be treated optimally with state-of-the-art analgesics.</description><creator>Nasir, Hibatulnaseer</creator><contributor>Terence Coderre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The role of protein kinase M zeta in chronic pain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278x06v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rx170</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rh16x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Purpose: Fractures are considered one of the most common injuries to occur in all patients irrespective their age group. Although most of these fractures are managed adequately, there is still a high incidence of complications including non-union or delayed union ranging from 5-10%. Current management options include bone grafting, growth factor implantation and stem cell therapy, but they have had limited success. Recent attention has been directed towards the WNT/ β-catenin pathway and its critical role in fracture healing. In this pathway a glycoprotein called sclerostin is considered a negative regulator of bone formation, through binding of the low-density lipoprotein receptor-related protein 5 (LRP5) thus antagonizing the WNT pathway and downregulating β-catenin. The effect of both sclerostin knockout and sclerostin depletion by antibody administration has been shown in the literature, no study compared the efficacy of sclerostin antibody administration to complete sclerostin knockout in an animal model. Our study compares the effectiveness of  sclerostin antibody (Scl-Ab) to complete sclerostin knockout in the mouse tibial fracture model at different time points of fracture healing radiographically, histologically and biomechanically. Methods: 10-week-old male Sclerostin knockout (SOST-KO) (N=20) and wild-type (WT) (N=40) mice underwent insertion of a tibial intramedullary pin after which a mid-shaft tibial osteotomy was performed. The mice were divided into three groups: SOST KO (N=20), WT with Scl-Ab injection (N=20) and WT with saline injection (N=20). The Scl-Ab group received an intravenous dose of 100mg/kg body weight weekly starting on day 7. Each group was managed and sacrificed similarly according to a specific protocol. Each group was assessed at 14, 21, 28 and 35 days post-surgery by micro-CT and biomechanical testing. For data analysis, one-way ANOVA (Analysis Of Variance) was performed followed by Tukey's post hoc test at each time point. P values&lt;0.05 were considered statistically significant. Results: Both Scl-Ab and KO groups showed significantly increased trabecular BV/TV (bone volume/ total volume) at the fracture site (mid-shaft of the tibia) compared to the saline group at all time points and also showed no significant difference between them at all time points (except at 28 days postoperative).On biomechanical testing the Scl-Ab and KO groups showed significant increased strength in stiffness at days 14, 28 and 35 compared to the saline group. Concerning ultimate force and work to failure the KO group showed significant increase in the force required compared to both the Scl-Ab and saline groups at 21,28 and 35 days. While the Scl-Ab group showed increased forced required to fracture the callus compared to the saline group at these time points, but this was only significant for work to failure at 28 days. Conclusion: Scl-Ab injections showed promising results, which were comparable to the complete depletion of sclerostin, especially at earlier stages of the healing process. In addition, our results indicate that sclerostin antibody exerts its greatest effect in the earlier stages of fracture healing (days 14 and 21), after which the healing process plateaus and thus completing this process at an earlier time point. Further research into accurate dosage and adequate timing of administration is required before these promising results can be implicated as a modality for accelerating fracture healing in humans and management of delayed / nonunion.</description><description>But: Les fractures sont considérées comme l'une des blessures les plus courantes à se produire chez tous les patients, quel que soit leur groupe d'âge. Bien que la plupart de ces fractures soient gérées de manière adéquate, il y a encore une forte incidence de complications, incluant les non-unions et les délais d'union, allant de 5 à 10%. Actuellement, les options de traitement comprennent la greffe osseuse, l'implantation de facteurs de croissance, et la thérapie par les cellules souches, mais ils ont encore un succès limité. Récemment, l'attention a été dirigée vers la voie Wnt/B-caténine et son rôle crucial dans la guérison des fractures. Dans cette voie, une glycoprotéine appelée sclérostine est considérée comme un régulateur négatif de la formation d'os, par l'intermédiaire de la protéine de liaison d'une lipoprotéine de basse densité liée au récepteur 5 (LRP5) antagonisant ainsi la voie Wnt et la régulation négative de B-caténine. L'effet des de la sclérostine KO et de l'appauvrissement en sclérostine par l'administration d'anticorps ont été démontré dans la littérature, mais nous n'avons pas rencontré d'étude comparant l'efficacité de l'administration d'anticorps sclérostine et la sclérostine KO dans le modèle animal. Notre étude compare l'efficacité de Scl-Ab pour et de la sclérostine KO dans le modèle de fracture tibiale chez la souris à différents points dans le temps de guérison radiologique, histologique et biomécanique. Méthodes: Des souris mâles de 10 semaines SOST KO (KO) (N=20) et de type sauvage (WT) (N=40) ont subi l'insertion d'une broche intramédullaire tibiale, après quoi une ostéotomie tibiale mi-diaphysaire a été effectuée. Les souris ont été divisées en trois groupes: SOST KO (N = 20), avec injection WT Scl-Ab (N = 20) et WT avec injection de solution saline (N = 20). Le groupe Scl-Ab reçu une dose intraveineuse hebdomadaire de 100 mg/kg, commençant le jour 7. Chaque groupe a été géré et sacrifié selon un protocole spécifique. Pour l'analyse des données, une analyse de la variance à un facteur a été effectuée, suivie d'un test post-hoc de Tukey à chaque point de temps. Les valeurs de P &lt;0,05 ont été considérées comme statistiquement significatives.Résultats: Les groupes Scl-Ab et KO ont montré une augmentation significative trabéculaire du volume osseux/volume total (VO/VT) au niveau du site de fracture (mi-diaphyse du tibia) par rapport au groupe de solution saline, à tous les points de temps et n'ont également montré aucune différence significative entre eux à tous les points de temps (sauf à 28 jours post-opératoires). Aux tests biomécaniques, les groupes Scl-Ab et KO ont montré une augmentation significative de la rigidité aux jours 14, 28 et 35 par rapport au groupe de solution saline. En ce qui concerne la force ultime et le travail à l'échec, le groupe KO montré une augmentation significative de la force nécessaire par rapport à la fois au Scl-Ab et au groupe de solution saline à 21, 28 et 35 jours. Alors que le groupe Scl-Ab a montré une augmentation de la force requise pour fracturer le cal par rapport au groupe de solution saline à ces points de temps, ce n'était significatif que pour le travail à l'échec à 28 jours. Conclusion: L'injection de Scl-Ab a montré des résultats prometteurs, qui étaient comparables à l'appauvrissement complet de la sclérostine, surtout aux premiers stades du processus de guérison. En outre, nos résultats indiquent que l'anticorps sclérostine exerce son plus grand effet dans les premiers stades de la guérison des fractures (jours 14 et 21), après quoi le processus de guérison atteint un plateau, complétant ainsi ce processus à un point de temps plus rapide. Des recherches plus poussées concernant le dosage précis et le moment adéquat de l'administration sont nécessaires avant que ces résultats prometteurs puissent être impliqués en tant que modalité pour accélérer la guérison des fractures chez les humains et pour traiter les délais de guérison et la pseudarthrose.</description><creator>Alzahrani, Mohammad</creator><contributor>Frank Rauch (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>C Reggie Hamdy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Effect of sclerostin depletion on fracture healing in the mouse model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r84d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh16x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wb12c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'agriculture durable peut être définie comme l'optimisation du rendement et la rentabilité sans compromettre l'environnement. Nécessitant des taux élevés de composés chimiques, qui accélèrent l'activité biologique des sols, les pratiques d'agriculture intensive entraînent l'émission de gaz à effet de serre (GES; CO2, CH4, et N2O), sans pour autant obtenir de meilleurs rendements. Quantifier les émissions de GES provenant des sols agricoles devient alors essentiel lors de l'évaluation de la durabilité des pratiques agricoles. N'ayant pas tenu compte de l'hétérogénéité des champs, les estimations d'émissions de gaz du passé ne consistaient qu'en une extrapolation à partir des émissions d'un petit nombre de sites d'échantillonnage. Des différences inhérentes quant aux propriétés physiques et climatiques des sols et des activités de gestion des cultures peuvent affecter significativement la répartition spatiale (à l'horizontale et en profondeur) et temporelle des émissions de GES. Conséquemment, l'amélioration de la fiabilité d'estimation des émissions de GES est étroitement liée à une connaissance approfondie de l'hétérogénéité des sols. En une première étude, la qualité de la cartographie de la conductivité apparente du sol (ECa), évaluée par induction électromagnétique (IEM) avec des instruments de contact à résistance galvanique (CRG) fut évalués en examinant les effets temporels et opérationnels d'une pelouse trempée (ECa = 5-15 ms m-1). Les effets opérationnels ont inclus la distance au-dessus de la surface (0 ou 0.10 m), et les angles de roulis et de tangage (0ᵒ et ±10ᵒ). Parmi les mesures d'EMI, le capteur DUALEM–21S en mode d'opération de conductivité perpendiculaire coplanaire (CPC) a offert les mesures les plus stables. Les variations en hauteur et roulis inférieures à la tolérance évaluée n'affectèrent pas l'ECa du sol, mais les variations en tangage par rapport à 0° ont réduit l'ECa. D'un point de vue pratique, les mesures de l'ECa du sol ont très peu varié à l'intérieur d'une tolérance en hauteur de 0.10 m, et de roulis et tangage de ±10ᵒ. Face à de gros volumes de données (&gt;30,000 échantillons de gaz) provenant de multiples (103 chambres à gaz à 6 sites) et divers (c.-à-d. sol, récolte, irrigation) emplacements dans l'est du Canada, une seconde étude s'adressa à la gestion des bases de données, le format de normalisation, et aux problèmes de calcul des flux et émissions. Pour ce faire, une série de scriptes MATLAB furent développés. L'estimation des flux et émissions utilisa les pentes médianes de régressions linéaires, une méthode permettant de filtrer les mesures erronées. Dans une troisième étude, les variations temporelles des émissions de GES sous différentes combinaisons de propriétés physiques et taux de décomposition de sols organiques à trois sites disposant de parcelles irriguées ou non irriguées furent suivies à l'aide de réseaux de capteurs sans fil pour le potentiel matriciel du sol, l'humidité du sol, et sa température. Les sols de terre noire émirent plus de N2O lorsque le sol était relativement humide et les conditions climatiques fraîches, tandis que les flux en CH4 furent plus élevés dans les sols détrempés. Les émissions de CO2 furent le plus élevées lorsque l'humidité du sol était modérée et les températures chaudes. Les corrélations entre les flux de GES et les propriétés du sol se révélèrent plutôt faibles, limitant le potentiel de modélisation des flux et des émissions de GES. Les émissions en CH4 étaient particulièrement élevées pour les terres noires (vs sols minéraux) principalement en raison de dépressions dans le champ et de la haute teneur en eau du sol dans ces dépressions. L'évaluation des variations spatiales et temporelles dans les caractéristiques physiques des sols peut aider à mieux comprendre la dynamique des émissions de GES, permettant ainsi de quantifier plus précisément les effets environnementaux des systèmes agricoles modernes.</description><description>Sustainable high-intensity agriculture involves optimizing yield and profitability without compromising the environment. High chemical inputs have the potential to accelerate soil systems' biological activity and emission of greenhouse gasses (GHG; e.g., CO2, CH4, and N2O) without increasing the yield. Quantifying emissions from agricultural soils is critical to assessing the sustainability of farming practices. Usually, estimates of agriculture-driven GHG emissions are based on a small number of sampling sites. Inherent differences in soil climatic and physical properties and crop management activities can significantly affect an agricultural field's spatial and temporal patterns of GHG emissions. Accordingly, a close knowledge of soil heterogeneity is critical for improving the reliability of GHG emission estimates. In this project, stability estimates of apparent soil electrical conductivity (ECa) measurements by electromagnetic induction (EMI) and galvanic contact resistance (GCR) instruments were assessed by testing for both temporal and operational effects of a sodden lawn (soil ECa = 5 15 ms m 1). Operational effects on the instrument included height above ground (0 or 0.10 m), roll angle (0ᵒ and ±10ᵒ), and pitch angle (0ᵒ and ±10ᵒ). Among EMI measurements, the perpendicular coplanar (PRP) operating mode of the DUALEM–21S provided the most stable measurements. Changes in height and roll within tolerance had no effect on soil ECa measurements, but increasing pitch reduced measurement values. From a practical point of view, soil ECa measurements varied little within the height tolerance of 0.10 m, and roll and pitch tolerance of ±10ᵒ. In a second study, a database management methodology was developed to analyze the &gt;30,000 GHG samples. This methodology included a means for data format standardization and flux/emission calculation based on 103 fixed sampling locations across Eastern Canada using a suite of automated MATLAB scripts. Flux estimates were determined using the median slope of temporal change of concentration, thereby filtering outliers arising from erroneous measurements. In a third study, temporal variations in GHG emissions under different soil physical properties and soil organic matter decomposition rates were monitored in three sites with replicated water treatment plots (sprinkler irrigation vs. no irrigation), using a network of wireless sensors that monitored soil matric potential, volumetric water content and soil temperature. Muck soils tended to emit more N2O under relatively wet and cool conditions, whereas CH4 fluxes peaked in fully wet soils, while moderate soil moisture levels and warm temperatures promoted CO2 emissions. Correlations between GHG fluxes and measured soil properties were rather weak, limiting the potential for modeling GHG fluxes and emissions. In a fourth and final study, placement of GHG monitoring sites was optimized for an agricultural field with variable soil conditions. Nine locations were selected and monitored to detect levels of GHG fluxes and emissions representing the most extreme soil conditions present in the chosen field. Different soil types, as well as soil moisture and temperature dynamics, resulted in different levels of GHG emissions. Due to high soil moisture content caused by a field depression, methane emissions were highest in muck (vs. mineral) soils. Assessment of spatial and temporal variations in soil physical characteristics can clarify GHG emission dynamics, allowing a more accurate quantification of modern farming systems' environmental impact.</description><creator>Mat Su, Ahmad Suhaizi</creator><contributor>Viacheslav Adamchuk (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Application of proximal soil sensing for environmental characterization of agricultural land</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg21z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb12c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397b91r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cellular senescence is a tumour suppressor mechanism which prevents the proliferation of malignant cells. In normal cells, oncogenic stimuli induce a senescence response and growth arrest coordinated by tumour suppressor genes, but the loss of expression of these genes impairs the establishment of senescence in cancer cells. We studied the role of histone methylation and oncogenic histone modifiers to assess their responsibility throughout the bypass of tumour suppressor pathways. We first used a PRMT6 knock-out mouse model to recognize the potential effect of PRMT6-mediated histone arginine methylation in cancer. Herein, we report that PRMT6 catalyzes the asymmetric di-methylation of histone H3 at arginine R2 (H3R2me2a) inside the promoter region of the Trp53 gene, resulting in the transcriptional repression of p53. In mice, functional inactivation of p53 is sufficient to bypass oncogene-induced senescence (OIS). We demonstrated that the overexpression of PRMT6 cooperates with oncogenic Ras in the bypass of OIS, suggesting an important role for histone arginine methylation mediated by PRMT6 in promoting tumourigenesis. In the second part of my thesis, I describe miR-137 as an inhibitor of KDM4A expression. KDM4A is a histone lysine demethylase participating in gene repression and the bypass of OIS to promote tumourigenesis in vivo. Specifically, KDM4A targets CHD5, a tumour suppressor and positive regulator p53 expression. We observed that miR-137 expression is lost in Ras-dependent pancreatic cancer. Moreover, restoration of its expression led to cellular growth arrest and senescence in pancreatic cancer cells. We used short hairpin inhibitors of p53 and p16INK4A to dissect the senescence pathways controlled by miR-137 and noticed that both ARF/p53 and p16INK4A/pRb tumour suppressor pathways were independently induced by miR-137. Importantly, expression of miR-137 is enhanced upon Ras activation, and the inhibition of miR-137 activity led to the bypass of OIS. These results suggest that miR-137 targets KDM4A to mediate senescence in response to oncogenic Ras, and that silencing of miR-137 could promote the Ras-driven transformation of pancreatic cancer cells. The work presented in this thesis emphasizes on the importance of the senescence response in tumour suppression. Our results provide a connection between deregulated histone methylation and defective OIS signaling in cancer. I propose that modulating the enzymes responsible for the repression of tumour suppressor genes could be a promising avenue in the prevention or treatment of cancer. Keywords : Senescence, Ras, cancer, p53, PRMT6, miR-137, KDM4A, histone methylation, tumor suppressor.</description><description>La sénescence cellulaire constitue un mécanisme de suppression tumorale qui a pour fonction la prévention de la prolifération des cellules malignes. Les stimuli oncogéniques induisent la sénescence et un arrêt de la croissance cellulaire dans les cellules normales. Cette réponse est coordonnée par les gènes suppresseurs de tumeur, mais la perte d'expression de ces gènes altère l'établissement de la sénescence chez les cellules cancéreuses. Nous avons étudié le rôle de la méthylation des histones et des enzymes oncogéniques responsable de cette modification pour évaluer leur implication lors du contournement des voies de signalisation de suppression tumorale. Nous avons généré un model de souris 'knock-out' pour le gène PRMT6 afin d'identifier le rôle potentiel de la méthylation d'histone en arginine médiée par PRMT6 dans le cancer. Nous rapportons la di-méthylation asymmétrique de l'histone H3 en arginine R2 (H3R2me2a) catalysée par PRMT6 au promoteur du gène Trp53, résultant en la répression transcriptionelle de p53. Chez la souris, l'inactivation fonctionnelle de p53 permet le contournement de la sénescence induite par les oncogènes. Nous avons démontré que la surexpression de PRMT6 participe au contournement de la sénescence induite par les oncogènes, en coopération avec l'expression de Ras oncogénique.  Cette observation suggère une fonction primordiale de la méthylation d'histone en arginine médiée par PRMT6 favorisant la tumorigénèse. La seconde partie de ma thèse présente miR-137 en tant qu'inhibiteur de l'expression de KDM4A. KDM4A est une histone lysine démethylase participant à la répression de gènes et au contournement de la sénescence induite par les oncogènes afin de promouvoir un état tumorigénique in vivo. En particulier, KDM4A cible CHD5, un suppresseur tumoral régulant positivement l'expression de p53. Nous avons observé que l'expression de miR-137 est abolie dans le cancer du pancréas dépendant de Ras. De plus, le rétablissement de son expression mène à un arrêt cellulaire et à la sénescence dans les cellules de cancer pancréatique. Nous avons utilisé des petits ARN interférents ciblant spécifiquement p53 et p16INK4A afin d'élucider les voies de signalisation de la sénescence contrôlées par miR-137 et avons remarqué que les voies ARF/p53 et p16INK4A/pRb étaient indépendamment activées par miR-137. Notamment, l'activation de Ras induit l'expression de miR-137, et son inhibition en présence de Ras oncogénique permet le contournement de la sénescence induite par les oncogènes. Ces observations suggèrent qu'en réponse à l'activation de Ras, miR-137 cible KDM4A afin de stimuler la sénescence, mais que la perte d'expression de miR-137 dans les cellules de cancer pancréatique favorise la transformation cellulaire.Le travail présenté dans cette thèse met l'emphase sur la fonction primordiale  de la sénescence dans la suppression tumorale. Nos résultats ont permis d'élucider la connexion qui subsiste entre la dérégulation de la méthylation d'histone et le dysfonctionnement de la sénescence induite par les oncogènes dans le cancer. Je propose que la modulation des enzymes responsables de la répression des voies de suppression tumorale constitue une stratégie prometteuse dans la prévention et le traitement du cancer.Mots-clés : Sénescence, Ras, cancer, p53, PRMT6, miR-137, KDM4A,  méthylation d'histone, suppression tumorale.</description><creator>Neault, Mathieu</creator><contributor>Stephane Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Role of histone methylation in the regulation of tumour suppressor networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rx188.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b91r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bx15z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The peripheral somatosensory system allows us to sense and react properly to changes occurring in the internal environment of the organism and at the body surface. Under normal conditions, peripheral nociceptors transduce noxious signals and relay them to the central nervous system where they undergo further integration leading to pain perception. In this case, pain helps protect the body from potential damage. Yet, under chronic pain conditions, sensitization mechanisms occur both peripherally and centrally causing alterations in the profile of sensory fibers and/or changes in the central processing of their input, driving sensory hypersensitivity. Thus, investigating the contribution of each subset of primary afferents to sensory transmission under naïve and sensitized conditions is critical in understanding pain physiology and designing effective chronic pain treatments.  Optogenetics consists of a molecular system that couples genetic targeting and optical stimulation to modulate neuronal activity with high spatiotemporal precision. Here, we used the voltage-gated sodium channel Nav1.8 as a genetic marker to selectively deliver the excitatory opsin Channelrhodopsin-2 to peripheral nociceptors. This approach allowed the development of the first mammalian model in which peripheral nociceptive circuits are optogenetically activated in behaving animals. We showed that acute non-invasive transdermal illumination of the hind paws of these mice generates robust nocifensive behaviors. We further showed that prolonged activation of Nav1.8+ terminals could induce thermal and mechanical hypersensitivity mainly through central sensitization mechanisms, in absence of tissue damage and neurogenic inflammation. On the other hand, in order to overcome the limitations of genetic ablations, we took advantage of the inhibitory proton pumps Archaerhodopsin-3 to optogenetically silence Nav1.8+ endings with high temporal precision and assess their role in sensitized conditions. Our findings showed that both acute and prolonged inhibition of Nav1.8+ afferents alleviate inflammatory and neuropathic hypersensitivity, confirming their contribution to chronic pain and highlighting the importance of peripheral inputs in the onset and maintenance of pain hypersensitivity. Moreover, we took advantage of MrgprD as a genetic marker to target non-peptidergic nociceptors and optogenetically investigate their role in normal sensory transmission and neuropathic allodynia. Acute blue light stimulation of MrgprD+ fibers generated nocifensive behaviors consisting primarily of hind paw withdrawal and lifting. Under neuropathy, optogenetic silencing of these fibers did not alter cold or mechanical allodynia 3 weeks post-nerve injury, suggesting that they are not essential mediators of neuropathic hypersensitivity, at least at that time point. Altogether, our work established the use of optogenetics to bidirectionally control the activity of peripheral nociceptive pathways non-invasively and with high spatial and temporal accuracy in behaving mice. This strategy is instrumental in evaluating the contribution of genetically defined subsets of sensory neurons to nociceptive and chronic pain. Furthermore, these findings set the stage for a deeper understanding of the physiology of sensory fibers, and for the potential use of optogenetic actuators in clinical applications.</description><description>Le système somatosensoriel périphérique nous permet de détecter et réagir adéquatement aux changements qui se produisent dans l'environnement interne de l'organisme ainsi qu'à la surface du corps. Dans des conditions normales, les nocicepteurs périphériques détectent et transmettent les signaux de danger au système nerveux central où ils subissent une intégration générant la perception de douleur. Dans ce cas-là, la douleur aide à protéger le corps d'un dommage possible. Par contre, dans des conditions de douleur chronique, des mécanismes de sensibilisation prennent lieu aux niveaux périphérique et central produisant des modifications dans le profil des fibres sensorielles et/ou des changements dans le traitement de l'information qu'elles transmettent, causant une hypersensibilité sensorielle. L'investigation de la contribution de chaque sous-groupe d'afférences primaires à la transmission sensorielle en conditions normales et sensibilisées s'avère donc essentielle à la compréhension de la physiologie de la douleur et au développement de traitements efficaces de la douleur chronique. L'optogénétique est un système moléculaire qui intègre le ciblage génétique et la stimulation optique afin de moduler l'activité neuronale avec une grande précision spatiotemporelle. Ici, nous avons utilisé le canal sodique dépendant du voltage Nav1.8 comme marqueur génétique pour livrer l'opsine excitatrice Channelrhodopsin-2 sélectivement aux nocicepteurs périphériques. Cette méthode a permis le développement du premier modèle mammifère dans lequel les voies nociceptives périphériques sont optogénétiquement activées dans des animaux éveillés. Nous avons montré que l'illumination transdermique non invasive des pattes postérieures de ces souris transgéniques génère de forts comportements nocifensifs. De plus, nous avons montré que l'activation prolongée des afférences Nav1.8+ pouvait induire une hypersensibilité thermique et mécanique grâce à des mécanismes de sensibilisation centrale, sans lésion tissulaire ni inflammation neurogénique. Afin de contourner les limitations des ablations génétiques, nous avons utilisé les pompes de protons Archaerhodopsin-3 pour inhiber les terminaisons Nav1.8+ avec une haute précision temporelle et évaluer leur rôle dans des conditions d'hypersensibilité. Nos résultats ont démontré que l'inhibition aiguë ainsi que l'inhibition prolongée des afférences Nav1.8+ sont capables de réduire l'hypersensibilité inflammatoire et neuropathique, confirmant leur contribution à la douleur chronique et soulignant l'importance de l'information neuronale périphérique dans la manifestation et le maintien de l'hypersensibilité sensorielle.           Ensuite, nous nous sommes servis de MrgprD comme marqueur génétique pour cibler les nocicepteurs non-peptidergiques et investiguer optogénétiquement leur rôle dans la transmission sensorielle normale et l'allodynie neuropathique. La stimulation des fibres MrgprD+ avec la lumière bleue a généré des comportements nocifensifs consistant principalement en retrait et lever de la patte. En neuropathie, l'inhibition optogénétique de ces afférences n'a affecté ni l'allodynie au froid ni l'allodynie mécanique 3 semaines après la lésion du nerf, suggérant que ces fibres ne sont pas essentielles dans l'hypersensibilité neuropathique, au moins à ce stade-là. En résumé, notre travail a établi l'utilisation de la stratégie optogénétique pour contrôler de façon bidirectionnelle et non invasive l'activité des voies nociceptives périphériques avec une précision spatiale et temporelle inégalée dans des souris éveillées. Cette méthode facilite l'évaluation de la contribution de sous-populations de neurones sensoriels identifiées génétiquement à la douleur nociceptive et chronique. De plus, ces découvertes préparent le terrain pour une compréhension plus approfondie de la physiologie des fibres sensorielles, et l'utilisation potentielle des outils optogénétiques dans des applications cliniques.</description><creator>Daou, Ihab</creator><contributor>Philippe Seguela (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Optogenetic investigation of peripheral pain pathways in behaving mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw48v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx15z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr524</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte. Les malformations du développement cortical (MDC) sont un groupe d'anomalies congénitales caractérisées par diverses déformations cérébrales et une importante épileptogénicité. IRM a révolutionné la prise en charge clinique de ces pathologies en raison de sa capacité incomparable à mettre en évidence des caractéristiques pathologiques. Cependant, sa sensibilité actuelle ne permet pas d'identifier la lésion focale dans l'ensemble du spectre des MDC, notamment dans le cas de discrètes anomalies, rendant difficile un diagnostic clinique fiable. Différentes études basées sur des données histologiques et d'IRM ont indiqué que des anomalies structurelles au niveau de la lésion focale pourraient s'étendre à des régions corticales éloignées. Alors que ces découvertes, suggèrent des substrats pathologiques distribués, les modèles anatomiques et principes topologiques sous-jacents aux MDC demeurent peu clairs. Objectif. Développer des méthodes computationnelles et d'imagerie multimodale avancée pour identifier et caractériser les MDC, ainsi que phénotyper la structure de l'ensemble du cerveau et son organisation en réseau.Méthodes. Nous avons effectué les projets suivants : 1) Implémentation d'une méthode de classification par apprentissage automatique reposant sur des paramètres IRM, afin de détecter de discrètes malformations; 2) Evaluation d'altérations structurelles du cerveau entier en utilisant l'épaisseur corticale et la complexité des circonvolutions corticales; 3) Développement d'un nouveau cadre pour caractériser la morphologie, l'intensité, la diffusion et la fonction de la lésion coupable; 4) Analyse statistique et selon la théorie des graphes du réseau cérébral structurel et fonctionnel chez les patients atteints de MDC. Résultats. Dans le projet 1, notre classificateur a identifié avec précision de subtiles DCF initialement négligées par une évaluation radiologique de routine. L'algorithme a montré une excellente sensibilité (74%) et une spécificité parfaite (100%). IRM et intensités de champs. Dans le projet 2, nous avons démontré que les anomalies s'étendent à partir de la lésion primaire vers des aires corticales éloignées, selon des modèles dépendant de différents sous-types pathologiques. Spécifiquement, les DCF de type I (uniquement caractérisées par une dyslamination à l'histologie) présentaient un amincissement cortical étendu, tandis que les type II (dyslamination et neurones dysmorphiques) étaient associées à un épaississement cortical bilatéral. La complexité des circonvolutions corticales divergeait également, augmentée dans les DCF de type I et diminuée dans celles de type II. Le projet 3 nous a permis de distinguer par IRM, au sein des sous-types de DCF sus-décrits, différentes entités : les DFC de type IIA, caractérisées par des neurones dysmorphiques isolés, et celles de type IIB, où une dyslamination est associée à la présence de cellules en ballons. En effet, en utilisant un profilage avancé intralésionnel et sous-cortical, nous avons retrouvé des marqueurs d'altération de morphologie, d'intensité, de diffusion et de fonction dans le type II-B, tandis que les DCF de type II-A se présentaient uniquement avec des changements modérés d'intensité et de diffusion près de la jonction substance blanche – substance grise. Enfin, le projet 4 a montré une réogranisation du réseau à large échelle dans les MDC. L'importance des anomalies suit un gradient possiblement en rapport avec l'évolution chronologique du processus malformatif sous-jacent. En effet, les FCD de type II, liées à des anomalies de la prolifération neuronale se déroulant aux premiers stades du développement cortical, présentent de discrets changements. Les hétérotopies de substance grise, liées à des anomalies de la migration neuronale, montrent quant à elles des changements intermédiaires. Enfin, les polymicrogyries liées à une désorganisation corticale tardive présentent une altération marquée de l'architecture du réseau cortical.</description><description>Background. Malformations of cortical development (MCD) are a group of congenital anomalies characterized by variable brain deformations and high epileptogenicity. MRI has revolutionized the clinical management of this disorder because of its unmatched ability to visualize pathological substrates. Yet, the current sensitivity to identify the primary lesion has a limit in covering the full spectrum of MCD, especially those with mild anomalies. Notably, sporadic histological and MRI studies have indicated that structural anomalies in the primary lesion may extend to remote cortical areas. While these findings suggest distributed pathological substrates, the anatomical patterns and topological principles underlying MCD remain poorly understood.Purpose. To develop advanced multimodal imaging and computational frameworks for the characterization and identification of MCD, and phenotype their whole-brain structure and network organization. Methods. We carried out following projects: 1) Implementation of an automated machine-learning classifier relying on surface-based MRI features to detect subtle malformations; 2) Evaluation of whole-brain morphology using cortical thickness and folding complexity; 3) Development of a novel framework to characterize morphology, intensity, diffusion, and function of the primary lesion; 4) Statistical and graph-theoretical analysis of structural-functional brain network across the MCD spectrum.Results. In project 1, our classifier accurately identified subtle FCD initially overlooked on routine radiological assessment. The algorithm showed an excellent sensitivity (74%), while achieving a perfect specificity (100%) in controls. The performance revealed generalizability across different cohorts, scanners, and field strengths. In project 2, we demonstrated that anomalies extend beyond the primary lesion to remote cortical areas, showing distinctive patterns relative to pathological subtypes. Specifically, FCD Type-I (characterized only by cortical dyslamination on histology) displayed widespread cortical thinning, while Type-II (dyslamination together with dysmorphic neurons) was associated with bilateral cortical thickening. Cortical folding complexity also diverged, with increases in Type-I and decreases in Type-II. Distinctive MRI signatures were also demonstrated in project 3, where we were able to dissociate within-subtype entities, namely FCD Type-IIA (characterized by isolated dysmorphic neurons) and IIB (dyslamination together with balloon cells). Indeed, by using advanced intra- and subcortical lesion profiling, we found marked patterns of abnormal morphology, intensity, diffusivity and function in Type-IIB, compared to IIA which presented with only mild intensity and diffusion changes close to the grey-white matter interface. These group-level findings were validated in single patients by machine-learning, which predicted with &gt;90% accuracy FCD histological subtypes in vivo based on MRI features. Finally, project 4 demonstrated large-scale network reorganization in MCD. The extent of anomalies followed a gradient relative to the putative timing of the underlying malformative process. Indeed, subtle changes were associated with FCD Type-II due to atypical neuronal proliferation occurring at the earliest stages of cortical development, intermediate effects were found in migration-related heterotopias, and markedly impacted cortical network architecture was seen in polymicrogyrias, malformations likely due to late-stage cortical disorganization.Significance. The proposed computational models enable the detection of the most-subtle malformative lesion with unprecedented accuracy, paving the way to surgical treatment for patients in whom conventional means are non-diagnostic. Furthermore, our studies unveiling large-scale organizational properties provide novel insights into the underlying anatomical and developmental principles of the most common epileptogenic cortical malformations. </description><creator>Hong, Suk Jun</creator><contributor>Andrea Bernasconi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Advanced multimodal imaging in epileptogenic malformations of cortical development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nh41h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr524</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd3760176</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Breast and prostate cancer are two most common malignancies associated with skeletal metastasis which affect the quality of life and result in high rate of mortality. Various lifestyle choices, genetic disposition and epigenetic factors can favour the process of cancer initiation and progression. Early detection of epigenetic changes can lead to early diagnosis and enhance treatment options for cancer patients to block skeletal metastasis and reduce cancer associated morbidity and mortality. In order to understand the role of epigenetics in cancer progression, I utilised two human osteosarcoma (OS) cell lines and treated them with a DNA methylating agent S-adenosylmethionine (SAM) and its inactive analogue s-adenosylhomocysteine (SAH) as a control. Treatment with SAM reduced the expression of tumor promoting genes and significantly decreased the proliferation and migration of tumor cells. In the xenograft model of OS where LM&amp; cells were inoculated via tail vein and directly into tibia, both lung and bone metastases were significantly reduced in the experimental group as compared to the control group of animals. To determine the epigenetic alterations in OS, I utilized SAM treated LM7 cell line and performed epigenome wide association studies (EWAS). The results showed significant differential methylation in genes involved in tumor progression and bone remodelling. The results were further validated by immunohistochemcial analysis of the identified genes on human OS tissue samples.Cancer immunosurveillance is a well-known mechanism by which immune system keeps a check on transformed cancer cells. We hypothesized that DNA methylation signature of breast cancer can be found in peripheral cells of the immune system. Towards these goals I employed T-cell DNA samples obtained from the blood of breast cancer patients. The DNA methylation signatures present in breast cancer patients were compared to an age matched cohort of normal women by EWAS analysis. The results showed significant differential methylation in genes involved in the phosphatase and tensin homolog (PTEN), p53 and retinoic acid receptor (RAR) activation pathways in breast cancer patients. I also investigated the DNA methylation pattern in post-menopausal women with osteoporosis, which is the most common bone disease associated with high incidence of morbidity. Whole blood DNA samples from osteoporotic women and age matched normal women were utilised for EWAS analysis. Results from these studies showed differential methylation of several genes involved in transcriptional regulation, angiogenesis, apoptosis and immune checkpoint pathways.Collectively these studies demonstrate an intricate relationship between epigenetic modifications in cancer progression and bone remodelling. The results presented pave the way for development of novel epigenetic based diagnostic tools and better treatment of metastatic cancers.</description><description>Le cancer du sein et de la prostate sont fréquemment associés aux métastases osseuses qui affectent grandement la qualité de vie des patients atteints et augmentent ainsi le taux de mortalité. Le mode de vie, la prédisposition génétique et les facteurs épigénétiques jouent un rôle important dans le développement et la progression du cancer. Un dépistage rapide des changements épigénétique permet un diagnostic précoce et des choix plus efficaces dans le traitement des métastases osseuses afin de réduire les taux de mobilité et mortalité.  Le rôle de l'épigénétique dans la progression du cancer a été étudié chez deux lignées cellulaires humaines d'ostéosarcome (OS) traitées avec un agent de méthylation de l'ADN, S-Adenosylmethionine (SAM) ou avec un analogue inactif S-Adenosylhomocysteine (SAH) comme contrôle. Le traitement au SAM réduisait l'expression des gènes favorisant la formation des tumeurs et diminuait de façon significative la prolifération et la migration des cellules tumorales. De plus, l'étude in-vivo, à l'aide d'un modèle de tumeur xénogreffée, où les souris sonts inoculées avec des métastases osseuses et pulmonaires, soit directement dans le tibia ou par la veine de la queue, a démontré une réduction significative des métastases dans le groupe traité au SAM comparé au groupe contrôle. Pour déterminer les altérations épigénétiques dans l'ostéosarcome métastasique, les cellules métastasiques dérivées de l'ostéosarcome humain (LM7) sont traitées au SAM et analysées avec la méthode de l'association épigénétique à l'échelle du génome (EWAS). Les résultats ont mis en évidence de la présence d'une méthylation différentielle significative au niveau des gènes impliqués dans la progression tumorale et le renouvellement osseux. Les gènes identifiés sont aussi validés par la suite par les analyses immunohistochimiques sur les échantillons de l'ostéosarcome métastasique humains. L'immunosurveillance est un mécanisme bien connu qui permet au système immunitaire de surveiller la transformation des cellules cancéreuses. Nous avons postulé que la méthylation de l'ADN des gènes associés spécifiquement au cancer du sein pourrait être détectée dans les cellules du système immunitaire périphérique. Afin de confirmer notre hypothèse, les échantillons de l'ADN des lymphocytes T, isolés à partir du sang des patientes atteintes du cancer du sein, ont été analysés par EWAS en comparaison avec un groupe contrôle de femmes de même âge. Les résultats obtenus chez les patientes atteintes du cancer du sein ont démontré qu'il y avait bien une méthylation différentielle significative des gènes impliqués dans les voies de signalisation des suppresseurs de tumeurs (PTEN), impliquant les phosphatases et les homologues de tensin, de p53 et de l'activation du récepteur de l'acide rétinoïde (RAR). Le phénomène de la méthylation de l'ADN a été aussi étudié chez les femmes ménopausées souffrant d'ostéoporose, une maladie osseuse fréquemment associée à un indice élevé de morbidité. L'analyse EWAS des échantillons de l'ADN, isolés du sang des femmes de mêmes âges avec ou sans ostéoporose, a démontré qu'il y avait une méthylation différentielle de plusieurs gènes impliqués dans les processus tels que la régulation de la transcription, l'angiogenèse, l'apoptose ainsi que les points de contrôle des voies de régulation du système immunitaire. L'ensemble des études de cette thèse démontre une relation très complexe entre les modifications épigénétique, observées dans la progression du cancer, et les processus de renouvellement osseux. Les résultats présentés ouvrent la voie au développement de nouveaux outils de diagnostiques à base épigénétique et à un meilleur traitement de cancers métastatiques. </description><creator>Parashar, Surabhi</creator><contributor>Shafaat A Rabbani (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Role of DNA methylation in skeletal metastasis and bone remodeling: diagnostic, prognostic and therapeutic implications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x57q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd3760176</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m677h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans ce mémoire, nous appliquons et développons des techniques de génétique des populations pour étudier les populations métissées et géographiquement étendues. Nous nous concentrons sur les longs haplotypes partagés résultant de lien de parenté et de métissage récent entre les ancêtres d'une population. Nous utilisons des méthodes statistiques développées récemment pour améliorer l'inférence de l'origine géographique d'haplotypes dans des populations métissées.Nous appliquons ces résultats à trois problèmes en génétique médicale et en génétique des populations. Premièrement, nous effectuons une analyse de cartographie du métissage pour identifier des locus responsables de la différence de sensibilité à la douleur par chaleur observée entre les Euro-Américains et Afro-Américains. En tenant compte des variables parasites, nous identifions une région génétique significative pangénomiquement qui comprend le gene C10orf11. Deuxièmement, nous étudions l'évolution du phénotype pygmée, en considérant la corrélation entre ancêtre et taille parmi des chasseurs-cueilleurs vivant dans la forêt équatoriale. Troisièmement, nous étudions la distribution des ancêtres d'origine européenne, africaine et autochtone à travers les États-Unis (ÉU) dans trois cohortes. Nous trouvons des différences entre les cohortes et entre les régions qui sont compatibles avec les méthodes d'échantillionage et les migrations historiques. Pour interpréter ces résultats, nous développons une méthode non-paramétrique qui utilise les longs haplotypes partagés entre des individus, ou n'importe quelle mesure de parenté, pour inférer des migrations dans des populations géographiquement étendues.Nous appliquons notre méthode pour modéliser les migrations des Afro-Américains dans les ÉU en analysant les données de la cohorte Health and Retirement Study (HRS). Nous identifions des routes de migration qui sont compatibles avec la Grande Migration Afro-Américaine.</description><description>In this thesis, we apply and develop population genetics techniques to study admixed and spatially extended populations. We focus on the long haplotype patterns resulting from relatedness and recent admixture among the ancestors of a population. We use recently developed statistical methods to improve the inference of geographic origin of individual haplotypes in admixed population cohorts. We take advantage of these methods to address three problems in population and medical genetics. First, we perform an admixture mapping analysis to identify loci associated with the observed difference in heat pain sensitivity between African-Americans and European-Americans. Correcting for possible confounders, we identify one genome-wide significant genomic region containing the C10orf11 gene. Second, we studied the evolution of the pygmy phenotype by considering the correlation between ancestry and height among rainforest hunter-gatherers. Third, we studied the distribution of European, African, and Native American ancestry across the United States (US) in three different cohorts and find variation across cohorts and across regions consistent with sampling schemes and historical migrations. To interpret the latter results, we developed a non-parametric method that uses long shared haplotypes between individuals, or any other measure of relatedness, to infer migratory events in spatially extended populations. We apply our method to model African-American migrations in the US by analyzing the Health and Retirement Study (HRS) Cohort data. We identify migratory routes that are consistent with the historical event known as the Great Migration.</description><creator>Barakatt, Maxime</creator><contributor>Mathieu Blanchette (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Simon Gravel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Genetics and geography in admixed populations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t897c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m677h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qs33j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Modern fantasy must be analyzed as a modernist literature that posits a critical gesture of refusal of the conditions of modernity. As a form of irrealism, a category that includes Gothic and magic realism, fantasy claims to represent a deeper realism even if it uses non-realist techniques to do so. The combined and uneven capitalist world-system inscribes itself in the urban fantasy of Charles de Lint, which as a peripheral modernism combines residual forms and folkloric, non-modern content within the realist novel. This symbolic act allegorizes 'the synchronicity of the non-synchronous,' a principal condition of modernity. In de Lint's novel Moonheart, the uneven relationship between colonizer and colonized becomes symbolically resolved through its utopian romance structure, despite the incapability of the Canadian state's policy of multiculturalism to redress First Nations inequality. Mulengro expands the Gothic horror of a Rom superstition into a diagnosis of the general conditions of alienation that haunt modern capitalist society. In Dreams Underfoot, de Lint's short story collection, fantasy represents the unevenness of cities, where the right to the urban life is at stake within the sublime urban totality.</description><creator>Rettino, Matthew</creator><contributor>Sandeep Banerjee (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>English</subject><title>Fantasy as a peripheral modernism: uneven development in Charles de Lint's Urban Fantasy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f6228.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qs33j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720g552</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le mécanisme principal de cyclogenèse aux latitudes moyennes est l'instabilité barocline. Le taux de croissance barocline, aussi appelé taux de croissance maximum de Eady, est un indicateur quantifiant cette instabilité. Un taux de croissance barocline calculé en prenant en compte les processus atmosphériques humides est utilisé dans le développement d'un indice de l'activité des tempêtes dans l'Atlantique Nord. Cet indice est défini comme l'étendue surfacique normalisée des maxima de taux de croissance dans le bassin de l'Atlantique Nord. Une étendue zonale continue significative d'une durée déterminée définit un évènement. Ces évènements sont des régimes météorologiques synoptiques à basse fréquence.Ces régimes ont été caractérisés par des masses d'air froid significativement anormales par rapport au champ d'épaisseur de l'atmosphère de 1000-500 hPa. Une intensification du gradient de température a été associée à ces masses d'air, souvent accompagnée d'une masse d'air anormalement chaude au sud, avec une expansion et une augmentation significative de l'intensité du courant jet de l'Atlantique Nord. Précédant les évènements, le réchauffement troposphérique a augmenté dans le voisinage d'une crête amplifiée dans les niveaux supérieurs de l'atmosphère, au-dessus des Aléoutiennes. Cela a soutenu le développement de la masse d'air froid sur le continent nord-américain.Ces évènements ont été associés avec un nombre anormalement élevé de cyclogenèse explosive, aussi nommée bombogenèse, dans l'Atlantique Nord. Des taux d'intensification très élevés, pouvant être classés de bombogenèse moyenne à bombogenèse forte, y ont également été associés.</description><description>The main mechanism of cyclogenesis in the midlatitudes is baroclinic instability. A measure of this instability is called the baroclinic growth rate, often referred to as the Eady maximum growth rate. A form of this metric incorporating moist processes was used in the development of an index for storminess in the North Atlantic. This was defined as the normalized areal coverage of growth rate maxima in the North Atlantic basin. Events were defined as continuously significant areal coverage for a specified duration. They are low-frequency, synoptic-scale weather regimes.These regimes were characterized by significantly anomalous cold air masses, as described by the 1000-500 hPa thickness field. Associated with these air masses was an intensification of the temperature gradient, often with an anomalously warm air mass to the south, and an equally significant strengthening and spatial expansion of the North Atlantic jet stream. Prior to the events there was enhanced tropospheric warming in the vicinity of an amplified upper-level ridge over the Aleutians. This helped support the development of the cold air mass over the North American continent.The events were associated with an anomalously large number of hours of explosive cyclogenesis, or bombogenesis, in the North Atlantic, and very high deepening rates, generally within the moderate and strong classifications of bombogenesis.</description><creator>Ronalds, Bryn</creator><contributor>John Richard Gyakum (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</subject><title>On the relationship between North Atlantic moist baroclinic growth rate regimes and surface cyclogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw494.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g552</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f399k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction : À ce jour, le monde médical n'a trouvé aucun moyen de guérir la maladie d'Alzheimer (MA). La cascade pathophysiologique de cette maladie débute des décennies avant l'apparition de la démence. De ce fait, les interventions thérapeutiques qui ciblent la MA sont actuellement tournés vers la prévention. Pour cibler un traitement préventif, il est nécessaire d'avoir des indicateurs précoces ou « biomarqueurs », de la maladie d'Alzheimer dans sa phase pré-symptomatique. La fonction auditive centrale (FAC) est affectée chez des patients atteints de la MA et également chez ceux qui présente un trouble neurocognitifs légers. Un dysfonctionnement dans la FAC peut même prédire l'apparition de la démence chez des individus cognitivement normaux, avec un hazard ratio jusqu'à 9.9. Nous avons donc examiné si la FAC pourrait être un biomarqueur de la MA en étudiant les liens entre la FAC et d'autres biomarqueurs de la maladie, dans la phase pré-symptomatique. Méthodes : La FAC des participants a été évaluée par deux examens; la compréhension dans un milieu bruyant (Synthetic Sentence Identification with Ipsilateral Competing Message (SSI-ICM); n=177) et la séparation binaurale (Dichotic Sentence Identification (DSI); n=187). Ils ont également complétés des tests cognitifs standards, des imageries cérébrales par IRM et IRM fonctionnelle, des ponctions lombaires ainsi que des analyses génétiques. Les relations entre ces mesures et la FAC ont été évaluées par des régressions linéaires robustes (robust-fit) corrigées pour les covariables. Résultats : Les résultats au test SSI-ICM étaient corrélés positivement aux résultats cognitifs pour l'attention uniquement (t=3,32, p=0,001). Pour les résultats au DSI, ils étaient corrélés positivement avec l'attention (t=3,73, p&lt;0,001), la mémoire immédiate (t=3,94, p&lt;0.001), la construction visuospatiale (t=2.15, p=0.032), langage (t=2,62, p=0,01) et la mémoire différée (t=3,30, p=0,001) mais uniquement pour les résultats provenant de l'oreille la moins performante (OMP). En calculant le degré de supériorité de l'oreille droite (DSOD) au test du DSI, les relations avec les scores cognitifs sont similaires en plus d'obtenir des corrélations avec les niveaux de protéines tau totales (t-tau) et de tau phosphorylé (p-tau) dans le liquide céphalo-rachidien (LCR) (t=2,16,  p=0,035 &amp; t=2,10,  p=0,040; en ordre respectif). Ces relations avec les protéines du LCR sont similaires pour les résultats du DSI pour l'OMP. Le DSOD au test du DSI est également positivement corrélé au volume du cortex entorhinal gauche (t=-2.17, p=0.031). Les scores de SSI-ICM sont corrélés à l'épaisseur du cortex parahippocampal droit, du cortex entorhinal, du precuneus bilatéral, du cortex occipital, du lobule pariétal inférieur et du gyrus temporal inférieur et moyen. Le DSOD au test du DSI est relié à l'épaisseur du gyrus temporal supérieur gauche et transverse, le gyrus temporal inférieur bilatéral, à l'épaisseur du pole temporal antérieur droit, du precuneus et du gyrus frontal dorsomedial et inférieur. Conclusion : La FAC a le potentiel d'être un biomarqueurs non-invasif et peu couteux pour détecter de façon précoce la progression de la MA dans sa phase pré-symptomatique.</description><description>Introduction: Attempts to cure the scourge of Alzheimer's disease (AD) are not working. The AD pathological cascade starts decades before onset of dementia. Therefore, the focus of AD therapeutics is shifting toward prevention. To choose promising preventive treatments, we need early indicators or biomarkers, of pre-symptomatic AD.  Central Auditory Processing (CAP) is impaired in patients who have AD dementia and its predecessor, Mild Cognitive Impairment. Dysfunction in CAP may also predict incident dementia in cognitively normal individuals, with a hazard ratio up to 9.9. We therefore examined whether CAP could be a potential biomarker of AD by studying its relationship with other biomarkers in pre-symptomatic disease. Methods: Participants were given tests of speech-in-noise comprehension (Synthetic Sentence with Ipsilateral Competing Message test (SSI-ICM); n = 177), and binaural separation (Dichotic Sentence Identification test (DSI); n = 187). They also completed traditional cognitive testing, structural and functional MRI, lumbar punctures, and genetic testing. Linear robust-fit regression assessed the relationship between these measures and CAP, controlling for covariates. Results: The SSI-ICM related to cognitive score for attention (t = 3.32, p = 0.001), while the DSI worse ear scores (WES) related to this (t = 3.73, p &lt; 0.001) and other tasks including immediate memory (t = 3.94, p &lt; 0.001), visuospatial construction (t = 2.15, p= 0.032), language (t = 2.62, p = 0.01), and delayed memory (t = 3.30, p = 0.001). The DSI right ear advantage (REA) score showed similar results, and also correlated with levels of CSF total tau (t-tau; t = 2.16, p = 0.035) and phospho-tau (P-tau; t = 2.10, p = 0.040), while the DSI WES showed similar trends. DSI REA also related to left entorhinal cortical volume (t = -2.17, p = 0.031). SSI-ICM score related to thickness of right parahippocampal and entorhinal cortices, bilateral precuneus and occipital cortices and left inferior parietal lobule and inferior and middle temporal gyri. DSI REA related to thickness of the left superior and transverse temporal gyri, bilateral inferior temporal gyri, and the thickness of right anterior temporal pole, precuneus, dorsomedial frontal and inferior frontal gyri. Conclusion: CAP may be an inexpensive and non-invasive biomarker for pre-symptomatic AD. </description><creator>Tuwaig, Miranda</creator><contributor>John Breitner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Central auditory processing as a marker for disease progression in individuals at risk for Alzheimer's dementia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d01m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f399k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hj24q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La mémoire épisodique est la capacité à se souvenir d'un élément ou un événement dans le détail riche contextuel. Le vieillissement normale est associé à une baisse de cette capacité, en plus de l'amincissement cortical généralisée. Ces baisses parallèles suggèrent que les changements liés à l'âge dans l'épaisseur corticale (EC) peuvent contribuer au déclin de la mémoire épisodique avec l'âge. Comme peu d'études ont examiné directement cette association, cette étude vise à explorer par methode transversale si l'épaisseur corticale (EC) régionale médiatise la relation entre l'âge et la mémoire épisodique telle que mesurée par une tâche de mémoire de contexte pour les visages. Les régions du cerveau examinées dans la présente étude ont été précédemment associée à la performance de la mémoire épisodique et démontre un amincissement associée à l'âge dans un échantillon d'adultes en bonne santé (N = 114). Les régions sur la gauche étaient les gyri lingual, fusiforme, rectus, parahippocampal, frontal supérieur, frontal moyen caudale, frontal inférieur, angulaire, et supramarginal; et les régions sur la droite étaient les gyri parahippocampal, rectus, angulaire, supramarginal, supérieure temporelle, temporelle, frontale supérieure du milieu, frontal moyen caudale et frontal inférieur. Des modèles de médiation conditionnelle ont été testés à l'aide de bootstrapping afin de déterminer si et comment ces régions médiatisent les changements liés à l'âge de la performance sur la tâche de mémoire de contexte. Il a été constaté que la EC des gyri parahippocampal droite et frontale supérieure droite étaient liés à la performance différentiellement avec l'âge, ce qu'appuye la conception que les relations de mémoire épisodique- matière gris changent avec l'âge. Les modèles ont également démontré que EC régionale médite la variance associée à l'âge de la performance de mémoire de contexte d'une manière qui est conditionnelle à l'âge. Aussi, l'analyse courante a identifié une dissociation entre la médiation de EC sur la variance de performance associée à l'âge, et la capacité de EC regionale pour prédire la performance après avoir ajuster pour l'âge. Dans l'ensemble, ces résultats soulignent l'importance de mettre en œuvre une approche longitudinale parce que l'examen des changements intra-individuels au fil du temps serait mieux pour démêler comment les changements d'EC associée à l'âge affectent la mémoire de contexte, sans la nécessité de tenir compte des relations d'EC- mémoire épisodique en raison de facteurs autres que l'âge.</description><description>Episodic memory is the ability to remember an item or event in rich contextual detail. Healthy aging is associated with declines in this ability in addition to widespread cortical thinning. These parallel declines suggest that age-related changes in cortical thickness may contribute to episodic memory decline with age. As few studies have directly examined this association, the current study aims to cross-sectionally explore whether regional cortical thickness (CT) mediates the relationship between age and episodic memory as measured by a context memory task for faces. The brain regions examined in the current study have been previously associated with episodic memory performance and demonstrate age-associated cortical thinning in the current healthy lifespan sample (N= 114). The regions on the left were lingual, fusiform, rectus, parahippocampal, superior frontal, caudal middle frontal, inferior frontal, angular, and supramarginal gyri; and the regions on the right were parahippocampal, rectus, angular, supramarginal, superior temporal, middle temporal, superior frontal, caudal middle frontal, and inferior frontal gyri. Conditional mediation models were tested using bootstrapping in order to determine whether and how these regions mediate age-associated changes in performance on the context memory task. It was found that CT of the right parahippocampal and superior frontal gyri were related to performance differentially with age, lending support to the conception that grey matter-episodic memory relationships change with age. The models also demonstrated that regional CT mediated age-associated variance in context memory performance in a way that is conditional upon age. Furthermore, the current analysis identified a dissociation between CT of a region mediating age-associated variance in accuracy, and predicting accuracy after controlling for age. Overall, these findings underscore the importance of implementing a longitudinal approach because the examination of intra-individual changes over time would better tease out how age-related changes in CT affect context memory, without the need to account for CT-episodic memory relationships due to factors other than age.</description><creator>Swierkot, Alexander</creator><contributor>Maria Rajah (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Psychiatry</subject><title>Relationships between age-associated changes in context memory and cortical thickness across the adult lifespan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ck19p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hj24q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc47j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rab GTPases are critical regulators of membrane trafficking and not surprisingly defects in Rabs contribute to various human diseases. For example, Rab13 is associated with several phenotypes associated with cancer, but the regulation of Rab13 in membrane trafficking is poorly understood. The general objective of this doctoral research was to study the function and regulation of Rab13 in endosomal trafficking. Rabs cycle between an active GTP-bound form and an inactive GDP-bound form. Upon activation by guanine nucleotide exchange factors, Rabs associate with membranes where they recruit effector molecules to mediate their downstream response. However, the spatio-temporal activation of Rab13 was unknown. Furthermore, the DENN-domain is an evolutionarily conserved protein module that functions enzymatically as guanine nucleotide exchange factors for Rabs. Here, we identified the DENN containing protein DENND2B as guanine nucleotide exchange factor for Rab13 and uncover a mechanism whereby activation of Rab13 by DENND2B in a complex with the Rab13 effector MICAL-L2 at the cell periphery drives cancer cell migration, invasion, and tumor metastasis. Furthermore, active Rabs typically anchor to membranes using a hydrophobic prenyl modification and dissociate from membranes upon inactivation. Here we discovered that Rab13 traffics on vesicles in its inactive form as part of a protein complex independent of prenylation. Therefore, in this doctoral thesis we have provided a detailed characterization of the regulation of Rab13 in endosomal trafficking. </description><description>Les protéines de type Rab GTPases sont des régulateurs essentiels dans le trafic intracellulaire membranaire.  Il n'est donc pas surprenant de constater que leur mauvais fonctionnement puisse causer différentes pathologies chez l'humain.  À titre d'exemple, Rab13 est associée à plusieurs phénotypes observés dans les cancers mais son fonctionnement dans le trafic cellulaire n'est toujours pas élucidé. L'objectif de cette thèse de doctorat était de mettre en lumière la fonction et la régulation de Rab13 dans le trafic endosomal.  Les protéines de type Rab oscillent entre une forme active liée au nucléotide GTP et une forme inactive liée au nucléotide GDP.  Après avoir été activées par les facteurs d'échange du nucléotide guanine, les Rabs s'associent aux membranes d'où elles recrutent d'autres molécules effectrices afin d'initier leur réponse cellulaire.  Toutefois, la réponse spatio-temporelle de Rab13 était jusqu'à maintenant inconnue.  Nous avons découvert la protéine DENND2B comme étant le facteur d'échange guanidique pour Rab13.  De plus, nous également révélé un mécanisme d'activation par lequel Rab13 et DENND2B en complexe protéique avec la protéine MICAL-L2 favorise la migration des cellules cancéreuses, l'invasion et le processus métastatique.  De plus, les formes actives des protéines Rabs se lient aux membranes par leur modification hydrophique de type prénylique pour ensuite s'en dissocier lors de leur inactivation.  Nos travaux démontrent que Rab13 trafique sur les vésicules membranaires dans leur forme inactive de façon non-tributaire de la prénylation.  Cette thèse de doctorat nous a donc permis de mettre en lumière un mécanisme clair et détaillé concernant la régulation de la protéine Rab13 dans le trafic endosomal.</description><creator>Ioannou, Maria</creator><contributor>Peter Scott McPherson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>The regulation of Rab13 in endosomal trafficking</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tp567.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc47j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jx27r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent studies suggest increased prevalence of food allergy and food-induced anaphylaxis. While genetics is likely to play a significant role in the development of food allergy, this rapid increase in prevalence implies a substantial role for modifiable environmental factors. I established a twin registry to assess gene-environment interactions in the development of food allergy. I assessed the concordance rate for food allergy in pairs of monozygotic (MZ) and dizygotic  (DZ) twins, for the 5 most common food allergies (peanuts, tree nuts, seafood, milk, and egg)  and, I evaluated the effect of environmental factors, lifestyle habits and the presence of atopic co-morbidities on the concordance of food allergies. Among 28 and 31 pairs of MZ and DZ twins respectively, concordance rates for peanut, cashew/pistachio, and egg allergy, were greater in DZ twins  ( (0.59 (%95CI 0.39, 0.77) vs. (0.50 (%95CI 0.26, 0.70),  difference of 0.09 (%95 CI 0.05, 0.42), (0.55 (%95CI 0.29, 0.81) vs. (0.5 (%95 CI 0.27, 0.72), difference of 0.05 (%95 CI 0.02, 0.80),     (0.51 (%95CI 0.19, 0.74) vs. 0.22 (%95 CI 0.03, 0.59) difference of 0.29 (%95 CI 0.11, 0.78)). respectively, implying that environmental factors contribute more in the development of those allergies. After controlling for age and sex, asthma was associated with concordance in almond and hazelnut allergy (OR 2.09, 95%CI 1.47, 3.04), (OR 2.11, 95%CI 1.63, 2.74) respectively.  Eczema (diagnosed in the first 2 years of life) was associated with concordance in peanut, pecan/walnut, cashew/pistachio, fish, and egg allergy ((OR 1.32, 95%CI 1.05, 1.83), (OR 2.32, 95%CI 1.58, 3.92) (OR 1.81, 95%CI 1.21, 2.68), (OR 2.15, 95%CI 1.96, 2.37), (OR 1.47, 95%CI 1.00, 2.14), respectively. My results indicate that environmental factors have an influence on cashew/pistachio, egg and peanut allergy, and that eczema (diagnosed in the first 2 years of life) and asthma may be modifiable risk factors in the development of the 5 most common food allergies (peanuts, tree nuts, milk, egg and shellfish). However, wide CI's and small sample size preclude any definitive conclusions. </description><description>Des résultats d'études récentes concluent que les taux d'anaphylaxies et d'allergies alimentaires sont plus hauts que jamais.   Il est dit que la génétique joue un rôle significatif dans le développement d'allergies alimentaires. Par contre, il est important de noter que la croissance soudaine et rapide de la prévalence d'allergies alimentaires implique forcément la contribution de facteurs environnementaux.      J'ai établi un registre de jumeaux identiques et fraternels, pour déterminer la contribution relative de facteurs génétiques et environnementaux envers le développement des allergies alimentaires les plus courantes (arachides, noix, crustacés, lait, œufs). J'ai aussi évalué l'effet qu'on les facteurs environnementaux, les facteurs de style de vies, et la présence de maladies atopiques sur le développement des même allergies. La concordance  d'allergies aux arachides, noix de Grenoble et œufs était plus élevée chez les jumeaux fraternels ((0.59 (%95CI 0.39, 0.77) vs. (0.50 (%95CI 0.26, 0.70),  avec une différence de 0.09 (%95 CI 0.05, 0.42), (0.55 (%95CI 0.29, 0.81) vs. (0.5 (%95 CI 0.27, 0.72), avec une différence de 0.05 (%95 CI 0.02, 0.80),  (0.51 (%95CI 0.19, 0.74) vs. 0.22 (%95 CI 0.03, 0.59) avec une différence de 0.29 (%95 CI 0.11, 0.78)) respectivement. Ceci suggère une contribution de facteurs environnementaux plus importante envers ces allergies. Une fois que l'âge et le sexe des jumeaux on était contrôlé, une association s'est manifestée entre l'asthme et la concordance d'allergie aux amandes et noisettes (OR 2.09, 95%CI 1.47, 3.04), (OR 2.11, 95%CI 1.63, 2.74) respectivement. Une association s'est aussi présentée entre l'eczéma infantile et la concordance d'allergie aux arachides, pacanes, pistaches, poissons, et œufs ((OR 1.32, 95%CI 1.05, 1.83), (OR 2.32, 95%CI 1.58, 3.92) (OR 1.81, 95%CI 1.21, 2.68), (OR 2.15, 95%CI 1.96, 2.37), (OR 1.47, 95%CI 1.00, 2.14)) respectivement. Mes résultats suggèrent que les facteurs environnementaux influence les allergies aux pistaches, œufs et arachides. Et que la présence d'asthme et d'eczéma rouent un rôle important dans le développement des allergies alimentaires les plus courantes. </description><creator>Dery, Alizee</creator><contributor>Moshe Ben-Shoshan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Bruce Mazer (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>"START": Susceptibility to food allergies in a registry of twins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s7527.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jx27r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117r61v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Nechalacho REE-Nb-Zr deposit at Thor Lake, Northwest Territories, Canada, consists of layers of hydrothermally altered eudialyte syenite. With combined measured, indicated and inferred resources of 269 Mt grading 1.47 wt. % REE-oxide, 0.35 wt. % Nb2O5 and 2.59 wt. % ZrO2, the deposit is one of the largest REE deposits in the World. The principal primary magmatic REE-Nb-mineral is kentbrooksite (eudialyte). Strong hydrothermal alteration led to its replacement by fergusonite-(Y), samarskite-(Y), columbite-(Fe) and -(Mn), xenotime-(Y), monazite-(Ce), bastnäsite-(Ce), parisite-(Ce), synchysite-(Ce), allanite-(Ce) and zircon. The host aegirine-nepheline syenite was metasomatically replaced by a phlogopite-quartz-magnetite-ankerite-fluorite assemblage. Peripheral pegmatites, the T-, R- and S-Zones, contain high-grade Li, Be, REE and Nb mineralization. The host to the Nechalacho REE-Nb-Zr deposit is an agpaitic nepheline syenite intrusion, the Nechalacho Layered Suite, which crosscuts the anorogenic 2176 Ma Blatchford Lake Igneous Complex. The laccolithic intrusion has a diameter of ~1.9 km, is &gt;1.1 km thick and displays modal layering of nepheline, sodalite, end-member aegirine and annite, K-feldspar, albite and eudialyte. A U-Pb zircon concordia age of 2176.0 ± 2.7 Ma shows that the nepheline syenites are contemporaneous with the other units of the complex. The initial εNd(2176 Ma) was between 1.1 and 3.1, averaging 2.0, and δ18Omelt and δDmelt values calculated from magmatic minerals are 5.1 to 7.8‰ and  60‰, respectively. In the earlier alkaline granite and quartz syenites of the complex (Grace Lake Granite, Thor Lake Syenite, Rim Syenite), δ18Omelt and δDmelt were 6.7 to 8.1‰ and -99 to  93‰, respectively. Combined with whole-rock trace element profiles, this indicates that the units of the complex formed from melt batches extracted from a deep crustal feeder magma chamber in which a mantle-derived, heterogeneous mafic parental melt, that was similar to modern ocean island basalt, underwent fractional crystallization. The Nechalacho Layered Suite formed from the youngest and most evolved batch, which was magnesium-free and enriched in Zr, REE, Nb, carbon species, fluorine and chlorine. Mineral equilibria indicate that at ~800 to &lt;500 °C and a pressure of ~4 kbar, oxygen fugacity was initially below FMQ+0.2 to FMQ+1.3, and later increased in response to auto-oxidation of the melt by annite crystallization. In situ fractional crystallization proceeded upwards and downwards and REE, Nb and Zr were enriched in an iron-rich residual melt until the magma became saturated with respect to eudialyte. Mineral fractionation led to variations in light/heavy REE, Zr/Hf and Nb/Ta, with the Basal Zone recording the strongest heavy REE enrichment. Magmatic-hydrothermal auto-metasomatism associated with ankerite-bastnäsite-(Ce) mineralization is indicated by trends of δ13C from -6.3 to  2.7‰ and of δ18O from 11.3 to 15.0‰ for hydrothermal carbonates. Ankerite from the T-Zone has similar values, demonstrating a genetic link to the peripheral pegmatites at the magmatic-hydrothermal interface. U-Pb and Th-Pb ages of hydrothermal monazite-(Ce) from the Basal Zone (1871 ± 14 to 1835 ± 57 Ma) indicate a late regional hydrothermal overprint associated with faulting along the southern margin of the Slave Craton. Hydrothermal temperatures determined using oxygen isotopes are ~300 °C and the fluids had δ18O of 3.1-9.3‰ and δD of  24‰, suggesting a crustal origin. Mineral equilibria indicate that the alteration fluid was reducing (FMQ+2.0 to +3.7) and that pH was moderately acidic to mildly alkaline (between 3.7 and 5.7). Likely, the alteration fluid was initially acidic and neutralized upon reaction with the nepheline syenites. This external crustal fluid was Mg-bearing and caused the in situ replacement of eudialyte by multiple REE-Nb minerals and phlogopite-magnetite-quartz alteration.</description><description>Le gisement d'ETR-Nb-Zr de Nechalacho, à Thor Lake (Territoires du Nord-Ouest, Canada), est composé de couches de syénite à eudialyte altérée hydrothermalement. Avec des ressources mesurées, indiquées et inférées combinées de 269 Mt pour une teneur moyenne de 1.47 %poids ETR-oxyde, 0.35 %poids Nb2O5 et 2.59 %poids ZrO2, le gisement est l'un des plus importants au monde. Le principal minéral d'ETR-Nb d'origine magmatique est la kentbrooksite (eudialyte). L'altération hydrothermale intense est caractérisée par son remplacement par la fergusonite-(Y), la samarskite-(Y), la columbite-(Fe) et -(Mn), le xenotime-(Y), la monazite-(Ce), la bastnäsite-(Ce), la parisite-(Ce), la synchysite-(Ce), l'allanite-(Ce) et le zircon. Les syénites à aegirine-néphéline encaissantes ont été remplacées par un assemblage à phlogopite-quartz-magnétite-ankerite-fluorite. La roche encaissante du gisement d'ETR-Nb-Zr de Nechalacho est une syénite agpaïtique, la Nechalacho Layered Suite, laquelle recoupe le complexe igné anorogénique de Blatchford Lake, daté à 2176 Ma. L'intrusion laccolithique, d'un diamètre de ~1.9 km et d'une épaisseur de &gt;1.1 km, affiche une stratification modale de néphéline, sodalite, aegirine (pôle pur), annite, K-feldspath, albite et eudialyte. Un âge U-Pb zircon (méthode concordia) de 2176.0 ± 2.7 Ma prouve que les syénites néphéliniques sont contemporaines avec les autres unités du complexe. Le εNd(2176 Ma) initial se situe entre 1.1 et 3.1 (2.0 en moyenne), et les valeurs du δ18Omagma et du δDmagma calculées pour les minéraux magmatiques sont de 5.1 à 7.8‰ et de  60‰, respectivement. Dans les granites alcalins précoces et dans les syénites quartzifères du complexe (Grace Lake Granite, Thor Lake Syénite, Rim Syénite), le δ18Omagma et le δDmagma atteignent 6.7 à 8.1‰ et -99 à  93‰, respectivement. En combinaison avec les profils des éléments en traces mesurés sur roche totale, cela indique que les unités du complexe se sont formées à partir de pulses magmatiques extraits d'une chambre d'alimentation crustale profonde, dans laquelle un magma mafique dérivé du manteau, similaire à un basalte de type OIB, a subi un processus de cristallisation fractionnée. Le Nechalacho Layered Suite s'est formée à partir du pulse le plus tardif et le plus évolué, lequel était dépourvu de magnésium et était enrichi en Zr, ETR, Nb, en espèces carbonées, en fluor et en chlore. Les équilibres minéraux indiquent que, de  ~800 à &lt;500 °C et à une pression de ~4 kbar, la fugacité en oxygène était initialement inférieure à FMQ+0.2 à FMQ+1.3, et augmenta en réponse à l'auto-oxydation du magma suivant la cristallisation de l'annite. La cristallisation fractionnée in situ a procédé vers le haut et vers le bas et les ETR, le Nb et le Zr ont été enrichis dans le magma résiduel riche en fer jusqu'à ce que le magma soit saturé en eudialyte. L'auto-métasomatisme d'origine magmatique-hydrothermal, associé à la minéralisation à ankérite-bastnäsite-(Ce), est indiqué par les variations de δ13C, de -6.3 à 2.7 ‰, et de δ18O, de 11.3 à 15.0 ‰, pour les carbonates hydrothermaux. Les âges U-Pb et Th-Pb obtenus sur la monazite-(Ce) hydrothermale provenant de la Zone Basale (1871 ± 14 à 1835 ± 57 Ma) indiquent un événement régional tardif de circulation de fluide hydrothermal associé à des failles le long de la marge sud du Craton des Esclaves. Les températures hydrothermales déterminées en utilisant les isotopes de l'oxygène atteignent ~300 °C et les fluides présentent un δ18O compris entre 3.1 et 9.3‰ et un δD de  24‰, ce qui suggère une origine crustale. Les équilibres minéraux indiquent que le fluide de l'altération était vraisemblablement réduit (FMQ +2.0 à 3.7), et que son pH était légèrement acide à faiblement alcalin (entre 3.7 et 5.7). Ce fluide crustal externe était riche en Mg et a causé le remplacement in situ de l'eudialyte par divers minéraux d'ETR-Nb ainsi que l'altération à phlogopite-magnétite-quartz.</description><creator>Moeller, Volker</creator><contributor>Anthony E Williams-Jones (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Earth and Planetary Sciences</subject><title>The nature and origin of the Nechalacho rare metal deposit (REE, Nb, Zr), Northwest Territories, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g20q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117r61v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623g210</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using cloud-resolving simulations, this study investigates the mechanisms and sensitivities of deep-convection initiation over an idealized surface-based convergence zone. A band of diurnal sensible heatflux centered in x over an otherwise unheated domain surface results in a convergence band and a quasi-linear boundary layer updraft with an amplitude of ∼2.4 ms−1 , centered on the heat anomaly, that forces cumulus convection. These initially shallow cumuli deepen progressively and, in favorable conditions, transition into deep convection. To investigate the mechanisms influencing this transition, a statistical method based on a thermal-tracking algorithm is developed, that follows cumulus cores from their formation up to their decay. This algorithm can be used to compare the impacts of environmental conditions (mid-level humidity and lapse rate) and initial core properties near cloud base (mean horizontal area, buoyancy, and vertical velocity) with the final cloud height, using a single method. The mechanisms studied using this method are grouped into two distinct categories: 1) Mechanisms influencing the Nature of the clouds, studied by analyzing the initial properties of the cloud under the level of free convection. 2) Mechanisms influencing the Nurture of the clouds, studied by analyzing the ascent conditions of the cloud in the midlevels. Generally, for a given set of mean midlevel environmental conditions (Nurture), the initial core area (Nature) controls the depth of the ascent and the deep convective initiation. In addition, the sensitivity of cloud depth to initial core area is greater in hostile environments and lesser in favorable environments. Simulated deep convection initiation is also sensitive to grid resolution, as the resolution of the boundary layer updraft influences directly the initial thermals' size distribution.</description><description>À l'aide de simulations numériques, la présente étude explore les mécanismes et la sensibilité de l'initiation convective profonde générée par une zone de convergence de surface. Une bande de flux de chaleur sensible centrée en x à la surface du domaine de simulation crée une bande de convergence et un courant ascendant quasi-linéaire d'une amplitude de∼2.4 m s−1 , centré sur l'anomalie thermique et qui force la formation de cumuli. Ces cumuli s'approfondissent progressivement et, dans des conditions favorables se transforment en convection profonde. Les mécanismes influençant cette transition sont étudiés à l'aide une méthode statistique basée sur un algorithme de poursuite de nuages, qui suit les cumuli, de leur formation jusqu'à leur dissipation. Cet algorithme de poursuite permet la comparaison des impacts des conditions environnementales (humidité de la troposphère et profil de température) et des propriétés initiales du nuage près de sa base (aire horizontale moyenne, flottabilité et vitesse verticale), sur la hauteur finale atteinte par le nuage, à l'aide d'une méthode unique. Les mécanismes étudiés ici peuvent être regroupés en deux catégories distinctes: 1) Les mécanismes qui influencent l'Inné du nuage, étudiés à travers l'analyse des propriétés du nuage avant qu'il n'acquière une flottabilité positive. 2) Les mécanismes qui influencent les Acquis du nuage, étudiés à travers l'analyse des conditions environnementales influençant l'ascension du nuage. En général, pour une combinaison donnée de conditions initiales environnementales (Acquis), l'aire horizontale initiale (Inné) du nuage contrôle la hauteur finale que le cumulus atteindra et l'initiation convective profonde. De plus, plus l'environnement est favorable au développement du nuage, moins la hauteur finale du nuage sera sensible à l'aire horizontale initiale. La simulation numérique de convection profonde est également sensible à la résolution de la grille numérique parce que cette dernière influence directement la distribution de taille initiale des nuages.</description><creator>Rousseau-Rizzi, Raphaël</creator><contributor>Daniel Kirshbaum (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Man K Yau (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</subject><title>The deep convective initiation over an idealized mesoscale convergence zone</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w501p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g210</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515r11g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: After extubation, extremely preterm infants are supported with some type of non-invasive respiratory therapy to prevent extubation failure. The two most common modes are nasal intermittent positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) and continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP). Both types have similar physiological effects on stable infants, but in infants who were recently extubated and are unstable, any physiological difference between those modes has never been investigated. Heart Rate Variability (HRV) has been shown to be a useful marker of physiological wellbeing in preterm infants during weaning from mechanical ventilation, with significant differences between infants that succeed or fail extubation. Therefore, evaluation of HRV may provide some insight into the physiological differences between NIPPV and CPAP in preterm infants recently extubated. There is no consensus on what is the best methodology to analyze HRV in neonates.Objective: To investigate for physiological differences between NIPPV and CPAP applied during the immediate post-extubation phase using several different methodologies for HRV analysis. The secondary objective was to investigate for differences in HRV with relation to the extubation outcome. Methods: Infants born with birth weight ≤1250g and undergoing their first extubation attempt were studied 30 min after extubation. Electrocardiogram (ECG) recordings were obtained while these infants were receiving NIPPV at a rate of 20 breaths per minute (NIPPV20) and 40 breaths per minute (NIPPV40), and nasal CPAP in a random order for 30-60 min each. Initial comparisons revealed no differences between NIPPV20 and 40, thus final comparisons wereonly performed between NIPPV20 and CPAP. Using time domain and frequency domain methods, HRV parameters were calculated from 5-minute segments of ECG obtained using the following four methodologies: 1) average of all acceptable (≥80% normal intervals) segments, 2) the last acceptable segment, 3) the last acceptable segment band-pass filtered, and finally 4) the best obtainable segment (100% normal intervals). Non-parametric comparisons were done between NIPPV20 and CPAP, for the absolute difference between NIPPV20 and CPAP (ΔHRV), and the relative difference (ΔHRV(%)) for all infants and between infants that failed and succeeded extubation. Extubation failure was defined as the need for reintubation within 72 hours.Results: Twelve out of 15 infants were analyzed (7 success and 5 failures); 3 infants were excluded due to low quality of ECG signals. No differences were found between NIPPV20 and CPAP for the overall population. From the third segment analysis, utilizing a single band-pass filtered segment, a significantly higher ΔHRV and ΔHRV(%) were observed in infants that failed when compared to success for all time domain HRV parameters. All these parameters showed high accuracy in predicting extubation failure, with area under the ROC curves &gt;0.9.Conclusion: There were no differences in HRV between NIPPV20 and CPAP. However, infants who failed extubation had significantly greater HRV on NIPPV20 compared to CPAP. This difference was only observed in the third segment analysis, which uses the most systematic approach to segment selection. Analysis of HRV may be a useful tool to identify infants at high risk of failing extubation as early as 2 hours post-extubation.</description><description>Contexte: Suite à l'extubation, les nourrissons extrêmement prématurés sont soutenus avec un certain type de thérapie respiratoire non-invasif afin de prévenir l'échec de l'extubation. Les deux modes les plus courants sont la ventilation nasale à pression positive intermittente (VPPIn) et la pression positive continue (PPC). Les deux types ont des effets physiologiques semblables sur les nourrissons stables.  Par contre, aucune étude a été effectuée sur la différence physiologique entre ces deux modes chez les nourrissons qui ont été récemment extubés et sont instables.  La variabilité du rythme cardiaque (VRC) est un marqueur utile pour démontrer le bien-être physiologique des nourrissons prématurés pendant le sevrage de la ventilation mécanique, avec des différences significatives entre les nourrissons qui ont été extubés avec ou sans succès. Par conséquent, l'évaluation de la VRC peut élucider les différences physiologiques entre la VPPIn et la PPC chez les nourrissons prématurés récemment extubés. Il n'y a pas de consensus de la meilleure méthode pour analyser la VRC chez les nourrissons.Objectif: Pour étudier les différences physiologiques entre la VPPIn et la PPC appliquées au cours de la phase post-extubation immédiate en utilisant plusieurs méthodes différentes pour l'analyse de la VRC. L'objectif secondaire est d'étudier les différences de la VRC reliées au succès de l'extubation. Méthodes: Les nourrissons nés avec un poids ≤1250g et subissant leur première essai d'extubation ont été étudiés 30 min après l'extubation. Les enregistrements d'électrocardiogramme (ECG) ont été obtenus alors que ces nourrissons recevaient la VPPIn à un taux de 20 respirations par minute (VPPIn20), et 40 respirations par minute (VPPIn40), et la PPC dans un ordre aléatoire pour 30-60 min chaque. Les comparaisons initiales n'ont révélé aucune différence entre les taux sur la VPPIn, donc les comparaisons finales ont été effectuées uniquement entre la VPPIn20 et la PPC. En utilisant des méthodes dans le domaine temporel et le domaine fréquentiel, des paramètres de la VRC ont été calculées en utilisant des segments de 5 minutes de l'ECG obtenus en utilisant les quatre méthodes suivantes: 1) moyenne de tous segments acceptables (≥80% des intervalles normaux), 2) le dernier segment acceptable, 3) le dernier segment acceptable filtré passe-bande, et enfin 4) le meilleur segment obtenu avec la plus faible quantité d'artéfacts. Des comparaisons non-paramétriques ont été effectuées entre la VPPIn20 et la PPC, la différence absolue entre la VPPIn20 et la PPC (ΔHRV), et la différence relative (ΔHRV(%)) pour tous les nourrissons, et entre les nourrissons qui ont échoués et réussis l'extubation. L'échec de l'extubation a été défini comme la nécessité de réintubation dans les 72 heures subséquentes.Résultats: Douze des 15 nourrissons ont été analysés (7 succès et 5 échecs); 3 enfants ont été exclus en raison de la faible qualité des signaux ECG. Aucune différence n'a été identifiée entre la VPPIn20 et la PPC pour la population globale. De la troisième analyse du segment, en utilisant un seul segment de 5 minutes filtré passe-bande, un ΔHRV et un ΔHRV(%) beaucoup plus élevé à été observée chez les nourrissons qui ont échoué par rapport à la réussite de tout des paramètres de la VRC dans le domaine temporel. Tous ces paramètres ont montré une grande précision dans la prédiction de l'échec de l'extubation. Conclusions: Il n'y avait aucune différence dans la VRC entre la VPPIn20 et la PPC. Toutefois, les nourrissons qui ont échoué l'extubation avaient significativement plus de VRC sur la VPPIn20 en comparaison à la PPC. Cette différence n'a été observée que dans la troisième analyse du segment, qui utilise l'approche la plus systématique à la sélection de segment. L'analyse de la VRC peut être un outil utile pour identifier les enfants à risque élevé d'échec à l'extubation dès 2 heures post-extubation.</description><creator>Latremouille, Samantha</creator><contributor>Guilherme Sant Anna (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Heart rate variability in extremely preterm infants receiving non-synchronized nasal intermittent positive pressure ventilation and continuous positive airway pressure immediately after extubation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm991.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r11g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795b41c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse porte sur la modélisation des canaux sans fil et les applications de la théorie des jeux à champ moyen aux systèmes de communication de téléphones cellulaires. Premièrement, on propose un nouveau modèle stochastique de canaux sans fil à espace d'états en temps continu qui combine les effets d'atténuation à long terme et ceux à court terme pour décrire la puissance d'émission d'entrée et de sortie d'un signal qui traverse le canal sans fil. Deuxièmement, le modèle et la théorie des jeux à champ moyen sont appliqués au problème de contrôle de puissance d'émission décentralisé de liaison montante dans les réseaux de téléphones cellulaires «Code Division Multiple Access» (CDMA). Dans ce problème, les utilisateurs sont en concurrence les uns contre les autres et contrôlent leur puissance d'émission. Dans un deuxième problème, la position dans l'espace est aussi contrôlée. Ceci a pour but de maximiser leur qualité de service et de minimiser leurs coûts de contrôle individuels. La troisième partie de cette thèse fournit un modèle dynamique des systèmes  de femtocellules «Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiple Access» (OFDMA) en temps continu. On formule ensuite un problème de contrôle de puissance d'émission de liaison descendante comme jeu dynamique où les joueurs en concurrence sont les femtocellules. Une partie importante du travail présenté dans cette thèse est basée sur la théorie non linéaire des jeux à champ moyen qui est utilisé afin de trouver des stratégies d'équilibre de Nash des problèmes de contrôle CDMA et OFDMA décentralisées. Précisément, on utilise des méthodes numériques pour résoudre les équations Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman et McKean-Vlasov-Fokker-Planck-Kolmogorov de la théorie des jeux à champ moyen. Des solutions illustratives et des exemples de simulation sont finalement présentés.</description><description>This thesis focuses on channel modelling and the applications of Mean Field Game (MFG) theory to cellphone communication systems. First, it proposes a new continuous time state-space stochastic channel model which combines the effects of long-term and short-term fading in order to describe the input and output signal power of the wireless channel. Then, second, the new channel model and MFG theory are applied to the problem of decentralized uplink power control in Code Division Multiple Access (CDMA) cellphone networks. In this problem, the user devices are competing with each other by dynamically controlling their transmit power, as well as their position in space in a second problem, in order to maximize individual quality of service (QoS) while minimizing individual control costs. The third part of this thesis provides a dynamic system model of Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiple Access (OFDMA) femtocell systems in continuous time; it then gives a formulation of a downlink power control problem for competing femtocell base stations in a dynamic game setting which is solved using MFG theory. In this work nonlinear MFG theory is used in order to solve for Nash Equilibrium strategies of the decentralized CDMA and OFDMA control problems, to be specific it employs numerical methods for the solutions of the Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman and McKean-Vlasov-Fokker-Planck-Kolmogorov equations of MFG theory. Illustrative solutions and simulation examples are then presented.  </description><creator>Destounis, Nicholas</creator><contributor>Peter Edwin Caines (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Communication network optimization via wireless channel modelling and mean field game theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq11k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b41c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rr53c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous montrons que la structure conforme pour les analogues riemanniens des métriques trou noir de Kerr peut être munie d'une structure ambitorique. Nous discutons ensuite des propriétés des applications moment. En particulier, nous observons que l'image de l'application moment n'est pas localement convexe près de la singularité qui correspond à la singularité de l'anneau à l'intérieur du trou noir. Nous étudions également les métriques de Tomimatsu-Sato, qui généralisent les métriques de Kerr. Nous montrons qu'elles admettent aussi un analogue en signature reimannienne et un analogue presque complexe de la structure ambitorique. Nous classifions ensuite les 4-orbifolds ambitoriques réguliers avec quelques hypothèses de complétude. Les outils développés nous permettent aussi d'obtenir une classification partielle des 4-variétés compactes riemanniennes qui admettent une 2-forme de Killing.</description><description>We show that the conformal structure for the Riemannian analogues of Kerr black-hole metrics can be given an ambitoric structure.  We then discuss the properties of the moment maps. In particular, we observe that the moment map image is not locally convex near the singularity corresponding to the ring singularity in the interior of the black hole. We also study the Tomimatsu-Sato metrics, which generalize the Kerr metrics. We  show that these also admit Riemannian signature analogues, and admit almost-complex analogues of ambitoric structures. We then proceed to classify regular ambitoric 4-orbifolds with some completeness assumptions. The tools developed also allow us to prove a partial classification of compact Riemannian 4-manifolds which admit a Killing 2-form.</description><creator>Dixon, Kael</creator><contributor>Vestislav Apostolov (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Niky Kamran (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Completions of regular ambitoric 4-manifolds: Riemannian Kerr metrics and beyond</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859j25q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rr53c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j160q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Students do not always know how or when to ask for help and they may lack the skills to initiate work on their own without guidance, otherwise known as "independent learning". Independent learning is a skill that leads to school success and it is proposed that improvements of independent learning would also reduce the engagement of risky behaviors. Therefore, the proposed research examined whether implementing a novel intervention on independent learning would improve independent learning strategies, overall academic performance, and reduce risky behaviors, among adult education students. Students receiving the intervention were compared to a control group receiving no intervention. No improvements of independent learning were observed after the intervention. In addition, the results revealed no improvements in academic performance in both groups at post-test. However, significant interaction effects in academic performance were observed between the groups. Finally, risky behaviors significantly increased in both groups. This perhaps indicates that the continued exposure to unhealthy environments may contribute to the initiation of risky behaviors among adult education students. Therefore, the results are explored and are discussed in relation to the current intervention.</description><description>Les élèves ne savent pas toujours comment et quand demander de l'aide et ils peuvent ne pas avoir les compétences nécessaires pour entreprendre des travaux eux-mêmes s'ils n'obtiennent pas de l'aide, autrement connu comme «l'apprentissage par autorégulation». L'apprentissage par autorégulation est une compétence qui mène à la réussite scolaire et il est suggéré que l'amélioration de l'apprentissage indépendant permettrait également de réduire le développement de comportements à risque. Par conséquent, la recherche proposée a évaluée si la mise en œuvre d'une nouvelle intervention sur l'apprentissage indépendant améliorerait les stratégies d'apprentissage indépendant, le rendement scolaire en général et la réduction des comportements à risque, et ce chez les élèves adultes. Les étudiants recevant l'intervention ont été comparés à un groupe témoin ne recevant aucune intervention. Aucune amélioration de l'apprentissage par autorégulation n'a été observée après l'intervention. De plus, les résultats n'ont révélés aucune amélioration dans le rendement scolaire chez les deux groupes au post-test. Cependant, les effets d'interaction sont significatifs en ce qui concerne le rendement scolaire  observé entre les groupes. Enfin, les comportements à risque ont significativement augmentés dans les deux groupes. Cela suggère que l'exposition continue à un environnement malsain peut contribuer à l'initiation des comportements à risque chez les élèves adultes. Par conséquent, les résultats de l'intervention actuelle sont explorés et discutés.</description><creator>Edwards, Mark-Damyan</creator><contributor>Steven Shaw (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</subject><title>Canadian adult education: the educator's guide to school-based interventions on independent learning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn00k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j160q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r580z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Post-stroke visuospatial neglect (VSN) is an attentional-perceptual disorder that alters the ability to detect and respond to relevant visual stimuli present in the contralesional space. Since locomotion is highly dependent on visual inputs, VSN may impair the modulation of walking in response to visuospatial cues such as obstacles, especially when located in the "neglected" side of space. Failure to adapt walking in response to obstacles may lead to collisions or falls. Also, since attentional resources are limited in persons with VSN, performing a cognitive task while walking could further alter obstacle avoidance performance. In this thesis, I have utilised a virtual reality paradigm consisting of obstacles approaching from the right, left or head-on, to assess how presence of VSN in stroke survivors interferes with their ability to safely avoid moving obstacles while walking. Stroke survivors with VSN (and without VSN for Manuscript 3 and 4) participated in a series of experiments that involved: (1) detecting moving obstacles; (2) avoiding the obstacle while walking towards a target; (3) using a joystick to navigate around the obstacle and (4) performing a cognitive task along with the obstacle avoidance task. During locomotor (Manuscript 1) and non-locomotor (joystick-driven, Manuscript 2) obstacle avoidance tasks, individuals with VSN (n=12) showed smaller minimum distances and higher collision rates for contralesional and head-on obstacles compared to ipsilesional ones. These results provide evidence that attentional-perceptual deficits due to VSN, independent of post-stroke locomotor deficits, alter obstacle avoidance abilities. In Manuscript 3, 26 stroke survivors (13 with and 13 without VSN) were assessed while concurrently performing the obstacle avoidance and a cognitive task i.e. dual tasking. Compared to the single task, dual tasking caused deterioration of both locomotor (higher collision rate, smaller minimum distances) and cognitive performances (higher error rate) in VSN individuals, suggestive of a "cognitive-locomotor interference". In contrast, individuals without VSN prioritised the locomotor task (no change in collision rates) over the cognitive task (higher cognitive error rates). In Manuscript 4, we examined kinematic strategies utilised by individuals with and without VSN to safely avoid the obstacles. For individuals free of VSN, deviating to the same-side as the obstacle emerged as a safe strategy to avoid diagonal obstacles, while an opposite-side deviation was riskier and led to collisions. VSN individuals deviated ipsilesionally for all obstacles; displaying same, and opposite-side strategies for ipsilesional and contralesional obstacles, respectively. In this group, contralesional collisions were frequent, observed for the opposite-side strategy, and associated with a delay in onset-of-heading change. Thus ipsilesional biases arising from VSN influenced the modulation of heading in response to the contralesional obstacle and, along with the adoption of the 'riskier' strategy, contributed to the risk of collisions in individuals with VSN. Collectively, these results reveal that the presence of VSN in stroke survivors puts them at a high risk for collisions with moving obstacles while walking, especially in the presence of increased attentional demands. As avoiding moving obstacles and coping with changing cognitive demands are critical for safe community ambulation, findings of this thesis may explain, in part, the poor community ambulation observed in persons with VSN. </description><description>La négligence visuospatiale (NVS) post accident vasculaire cérébral (AVC) est un trouble perceptuo-attentionnel qui altère la capacité à détecter et répondre à des stimuli visuels du côté opposé à la lésion corticale. Puisque la locomotion dépend fortement de l'information visuelle, la NVS pourrait altérer les comportements de marche en réponse à des stimuli visuo-spatiaux, tel que des obstacles, en particulier lorsqu'ils sont situés du côté 'négligé' de l'espace. Une incapacité à adapter la marche en réponse à des obstacles pourrait engendrer des collisions ou des chutes. De plus, étant donné que les ressources attentionnelles sont limitées chez les personnes avec NVS, l'ajout d'une tâche cognitive durant la marche est susceptible d'altérer leur performance lors de l'évitement d'obstacles. Dans cette thèse, j'ai utilisé des obstacles virtuels approchant de différentes directions (droite, gauche ou de l'avant) pour examiner comment la présence de NVS interfère avec la capacité à éviter des obstacles en mouvement de manière sécuritaire lors de la marche. Des participants post AVC avec NVS (et sans NVS dans les Manuscrits 3 et 4) ont participé à des tâches consistant à : (1) détecter des obstacles en mouvement; (2) éviter ces mêmes obstacles en marchant vers une cible; (3) utiliser une manette de jeu pour naviguer autour des obstacles et (4) exécuter une tâche cognitive en même temps que la tâche d'évitement d'obstacles. Durant la tâche d'évitement d'obstacle à la marche (Manuscrit 1) et dans un contexte non-locomoteur (Manuscrit 2), 12 individus avec NVS ont montré une distance minimale réduite et un taux de collision plus élevé avec des obstacles provenant du côté contralésionnel et de l'avant, comparativement aux obstacles ipsilésionnels. Ces résultats suggèrent que les déficits perceptuo-attentionnels attribuables à la NVS altèrent la capacité d'évitement d'obstacles. Dans le Manuscrit 3, 26 individus ayant un AVC (13 avec et 13 sans NVS) ont été évalués à la marche tout en performant simultanément une tâche cognitive i.e. en double tâche. Comparativement à une tâche simple, la tâche double a causé une détérioration de la performance locomotrice (plus de collisions, distance minimale réduite) et cognitive (taux d'erreur augmenté) chez les participants avec NVS, suggérant une 'interférence cognitive-locomotrice'. Les individus sans NVF ont quant à eux priorisé la tâche locomotrice au détriment de la tâche cognitive. Le Manuscrit 4 décrit les stratégies cinématiques pour éviter un obstacle utilisées par les mêmes participants que le Manuscrit 3. Chez les individus sans NVS, une déviation du même côté que l'obstacle s'est révélée une stratégie sécuritaire pour éviter les obstacles approchant en diagonale, alors qu'une déviation du côté opposé s'est avéré plus risquée, menant à des collisions. Les individus avec NVS ont dévié du côté ipsilésionnel, démontrant des stratégies 'même côté' ou 'côté opposé' pour les obstacles ipsilésionnel et contralésionnels, respectivement. Dans ce groupe, les collisions avec des obstacles contralésionnels étaient fréquentes, observées avec des stratégies du côté opposé et associées à un délai dans l'initiation d'une stratégie d'évitement. Ainsi, le biais ipsilésionnel découlant de la NVS influence la modulation de la trajectoire de marche en réponse à un obstacle contralésionnel et, avec l'adoption d'une stratégie plus risquée, contribue au risque de collision. Collectivement, les résultats indiquent que la présence de NVS après un AVC hausse le risque de collision avec des objets en mouvement pendant la marche, en particulier en présence d'une demande attentionnelle accrue. L'évitement d'obstacles et la capacité à faire face à des demandes cognitives changeantes sont critiques pour une marche en communauté sécuritaire. Les résultats de cette thèse peuvent expliquer, en partie, la difficulté qu'ont les personnes avec une NVS à marcher dans la communauté. </description><creator>Aravind, Gayatri</creator><contributor>Anouk Lamontagne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Physical &amp; Occupational Therapy</subject><title>The presence of visuospatial neglect impairs the ability of post-stroke individuals to safely negotiate moving obstacles while walking</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tf81z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r580z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zb48x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine la nature du pouvoir artistique et son fonctionnement dans le contexte de la mondialisation. En m'appuyant sur les conceptions du pouvoir de Michel Foucault, je développe un modèle théorique binaire dans lequel je propose que le pouvoir artistique est rendu possible par un ensemble de savoirs – notamment l'histoire de l'art et l'esthétique – qui permettent aux acteurs du milieu des arts visuels de formuler un discours sur les œuvres. Or, le pouvoir artistique est aussi constitué d'une dimension stratégique, incarnée dans la réputation des acteurs, qui détermine la capacité de ces derniers à influencer le développement des arts visuels.La thèse est articulée autour de trois études de cas qui examinent des institutions artistiques globales qui organisent des compétitions ouvertes aux contributions venues des quatre coins du monde: la Biennale de Venise, l'une des manifestations d'art contemporain les plus connues mondialement, la Liste du patrimoine mondial de l'UNESCO qui répertorie des éléments « exceptionnels » du patrimoine bâti situés dans toutes les régions de la planète et le prix Future Generation Art Prize, une nouvelle récompense qui souhaite reconnaître les jeunes artistes les plus prometteurs au monde. Chaque étude de cas se penche sur l'évaluation comparative faite dans le cadre de ces institutions artistiques globales.Je soutiens dans cette thèse que le prestige est un mécanisme de gouvernance clé dans le monde global des arts. En effet, c'est bien parce qu'elles sont des institutions artistiques prestigieuses que les jugements émis par ces acteurs comptent dans le milieu des arts visuels. Or, chaque jugement est également l'occasion pour ces institutions de renforcer leur prestige, ou inversement, une opération qui peut potentiellement le dégrader. Ainsi, le prestige peut être envisagé comme le pivot du pouvoir artistique puisqu'il fonctionne à la manière d'un mécanisme de régulation du pouvoir dans l'environnement complexe qu'est le monde global des arts.</description><description>This dissertation examines the nature of artistic power and its operating modes in a global context. Drawing on Michel Foucault's conception of power, I develop a dualistic theoretical model in which I propose that artistic power is enabled by a body of knowledge, mainly that of art history and aesthetics, that allows actors in visual art circles to articulate a discourse on works of art. At the same time, artistic power is also constituted of a strategic component, embodied in the reputation of the actor, that determines his or her capacity to influence the development of the field. This dissertation is articulated around three case studies which examine global artistic institutions that run competitions open to contributions from around the world: the Venice Biennale, one of the best-known contemporary art manifestations, the UNESCO World Heritage List, which itemizes "outstanding" built heritage elements situated in each of the world's regions, and the Future Generation Art Prize, a biannual art prize recently created to reward the most promising young artists in the world. Each case considers how comparative evaluation is performed within the framework of these global artistic institutions.I argue that prestige is a key governance mechanism in the global art world. Indeed, it is because the artistic institutions studied here are prestigious that the judgments they issue matter in the global art world. Each judgment is also the occasion for an artistic institution to further develop its prestige or, conversely, damage it. Prestige can therefore be thought as the linchpin of artistic power because it functions as a mechanism that regulates power in the complex environment of the global art world.</description><creator>Sirois, Guillaume</creator><contributor>Marc Raboy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Art History and Communications Studies</subject><title>The art of being on top: power and prestige in the global art world</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60d024j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zb48x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t1868</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:43:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ascending thoracic aortic aneurysms (ATAAs) is an arterial disease which can lead to a dissection or rupture of the aorta, causing the death of the patients. Several studies have investigated the rupture mechanisms of ATAAs, however, underlying reasons behind aortic rupture (failure) have not been fully understood and further investigations are necessary. Surgical interventions used to treat this disease are associated with risks of mortality and morbidity. While size is the main clinical measure for aortic replacement surgery, there are uncertainties about the efficiency of this measure. To better guide surgical decision making, a biomechanical surrogate measure estimating ATAA wall properties is needed to better stratify patients. Understanding the biomechanical and histopathological changes associated with ascending thoracic aortic aneurysms (ATAAs), this research investigates different mechanical properties of the aorta. The rupture of pathological aortic tissue is a local phenomenon resulting from defects or tears in the vessel wall. In this work, the toughness-based rupture properties of human ATAAs have been examined. The toughness, biaxial tensile characteristics, and histological properties of aneurysmal and control ascending thoracic aortas (ATAs) were characterized from four quadrants of surgically excised aortic rings. To further explore the rupture propensity of ATAAs, the inter-correlation of the toughness properties with histological characteristics have been explored. The toughness properties were also investigated for cryopreserved and control porcine tissues.The loss factor, a surrogate measure defined as the ratio of dissipated energy to the energy absorbed during a tensile cycle, the incremental modulus, and their anisotropy index were also determined for the controlled and aneurysmal human ATAs. These parameters were compared with the media fiber compositions, the aortic diameter, and patients' age for the ATAAs associated with bicuspid aortic valve (BAV) and tricuspid aortic valve (TAV). Additionally, the variations of fiber contents through the aortic thickness and the non-linear tensile characteristic of the aortas have been examined.The results obtained suggest tissue remodeling could affect toughness and stiffness properties differently in ascending aortic aneurysms. The results propose the loss factor, which may be measured non-invasively, could be a useful surrogate measure to describe the histopathology of aneurysmal tissue and to demonstrate the differences between ATAAs with bicuspid and tricuspid aortic valve types.</description><description>L'anévrisme de l'aorte thoracique ascendante (les ATAAs) est une maladie artérielle qui peut conduire à une dissection ou une rupture de l'aorte, pouvant causer la mort. Plusieurs études ont analysé les mécanismes de rupture des ATAAs, cependant, les raisons sous-jacentes à la rupture de l'aorte (échec) n'ont pas été entièrement élucidées et des investigations additionnelles sont nécessaires. Les interventions chirurgicales utilisées pour traiter cette maladie sont associées à des risques de mortalité et de morbidité élevés. Bien que la taille soit la principale mesure clinique pour la chirurgie de remplacement aortique, il existe des incertitudes quant à l'efficacité de cette intervention. Pour mieux orienter la prise de décision chirurgicale, une mesure de substitution biomécanique pour l'estimation des propriétés de la paroi ATAA est nécessaire pour mieux stratifier les patients. Pour comprendre les propriétés mécaniques de l'aorte, cette recherche étudie différents changements biomécaniques et histopathologiques associés aux anévrismes ascendants de l'aorte thoracique (ATAAs). La rupture du tissu aortique pathologique est un phénomène local résultant de défauts ou de déchirures dans la paroi du vaisseau. Dans ce travail, les propriétés de rupture basées sur la ténacité d'ATAAs humains ont été caractérisées. La ténacité, les caractéristiques de traction biaxiale et les propriétés histologiques anévrysmales et de contrôle d'aortes ascendantes thoraciques (ATAs) ont été caractérisées à l'aide de quatre quadrants et anneaux aortiques chirurgicalement excisées. Pour explorer davantage la propension à la rupture des ATAAs, l'inter-corrélation des propriétés de ténacité avec les caractéristiques histologiques a été explorée. Les propriétés de ténacité ont également été étudiées pour les tissus porcins cryoconservés.Un facteur de perte a été défini, c'est une mesure de substitution définie comme étant le rapport entre l'énergie dissipée à l'énergie absorbée pendant un cycle de traction, le module supplémentaire, et leur indice d'anisotropie ont également été déterminés pour les ATAs humains contrôlées et anévrysmles. Ces paramètres ont été comparés avec les compositions de fibres de la média, le diamètre de l'aorte et l'âge des patients avec ATAAs associés à la bicuspidie aortique (BAV) et la valve aortique tricuspide (TAV). En outre, les variations des teneurs en fibres sur l'épaisseur de l'aorte et de la résistance caractéristique non linéaire des aortes ont été examinées.Les résultats obtenus suggèrent que le remodelage tissulaire pourrait affecter les propriétés de ténacité et de rigidité des anévrismes de l'aorte. Les résultats proposent que le facteur de perte, qui peut être mesuré de manière non invasive, pourrait être une mesure de substitution utile pour décrire l'histopathologie du tissu anévrismal et de démontrer les différences entre ATAAs avec types de valves aortiques bicuspides et tricuspides.</description><creator>Shahmansouri, Nastaran</creator><contributor>Rosaire Mongrain (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Richard L Leask (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Theoretical and experimental analyses of the rupture of ascending thoracic aortic aneurysm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n945.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t1868</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7125</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>