<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:25:16Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21700" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r896n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The attitudes of selected memoir authors are surveyed with regard to their commentary on London Society ranging from the late Nineteenth century to the Nineteen Thirties. The experience of these Society participants is divided between aspects of continuity and change before and after the First World War. During this time-frame, London Society, as the community of a ruling class culture, may be seen to have undergone the transition from having been an aristocratic entity dominated by the political and social prestige of the landed classes, to that of an expanded body, more reflective of democratic evolution and innovation. The memoir testimony treated in this inquiry affords a means of reflecting not only Society's passage of experience but also more pointedly, its evaluation, shedding light on the values and vulnerability of a hitherto assured, discreet and otherwise adaptive class character at a time of accelerated change and challenge.</description><creator>Little, Roger C.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>London (England) -- Social life and customs -- History -- 19th century</subject><subject>London (England) -- Social life and customs -- History -- 20th century</subject><subject>Aristocracy (Social class) -- England -- London -- History -- 20th century</subject><subject>Aristocracy (Social class) -- England -- London -- History -- 19th century</subject><title>Transition and memory : London Society from the late nineteenth century to the nineteen thirties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs07p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r896n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g6288</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The sources of the theories underlying Czech Cubist architecture before World War I have been only sketchily studied to date. To analyze these theories and identify their sources, I focus on the work of architect and theorist Pavel Janak (1882-1956), an early proponent of Cubist architecture in Bohemia. The thesis incorporates my translation of Janak's unpublished journal for 1911-1914, the dominant years of Czech Cubism. Through this journal and Janak's published writings, together with an examination of his own readings, I trace the development of his theories, and situate his sources, within their historical context. Janak was no mere imitator of French Cubism but was concerned to develop innovative architecture that yet possessed both historical continuity and universal validity, thanks to its space-creating qualities. The thesis includes a facsimile of Janak's journal with its numerous sketches, a translation en face, and a complete bibliography of his sources.</description><creator>Žantovská Murray, Irena, 1946-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Janák, Pavel, 1882-1956 -- Diaries</subject><subject>Architecture -- Czechoslovakia -- 20th century</subject><subject>Cubism -- Czechoslovakia</subject><subject>Janák, Pavel, 1882-1956</subject><title>Sources of cubist architecture in Bohemia : the theories of Pavel Janak</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr24h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g6288</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bg16z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study relationships between completely integrable Hamiltonian flows $L sb{t}( lambda$) of matricial polynomials on finite dimensional coadjoint orbits in the dual of a loop algebra and differential operators arising from points in an infinite dimensional Grassmannian Gr. Adams, Harnad, Hurtubise, and Previato have described how moment maps lead one to consider these flows, and how the systems can be integrated by constructing a linear flow $E sb{t}$ of line bundles over a curve $ tilde S$. Segal and Wilson have explained how a differential operator L and an eigenfunction called the Baker function $ psi sb{W}$ can be associated to each point $W in Gr$. In this thesis, we give a vector version of the construction described by Segal and Wilson. Then spaces $W in Gr$ correspond to sections of $E sb0$ over $ tilde S { lambda = infty }$, the r-dimensional space of Baker functions corresponds to the space of holomorphic sections of $E sb{t}$, and the differential operator L corresponds to the matricial polynomial $L sb{t}( lambda).$</description><creator>New, Stephen J. H.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Hamiltonian systems and loop groups applied to equations of KdV type</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b7330.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg16z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz8060968</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis looks at certain integral equations which are used to obtain statistical distributions, particularly in the multivariate case. In all, seven integral equations are considered. Two of the integral equations were introduced by Wilks (1932) and these are known as type A and type B integral equations. The other five known as type C to type G were introduced by Mathai (1984). Some statistical distributions associated with the solutions to these integral equations will also be discussed.</description><creator>Munsaka, Melvin Slaighter</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Some integral equations connected with statistical distribution theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010r28q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8060968</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354g465</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Robot manipulators can have difficulties when coming into contact with their environment if there is uncertainty in the system parameters. These difficulties include large impact forces and long task completion times. A design goal is to present trajectory generation and control strategies to overcome these problems. A cost function based on the magnitude of the largest possible impact force and the longest possible time to complete the task is minimized with respect to the trajectory parameters to yield an optimal trajectory. The cost function is determined by bounds given to the unknown parameters. These parameters are estimated in order to improve performance. The one dimensional problem of manipulating a load along a horizontal surface including contact with a vertical surface is simulated. The mass of the load and the force of Coulombic friction are estimated. The simulations show that the optimal trajectory presented in this thesis provides a good tradeoff between impact force reduction and reduction in task completion times. Moreover, the simulations show that the use of parameter estimation significantly improves performance as measured by the aforementioned cost function.</description><creator>Huculak, Michael</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Compliant motion for tasks involving impact, time constraints and uncertainty</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g133m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g465</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139310t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explored variables affecting and factors related to the career choices of female and male undergraduate physical science students. The variables that were examined are self-confidence, career values and attributions. Included in the examination of career plans was an attempt to establish enrollment patterns in honours and major physical science departments at McGill University. Results indicated that there was a decline in the enrollment rate for women in all science programmes (except for geology) and an increase in enrollment for males in all programmes (except for geology and physics). Contrary to previous findings, the results suggested that women in science programmes wish to remain in science or science-related occupations. While there were no conclusive findings for the variables affecting career planning, the results did reveal a pattern of gender differences that resembled gender role stereotypes.</description><creator>Harris, Eileen Ophelia</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Women in science.</subject><subject>Women college students.</subject><subject>Women -- Vocational guidance.</subject><title>An exploration of the career goals of undergraduate physical science students : where are the women in science?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp008.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139310t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50ts782</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental study was carried out to identify a suitable electrode material for the treatment of TiCl$ sb4$ in a plasma arc. The behavior of the arc voltage, velocity and rate of electrode erosion were examined in a DC plasma torch using concentric cylindrical electrodes and arc rotation by an axial magnetic field. The results of the experiments and analyses showed that pure TaC was not suitable as an electrode material because of its mechanical failure under thermal stress. A new composite material, TaC infiltrated with Al proved to be successful. Stable plasmas were produced containing up to 30% titanium tetrachloride in argon at a current of 100 amperes, an interelectrode gap of 4 mm, and a magnetic field strength of 1000 Gauss. The cathode erosion rate was less than 30 micrograms/C at a titanium tetrachloride concentration of 14.3%.</description><creator>Gao, Yong, 1955-</creator><contributor>Munz, R. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Tsantrizos, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The behavior of TaC and TaC+Al electrodes in TiCL4 plasma gases /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht04s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts782</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv614</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The paper details and discusses the compositional issues and techniques employed in the candidate's M.Mus. Thesis Composition Filigranes pour les Freres Limbourg. The piece takes its title and inspiration from the work of the fourteenth-century master-illuminators and also makes reference to music of the same period, while at the same time being grounded in a post-serial aesthetic. The composition's relationship to these models and the specific compositional processes derived from the resulting fusion of certain aspects of mediaeval music (including modality and numerology) with serial technique are described and illustrated. Special emphasis is placed on the interaction of abstract organisational principles (such as permutation) and their musical results.</description><creator>Fitch, Fabrice</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Fitch, Fabrice -- Manuscripts -- Facsimiles</subject><subject>Quintets (Flute, oboe d'amore, recorder, viola, violocello) -- Scores</subject><subject>Music -- Manuscripts -- Facsimiles</subject><title>Filigranes pour les Frères Limbourg</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb976.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv614</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257g18r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>About twelve miles to the south of Newfoundland's Burin Peninsula, there are two small islands, called St. Pierre and Miquelon which have belonged to France for nearly four centuries. In June of 1940 when France succumbed to the onslaught of the Nazis, the territory, like all other French holdings in the New World, fell under the control of the Vichy French government. But on December 24th, 1941, the Islands were seized by a Free French Naval task force acting under the direction of Charles de Gaulle, who had ordered this action not only in direct contradiction to the expressed wishes of the Allies, but also after having specifically assured them that he would not attempt to undertake such a move. The result was a serious diplomatic crisis, the ramifications of which far outweighed any importance the Islands themselves may have had. For by seizing this territory de Gaulle had brought himself into direct conflict with U.S. policy regarding the Western Hemisphere and, in addition, created great difficulties between the Allies over the issue of U.S. recognition of Vichy, versus British support for de Gaulle. This thesis, then, will examine the events which led up to this crisis, and will attempt to ascertain what significance, if any, it had on the conduct of the war as a whole.</description><creator>Woolner, David B., 1955-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- France.</subject><subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Saint Pierre and Miquelon.</subject><subject>Saint Pierre and Miquelon -- History</subject><title>Storm in the north Atlantic : the St. Pierre and Miquelon affair of 1941</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p834r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257g18r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515p465</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High quality, well oriented Zinc Oxide polycrystal thin films on oriented Si crystal surfaces and amorphous SiO$ sb2$/Si, Corning Glass and Al/SiO$ sb2$/Si substrates have been produced by a DC conical reactive S-GUN magnetron sputtering technique. X-Ray diffraction measurements, scanning electron microscopy measurements and ultrasonic measurements have been used to characterize the film properties. It has been shown that our films have 1$ sp circ$ Full Width Half Magnitude rocking curves of (002) and (004) reflection planes on Si surfaces, 1.2$ sp circ$ FWHM (002) and (004) plane rocking curves on Al/SiO$ sb2$/Si substrates and 2.0$ sp circ$ FWHM (002) rocking curves on Corning Glass slides. The films have close-to-bulk Zinc Oxide densities and an electromechanic coupling constant of 0.25, compared to the bulk value of 0.29. These data, to our best knowledge, are the best that have been reported. Using the same technique, Zinc Oxide thin films have been grown onto the cross sections of tapered cladded acoustic fibers to excite acoustic waves propagating along the fiber cores. Experiments revealed that good quality ZnO transducers, structured as Au/ZnO/Al/acoustic-fiber, have been fabricated on the tapered fibers and shear acoustic waves were guided along the acoustic fiber cores.</description><creator>Tang, Zhirong</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Zinc oxide thin film fabrication, characterization and application to acoustic fibers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4305915.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515p465</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf15t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The majority of commentators have taken Luke 12:5 as a reference to God, while a few well-known New Testament scholars have taken it to be a reference to Satan. Yet neither position has adequately substantiated its interpretation with reference to the setting in Luke's gospel. We argue that taking it as a reference to Satan makes better sense of the passage within its context. The literature is reviewed to show which commentators, namely Conzelmann, Wink and Lampe, have understood this verse as a reference to Satan. A comparison with the parallel text in Matthew reveals the differences in text and context between Matthew and Luke. These are significant enough to allow for different interpretations of the reference in Matthew and Luke. Focussing on $ varepsilon chi o upsilon sigma grave iota alpha$ and Satan shows that Luke uses these concepts in a more developed way, and ascribes authority to Satan in his writings. This interpretation of Luke 12:5 fits in well with the theme of conflict developed in Luke's gospel. The cumulative weight of these arguments points in the direction of Luke 12:5 being a reference to Satan.</description><creator>Wismer, Robert D. (Robert David)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Devil -- Biblical teaching</subject><title>The authority of Satan : an investigation into Luke 12:5</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj220.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf15t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr66h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Notre-Dame de Paris 1482, by Victor Hugo, is a work which collects many genres. This poetry however gives all signs of clumsiness (let us think of Gringoire's play or of Quasimodo's "verses"), of vulgarity (the language used by the rogues, Jehan Frollo's drinking songs), of analphabetism (a condition shared by Esmeralda, Quasimodo, and "le peuple"), of the secular, even more of the profane (the heresy and anticlericalism present in the novel). The poetry of Notre-Dame de Paris is scattered (dissipated) into a number of under-texts which appear to perturb the rules of "good" literature. A first part of this thesis examines a few characteristics of the writing of Hugo: its tendency toward a certain declassification, as well as some of its most important aesthetics, such as the grotesque and the excessiveness. A second section is an analysis of different aspects of Gringoire's morality, songs of Jehan and Esmeralda, Quasimodo's "poem"--these aspects being studied through the element of locality and the theme of the volatile.</description><creator>Trottier, André</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885. Notre-Dame de Paris</subject><title>La poésie dissipée dans Notre-Dame de Paris, 1482 /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc59m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr66h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cm21d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During his eight-year Italian sojourn (1600-1608), Sir Peter Paul Rubens became familiar with villeggiatura, a form of villa life (unique to Italy) modeled on the antique garden. Rubens' experience was personal, for a close examination of a select number of his works demonstrates that he fully assimilated this humanistic tradition. He participated in the intellectual currents of his time, the source of ars hortulorum. In his pictures, Rubens took over forms found in gardens of antiquity, the Renaissance or the Baroque and, in certain instances, recreated the mood, function and sense found in these gardens and as described by literary works. Most important, Rubens' own life of villeggiatura is clearly made evident in several of these paintings. His preference for the humanistic hortus over the garden traditions of other countries reveals Rubens' admiration, shared with other humanists for the ancients and their culture which provided personal models for poise and enlightenment. The result of this study focuses on a new dimension to our understanding of Rubens' oeuvre, his involvement with villeggiatura and the ars hortulorum.</description><creator>Brendel, Maria Lydia</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Gardens in art</subject><subject>Rubens, Peter Paul, Sir, 1577-1640</subject><title>Rubens and the humanistic garden</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g43v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm21d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t17v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to compare first- and second-language text comprehension across passage types. Results indicate that there was no main effect for language when the total texts were compared. In contrast, a large difference was found for the type of passage read. Significantly higher recall and inferencing were found on the passages for which subjects had prior knowledge, regardless of the language of presentation. Although global comprehension measures did not reveal differences in text processing, more detailed paragraph-level analyses indicated that text processing differences were present. Total reading times indicated that there was a large effect for the language in which the passage was read, with significantly longer reading times recorded for passages read in the second language. These findings were interpreted as an indication that second-language reading comprehension capacity is underestimated. The findings also suggest that the type of passage read influences text comprehension more than the language in which it is read.</description><creator>Goyette, Els Spekkens</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Language and languages -- Ability testing</subject><subject>Reading comprehension</subject><title>Second-language text comprehension : knowledge and text type</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b736t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t17v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x5126</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the effects of an orientation program on the acculturative stress of international students. The sample consisted of 36 international graduate students who were studying at McGill University. An orientation program was designed and implemented using three delivery methods--information giving, support, and a combination of the two. Pre- and posttreatment levels of acculturative stress were statistically analysed to ascertain the effects of this program. The quantitative results lacked statistical significance, but the qualitative analysis of the data indicated the orientation program was beneficial for international students. Participant responses denoted that the combination method was the most effective in meeting their needs. Additionally, a desire for more orientation programs specifically designed to meet the needs of future international students was indicated. Based on these findings, recommendations for future orientation programs and research on international students are outlined.</description><creator>Alex, Scarlett</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Acculturation</subject><subject>Students, Foreign</subject><title>Acculturative stress and the international student : a comparison of three treatment modalities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n16f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x5126</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk99v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the six plays studied, the songs fulfill an essential role in the development of the story. They nourish, motivate and direct the very essence of the narrative while communicating a precise message: an emotion, an inner reflection or a want which could not be transmitted by other means (be it through the characters, the stage direction or the decor). The author explores the central hypothesis which suggests that the songs represent the voice of a silence: the silence of those characters suffering from a profound solitude and incommunicability. The first chapter examines the songs written by Marie Laberge while the second focusses on those borrowed from other sources. Through the use of Greimas' model, the study underlines the importance in the choice of the songs and in the strategic place they occupy within each play.</description><creator>Cardinal, Isabelle</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Laberge, Marie, 1950- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>La fonction des chansons dans l'œuvre théâtrale de Marie Laberge /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2040301.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk99v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js311</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In just three decades of human exploration and utilization of outer space, an unwanted legacy of thousands of artificial space debris has been left behind. The purpose of this thesis is to analyse the appropriate technical aspects of the artificial space debris issue and to explore the legal ramifications of the question. The first chapter is devoted to the technical aspects and covers topics such as the origins and location of artificial space debris, the hazards they constitute, the anticipated damage that might be caused by such debris and the likelihood of its occurrence. In the second chapter, the legal aspects are explored by first looking at space law generally. A brief historical perspective of space law as well as the role of the United Nations in the making of space law is offered. Space law as it relates to the space debris issue is then analysed by first trying to define terms such as "space object", "component parts" and "space debris". Particular emphasis is then placed on issues like jurisdiction and control over space debris, international responsibility for space debris, their identification and, finally, liability for damage caused by space debris.</description><creator>Fortin, Pierre, 1960-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Artificial space debris and international law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t040f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js311</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gh476</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many nations, except the United States, have long regulated non-scheduled air services under their bilateral air transport agreements. Though inconstant and largely superficial, this regulation has served to alleviate the constrictive effects of multifarious laws and regulations, enacted to keep charter expansion in check. The (mainly) unilateral, diverse legal regimes charters have had to face have not stopped their growth. The late 1960s saw their worth: inter alia, their low fares facilitated tourism, filled empty aircraft seats, and injected some competition into a highly regulated industry. The Americans then realised that, absent the legal uncertainty that continuously plagued charters, and fueled by free-enterprise concepts, non-scheduled US carriers, to their benefit, could move substantial national traffic. Legal certainty and competition, assured by bilateral treaties, led the United States to begin substantial bilateral regulation of charter services. This evolution of non-scheduled air services, through bilateralism, is traced in this thesis.</description><creator>Thaker, Jitendra S.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>The regulation of non-scheduled air services under bilateral air transport agreements /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc88b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gh476</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm83j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The measles virus (MV) V protein has been predicted to arise from an edited phosphoprotein (P) mRNA, in which an additional nontemplated G residue has been inserted, thereby permitting access to another reading frame. The P and V proteins have identical amino-termini but differ in their carboxy-terminal residues. Although an edited P mRNA has been detected in MV-infected cells, no corresponding protein has yet been identified in vivo (Cattaneo et al., 1989). The present research characterizes the V protein in vivo. Antisera directed against synthetic peptides corresponding to five different regions of the MV V protein were prepared. Three of these regions were located in the amino-coterminal region, while two were located in the unique V carboxyl terminus region. The resulting peptide antisera were used to immunoprecipitate in vitro and in vivo synthesized P and V proteins. V protein (M$ sb{ rm r}$ 40,000) was detected in MV-infected Vero cells by immunoprecipitation, and found to be phosphorylated. Immunofluorescence techniques revealed that the V protein was distributed throughout the cytoplasm of infected Vero cells.</description><creator>Wardrop, Elizabeth Ann.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>The measles virus V protein /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bq51w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm83j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mn35r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the doctrine of forum non conveniens as follows. First, the preliminary factors for foreign aircraft accident plaintiffs to consider, such as the diminishing deterrents to aircraft accident litigation and requirements for bringing a suit to a U.S. forum, are set forth. Second, the development of the doctrine of forum non conveniens is traced from its origins to the landmark case of Piper Aircraft Co. v. Reyno, 454 U.S. 235 (1981) to present. Finally, after examining various model solutions to the problems raised by the doctrine of forum non conveniens, a new solution is proposed.</description><creator>Sasamori, Norman Cousins</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Forum non conveniens : foreign plaintiffs and U.S. aviation litigation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204032k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn35r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tw332</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a research program designed to evaluate the performance of the gold gravity circuit at Les Mines Camchib Inc. A detailed sampling program was conducted on the grinding and gravity circuits. Samples were screened and each size class was processed on a Mozley Laboratory Separator to determine free gold content. The performance of pinched sluices, Knelson concentrators, and a riffleless table is characterized on the basis of particle size, shape and liberation of gold. The amount of total gold and free gold in each size class of grinding circuit streams was also determined. The pinched sluices recover from 8 to 17% gold in 4.8 to 7.3% of the mass. The double sluice recovers slightly more gold at a higher yield than the single sluice. In addition, the double sluice performed better at a higher feed density. The 76 cm (30") Knelson recovers 62 to 71% of the feed gold, at very high upgrading ratios (326 to 480). Free gold recovery is high, generally above 90% for all size classes. Gold recovery decreases when wash water pressure is lowered from 100 to 40 kPa; a 90 minute cycle time does not cause concentrate overload, i.e. decreased gold recovery. The 19 cm (7.5") Knelson used in the gold room yielded 90% recovery. Reprocessing the tails in the same unit give only a marginal gold recovery, suggesting that a single pass is adequate. Fine gold losses on the riffleless table are significant, especially in $-$38 $ mu$m (400 mesh).</description><creator>Liu, Lilan</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>An investigation of gold recovery in the grinding and gravity circuits at Les Mines Camchib Inc. /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f39n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw332</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612p810</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the problem of recovering the local structure of surfaces from discrete range data. It is assumed that this recovery is done mostly in a bottom-up fashion, that is, without the help of a priori knowledge about the viewed surface. Because the problem is ill-posed, we nevertheless need to place constraints on the recovered structure to get a unique solution. In a bottom-up approach, these constraints must come from generic assumptions that apply to all surfaces. Many methods of bottom-up surface reconstruction have been proposed up to now, some of them dealing with intensity surfaces, some with range surfaces. Each of these methods either explicitly or implicitly applies a set of constraints on the data. The way in which the constraints are applied also varies from method to method. The main contribution of this thesis is some success at unifying a number of those methods under a common formalism of energy minimization, which will permit to better compare the choice of constraints between methods. We also show that the most successful surface reconstruction methods form idempotent operators, which we argue is to be expected. One method, Sander's curvature consistency, is studied in more detail than the others because it has not been studied much elsewhere yet.</description><creator>Lagarde, Jean W. (Jean Wilfrid)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Constraints and their satisfaction in the recovery of local surface structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pr46s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p810</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806097j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the interpretation of art, set against the background of the medieval Christian Neoplatonism of John Scotus Eriugena. For him, art and philosophy are regarded as the handmaidens of meaning. Therefore, although this thesis begins with a consideration of Eriugena's Periphyseon, it develops into a discussion on aesthetic theory, and ultimately into one on poetic theory. The object of this discussion is to account for meaning in Chaucer's Troilus and Criseyde according to Eriugenian poetics. The essence of art will thus be pursued within the parameters of the Neoplatonic scala natura. In this way, the whole poetic interpretation of Chaucer's poem is grasped as a mirror of the ontological exitus-reditus pattern. In understanding the poem this way, this thesis comes to immediate terms with the medieval concept of the imago Dei, and understands the likeness of mankind to God to be primarily one made by virtue of language.</description><creator>Logan, Frank Daniel Hermitage</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Erigena, Johannes Scotus, ca. 810-ca. 877. De divisione naturae.</subject><subject>Chaucer, Geoffrey, d. 1400. Troilus and Criseyde</subject><title>Poiesis : an Eriugenian interpretation of Chaucer's Troilus and and Criseyde</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vc64h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806097j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h561n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary purpose of this study is to examine the effects of the social and cultural revolution in post-World War One American society on gender relationships in F. Scott Fitzgerald's novels and a selection of his short stories. In his fictional works, Fitzgerald becomes a kind of social and cultural historian, reflecting the fundamental changes that began to occur in the 1920s. There were many factors that contributed to this Jazz-Age revolution in "manners and morals": the emancipation of women, giving rise to the American New Woman; the influence of Freud and his psychoanalytic theories on the already blossoming sexual revolution; and the mechanization and commercialization of all aspects of life in the machine age, drastically altering the way men and women had traditionally thought, behaved, and, communicated with one another.</description><creator>Kuxdorf, Stephanie</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940. Great Gatsby</subject><title>Love in a machine age : gender relationships in the novels and short stories of F. Scott Fitzgerald</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz28p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h561n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vm198</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Winnipegosis reef complexes probably consist of coalesced buildups, 75 to 100 m thick. They occur on a platform, 10 to 15 m thick. Basin sediments, 10 m thick, surround the complexes. Six facies are identified: (1) platform (lower and upper platform subfacies); (2) buildup interior; (3) buildup flank (laminated, bioturbated, cemented subfacies); (4) organic rim; (5) stromatolite cap; (6) basin (Brightholme, Ratner Members). Diagenesis occurred in four diagenetic environments: (1) open marine; (2) subaerial/meteoric; (3) restricted marine/shallow subsurface; (4) deeper subsurface. Fibrous cements occur in the cemented subfacies. Calcrete horizons with pendant cements formed in the stromatolite cap facies. All sediments are dolomitized. Isotopic data suggest that dolomitization occurred in the restricted marine and shallow burial environments in fluids derived from normal to slightly hypersaline Middle Devonian marine waters. Dolomitizing fluids derived from either the mechanical compaction of encasing evaporites or deeper formation waters were probably funnelled into the buildups. Minor fracturing and calcite cementation occurred in the deeper subsurface. Dedolomitization and calcitization of evaporites probably occurred at greater depths.</description><creator>Teare, Mark</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Sedimentology and diagenesis of middle devonian winnipegosis reef complexes Dawson Bay, Manitoba</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q517m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm198</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21725</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>