<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:51:47Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b768b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The introduction of minimally invasive surgery has resulted in revolutionary changes in the process of surgery. As a consequence, surgeons have had to adopt an entirely new skill set, one which requires additional training. To this end, surgical simulators have been developed, (physical simulators and virtual reality based simulators). We endeavored to validate the LapSim virtual reality simulator and assess its potential in the learning and acquisition of basic and complex laparoscopic skills. A series of studies were undertaken to provide evidence for the simulator's validity. They include the formulation of metrics, transference of basic skills to more complex laparoscopic tasks, and the transference of skills acquired using the simulator to the in vivo model. Through these studies, it is demonstrated that the virtual reality simulator is effective in enhancing laparoscopic skills in novices in both in vitro and in vivo environments.</description><creator>Sherman, Vadim.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Validation of a virtual reality surgical simulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Vadim Sherman, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54ks29v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b768b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gx90w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Activity of the cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR) is tightly regulated by cAMP-dependent phosphorylation, but the protein phosphatases (PP) that dephosphorylate and inactivate CFTR remain poorly understood. Differential regulation of single CFTR channels by protein phosphatase 2C (PP2C), protein phosphatase 2A (PP2A) and other phosphatases has been reported. The results suggest multiple protein phosphatases are required for complete CFTR deactivation, and that PP2C may be the primary phosphatase regulating CFTR in human airway and colonic epithelia, two major sites of disease. The goal of this project was to identify PP2C isoforms that regulate CFTR. Six isoforms of PP2C reported previously in mouse were recently recloned in this laboratory with epitope tags, and their interaction with CFTR was assessed by co-immunoprecipitation. Preliminary results indicated that MB2.1, one of the PP2Cbeta isoforms, and MA3, one of the PP2Calpha isoforms, interact with CFTR. To overexpress these phosphatases, I developed two inducible systems in which MB2.1 or MA3 gene expression is controlled by a promoter that is activated upon treatment of cells with ponasterone A, an ecdysone analogue. Although specific PP2C inhibitors are not presently available, mutagenesis and enzyme assays have identified residues that are essential for its enzymatic activity. I made PP2Calpha and PP2Cbeta mutants which are predicted to act as dominant negative inhibitors, and have stably transfected them using the inducible gene expression system. Furthermore, I showed that MB2.1 and MA3 are functionally expressed in the inducible expression system and that site-directed mutagenesis inactivated their phosphatase activity as assayed using phosphatase p-nitrophenyl phosphate (pNPP) as a substrate. Baby Hamster Kidney (BHK) cells stably expressing CFTR + inducible MB2.1, MA3 or their dominant negative mutants, are presently being used in iodide efflux assays to study the downregulation of CFTR by MB2.1 and MA3. Based on results, we exclude PP2C beta regulating CFTR. However, if PP2C alpha is the phosphatase which dephosphorylates CFTR can not be tested because of iodide loading problem.</description><creator>Liu, Na, 1979-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>A study of protein phosphatase 2C in cystic fibrosis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Na Liu, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p78k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx90w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cv87n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many human cancers have been associated with the deregulation of receptor tyrosine kinases. This occurs through various molecular mechanisms, including gene amplification, chromosome translocation and point mutations some of which involve loss of negative regulatory signals. Negative regulation of RTKs involves their internalisation and subsequent degradation in the lysosome. RTK oncoproteins activated following chromosomal translocation are no longer transmembrane proteins and would be predicted to escape lysosomal degradation. In this study, we addressed whether the Tpr-Met oncogene, produced via chromosomal translocation, escapes downregulation thereby leading to its oncogenic activity. Unlike the Met receptor, Tpr-Met is localized to the cytoplasm and lacks the binding site for Cbl, E3 ubiquitin ligases. Ubiquitination of RTKs, including the Met receptor, target them for efficient degradation in the lysosome. To address whether the subcellular localization of Tpr-Met, and/or loss of its Cbl binding site, is important for its oncogenic activity, Tpr-Met variants, targeted to the plasma membrane with and without Cbl recruitment were examined. The presence of a Cbl binding site and ubiquitination of cytosolic Tpr-Met oncoproteins does not alter Tpr-Met transforming activity, or protein stability, and these proteins fail to enter the endocytic pathway. However membrane targeting allows Tpr-Met to enter the endocytic pathway and transformation and protein stability are decreased in a Cbl dependent manner. These data demonstrate that the oncogenic activity of Tpr-Met is in part dependent on its ability to escape normal down-regulatory mechanisms and provides a paradigm for many RTK-derived oncoproteins activated following chromosomal translocation.</description><creator>Mak, Hayley Hoi Lam.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Loss of downregulation : a mechanism for oncogenic activation of receptor tyrosine kinase-derived oncoproteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hayley Hoi Lam Mak, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cj61s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cv87n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rn432</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. An online research network was set up among 11 dentists and 2 researchers in Montreal to test the feasibility of data collection over one year. Objectives. We evaluated the pilot participants' experiences and their perspectives regarding its potential utility. Methods. One-on-one qualitative interviews with 4 researchers, 4 dentists, and 3 policy makers. Interviews were recorded on audiotape and transcribed for coding and interpretation. Results. Although feasibility of data collection was evident in the pilot results; qualitative data revealed the limitations of the pilot, the unmet expectations, and the lack of impact of research findings. In terms of potential utility; the participants expressed interest in research, online communication and continuing education. Qualitative analysis revealed differences in perspectives and shared interests among the participants. Conclusion. An online research network can reduce the gap between research and practice. However, to attract participants, it must consider the needs and expectations of those involved.</description><creator>Makansi, Nora Nader.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><title>The potential utility of an online dental research network from the operspectives of clinicians, researchers, and policy makers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nora Nader Makansi, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fr08t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rn432</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sf837</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Netrins are bifunctional axon guidance cues, known to play an integral role in spinal cord development. It has previously been hypothesized that netrin-1 can regulate synaptogenesis by increasing the chances of axo-dendritic contact by causing axonal and dendritic branching and filopodial formation (N. X. Tritsh, M.Sc. thesis). The current study further investigates the role of netrin-1 at the rodent synapse. The results of this study indicate a possible role for the netrin receptor DCC and netrin-1 in spine morphology. Morphological changes were observed in dendritic spines of netrin-1 and DCC knock-out and heterozygous mice. The phenotypes observed in these mice, along with immunocytochemistry of hippocampal neurons, indicate the possible involvement of Unc5 homologues in dendritic spine morphology. We thus propose here a novel involvement of netrin-1 and the receptors DCC and possibly Unc5 homologues in modulating dendritic spine morphology.</description><creator>Luk, Tamarah.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>An investigation of the role for netrin-1 and the netrin receptor deleted in colorectal cancer in regulating dendritic spine morphology /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Tamarah Luk, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k946k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sf837</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v683r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Obesity is a growing major public health concern and is associated with various co-morbidities. Given recent evidence of increased bacterial infections in bariatric patients, morbid obesity may adversely affect the immune system. As a pleiotropic pro-inflammatory mediator produced primarily by adipocytes, leptin is a link between metabolism and immunity. Consequently, excessive leptin secretion may hinder the body's ability to defend against bacterial infection. This situation arises in morbid obesity, where chronic hyperleptinemia is observed. We used an in vivo murine model of hyperleptinemia to determine whether abnormal levels of circulating leptin have a detrimental effect on the trafficking of neutrophils, with respect to the number present, their rolling velocity, preadherence, and adherence to the endothelium. Male CD1 background mice (6-8 weeks) were divided to 3 treatment groups receiving once daily ip injections (1) sham (PBS); (2) low leptin (1mug/g); (3) high leptin (5mug/g). After 7 days of treatment, intravital microscopy was used to visualize post-capillary venule microcirculation of the cremaster muscle in the scrotum. Parameters such as neutrophil rolling, rolling velocity, preadherence, and adherence, were recorded and measured to assess PMN kinetics. High doses of leptin resulted in increased preadherence and adherence of neutrophils in post-capillary venules. Serum leptin and TNFalpha levels were found not to correlate with this observation; consequently, potential pathways through which leptin increases PMN adhesion could not be elucidated. Conceivably, excessive adhesion could adversely affect neutrophil trafficking by producing a shift towards the marginal pool, limiting their ability to appropriately home into bacterial targets. This could parallel the situation in morbid obesity where high concentrations of leptin are also observed.</description><creator>Chen, Justin.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>The effect of hyperleptinemia on polymorphonuclear neutrophil-endothelial interactions /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Justin Chen, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53x1205.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v683r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of General Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zs55n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There are a number of isoforms in the PLA2 superfamily, including secretory PLA2s (sPLA2) cytosolic PLA2s (cPLA 2), and calcium independent PLAS (iPLA2beta-short, beta-long, and gamma). In membranous nephropathy, glomerular epithelial cell (GEC) injury by complement C5b-9 leads to morphological changes in GEC and proteinuria, in association with cPLA2alpha activation. The present study addresses the role of iPLA2 in GEC injury. Complement-mediated release of [3H] arachidonic acid was most significantly augmented in GEC overexpressing iPLA2gamma (GEC-iPLA2gamma) as compared with GEC-Neo control. The accelerated AA release was inhibited by the iPLA2-directed catalytic inhibitor bromoenol lactone (BEL). For comparison, GEC-iPLA2gamma also amplified [3H]AA release after incubation of GEC with H2O2, or chemical anoxia followed by re-exposure to glucose, whereas stable clones overexpressing iPLA2gamma only amplified [3H]AA release after incubation with H2O2. Complement-mediated cytotoxicity (measured by release of lactate dehydrogenase) was attenuated significantly in GEC-iPLA2gamma, as compared with GEC-Neo, and the cytoprotective effect of iPLA2gamma was reversed by BEL and partially by Indomethacin. In keeping with previous results, incubation of GEC-cPLA2alpha with complement increased free [3H]AA. This increase in [ 3H]AA was blocked by BEL, although BEL did not block cPLA2alpha activity in cell extracts in vitro. Thus, in addition to cPLA2alpha, iPLA2gamma may be involved in complement-mediated release of AA. Moreover, activation of cPLA2alpha by complement appears to be, at least in part, dependent on iPLA2gamma. Modulation of iPLA2gamma activity may provide a new approach to reducing GEC injury.</description><creator>Cohen, Daniel, 1980-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Role of iPLA₂ in complement (C5b-9) mediated GEC injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Daniel Cohen, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw70g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zs55n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rq53g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While some strains of Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans serve as causative agents of Localized Aggressive Periodontitis (LAP), there are strains of A. actinomycetemcomitans that live as members of the microflora in the oral cavities of periodontally healthy individuals. Two-component signal transduction is an important determinant of bacterial behaviour and plays an essential role in the regulation of virulence factors. Hence, our study investigates the two-component systems (TCSs) among A. actinomycetemcomitans strains of varying virulence levels. Among the groups of highly and mildly virulent strains that were studied, we found there to be significant differences in the ygiX/ygiY TCS. In the most virulent strains, the genes encoding the ygiX/ygiY TCS are part of an operon that includes 4 phage-related genes and a gene homologous to ygiW a gene that encodes a periplasmic protein. Hence, considering the importance of TCS in the regulation of virulence, we hypothesize that the ygiX/ygiY TCS might play a significant role in the regulation of virulence factors in highly virulent strains of A. actinomycetemcomitans . Further characterization of the ygiX/ygiY TCS will determine whether it indeed regulates the expression of genes that encode virulence factors.</description><creator>Cieslak, Alicja.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Two-component signal transduction in Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Alicja Cieslak, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wv80p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rq53g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53x121f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Among the ATP-gated channels, the P2X3 subtype is exclusively expressed in nociceptors of dorsal root ganglia (DRG) and trigeminal ganglia, where it plays a major role in enhanced pain sensation observed in chronic pain states. We tested the hypothesis that P2X3 receptors are modulated by metabotropic receptors, such as 5-HT2A, mG1uR5 and trkA, leading to increased P2X3-mediated currents. Double fluorescence labeling confirmed that P2X3-expressing neurons are labeled by the lectin IB4 and we showed that 5-HT2A and mGluR5 receptors, but not trkA, are expressed in a fraction of IB4-positive neurons. Using confocal microscopy, we examined the subcellular distribution of P2X3 and we observed that 5-HT induced a translocation of P2X3 labeling in a significant number of neurons. In Xenopus oocytes, we recorded a short-lasting and kinase-dependent potentiation of P2X3 currents by activation of co-expressed 5-HT2A and mGluR5 receptors. The data presented here show that both 5-HT2A and mG1uR5 are potential modulators of P2X3 receptors in a subset of nociceptors in DRG.</description><creator>Chabot-Doré, Anne-Julie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Metabotropic regulation of ATP-gated P2X3 receptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Anne-Julie Chabot-Doré, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580r83b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x121f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z935x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Constant improvements in computer communications, microprocessors and operating systems are finally making wide-area public computing utilities (PCUs) a reality. The core idea of a CU is to connect resources that are geographically distributed and potentially heterogeneous into a single networked system such that clients can obtain on-demand the necessary resources for their computing needs from this system. Several PCUs have been created in the recent past using the Grid technology for both research and commercial purposes. Because PCUs often bring together resources from geographically distributed locations, they are ideally suited for applications that have geographically distributed resource demands. An example application with geographically distributed demand is online gaming. A popular online game can be a meeting point for a large number of players from diverse network locations. Often the gameplay can generate network and process intensive transactions that should be carried out by the game servers in a timely fashion for positive player experience. Using PCUs and distributed game server architectures, it is possible to locate game servers closer to major concentrations of the player population, which can satisfy the quality of service requirements of vast majority of the players. In this thesis, I present an approach for online game hosting on wide-area computing utilities. My approach is based on virtual clusters (VCs) that are equivalent to virtual organizations (VOs). A VC can be considered as a "slice" of the PCU resource pool that is allocated for a single game or class of games. Because I was only concerned about the resource allocation problem, I refer to the slice as VC instead of VO. This study has two parts. In the first part, a performance model is developed for an online game that can be used for hosting purposes. Quake, as a sequential (from Quake I to Quake IV), publicly available, multiplayer game server became my study object because it is a commercial server application that has been used extensively and exhibits many of the required characteristics. The performance modeling methodology, however, is sufficiently generic and should be applicable to other online games. In the second part, a resource allocation algorithm is developed for multiple VCs creation. This algorithm is capable of creating multiple VCs with different demand profiles. The multiple VCs creation problem is equivalent to a facility location problem that is proven to be NP-hard, which is concerned with optimally placing a number of facilities (equivalent to serving resources) to cover demands at a predefined set of points. The assumption is that placing a facility at a given candidate location incurs a fixed cost and each facility has a limited capacity of covering the demands. An efficient heuristics is developed, which can be deployed at short time scales. To minimize the multiple VCs reconfigurations, redundancy is built into the multiple VCs model. Extensive simulation studies were used to evaluate the performance of the multiple VCs model. The experimental results prove that the developed algorithm for multiple VCs model can treat each VC in a fair and efficient way.</description><creator>Yuan, Weiquan, 1978-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Hosting online games on wide-area computing utilities using model-based resource provisioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Weiquan Yuan, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dt67k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z935x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b769m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) are a group of 209 chemical congeners that are toxic and persistent organic contaminants---they have been present in the environmental for several decades. Sites contaminated with PCBs pose serious health and safety risks to the surrounding environment due to their toxicity, persistence and bioaccumulation in creature. Polychlorinated biphenyls were commercially produced complex mixtures for a variety of applications. Before production was discontinued world-wide in 1977, several million tons of PCBs have been directly disposed to the soil. Researchers have been encouraged to develop novel techniques/approaches to detoxify PCB compounds and PCB contaminated soil. Ideally, these methods would be inexpensive, rapid, efficient and environmentally benign. This study investigated novel approaches/techniques for PCB hydrodechlorination with noble metal catalyst in a continuous hydrogenation system, using a reactor column filled with Pd0/gamma-Al2O3 catalyst. Appreciable quantities of PCB compounds or other aromatic compounds were hydrodechlorinated and/or hydrogenated under mild conditions (90°C). The reaction efficiency was virtually complete if sufficient H2 was included in the mobile phase either by pure H2 or supercritical CO 2 combined with 5% H2. The study also optimized conditions to wash PCBs washing condition from contaminated soil by sonication mixing and outlined an environmentally benign industrial application that combined soil washing with an at line PCBs hydrodechlorination process. The techniques/approaches developed in this study would seem to have a broad application in PCB dechlorination/detoxification and in the remediation of historically contaminated soil/sediments.</description><creator>Yu, Liang, 1978-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Polychlorinated biphenyls -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Surface active agents.</subject><title>Washing to detoxify soil burdened with PCB compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Liang Yu, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n854.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b769m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462958v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The zero-temperature equilibrium conductance of mesoscopic devices due to single-particle resonant tunneling was first described by Landauer [1]. The Landauer formula was later extended to the multi-channel case by Fisher and Lee [2], who reduced the problem of calculating electronic transport properties to the problem of solving for the Green's function for a given system geometry. In this work, the single-particle formalism is extended to the study of higher-order two-particle cotunneling processes by considering many-body Green's functions. The effect of attaching leads to the system is described in terms of a two-particle self-energy, whose analytical form is written in terms of a Feynman path integral over all possible tunneling processes between the leads and the device. In addition, an efficient numerical technique for the calculation of the fully dressed Green's function of a device region attached to two-particle leads is presented. The problem of two-particle transport is then approached, and an analogy to single-particle transport on the infinite plane is drawn. It is shown that, for nonspin flip cotunneling processes, the two-particle transport result can be related to the single-particle conductance by way of a simple convolution. Finally, results for the cotunneling contribution to the conductance of double quantum dots, or charge qubits, are presented.</description><creator>Young, Carolyn, 1979-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Many-body cotunneling in coupled quantum dots</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carolyn Young, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x803v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462958v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jg50r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The closure of the US border to Canadian live cattle and beef products after the confirmation of a single Canadian BSE case in May, 2003 seriously jeopardized the Canadian beef cattle industry, which had relied heavily on exports. The inventory of cattle rapidly increased and farmers were paid record low prices for live cattle. But at the same time, the cattle slaughtering industry experienced a substantial increase in profits. The enlarged price spread between the value of live cattle and beef steak raised concerns about oligopsony market power in the live cattle market. This thesis investigates the hypothesis that the Canadian slaughtering industry exercised this market power in the months following the discovery of BSE. Two models, the conjectural variation model from the New Empirical Industrial Organization and an asymmetric price transmission model were used and the results from both models do not support the hypothesis of oligopsony market power.</description><creator>Xu, Xiaoqiong, 1982-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Beef cattle -- Prices -- Canada.</subject><subject>Cattle trade -- Canada.</subject><subject>Beef -- Prices -- Canada.</subject><subject>Bovine spongiform encephalopathy -- Economic aspects -- Canada.</subject><subject>Beef industry -- Canada.</subject><title>The effect of BSE on the pricing behaviour of the Canadian cattle slaughtering industry /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Xiaoqiong Xu, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kc62s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jg50r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000428h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Earthworms are well known to increase decomposition of organic matter and release of plant available nutrients. They can also increase CO 2 and N2O fluxes from the soil by stimulating respiration, denitrification, and nitrification caused by soil microorganisms. The objective of this thesis was to examine the influence of different earthworm species and population numbers on CO2 and N2O fluxes from a corn agroecosystem. In the field study, earthworm treatments had a significant effect on CO2 fluxes, but there was no difference between CO 2 fluxes from the two species (Lumbricus terrestris L., Aporrectodea caliginosa Savigny) or from the two population levels (1x and 2x the naturally-occuring population). Also, the earthworm treatments had no significant effect on N2O fluxes. Since all treatments contained mixed species and similar population levels at the end of the study, it is likely that CO2 and N2O fluxes in the field were affected more by soil temperature and moisture fluctuations than by the earthworm treatments. The study was repeated in laboratory microcosms under environmental control. Again, earthworm treatments had a significant effect on CO2 fluxes, but not on N2O fluxes. Interestingly, the N 2O fluxes from microcosms containing L. terrestris came solely from denitrification, while the N2O fluxes from A. caliginosa microcosms were produced mostly by nitrification. It is not known why these species stimulate different groups of microorganisms that can produce N2O, and this remains to be investigated.</description><creator>Speratti, Alicia B.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Corn -- Soils -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Atmospheric carbon dioxide.</subject><subject>Atmospheric nitrous oxide.</subject><subject>Earthworms -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Earthworm-microbial interactions influence carbon dioxide and nitrous oxide fluxes from agricultural soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Alicia B. Speratti, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430897f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000428h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j5322</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A model-driven approach to scenario-based requirements engineering is proposed. The approach, which is based on Computer Automated Multi-Paradigm Modeling (CAMPaM), aims to improve the software process. A framework is given and implemented to reason about models of systems at multiple levels of abstraction, to transform between models in different formalisms, and to provide and evolve modeling formalisms. The model-driven approach starts with modeling requirements of a system in scenario models and the subsequent automatic transformation to state-based behavior models. Then, either code can be synthesized or models can be further transformed into models with additional information such as explicit timing information or interactions between components. These models, together with the inputs (e.g., queries, performance metrics, test cases, etc.) generated directly from the scenario models, can be used for a variety of purposes, such as verification, analysis, simulation, animation and so on. A visual modeling environment is built in AToM3 using Meta-Modeling and Model Transformation. It supports modeling in Sequence Diagrams, automatic transformation to Statecharts, and automatic generation of requirements text from Sequence Diagrams. An application of the model-driven approach to the assessment of use cases for dependable systems is shown.</description><creator>Sun, Ximeng, 1979-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Engineering design -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Computer-aided design.</subject><title>A model-driven approach to scenario-based requirements engineering /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ximeng Sun, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236654r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j5322</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892g28w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, Mars Global Surveyor mapping-phase magnetic data are used to derive a combined spherical harmonic model of both Martian crustal and time-dependent external magnetic fields. A 60-degree spherical harmonic model of the crustal magnetic anomalies is first isolated, by averaging of in-shadow data over 0.5° x 0.5° latitude and longitude bins, and covariance analysis between multiple independent models. This model is then subtracted, separately, from day-side and night-side measurements. External residual data are expended in terms of now time-dependent 30-degree spherical harmonics, using 1 year and 1/2 year periods, and with separate internal and external radial dependencies. Independent Fourier series expansions allow to validate the temporal variations of the preceding model. As a result, I obtain, along with the crustal anomaly maps, the spatial distribution of the external fields, their steady-state features, and the amplitude maps of their yearly and half a year variations, separately for day and night sides of Mars. Although the maxima of the temporal amplitudes show good correlations with the strong crustal anomalies, there are significant differences between them. </description><creator>St-Laurent Lemerle, Alexandre.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>Analysis of Mars Global Surveyor magnetic data : crustal and time-dependent external magnetic fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Alexandre St-Laurent Lemerle, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mp05h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892g28w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cj63b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study the problem of computing the medial surface of a polyhedral solid. As this problem is difficult to solve exactly, we consider an approximate solution that locates regions of space through which the medial surface passes. The algorithm we design is based on the measure of the average outward flux of the gradient of the Euclidian distance transform of the polyhedron through the surface of a spherical region shrinking to a point. We extend previous methods by developing a completeness criterion that adopts this measure for spheres of non-zero size. As a result, we obtain a coarse-to-fine algorithm that reveals those voxels that contain sections of the medial surface. Such an implementation has the advantage that digital thinning with homotopy type preservation can be borrowed from past work. We argue that the error due to discrete flux computations is bounded.</description><creator>Stolpner, Svetlana.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Coarse-to-fine medial surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Svetlana Stolpner, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qv169.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cj63b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qx01h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the context of gene expression, we proposed a nonlinear stochastic delay differential equation as a mathematical model to study the effects of extrinsic noise on a delay induced Hopf bifurcation. We envisaged its direct numerical resolution. Following the example of the noisy oscillator, we first solved a linearized version of the equation, close to the Hopf bifurcation. The numerical scheme used is a combination of a standard algorithm to solve a deterministic delay differential equation and a stochastic Euler scheme. From our calculations we verified that the deterministic behaviour is fully recovered. For the stochastic case, we found that our solution is qualitatively accurate, in the sense that the noise induced shift in the critical value a, follows the trend the known analytic results predict. However, our numerical solution systematically overestimates the value of the shift. This is explained because the accuracy in the numerical estimation of the decay rate of a solution towards the stationary state value is a function of the control parameter a. We believe the mismatch between the numerical solution and the analytic results is due to a lack of convergence of our scheme, rather than to lack of accuracy. As our numerical scheme is an hybrid, the convergence problem can be improved, both at the deterministic and at the stochastic parts of the scheme. In this work we left our numerical results on the nonlinear case out, because before proceeding to the investigation of the nonlinear equation, the convergence must be assured in the linear case.</description><creator>Mondraǵon Palomino, Octavio.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Genetic regulation -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Bifurcation theory.</subject><title>A numerical study of the effects of multiplicative noise on a supercritical delay induced Hopf bifurcation in a gene expression model /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Octavio Mondraǵon Palomino, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sm450.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qx01h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096c18c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Habitat fragmentation can influence the genetics of a population through the direct loss of genetic diversity, and by the genetic processes that occur as a result of small remnant populations or the geographic isolation of populations. I examined the population genetics of two woodland amphibian species in localities with different land-use histories. The wood frog (Rana sylvatica) and the red-backed salamander (Plethodon cinereus) use the same general habitat but differ with respect to a few key life-history characteristics relating to dispersal. I then compared between species the relative influence each land-use scenario had on the population genetic structure. I found that habitat fragmentation affected the population genetics of the two amphibians and did so differently for each species. The differential population genetic response of these two amphibians to habitat fragmentation reinforces the important role of life-history characteristics in how the genetic structure of a population is shaped over time.</description><creator>Meyer, Shavonne.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Fragmented landscapes -- Saint Lawrence River Valley.</subject><subject>Wood frog -- Saint Lawrence River Valley -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Amphibian populations -- Saint Lawrence River Valley.</subject><subject>Plethodon cinereus -- Saint Lawrence River Valley -- Genetics.</subject><title>Landscape history, dispersal, and the genetic structure of amphibian populations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Shavonne Meyer, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cv88x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096c18c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x5441</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regulation of nutritional intake by herbivorous insects often leads to optimal performance. When given choices, beet armyworm, Spodoptera exigua, caterpillars selected a diet with a protein to digestible carbohydrate ratio of 22p:20c. Restriction to carbohydrate-biased diets led to increased mortality and developmental time. On protein-biased diets, caterpillars possessed metabolic strategies to maintain optimal performance. Caterpillar glucose oxidase (GOX), which catalyzes the oxidation of glucose, may be a pre-ingestive mechanism to cope with excess dietary carbohydrates. GOX activity was highest in the labial salivary glands of 4th instar caterpillars and was higher in caterpillars reared on a meridic artificial diet (AD) compared to those fed Medicago truncatula. Following transfer from plants, labial salivary GOX activity increased with time spent on AD suggesting that a dietary factor is involved in this enzyme's regulation. Dietary carbohydrate levels do not appear to regulate GOX activity; however nutritional content may play a role its regulation.</description><creator>Merkx-Jacques, Magali.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Beet armyworm -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Beet armyworm -- Food.</subject><title>Nutritional regulation in the generalist caterpillar Spodoptera exigua (Hübner)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Magali Merkx-Jacques, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t65v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x5441</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wm49v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We analyze the hadronic phase of QCD using effective thermal field theory techniques. Our goal is to investigate the medium created in heavy ion collisions by calculating the electromagnetic emissivity of strongly interacting matter in the hadronic phase. We proceed through examining the vector meson properties in a thermal bath where the temperature reaches deconfinement and chiral symmetry is restored. In particular we observe the behavior of the rho spectral function in thermal medium and use it as a probe to examine the thermal environment generated in the collision.</description><creator>Mia, Mohammed Shahpur.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Vector mesons.</subject><subject>Quantum chromodynamics.</subject><title>Vector meson properties in a strongly interacting thermal medium</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mohammed Shahpur Mia, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sv201.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wm49v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vg71j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Caenorhabditis elegans clk-1(qm30) and isp-1(qm150) mutants exhibit highly pleiotropic phenotypes that include slow development and long lifespan. clk-1(qm30) and isp-1(qm150) correspond to loss of function mutations in genes necessary for ubiquinone biosynthesis and complex III electron transport, respectively. Previous research has lead to the hypothesis that altered levels of cellular reactive oxygen species (ROS) may underlie clk-1(qm30) and isp-1(qm150) mutant phenotypes. To test this hypothesis RNA interference (RNAi) by feeding was used to indirectly alter cellular ROS levels by knocking down genes that encode ROS detoxification enzymes. Specifically, genes that detoxify ROS using glutathione or thioredoxin, both of which are important cellular thiol-redox molecules, were knocked down to examine the role of ROS in determining clk-1(qm30) and isp-1(qm150) lifespan, post-embryonic development, and germline development. In summary, knocking down ROS detoxification genes does not severely appear to affect the phenotypes that were studied. ROS detoxification gene knockdowns consistently induced mild decreases in wild type, clk-1(qm30), and isp-1(qm150) lifespan. However, knocking down NAD+-dependent isocitrate dehydrogenases, which are not closely involved in ROS detoxification, similarly affected lifespan, indicating that decreases are not specific to ROS detoxification. Of note, knocking down gcs-1, which is required for glutathione biosynthesis, induced lethal intestinal abnormalities in wild type, c1k-1(qm30), and isp-1(qm150) worms. Overall, findings do not support that low ROS underlies the clk-1(qm30) and isp-1(qm150) mutant phenotypes.</description><creator>Lee, Sansan.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Longevity.</subject><subject>Active oxygen in the body.</subject><title>The effects of knocking down ROS detoxification enzymes on the Caenorhabditis elegans mutants clk-1(qm30) and isp-1(qm150) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sansan Lee, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483p458.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vg71j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r5212</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although the range dynamics of North American amphibians during the last glacial cycle are increasingly better understood, the recolonization history of the most northern regions and the impact of southern refugia on patterns of genetic diversity in these regions are not well reconstructed. In this study I present the phylogeographic history of a widespread and primarily northern frog, Rana sylvatica. For this study, 45 individuals from 34 localities were surveyed for a 700 b p. fragment of cytochrome b and 551 individuals from 116 localities were surveyed for 650 b.p. of the NADH dehydrogenase subunit 2 and tRNATRP mitochondrial genes. Phylogenetic analyses revealed two distinct clades corresponding to eastern and western populations. Phylogeographic patterns within each of these clades revealed similarities as well as differences from patterns found in other species. Specifically, the results corroborate eastern refugia located in the southern Appalachians near present-day North and South Carolina and in the interior plains in the lower Ohio River Valley. Current Maritime populations form a subclade amongst eastern populations and appear to have been colonized from the southern refugium. However, a more northern refugium located in the Appalachian highlands seems to have been source for most other northeastern wood frog populations. Rana sylvatica populations in the Great Lakes region appear to have been colonized from a western refugium located in present-day Wisconsin. This refugium was also a likely source for populations in the species' expansive northwestern range since there is no evidence to support additional, more western refugia.</description><creator>Lee-Yaw, Julie A.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Wood frog -- North America -- Geographical distribution.</subject><subject>Wood frog -- North America -- Phylogeny.</subject><title>The phylogeographic history of the wood frog (Rana sylvatica) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Julie A. Lee-Yaw, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8384693.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r5212</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988q05d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective. to determine how patterns of respiratory symptom change, patient behavior, and health status are related among patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and a history of exacerbations. Methods. The study population was 421 community-dwelling adults with moderate to severe COPD. Symptom-based events (exacerbations) were defined to be any increase in at least one key symptom (dyspnea, sputum amount, sputum color) recorded in the daily diary on at least two consecutive days. An event was reported if it resulted in an exacerbation phone call or documented health-care utilization. Predictors of reporting were assessed using a Cox proportional hazards model. Results. Two-thirds of all events and 40% of events with 4 or more symptoms were not reported. Reporting an event was positively associated with a greater number of respiratory symptoms (HR:1.58, 95% CI: 1.37-1.81), a younger age (HR:1.12, 95% Cl:1.02-1.22 each 5 years), a lower FEV1 (HR:1.20, 95% CI:1.01-1.43 each 10% of predicted FEV1), and weekdays versus weekend (HR:3.03 and 95% CI:1.89-4.76). Conclusion. There was a high incidence of unreported exacerbations and some were important enough (4 or more symptoms) to have an indication for treatment. Reporting was related to the severity of exacerbation and underlying disease.</description><creator>Langsetmo, Lisa.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><title>Under-reporting exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease : incidence and predictors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Lisa Langsetmo, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945w18x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988q05d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xd81s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:13:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sepsis-induced diaphragmatic force loss and failure are associated with an increased exposure to proinflammatory mediators. The septic diaphragm has recently been reported to overexpresse chemokines, including the CC chemokine MCP-1 (monocyte chemoattractant protein-1). This thesis seeks to address the significance of MCP-1 overproduction in diaphragm proinflammatory mediator expression and skeletal muscle contractile function. Neutralization of endogenous MCP-1, produced following administration of LPS, decreased transcription of iNOS, IL-6, IL-1alpha, IL-1beta and MCP-1 in the diaphragm and prevented a decrease in diaphragm force production. Furthermore, exogenous MCP-1 stimulated IL-6 and MCP-1 transcription in primary diaphragm myotubes, and injection of MCP-1 in the healthy EDL muscle led to contractile weakness. Taken together, these results suggest that increased MCP-1 production in the septic diaphragm stimulates proinflammatory mediator production by diaphragm myocytes, contributing to the muscle's contractile dysfunction.</description><creator>Labbé, Katherine.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The role of monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 in diaphragm dysfunction during sepsis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Katherine Labbé, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sz10v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xd81s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>