<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:43:28Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40100" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k6876</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis proposes that the United Kingdom's constitution is changing so as to incorporate written principles that restrain Parliament through judicial review. This model originates in the common law as well as the orthodox theories of Blackstone and Dicey. It is supported by the ultra vires doctrine and provides a basis for judicial review of Parliament itself. As constitutions may accommodate written and unwritten elements, along with various means of enforcement and change, they are defined by how strongly they reflect underlying norms. This expressive function, with a shift in the rule of recognition endorsing judicial review, democratically legitimizes constitutional texts as positivist expressions of popular will binding Parliament. Furthermore, through common-law adjudication, courts may constitutionalize statutes or treaties coming over time to represent shifting norms. This "quasi-written" common-law constitution is already emerging in the United Kingdom, as illustrated through cases based upon the Human Rights Act and the European Communities Act.</description><creator>Jenkins, Christopher D.</creator><contributor>Glenn, H. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>From unwritten to written : transformation in the British Common-Law constitution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf61n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k6876</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df40z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The judicial system in what is now the European Union has been subject to only a few structural changes since the Court of Justice assumed jurisdiction over the European Economic Community and the European Atomic Energy Community. In a more significant development, the Court of Justice has shaped its own role and its relationship with the courts of the Member States. Today, the functioning of the resultant system is put at risk by an increasing case-load and duration of proceedings, but also by the impact of certain developments in the Community legal order and the intended enlargement of the European Union. Various mechanisms of reform, including those now framed by the Treaty of Nice, may remedy individual problems. But only the re-organisation of the courts according to their different essential tasks will lead to a principled structure for the future.</description><creator>Hoehler, Ulrich Walter.</creator><contributor>de Mestral, Armand (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>The future of the judicial system in the European Union /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw952.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df40z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150k897</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis the author explores the role of women as participants in the Rwandan genocide. The thesis is informed by the insights of Western feminist criminologists, as well as a consideration of women's status in pre-genocide Rwanda. The author then draws from empirical research conducted both with female genocide suspects in the Rwandan prisons and with persons working in the Rwandan criminal justice system to reveal that popular understandings of 'participation' in the genocide do not always equate with formal legal meanings. She also considers questions of power and women's motivations for participating in the genocide. She argues that despite the adoption of a formal 'equal treatment' approach to genocide suspects, gender comes into play at almost every step of the Rwandan and international criminal justice processes, with the effect that some women appear to be receiving impunity for their actions, while others are being unfairly disadvantaged.</description><creator>Hogg, Nicole.</creator><contributor>Toope, Stephen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>"I never poured blood" : women accused of genocide in Rwanda</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f67n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k897</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064760n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mechanisms involved in morphine tolerance are poorly understood. It was reported that calcitonin gene-related peptide (CGRP) immunoreactivity was increased in the spinal dorsal horn during morphine tolerance and an in vitro repetitive morphine treatment was able to mimic the in vivo results by inducing increases in CGRP- and substance P (SP)-immunoreactive (IR) neurons in cultured dorsal root ganglia (DRG). The aim of this study was to validate the DRG cell culture model by establishing which subtypes of opioid receptors are involved in the induction of CGRP and SP in cultured rat DRG neurons and to examine the signaling pathway involved in the induction of the neuropeptides following repetitive opiate treatments. Following treatment with any of the three opioid agonists [mu; DAMGO, delta; DPDPE, kappa; U50488H], the number of CGRP- and SP-IR neurons increased significantly, in a concentration-dependent manner. Double-immunofluorescence staining showed that the three opioid receptors were colocalized with both of the pain-related neuropeptides. Protein kinase C (PKC)-IR was found to be significantly increased following a repetitive treatment with DAMGO. Double-immunofluorescence staining showed the colocalization of PKCalpha with CGRP or SP in cultured DRG neurons. Moreover, a combined treatment of the opioid with a PKC inhibitor was able to block the effects of the opioid on increased CGRP-like IR. In conclusion, the data suggests that the three opioid receptors may be involved in the induction of CGRP and SP observed following chronic exposure to opiates and that PKC probably plays a role in the signaling pathway leading to the upregulation. These findings further validate the DRG cell culture as a suitable model to study intracellular pathways that govern changes seen following repetitive opioid treatments.</description><creator>Belanger, Serge.</creator><contributor>Quirion, Remi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Expression of calcitonin gene-related peptide and substance P in cultured dorsal root ganglion neurons following chronic exposure to opiates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n510h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064760n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr1720052</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dynamically delivered intensity modulated beams (IMBs) pose unique verification problems that may be addressed with the use of integrating continuous 3D dosimeters such as gel based Fricke dosimeters. Accurate knowledge of the ability of these dosimeters to measure adequately and precisely the delivered dose is a prerequisite for their clinical use. The magnetic properties of the ferrous and ferric ions present in the gel based Fricke dosimeter after its irradiation are the basis for the use of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in the measurement of dose. This thesis presents the investigation of a 3D gel based Fricke dosimetry system (Fricke-gel). A software system is developed and spin-lattice relaxation rate (R1) images are computed from MR images of irradiated Fricke-gel phantoms in order to quantify the dosimetric uncertainties resulting from the MR imaging system, from the gel itself, as well as from the external parameters. The sensitivity and the minimum detectable dose of the Fricke-gel dosimeter are determined. Validation of the dosimeter's capacity to measure dose distributions is made through measurement of percent depth dose curves (PDD's), and field profiles (open and wedged). An example of clinical utilisation of the Fricke-gel dosimeter is presented. Dose distributions are evaluated visually by 3D software tools and quantitatively analyzed by dose-volume histograms. Results show a good correlation between the Fricke-gel measured dose distributions and treatment planning software dose calculations.</description><creator>Belanger, Philippe.</creator><contributor>Hristov, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Parker, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>MR based frickle-gelatin dosimetry : uncertainty evaluation and computerised analysis of measured dose distributions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37638829.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1720052</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xd48g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines modern relationships among salt marsh plant species and their pollen in three salt marshes located on the northwest coast of the Bay of Fundy, New Brunswick. Linear regression analysis of pollen in 35 surface sediment samples and vegetation cover on small (&lt;15 m) and broad (&gt;15 m) scales show that, with the exception of Poaceae and Cheno Am, pollen corresponds well with fine-scale patterns of salt marsh vegetation. Scatter diagrams of paired pollen and cover data illustrate that cover of Triglochin is over-represented by its pollen, Glaux is under-represented, and Poaceae, Cheno Am, and Plantago are inconsistent. Tidal mixing and differential inputs from local, regional, and extra-regional sources with elevation limit the establishment of plant-pollen relationships for Cheno Am and Poaceae but not for other taxa. Comparison of 35 modern analogs from five vegetation zones using squared chord distance show that zones are distinct such that the marsh-terrestrial interface can be tracked with the greatest degree of certainty in a salt marsh paleo-ecological record and other marsh zones can be tracked when a conservative threshold of dissimilarity is used.</description><creator>Beecher, Carolyn Beth.</creator><contributor>Chmura, G. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Pollen -- Fundy, Bay of -- Dispersal.</subject><subject>Salt marsh plants -- Fundy, Bay of.</subject><title>Modern pollen and vegetation relationships in Bay of Fundy salt marshes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b293z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd48g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634564m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since cranberry skin is thick and has low porosity, skin pretreatments were considered before drying in order to facilitate water diffusion. Mechanical and chemical pretreatments were considered, by cutting the fruits in half, by making pin holes in each cranberry, and by dipping the fruits in an alkaline solution. A second pretreatment seemed necessary when drying cranberries in order to reduce their tartness. Cranberries were osmotically dehydrated, by immersing them in osmotic solutions of sucrose or high fructose corn syrup. Once the pretreatment conditions were selected, four drying methods were tested on the pretreated cranberries. These methods included hot air drying, freeze-drying, vacuum drying and a combination of hot air and microwaves. A quality evaluation of the dried samples was also performed, including evaluation of overall appearance, taste, color, water activity, rehydration capacity and texture. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Beaudry, Claudia.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Microwave drying.</subject><subject>Cranberries -- Drying.</subject><title>Evaluation of drying methods on osmotically dehydrated cranberries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg66d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634564m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268695w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this work was to model a transferred arc metal evaporator including the behavior of a plasma arc and the molten anode being continuously evaporated. The model predicted the system temperature and velocity distributions as well as the rate of metal evaporation. The effects of arc current, arc length, plasma gas flow rate, crucible temperature, surrounding temperature, and hydrogen addition to an argon arc have been investigated and some optimization of operating conditions was done. The appropriate governing equations were solved numerically. The numerical results of the present investigation revealed that the geometry of the crucible did not significantly affect the temperature distribution of anode surface or the metal vaporization rate. Increasing plasma torch flow rate also did not lead to an increase of the temperature of the anode surface and the metal vaporization rate. However, the crucible temperatures significantly affected the vaporization rate; the crucible should be maintained at a high temperature, which is compatible to the physico-chemical properties of the crucible material. The arc current strongly affected the vaporization. Addition of hydrogen to the plasma gas caused a significant increase of vaporization rate. The arc length greatly affected the surface temperature distribution, the metal vaporization rate, the arc voltage, and the total power. Shorter arcs were found to be more effective. The modeling results were in reasonable agreement with the experiment results.</description><creator>Yu, Jun, 1965-</creator><contributor>Munz, R. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Modeling of a transferred arc metal evaporator for the production of ultrafine metal powders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t34b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268695w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r740v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We questioned whether adrenergic amines extracted from the Seville orange Citrus Aurantium (CA) increases metabolic rate and enhance the thermic response to a 1.7MJ mixed meal (TEF) in lean and obese men and women; the latter had upper-body obesity, a condition associated with defective TEF, attributed to altered SNS. Nine lean (7M, 2F; BMI: 23 +/- 1 k g/m 2; waist circumference: 78 +/- 2 cm) and 13 obese (4M, 9F; BMI: 35 +/- 1 kg/m2; waist circumference: 105 +/- 3 cm) subjects were studied. With CA: (1) RMR increased more in men vs women (94 vs 42 kJ over 5 h), independently of body composition; (2) urinary epinephrine excretion increased in both groups and dopamine only in men. A 17% lower TEF in obese subjects was no longer significant when controlled for gender. By contrast, there was an effect of gender on TEF that remained significant when adjusted for measures of obesity. Women had a lower TEF that increased to values no longer different from men with CA. CA did not affect TEF in men. CA had no cardiovascular effects. Thus, CA ingestion increased thermogenesis by 4% above RMR and enhanced the lower TEF of women by 29% (46kJ).</description><creator>Adam, Mariam M.</creator><contributor>Gougeon, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Weight loss.</subject><subject>Sour orange.</subject><subject>Metabolism -- Effect of drugs on.</subject><title>Thermogenic effect of beta-sympathicomimetic compounds extracted from Citrus aurantium in humans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z957p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r740v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172006b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dimorphic Leishmania donovani parasites exist as promastigotes in the sandfly vector and differentiate into amastigotes once injected into the skin of human hosts during a blood meal. The mechanisms and signals that are involved in triggering differentiation are not well understood in Leishmania. We have investigated whether tyrosine phosphorylation is a possible signalling component. Differential levels of tyrosine-phosphorylated proteins were observed in extracts from in vitro promastigote and amastigote cultures, with an overall reduction in the latter stage. Following this observation, the inhibition of tyrosine phosphorylation was examined in promastigotes using Tyrphostin AG1433, a broad-spectrum tyrosine phosphorylation inhibitor. AG1433 treated in vitro promastigote cultures differentiate into amastigote-like morphology, have reduced tyrosine phosphorylation level, and express the amastigote-specific marker A2 proteins. Our studies demonstrate that signal transduction mechanisms involving tyrosine phosphorylation/dephosphorylation events are involved in controlling L. donovani promastigote differentiation into amastigote forms.</description><creator>Abourjeily, Nay.</creator><contributor>Matlashewski, Greg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Leishmania -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Protein-tyrosine kinase.</subject><subject>Protein-tyrosine phosphatase.</subject><subject>Phosphorylation.</subject><subject>Leishmaniasis -- Molecular aspects.</subject><title>Involvement of tyrosine phosphorylation during Leishmania donovani differentiation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r497x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172006b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c007b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies have attempted to associate aspects of course and outcome with the schizophrenia genotype. Reliance on a dichotomous familial loading variable as the single indicator of genetic loading has yielded inconsistent results. The goal of the present study was to create a continuous loading variable based on multiple indicators of the schizophrenia genotype (family history of schizophrenia and attention and verbal memory in the 1st degree relatives of the patient) and to determine its association with premorbid adjustment, age at onset, symptoms, and chronicity. Our results suggest that a continuous family history variable predicted problems in premorbid adjustment and an earlier age at onset. Hierarchical regression analysis revealed that verbal memory in the siblings of the patient increased the amount of variance accounted for in premorbid attention problems, over and above that predicted by family history. A "genetic loading" variable based on the incorporation of neuropsychologically impaired siblings into the calculations of family history was significantly correlated with premorbid attention problems.</description><creator>Champagne, Frances Anne.</creator><contributor>King, Suzanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Genetic loading and Schizophrenia : relation to course and outcome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx306.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c007b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc96h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les tentatives d'enrayer l'avance de la suite des                changements climatiques sont maintenant de nature mondiale. Centrale à la réalisation                de ces objectifs est la nécessité de mettre à profit le marché ainsi que de permettre                à des gouvernements de la portée et le pouvoir de faire de réels changements                réglementaires. La création de régimes d'échange de droits d'émission au titre de la                CCNUCC et du Protocole de Kyoto est un instrument du marché qui peut, s'ils sont                utilisés correctement, contribuent de manière significative aux efforts de la                communauté internationale. L'industrie aérienne est soumise à de fortes pressions                pour faire ses propres réductions d'effectifs, pour toutes sortes de gaz à effet de                serre. À ce jour, l'assujettissement de l'industrie de l'aviation à cette                réglementation a été laissée dans le contrôle de International Civil Aviation                Organisation. Le Progrès réalisé par cet organisme n'est pas considérable. En                conséquence, certains États ont considéré qu'il est nécessaire de faire le premier                pas en soumettant l'industrie de l'aviation à de systèmes d'échange d'émissions. Le                premier de ces efforts a été fait par l'Union européenne avec leur intention d'y                inclure des vols déjà établis dans le cadre de leur système d'échange d'émissions.                Comme un élément central de ce régime, l'UE a l'intention que tous les vols soient                soumis à ce régime, indépendamment de la nationalité des compagnies aériennes et de                son point de départ ou d'arrivée. Essentiellement, le régime cherche à réglementer                les vols internationaux de compagnies aériennes non membres de l'UE. Il est l'objet                de cette thèse d'étudier l</description><description>Attempts to stem the continued advance of climate change are now global                in nature. Central to achieving these aims is the need to harness the market as well                as permitting governments the scope and power to make real regulatory changes. The                creation of emissions trading schemes under the UNFCCC and its Kyoto Protocol is just                such an market instrument which can, if used correctly, contribute significantly to                the international communities efforts. The airline industry is under significant                pressure to make its own reductions, for all manner of greenhouse gases. To date, the                subjection of the aviation industry to such regulation has been left in the control                of the International Civil Aviation Organisation. Progress by this body has not been                substantial. As a result, some States have seen it necessary to make the first move                in subjecting the aviation industry to emissions trading schemes. Foremost in these                efforts has been the European Union's intention to bring flights within its already                established emissions trading scheme. As a central tenet of this scheme, the EU                intend subject all flights to the scheme, irrespective of the airlines nationality                and its point of departure or arrival. Essentially, the scheme will seek to regulate                international flights of non-EU airlines. It is the purpose of this thesis to                consider the appropriateness of these steps by the EU. Does this project extend the                regulation of airline emissions extraterritorially? Should the answer to this                question be yes, does this prevent the EU from actually taking these steps? These and                other questions are considered in the thesis. Ultimately, the paper seeks to address                the proposed inclusion of aviation withi</description><creator>Price, Gareth</creator><contributor>Richard Janda (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The EU ETS and unilateralism within international air transport</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967544k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc96h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc97s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The improvements in mechanical properties of microalloyed steels result                mainly from the refinement of ferrite grain size together with a controlled amount of                precipitation strengthening. Applying small amounts of deformation, at very low hot                working temperatures (e.g. coiling temperature), in the ferrite region (i.e. cool                deformation) is found to improve strength and toughness by controlling the final                microstructure of the steel. The main reason is thought to be the much finer and more                uniformly dispersed precipitates in the steel matrix. In the present study, the                effects of Nb and Cu on mechanical properties and corresponding microstructures in                steels with different levels of cool deformation are investigated. The mechanical                properties of the samples were determined with shear punch testing and the                microstructure was examined by scanning and transmission electron microscopy.                Thermodynamics simulations with FactSage were done to further analyze the possibility                of precipitation of different elements. It has been found that these alloying                elements respond very well to cool deformation, with the strength being highest in                steels containing both Nb and Cu. However, there was also a cool deformation effect                in the non Nb and Cu bearing steel. It was confirmed that precipitation plays a key                role in the effect of cool deformation, with much of the precipitation taking place                dynamically. However, static processes also seem to have a measurable effect on room                temperature properties. Even low amounts of copper (e.g. ~0.4 wt%) can contribute to                strengthening of the steel. The Cu addition is found to affect the mechanical                properties by affecting the precipitation and growth of Nb co</description><description>L'amélioration des propriétés mécaniques des aciers                faiblement alliés est la résultante d'un affinement de la taille des grains couplé à                une quantité controllée de précipités cohérents. Une faible déformation plastique de                la ferrite, Cool Deformation, à basse température, augmente la force et la résistance                de l'alliage, conditionnellement au contrôle de la taille des grains. L'explication                retenue face à ce phénomène est l'augmentation de l'homogénéisation des précipités,                mis de pair avec la diminution de leur taille. . Dans le présent travail, les effets                du niobium et du cuivre sur les propriétés mécaniques et microstructures d'acier                laminés à divers degrés ont été étudiées. Pour leur part, les microstructures                métallographiques ont été observées au microscope à balayage électronique et à                transmission. Pour compléter, des simulations thermodynamiques ont été testées avec                le logiciel FactSage afin d'analyser la possibilité de précipitation des différents                éléments. . Au cours de l'étude, il a été constaté que l'acier et ses éléments                d'alliages répondent bien au Cool Deformation, particulièrement dans la cas des                aciers contenant du cuivre et du niobium, lesquels ont obtenu un meilleur                renforcement des propriétés mécaniques. Toutefois, il a été observé qu'une                augmentation des propriétés mécaniques résultait également du laminage d'aciers                n'ayant pas de niobium ni de cuivre ajouté, selon le phénomène de durcissement par                écrouissage. Le rôle clé des précipités dans le durcissement par consolidation (ou                écrouissage) a été démontré, les précipités prenant place lors de la déformation                plastiqu</description><creator>Fatehi, Arya</creator><contributor>Stephen Yue (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Effect of cool deformation on mechanical properties and microstructure of Nb microalloyed steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns74k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc97s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x0872</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Infecting an estimated 350 to 500 million people and associated with more than 1 million deaths yearly, malaria remains one of the most devastating infectious diseases. Among the different drug targets, figures the malaria pigment. Its production is non-mutagenic and essential to the parasite survival. Its pro-inflammatory properties also place it as a potential agent in the elaboration of  a malaria vaccine. These black prismatic microcrystals, also named hemozoin, result  from hemoglobin catabolism by the parasites as they invade the red blood cells. As the natural compound is difficult to harvest, two synthetic routes were investigated.  The acid-catalyzed method utilises accessible material and common laboratory procedures. It has been optimized to produce hematin anhydride microcrystals of about 1 μm long in a reproducible manner. Another method, the anhydrous base-annealing procedure, was also studied with the goal to produce crystals of a size which would enable single crystal XRD as well as biomimetics crystals. All of the reactive components have been varied: the source of the initial material, the solvents used, and the incubating temperature. The crystallization pathway appeared to be an equilibrium process where smaller crystals were obtained at room temperature, from methanol rich solvent systems and high concentration of hemin. Conditions were optimized to obtain single domain parallelepipeds of 1.4 μm, close to hemozoin size. Suggestions are given from these results for new starting point to make larger crystals enabling single crystal XRD. Unit cell orientation within the crystalline lattice has been ascertained theoretically by previous autho</description><description>Infectant entre 350 et 500 millions d'humains et associé avec plus d'un million de décès par année, le paludisme se trouve parmi les maladies infectieuses, les plus dévastatrices. Parmi les différents vecteurs de médication, se trouve le pigment malarique présentant une biochimie unique et essentielle au parasite ainsi qu'une production non-mutagène. Ses propriétés pro-inflammatoires en font également un agent potentiel dans l'élaboration d'un éventuel vaccin. Ces petits cristaux, également appelés hémozoïne résultent du catabolisme de l'hémoglobine par le parasite infectant les globules rouges. Due aux difficultés rencontrées dans l'isolation du matériel naturel, deux méthodes de synthèse on été étudiées. La précipitation de l'hémine catalysée par un acide organique représente une méthode de synthèse accessible utilisant des produits communs ainsi qu'une procédure adaptée à des conditions usuelles de laboratoire. Elle a été optimisée produisant à son tour de petits cristaux d'anhydride d'hématine d'environ 1 μm de long de façon reproductible. Une méthode plus élaborée, la déhydrohalogénation de l'hémine en présence d'une base anhydre, a également fait partie de l'étude dans le but de synthétiser des cristaux permettant la diffraction à rayons X de monocristaux ainsi que des biomimétiques. Les différents composés entrant dans le procédé ont tous été étudiés à partir des matériaux de départ, des solvants utilisés et la température d'incubation. La cristallisation du matériau semble sous l'influence d'un équilibre et de petits cristaux ont été observés à température ambiante avec une c</description><creator>Bellemare, Marie-Josée</creator><contributor>David Bohle (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Chemistry - Inorganic</subject><title>The malaria pigment hematin anhydride: surface chemistry and photoluminescence phenomenon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z958z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x0872</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx31g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les d\'eveloppeurs de logiciels investissent une grande                partie de leur temps \`a explorer le code source pour trouver des \'el\'ements du                code reli\'es \`a leurs t\^aches, et aussi pour mieux comprendre le contexte de leur                t\^ache. Le contexte de leur t\^ache n'est g\'en\'eralement pas enregistr\'ee \`a la                fin de leur s\'eance d'exploration de code et est oubli\'e au fil du temps. De                m\^eme, il n'est pas possible de partager le contexte de leur t\^ache avec d'autres                d\'eveloppeurs travaillant sur des t\^aches reli\'ees. Les solutions propos\'ees pour                enregistrer automatiquement le r\'esum\'e de leur exploration du code souffrent de                limitations m\'ethodologiques li\'ees aux techniques et aux sources de donn\'ees                utilis\'ees pour g\'en\'erer le r\'esum\'e, ainsi qu'\`a la granularit\'e \`a                laquelle il est g\'en\'er\'e. Pour surmonter ces limitations, nous \'etudions                l'emploi de techniques d'apprentissage machine, en particulier l'arbre de d\'ecision                d'apprentissage, pour pr\'evoir automatiquement le contexte de la t\^ache \`a partir                des transcriptes de navigation d'une session d'exploration de code du d\'eveloppeur.                Nous avons effectu\'e une \'etude de cas afin de recueillir des transcriptions de                navigation g\'en\'er\'es par des d\'eveloppeurs lors de l'exploration du code source.                Nous avons utilis\'e les donn\'ees de cette \'etude pour tester les classifications                de l'arbre de d\'ecision. Nous avons compar\'e l'algorithme \`a arbre \`a d\'ecision                avec deux approches existantes, et avons d\'emontr\'e que cette nouvelle approche se                compare favorablement dans la plupart des cas. Additionnellement, nous avons                d\'evelopp\'e un plug-in Eclipse qui g\'en\`ere automatiquement un</description><description>Developers invest a large portion of their development time exploring                program source code to find task-related code elements and to understand the context                of their task. The task context is usually not recorded at the end of the task and is                forgotten over time. Similarly, it is not possible to share the task context with                other developers working on related tasks. Proposed solutions to automatically record                the summary of the code investigation suffer from methodological limitations related                to the techniques and the data sources used to generate the summary as well as the                granularity at which it is generated. To overcome these limitations, we investigate                the use of machine learning techniques, in particular decision tree learning, to                predict automatically the task context from session navigation transcripts obtained                from developers performing tasks on the source code. We conducted a user study to                collect navigation transcripts from developers engaged in source code exploration                tasks. We used the data from the user study to train and test decision tree                classifiers. We compared the decision tree algorithm with two existing approaches,                and found that it compares positively in most cases. Additionally, we developed an                Eclipse plug-in that generates automatically a developer session summary using the                decision tree classifier learned from the data collected during the user study. We                provide qualitative analysis of the effectiveness of this plug-in.</description><creator>Agrawal, Punit</creator><contributor>Doina Precup (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Martin Robillard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Program navigation analysis using machine learning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw96b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx31g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870x706</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is common practice to add reactive metal particles to high-explosive                formulations in order to increase the total energy output. The present study is an                effort to increase the understanding of metal particle combustion in detonation                products. Aluminum and magnesium particles ranging from 2 to 100 μm are subjected to                the flow of detonation products of a stoichiometric mixture of hydrogen and oxygen.                Luminosity emitted from the reacting particles is used to determine the reaction                delay and duration. It is found that the reaction duration increases as d^n with n ≈                0.5, more consistent with kinetically controlled reaction rather than the classical                diffusion controlled regime. Emission spectroscopy is used to estimate the combustion                temperature, which is found to be well below the flow temperature. This fact also                suggests combustion in the kinetic regime. Finally, the flow field is modelled with a                CFD code and the results are used to model analytically the behaviour of the aluminum                particles. Furthermore, a simple analytical model is developed to predict ignition of                magnesium particles in nitromethane detonation products. The flow field is simplified                by considering the detonation products as a perfect gas expanding in a vacuum in a                planar geometry. This simplification allows the flow field tobe solved analytically.                A single particle is then introduced in this flow field. Its trajectory and heating                history are computed. It is found that most of the particle heating occurs in the                Taylor wave and in the quiescent flow region behind it, shortly after which the                particle cools. By considering only these regions, thereby considerably simplifying                the problem, the flow field ca</description><description>Il est maintenant courant d'ajouter des particules de                métaux réactifs aux formulations d'explosifs pour augmenter l'énergie libérée. Cette                étude vise une meilleure compréhension de la combustion de métaux dans les produits                de détonation. Des particules d'aluminium et de magnésium de 2 à 100 μm sont exposées                à l'écoulement des produits de la détonation d'un mélange d'hydrogène et d'oxygène.                La lumière émise par les particules est utilisée pour déterminer le délai et la durée                de la réaction. La durée de la réaction augmente selon d^n avec n ≈ 0.5. Ces                résultats suggèrent un régime de combustion cinétique plutôt que le régime diffusif                classique. La température de combustion est mesurée à l'aide de spectroscopie                d'émission. La température mesurée est plus basse que celle de l'écoulement, ce qui                est également cohérent avec un régime de combustion cinétique. Finalement,                l'écoulement est modélisé avec un code Euler, dont les résultats sont utilisés pour                modéliser analytiquement le comportement des particules. Dans un deuxième temps, un                modèle analytique simple est développé pour prédire l'ignition de particules de                magnésium dans les produits de détonation de nitrométhane. L'écoulement est simplifié                en traitant les produits comme gaz parfaits, qui prennent de l'expansion dans le vide                dans une géométrie planaire. Ces simplifications permettent de résoudre l'écoulement                analytiquement. Ensuite, la trajectoire et la température d'une seule particule                introduite dans l'écoulement sont calculées. La particule est chauffée principalement                dans le "Taylor wave" et dans la région quiescente derrière celle-ci. En ne</description><creator>Tanguay, Vincent</creator><contributor>Andrew J Higgins (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Combustion of reactive metal particles in high-speed flow of detonation products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q45b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x706</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537288b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pseudo-dynamic combinatorial chemistry (pDCC) combines the synthesis,                screening and destruction of combinatorial libraries to kinetically resolve                inhibitors based on their affinity for a target. In our proof-of-principle studies, a                library of dipeptides was formed in the presence of a target, carbonic anhydrase                (CA), and a destruction mechanism, a protease. Since the target and the protease were                separated by a dialysis membrane, only the proportion of dipeptides that was not                bound to the target was available for destruction and therefore, the rate of                hydrolysis of the pseudo-dynamic combinatorial library (pDCL) could be correlated to                the librarie's relative affinity for the target. The first set of proof-of-principle                pDCC experiments were found to be flawed. Rather than reflecting the binding affinity                of the library for the target, the final product distribution reflected the                protease's substrate specificity. The main problems with these pDCLs were                insufficient and imbalanced rate of destruction of the peptides in the absence of the                target, pH drift, and insufficient permeability across 1000 MWCO cellulose ester                membranes. A dipeptide amide based pDCL that was efficiently cleaved by thermolysin                was designed. The new pDCL could be used in pH 7.5 75 mM HEPES, 16.6 mM CaCl2 buffer,                provided that the chambers were limited by 3500 MWCO membranes. A 4th generation pDCC                experiment that evolved reflecting the library's affinity for the target was                performed. In order to study pDCC behavior a simplified pDCC mimic (pDCCm) was                designed. In pDCCm, synthesis was replaced by a static library of compounds and                destruction by dilution. The design of a pDCCm based kinetic model led to a</description><description>La chimie combinatoire pseudo dynamique (pDCC) combine la                synthèse, le criblage et la destruction de libraires combinatoires afin de                sélectionner cinétiquement des inhibiteurs sur la base de leur affinité pour une                cible. Nos études préliminaires ont été basées sur une librairie de dipeptides formés                en présence de l'anhydrase carbonique (CA) comme cible et détruits grâce à une                protéase. Étant donné que la cible et la protéase étaient séparées par une membrane                de dialyse, seuls les dipeptides non complexés avec la cible étaient susceptibles                d'être détruits. Ainsi, la vitesse d'hydrolyse des membres de la librairie                combinatoire pseudo-dynamique (pDCL) peut correspondre aux affinités relatives des                molécules pour la cible. Les premières expériences prototypes de pDCC étaient                défectueuses. Plutôt que de refléter l'affinité des membres de la librairie pour la                cible, la distribution finale des produits reflétait la préférence de la protéase                pour les substrats. Les principaux problèmes de ces pDCL étaient: une vitesse de                destruction des peptides insuffisante et inégale en l'absence de la cible, une                déviation progressive du pH et une perméabilité insuffisance au travers les membranes                d'ester de cellulose 1000 MWCO. Une pDCL basée sur des amides dipeptidiques, aptes à                être efficacement clivés par thermolysine a été élaborée, et utilisée avec succès.                Afin d'étudier les pDCC, une expérience modèle simplifiée (pDCCm) a été créée. Dans                ce modèle, la synthèse a été remplacée par une librairie statique de molécules et la                destruction par une dilution. Le design d'un modèle cinétique basé sur la pDCCm a                mené à la cr</description><creator>Soriano Del Amo, David</creator><contributor>James L Gleason (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Pseudo-dynamic combinatorial chemistry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k4472.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537288b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mr664</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High rates of malnutrition among Ghanaian children indicate the need to                examine determinants of diet and nutritional status in this population. This study                examined differences in the diets of children 2-5 y of age associated with: 1) pre-                to post-harvest season changes in rural northern Ghana (n=190) and 2) attendance at                daycare centres (DCC) with informal school feeding programs in rural mid-country                Ghana (n=193). Interviewer-administered questionnaires were used to collect dietary                (24-hour recall), morbidity and demographic information. Although diets improved with                the post-harvest season, illness increased and acute nutritional status deteriorated                which were likely due to unexpected severe flooding prior to post-harvest data                collection. Children who attended DCC had higher daily intakes of energy, protein,                calcium, iron and zinc than their non-DCC counterparts. These findings provide                important insights into determinants of diet and nutritional status among Ghanaian                children as well as a potential mechanism for improving diets in this population.</description><description>Des taux élevés de malnutrition parmi enfants ghanéens                indiquent le besoin d'examiner les déterminants d'alimentation et de nutrition dans                cette population. Cette étude a examiné les différences d'alimentation des enfants                âgés 2 à 5 ans associées avec : 1) les changements avant et âpres-saison moisson dans                le canton nord du Ghana (n=190) et 2) la présence aux garderies (DCC) qui se                comprennent des programs non-officiels d'alimentation au milieu du pays (n=193). Des                questionnaires administrés par des interviewers étaient utilisés pour collecter                information diététique (rappel 24-heur), de morbidité et démographique. Bien que                l'alimentation s'est améliorée lors de l'âpres-saison moisson, les maladies se sont                augmentées et le statu aigu nutritionnel s'est détérioré, lesquels il est probable                étaient en raison des inondations sévères inattendues avant que l'information                d'âpres-moisson aie été collecté. La consommation d'énergie, protéine, calcium, fer                et zinc parmi les enfants qui se présentaient aux garderies était plus élevée que                celle des ses homologues. Ces découvertes apportent des aperçus importants à propos                des déterminants du statu nutritionnel et d'alimentation des enfants ghanéens, et                aussi des mécanismes potentiels pour améliorer l'alimentation de cette population. </description><creator>Harding, Kimberly</creator><contributor>Grace Marquis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Dietary intakes and nutritional status of rural Ghanaian children: are season and attending daycare important determinants?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz52j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr664</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k06989337</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The transient interaction of the Fyn SH3 domain with a proline-rich                peptide was studied using Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) and isothermal titration                calorimetry (ITC). Our results are consistent with an effectively two-state binding                reaction mechanism. The association rate constants calculated using NMR and ITC data                exhibit the magnitude and temperature dependence consistent with a diffusion-limited                process. An Eyring plot of koff exhibits a slight curvature, suggesting that                non-polar residues of the hydrophobic interface are solvated in the transition state                for dissociation. The temperature dependence of NMR-derived dissociation rates                closely matches the heat capacity and enthalpy changes determined by ITC. The                combination of NMR and ITC data sheds light on how the Fyn tyrosine kinase is                activated by binding to proline-rich targets, and represents a powerful approach for                characterizing transient protein-protein interactions.</description><description>L'interaction rapide entre le domaine SH3 de la protéine                Fyn et un peptide riche en proline a été étudiée par résonance magnétique nucléaire                (RMN) et titration calorimétrique isotherme (TCI). Nos résultats concordent avec un                mécanisme de réaction à deux états. Les vitesses d'association, calculées par RMN et                TCI, indiquent une réaction limitée par la diffusion. Dans un graphique d'Eyring, les                vitesses de dissociation exhibent une légère courbure, suggérant que l'interface                hydrophobique entre les deux composés est solvatés dans l'état de transition; cette                courbure est apparentée à la différence de capacité thermique ayant été déterminée                par TCI. L'utilisation combinée de RMN et TCI nous a permis de mieux comprendre                comment la tyrosine kinase Fyn est activée par son association avec des peptides.                Ainsi, nous avons développé une approche robuste pour caractériser les interactions                rapides entre protéines.</description><creator>Demers, Jean-Philippe</creator><contributor>Anthony Mittermaier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biophysics - General</subject><title>Understanding the binding mechanism of an SH3 domain using NMR and ITC</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q725.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06989337</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp12n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude contribue à remettre en question la célèbre                dichotomie entre l'art et l'artisanat en se penchant sur les représentations de                l'artisanat dans la littérature. Plus spécifiquement, cette étude vise à explorer les                représentations de l'artisanat textile et de la figure de l'artisan dans le roman                canadien au tournant du vingt-et-unième siècle, à travers trois romans publiés après                1990 : Alias Grace (1996) de Margaret Atwood, The Polished Hoe (2002) d'Austin Clarke                et A Fine Balance (1995) de Rohinton Mistry. Une analyse de ces trois                romans-patchwork et du rapiéçage qui en informe leur structure et leur contenu nous                révèle une nouvelle façon de conceptualiser l'artisanat tout en remettant en contexte                des formes traditionnelles du passé (tels que tissage, tressage, couture) dans la                littérature canadienne contemporaine. Le premier chapitre, explorant les théories                transdisciplinaires autour de l'artisanat apparues vers 1970 et atteignant leur                apogée dans les années 1990, propose trois paradigmes structurant mon analyse dans                chacun des chapitres, à savoir, les relations entre l'artisanat textile et (a) le                récit, (b) la ruse, et (c) la transformation et la pluralité. Chacun des chapitres                suivants explore les récits rapiécés et les variations autour de la figure mythique                du (de la) fileur(euse) rusé(e) (la figure du « trickster » dans le mythe                nord-américain) qui constituent un ensemble caractéristique du roman patchwork. Le                deuxième chapitre propose le patchwork présent dans Alias Grace comme un modèle de                processus de récupération et de fragmentation propre au roman historique (ou ce que                Linda Hutcheon nomme « historiographic m</description><description>The very impetus of this study — to examine the representations of craft                in literature — defies the functional binaries so long attributed to art and craft.                This study examines the literary formulations of textile crafts and their makers in                Canadian works of fiction at the turn of the twenty-first century. Included are three                Canadian novels published after 1990: Margaret Atwood's Alias Grace (1996), Austin                Clarke's The Polished Hoe (2002) and Rohinton Mistry's A Fine Balance (1995). Through                close analysis of these patchwork novels, I suggest ways of reading quilts and other                textile crafts as a recontextualization of the forms of the past (through the                workings of displacement and parody) in Canadian literature. Chapter One proposes                theoretical reconceptualizations of crafts culminating in the 1990s and establishes                three paradigms that structure my analysis in each of the chapters: the relations of                textile crafts with (a) narrative, (b) trickery, and (c) a dehierarchical and plural                aesthetic. In the subsequent chapters, each one dealing with a single novel, I                explore the reassembled quality of the narratives and variations of the spider-weaver                archetypes they represent, both of which I consider fundamental to the patchwork                novel. In Chapter Two, I posit the patchwork quilt in Atwood's Alias Grace as a model                for the processes of recollection and fragmentation involved in historiographic                metafiction. Chapter Three establishes the crafted object in Clarke's The Polished                Hoe as a site of struggle and an embodiment of the collective and composite nature of                heritage in the neoslave narrative. Chapter Four focuses on the way the "sordid                quiltings" (379) of Mistry's A Fine B</description><creator>Morel, Pauline</creator><contributor>Nathalie M Cooke (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Literature - Canadian (English)</subject><title>Rag bags: Textile crafts in Canadian fiction since 1980</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q00h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp12n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z9597</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La disponibilité et la qualité des ressources diffèrent à                travers le gradient spatial vertical d'une forêt. On prédit que les communautés                d'arthropodes se distribuent suivant ces ressources tout en évitant les prédateurs.                J'ai investigué la distribution verticale à petite échelle des araignées et des                coléoptères dans la canopée d'une érablière à sucre (Acer saccharum Marsh.). En                comparant quatre strate d'élévation (de la strate arbustive à la haute canopée), j'ai                documenté les gradients de densité et de diversité ainsi que la composition en                espèce, incluant une plus forte réponse au gradient vertical de la part des                assemblages d'araignées. J'ai employé le concept de refuge des ennemis naturels pour                explorer comment les impacts des prédateurs varient dans l'espace verticale. Des                expériences avec des exclos aviaires ont démontré que les pressions de prédation                aviaire augmentent en s'éloignant du sol, alors que celles utilisant des appâts                indiquent une forte pression des prédateurs invertébrés dans la basse canopée. Mis                ensemble, ces résultats indiquent que l'hétérogénéité spatiale verticale peut                produire des différences dans les communautés d'arthropodes à de petites échelles                spatiales.</description><description>Resource quality/availability differ throughout vertical space in the                forest. It is expected that arthropod communities distribute themselves in relation                to these different resources while also avoiding predators. I investigated                small-scale heterogeneity in the vertical distribution of spider and beetle                communities in a sugar maple (Acer saccharum Marsh.) canopy. Comparing across four                strata (understory through upper canopy crown), I documented gradients in density,                diversity and species composition, with a stronger response to vertical gradation                exhibited by spider assemblages compared to beetle assemblages. I used the concept of                refuge from natural enemies to explore how impacts of predators vary in vertical                space. Bird exclosure experiments demonstrated an impact of avian foraging that                increased with distance from the forest floor, while bait trial experiments indicated                strong predation pressure from invertebrate predators in the lower canopy. Taken                together, these results indicate that heterogeneity in vertical space is able to                produce differences in arthropod communities over small spatial scales</description><creator>Aikens, Kathleen</creator><contributor>Christopher Buddle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Entomology</subject><title>Heterogeneity in a temperate forest canopy: describing patterns of distribution and depredation of arthropod assemblages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q336q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z9597</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s30b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les études portant sur le nationalisme ont                traditionnellement ignoré la question des genres, du moins dans une large mesure. Or,                une mouvance intellectuelle et féministe récente affirme de plus en plus que tous les                nationalismes impliquent clairement cette distinction entre les genres, et explore                l'impact de ce phénomène auprès des femmes. Dans la présente thèse, j'analyserai                comment l'emphase placée sur les mères dévouées en tant que symboles de la nation                dans le cadre d'idéologies nationalistes peut, lorsque codifiée en droit, engendrer                des effets néfastes pour ce qui concerne l'autonomie reproductive des femmes. À cet                égard, les cas de la République d'Irlande et de la République islamique d'Iran                suscitent de surprenants parallèles. En comparant ces deux États, l'un catholique et                l'autre musulman, j'espère souligner les façons dont les nationalismes variés                emploient la religion afin de justifier des mesures politiques visant à contrôler et                à subjuguer les femmes.</description><description>Traditionally, studies of nationalism have largely ignored the issue of                gender but, more recently, there is a growing body of feminist scholarship asserting                that all nationalisms are gendered and exploring the effects of this gendering on                women. In this thesis, I will examine how the focus on devout mothers as symbols of                the nation in nationalist ideology can, when codified into law, engender negative                effects on women's reproductive autonomy. Two countries that show surprising                parallels in this regard are the Republic of Ireland and the Islamic Republic of                Iran. Through comparing these two countries, one Catholic and one Muslim, I hope to                highlight the ways in which diverse nationalisms use religion to justify what are                politically motivated actions taken to control and subjugate women.</description><creator>O'Mahoney, Sarah</creator><contributor>Colleen Sheppard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Mothers of the nation: the effect of nationalist ideology on women's reproductive rights in Ireland and Iran</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk38f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s30b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j294f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les mosaïques visuelles peuvent être utiles pour la                cartographie, la localisation, et les esthétiques. Cette thèse démontre une méthode                entièrement automatisée pour prendre les séquences visuelles d'une scène de multiples                points de référence disparates et de combiner ces vidéos ensemble en mosaïque. La                dissertation commence par une nouvelle approche à créer des mosaïques avec des photos                de plateaux contenant des objets dynamiques. Ensuite, avec la vidéo, la segmentation                du premier plan est réalisée utilisant un modèle multigaussien mélangé. Ceci est                applique a créer un fond d'image sans bruit. Les fonds d'images se sont âpres alignés                dans l'espace en utilisant des dispositifs d'images. Les vidéos sont alignées                temporellement utilisant une technique originale basée sur des propriétés d'éclat.                Les nouvelles techniques de créer les mosaïques en utilisant l'optimisation de                couture sont utilisées pour souplement combiner les vidéos ensemble. Le procédé est                validé utilisant des données synthétiques et une séquence sous-marine.</description><description>Video mosaics are useful for mapping, localization, and asthetics. This                thesis demonstrates a fully automated method to take video sequences of a scene from                multiple disparate reference points and mosaic them together. The dissertation begins                with a new approach to mosiacing still images with dynamic objects. Extending to                video, foreground segmentation is achieved using a multi-Gaussian mixture model. This                is applied to creating a noise free background image. Backgrounds are then aligned                spatially using image features. Videos are aligned temporally using a novel technique                based on brightness properties. Finally, new techniques to smoothly mosaic videos                together using seam optimization creates the final result. The procedure is validated                using synthetic data and an underwater sequence.</description><creator>Mills, Alec</creator><contributor>Gregory L Dudek (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>A stitch in time. A dissertation on video mosaicking</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd614.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j294f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j64b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explains the increasingly homogenous institutional and                policy framework of Official Development Assistance. Whereas multilateral actors like                the World Bank or the issue of civil society involvement in development have been                substantially researched and discussed, less attention has been paid to the                institutions of bilateral donor agencies and the processes by which they arrive at                common policy positions. It is of great importance to better understand how donors                arrive at these consensus policy positions, essentially limiting development                possibilities worldwide. Engaged with the literatures on world polity theory,                development assistance, and social movements, this dissertation examines the social                processes which explain this growing uniformity among major bilateral development                assistance donor agencies. This research adopts a mixed-methods approach of both                quantitative and qualitative methods to illustrate the working of world polity                influences on nation-state donor agencies. Event history analysis techniques at the                macro level are used to show the influence of world society on donor states, then the                relationships identified in this quantitative analysis are used to frame two in-depth                qualitative case studies on gender and security policy among three countries, Canada,                Sweden, and the United States. My results show that despite different national                contexts, there are common social processes and mechanisms of globalisation that                promote conformity and isomorphism among donor countries. Five primary social                processes are identified: (1) internalisation and certification; (2) donor agency                embeddedness with civil society; (3) bureaucratic activism; (4) catalyt</description><description>L'objet de cette thèse est d'expliquer les raisons pour                lesquelles le cadre politique et institutionnel de l'aide publique au développement                devient de plus en plus homogène. Si les organismes multilatéraux (comme la Banque                mondiale) et la participation de la société civile dans le développement ont fait                l'objet de nombreux débats et d'études approfondies, il en est tout autrement pour                les institutions des organismes donateurs bilatéraux et les processus via lesquels                ils aboutissent à une position politique commune. Il est donc primordial de mieux                comprendre comment les donateurs parviennent à ces consensus politiques qui limitent                avant tout les possibilités de développement dans le monde. À travers l'étude de la                littérature portant sur la théorie de la politie planétaire, sur l'aide au                développement et sur les mouvements sociaux, cette thèse examine les processus                sociaux qui expliquent l'uniformité croissante parmi les principaux organismes                donateurs d'aide bilatérale au développement. Cette recherche se fonde sur une                approche méthodologique mixte, à la fois quantitative et qualitative, pour démontrer                comment la politie planétaire influence les organismes donateurs des États-nations.                Des techniques de macro-analyse des transitions sont employées pour montrer                l'influence de la société mondiale sur les États donateurs. Les relations identifiées                dans cette analyse quantitative sont ensuite utilisées pour formuler deux études de                cas détaillées, l'une sur les politiques en matière d'égalité entre les sexes et                l'autre sur les politiques de sécurité, dans trois pays : le Canada, la Suède et les                États-Unis d'Amérique. Mes résultat</description><creator>Swiss, Liam</creator><contributor>Kathleen Fallon (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Sociology - Social Structure and Development</subject><title>Developing consensus: the globalisation of development assistance policies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs53j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j64b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cm760</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La protéine 53BP1 (p53 binding protein 1) (53BP1) est une                protéine impliquée dans la surveillance du cycle cellulaire (checkpoint) activé par                les brisures d'ADN double-brin (double-strand break ou DSB). L'absence ou la                réduction d'expression de 53BP1 est une caractéristique retrouvée dans la majorité de                carcinomes. 53BP1 est recrutée rapidement aux sites de DSB par ses domaines Tudor                tandem qui reconnaissent les résidus de lysines dimethylées des histones. Les                domaines 53BP1 Tudor tandem (53BP1TT) est comprennent deux domaines Tudor suivi par                une hélice alpha au C-terminal et ces domaines ont une affinité spécifique pour les                lysines methylées H4K20 et H3K79 des histones. Étant donné que les domaines Tudor                tandem sont généralement caractérisés par leur interaction avec le des résidus                methylés, j'ai émis l'hypothèse que les 53BP1TT pourraient d'interagir avec des                protéines autres que les histones contenant des résidus methylés, ce qui révèlerait                un rôle important dans le maintien de la stabilité génomique. Donc, le principal                objectif du travail présenté dans cette thèse est l'identification de protéines                interagissant avec 53BP1TT. Pour ce faire, j'ai employé la réaction couplée de                transcription et traduction in vitro sur une banque d'ADNc. Ceci m'a permis                d'identifier deux cibles putatives de 53BP1TT, soit CHK1 (checkpoint kinase 1) et                BRG1 (brahma-related gene 1). Chk1 est connu de jouer un rôle clé dans la cascade de                signalisation des brisures d'ADN double-brin et pour son interaction avec les                homologues de levure de 53BP1, tandis que BRG1 est la sous-unité ATPase des complexes                SWI/SNF impliques dans le remodelage de la chroma</description><description>Tumor protein p53 binding protein 1 (53BP1) is a cell cycle checkpoint                protein that is important in the early DNA double strand break (DSB) response signal                pathway. Aberrant reduction or lack of 53BP1 is found in significant proportions of                carcinomas. 53BP1 is recruited to DSB sites and forms foci through its tandem Tudor                domain by recognizing dimethylated lysines in histones. The 53BP1 tandem Tudor                (53BP1TT) domain consists of two tightly packed Tudor domains follow by a C-terminal                alpha helix, and actively binds to methylated histone lysines H4K20 and H3K79. I                hypothesized that 53BP1TT domain can potentially interact with non-histone targets,                which contain methylated residues, and may be involved in the maintenance of genomic                stability. The primary goal of the work presented in this thesis is to identify the                proteins that interact with the 53BP1TT domain. I performed a proteomic screen by                employing in vitro transcription/translation coupled reactions on pools of cDNA                plasmids and identified two putative 53BP1TT targets, brahma-related gene 1 (BRG1),                which is a chromatin remodeling catalytic subunit that has helicase and ATPase                activities, and is thought to regulate transcription by altering the chromatin                structure, and checkpoint kinase 1 (CHK1), which mediates DNA damage signal to                downstream damage responsive proteins and initiates cell cycle checkpoint arrest. I                demonstrated that both endogenous BRG1 and CHK1 interacted with the 53BP1TT domain in                glutathione-S-transferase pulldown assays. Co-immunoprecipitation between ectopically                expressed BRG1 and 53BP1 was observed. Interestingly, the interaction between                endogenous BRG1 and 53BP1 was observed only after DNA dama</description><creator>Chang, Kai-wei</creator><contributor>Stephane Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>The identification of proteins interacting with the 53BP1 tandem Tudor domains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn339.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm760</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40125</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>