<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:09Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bq672" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bq672</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:00:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biomass heating is used more and more by the greenhouse industry to reduce costs and the environmental footprint of production. The objective of this research project was to investigate the possibility of using the carbon dioxide (CO2) from the exhaust gas of a biomass heating system to enrich greenhouses with CO2 and improve crop yield. When compared to direct combustion, biomass gasification technology offers better control, which helps in reducing atmospheric emissions. Gasification is a thermo-chemical reaction, which converts solid biomass into a gaseous fuel, known as syngas. Experiments were performed at McGill University (Montreal, QC, Canada) using a downdraft gasifier to monitor its performance, with sawdust wood pellets as feedstock. Temperature and pressure monitoring provided valuable insights on optimal gasification temperatures, biomass fuel depletion in the reactor, ash grate shaking requirements, micro-explosions detection, char bed packing and pressure drop across the packed bed filter. The gasifier operated with an average equivalence ratio (the actual air to fuel ratio relative to the stoichiometric air to fuel requirement) of 0.17, below the optimal value of 0.25, and achieved a cold gas efficiency of 59%. Syngas combustion emissions produced an average of 8.8 ppm of carbon monoxide (CO), with 60% of the trials below the ASHRAE standards for indoor air quality and 90% below 20 ppm. The sulphur dioxide (SO2) emissions were below ppm levels, while ethylene (C2H4) emissions were below the critical concentration of 50 ppb for CO2 enrichment. The average nitrogen oxides (NOx) emissions were 23.6 ppm and would need to be reduced to allow commercial operations. From the empirical data, the gasifier operating with sawdust wood pellets, with a consumption of 7.7 kg/hr, could provide a maximum of 22.9 kW of thermal energy and could enrich a maximum of 1540 m2 of greenhouse surface area. Results indicated that biomass, following combustion or gasification, could provide more CO2 for greenhouse enrichment than propane or natural gas per unit of energy. Biomass gasification coupled with syngas combustion could be a promising renewable alternative to propane and natural gas for CO2 enrichment in greenhouses.</description><description>Le chauffage à la biomasse résiduelle est utilisé de plus en plus par l'industrie serricole afin de réduire les coûts d'opérations et les impacts environnementaux. L'objectif de cette recherche était d'examiner la possibilité d'utiliser le dioxyde de carbone (CO2) des gaz d'échappement d'un système de chauffage à la biomasse afin d'enrichir les serres en CO2 et favoriser le rendement des cultures. Par rapport à la combustion directe, la gazéification de la biomasse offrent un meilleur contrôle qui permet de réduire les émissions atmosphériques. La gazéification est une réaction thermochimique qui convertit la biomasse solide en un combustible gazeux, le syngas. Des expériences ont été réalisées à l'Université McGill (Montréal, QC, Canada) pour étudier les performances d'un gazogène à courant descendant, alimenté avec des granules de sciure de bois. Les données de température et de pression ont fourni des informations sur les températures de gazéification optimale, le niveau de combustible dans le réacteur, les besoins d'agitation de la grille de cendre, la détection de micro-explosions et les chutes de pression au travers du lit de charbon du réacteur et du filtre au charbon. Le gazogène a fonctionné avec un ratio d'équivalence (i.e. le ratio réel par rapport au ratio stoichiométrique d'air et de combustible) moyen de 0.17, inférieur à la valeur optimale de 0.25, et une efficacité de 59%. La combustion du syngas a produit une moyenne de 8.8 ppm de monoxyde de carbone (CO), où 60% des essais ont respecté les normes de qualité de l'air, et 90% ont été en dessous de 20 ppm. Le dioxyde de soufre (SO2) a été indétectable à une résolution en ppm, et les émissions d'éthylène (C2H4) ont été inférieures à la concentration critique de 50 ppb pour l'enrichissement au CO2. La moyenne d'oxydes d'azote (NOx) a été de 23.6 ppm et devrait être réduite pour des opérations commerciales. Le gazogène alimenté aux granules de bois, avec une consommation de 7.7 kg/hr, pourrait fournir 22.9 kW d'énergie thermique et enrichir une serre d'une surface de 1540 m2. Les résultats indiquent que la gazéification de biomasse, couplée à la combustion de syngas, est une alternative prometteuse au propane et au gaz naturel pour l'enrichissement des serres au CO2, puisque davantage de CO2 par unité d'énergie est fournie et ce, à partir d'un combustible renouvelable. </description><creator>Dion, Louis-Martin</creator><contributor>Mark Lefsrud (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Agricultural</subject><title>Biomass gasification for carbon dioxide enrichment in greenhouses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xn857.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bq672</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>