<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:04:14Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):28775" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707958915</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Deep interceptor drains are commonly used to control canal seepage in southern Alberta, Canada. Recently, shallow grid drainage was introduced. A study was initiated in 1987 to assess the effectiveness of grid drainage to intercept canal and natural groundwater seepage and reclaim the resulting saline affected land. Using a groundwater flow model, MODFLOW, it was found that a single deep interceptor drain would have failed to intercept all canal seepage and maintain the water table downslope of the canal below the 1.0 m design water table depth. Conversely, simulations indicated that with a grid drainage system, all canal and natural groundwater seepage would be intercepted and the water table would remain below the design water table depth, with or without irrigation recharge that would maintain a steady state salt balance. The benefits of fall irrigation were demonstrated using three test plots near the canal.</description><creator>Millette, Denis</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Irrigation canals and flumes -- Alberta.</subject><subject>Seepage.</subject><subject>Reclamation of land -- Alberta.</subject><subject>Hydraulic engineering -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Reclamation of canal seepage affected land</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg20n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707958915</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qn17k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To investigate the lineage relationships that are postulated to underlie the origins of phenotypically different neurons, Thy-1.1 $ leftrightarrow$ Thy-1.2 and hNF-L $ leftrightarrow$ +/+ mouse chimeras were examined for the distribution of the two neuron genotypes. Throughout the nervous system, a finely variegated pattern of mosaicism was always observed and, in each chimera, similar genotype proportions were found in all analysed neuronal populations of the peripheral and central nervous system. These findings require that the chimera neuroectoderm was a homogeneous mix of the two genotypes and that different neuronal phenotypes do not arise clonally from a small number of prespecified progenitors. Rather it would seem that all progenitors contribute daughter cells to all of the neuronal subpopulations at each level of the neuroaxis.</description><creator>Mayor, Olivier</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Developmental neurobiology.</subject><subject>Mosaicism.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><title>Lineage analysis of neurogenesis in mouse chimera</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk243.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn17k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q520x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Whether in common law jurisdictions or in German civil law, the issue of pre-incorporation transactions has always been the subject of considerable controversy. Concerned with the promoters, third parties, the company and its shareholders, the law has found it difficult to balance these frequently conflicting interests without neglecting the need for clear and simple rules. Common law courts, sometimes excessively committed to legal principles, have even come up with absurd results. This survey looks at the various attempts made in order to reconcile legal principles and business requirements--legislative in most common law jurisdictions, juridical in Germany. It will critically examine the approaches taken in Anglo-Saxon jurisdictions and compare their results and reasoning with the solution found in German law. It will be seen that even among closely related legal systems, results differ considerably. The survey will illustrate how established rules of law have turned out to be largely incapable of meeting the challenge of pre-incorporation transactions. From a comparative point of view, some suggestions will be made in order to achieve a solution that is more satisfactory in result and reasoning.</description><creator>Heinemann, Klaus</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Business Administration, General.</subject><title>Pre-incorporation transactions : a comparative analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k391.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q520x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806100n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ten year debate over the introduction of pay television in Canada is addressed using the concept of external signals to examine the interactions between the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission (CRTC) and the players in the regulatory environment. A critique of the notions of "public interest" and of regulatory "capture" precedes the analysis. An historical overview establishes the key issues shaping the nature of the CRTC as a signal-sending and signal-receiving institution. The evidence demonstrates that the CRTC was not a passive receptor of external signals, but actively shaped and directed or deflected incoming signals according to its own public priorities. The conclusion holds that the traditional capture model does adequately describe the CRTC's behaviour as it attempted to manage the complex political and technological forces surrounding the pay television issue.</description><creator>Henderson, Jane</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Subscription television -- Canada</subject><subject>Radio broadcasting -- Canada</subject><subject>Canadian Radio-Television Commission</subject><subject>Television broadcasting -- Canada</subject><title>Decade of denial : the CRTC, the public interest, and pay television, 1972-1982</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk321.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806100n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36tz78j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An X-band transmitter ($ lambda$ = 3,2 cm) should perform better than an S-band transmitter ($ lambda$ = 10,4 cm) in the remote measurement of snowfall by radar. Comparisons between groundtruth measurements and their radar measured counterparts are done for two similar snowstorms (November 20th and 21st 1986, January 30th and 31st 1987), scanned respectively with an S-band and an X-band transmitter, mounted on the 10 m wide antenna of the Weather Radar Observatory of McGill University; these observations confirmed the hypothesis. A mixed rain-snow precipitation event was also observed on February 21st 1989, using alternatively the X-band and the S-band transmitter on the same antenna during the course of the event; this allowed an almost simultaneous comparison of the transmitters. Modifications to the regular sequence of observation of the weather radar during winter are proposed to take advantage of the potential of the X-band transmitter in the measurement of snowfall.</description><creator>Giguère, André</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Comparaison de deux émetteurs radar dans la télémesure des chutes de neige</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x5151.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tz78j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kh58g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The current excitement surrounding string theory prompted us to tackle the problem of black hole radiation. Claims have been made concerning a possible 'stringy mechanism' that would avoid the singularity problem by giving a divergent energy-dissipation rate. As a check on such arguments, the Casimir energy of the string between two infinite parallel mirrors is computed using the closed, oriented bosonic string. Such a calculation is also a prerequisite to the understanding of the more interesting situation of string behaviour in the presence of accelerating boundaries. The formalism used here is the first-quantized Polyakov approach, which most simply translates to an orbifold problem.</description><creator>Hambli, Noureddine</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, General.</subject><title>Spacetime boundaries as orbifolds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zh90v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kh58g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t756x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work of Jean Cocteau (1889-1963), the poet, while extremely diverse, presents nonetheless a coherence and a unity of tone which transmit his artistic vision and at the same time reveal his creative process. Cocteau's art rests on the notion he has of poetry. With the help of the example set by Erik Satie, Raymond Radiguet and Pablo Picasso, he understood at an early age that poetry resided within him and that only by exploring himself and by following a set of morals--in this instance, morals signifies behaviour which conforms to the demands of poetry--would he attain a level of pure poetry. All of this is evident as much in the ideas the poet conveys as in his style. The personality of the poet, his "ligne" to use Cocteau's words, becomes apparent the more the idea is accurate and the word chosen significant. As a result of this "ligne", of its presence in the work, the poet approaches immortality. According to Cocteau, the work of a poet cannot flourish within human limits. The poet must transcend such limits to embody universal activity. It is for this reason that the poet must redefine religion and create for himself a personal mythology, that he must reconstruct the world starting from a play of spatial and temporal perspectives. His role thus proves essential to human survival. In effect, the poet fills the cosmic void in which man is evolving.</description><description>Three works in particular, Opium--Journal d'une desintoxication, La difficulte d'etre et le Journal d'un inconnu, permit us to retrace his poetic course.</description><creator>Prpić, Maya</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Jean Cocteau : la morale du poète</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx63n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t756x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935423q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis examines the reception and importance of Pietro Metastasio's dramatic work in Vienna and other major German centres and concentrates on the German dramatic versions of Demetrius. The first chapter discusses the eighteenth-century reception of Metastasio's Demetrius as opera and as drama in Vienna and across Germany, considers the Viennese dramatic performances of other well-known metastasian dramas and argues that Metastasio's works had their own independent literary validity before serving the music. The second chapter, which examines the publication history of both Metastasio's individual and collected works until 1800, maintains that German translations of Metastasio's texts were indeed required by Germans and Austrians during the eighteenth century. The last chapter, an intensive study of Demetrius, draws a precise comparison of a Viennese dramatic version of this work with the original Demetrio libretto, and comments on other German dramatic versions of the play. It is contended that Metastasio's texts could easily be adapted to become dramatic works. It is further argued that Metastasio was not only successful as librettist but also as dramatist in eighteenth-century German-speaking territory.</description><creator>Putalivo, Patrizia</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Metastasio, Pietro, 1698-1782 -- Appreciation -- Austria</subject><subject>Metastasio, Pietro, 1698-1782 -- Appreciation -- Germany</subject><subject>Metastasio, Pietro, 1698-1782. Demetrio</subject><title>Metastasio as dramatist : the example of Demetrius</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m055s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935423q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm853</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the role of the "false Messiah" in modern Yiddish Literature. The figure of the Messiah in Jewish religious imagination signifies the prophetic yearning for redemption at the end of days, but it also provoked hopes in a strong leader who will bring about social and political redemption. Based on historical models, literature from the twelfth to the twentieth century addressed these "false Messiahs" and in the modern period used them to define and illustrate contemporary catastrophe. Shlomo Molcho by American Yiddish poet Aaron Glanz-Leyeles and Prince Reuveni by Soviet Yiddish author David Bergelson are two twentieth century poetic historic dramas based on two messianic figures of the sixteenth century. These two modern works are compared in relation to the respective authors' life and times, political and aesthetic outlook, and dramatic powers. The comparison shows the usefulness of the "false Messiah" in dramatizing and expressing difficult contemporary issues.</description><creator>Ben-Shach, Jane Respitz</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Bergelson, David, 1884-1952. Prints Reuveni</subject><subject>Pseudo-Messiahs in literature</subject><subject>Glanz-Leyeless, A. (Aaron), 1889-1966. Shelomoh Molkho</subject><subject>Yiddish literature -- History and criticism</subject><title>The false Messiah in Yiddish literature : a comparison between two dramatic works</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v663q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm853</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nm67f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we are concerned with trajectory generation for the control of robot motion. When both time and energy are taken into consideration, evidence shows that some trajectories are more efficient than others. Power availability, joint rate bounds, and joint acceleration bounds represent an interesting set of constraints imposed on the manipulator. Because of the omnipresent energy overhead of any robot, the above mentioned constraints limit the efficiency domain of the machine. Pick-and-Place applications are of particular interest for our trajectory planning experiments. Three types of polynomials are used to compute the robot trajectories. Particular classes of functions are used to carry out the smooth interpolations in position, velocity and acceleration of each joint, namely cubic splines, as well as cubic and quintic polynomials. Finally, a trajectory planner using the aforementioned shape functions is implemented on a Puma 260 robot.</description><creator>Hoffman Zukowski, Marc</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Near-minimum-time robot trajectories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t0438.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm67f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193b19p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A critical study of the Jiles and Atherton Mean Field Model was done to determine the validity of the model, a tool in describing and understanding the magnetization process in textured silicon steels. Hysteresis loops were generated using an Epstein apparatus in various directions with respect to the rolling direction and for various external magnetic fields. Techniques were then used to obtain the model parameters, namely a$ sp prime,$ $ alpha sp prime,$ and k$ sp prime.$ After creating a new version of the model, M$ sb{ rm s}$ was also obtained from the data hysteresis loops. The model gives a close description of the influence of texture on hysteresis behaviour and predicts the variation of the parameter k$ sp prime,$ which agrees with our understanding of the role of texture in changing the parameter. We have observed that the highest value of this parameter coincides with the angles at which it is most difficult to magnetize the specimen. The proposal of the model's creators that the main drawback of the model that the pinning parameter $k sp prime$ is not constant, is not justified by them and not supported by our analysis of experimental data.</description><creator>Kozina, Thomas</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Using the mean field model to analyze the influence of texture on the hysteresis behaviour of silicon steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n231x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b19p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p8369</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cyathocotyle bushiensis (Digenea) and Sphaeridiotrema globulus (Digenea) are gastrointestinal pathogens of waterfowl, and are known to co-occur in salvaged ducks. The intensity and time-dependent pathogenesis induced by single infections of the two digeneans, and concurrent infections were studied in two species of dabbling ducks. Gross tissue pathology by single C. bushiensis infection was found to be a function of both the intensity and the duration of infection. Infection with single species infections of C. bushiensis and S. globulus was associated with decreased weight gain, tendencies for increased body temperatures and increased hematological parameters in Pekin ducklings. The hematological parameters in blue winged teal infected with C. bushiensis were found to decrease. Infection with S. globulus did not induce any significant systemic changes in the blue winged teal. A preliminary study of the effects of concurrent infection on the duck hosts suggests that in general, concurrent infection enhances the detrimental aspects of single infection, decreasing weight gain, increasing body temperatures, and decreasing hematological parameters in both species.</description><creator>Gagnon, Christine</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Ducks -- Pathogens.</subject><subject>Ducks -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Digenea.</subject><title>Pathological consequences of infection by Cyathocotyle bushiensis Khan, 1962 and Sphaeridiotrema globulus (Rudolphi, 1814) in two species of dabbling ducks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm23v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p8369</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rx864</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Arnold Schoenberg's Second String Quartet, Op.10, completed in 1908, is the last of his works in which a key signature is used, and is generally regarded as a transitional work leading towards his 'atonal' period. Each of the first three movements has a key signature, whereas the last movement has no key signature--a characteristic of his later atonal works. This study traces how the harmonic language evolves over the four movements of the quartet. The present analysis of each movement shows the structural procedures, the nature of the polyphony and the compositional techniques employed, including those which result in the dissolution of tonality. These changes contribute to the significance of the quartet as a critical work within the transition from the tonal to atonal medium.</description><creator>Kim, Kyŏng-ŭn.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951. Quartets, strings, op. 10, F#minor.</subject><subject>Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951 -- Harmony</subject><title>The harmonic language of Arnold Schoenberg's second string quartet op. 10 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn38k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rx864</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s04z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A method for PLA test pattern generation based on a branch and bound algorithm that exploits function monotonicity is presented. The algorithm makes irrevocable input assignments first, resulting in the efficient generation of compact test sets. In most cases there is no backtracking. An intelligent branching heuristic is presented. The algorithm handles extended fault models including crosspoint and delay faults. Heuristics which speed up test set generation and improve test set compaction are discussed. Results of tests on a wide range of benchmark PLAs are included.</description><creator>Robinson, Markus F.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A method of test pattern generation for programmable logic arrays /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3333401.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s04z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm86c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human skin fibroblasts derived from patients with all 7 known inborn errors of vitamin B$ sb{12}$ metabolism have been studied for functional integrity of methylmalonyl CoA mutase and methionine synthase. Cocultivation of cblC and cblF fibroblasts in the absence of polyethylene glycol resulted in a twofold increase over the expected in both ($ sp{14}$C) propionate and ($ sp{14}$C) methyltetrahydrofolate incorporation into acid-precipitable material, suggesting that metabolic cooperation between cells occurs. CblD fibroblasts, which are biochemically similar to cblC cells (Goodman et al, 1970; Willard et al, 1977), do not cooperate metabolically when mixed with cblF cells. Partial correction in phenotype was seen in mixtures of cblD and cblG cells, but not cblC and cblG cells. These observations lend further support for the division of cblC and cblD disease into two discrete complementation classes. Cocultivation of cblF fibroblasts with both cblE and cblG cells also resulted in partial correction in phenotype. ($ sp{14}$C) Propionate incorporation in both cblC and cblF cells exposed to conditioned medium from control cells was increased more than twofold. ($ sp{14}$C) methyltetrahydrofolate incorporation in cblC cells exposed to conditioned medium from cblF cells was increased twofold. This suggests the presence of a diffusible factor correcting the defect in the mutant cell lines.</description><creator>Byck, Susan</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Metabolism, Inborn errors of.</subject><subject>Vitamin B12 -- Metabolism -- Disorders.</subject><title>Cross-correctional studies in inborn errors of vitamin B12 metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk339.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm86c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm87n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study's goal is to quantify the influence of large-scale forcing on surface cyclogenesis. This is accomplished by considering seventy surface cyclones, whose maximum deepening occurs in the western North Pacific Ocean. Cyclone classification is based on this pressure change, ranging from +10 to $-$40 hPa/24 h. Composite surface, 850 and 500 hPa analyses for each class, constructed from NMC gridded data are used to diagnose quasi-geostrophic omega and frontogenetical forcing and static stability. Explosive cyclones are distinguished by strong downstream 850 and 500 hPa frontogenesis, suggesting deep baroclinicity's importance during the maximum deepening phase. Cyclogenesis, embedded in a deep, conditionally unstable environment increases with composite forcing. However, regression analyses, relating forcing and intensification, show explained variance to be generally small, owing to large case to case variability within classes. This variability is caused by exclusion of exponential surface vorticity enhancement and static stability effects, coarse-resolution data and analysis errors.</description><creator>Bullock, Timothy A. (Timothy Augustine)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A diagnostic study of cyclogenesis in the western Pacific Ocean /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz70w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm87n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010r34v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Intensity of axial turbulence at the nozzle exit and impingement heat transfer rate were measured for the re-entry slot channel nozzle, with nozzle length, L, nozzle width, w, and jet Reynolds number, Re, as parameters. With increasing Reynolds number over the range 5000-20000 the turbulence intensity decreases, but only slightly. For the shortest nozzles, i.e. orifices, turbulence varies greatly across the nozzle width, from  0% near the nozzle walls. A nozzle length of 3w-4w is sufficient to produce relatively flat profiles. Turbulence intensity is better characterized at the mid-plane, I$ sb{ rm jmp}$, than at the center line, I$ sb{ rm jcL}$. By varying w between 6 and 11 mm, and L from 13w down to an orifice, I$ sb{ rm jmp}$ varies between 4% and 9%. Impingement heat transfer is not significantly influenced by L/w. This geometry of nozzle operated at spacings, H/w of 3 and 6, gives heat transfer rates that match the maximum obtained with the ASME standard contoured entry nozzle at H/w precisely of 8.</description><creator>Chen, Guohua, 1963-</creator><contributor>Heiningen, A. R. P. van (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Douglas, W. J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Impingement heat transfer with re-entry channel nozzles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591953m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010r34v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q2713</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although the reduced scalar potential method of computing magnetic field problems is attractive for its computational economy, it is unable to produce satisfactory results, as reported by prior researchers. The cause of the inaccuracy was believed to be the cancellation between the separately-computed applied field H$ sb{ rm a}$, and the induced field H$ sb{ rm p}$ inside the permeable regions of the problem. Re-analysis of the problems which were previously treated by other researchers suggests that the way in which the total field H is separated into two parts, the applied field H$ sb{ rm a}$ and the induced field H$ sb{ rm p}$, in the reduced scalar method is indeed responsible for the near cancellation of these two fields in highly permeable regions. The numerical error seemed to be associated with the type of applied field that was used. In the reduced scalar potential approach, the trial functions representing the applied field H$ sb{ rm a}$ and the induced field H$ sb{ rm p}$(= $-$gradp) are not polynomials of the same degree, hence the cancellation difficulties inside the permeable regions are likely to be produced by this mismatch.</description><creator>Chen, Anna, 1959-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Reduced scalar potential analysis of magnetostatic fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph57f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q2713</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jf99r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Textural evidence, high carbonate concentration and septarian cracks in dolomite and calcite concretions and beds of the Middle Ordovician Cloridorme and Cow Head formations indicate early carbonate precipitation during very shallow burial in uncompacted or little compacted host-sediments. These carbonates started to form at a depth not exceeding 5 m from the seafloor, where porosities were as high as 90%, and continued to grow in the sediment column to subsurface depth of 150 meters. Concretions of the Silurian La Vieille Formation and Lower Ordovician Levis Formation started to form at somewhat greater depths of 50 and 350 meters, when porosities amounted to 65 and 25%, respectively, and continued to grow to depths of 350 and 600 meters, respectively. Covariation between $ delta sp{13}$C and $ delta sp{18}$O values of these carbonates further supports early diagenetic concretion growth. Variation of major and minor elements (i.e., Ca, Mg and Sr) observed along AAS traverses in the Cloridorme, Levis and Cow Head carbonates indicate that they grew in continually changing chemical environments.</description><creator>Shah, Jehangir A.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Early diagenetic deep-sea dolomites from the middle ordovician cloridorme formation, Gaspé Peninsula, Québec Appalachians and related occurrences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t044j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jf99r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m2991</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this work is to offer a quantitative assessment as to what extent the texture and the microstructure influence the cold headability of steel wires. For this, a set of cold drawn low carbon steel wires/AISI 1030 were prepared. The samples were drawn, without heat treatment, in between passes of up to 78% reduction in area (RA) in 5 passes. The deformed samples were then heat treated according to various schedules. Texture development was studied at a given thickness, by measuring the (110), (200) and (211) pole figures by X-ray diffraction; furthermore, the results were represented and using the Orientation Distribution Function (ODF). A strong $ langle$110$ rangle$ texture was found. Using special dies, compression tests were made in order to obtain information on such mechanical properties as the yield strength and the homogeneous strain energy. Multiple regression analysis was made in order to correlate the aspect ratio, the grain size, the Taylor factor and the maximum ODF intensity against the yield strength and the homogeneous strain energy.</description><creator>Sugondo</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Textures versus microstructure in determining mechanical properties in wires</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px23p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m2991</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hk35v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pseudomonas aeruginosa ATCC 9027 grew in a chemically defined medium with n-hexadecane or glucose, 0.5% (v/v or w/v, respectively), as the sole carbon source, and the K$ sb2$HPO$ sb4$, concentration was either 0.6 mM or 2.3 mM with both carbon sources. Only cells grown on n-hexadecane and 0.6 mM K$ sb2$HPO$ sb4$ produced pyocyanine. The variable lag period associated with cells grown on n-hexadecane was regulated by the state of the inoculating culture, grown on glucose and 2.3 mM K$ sb2$HPO$ sb4$. It was found that organic phosphate was more prevalent in cells grown on both phosphate concentrations with glucose and the high phosphate concentration with n-hexadecane, than it was for the low phosphate, n-hexadecane grown cells. The inorganic phosphate levels remained low under all conditions, decreasing as the cell culture became older. The inorganic polyphosphate level remained stable for all conditions, except in the high phosphate, n-hexadecane grown cells, where there was an increase.</description><creator>Suchorski, Anna M. (Anna Margaret)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Pseudomonas aeruginosa.</subject><subject>Phosphates.</subject><subject>Bacteria -- Physiology.</subject><title>The regulatory role of phosphate in the metabolism of N-hexadecane by Pseudomonas aeruginosa /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602204n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hk35v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qd34m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tinker, Stephen H.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Corn -- Losses</subject><subject>Red-winged blackbird</subject><title>Corn damage by captive red-winged blackbirds.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2363234.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd34m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967491r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Lafond, Lucie.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Staphylococcus</subject><subject>Neisseria gonorrhoeae</subject><title>Inhibition de la croissance de Neisseria gonorrhoeae par des staphylocoques coagulase-negatifs isoles de la flore urogenitale.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm25h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967491r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj31w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Nymark, Everdina C. M.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Food habits -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Nutrition -- Québec (Province) -- Psychological aspects.</subject><title>Food practices of a selected group of industrial workers in Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3333419.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj31w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53ww982</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:07:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Al-Kanani, Thamir Sadoon H., 1951-</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Engineering, General.</subject><title>Release of K in relation to the mineralogy of five selected soils from Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x50n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53ww982</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):28800</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>