<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:49:19Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04ds752</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The lifting of the government imposed ban on uranium prospecting, in 1948, has resulted in a surge of activity in the Goldfields region of northern Saskatchewan. In response to the insuing demand for geological maps the Geological Survey of Canada has undertaken to systematically map the region on a 1 mile to 1 inch scale. In 1950 and 1951 the writer carried out this work east of Goldfields by mapping Forget Lake and Nevins Lake map-areas ( Blake 14, 15 ). The main interest of these areas at present is in their nearness to the scene of active prospecting and development and in the continuation of the now-famous St. Louis fault they contain. The present work includes the results of the field investigations and subsequent laboratory studies. The Forget Lake and Nevins Lake map-areas lie between longitudes 107°45’ and 108°15’, and latitude 106°45’ and the north shore of Lake Athabasca. They have a combined width of l7½- miles and extend northward from the lake shore for a distance of about 22 miles to within 17 miles of the Northwest Territories. Thus, the area under study is nearly square and approximately 390 square miles in extent. The mining town of Goldfields, situated on the north shore of Lake Athabasca, is nine miles west of the southwest corner of the area. The Indian settlement of Fond du Lac, the next closest community, is situated, as the name indicates, at the end of the lake twenty miles east of the area. [...]</description><creator>Blake, Donald A. W. (Donald Alan Wright), 1925-</creator><contributor>Kranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The geology of the Forget Lake and Nevins Lake map-areas, Northern Saskatchewan.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cx38w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds752</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qw03v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Distortion of radar echo patterns by rain attenuation can be corrected by measuring the area under the rain intensity-range curves in successive steps and correcting the succeeding steps in accordance with the attenuation indicated by the preceding ones. Great accuracy in the initial calibration of the radar is necessary to avoid increase of error in the corrected rain intensities with depth into the rain shower. A radar calibration error of plus or minus 15% in rain intensity, or approximately 1 db in power level, is amplified by attenuation corrections, until at a depth into the shower equivalent to 100 mm hr^-1 miles, the rain intensity determination may be in error by a factor of 2. The effect of calibration error increases rapidly with decreasing wavelength in the range 10 - 3 cm. For accuracy in attenuation correction comparable with the experimental accuracy possible with non-attenuating radars, wavelengths greater than about 7 cm should be used.</description><creator>Bordan, Jack.</creator><contributor>Marshall, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Radar measurement of rainfall at attenuating wavelengths.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301462c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qw03v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk68c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The early observation that chlorination was an effective delignification agent of wood eventually led to the commercial Pomilio pulping process and to the alkaline hypochlorite bleaching of wood pulps. The study of the lignin products from these and other chlorination processes suffered from the presence of the carbohydrate fraction and from the pressure of the industrial point of view. Moreover, the conditions employed in industry were not necessarily the most advantageous for fundamental lignin studies, so that many lignin products were often highly chlorinated and badly degraded. This circumstance led to the abandonment of chlorination as a means of studying lignin structure. Some years ago, it was found possible to isolate most of the lignin from wood in a state that was only slightly chemically changed. The product, periodate lignin, was a light brown powder retaining the original morphological detail of the wood and differing from most other isolated lignins in retaining the original insolubility of lignin in organic solvents, while still behaving as lignin in situ towards a standard bisulfite cook. The availability of this material meant that fundamental studies could now be performed without the complication of the carbohydrate fraction. The effect of chlorine under alkaline conditions was then investigated on periodate lignin and it was shown that minimum oxidation and chlorination occurred at about pH 12. [...]</description><creator>Brounstein, Cyril James.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Oxidation of periodate lignin with sodium hypochlorite at pH12.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd93r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk68c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214s44n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose or this investigation is to give a description of the geology, with accompanying maps, of two areas near Millertown, Newfoundland. The field work was done during the summers of 1950 and 1951 for the Buchans Mining Company as a part of its scheme of systematically mapping their large mineral concession. Although the areas are not adjoining, the geology of the two will give a picture of the rock types found in crossing the “Central Mineralized Belt of Newfoundland”· Location The northern, or Buchans Junction Area, extends south of the C.N.R. tracks from points about eight miles west and two miles east of Millertown Junction to an east-west line running through the town or Millertown. ‘l’he centre of this area is approximately located at 48° 55’N - 56° 20’W. The southern, or Ambrose Lake Area, has a northern boundary about eight miles southwest of the Buchans Junction Area. It extends southward between the Victoria River on the west and the Anglo Newfoundland Development Company tramway on the east, to an east-west line a mile south of the depot at Ambrose Lake. To the south, the area extends 3½ miles east of a north-south running truck road of the A.N.D. Co. and thence south and southwest or the Noel Paul Brook. The position or the Ambrose Lake depot is approximately 48° 36’N - 56° 38’W. Rough geological sketches of this area were first made by W.E. Cormack in his trek across the island in 1822. [...]</description><creator>Brown, Norman Elwood.</creator><contributor>Riddell, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The geology of the Buchans Junction area, Newfoundland.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m725z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214s44n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g506</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the months of July, August and early September of 1950 and 1951, a survey was conducted in southern Saskatchewan to determine the presence or absence of sylvatic plague (Pasteurella pestis (Lehmann and Neumann)) in native rodents, with special reference to Richardson’s ground squirrel (Oitellus richardsonii richardsonii (Sabine)) and its flea ectoparasites. The investigation was carried out in conjunction with field work done in May and June of the same years in a search for Rocky Mountain spotted fever (Dermacentroxenus rickettsi (Walbach)) and tularaeoeia (Pasteurella tularensis (McCoy and Chapin)), in the two species of ticks, Dermacentor variabilis (Say) and Dermacentor andersoni Stiles, which occur in south-eastern and south-western Saskatchewan respectively. The survey disclosed that Richardson’s ground squirrel harboured many ectoparasites other than fleas; upon examination, these proved to be ticks, mites and lice. A search of the literature failed to reveal a comprehensive paper on the ectoparasites of C. r. richardsonii. Thus, it was decided that a study should be made. The following pages are a result of this work. A parasitological survey of the genus Citellus was made in Manitoba by McLeod in 1933. This entailed collecting and identifying ecto- and endo-parasites. Five species of ectoparasites were identified: Dermacentor venustus, Liponyssus occidentalis, Liponyssus montanus, Ceratophyllus bruneri, Linognathoides montanus. [...]</description><creator>Burgess, Glenn Dewey.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>Haematophagous Ectoparasites of Citellus richardsonii richardsonii (Sabine) (Mammalia: Sciuridae) with note on biology, distribution and relationship to endemic diseases in southern Saskatchewan.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g51g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g506</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r432c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nutrient allowances presently recommended for growing chicks have been established using dietary protein levels of eighteen percent and a growth period of zero to eight weeks. This tends to mask the higher growth rate and possibly higher nutrient requirements of the initial four week period. Current research indicates that growth rate and efficiency of feed utilization can be improved by increasing the protein content and otherwise providing better nutritional balance of the ration. This raises the question of the adequacy of presently recommended vitamin allowances under the conditions of higher growth rate and feed efficiency now possible. The influence of parental nutrition on the vitamin content of the egg, hatchability and growth of chicks fed deficient diets has been observed repeatedly. Little evidence has been advanced, however, to demonstrate that these differences in egg reserves can affect the growth of chicks fed rations of the recommended vitamin content. It is the purpose of this study to investigate the vitamin requirements of the chick during the initial month of life and to determine if they may be modified by more rapid rate of growth and different vitamin reserves in the newly-hatched chick.</description><creator>Burgess, Ralph C.</creator><contributor>Nikolaiczuk, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Poultry Husbandry.</subject><title>Vitamin requirements for hatchability and early chick growth.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw94s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r432c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Poultry Husbandry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nm42t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Agricultural research in Canada is largely centralized on Experimental Farms and Stations and at Agricultural Schools and Colleges where the property is owned, considerable equipment is available and a highly technical staff is employed. It is not possible for government services or educational institutions to establish such units in each of the numerous localities where study is required. Various methods of solving this problem have been developed, Many methods are dependent on farmer interest for their success, in others a small allowance is made for crop loss and inconvenience caused by the presence of tests on the farm. Some local problems are studied by technical men, other studies are dependent on the accuracy of the farmer co-operator. The Experimental Farms Service of the Federal Department of Agriculture has conducted experiments dealing with local problems through Illustration Stations; the Agricultural Colleges through local tests, and the farmers themselves have organized into Crop Improvement and other Associations in attempts to solve some of their own problems. All of these methods serve a useful purpose, particularly where they are close to a centralized station with its available technical staff and certain crop and other tests of short duration may be laid down and managed by trained personnel. Such experiments are usually of a demonstrational nature laid down to illustrate the results of well designed experiments conducted [...]</description><creator>Cairns, R. R.</creator><contributor>Steppler, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Agronomy.</subject><title>A method of conducting agricultural experiments in remote areas.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602420f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nm42t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agronomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720h03h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Klondike District of Central Yukon Territory around Dawson City is particularly advantageous for the study of the sequence of the Pleistocene epoch because it was never glaciated and therefore has never lost its fossiliferous superficial deposits. This paper presents a pollen diagram from a Sphagnum peat bed, which was the youngest deposit discovered, and pollen floras from different ages back to the Pliocene. The peat bed flora shows fairly steady climatic conditions little different from the present; the Pliocene flora shows a distinctly warmer climate; and all the others appear to show colder climates. The paper also presents a theory of correlation of geological events in the district with world-wide climatic variations: cutting of very broad creek valleys; climate warm - Earlier Tertiary - deposition of the oldest gravels; climate warm - Pliocene - deposition of oldest unweathered gravels; climate cold - Nebraskan Glaciation - rapid cutting of narrow lower creek valleys - Three Major Interglacial Ages - major interruptions of valley cutting; climate cold - Kansan and Illinoian Glaciation - deposition of thick valley - bottom muck; climate cold - Wisconsin Glaciation - erosion of valley - bottom muck; climate warmer than the present - Post-Glacial Climatic Optimum - deposition of Sphagnum peat bed; climate same as today - Recent Time [...]</description><creator>Campbell, John Duncan, 1923-</creator><contributor>Roscoe, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Sediments (Geology) -- Yukon -- Klondike River Valley.</subject><subject>Klondike River Valley (Yukon) -- Gold discoveries.</subject><subject>Paleobotany -- Yukon -- Klondike River Valley.</subject><subject>Paleobotany -- Pleistocene.</subject><title>The palaeobotany and stratigraphic sequence of the pleistocene Klondike "muck deposits".</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rs10s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720h03h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hg33h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a study of common human needs as presented by 97 recipients of War Veterans’ Allowance^1 who during 1949 first applied to the Montreal District Office of the Department of Veterans’ Affairs^2 for supplementation from the Assistance Fund. The study is concerned with the way in which these needs have been determined, how the Assistance Fund was set up and how it bas been administered to meet them. Considerable change in public welfare principles, in Canada, United States, Great Britain and other western democracies, bas taken place during the last two decades. This transition has been away from the palliative type of public welfare which developed after the passing of the Elizabethan Poor Law and toward the ameliorative type of public welfare programmes which arose in these countries out of the 1930 depression. In Canada and the United States casework and social services have been incorporated in some public assistance programmes. In European countries the programmes were established earlier than in Canada and have created protection in many areas through social insurance. The trend there has been toward providing more social security through material assistance such as adequate housing, through public housing projects, and government sponsored medical facilities. During the depression era society could no longer refuse to recognize that some individuals were in necessitous circumstances through no fault of their own but through flaws in our economic systems [...]</description><creator>Carlson, Leonard I.</creator><date>1952</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>A federal supplementary assistance programme from a social work viewpoint.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c542.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hg33h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268850z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study of the swelling of fibers in liquids has been made, using the permeability method based on the Kozeny equation. The rectified form of this equation was found to be generally applicable to liquid flow through beds of swollen fibres.  The experimental limitations of the method have been analyzed and discussed. The swelling of pulp in a homologous series of alcohols has been examined. A relationship has been shown between the swelling of a pulp in water produced by beating and the development of paper strength in the beater. It was also found that extraction of this beaten pulp with alkali caused a reduction in the degree of swelling which was paralleled by a reduction in paper strength.  The significance of swelling in the beating process and the participation of hemicelluloses in this process are discussed. </description><creator>Carroll, Murray Norman.</creator><contributor>Mason, S. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Swelling studies of some natural and synthetic fibers.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b921m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268850z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s074x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hemlock looper, Lambdina fiscellaria fiscellaria (Guenée), has been an important forest pest in Newfoundland for many years. Outbreaks have been reported from widely separated parts of the province, and in most cases, there has been a high mortality of balsam fir, Abies balsamea (L.) Mill. (Fig. l). A study of the insect was initiated in the spring of 1950, in Newfoundland, by the Division of Forest Biology, Dominion Department of Agriculture. The object of the study was to determine what factors influence the rise and fall of looper populations. Unfortunately, the outbreak had reached its peak when the study was started. In 1951 populations had fallen to an endemic level, resulting in rather meagre information on many aspects of the investigation. Biological and population studies of the hemlock looper and associated insects were carried out by the writer and an assistant at a summer field station established near Lake St. George, St. George’s District, Newfoundland. The station was used from May to September in 1950 and 1951. Studies on the external morphology of all developmental stages of the species were made at the Dominion Entomological Laboratory, Fredericton, N. B. Morphological studies were conducted to discover if specimens found in Newfoundland and New Brunswick are conspecific. Although climatic conditions and forest composition are fairly similar in both provinces the looper has never been a serious pest in the latter. [...]</description><creator>Carroll, William Joseph.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The biology and external morphology of the Hemlock Looper, Lambodina Fiscellaria Fiscellaria (Guenee), in Newfoundland (Lepidoptera, Geometridae).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr273.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s074x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712mb074</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The terminal impedance of a full-wave dipole as a function of centre spacing has been measured for dipoles with the ratio of wave length to diameter (λ/D) equal to : 188, 94.3, 75.7, 62.9, 47.2, and 23.6 for centre spacings (S/λ)of .0212, .0423, .074, and .105. All measurements were made at 1000 megacycles using a standing wave measuring method with the half dipole above an image plane. The variation of resistance and reactance of the terminal impedance with centre spacing is shown in a series of graphs. A considerable increase in anti-resonant resistance and in antenna length for anti-resonance is observed to occur with increased gap length. The results are shown to agree well with existing literature.</description><creator>Clark, George Denton.</creator><contributor>Howes, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>The input impedance of a full-wave dipole.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676z95s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712mb074</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g3306</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work is part of an extensive program of investigations, by various governmental agencies in Canada and the United States of America, into the cause of damage to birch in the forests of Eastern North America. Birch, once considered as little better than a weed tree, is now in great demand as the source of an increasingly popular and useful hardwood. This intensive utilization of birch wood could have revitalized the old hardwood industries of the east and might even have encouraged the establishment of new ones had not the source of raw material been drastically reduced by an insidious malady now generally known as birch ‘dieback’. Fullerton (1952) sums up the past, present, and future status of birch from the industrialists’ viewpoint in these words:- “A fact to be reckoned with is that birch wood has never been so much in favour or demand, for either industrial or decorative purposes, as at present. Once used mostly as fuel for home fires it now ... ranks among the high class woods of the world. Present demand for birch is for use in manufacture of flooring, interior house finish, doors, board lumber, veneer and plywood, furniture, tool handles, implements and body parts, and in recent years airplane frames. The shortages are not imaginary or artificial. New Brunswick, heretofore a heavy producer, is now buying birch from Quebec and Nova Scotia, but the latter province has itself a problem in getting the supplies it needs for its own use." [...]</description><creator>Clark, John.</creator><contributor>Gibbs, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Botany.</subject><title>The water requirements of yellow birch.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd24p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g3306</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569751m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Grain crops are often afflicted with a disease commonly referred to as root rot or foot rot. Because root rot diseases are very variable in their symptom expression, they are frequently overlooked as the abnormal condition is often attributed to drought, wind, frost or other causes. For these reasons it is difficult to estimate the damage caused exclusively by root rots. It is generally agreed that the fungus Helminthosporium sativum P.K. &amp; B. is of prime importance in the root rot complex affecting barley and wheat. By plating tests of seed samples of barley and wheat grown in representative areas of Canada, Greaney (1944) showed that the most important pathogen present was H. sativum. Oswald (1950) in California found the four primary pathogenic fungi attacking barley and wheat, in their order of apparent economic importance, to be Helminthosporium sativum, Fusarium roseum f. cerealis, Ophiobolus graminis and Fusarium nivale. Simard and Ludwig (1946) found that, in the years 1942 and 1943, 65 per cent of the Quebec grown barley seed samples examined by them carried H. sativum. The significance or Helminthosporium sativum in the barley and wheat growing areas is indicated by estimates of the damage caused by this fungus. Maohaeek (1943) concluded from the results of a three year survey in Manitoba that barley and wheat yields are reduced by as much as 12 per cent because of root rot.[...]</description><creator>Clark, Robert Vernon.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>Studies on the role of the toxic substances produced by helminthosporium sativum P.K. &amp; B. in its parasitism.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214s45x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569751m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085p43w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to describe the nature and quality of settlement in a typical part of the Quebec country-side, and to trace the evolution of the present pattern of settlement and the cultural landscape. The Richelieu Valley was chosen because of its significance in the history of the province of Quebec and because of its geographical interest. In the southern part of the Province of Quebec are round the St. Lawrence Lowlands. This level, fertile area, along the St. Lawrence River provides a great contrast to the rough, forested lands of the rest of the province. The lowlands were the first lands in Quebec to be settled, and they have become the most densely populated, as well as being the most productive agricultural region in the province.· The Richelieu River, flowing north from Lake Champlain, and almost parallel to the St. Lawrence, crosses the Montreal Plain, a section of the lowlands, and for most of its length the river valley may be regarded today as a cross-section of this part of Quebec. The land on either aide of the river is, then, very flat, and the Richelieu Valley is not an obvious physical unit. In order to delimit the area to be studied, the land included within the drainage system of the Richelieu in Quebec was delineated and this line was adopted as the boundary. A few minor changes were made, and these are considered in the following paragraphs.[...]</description><creator>Cobban, Aileen Anne.</creator><creator>Lithgow, Robert Morrison.</creator><contributor>Summers, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Geography.</subject><title>A regional study of the Richelieu valley.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bx62b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085p43w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wn54n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bacteriophages, regarded today as viruses parasitic on bacteria, are characterized by a number of well-defined properties, one of these being the specificity exhibited by some varieties of phages, not only for a single species of bacteria, but also for certain strains or types of that single species.  A practical application of this property has been the use of bacteriophage for the identification or phage typing of certain strains of a given species.  Fisk (1942) introduced a method of phage typing of staphylococci which has been successfully used for tracing sources of infection in epidemic outbreaks of staphylococcal enterotoxin food-poisoning and of staphylococcal infections of the skin in babies in maternity hospitals.  Although this method is relatively simple and rapid, many strains of staphyloccoi are resistant to the action of the available phages and the absolute specificity of the phage types is questionable.  The purpose of this work is to investigate the growth and multiplication requirements and the stability of the staphylococcus bacteriophages now available, and to use anti-bacteriophage sera (prepared by immunizing rabbits with selected phage strains) as a means for recognition of specificity.  If the phages could be divided into a few representative groups, it is hoped that by a careful selection of these phages, a simpler method of phage typing applicable in every laboratory may be developed.</description><creator>Comtois, Romuald D.</creator><contributor>Kalz, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Bacteriology &amp; Immunology.</subject><title>Differential characterization and selection of staphylococcus bacteriophages.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tj66x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wn54n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bacteriology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t537v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:14:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De toutes les créations - et elles sont innombrables! - qui sont nées de la plume, merveilleusement douée de Victor Hugo, celle qui reste la plus populaire, c’est son roman “Notre-Dame de Paris”. On rencontre ici, à son moment le plus sublime, le travail d’un grand talent. Grâce au don de Hugo de décrire les choses longtemps disparues de la manière la plus éclatante, grâce à son immense imagination créatrice, on se sent, dès les premières lignes du roman, dans le Paris de 1482 - dans son atmosphère, parmi ses habitants. Mais quand, après avoir lu le dernier mot, on ferma le livre et revient à 1952, on peut se demander: ces descriptions sont-elles vraiment historiques?- ces personnages qui pensent et agissent dans le vieux Paris, sont-ils vraiment du moyen âge? Cette thèse est une étude du. moyen âge dans “Notre-Dame de Paris”; le but est de montrer que Victor Hugo a créé un décor authentique, un tableau original et puissant, une vision hallucinante du vieux Paris et de sa grandiose cathédrale, mais qu’il n’a pas réussi dans ce cadre magnifique à mettre en scène des êtres qui, par leurs idées et leurs sentiments, évoquent leurs prototypes de 1482: l’intrigue mince, les personnages factices et conventionnels évoquent beaucoup plus des romantiques du XIXe siècle que des âmes du XVe siècle. Le premier chapitre est un coup d’oeil bref, et général sur le moyen âge chez Hugo. [...]</description><creator>Corey, Earl Edward Charles Hector.</creator><contributor>Furness, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885.</subject><title>Le moyen âge dans "Notre-Dame de Paris".</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q753w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t537v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mt11z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The protein hormone, prolactin, has been of great interest to endocrinologists ever since the demonstration of its presence in the anterior pituitary by Stricker and Grueter in 1929. The action of this hormone was shown to be exerted on the fully developed mammary gland, causing the induction and maintenance of lactation (Nelson, 1936). This role of the hormone has even been of economic interest since prolactin for a time was used in Britian to prevent the decline in the spring in milk production of cows. More recently, there have been reports that prolactin may have other effects in the body besides its function in lactation. It is thought to induce the secretion of hormones from the corpus luteum; but here again, only when the gland is fully developed and ready to function. In 1947 when the present problem was undertaken, almost nothing was known about the behavior of the hormone in the animal body. Questions such as “where does it go, and what does it do?” could not have been answered. The search for answers to questions like this are a proper responsibility of modern endocrinology. As tools for investigations of this nature, radioactive isotopes are proving indispensible, because use of them allows study of the behavior of the hormones in minute doses, and these potent biological entities exert widespread effects when present in almost infinitisimal amounts.[...]</description><creator>Cox, Phoebe L.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>The preparation, distribution, and metabolism of iodo-prolactin labelled with I131.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d317h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mt11z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f6873</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work to be reported in this thesis has been restricted to the study of carbohydrate absorption. Since a number of aspects of the problem have received attention, these aspects have been dealt with in different chapters. It was thought that the subject could be more easily followed if the literature concerning each aspect was reviewed in the opening paragraphs of the separate chapters. For this reason the General Introduction will be limited to a brief description of the most common methods used in the past for the study of the intestinal absorption of carbohydrates, and following this to a consideration of the evidence quoted by Verzar in support of a phosphorylative mechanism of absorption. The plausibility of the phosphorylation theory has gained for it wider acceptance than the proof advanced would seem to warrant, and subsequent researches have been greatly influenced by this concept.</description><creator>Darlington, Walter A.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Absorption studies with isolated surviving intestine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g8221.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f6873</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3335641</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the beginning of the present century, many workers have been interested in various aspects of insect nutrition.  The early investigators were interested in the effects of bacterial action and consequently were led to investigate the effect of sterilization of both the experimental animals and the dietary substrate.  Pasteur, although he never attempted to do so himself, once declared to the Academy of Science that he hoped to see a research worker attempt to rear an animal under strictly aseptic conditions.  Much of the nutritional literature is concerned with a continuation of this argument.  Even today, such eminent workers as Wigglesworth (93), Mansour (63) (64), and Koch (57) (580 (59) are unwilling to define the role played by bacteria in nutrition.  Bacteria, regardless of their role, fall into two main categories: those contained in the food; and those living in the mycetomes, which in some cases communicate with the gut.  The subject is important because of the fact that bacteria may be capable of fixing free nitrogen or of converting one type of amino acid to another.  For very precise work, undoubtedly bacterial action is an important factor.  However, in some cases, it is possible to neglect the question of the action of bacteria on the food.  In the natural state, the food is certainly contaminated with bacteria, and under normal conditions, there is no such things as asepsis. [...]</description><creator>Davis, Gordon Richard Fuerst.</creator><contributor>Stanley, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Beetles -- Nutrition.</subject><title>A nutritional investigation of Oryzaephilus surinamensis Linné.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806334w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3335641</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qd002</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The object of this investigation was firstly to compare the three methods for the preparation of quinolinic acid (pyridine 2,3-dicarboxylic acid), namely, the oxidation of quinoline in a water solution either by potassium permanganate or hydrogen peroxide and the oxidation of 8-hydroxy quinoline with nitric acid at low temperatures. The first method seemed to be the most desirable since quinoline from coal-tar is an inexpensive material and potassium permanganate costs less than hydrogen peroxide. Previous publications dealing with this oxidation give low and inconsistent yields. Therefore, it was of interest to improve the method of oxidation of quinoline with potassium permanganate. The other problem in this research was to study the condensation of diethyl quinolate and ethyl acetate with basic catalysts in order to obtain derivatives of the pyrindene series.</description><creator>Dennis, Donald Albert.</creator><contributor>Taurins, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies in diethyl quinolate.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h486m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qd002</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p147g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper deals with the explanation of what seemed, under the circumstances, a rather surprising activity of about 30 minutes induced in crystals of potassium iodide when bombarded at 40 Mev in the McGill cyclotron. It is shown that the activity is, in reality, complex and arises from (1) C134 (32 min) formed from the K nuclei and (2) I128 127 (25 min) formed by neutron capture in I127. This is the first example of a strong activity so formed in the McGill cyclotron by capture of the numerous neutrons known to be released in all targets at high energies. In the fall of 1950, D. E. Tilley, J. D. Keys and W. S. Boyle, all members of the McGill Radiation Laboratory, bombarded, in the McGill cyclotron, crystals of iodine and iodine salts with protons of various energies. In newly bombarded crystals (i.e. before any separation of the elements was attempted) they noticed, among other things, an activity of half-life approximately 30 minutes. This particular activity appeared most markedly when the bombarding protons had energies from 30 to 50 Mev. The purpose of the work reported here is to identify this 30 minute activity. Iodine, atomic number 53, has only one stable isotope, I127. Some of the present published knowledge(l, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8) about the active iodine isotopes, and about the isotopes of xenon (atomic number 54) and other nearby elements, is summarized in Figure 1. The chart shows the relative abundances of the stable isotopes [...]</description><creator>Dewdney, John Wells.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>The identification of some radioactive products from the proton bombardment of iodine and iodine salts.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nv138.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p147g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n46b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On découvre en Maeterlinck deux hommes: le poète et le naturaliste: le poète avec sa délicatesse et sa sensibilité, et le paysan flamand d`une constitution lourde et carrée. Maurice Maeterlinck naquit en 1862 dans la villa familiale d‘Oostacker, près de Gand. Le paysage belge lui fournit la scène pour Les Sept Princesses: une terre noire de marais, avec des chênes et des saules, des châteaux sombres sur des voûtes, et des canaux sinueux où flottent des cygnes. Le milieu mélancolique de Gand l’inclinait vers le fatalisme de ses premiers ouvrages. Il cherchait toujours la solitude; il aimait beaucoup le silence. Même les sports qu’il choisissait le menèrent d`être seu1: en été, il faisait de longues promenades en barque sur les sombres canaux, il fuyait en bicyclette au bord des grandes prairies solitaires; en hiver, il patinait. Il resta paysan toute sa vie. Il reçut son éducation au Collège des Jésuites aux bords de la Lys. Il détestait les Jésuites; leur enseignement religieux terrifiait son imagination de petit garçon sensible. La peur de l’enfer, qu’ils lui enseignaient laissa indélébile une marque sur sa vie, et sur son être. “On ne devrait pas avoir le droit,” disait-il, “de déformer ainsi de futurs hommes.” (l) Pour faire plaisir à ses parents, il devint avocat, mais son inaptitude à la profession juridique était bien apparente. Après son dernier procès: “C’est fini, je ne plaiderai plus [...]</description><creator>Dick, Helen.</creator><contributor>Nardin, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Maeterlinck, Maurice, 1862-1949 -- Characters -- Women.</subject><title>Les heroines du théâtre de Maurice Maeterlinck.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hd00v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n46b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qt06v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In connection with hydro-power development at Tranche, Quebec, series of hydraulic tests were performed on a model of the spillway in Hydraulics Laboratory of the Ecole Polytechnique de Montréal. The resulting discharge coefficient-versus-head curves for floodways Nos. 1, 2 and 3 were quite consistent and satisfactory except those for floodway No. 4, where repeated tests showed irregularities and deviations. All the above curves are given on page 12 of this thesis. The object of this thesis is to explain the deviations of the curves for floodway No. 4, employing detailed hydraulic tests and investigations. First part of the investigations consisted of the following: a) Measurements and plot of free surface profile. b) Measurements of pressure on the downstream face of the spillway. c) Measurements of the flow velocity along streamlines and throughout the nappe. During all above measurements and investigations, the upstream river bottom topography of the model was left unchanged. A converging of streamlines and angularity of flow was found to be existing, as represented on page 34. This observation as well as other data of investigations necessitated certain changes in the topography of the upstream river bottom. Hydraulic tests run after the changes showed considerable improved discharge coefficient and head relations, though some irregularities were still existing. [...]</description><creator>Drouin, Paul-Emile.</creator><contributor>Craig, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>The relation between head and discharge in a curved spillway.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jc11q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qt06v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257j07n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:15:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Burnt Creek - Goodwood area, represents a part of the main ore zone on the contiguous exploration concessions of the Hollinger North Shore Exploration Company, in New Quebec, and of the Labrador Mining and Exploration Company, in Labrador, Newfoundland. The concessions cover the southern part of the “Labrador Trough”, a geological unit made up of folded and faulted sedimentary and volcanic series of late Precambrian Age. (Figure 1 ) This paper deals with a detailed study of the Kaniapiskau system with special reference to the Sokaman iron formation, the most important economic member of that system, in an area where large concentrations of iron ore ( as hematite and goethite ) occur within the iron formation. Field work conducted by the writer at various localities in the area during the summers of 1947, 1948 and 1949, particularly between Wishart Lake and Irony Mountain and to the north in the vicinity of Goodwood deposit ( Figure 2 ), together with field data of other members of the staff, form the basis of this study. The field work was followed by laboratory investigations at McGill University and at the University of Minnesota. A map of the vicinity of Burnt Creek accompanies this report to illustrate the major features of the geology of the area.</description><creator>Dufresne, Cyrille.</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>A study of the Kaniapiskau system in the Burnt Creek-Goodwood area, New Quebec and Labrador, Newfoundland.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jv41p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257j07n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>