<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:50:37Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xm437</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tiempos del caos is a composition in five sections for chamber  orchestra (28 players) and real-time computer-generated sounds, with a duration of  approximately 15 minutes. A performer is required to control the computer-generated  sounds which are produced using the software jMax. The inspiration for the form of  the piece comes from my reading of the novel One Hundred Years of Solitude by  Gabriel Garcia Marquez. The harmonic material is derived mainly from analyses of the  acoustical properties of recorded instrumental sounds.</description><creator>MacCallum, John</creator><contributor>Rea, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Electronic music</subject><subject>Chamber orchestra music -- Scores</subject><title>Tiempos del caos</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h949p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm437</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547s02m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermal stability of organoclays and polystyrene (PS)  intercalation in organoclays by melt processing were studied. The effects of polymer  viscosity, processing conditions, type of mixing and the type of fillers on the  intercalation process were evaluated. The resulting nanocomposites were tested to  characterize structure, thermal stability and mechanical properties. Two new organoclays were used in this study exhibited good  thermal stability. This suggested their potential use in the preparation polymer  nanocomposites at high processing temperatures. Batch mixing promoted polymer intercalation in most cases. PS  nanocomposites showed a combination of intercalated and unintercalated or collapsed  structures. In general, thermal stability and mechanical properties of PS were  enhanced by incorporation of organoclays. Processing conditions in the batch mixer  had only a small influence on intercalation behavior. However, they had a strong  effect on thermal stability and mechanical properties. The degree of intercalation  was dependant on the type of organoclay. As a result thermal stability and  mechanical properties were influenced by the type of organoclay used. The best  mechanical properties were obtained with Cloisite 10-A. Mixing in the twin screw extruder promoted intercalation of low  viscosity PS. Thermal stability was increased in all cases, but mechanical  properties did not improve significantly. The tensile modulus of nanocomposites was calculated using five  models reported in the literature. The results were compared to experimental data  obtained in this study. Up to 1% wt Cloisite 10-A content, the experimental results  showed very good agreement with the predictions of the Halpin-Tsai and Brune models,  which predicted the highest modulus values. The experimental values fell rapidly  bellow theoretical predictions above 1% wt clay content.</description><creator>Uribe Calderón, Jorge Alonso</creator><contributor>Kamal, Musa R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Melt intercalation andor exfoliation of polystyrene-montmorillonite nanocomposites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tv700.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s02m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nm088</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The stretch reflex is an involuntary contraction produced in response to muscle stretch. Despite extensive research, its role in the control of movement and posture remains controversial. One reason for this is that the torque output produced by reflex activity has been studied in only a limited number of tasks and behaviours. The main thrust of this thesis is to examine whether the central nervous system (CNS) modifies stretch reflex properties to suit the task. An electro-hydraulic actuator applied perturbations to the ankles of five subjects while they performed position-matching (PM) and torque-matching (TM) tasks. Stretch reflex properties were determined using a new closed-loop, reflex identification algorithm that analytically separated the torques produced by stretch reflexes from the overall ankle torque. Stretch reflex gain was greater in the PM task than for the TM task, under matched conditions.</description><creator>Tung, James, 1975-</creator><contributor>Kearney, Robert E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Recreation.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Task-dependent modulation of stretch reflex stiffness in the ankle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w21k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm088</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708x203</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experimental results of scalar dispersion from a concentrated  source in an inhomogeneous turbulent flow field are presented in this  thesis. The flow field is fully developed channel flow---one of the  simplest inhomogeneous turbulent flows. A fine line source is used to inject the  scalar (temperature). The temperature injection does not affect the flow field,  hence it is passive. The line source is in the spanwise (z) direction of the  channel, and is located at transverse (i.e., wall-normal) locations: y/h = 0.067,  0.17, and 1.0 (where h is the channel half-width). Measurements of the resultant  thermal plume for each source location are taken for two Reynolds numbers: 10400 and  22800 (where Re = Uch/nu: U c is the centerline velocity and nu is the kinematic  viscosity). Hot-wire anemometry and cold-wire thermometry are used to acquire  velocity and temperature data, respectively. It is shown that the downstream decay of the mean temperature  rise is less than that of isotropic grid-generated turbulence and homogenous  turbulent shear flow. The peak RMS temperature fluctuation also decays at a slower  rate. For the near-wall source locations, the peak of the transverse RMS temperature  profile drifts toward the channel centerline with increasing downstream distance  from the source. Also, for the near-wall source locations, the scalar PDF is  quasi-Gaussian, indicating improved mixing in that region. As the plume is traversed  toward the centerline, the PDF evolves into a very positively skewed  shape. An extensive database of the thermal plume is compiled, which  consists of the mean, RMS, and skewness profiles of the temperature field, PDFs of  the temperature field, and temperature-velocity correlations. This database can be  used to test numerical and/or theoretical models, highlighting their strengths and  weaknesses.</description><creator>Lavertu,Robert A.</creator><contributor>Mydlarski, L. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Scalar dispersion in turbulent channel flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h5041.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708x203</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139253d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the possibility of using both miniature  reflection (MSR-IE) and Ultrasonic (PUNDIT) techniques for the appraisal of paste  backfill. The use of paste backfill is gaining popularity, however various  technical, environmental and regulatory constraints complexify the study of its  behaviour. There are various laboratory experiments available for the appraisal of  this material; however the results do not necessarily correspond to its in-situ  response. The main objective of this experimentation is to evaluate the quality of  the fill by the study of its P-wave velocity, hence establish a relationship between  the curing-time, strength and P-wave velocity of the material. This preliminary  analysis in the field of mining demonstrates the possibility of finding an easy,  reliable and cost effective in-situ method of appraising paste  backfill. Given the complexity of the research project, the work focuses  on correlating the quality of the paste fill, with the MSR-IE and PUNDIT systems, in  a laboratory environment. The results demonstrate the potential of the MSR-IE  investigation on Paste backfill and the near future possibility of in-situ testing  with this method.</description><creator>Latifpour Moozar, Kasra</creator><contributor>Ouellet, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hassani, F. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Non-destructive appraisal of paste backfill</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q458n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139253d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924c33q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The low capital and operating costs of aerated lagoons has lead  to their extensive use in rural areas as a method of wastewater treatment. Although  the performance of the system depends directly on the hydraulic mixing, there is  currently no consensus on the key hydraulic parameters that influence the mixing of  these lagoons. Tracer studies were performed on the St-Hermas aerated lagoon and a  dynamically similar laboratory model to determine the effects of the water flow rate  and the aeration rate on the performance of these aerated lagoons, to evaluate the  method of dynamic similarity used to design the laboratory model and to evaluate the  accuracy of predictive empirical dispersion models. The results were analysed using  flow visualisation, simple observational and mathematical Retention Time  Distribution (RTD) techniques and various hydraulic models. From these results it is  concluded that the water flow rate and the aeration rate both significantly affect  the hydraulic mixing of aerated lagoons, with the water flow rate being the dominant  parameter. Furthermore, it is proven that the method of dynamic similarity used in  this research is valid and that the only dispersion model that predicted reasonably  accurate results was Arcievala (1981). An additional finding during the course of  this research indicates that tracer study E-curves must be developed to completion  in order to ensure conservation of mass and accurate analytical  results.</description><creator>Delatolla, Robert</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Characterization of hydraulic parameters affecting the performance of aerated lagoons by Robert Delatolla.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290b074.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c33q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h34d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Current advanced engineering composites suffer from high-cost of  manufacturing as well as design and processing weaknesses. On the other hand, nature  produces high-performance composites under benign conditions using simple  constituents. Hence, it seems that imitating nature constitutes the future of  material science. This thesis attempts to answer some of the basic questions  concerning the formation of biological fibrous composites. Microstructural studies  of these materials have revealed that they exhibit a common architecture known as  twisted plywood. This architecture results from the passage of the matrix into a  cholesteric liquid crystalline phase during the development of the composite. The  main objectives of this work are: to develop a mathematical model based on the  well-established liquid crystalline theory of Landau-de Gennes, to describe the  formation process of the twisted plywood architecture; to solve the set of governing  partial differential equations, to use the theoretical and computational results  obtained to provide a picture of the structure evolution and its  kinetics.</description><creator>De Luca, Gino</creator><contributor>Rey, A. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Theory and simulation of microstructure transformation in cholesteric liquid crystalline materials : applications to biological fibrous composites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb45f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h34d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bp872</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with development and implementation of  an efficient and numerically reliable positioning algorithm based on the combination  of code pseudorange (C/A) and carrier phase (L1) measurements with cycle slip  detection. In GPS a typical technique for kinematic position estimation is  relative positioning where two receivers are used, one receiver is stationary and  its exact position is known, the other is roving and its position is to be  estimated. We describe the physical situation and give the mathematical model based  on the difference of the measurements at the stationary and roving receivers. The  model we consider combines both code pseudorange and carrier phase measurements. We  then present: a recursive least squares approach for position estimation. We take  full account of the structure of the problem to make our algorithm efficient, and  use orthogonal transformations to ensure numerical reliability of the  algorithm. At each epoch, possible cycle slips must be detected, otherwise  it may significant deteriorate the positioning accuracy. A cycle slip detection  method based on the higher-order difference technique, one of typical techniques for  cycle slip detection, is developed and incorporated into the preprocess of our  positioning algorithm. Finally, real data testing for our positioning algorithm and  cycle slip detection algorithm are performed. The results suggest our algorithms are  very effective.</description><creator>Yin, Lan, 1969-</creator><contributor>Chang, Xiao-Wen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Geodesy.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>GPS based positioning with cycle slip detection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4305427.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp872</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fc23h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RET is a tyrosine kinase receptor that induces cell survival,  proliferation and migration. When bound by its ligand, GDNF (glial derived  neurotrophic factor) and its co-receptor, GFRalpha-1 (GDNF family receptor alpha-1),  tyrosine residues in the intracellular domain of the receptor are phosphorylated as  part of signal transduction. In the kidney, RET is required for branching of the  ureteric bud and it also regulates the maturation of the ureter in the urinary  tract. Although it is well established in mice that the absence or overexpression of  RET leads to severe kidney abnormalities, the cellular basis for these defects  remains unexplored. To determine whether the overexpression of RET affected the  development of the urinary tract, HoxB7/RET mice were tested for the presence of  vesico-ureteric reflux (VUR) in which urine flows retrogradely from the bladder back  up the ureter. To further understand how the urinary tract is formed, we looked for  the presence of VUR in HoxB7/RET and wildtype mice at E17. These results provide a  new understanding of how combined kidney and urinary tract malformations occur in  humans.</description><creator>Yu, Hoi Yun Oriana, 1978-</creator><contributor>Gupta, Indra R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>The role of RET tyrosine kinase in kidney and urinary tract development /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k79w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fc23h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm62z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of seismic attribute studies in the petroleum industry  is fast spreading. Seismic attribute studies entail the integration of derived  attributes from 3-D seismic data with well log, core and/or outcrop data (through  multivariate linear regression, neural networks, etc.) to estimate and project  physical properties in areas of sparse data control. Because of the accuracy of this  technique in predicting the subsurface distribution of physical properties in 3-D  space, and delineating depositionally and non-depositionally controlled trends not  readily apparent from other methods commonly used in sedimentary geology (e.g.,  facies modeling, geostatistics, and sequence stratigraphy), it becomes an important  tool for sedimentary geologists. We illustrate the techniques and advantages of the approach to  predict 3-D distribution of porosity in stratigraphically complex carbonate buildups  of the Upper Jurassic Smackover Formation at Appleton Field, southwest Alabama. We  predict that porosity is thicker on the forereef flanks than on the crest of  paleostructure.</description><creator>Tebo, Juliana M.</creator><contributor>Hart, Bruce S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>Use of volume-based 3-D seismic attribute analysis to characterize physical property distribution : a case study to delineate reservoir heterogeneity at the Appleton Field, SW Alabama</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sk17b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm62z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fr932</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this thesis were (1) to identify older women's  health priorities for promoting physical, psychological and social well-being; and  (2) to measure the extent to which women perceive that their health priorities are  being met. A qualitative methodology using 3 focus group sessions with 36  community-dwelling women aged 65 year and older was used to elicit older women's  health priorities. Priorities were categorized into three groups: disease-related  priorities, disability-related priorities, and psychosocial-related priorities. A  questionnaire was developed to quantify the extent to which women perceive that  these different priorities are being addressed. The survey was administered to a  convenience sample of 609 community-based women aged 55--93 years (mean age 70 +/- 9  years) attending outpatient medical clinics. Unaddressed disability-related  priorities were most prevalent. Women aged 75 years and older were significantly  less likely to perceive that their priorities were unmet compared to younger mature  women (OR 0.564; 95% confidence interval: 0.387--0.821) when adjusting for other  health and socio-demographic variables. The implications of these findings and  opportunities for improving preventive health care for older women are  discussed.</description><creator>Tannenbaum, Cara</creator><contributor>Mayo, Nancy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Women's Studies.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Gerontology.</subject><title>Women's health priorities in late life : perceived strategies for successful aging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064667c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fr932</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb4949078</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human prostate cancer is one of the most common malignancies  affecting men. It is associated with a high degree of mortality and morbidity due to  the development of non-skeletal and skeletal metastases. A common complication in  patients suffering from prostate cancer is the development of hypercalcemia of  malignancy. While determination of PSA and PSP-94 levels can serve as  diagnostic/prognostic markers, PSP-94 can also serve as a therapeutic agent. The  efficacy of PSP-94 to block tumor progression and hypercalcemia of malignancy was  tested in our syngeneic in vivo rat model of prostate cancer. Rat prostate cancer  Mat Ly Lu cells were transfected with full length cDNA encoding PTHrP [Mat Ly  Lu-PTHrP] which is known to be the main factor responsible for hypercalcemia of  malignancy. Mat Ly Lu-PTHrP cells were inoculated subcutaneously into the right  flank or via intracardiac injection into the left ventricle of male Copenhagen rats.  Animals were treated with different doses of PSP-94. Tumor volume, time of hind-limb  paralysis, plasma calcium and plasma and tumoral PTHrP levels were determined.  PSP-94 caused a significant delay in the development of hind-limb paralysis,  reduction in tumor volume, plasma calcium levels, plasma and tumoral PTHrP levels as  compared to control animals receiving vehicle alone. These effects were due to the  induction of tumor cell apoptosis. In conclusion, our studies illustrate the ability  of PSP-94 to block prostate cancer growth and skeletal metastases.</description><creator>Shukeir, Nicholas</creator><contributor>Rabbani, Shafaat A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Evaluation of prostate secretory protein (PSP-94) as a novel therapeutic agent for blocking prostate cancer progression and hypercalcemia of malignancy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p098g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb4949078</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j161p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The microbial degradation of pyrene, a 4-ring polycyclic  aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH), has been elucidated with the increasing number of  pyrene-degrading bacteria that have been isolated in recent years. A pyrene  degrading bacterium identified as Mycobacterium sp. strain S65, was isolated from a  jet-fuel contaminated site in Sept-Iles, northern Quebec, Canada. S65 utilized  pyrene, phenanthrene, and fluoranthene as sole carbon and energy sources, but did  not degrade naphthalene, anthracene, and fluorene. Pyrene mineralization was  enhanced by adding benz[a]anthracene, benzy[a]pyrene, or phenanthrene as  cosubstrates. When added to PAH contaminated soil as a potential bioaugmentation  agent, S65 did not appear to survive well, nor was it effective at degrading PAHs  under these conditions. Pyrene catabolic genes in S65 were partially characterized by  Southern hybridization using a probe constructed from the naphthalene inducible  pyrene dioxygenase gene, nidA, from the pyrene-degrading bacterium, Mycobacterium  sp. strain PYR-1.</description><creator>Sho, Michiei, 1976-</creator><contributor>Hamel, Chantal (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Greer, Charles W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Mycobacterium.</subject><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Pyrene (Chemical) -- Biodegradation.</subject><subject>Bioremediation.</subject><title>Characterization of pyrene degradation by Mycobacterium sp. strain S65</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm95r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j161p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sq762</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since physical activity is part of a healthy lifestyle, there is  a lot of interest concerning the determinants of this behaviour in youth since it is  tracked into adulthood. Environmental determinants belong to one subset of factors  that influence physical activity. Baseline and one-year follow-up data on level of  physical activity were collected in classroom questionnaires from 1264 7th grade  students (56.2% of eligible students). Physical activity was assessed via an  adaptation of the Weekly Activity Checklist. The effect of a ban on extracurricular  activities on adolescent physical activity levels was determined. Multivariate  logistic regression analyses were used to determine the effect of the ban when  controlling for baseline physical activity, the number of extracurricular activities  regularly offered at the school, and season at baseline. Students attending high  implementation schools were significantly more likely to increase their levels of  physical activity after the ban was lifted, than students in low implementation  schools (odds ratio (OR) = 1.49 (95% CI = 1.16, 1.91) and 2.19 (95% CI = 1.80, 2.67  for boys and girls respectively). These results suggest that a teachers' ban on  sports-related ECAs was associated with a decrease in the PA levels of students  attending secondary schools. The impact was higher among girls than  boys.</description><creator>Pabayo, Roman</creator><contributor>Gray-Donald, Katherine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Exercise -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Student activities -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Physical education and training -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>High school teachers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>The effects of a ban on extracurricular activities by teachers on students' levels of physical activity in the Montreal area /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xx91n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sq762</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494908j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Turnip mosaic potyvirus (TuMV) is a single-stranded RNA plant  virus. One of its proteins, the cylindrical inclusion (CI) protein, was hypothesized  to interfere with host transcription via interaction with histone H3 protein.  Interaction between CI and histone H3 was previously observed in Dr. Fortin's  laboratory. Based on previous studies that demonstrated the importance of the H3  tail domain in gene regulation and chromosome arrangement, it was hypothesized that  CI would interact with the tail rather than the globular domain. The objective of  this project was to identify which histone H3 domains CI protein interacts with. The  full-length, globular, and tail domains of histone H3 DNA were expressed in E. coli  and purified. Based on in vitro interaction experiments, the CI protein was observed  to interact with the globular domain of histone H3.</description><creator>Ozumit, Alen</creator><contributor>Fortin, Marc G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Disease and pest resistance.</subject><subject>Plant-pathogen relationships -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Histones.</subject><subject>Turnip mosaic virus.</subject><title>Interaction between turnip mosaic potyvirus (TuMV) cylindrical inclusion protein and Arabidopsis thaliana histone H3 protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m233x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494908j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924c358</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ilopango Caldera, which is part of the Central American volcanic  arc in El Salvador, is a lake-filled caldera located approximately 10 km east of the  capital city has an eventful history of eruption; the most recent pyroclastic  eruption, known at the Tierra Blanca Joven (TBJ), took place ~1600 years  ago. In 1880 a lava dome was erupted into the center of the caldera lake. The aim of  this study is to understand the nature of Ilopango eruptions, the magmatic evolution  of Ilopango through time and attempt to place Ilopango into a regional context. I  conclude that the intracaldera stratigraphy is mostly subaqueously emplaced and that  the caldera was occupied by a lake &gt;53,000 years ago during formation of the San  Agustin Block unit. The eruption which formed the San Agustin Block unit began with  a phreatomagmatic phase and progressed to a more degassed phase, spalling pumices  from the quenched carapace of the lava dome. The magmatic evolution of Ilopango is  not a progressive magmatic process related to a time factor, but rather reflected by  a reservoir that experiences replenishment of a more mafic composition causing  fluctuations in magma composition over time. Ilopango is less evolved than other  Central American silicic centers such as Atitlan, Amatitlan and Zunil, but is  similar in composition to Santa Maria, Santiaguito and Acantenango.</description><creator>Mann, Crystal P.</creator><contributor>Stix, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Intracaldera geology of the llopango Caldera, El Salvador, Central America</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g469.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c358</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pn544</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nonvalidated practices are characterized by a therapeutic intent  and a relative lack of evidence to support their adoption into the practice of  medicine. They occupy a continuum of progressive departures from the standard of  care, bounded on the one extreme by validated practices and on the other by  research. Presently, nonvalidated practices are performed largely at the discretion  of physicians, and this approach has been justified by appeal to the notions of  professional autonomy and societal beneficence. Current guidelines do not require  any special form of monitoring of nonvalidated practices. However, the principle of  non-maleficence favours the adoption of a novel monitoring system which would assure  the protection of patients and society. This novel monitoring system should be based  on a review which is proportionate, prospective, and primarily local but with an  important national element. As well, such a system should be based largely on the  existing hospital practice committees.</description><creator>Maniatis, Thomas, 1972-</creator><contributor>Glass, Kathleen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Nonvalidated practices : understanding the issues and balancing the risks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z141z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn544</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fr95m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following a departmental expansion, an isocentric cobalt-60  external beam teletheraphy unit was modified to produce a large fixed field for  total body irradiation. The sourcehead was separated from the gantry and installed  at a distance of 251.2 cm from the floor. The collimator was removed and replaced  with a custom built secondary collimator projecting a 277 x 132.6 cm 2 radiation  field at floor level. The work presented in this thesis describes the measurements  performed to bring the unit into clinical use for total body irradiation. A custom  flattening filter was placed below the secondary collimator to flatten the beam to  within +/-3% of the central axis dose as measured at 10 cm in water. Percent depth  dose, tissue-phantom-ratios, surface dose and absolute output were measured in the  radiation field. The effects of inhomogeneities were studied and the thickness of  lead used for lung attenuators was determined. Verification of treatment planning  and delivery was performed with an Alderson-Rando anthropomorphic phantom and showed  dose uniformity within +/-10% of the prescribed dose when a lead attenuator was used  over the lung.</description><creator>Larouche, Renée-Xavière</creator><contributor>Evans, M. D. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Total body photon irradiation with a modified cobalt-60 unit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg09x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fr95m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rh62f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sibutramine is a serotonin-noradrenaline reuptake inhibitor  (SNRI) which has been shown to be a safe and effective weight-loss drug. The purpose  of this study was to examine whether sibutramine has an effect on macronutrient  selection in both female and male rats in addition to total food intake. Wistar rats  of both sexes were divided into three groups and each group was offered a different  set of three diets, each set included a carbohydrate-rich diet, a protein-rich diet  and a fat-rich diet. Sibutramine (10mg/kg) was shown to consistently decrease  carbohydrate and fat intake at all data points regardless of gender and diets. The  effect of sibutramine on protein intake was diet and gender-specific. All doses of  sibutramine decreased total food intake regardless of gender and diet group  beginning at 6-h post-administration. In conclusion, sibutramine affected  macronutrient selection and emphasis on dietary recommendations should be considered  during therapy.</description><creator>LeBlanc, Marisa</creator><contributor>Thibault, Louise (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Rats -- Food.</subject><subject>Sibutramine.</subject><subject>Food preferences.</subject><title>Effect of sibutramine on macronutrient selection in male and female rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t64w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh62f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h36z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Closure of bone defects that do not heal spontaneously require  some form of bone inducing agent in order to ensure complete repair. Autogenous bone  is the clinical gold standard for the management of these types of defects. Present  research is aimed at finding acceptable alternatives to harvesting autogenous bone  grafts in patients for obvious reasons. Recent literature supports that  demineralized bone matrix (DBM) is osteoinductive, although this is not the case for  all commercially available forms of DBM. An in vivo study was conducted which attempted to evaluate the  healing of critical sized defects in New Zealand white rabbit calvarium using  various grafting materials. By combining demineralized bone matrix and a poloxamer  gel carrier, a putty-like material that is surgically convenient can be delivered to  these defects and allowed to heal.</description><creator>Jackson, Michael T., 1969-</creator><contributor>Cloitie, Cameron M. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Assessment of the closure of critical sized defects in the rabbit calvarium utilizing demineralized bone matrix putty as an allogenic graft material</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859g29d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h36z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2685781</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR)  constitutes an ohmic chloride channel, the gating of which is dependent on  cAMP-dependent phosphorylation of a regulatory (R) domain and ATP binding and  hydrolysis by two nucleotide binding domains (NBDs). Previous studies have suggested  that CFTR activation results from PKA phosphorylation of the R-domain, which either  relieves its inhibition of the channel, or induces a positive catalytic effect of  this domain on ATP dependent gating. In this study, the function of the R-domain was  examined using a CFTR variant lacking the entire R-domain. These split channels  assemble from separate polypeptides corresponding to the two halves of CFTR after  translation of a single mRNA. Even though the back half of the split CFTR channel is  expressed as a core glycosylated protein, both halves are able to fold independently  and associate with one another to form a PKA-independent, constitutively active  channel; however, this occurs with low efficiency. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</description><creator>Irvine, Thomas</creator><contributor>Hanrahan, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Studies of split R domain deleted CFTR channels expressed in mammalian cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451j14j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2685781</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b4109</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mouse node is the structural equivalent of Spemann's  Organizer. The transcription factor Foxa2 (HNF3beta) is required for node and  notochord specification and its enhancer has been characterized to a 500bp element  that drives the expression of a reporter gene to the node and notochord in  transgenic embryos. The aim of the study was to identify sequence elements, within  this enhancer, required to drive node/notochord specific-expression. Since, in the  Xenopus organizer, Siamois activates organizer-specific gene expression, it was  tested whether this factor could activate expression from the Foxa2 node-specific  enhancer. Using deletion analysis, the response element was mapped to a 33bp region  and it was shown that this element was both necessary and sufficient for reporter  gene activation by X-Siamois . Furthermore, it was shown that X-Siamois can bind  this DNA element and two sequence motifs required for binding and transactivation by  X-Siamois were identified. Preliminary results suggest that the 33bp element, within  the 500bp enhancer, is required for the maintenance of expression in the notochord  of transgenic mice.</description><creator>Islam, Ayesha</creator><contributor>Clarke, Hugh (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Dufort, Daniel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Transgenic mice.</subject><subject>Notochord.</subject><subject>DNA-binding proteins.</subject><title>Characterization of the Foxa2 node-specific enhancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q957k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b4109</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623d21k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance of the role of halogen chemistry in regulating  tropospheric ozone budgets was revealed in the Arctic Marine Boundary Layer (MBL)  during Polar Sunrise Studies where episodic destructions of ozone were accompanied  by increases in bromine containing compounds. Chlorine chemistry becomes especially  relevant in the tropospheric MBL and in coastal regions due to the existence of  elevated concentrations of chlorine generated from sea-salt aerosols. In this  thesis, the kinetic study of the reactions of seven tropospherically important  hydrocarbons with chlorine atoms was done at atmospheric pressure and 298 &lt; T  &lt; 358 K using a Gas Chromatograph with Flame Ionization Detection. This data  set not only compares well with available literature values but also provides a  first report on several systems for which no temperature dependent kinetic data  existed. Some of these reactions were found to be fast enough to compete with HO  radical chemistry in the MBL. Mass spectral product studies of Cl-initiated  reactions of CHBr2Cl and CHBr3 indicated that halogen atoms could be recycled back  to the atmosphere. The importance of these reactions on the chemistry of the  troposphere is discussed.</description><creator>Garib, Anisha</creator><contributor>Ariya, Parisa A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Chlorine atom initiated reactions of selected hydrocarbons observed in the marine boundary layer : rate constants and potential mechanisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472x08w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d21k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c8164</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The language and communication abilities of a deaf child (15;9)  acquiring American Sign Language (ASL) as his first-language after puberty were  investigated. The participant had been exposed to ASL for approximately three years  at the time of testing. Background information and data concerning the participant's  language and communication skills were collected from his foster parents. Videotaped  language samples were collected in conversational and narrative contexts using  various elicitation devices. Data from the language samples were transcribed and  analyzed with respect to the participant's lexical, morphological, syntactic, and  pragmatic skills. Comparison of the results of these analyses to what is known about  native language acquisition, homesign, and late first-language acquisition revealed  both similarities and differences between the participant and members of each of  these three groups. Contrary to previous claims of dissociations between lexical,  morphological, syntactic, and pragmatic development by late first-language learners,  the participant demonstrated relatively similar abilities across different areas of  language and communication. The theoretical implications of these results, as well  as clinical implications and directions for future research, are  discussed.</description><creator>Gates, Andrea</creator><contributor>Mayberry, Rachel I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Psychology, Developmental.</subject><subject>Language, Linguistics.</subject><title>The effects of delayed first-language exposure on language acquisition : a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jp338.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c8164</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pn56p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:14:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mesial temporal lobe epilepsy is a neurological disorder that is  associated with neuronal death in the hippocampus and in parahippocampal structures  such as the entorhinal and perirhinal cortices. However, clinical and experimental  investigations regarding the function and the contribution of the perirhinal cortex  in epileptogenesis are as yet limited. To determine the network interactions of the  perirhinal cortex and the entorhinal cortex in ictogenesis, my investigations were  conducted in the combined hippocampus-entorhinal-perirhinal slice preparation.  Sliced were superfused with either 4-aminopyridine or Mg2+-free artificial  cerebrospinal fluid to generate in vitro epileptiform activity. In these experiments  I demonstrated alternating sites of initiation of epileptiform activity within the  parahippocampus, as well as, preferential ictal initiation within the perirhinal  cortex. In addition, ictal duration in the perirhinal cortex did not change  following physical separation of the three limbic structures, while it decreased in  the lateral and medial entorhinal cortices. My results suggest the perirhinal cortex  is potentially epileptogenic as indicated by its propensity for initiating ictal  events and its ability to generate ictal activity of similar size after isolation.  This evidence indicates that all parahippocampal networks analyzed in this study can  generate epileptiform synchronization that sustains limbic seizures.</description><creator>De Guzman, Philip Henry</creator><contributor>Avoli, Massimo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Interactions between neuronal networks in the entorhinal and perirhinal cortices electrographic seizures in vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gn91r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn56p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>