<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:06:06Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4150" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fk358</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Early auditory stimulation is essential for normal central auditory system maturation and language acquisition. Nevertheless, hearing loss is a widespread problem among young children, which might is associated with poor auditory intelligence and academic performance despite the alleviation of the hearing loss.  Objectives: ●Create and validate an animal model for reversible hearing loss.●Investigate the long-term impact of transient early-life deafness on the central auditory processing.●Investigate the potential usefulness of dark rearing and noise exposure on theto promote recovery of auditory functions from early-life deafness.Methods: A new technique of external auditory canal ligation and reopening was is described. Auditory brainstem responses evaluation waswere used to measure both the degree of hearing loss induced by the external auditory canal ligation and the hearing levelauditory thresholds post following the hearing restoration reopening procedure. One control and four experiment groups were designed included to study the impact of early-life deafness and the potential usefulness of different interventions on recovery. Electrophysiological responses to auditory stimulation were recorded from the primary auditory cortices cortex in all groups.Results: External auditory canal ligation and reopening procedures revealed had success rates of 81% and 78%, respectively. The average hearing threshold dropped by 40 decibels, with more greater hearing loss in thefor high frequencies.An Uunder-representation of high frequency sounds and altered electrophysiological responses to sound stimuli were results consequences of early-life deafness and were shown to persisted despite  following hearing restoration. While dark rearing had failed to stimulate recovery, the noise exposure group was found to reinstated a normal frequency distribution and central auditory processing within the primary auditory cortex.Conclusion: Early-life deafness has a long-term impact on the central auditory processing. Visual deprivation post failed to aid in recovery of function following hearing restoration failed to stimulate recovery. Continuous noise exposure, however, showed  promising benefits for recovery. The mechanisms underlying this improvement remain unknown, showed the best signs of recovery form early-life deafness for which the pathophysiology in unknown and further studies are recommended. </description><description>Introduction: La simulation auditive est essentiel pour le développement normal du système auditif central ainsi que sa maturation et l'acquisition du langage. Malheureusement les pertes auditives sont fréquentes chez les jeunes enfants et sont associés à des problèmes auditifs ainsi que des problèmes scolaires même après que la surdité a été traité.Objectifs:•Créer et valider un modèle animal de la surdité réversible.•Étudier l'impact à long terme d'une déficience auditive sur le fonctionnement auditive central.•Étudier l'impact de l'élevage dans l'obscurité et dans le bruit sur la fonction auditive après une surdité précoce.Méthodes: Une nouvelle technique a été développer pour ligaturer d'une manière réversible et pour plus tard rouvrir le conduit auditif externe. Les potentiels évoqués auditive du tronc cérébral ont été étudié afin de vérifier le niveau de surdité attend par la ligature du conduit auditif externe avant et après la réouverture du conduit. Un groupe contrôle et quatre groupes expérimentaux ont été inclus dans cette étude sur la surdité a un bas âge et le potentiel de différentes interventions à pallier à ses ravages à long terme. Des mesures électrophysiologies ont été prises aux niveau du cortex cérébral auditive de chaque groupe. Résultats: La ligature et la réouverture du conduit auditif externe avait un taux de succès de 81 % et de 78 % respectivement. Les seuils auditifs ont diminué de 40 dB avec la ligature. Nous avons noté une atteinte plus importante dans les hautes fréquences.Nous avons observé une sous-représentation des hautes fréquences et une altérations électrophysiologique de réponse au son comme conséquence de surdité induite à un jeune âge. Elles ont persisté même après la réouverture du conduit. L'Élevage dans l'obscurité n'a pas aidé. Par contre, l'exposition au bruit continue a eu comme résultat une redistribution vers la normale dans le cortex auditive.Conclusion: Exposition un bruit continue à démontrer certaines promesses. Le mécanisme de cette amélioration demeure inconnu et plus d'études seront nécessaires.</description><creator>Alkhateeb, Ahmed</creator><contributor>Anthony G Zeitouni (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Etienne De Villers-Sidani (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery</subject><title>Impact of early reversible deafness and cross-modal interactions on adult central auditory processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h190t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fk358</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d98r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une des pires épidémies de santé du XXIe siècle est le Diabetes Mellitus, caractérisé par la destruction des cellules β productrices d'insuline. L'inflammation, en particulier les cytokines pro-inflammatoires, jouer un rôle clé dans l'initiation et la progression de la mort des cellules β. Le but de notre recherche est de développer une nouvelle approche pour préserver et accroître la masse des cellules β pancréatiques. Cette thèse étudie la capacité protectrice des cellules β de deux protéines candidates: (i) Islet Neogenesis Associated Protein (INGAP), co-découverte par le Dr Rosenberg comme la première molécule néogénique inversant le diabète dans les modèles animaux en régénérant les cellules β productrices d'insuline (son peptide bioactif dérivé, INGAP-P, est actuellement en phase 2 d'essais cliniques); et (ii) une protéine de fusion, initialement conçue à McGill par le Dr Schneider, composée d'un anticorps monocaténaire spécifique de cellules β (SCA-B1) fusionné avec un peptide inhibiteur de NF-κB (NBD) qui protège les souris contre le diabète induit par streptozotocin.Hypothèse: En plus de ses propriétés néogènes, l'INGAP protège les cellules β contre la mort de cellules induite par les cytokines en inhibant la signalisation induite par ces cytokines; cet effet peut être encore amélioré en combinant un traitement avec l'inhibiteur NF-κB, β-spécifique, SCA-B1-NBD.Le prétraitement avec la protéine INGAP recombinante entière (rINGAP) et INGAP-P a partiellement inhibé la cytotoxicité induite par les cytokines, amélioré la viabilité, réduit les niveaux de NO et a aussi réduit l'apoptose induite par les cytokines. Alors que les deux molécules permettent la survie des cellules β, le rINGAP semble être un agent cytoprotecteur plus puissant et plus durable que l'INGAP-P. L'analyse des événements de signalisation a révélé que l'INGAP bloque partiellement l'apoptose induite par les cytokines en inhibant la signalisation de NF-κB, en diminuant la phosphorylation de p65, IκBα et le complexe de kinase IKK. L'inhibition induite par INGAP de la signalisation de NF-κB a été suivie par une expression diminuée de sa cible aval, l'expression du gène NOS2 et de son produit génique, la protéine iNOS. Nos données suggèrent également que rINGAP a inhibé la phosphorylation de p65 induite par les cytokines de manière dépendante et indépendante de l'IKK. rINGAP a partiellement inhibé d'autres voies de signalisation impliquées dans la régulation de iNOS - activation réduite de JAK2 et STAT3, JNK et p38. Enfin, le traitement par les cytokines a induit une phosphorylation précoce de l'AKT qui a diminué avec le temps. Le prétraitement par rINGAP a partiellement inhibé les effets induits par les cytokines sur l'AKT.Nous avons généré et purifié avec succès le SCA-B1-NBD et validé sa fonctionnalité selon: (i) la liaison spécifique aux cellules β et (ii) l'inhibition partielle de la signalisation de NF-κB dans les lignées cellulaires RINm5F et INS-1 ainsi que dans les ilots humains. Le prétraitement avec SCA-B1-NBD a amélioré la viabilité, réduit l'expression de NOS2 induite par les cytokines, de la protéine iNOS et des niveaux de NO et inhibé partiellement l'apoptose en diminuant l'activation de la caspase-3 et de la PARP. Le co-traitement des lignées cellulaires avec INGAP et SCA-B1-NBD a montré des effets additifs minimaux contre la mort des cellules β induite par les cytokines. Les effets positifs limités de ce traitement combinatoire pourraient s'expliquer en partie par le fait que les deux protéines affectent la même voie de signalisation, NF-κB. Des études additionnelles, y compris l'expérimentation avec le temps de l'administration et la posologie in vitro de chaque médicament ainsi que des modèles in vivo de diabète nécessitant à la fois des interventions régénératrices et anti-apoptotiques, sont nécessaires pour conclure avec certitude si ce régime combinatoire est efficace contre le diabète.</description><description>One of the most challenging health epidemics facing the 21st century is Diabetes Mellitus, characterized by destruction of the insulin-producing β-cells. Inflammation, in particular pro-inflammatory cytokines, plays a key role in initiation and progression of β-cell death. The goal of our research is to develop a novel approach to preserve and expand the pancreatic β-cell mass. This PhD thesis investigates the β-cell protective capacity of two candidate proteins: (i) Islet Neogenesis Associated Protein (INGAP), co-discovered by Dr. Rosenberg as the first neogenic molecule to reverse diabetes by regenerating insulin-producing β-cells (a derived bioactive peptide, INGAP-P, is currently in phase 2 clinical trials); and (ii) a fusion protein, originally engineered at McGill by Dr. Schneider, made up of a β-cell specific single-chain antibody (SCA-B1) fused with an NF-κB inhibitor peptide (NBD) that has been shown to protect mice from streptozotocin-induced diabetes. Hypothesis: In addition to its neogenic properties, INGAP protects β-cells against cytokine-induced cell death by inhibiting cytokine-induced signaling; this effect can be further enhanced by combinatorial treatment with the β-specific NF-κB inhibitor, SCA-B1-NBD. Pre-treatment with recombinant full-length protein INGAP (rINGAP) and INGAP-P partially inhibited cytokine-mediated cytotoxicity, improved viability, reduced NO levels, as well as cytokine-induced apoptosis. While both molecules conferred survival to β-cells, rINGAP appeared to be a more potent and longer-lasting cytoprotective agent compared to INGAP-P. Analysis of signaling events revealed that INGAP partially blocks cytokine-induced apoptosis by inhibiting NF-κB signaling, decreasing phosphorylation of p65, IκBα and kinase complex IKK. INGAP-mediated inhibition of NF-κB signaling was followed by decreased expression of its downstream target, NOS2 gene expression and its gene product, iNOS protein. Our data suggest that rINGAP inhibited cytokine-induced p65 phosphorylation in an IKK-dependent and independent manner. rINGAP partially inhibited other signaling pathways implicated in regulation of iNOS – reduced activation of JAK2 and STAT3, JNK and p38. Finally, cytokine treatment induced early AKT phosphorylation which decreased over time. rINGAP pre-treatment partially inhibited cytokine-mediated effects on AKT.We successfully expressed and purified SCA-B1-NBD and validated its functionality as per: (i) binding β-cells specifically and (ii) partially inhibiting the NF-κB signaling pathway in RINm5F and INS-1 cell lines as well as in human islets. Pre-treatment with SCA-B1-NBD improved viability, reduced cytokine-induced NOS2 expression, iNOS protein and NO levels and partially inhibited apoptosis by decreasing activation of caspase-3 and PARP. Co-treatment of the cell lines with INGAP and SCA-B1-NBD exhibited minimal additive effects against cytokine-induced β-cell death. The limited augmented effects of this combinatorial treatment could be explained in part by the fact that both proteins affect the same signaling pathway, NF-κB. Additional studies, including experimentation with timing and dosage of in vitro administration of each drug as well as in vivo models of diabetes requiring both regenerative and anti-apoptotic interventions, are necessary in order to confidently conclude whether this combinatorial regimen is effective against diabetes.This is the first time INGAP has been shown to protect β-cells against cytokines and to inhibit NF-κB signaling. These studies have broadened our current understanding of INGAP-mediated effects as well as provided novel insight into its anti-apoptotic potential and the underlying intracellular signaling mechanisms. Additionally, successful production and validation of β-cell specific SCA-B1-NBD protective effects have laid the necessary foundation for future in vitro and in vivo studies on pancreatic β-cell mass preservation.</description><creator>Nano, Eni</creator><contributor>Lawrence Rosenberg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Protecting pancreatic b-cells against cytokines: novel function of islet neogenesis associated protein (INGAP) and combinatorial treatment with NF-kB inhibitor SCA-B1-NBD</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q3808.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d98r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xb90b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'éducation physique inclusive (EPI) suggère que les étudiants en situation de handicap (ESH) participent à l'éducation physique générale avec leurs pairs, tout en recevant le soutien supplémentaire nécessaire. Des recherches antérieures au niveau international ont révélé que les croyances sur l'inclusion des futurs enseignants en éducation physique et de la santé (FEEPS) étaient influencées par la perception de leur compétence, leur préparation académique et leur expérience avec les personnes en situation de handicap, leur sexe, et leur niveau académique. Le but de cette étude était d'explorer les perceptions de FEEPS sur l'EPI afin d'acquérir une nouvelle compréhension de l'EPI. La question de recherche primaire de cette étude était la suivante: Qu'elle est la perception des FEEPS à propos de l'EPI pendant leur formation universitaire en enseignement? Cette étude de cas qualitative a consisté en des entrevues semi-structurées avec six femmes et trois hommes de quatrième année et récemment diplômés en FEEPS. Chaque entrevue a été enregistrée avec un enregistrement sonore afin que les données puissent être transcrites textuellement pour ensuite en faire une analyse thématique. Les cinq thèmes suivants ont ressortis de l'analyse des données:  «Le programme de formation des enseignants en éducation physique et de la santé (PFEEPS)», «Les expériences sur le terrain», «Les expériences avec les personnes en situation de handicap", «Les perceptions des étudiants en situation de handicap», et «Les perspectives sur L'éducation physique inclusive». Les FEEPS ont discuté de l'impact de leurs expériences de terrain (ETs), du programme PFEEPS et de leurs expériences antérieures en dehors du programme PFEEPS sur leur perception sur l'inclusion. Certaines constatations qui étaient propres à cette étude incluaient les expériences des participants avec leur enseignant formateur sur leurs ETs, la capacité des participants à identifier les ESH lors de leurs ETs et l'utilisation des techniques d'enseignement par les participants lors de l'enseignement des ESH. Cette étude rehausse la littérature de recherche sur ce sujet car l'exploration des expériences vécues et les perceptions des FEEPS ont aidé à identifier les lacunes dans les pratiques d'EPI actuelles et à développer de nouvelles perspectives sur l'EPI. Des pistes de recherche futures sont incluses dans la conclusion de cette thèse.</description><description>Inclusive physical education (IPE) suggests students with disabilities (SwD) participate in general physical education with their peers, with any additional support needed. Previous international research found that physical and health education student teachers' (PHE-STs) beliefs on inclusion were influenced by their perceived competence, academic preparation and experience with people with disabilities, gender and academic year. The purpose of this study was to explore PHE-STs' perceptions about IPE in order to gain a novel understanding of IPE. The central research question of this study was: What do PHE-STs perceive about IPE during university teacher training? This qualitative case study consisted of semi-structured interviews with six female and three male fourth-year and recently graduated PHE-STs. Each interview was audio-recorded so data could be transcribed verbatim for a thematic analysis to be conducted. The following five themes emerged through the data analysis: "The physical and health education teacher education program (PHETE)", "Field experiences", "Experiences with people with disabilities", "Perceptions about students with disabilities", and "Perspectives about inclusive physical education". PHE-STs discussed the impact of their field experiences (FEs), the PHETE program, and their prior experiences with SwD outside of the PHETE program on their perceptions about inclusion. Some findings that were unique to this study included participants' experience with their co-operating teacher on their FEs, ability to identify SwD on their FEs, and use of teaching techniques when instructing SwD. This study adds to the research literature because the exploration of PHE-STs' lived experiences and perceptions about IPE helped to identify gaps in current IPE practices and develop new perspectives about IPE. Future research directions are provided at the conclusion of the thesis.</description><creator>Cere, Susanna</creator><contributor>William James Harvey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>The perceptions of physical and health education student teachers about inclusive physical education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z31q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb90b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967604t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les souvenirs autobiographiques sont nos souvenirs conscients d'expériences personnelles passées, dont la récupération est un processus cognitif fondamentalement reconstructif. Cela nous permet de nous rappeler d'un souvenir en se concentrant sur les éléments contextuels, ou alternativement, les éléments conceptuels de l'événement. L'objectif de cette thèse est de décrire les dissociations neuronales de ces différentes façons de se souvenir en utilisant l'imagerie par résonance magnétique fonctionnelle (IRMf). Pour cet objectif, nous avons demandé à 24 participants de se rappeler de leurs mémoires autobiographiques dans deux conditions expérimentales. Dans la condition conceptuelle, la récupération de la mémoire était basée sur la construction d'une représentation mentale de l'évènement à un niveau conceptuel. Dans la condition contextuelle, cette représentation mentale était ancrée dans les éléments spatiaux spécifiques de l'évènement. Trois approches analytiques ont été prises. Tout d'abord, nous avons examiné l'activité neuronale dans tout le cerveau afin d'identifier les régions impliquées dans la mémoire autobiographique. Par la suite, une analyse par région d'intérêt a été effectuée afin d'explorer ces activations dans les lobes temporaux médiaux et l'hippocampe. Finalement, une analyse de connectivité fonctionnelle a été menée pour déterminer si les différences entre nos conditions sont reflétées dans les patrons de connectivité de l'hippocampe avec le reste du cerveau. Premièrement, nos analyses ont indiqué la présence de patrons d'activité neuronale spécifiques à chacune de nos conditions expérimentales. En effet, l'activité cérébrale était plus diffuse pour la condition conceptuelle et plus localisée pour la condition conceptuelle. Dans le cas de l'hippocampe, nos résultats ont partiellement soutenu cette dissociation. En tant que tel, l'hippocampe postérieur soutient préférentiellement la récupération des éléments contextuels d'une mémoire. Enfin, nos analyses de connectivité ont montré que l'hippocampe antérieur joue un rôle essentiel dans l'orchestration des différents processus cognitifs nécessaires qui sont recrutés pour soutenir la récupération des mémoires autobiographiques. Nos résultats sont interprétés dans le cadre de la théorie du traitement par composante de la mémoire autobiographique.</description><description>Autobiographical memories are our conscious recollections of past personal experiences, the retrieval of which is a fundamentally reconstructive process. This allows for a memory to be recalled by focusing on the contextual, or alternatively, the conceptual elements of the event. The aim of this thesis is to characterize the neural dissociations of these distinct ways of remembering by using functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI). To this end, 24 participants recalled autobiographical memories under two conditions. A conceptual condition instructed participants to build a mental representation of the remembered event by focusing on the overall theme of the event. A contextual condition, instructed participants to build a mental representation of the event anchored in the spatial elements of the event. Three analytic approaches were taken: (1) neural activity was contrasted across the whole brain, (2) a region of interest approach was taken to explore these contrasts in the medial temporal lobes and the hippocampus, and (3) a functional connectivity analysis was used to investigate whether condition differences are reflected in the hippocampus' connectivity patterns. First, our analyses revealed a dissociable pattern of neural activity associated with the remembering conditions. This pattern was more diffuse for the conceptual condition and more localized for the conceptual condition. Within the hippocampus, partial support was found for this dissociation with the posterior hippocampus preferentially supporting the retrieval of contextual elements of an event. Lastly, our connectivity analyses showed that the anterior hippocampus has a privileged role in orchestrating the different components needed to retrieve memories. These results are interpreted within the framework of component process models of autobiographical memory.</description><creator>Gurguryan, Lauri</creator><contributor>Signy Sheldon (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Assembling the past from concepts and contexts: the neural mechanisms that support alternate ways of recalling autobiographical memories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pz40j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967604t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj64s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>People who experience homelessness and have mental illness are at increased risk of involvement with the criminal justice system that comes at significant personal, social and economic cost. While there is strong evidence that Housing First increases residential stability, the literature suggests that Housing First does not, on average, have any impact on justice outcomes. This thesis seeks to explore if this absence of impact is due to a heterogenous intervention effect, both in terms of profiles of criminal justice involvement and in terms of the nature of the offense, using data from the multisite randomized controlled trial At Home/Chez soi. In a prior paper, we empirically identified five profiles: Non/Infrequent Offenders (very few offences, but some single violent offences), Moderate Offenders (higher mean number of offences, longest duration of homelessness), Antisocial Offenders (highest means of violent and nuisance offences), Versatile Subsistence Offenders (highest mean of all offences and highest means of subsistence-related offences – e.g., theft), and Drug Offenders (highest mean number of drug-related offences). The first manuscript explores whether the absence of impact of Housing First on criminal charges overall was due to heterogenous intervention effects. The Risk-Needs-Responsivity model of offender rehabilitation suggests that individuals with certain risk factors of criminal justice involvement would be more likely to experience a reduction in criminal justice involvement as a result of Housing First, while others could experience an increase. For example, people for whom offending is in part driven by poverty and homelessness (Moderate Offenders) or by substance abuse (Drug Offenders) before coming into the program would be more likely to experience a reduction in offending as a result of increased residential stability and a harm reduction approach to substance abuse than Antisocial Offenders and Versatile Subsistence Offenders, whose criminogenic needs might not be addressed as part of the intervention. For these profiles, the intervention could even have a deleterious effect. Results showed that the impact of Housing First on violent charges differs by profiles. Moderate and Drug Offenders were more likely to experience fewer charges for violent crimes from Housing First (-0.40 [95% CI: -0.70, -0.10] and -0.53 [95% CI: -1.01, -0.05] new charges over two years, respectively). There was no impact of Housing First on subsistence charges and charges related to the administration of justice for any profile.The second manuscript assessed, first, the association between CJI profiles and days stably housed as well as costs. Second, it tested whether the effect of Housing First and its net benefit differed according to profile. On average, controlling for group assignment and other variables, Antisocial Offenders spent 48 fewer nights annually (95% CI: -72.1, -23.0) in stable housing than Non/Infrequent Offenders. Versatile Subsistence and Moderate Offenders engendered greater costs (1.33 [95% CI: 1.11, 1.59] and 1.21 [95% CI: 1.07, 1.36] times, respectively). However, the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of the intervention did not differ by profile. Findings suggest that Housing First, when provided to homeless individuals with mental illness who have an ongoing risk of offending, may need to target the criminogenic needs of the participants in order to observe an overall reduction in criminal justice involvement. Future research could, for example, develop and test voluntary adjunctive interventions for specific groups of offenders who want to reduce their criminal justice behaviour. However, neither the effectiveness, in terms of residential stability, nor the cost-effectiveness of Housing First compared to usual services varied by profile. Our findings suggest that there is no ground for selective admission into Housing First programs based on criminal history.</description><description>Les personnes en situation d'itinérance vivant avec une maladie mentale sont plus à risque de judiciarisation, ce qui entraîne d'importants coûts personnels, sociaux et économiques. Bien que Logement d'abord augmente la stabilité résidentielle, la littérature suggère que l'intervention n'a pas d'impact, en moyenne, sur la judiciarisation. Ce mémoire cherche à explorer si cela ne serait pas dû à une hétérogénéité de l'effet de l'intervention, à la fois en termes de profils de judiciarisation et de nature des délits, en utilisant les données de l'essai randomisé Chez Soi. Dans un manuscrit précédent, nous avons identifié cinq profils de judiciarisation: peu ou pas de criminalité (individus ayant peu ou pas de délits, certains ayant un délit violent); criminalité modérée (individus ayant un plus grand nombre de délits, ayant vécu une plus longe période d'itinérance); criminalité antisociale (individus ayant des délits violents ou de nuisance); criminalité versatile (individus ayant des délits liés à la subsistance et qui ont une criminalité variée); criminalité liée aux drogues. Le premier manuscrit explore la possibilité qu'aucun impact globalement de Logement d'abord sur les mises en accusation n'ait été identifié à cause d'effets hétérogènes de l'intervention. Le modèle du risque, des besoins et de la responsivité suggère que les personnes dont le comportement criminel est en partie motivé par la pauvreté et l'itinérance (criminalité modérée) ou par l'abus de substance (criminalité liée aux drogues) pourraient connaître une réduction du nombre de mises en accusation grâce à une augmentation de la stabilité résidentielle ou grâce à l'approche de réduction des méfaits par rapport à l'abus de substance. Les individus dont les facteurs de risque plus complexes ne sont pas ciblés dans le cadre de l'intervention pourraient ne pas connaître une telle réduction, voire même connaître une augmentation. Les résultats montrent que l'impact de Logement d'abord sur les mises en accusation pour crimes violents diffère selon le profil. Les participants avec une criminalité modérée et ceux avec une criminalité liées aux drogues connaissaient une réduction des mises en accusation pour crimes violents grâce à Logement d'abord (-0.40 [95% CI: -0.70, -0.10] et -0.53 [95% CI: -1.01, -0.05] nouvelles mises en accusation sur deux ans). Il n'y avait pas d'impact de Logement d'abord sur les crimes liés à la subsistance ou liés à l'administration de la justice.Le deuxième manuscrit mesure en premier lieu l'association entre les profils et les jours en logement stable ainsi que les coûts. En deuxième lieu, il teste si l'efficacité et la coût-efficacité de Logement d'abord varie selon le profil. En moyenne, les participants avec une criminalité antisociale ont passé 48 jours de moins en logement stable que les participants avec peu ou pas de criminalité (95% CI : -72.1, -23.0). Les participants avec une criminalité versatile ou modérée entraînent des coûts totaux plus élevés (1.33 [95% CI: 1.11, 1.59] et 1.21 [95% CI: 1.07, 1.36] fois, respectivement). Le profil n'avait pas d'influence sur l'efficacité ou la coût-efficacité de l'intervention.Les résultats suggèrent que Logement d'abord, lorsqu'offert aux personnes itinérantes ayant une maladie mentale et qui sont à risque de judiciarisation, devrait cibler les besoins criminogènes des participants afin d'observer une réduction globale de la judiciarisation. Les futurs projets de recherche sur Logement d'abord pourraient développer et évaluer des services complémentaires offerts sur une base volontaire pour certains groupes de personnes souhaitant réduire leur comportement criminel. Nos résultats suggèrent que l'efficacité, en termes de stabilité résidentielle, et la coût-efficacité de Logement d'abord comparé aux services habituels ne varient toutefois pas en fonction des profils. Selon nos résultats, il n'y a pas raison de restreindre l'accessibilité au programme sur la base de la judiciarisation.</description><creator>Leclair, Marichelle</creator><contributor>Eric A Latimer (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Anne Crocker (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</subject><title>Impact of criminal justice involvement profiles on the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of Housing First among homeless people with mental illness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs834.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj64s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj66m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Antibody microarrays enable multiplexed protein detection with minimal reagent consumption, and although quality appears adequate when characterized using local replicates, they continue to be plagued by lack of reproducibility. Chemically-functionalized glass slides are the foundation of antibody microarrays, yet spatial inhomogeneity and its effect on assay variability has not been analyzed. Here, we (i) characterize spatial bias in antibody microarrays by measuring signal variation across the surface of 5 commercial slide models, and (ii) develop an experimental approach to minimize bias and optimize assay reproducibility. We used PBS and the 2 optimal buffers (among 28) for each slide to print 3 different antibodies as 9 overlapping arrays across the slide. The fluorescence for antibody immobilization and assay signal of 5 different slide models was used to generate 270 heatmaps characterizing the spatial bias and variability, which varied significantly across models. We then compared reproducibility measures obtained with local, random, and structured random replicates; local replicates poorly estimated the whole-slide mean signal and gave misleading CV values up to 7 times less than the 'true' whole-slide CV, while structured random replicates distributed throughout the slide gave the most accurate estimates. When using a slide model with low spatial bias, assays achieved good intra-slide CV of 7.3% and inter-slide of 6.3%. Our results highlight spatial bias as an underappreciated source of variability and the inadequacy of commonly used local replicates in assessing assay performance, leading us to recommend the use of distributed replicates to ensure reproducibility of antibody microarray results.</description><description>Les biopuces d'anticorps permettent la détection multiplexée de protéines avec consommation minimale de réactifs, et bien que leur qualité paraisse adéquate lorsqu'elles sont caractérisées à l'aide de répétitions locales, elles continuent d'être atteintes d'un manque de reproductibilité. Les lames de verre fonctionnalisées chimiquement constituent le fondement des biopuces d'anticorps, mais l'inhomogénéité spatiale et son impact sur la variabilité de ces tests immunologiques n'ont pas été analysés. Dans ce travail, nous (i) caractérisons le biais spatial des biopuces d'anticorps en mesurant la variation du signal à la surface de cinq modèles de lames de verre commerciales, et (ii) nous développons une approche expérimentale pour minimiser le biais et optimiser la reproductibilité du test immunologique. Nous avons utilisé du PBS et deux solutions tampons optimales (parmi 28) pour chaque lame afin d'imprimer trois anticorps différents, créant neuf biopuces superposées à la surface des lames. Les signaux fluorescents associés à l'immobilisation des anticorps et au test immunologique menés sur cinq modèles de lames ont été utilisés pour générer 270 cartes thermiques qui caractérisent le biais spatial et la variabilité, lesquels diffèrent significativement d'un modèle de lame à l'autre. Nous avons ensuite comparé la reproductibilité obtenue avec des répétitions locales, aléatoires, et aléatoires-structurées; les répétitions locales ont mal estimé les « vraies » valeurs de la moyenne et du CV de la lame complète et ont produit des valeurs de CV trompeuses, jusqu'à 7 fois inférieures aux « vraies » valeurs, tandis que les répétitions aléatoires-structurées ont produit les estimations les plus précises. En utilisant un modèle de lame avec un biais spatial faible, nous avons mesuré la concentration d'une protéine avec une biopuce d'anticorps et obtenu un bon CV intra-lame de 7,3 % et inter-lame de 6,3 %. Nos résultats mettent en évidence que le biais spatial est une source de variabilité sous-estimée et que les répétitions locales sont insuffisantes pour mesurer la performance des tests immunologiques, ce qui nous mène à suggérer l'utilisation de répétitions distribuées pour assurer la reproductibilité des résultats de biopuces d'anticorps.</description><creator>Normandeau, Frédéric</creator><contributor>David Juncker (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Slide spatial bias in antibody microarrays: from characterization to minimization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps85p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj66m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q381j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dams across North America are coming to the end of their planned lifespans and are increasingly being considered for removal, which would significantly change river ecology and hydrology and the provision of ecosystem services. Such changes affect stakeholders differently, according to their uses, values and perceptions of ecosystem services. Understanding these impacts is necessary for effective and equitable decision making concerning dam removal, and for conflict resolution. The aims of this thesis were to analyse social demand for ecosystem services and its contribution to stakeholder conflict, and explore options for conflict resolution.A conceptual framework was developed to link ecosystem services and conflict from a wider range of angles than has been studied to date. The focus was on social demand for ecosystem services, rather than their biophysical provision or economic valuation, as the aspect most relevant to stakeholders and the least studied. Frame theory was used to analyse stakeholders' perceptions of dam removal and how differences between them contributed to conflict. The strategic implications of how the decision-making process was framed using scale were explored. Place meanings were used to explore the emotional dimensions of the conflict. Such theories on stakeholder conflict have not been applied to the context of dam removal. The framework was applied to a decision-making process around the Mactaquac Dam on the Saint John River, New Brunswick, Canada, which was being considered for removal at the time of study. Study of dam removals has been limited to small dams to date – as a large dam, this was an important test case for other similar dams. A qualitative approach was used to explore the full range of ecosystem services used and how they related to conflict. Fifty stakeholders participated, who represented a range of interests and were located both up and downstream of the dam. Semi-structured interviews were used to explore how they used the river and their opinions on the future of the dam. Participatory mapping was then used to reveal the spatial distribution of ecosystem service demand and place meanings.Stakeholders used a range of ecosystem services. Although there were few differences in the services used by those who preferred to retain the dam and those who preferred to remove it, there were clear differences in how they used the same services and in their spatial distribution. Participatory mapping was used for the first time to test whether stakeholders could map ecosystem services under future scenarios. Although few could map ecosystem services if the dam were removed, the process was useful to uncover perceptions of change and its causes.Stakeholders' use of ecosystem services informed their frames of the dam, river and decision-making process. Their frames showed loss aversion, being less willing to experience a loss than give up a potential gain. Those in favour of removal framed the decision using spatial and temporal scales differently to those against, in ways that deemed certain arguments and stakeholders as being relevant to the decision and others irrelevant. The temporal scale was newly revealed as important in scale framing in this context. Stakeholders held numerous intangible place meanings, suggesting a strong connection to specific locations in the area, many of which were shared between the two groups.The study found that a range of ecosystem services were locally important and would be affected if the dam were removed. Theories of stakeholder conflict revealed that differing demand for services contributed to conflict, but also offered opportunities for its resolution. There was widespread agreement about the importance of ecosystem protection and many shared place meanings. Participatory approaches centred around ecological protection and shared place meanings have the potential to allow stakeholders to build trust and to manage conflict.</description><description>Le démantèlement des barrages à la fin de leur vie opérationnelle est de plus en plus considéré, ce qui modifierait l'écologie et l'hydrologie de la rivière et la prestation de services écosystémiques. De tels changements affectent des intervenants différemment selon ses besoins, valeurs et perceptions des services écosystémiques. Pour une prise de décision et une résolution de conflits efficaces et équitables, il est nécessaire de comprendre ces effets. Les objectifs de cette thèse furent d'analyser la demande sociale pour les services écosystémiques et sa contribution aux conflits, et en quelle mesure elle peut servir à leur résolution. Un cadre conceptuel fut développé qui lie les services écosystémiques au conflit. Plutôt que l'apport biophysique ou l'évaluation économique des services, le cadre fut axé sur sa demande sociale, soit l'aspect le moins étudié. Une théorie de l'encadrement permit d'analyser des perceptions des intervenants quant à la décision et de leur contribution au conflit. Une exploration se fit des implications stratégiques du cadrage de la décision au niveau de son échelle et des mérites des lieux. Ces théories n'ont jamais été appliquées dans le contexte du démantèlement de barrages. Ce cadre servit à sonder un processus décisionnel du barrage Mactaquac sur le fleuve Saint-Jean au Nouveau-Brunswick, Canada. Lors de l'étude, son démantèlement potentiel a été envisagé, ce qui représente un important cas type pour d'autres grands barrages. Une approche qualitative offre un survol de l'étendue complète des services écosystémiques en demande et de leur rapport au conflit. 50 intervenants participèrent, qui étaient représentatifs d'un vaste éventail d'intérêts et qui étaient issus d'en amont et d'en aval du barrage. Des entrevues semi-structurées servirent à étudier les utilisations de la rivière des intervenants, ainsi que leurs opinions quant à l'avenir du barrage. Une cartographie participative révéla la répartition spatiale des demandes en services écosystémiques et les mérites des lieux. Les intervenants ont exigé une large gamme de services écosystémiques. Quoiqu'il n'y eût que très peu de différences dans les services demandés par les groupes pour et contre le démantèlement du barrage, des différences existaient entre leurs utilisations de ces services et la répartition spatiale de ceux-ci. Leur habileté à cartographier les services écosystémiques sous divers scénarios éventuels fut testée ici pour la première fois. Peu d'intervenants s'avéraient capables d'identifier les lieux éventuels des services écosystémiques et pourtant le processus révéla les perceptions du changement potentiel et de ses causes. Grâce aux informations tirées de leurs utilisations des services écosystémiques, les intervenants ont pu encadrer son état présent et le processus de prise de décision. Ils ont montré une aversion aux pertes, c'est-à-dire que ces individus étaient moins disposés à subir une perte que de renoncer à un gain éventuel. Les deux groupes ont employé des différentes échelles spatio-temporelles pour encadrer leurs décisions, ce qui influence des arguments et des individus considérés comme pertinents et non à la décision. Les intervenants tenaient à plusieurs valeurs intangibles données aux lieux, suggérant un fort lien à certains endroits dans ou près de la rivière, dont plusieurs étaient partagées par les deux groupes. Cette étude démontra qu'un éventail de services écosystémiques est important. Le démantèlement du barrage affecterait la qualité et la nature des services. Les théories des conflits ont souligné le fait que la divergence des demandes de service à favoriser le développement du conflit. L'analyse souligna un consensus quant à la protection des écosystèmes et révéla les nombreuses valeurs communes aux lieux. Des approches participatives centrées sur la protection écologique et des mérites des lieux peuvent permettre d'instaurer la confiance et de résoudre des conflits.</description><creator>Reilly, Kate</creator><contributor>Jan Adamowski (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>The role of ecosystem services in conflicts over potential dam removal - the case of the Mactaquac Dam, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n3471.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q381j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483m47d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although visual areas hMT+ and hV4 are considered to have segregated functions for the processing of motion and form within the dorsal and ventral processing streams, respectively, more recent evidence favors a degree of functional overlap between regions. Here we use fMRI-guided, online rTMS to test two associated hypotheses: that ventral area hV4 is causally involved in the perception of motion and dorsal area hMT+ in the perception of static form. We use four variations of a common global stimulus to test performance on two dynamic motion-based tasks and two static form-based tasks for stimuli presented in both the ipsilateral and contralateral visual fields. We find that rTMS to both hMT+ and hV4 significantly impairs direction discrimination and causes a perceptual slowing of motion, implicating hV4 in motion perception. Stimulation of hMT+, however, produces bilateral impairments affecting both visual fields, demonstrating that area hMT+ has a bilateral visual field representation for motion-based tasks and that both functional hMT+s are needed for optimal motion performance. For the second hypothesis, we find that stimulation of hV4 significantly reduces perceived contrast of a static stimulus. hMT+ stimulation also produces an effect, implicating dorsal areas in static contrast perception. Taken together, our findings suggest a less rigid functional segregation between hMT+ and hV4 than previously thought and contribute to a re-evaluation of dorsal-ventral functional segregation as a general rule in visual perception.</description><description>Bien que les aires visuelles hMT+ et hV4 soient considérées avoir des fonctions ségrégées pour le traitement du mouvement et de la forme, respectivement au sein des voies dorsale et ventrale de traitement, des découvertes récentes suggèrent un recouvrement entre les fonctions de ces régions. Nous utilisons de la SMTr en ligne guidée par neuronavigation IRMf pour tester deux hypothèses associées: que l'aire ventrale hV4 est causalement impliquée dans la perception du mouvement et l'aire dorsale hMT+ dans celle des formes statiques. Nous utilisons quatre variantes d'un stimulus global commun pour tester la performance sur deux tâches basées sur le mouvement dynamique et deux tâches basées sur la forme avec des stimuli présentés dans les champs visuels ipsilatéral et controlatéral. Nous trouvons que la SMTr de hMT+ et hV4 compromet significativement la discrimination de direction et cause un ralentissement perceptif du mouvement, impliquant hV4 dans la perception du mouvement. La stimulation de hMT+, cependant, produit des déficits bilatéraux affectant les deux champs visuels, démontrant que l'aire hMT+ a une représentation bilatérale du champ visuel pour les tâches basées sur le mouvement et que le fonctionnement des deux hMT+ est requis pour une performance optimale sur le mouvement. Pour la seconde hypothèse, nous trouvons que la stimulation de hV4 réduit significativement le contraste perçu d'un stimulus statique. La stimulation de hMT+ produit également un effet, impliquant les aires dorsales dans la perception du contraste statique. Ensembles, nos résultats suggèrent une ségrégation entre hMT+ et hV4 moins rigide que supposée jusqu'alors et contribuent à une réévaluation de la ségrégation fonctionnelle dorsale-ventrale comme règle générale en perception visuelle.</description><creator>Cohen, Daniel</creator><contributor>Kathleen T Mullen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Evaluating hMT+ and hV4 functional connectivity using fMRI-guided repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g65g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483m47d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289m311</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>LGBTQ+ individuals face an array of challenges to physical activity participation, such as discrimination and exclusion. The purpose of this thesis was to gain an understanding of diverse LGBTQ+ experiences within physical activity. The research program represented by this thesis employed a mixed-methodology and was composed of two distinct studies. The first was a qualitative study in which we explored LGBTQ+ individuals' experiences with physical activity through eight focus group discussions (N = 42). Using a semi-structured interview guide, participants were encouraged to broadly discuss their personal physical activity experiences. All focus groups were audio-recorded, transcribed verbatim, and subject to thematic analysis. Three main themes emerged: (a) intersectionality within physical activity - an intersectional approach is required to explore the complexity of LGBTQ+ experiences within physical activity, (b) the contested concept of "athlete" - LGBTQ+ communities have unique conceptions associated with "athlete" that can render sport, and by extension physical activity contexts as elitist and inaccessible, and (c) "a safe space for us" - LGBTQ+ friendly physical activity practices should be explored to provide practical suggestions for inclusivity. These three resulting themes were interpreted as significant research considerations that were used to inform the second study in this thesis. Given that the majority of participants in study 1 spoke about specific instances of LGBTQ+ minority stress within physical activity contexts, study 2 was designed to explore the relationship between LGBTQ+ minority stress and motivation to participate in physical activity. Study 2 proposed a theoretical model to better understand LGBTQ+ experiences in physical activity, that explored whether LGBTQ+ minority stressors, as indicators of the social-environmental context, would relate to the basic psychological needs—motivation—physical activity pathway, as per self-determination theory. An online cross-sectional survey was completed by 798 self-identifying LGBTQ+ adults. Structural equation modelling analyses suggest that LGBTQ+ minority stressors are statistically significantly and negatively related to need satisfaction within physical activity, which in turn is related to lower levels of motivation and physical activity. Together these two studies provide a novel, in-depth exploration of how diverse LGBTQ+ experiences, specifically LGBTQ+ minority stressors, influence experiences within physical activity contexts. </description><description>Les personnes LGBTQ + font face à un éventail de défis à la participation à l'activité physique, tels que la discrimination et l'exclusion. Le but de cette thèse était de comprendre les différentes expériences LGBTQ + dans l'activité physique. Le programme de recherche représenté par cette thèse utilisait une méthodologie mixte et était composé de deux études distinctes. La première était une étude qualitative dans laquelle nous avons exploré les expériences des personnes LGBTQ + en matière d'activité physique au moyen de huit discussions de groupe (N = 42). À l'aide d'un guide d'entrevue semi-structuré, les participants ont été encouragés à discuter largement de leurs expériences personnelles d'activité physique. Tous les groupes de discussion ont été enregistrés, retranscrits textuellement et soumis à une analyse thématique. Trois thèmes principaux ont émergé: (a) l'intersectionalité dans l'activité physique - une approche intersectionnelle est requise pour explorer la complexité des expériences LGBTQ + dans l'activité physique, (b) le concept contesté d '«athlète» - les communautés LGBTQ + ont des conceptions uniques associées à «athlète» (c) «un espace sûr pour nous» - les pratiques d'activités physiques amicales LGBTQ + devraient être explorées pour fournir des suggestions pratiques pour l'inclusivité. Ces trois thèmes résultants ont été interprétés comme des considérations de recherche importantes qui ont été utilisées pour éclairer la deuxième étude dans cette thèse. Étant donné que la majorité des participants à l'étude 1 parlaient de cas particuliers de stress LGBTQ + minoritaire dans des contextes d'activité physique, l'étude 2 visait à explorer la relation entre le stress minoritaire LGBTQ + et la motivation à participer à l'activité physique. L'étude 2 a proposé un modèle théorique pour mieux comprendre les expériences LGBTQ + dans l'activité physique, explorant si les facteurs de stress minoritaires LGBTQ +, en tant qu'indicateurs du contexte socio-environnemental, se rapporteraient aux besoins psychologiques fondamentaux - motivation - activité physique, selon l'autodétermination théorie. Une enquête transversale en ligne a été menée auprès de 798 adultes LGBTQ + auto-identifiés. Les analyses de modélisation des équations structurelles suggèrent que les facteurs de stress minoritaires LGBTQ + sont statistiquement significativement et négativement liés à la satisfaction des besoins dans l'activité physique, qui est elle-même liée à des niveaux inférieurs de motivation et d'activité physique. Ensemble, ces deux études offrent une exploration inédite et approfondie de la façon dont les diverses expériences LGBTQ +, en particulier les facteurs de stress minoritaires LGBTQ +, influencent les expériences dans les contextes d'activité physique.</description><creator>Herrick, Shannon</creator><contributor>Lindsay Duncan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>An examination of physical activity participation among LGBTQ+ adults through the integrated perspective of self-determination theory and the minority stress model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps86z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m311</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p94f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les récents efforts en matière de justice internationale pénale ont accordé une attention croissante aux victimes de crimes internationaux. Toutefois, le droit international s'intéresse aux victimes depuis sans doute beaucoup plus longtemps. Ce qui est nouveau, c'est la tentative de formaliser et de légaliser le statut des victimes, ainsi que les dilemmes que cela suscite. Par ailleurs, il ne s'agit pas simplement d'octroyer aux victimes certains droits en droit international pénal, mais de leur garantir un statut. Dans ce cadre, le droit international doit constamment arbitrer les dilemmes complexes ayant trait à la nature fondamentale de la qualité de victime. Nait dès lors la notion de victime idéale. L'enfantement de la qualité de victime par le droit international participe sans doute de l'autoréalisation du droit international lui-même. Dans la présente thèse, nous examinerons quelques-uns des critères sous-tendant la qualité de victime retenus dans l'histoire du droit international et analyserons la manière dont la poursuite de cette démarche pourrait être maitrisée davantage afin de parvenir à une meilleure compréhension de la nature évolutive du droit international. La désignation des victimes en droit international et en droit international pénal demeure une entreprise complexe et à forte tonalité idéologique.</description><description>There has been an increase in the attention paid to victims of international crimes in the context of recent efforts made in the field of international criminal justice. However, international law's attention to victims is arguably much older. What is new, is the attempt to formalize and legalize the status of victims and the ensuing dilemmas that arise. Moreover, it is clearly not simply the case that international criminal law grants victims' certain rights. Rather, in the process of granting such rights, international criminal law constitutes victims. In doing so, international law is required to constantly arbitrate the complex dilemma surrounding the fundamental nature of victimhood. A certain 'ideal victim' is thereby produced. The production of victimhood through international law is arguably part of the self-constitution of international law. This thesis will investigate some of the ways in which victimhood has been produced in the history of international law, and how the continuation of that process can be harnessed to better understand the evolving nature of international law. Thus, this thesis argues that the production of victimhood in international law and international criminal law remains a fraught and ideologically loaded process. </description><creator>Akenroye, Ayodele</creator><contributor>Frederic Jean Megret (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Law</subject><title>The pursuit of international criminal justice and the construction of victimhood</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd482.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p94f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t156j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La sclérose en plaque (SP) est une maladie inflammatoire chronique, neurodégénérative et liée à une perte de gaines de myéline dans le système nerveux central (SNC). Les astrocytes jouent un rôle conventionnel dans la SP en étant impliqués dans la formation de la cicatrice gliale durant les dernières étapes de la pathologie. De plus, les astrocytes interagissent non seulement avec leur environnement glial mais aussi avec les cellules du système immunitaire et leur implication dans le développement des lésions lors des premiers stades de la maladie est reconnue par l'ensemble de la communauté scientifique. Dans notre étude, nous avons mesuré l'expression d'un ensemble de microARNs (miARNs) qui sont reliés aux fonctions essentielles des astrocytes dans des coupes de cerveaux de patients SP et avons comparé ces résultats aux cerveaux de patients contrôles. Nous avons pu mettre en évidence une différence dans l'expression de miARNs entre ces deux groupes. En effet, nous avons démontré une augmentation de l'expression de miARNs, associés à une ischémie, dans les lésions actives de la matière blanche et une faible expression de miARNs inflammatoires dans les lésions SP. Les miARNs apparentés à la neuroprotection et à la régulation de la barrière hémato-encéphalique ont aussi été altérés. Certaines expressions miARNs ont démontré une tendance au retour à un niveau normal dans les régions des lésions inactives. De plus, nous avons pu mettre en évidence l'effet à long terme de l'interleukine-1β (IL-1β) sur l'expression des miARNs dans les astrocytes primaire de foetus humains. En conclusion, nos observations nous apportent une meilleure illustration du rôle des astrocytes dans la SP et de leur réponse en situations de dommages et inflammation.</description><description>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a chronic inflammatory, neurodegenerative demyelinating disease of the central nervous system (CNS). The conventional role of astrocytes in MS is the formation of glial scar in the later stage of the pathology, but their interaction with other glial and immune cells as well as their involvement in the lesion development in the early pathology are also recognized nowadays. In our study, we measured the expression of a set of miRNAs (microRNAs) related to multiple astrocyte functions in astrocytes from brain sections of MS patients and compared them with those from normal controls. We found a differential expression of miRNAs between MS patients and normal controls. An upregulation of ischemic-related miRNAs in active lesions from white matter and a low expression of inflammatory-related miRNAs in MS lesions were observed. MiRNAs thought to be involved in neuroprotection and in regulation of the blood brain barrier were also altered. The overall miRNA expression also showed a tendency for several miRNAs to return to normal levels in inactive lesions. In addition, we demonstrated the long term effect of interleukin-1β (IL-1β) on miRNA expression in primary human fetal astrocytes. In summary, these findings may help us illustrate the roles of astrocytes in MS and how they respond to injury and inflammation.</description><creator>Fuh, Shih-Chieh</creator><contributor>Jack P Antel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Astrocyte miRNA profiling in multiple sclerosis and normal human brains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3460.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t156j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773z039</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La depression majeure est un trouble mental qui affecte 300 millions d'individus et représente la première cause d'invalidité dans le monde. La survenue de la dépression est fortement précipitée par les expériences de vie aversives pendant le développement, en particulier la maltraitance infantile, qui augmente de façon considérable le risque de suicide. Bien que notre groupe de recherche ait précédemment caractérisé les altérations cellulaires et moléculaires de la matière blanche corticale frontale associées à la dépression et la maltraitance infantile, les effets de ces deux facteurs dans la matière blanche sous corticale, en particulier les faisceaux associatifs tel que le faisceau inciné sont inconnus. Ce dernier est un faisceau cortico-limbique impliqué dans la mémoire et les comportements socio-émotionnels dont la maturation, de façon intéressante, n'est atteinte qu'au cours de la troisième décennie après la naissance. Cette maturation particulièrement tardif pourrait rendre le faisceau inciné plus sensible aux effets de la maltraitance infantile. En effet, de nombreuses études d'imagerie ont mis en évidence que l'intégrité de la matière blanche du faisceau inciné est altérée chez les individus souffrant de dépression et les victimes de maltraitance infantile. Nous avons étudié l'organisation cellulaire et moléculaire du faisceau inciné en mesurant l'expression de gènes et de protéines constitutives de la myéline ainsi que la morphologie et densité des oligodendrocytes ausein d'échantillons cérébraux humains postmortem. Nos résultats indiquent que les altérations présentes dans la matière blanche corticale (en particulier dans le cortex cingulaire antérieur et préfrontal ventromedian) ne sont pas observées dans le faisceau inciné, suggérant qu'un historique de maltraitance infantile est associé à des changements spécifiques à certaines régions de la matière blanche cérébrale.</description><description>Major depressive disorder (MDD) is a mental illness that affects over 300 million people globally, making it the largest cause of disability worldwide. Suicide is significantly associated with depression and the majority of people who die by suicide have been diagnosed with depression. In addition, early life adversity, such as child abuse (CA), is also strongly associated with the manifestation of depressive symptoms and an increased risk for suicide.While our group has previously characterized cellular, transcriptional, and anatomical alterations associated with CA in frontal cortical white matter, it remains unknown if subcortical white matter, found in white matter association tracts, displays similar deficits. One such association tract is the uncinate fasciculus (UF), a corticolimbic tract implicated in memory and socioemotional processing; interestingly, this tract only reaches full maturity in the third decade of life and this protracted development may make the UF differentially vulnerable to MDD or CA. Indeed, many brain imaging studies have shown that white matter integrity is impaired in the UF of MDD patients and people with a history of CA.We investigated the cellular and molecular organization of the UF by examining the expression of myelin-constituent mRNA and proteins, as well as the morphology and cell density of oligodendrocyte-lineage cells in post-mortem UF tissue. We found that the subcortical white matter of the UF displays none of the cellular or molecular abnormalities that we had previously uncovered in anterior cingulate cortex (ACC) and ventromedial prefrontal cortex (vmPFC) white matter. Our results suggest that a history of CA is not associated with global changes in white matter throughout the brain, and that different white matter areas display very different oligodendrocyte development and myelin-constituent protein expression patterns in the context of CA.</description><creator>Kim, John</creator><contributor>Naguib Mechawar (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>A post-mortem analysis of the uncinate fasciculus in depressed suicides with a history of child abuse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g738q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773z039</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698980m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le micro-usinage au laser femtoseconde (fs) est une méthode de texturation de surface sans contact qui peut créer des structures à rugosité hiérarchique (micrométrique et nanométrique à la fois). Tandis que les structures induites par les lasers fs ont été amplement étudiées sur les métaux, très peu de publications se sont intéressées à leur formation sur les surfaces de polymères. Récemment, il a été démontré que l'irradiation fs d'une surface de poly(tétrafluoroethylène) entraîne la formation d'une structure poreuse de grande surface. Une telle structure peut être avantageuse dans plusieurs applications comme les matériaux auto-nettoyants et les implants biomédicaux. Cependant, on ne sait pas si cette structure est reproductible sur d'autres polymères. D'autant plus que ni ses propriétés optiques et chimiques ni le mécanisme de sa production ne sont encore connues. Par conséquent, dans cette thèse, un travail détaillé d'investigation et de caractérisation a été accompli sur les structures induites par laser fs sur les surfaces polymériques.    En ajustant plusieurs modèles d'absorption aux données d'ablation, on a constaté que la formation de structures poreuses se produit à la suite d'une ébullition explosive et dépend du seuil de fluence aux conditions d'usinage. En ce qui concerne les polymères ayant un seuil élevé de fluence, une petite partie de l'énergie entrante est convertie en ionisation du matériau. Donc, la couche de surface en fusion chauffe au-delà de la température critique de l'ébullition explosive causant une nucléation homogène de bulles. Le refroidissement rapide de la couche en fusion entre deux impulsions consécutives entraîne la formation de pores qui correspondent au volume occupé par les bulles durant l'ébullition explosive. La caractérisation par spectroscopie UV-VIS et photo électronique par rayons X à deux longueurs d'ondes différentes a permis d'identifier les paramètres qui affectent le seuil de fluence à travers les effets d'incubation. Des seuils de fluence plus élevés et des coefficients d'incubation plus bas ont été observés durant l'irradiation infrarouge en comparaison avec l'irradiation ultraviolette. Ce comportement durant l'irradiation infrarouge a été attribué à la transition d'une absorption multiphoton pour un nombre réduit d'impulsions à une absorption linéaire pour un nombre élevé d'impulsions. On a constaté que cet effet était plus prononcé pour les polymères susceptibles de photo-oxydation. L'ébullition explosive a été mise en évidence grâce à une étude cristallographique par diffractométrie de rayons X à incidence rasante. Avec du poly(éthylène) de haute densité, le micro usinage laser a provoqué la baisse locale du niveau de cristallinité et l'apparition d'une phase monoclinique qui n'est habituellement stable qu'à haute température et pression élevée. Cela a confirmé que les structures produites par le laser fs se forment à partir d'une couche en fusion rapidement refroidie. De plus, nous avons étudié l'effet des propriétés viscoélastiques du polymère en fusion sur la taille des pores. Nous avons constaté qu'avec de plus grandes masses moléculaires (et donc des viscosités plus élevées), on obtient des pores de plus petite taille à cause de la diminution de la vitesse de croissance des bulles durant l'ébullition explosive.Enfin, une nouvelle technique de dépôt par ablation laser à impulsions a été conçue pour incorporer des nanoparticules à l'intérieur des structures poreuses.  Grâce à cette technique, de l'oxyde de titane hydrophile a été incorporé dans du poly(téréphthalate d'éthylène) poreux. En contrôlant l'étendue de la couverture de la surface par les nanoparticules au moyen de la fluence, la mouillabilité de la surface a pu être contrôlée. Par conséquent, cette technique permet l'optimisation des structures induites par laser fs pour des applications spécifiques sans compromettre la topologie poreuse.  </description><description>Femtosecond (fs) laser micromachining is a single-step, contactless surface texturing method which can create hierarchical structures that present both micro- and nanoscale roughness. While fs laser-induced structures have been extensively studied on metals, very few publications have investigated their formation on polymer surfaces. It has recently been shown that homogeneous fs irradiation of a poly(tetrafluoroethylene) surface leads to the formation of a high surface area porous structure. Such a structure could be highly beneficial for several applications such as self-cleaning materials and biomedical implants. However, as of yet, no basis for the optimization of this novel topology exists since its optical and chemical properties and the mechanism behind its formation have not been investigated. Thus, in this thesis, a detailed investigation and characterization of femtosecond laser-induced structures on polymer surfaces was performed.By fitting several absorption models to ablation data, porous structure formation was determined to form as a consequence of explosive boiling and was observed to depend on the threshold fluence at machining conditions. For polymers with a sufficiently high threshold fluence, a minority of the incoming energy is converted into material ionization. Thus, the surface melt layer heats above the critical temperature for phase explosion and homogeneous bubble formation occurs. The quenching of the melt layer in between consecutive pulses leads to the formation of pores which are a remnant of the volume occupied by the bubbles during explosive boiling. Spectroscopy and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy characterization at different wavelengths helped identify the parameters that affect the threshold fluence through incubation effects. Higher threshold fluences and lower incubation coefficients were observed during near-infrared irradiation as opposed to ultraviolet irradiation. This behavior at longer wavelengths was attributed to a shift from a multiphoton absorption mechanism at low pulse numbers to a linear absorption mechanism at higher pulse numbers. This effect was observed to be more significant for polymers that are susceptible to photooxidation.Crystallographic evidence of explosive boiling was measured by grazing incidence X-ray diffractometry. For high density poly(ethylene), laser micromachining was observed to induce a local decrease in crystallinity and the appearance of a monoclinic phase that is typically only stable at high temperatures and pressure. This confirmed that fs laser-induced polymer structures form from a quenched melt layer. In addition, the effect of viscoelastic melt properties on pore size was investigated. It was observed that for higher molecular weights (and thus higher viscosities), smaller pore sizes are achieved due to a decreased bubble growth rate during explosive boiling.Finally, a novel atmospheric pulsed laser deposition setup for the incorporation of nanoparticles into laser induced porous structures was developed. Through this technique, hydrophilic titanium oxide nanoclusters were incorporated into porous poly(ethylene terephthalate). By controlling the extent of nanoparticle coverage through the operating fluence, tunable wettability was achieved. Thus, this technique allows the optimization of fs laser induced structures for specific applications without compromising the porous topology.</description><creator>Assaf, Youssef</creator><contributor>Anne-Marie Kietzig (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Femtosecond laser micromachining of polymer surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj628.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698980m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698981w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les systèmes sensoriels ont évolué pour encoder de façon optimale les stimuli trouvés dans l'environnement naturel. Afin de parvenir à ce codage optimal, les stratégies de codage neuronal dans des nombreux systèmes sensoriels ont été adaptées aux statistiques de la scène naturelle pour coder efficacement les stimuli sensoriels. Ainsi, les neurones au sein des systèmes sensoriels doivent effectuer des nombreux calculs complexes de façon concertée pour donner naissance à ce que nous percevons comme le monde extérieur. Dans cette thèse, j'ai étudié comment les neurones sensoriels primaires du cerveau postérieur codent et traitent les stimuli sensoriels de 2eme ordre naturels chez les poissons faiblement électriques. Ces neurones, appelés cellules pyramidales dans la région du cerveau postérieur, lobe de ligne latérale électrosensoriel (ELL), reçoivent une multitude d'informations provenant à la fois du feedforward et du feedback. Utilisant une combinaison d'électrophysiologie extracellulaire, de pharmacologie et de paradigmes comportementaux, les résultats de cette thèse démontrent que le poisson faiblement électrique utilise un circuit complexe d'entrées neuromodulatrices, ce qui donne lieu à une stratégie de codage optimale qui code efficacement la scène naturelle de 2eme ordre statistiques qu'ils rencontrent dans leur environnement.</description><description>Sensory systems have evolved to optimally encode stimuli found in the natural environment. In order to achieve this optimal coding, neural coding strategies in many sensory systems have been adapted to the natural scene statistics to efficiently encode sensory stimuli. Thus, neurons within sensory systems must perform numerous complex computations in a concerted manner in order to give rise to what we perceive as the external world. In this thesis, I studied how primary sensory neurons in the hindbrain encode and process natural second-order sensory stimuli in the weakly-electric fish. These neurons, known as pyramidal cells, in the hindbrain area, electrosensory lateral line lobe (ELL), receive a multitude of inputs from both feedforward and feedback and it is unknown to date how these neuromodulatory inputs integrate to determine neural coding and behavioural perception. Using a combination of extracellular electrophysiology, pharmacology, and behavioural paradigms, the results from this thesis demonstrate that the weakly-electric fish utilizes a complex circuitry of neuromodulatory inputs, which gives rise to an optimal coding strategy which efficiently encodes the second-order natural scene statistics they experience in their environment.</description><creator>Huang, Chengjie</creator><contributor>Maurice Chacron (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Physiology</subject><title>Neuromodulatory inputs generate and optimize neural responses and behavioural perception to second-order natural sensory stimuli</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf05w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698981w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77ss161</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Afin d'assurer leur survie, les cellules doivent être capables de s'adapter à une myriade de forces mécaniques. Elles y arrivent en maintenant les forces les affectants dans un état d'homéostasie dynamique leur conférant un certain degré de stabilité structurelle et est souvent décrite sous l'égide du mot-valise tenségrité. Lorsque qu'une cellule est endommagée, sa tenségrité est interrompue, menant à une augmentation transitoire de la tension autours du dommage cellulaire. La cellule endommagée se doit donc de réparer les dommages faits à sa membrane plasmidique et à son cytosquelette. La réparation du cytosquelette est orchestrée par l'activité coordonné de RhoA et de Cdc42 qui régule la formation et la contraction d'un anneau d'actomyosine se formant autour de la "plaie" cellulaire. La formation de cet anneau est reconnu de dépendre principalement del'influx de calcium et les changements de composition lipidique de la membrane plasmidique qui accompagnent les dommages cellulaires. En revanche, la présence d'une possible relation entre les changements dynamiques de tension ayant lieux au site de dommages cellulaires et la réparation cellulaire médiée par la formation et la contraction d'un anneau d'actomyosine reste entièrement inexplorée.Hypothèse: L'augmentation de la tension locale transitoire aux sites de dommage cellulaire est nécessaire pour la réparation cellulaire médiée par la formation et la contraction d'anneau actomyosine.Méthodes: Afin de diminuer les changements dynamiques de tension ayant lieux au site de dommages cellulaires, des ovocytes de Xenopus laevis furent incubés dans des milieux de cultures hypertoniques. L'efficacité de ces traitements fut ensuite confirmée en mesurant le module d'élasticité (module de Young) des ovocytes traités et d'ovocytes contrôles par microindentation. L'impact de la diminution de la tension sur la réparation cellulaire et la formation d'anneaux d'actomyosine fut ensuite directement évaluée par microscopie confocale. Les niveaux de RhoA, de Cdc42 furent également évalués par le biais d'immunotransferts (western blots) et d'immunoprécipitations.Résultats: Tel qu'attendu, les ovocytes incubés dans les milieux hypertoniques avaient des modules d'élasticités nettement plus bas que les ovocytes contrôles, ce qui serait compatible avec une diminution de la tension cellulaire dans ces ovocytes. Parallèlement, les ovocytes incubés dans les milieux hypertoniques montraient de sévères lacunes en ce qui concerne la réparation du cytosquelette et avaient des diminutions notables dans l'enrichissement d'actine et de RhoA actif en périphérie des plaies cellulaires. En revanche, l'accumulation de Cdc42 actif autour de la plaie était inchangée. Nos résultats d'immunotransferts et d'immunoprécipitations ont également révélés la présence de niveaux réduits de RhoA actif et des niveaux accrus de Cdc42 actif dans les extraits d'ovocytes incubés dans les milieux hypertoniques. Conclusions: La présence d'une augmentation transitoire de tension locale aux sites de dommage cellulaire est nécessaire pour la réparation cellulaire médiée par la formation et la contraction d'anneau d'actomyosine.</description><description>Introduction: Living cells need to respond to a myriad of mechanical forces for their continued survival and function. This is rendered possible by the cell's ability to maintain homeostasis of its own structural and tensile stability, referred to as tensegrity. When a cell is wounded, this homeostasis is compromised in the form of transient tension increase at the wound site. To restore cellular tensegrity after wounding, cells must repair the damage done to its plasma membrane and cytoskeleton. Cytoskeletal repair through its reorganization is controlled by activities of Rho GTPases RhoA and Cdc42 which regulate the formation and contraction of an actomyosin ring around the wound. Recruitment of these Rho GTPases are recognized to depend on Ca2+ influx and the dynamic changes in plasma membrane lipid domains that occurs upon wounding. However, the effect of the changes in cell-wide and local tension arising from the wound damage on the regulation of actomyosin-mediated wound healing has yet to be thoroughly explored.Hypothesis: Transient local tension increase is necessary for actomyosin-mediated wound healing.Methods: To decrease wound-induced tension dynamics at the local wound site, Xenopus laevis oocytes were incubated in hyperosmotic sucrose media of various concentrations. This cell tension decrease was confirmed through comparative measurements of oocyte Young's moduli via microindentation. Cell tension reduction's influence on actomyosin ring regulation was then observed by time lapse confocal microscopy. RhoA and Cdc42 activity levels were also analyzed in western blot and pulldown assays.Results: Dose-dependent decrease in Young's moduli was confirmed in sucrose media-incubated oocytes. Sucrose-treated oocytes were observed to heal wounds more slowly, with decreased wound peripheral enrichment of actin and active RhoA. In contrast, active Cdc42 accumulation around the wound was unchanged. At the cell-wide level, decreased levels of active RhoA and increased levels of active Cdc42 were observed in sucrose-treated oocytes.Conclusions: The cell's Rho GTPase regulation of its actomyosin-mediated wound healing response requires transient cell tension increase at the local wound site.</description><creator>Kato, Tatsuya</creator><contributor>Craig A. Mandato (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Anatomy and Cell Biology</subject><title>Tension change of «Xenopus laevis» oocytes influences Rho GTPase regulation of wound healing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nb118.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77ss161</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff22n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Essential elements are required for the proper functioning of the human body and are critical to growth and development. Dried blood spots (DBS), capillary blood collected on specialized filter paper by pricking an individual's finger or heel, are a minimally invasive and cost-effective alternative to venipuncture for multi-element analysis. Nutritional assessments using DBS can help overcome logistical challenges faced by researchers, particularly in terms of data collection efforts in resource-limited regions and newborn screening programs. Although previous studies have used DBS for elemental measurements, technological and practical hurdles remain, such as detection limits and sample volume requirements. In addition, there is currently no widely accepted standard method of analysis.Objectives: The primary objective of this research was to develop a method for quantifying select essential elements (copper, selenium and zinc) in DBS using Total Reflection X-Ray Fluorescence Spectroscopy (TXRF) and apply this method to a cohort of newborns from the Michigan BioTrust for Health Program. Methods: The study was conducted in two phases. In Phase 1, method development and validation was established using human whole blood standard reference material (SRM) of known elemental concentrations from the Institut National de Santé Publique du Québec (INSPQ; n=7). The selected protocol on 3mm diameter DBS sub-samples was subsequently used in Phase 2 to analyze essential elements in sub-sampled human DBS from a cohort of newborns from the Michigan BioTrust for Health Project (n=675). Three of the SRMs were selected for inter-assay accuracy (n=38 batches) and precision analysis. The generalized extreme studentized deviate (ESD) test was applied to detect outliers in the cohort. Descriptive statistics, accuracy and precision measures were first calculated, followed by Student's t-tests and one-way analysis of variance (ANOVA) to measure inter-assay variation, variation in punch type and storage temperature. All analyses were conducted using JMP®Pro 13.0.0 and Microsoft Excel 15.4.Results: Accuracy was measured by comparing TXRF DBS concentrations to corresponding whole blood SRM concentrations. Accuracy (mean±SD) for triplicate measurements of copper (Cu), selenium (Se), and zinc (Zn) using a 3mm diameter SRM DBS sub-sample were 99.5±3.4%, 100.2±6.9%, 102.6±4.4%, respectively. Accuracy of the selected SRMs (n=3) analyzed in the Michigan BioTrust Cohort for Cu was 107.8 ± 16.3%, 93.7 ± 14.2% for Se, and 109.0 ± 15.7%for Zn. The coefficient of variation, a measure of precision, of the SRMs across all batches was 13.3% for Cu, 17.3% for Se, and 13.7% for Zn. The Michigan BioTrust Cohort population values for Cu, Se, and Zn in the DBS were 1018.1 ± 269.9 mg/L, 241.0 ±58.2 mg/L, and 4250.0 ±1314.9 mg/L, respectively. High concentrations and high variability of Cu, 818.0 ± 1413.9 g/L, and Zn, 2005.3 ± 1622.2 g/L, were detected in the blank filter paper and are a barrier to quantitative analysis of DBS. Implications: These results imply that elemental analysis of DBS using TXRF provide a semi-quantitative method for measuring select essential elements in sub-sampled DBS. The values obtained are for Cu and Se are comparable to human adult population reference values whereas the Zn values are lower, reflecting physiologically lower Zn concentrations in newborns. Given present limitations in the quantitative analysis of DBS, this method has the potential to be used as a screening tool in the evaluation of essential elements in nutritional research, overcoming many of the challenges associated with venipuncture and current analytical methods–potentially leading to informed health policies and interventions.</description><description>Introduction: Les éléments essentiels sont exigés pour le bon fonctionnement du corps humain. Les taches de sang séchées (DBS), soit du sang capillaire sur du papier filtre spécialisé, sont obtenues en piquant le doigt ou le talon d'un individu. Cette technique est une alternative à la fois peu envahissante et rentable au prélèvement sanguin pour l'analyse multiéléments. Des évaluations nutritionnelles utilisant DBS peuvent aider à surmonter les défis logistiques auxquelles sont confrontés les chercheurs, notamment en termes d'efforts requis pour la collecte de données dans les régions à moyen limitées et les programmes de dépistage pour les nouveau-nés. Bien que des études précédentes aient utilisé DBS pour des mesures d'éléments, des obstacles technologiques et pratiques tels que des limites de détection et d'échantillonnent persistent. Il n'y a présentement pas de méthode standard d'analyse acceptée universellement.Objectifs: L'objectif est de développer une méthode pour quantifier certains éléments essentiels (le cuivre, le sélénium et le zinc) qu'on retrouve dans les DBS en utilisant la Spectroscopie à Fluorescence X à Réflexion Totale (TXRF) et de l'appliquer sur les DBS d'une cohorte de nouveau-nés du Michigan BioTrust.Méthodes: Dans la phase 1, le développement et la validation de la méthode ont été établis en utilisant la norme de sang entier (SRM) dont la concentration des éléments est connues par l'Institut National de Santé Publique du Québec (INSPQ; n=7). Dans la phase 2, le protocole choisi dans la phase 1 soit, le protocole avec les DBS d'un diamètre de 3mm, a été utilise sur des échantillons DBS d'une cohorte de nouveau-nés du Michigan BioTrust (n=675) afin d'analyser la concentration des éléments essentiels. Trois des SRMs ont été choisis pour mesurer l'exactitude entre les lots (n=38 lots) et la précision. Le test « generalized extreme studentized deviate (ESD) » a été appliqué pour détecter des valeurs atypiques dans la cohorte. Des statistiques descriptives suivi par le t-test de l'étudiant et une analyse de variance a un facteur. Toutes les analyses ont été effectués en utilisant JMP ® Pro 13.0.0 et Microsoft Excel 15.4.Résultats: L'exactitude a été mesurée en comparant les résultats du niveaux de concentration du TXRF DBS au concentration du sang entier correspondant SRM. L'exactitude (moyenne ± écart type) pour les mesures de cuivre (Cu), sélénium (Se) et zinc (Zn)  en utilisant un SRM DBS de 3mm de diamètre était de 99.5±3.4 %, 100.2±6.9 %, 102.6±4.4 %, respectivement. L'exactitude des SRMs sélectionnés (n=3) analysés au "Michigan BioTrust Cohorte" était de 107.8 ± 16.3% pour le Cu, 93.7 ± 14.2% pour le Se, and 109.0 ± 15.7% pour le Zn. Les coefficients de variation, une mesure de précision du SRM à travers tous les lots, était de 13.3 % pour le Cu, 17.3 % pour le Se et 13.7 % pour le Zn. Les résultats pour la population de « Michigan BioTrust Cohorte » pour le Cu, Se et Zn dans les DBS était de 1018.1 ± 269.9 mg/L, 241.0 ±58.2 mg/L et 4250.0 ±1314.9 mg/L, respectivement. Des hautes concentrations et des grandes variabilités de Cu (818.0 ± 1413.9 µ G/L) et de Zn (2005.3 ± 1622.2 g/L) qui ont été détecté dans les papier filtres sont des entraves a une analyses quantitative complète des DBS.Retombées: Ces résultats indiquent que l'analyse d'éléments pour les DBS en utilisant TXRF offre une approche semi-quantitative pour mesurer la concentration d'éléments essentiels. Les résultats obtenue pour le Cu and Se sont comparable aux résultats établis, alors que les résultats pour le Zn sont inférieurs aux résultats établis pour les adultes, ce qui reflètent les concentrations de Zn physiologiquement plus faible chez les nouveau-nés. Cette méthode peut être utilisée comme outil de sélection dans l'évaluation des éléments essentiels et permet de remédier à de nombreux défis associés au prélèvement sanguin.</description><creator>Pawly, Jessica</creator><contributor>Niladri Basu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Human Nutrition</subject><title>Elemental analysis of dried blood spots using total reflection X-ray fluorescence spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m6393.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff22n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs028</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Wetlands and floodplains play an important role in a myriad of environmental services including flood and drought protection, water provision for humans and agriculture, sustainment of fisheries, water quality regulation, carbon storage, and habitat provision for a multitude of species. As a result of these important services, changes to inundated areas can have major socioeconomic and environmental consequences. In addition to continued anthropogenic degradation, global climate change is expected to pose an increasingly large threat to wetlands and floodplains in the coming century. Despite their importance, the fate of wetlands and floodplains under climate change is poorly understood at large scales. Spatially detailed knowledge about projected changes in inundation is necessary to inform large-scale risk assessments and to focus conservation and climate mitigation efforts on regions and populations with high levels of exposure to likely inundation change. In order to produce large-scale estimates of inundation change in Africa and Europe, the novel concept of 'floodsheds' is proposed and developed in this thesis to delineate the flooding extent of rivers. The floodshed approach is used to produce maps of large-scale monthly inundation estimates based on discharge simulations from a global hydrological model at an unprecedented spatial resolution of 15 arc-seconds (~500 m) for both present and future conditions. The predicted long-term changes to annual inundation patterns are then used to assess exposure of land areas and human populations. The results of this globally applicable model are shown for Africa and Europe under a business-as-usual development pathway for the year 2050 and are overlaid with population distribution to highlight critical regions of exposure to inundation changes under climate change. Different patterns of exposure are found when considering floodplain area versus floodplain population. Out of the total floodplain area in the region of study, 42% will experience some loss of annual inundation and 63% will experience some new annual inundation by the year 2050. By contrast, population distribution within the floodplain area has greater exposure to loss of annual inundation: an estimated 239.5 million people (54% of floodplain population) will be exposed to a loss of inundation and 220.4 million (50%) exposed to new inundation. The resulting inundation change maps can also be applied to conservation efforts, as demonstrated through their use in determining sites of concern for migratory birds in the African-Eurasian flyway.</description><description>Les milieux humides et les plaines d'inondation jouent un rôle important à la base de nombreux services environnementaux : ils protègent contre les inondations et la sécheresse, approvisionnent en eau les humains et l'agriculture, soutiennent les pêcheries, régulent la qualité de l'eau, stockent du carbone et forment des habitats essentiels pour une variété d'espèces animales. Compte tenu de ces services importants, des changements aux zones inondées peuvent avoir des conséquences socioéconomiques et environnementales majeures. En plus de la dégradation anthropogénique continue, les changements climatiques poseront un risque aux milieux humides et aux plaines d'inondation de plus en plus grand dans le prochain siècle. Malgré leur importance, l'influence des changements climatiques sur ces milieux est peu étudiée à grande échelle. Une connaissance approfondie des changements anticipés dans la distribution spatiale des inondations est nécessaire pour évaluer les risques et concentrer les efforts de conservation de la nature et d'adaptation aux changements climatiques vers les régions et les populations grandement exposées aux changements d'inondation. Dans le but d'estimer les changements d'inondation en Afrique et en Europe, le nouveau concept de 'bassins d'inondation' (floodsheds) est proposé et développé dans cette thèse pour déterminer l'ampleur de la crue des rivières. Cette approche permet de produire des cartes estimant les zones inondées mensuelles à grande échelle, basées sur des simulations de débit de cours d'eau d'un modèle hydrologique global d'une résolution spatiale sans précédent de 15 arc-secondes (~500 m), et ce pour les conditions actuelles et futures. Les changements projetés à long terme dans la distribution annuelle d'inondation sont ensuite utilisés pour examiner les risques sur les territoires et les populations humaines. Les résultats de ce modèle à application globale sont présentés pour l'Afrique et l'Eurasie suivant le scénario de développement sans changement majeur (business-as-usual) pour l'année 2050, puis juxtaposés avec une distribution de population humaine dans le but de déterminer les régions critiques exposées aux changements d'inondation découlant des changements climatiques. Différents motifs d'exposition sont identifiés en analysant l'aire totale des plaines d'inondation ou de la population y vivant. Selon les résultats de cette étude, 42% des plaines d'inondation de la région étudiée verront une perte annuelle d'aires inondées et 63% verront de nouvelles inondations annuelles d'ici 2050. En revanche, la population humaine sur les plaines d'inondation est plus à risque de pertes d'inondation annuelles : environ 239.5 million de personnes (54% de la population vivant sur les plaines d'inondation) seront exposées à une perte d'inondation annuelle et 220.4 million de personnes (50%) seront exposées à de nouvelles inondations. Les cartes de changements d'inondation résultant de cette thèse peuvent également être utiles à divers efforts de conservation, tel que démontré par leur usage dans la détermination d'endroits à risque sur la route africaine-eurasienne d'oiseaux migrateurs.</description><creator>Anand, Mira</creator><contributor>Bernhard Lehner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Geography</subject><title>The future of flood-prone areas in Africa and Europe: predicting changing inundation patterns under climate change</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c502f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs028</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870z320</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Non-small cell lung cancers (NSCLCs) account for ~85% of lung cancers, which are the leading cause of cancer death worldwide, and consist of different subtypes driven by distinct oncogenic mutations. Selective inhibitors targeting several driver receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) in NSCLC subtypes, such as those harboring activating EGFR mutations or ALK rearrangements, have led to dramatic initial responses. More recently, ROS1-translocated NSCLCs is approved to be treated with crizotinib, an inhibitor initially approved to target ALK but can also inhibit ROS1 due to the structural similarity of ROS1 and ALK RTKs. However, resistance to crizotinib inevitably arises limiting its clinical benefit and resistant mechanisms to ROS1 inhibition are less understood. In my thesis, I aimed to uncover novel mechanisms of drug resistance to ROS1 inhibition in NSCLC. HCC78, a NSCLC cell line established from a treatment naïve-patient tumor, harbors the SLC34A2-ROS1-rearrangement. Our laboratory has previously identified HCC78 clones with differential drug sensitivities to crizotinib. In contrast to the sensitive populations, I found that the resistant HCC78 clones express reduced levels of SLC34A2-ROS1 mRNA and protein and maintain mTORC1 signaling upon crizotinib treatment. Consistently, the resistant clones are highly sensitive to mTORC1 inhibition. In a parallel approach using shRNA screening, we identified that suppression of MSK2 is selectively effective in inhibiting proliferation of HCC78 resistant clones, however, without affecting mTORC1signaling. Thus, we have identified two novel mechanisms of resistance to ROS1 inhibition in NSCLC and the potential treatment strategy using mTORC1 inhibitors to overcome resistance. </description><description>Le cancer du poumon non à petites cellules (NSCLC, selon l'acronyme anglais) représente environ 85% de cas de cancer du poumon, et est la principale cause de décès dû au cancer dans le monde. Il consiste de différents sous-types entraînés par des mutations oncogéniques distinctes. Des inhibiteurs sélectifs ciblant plusieurs récepteurs de tyrosine kinases (RTK) dans les sous-types de NSCLC, tels que ceux qui hébergent des mutations EGFR activantes ou des réarrangements ALK, ont mener à des réponses initiales dramatiques. Plus récemment, les NSCLC transloqués par ROS1 ont été approuvés pour être traités avec le crizotinib, un inhibiteur qui a initialement été approuvé pour cibler ALK, mais qui peut également inhiber ROS1 en raison de la similarité structurelle des RTK ROS1 et ALK. Cependant, la résistance au crizotinib se développe inévitablement et nuit aux bénéfices cliniques. De plus, les mécanismes résistants à l'inhibition de ROS1 sont moins bien compris. Dans ma thèse, je vise à découvrir de nouveaux mécanismes de résistance aux médicaments contre l'inhibition de ROS1 dans le NSCLC. HCC78, une ligne cellulaire NSCLC établie à partir d'une tumeur n'ayant jamais reçu de traitement, héberge le réarrangement SLC34A2-ROS1. Notre laboratoire a déjà identifié des clones de HCC78 qui portent des sensibilités médicamenteuses différentielles au crizotinib. Contrairement aux populations sensibles, j'ai trouvé que les clones HCC78 résistants expriment des taux réduits d'ARNm et de protéine de SLC34A2-ROS1 et maintiennent la signalisation de mTORC1 lors du traitement avec le crizotinib. De manière systématique, les clones résistants sont très sensibles à l'inhibition de mTORC1. Dans une approche parallèle utilisant le dépistage de shRNA, nous avons identifié que MSK2 est efficace de manière sélective dans l'inhibition de la prolifération des clones résistants au HCC78, mais n'a aucun effet sur la signalisation de mTORC1. Nous avons donc identifié deux nouveaux mécanismes de résistance à l'inhibition de ROS1 dans NSCLC et la stratégie de traitement potentielle en utilisant des inhibiteurs de mTORC1 pour surmonter cette résistance.</description><creator>Ferwati, Sara</creator><contributor>Sidong Huang (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>Mechanisms of drug resistance to ROS1 inhibition in non-small cell lung cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t8717.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z320</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193c20n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Though many promising methods and technologies have been introduced in 5G to satisfy the ever-increasing connectivity of modern society, key questions such as the modulation technique have yet to be resolved. Should the conventional technique of orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM) employed in 4G remain? Or should a more exotic form of non-orthogonal modulation be adopted, which – though more complex – can provide tangible benefits in terms of capacity and bandwidth efficiency? Recent work has proposed a new receiver architecture designed to overcome one of these key complexities: noise correlation. Though promising, it has to date focused on the special case of rectangular modulation with integer compression in the time-domain, limiting its use in practical settings. This work will extend upon this concept by presenting a general receiver architecture, providing the flexibility demanded by the changing landscape of telecommunications.This will be accomplished by gradually increasing the generality of the receiver, first establishing key concepts by adapting the above-mentioned special case to a frequency setting. The design will then be adapted to accommodate arbitrary modulation waveforms with integer compression. Once established, this receiver will be further extended to MIMO systems, with each being evaluated based on its maximum information rate, or system capacity. This thesis will culminate with the introduction of a general methodology to generate and analyze a receiver architecture for arbitrary compression factor and waveform, which will be verified by generating the initial special case.</description><description>Bien que de nombreuses méthodes et technologies prometteuses aient été introduites dans la 5G pour satisfaire la connectivité croissante de la société moderne, des questions clés telles que la technique de modulation doivent encore être résolues. La technique conventionnelle de multiplexage par répartition orthogonale de la fréquence (OFDM) utilisée dans la 4G devrait-elle rester? Ou faut-il adopter une forme plus exotique de modulation non-orthogonale, qui, bien que plus complexe, peut apporter des avantages tangibles en termes de capacité et d'efficacité de la bande passante?Des travaux récents ont proposé une nouvelle architecture de récepteur conçue pour surmonter l'une de ces complexités clés: la corrélation de bruit. Bien que prometteur, il s'est concentré à ce jour sur le cas particulier de la modulation rectangulaire avec compression de nombre entier dans le domaine temporel, ce qui limite son utilisation dans des environnements pratiques. Ce travail s'étendra à ce concept en présentant une architecture de récepteur générale, apportant la flexibilité exigée par l'évolution du paysage des télécommunications.Ceci sera accompli en augmentant progressivement la généralité du récepteur, en établissant d'abord des concepts clés en adaptant le cas spécial mentionné ci-dessus à un réglage de fréquence. La conception sera alors adaptée pour prendre en charge des formes d'onde de modulation arbitraires avec une compression d'entier. Une fois établi, ce récepteur sera étendu aux systèmes MIMO, chacun étant évalué en fonction de son débit d'information maximal ou de la capacité du système. Cette thèse aboutira à l'introduction d'une méthodologie générale pour générer et analyser une architecture de récepteur pour un facteur de compression et une forme d'onde arbitraires, qui sera vérifiée en générant le cas spécial initial.</description><creator>Watts, Dylan</creator><contributor>Jan Bajcsy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Design and capacity analysis of an orthogonal SEFDM receiver, its generalization, and extension to MIMO</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k4935.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193c20n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9998949</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many patients who are admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU) experience a reduction in their level of mobility that can have detrimental physiological effects on several body systems. Early mobilization (EM) is an intervention that reduces the level of immobility during critical illness. There is evidence that EM is associated with more ventilator-free days, shorter ICU and hospital length of stay, improved functional status and increased quality of life after hospital discharge. However, implementation of EM is not without challenges. The overall aim of this thesis, which contains four manuscripts, is to provide insight into the barriers and facilitators to the implementation of EM in local area ICUs and to contribute to the existing body of knowledge in order to ultimately to help improve the practice of EM.The first study involved a survey of 138 clinicians from three local area ICUs to identify the barriers and practice patterns of EM. The results showed that many clinicians did not perceive EM as a top priority, were not fully aware of the benefits of EM, and did not feel well trained to mobilize mechanically ventilated patients. It also showed that most ICUs required a physician's order for initiation of physiotherapy care and that physiotherapy services were unavailable during evening hours and limited on weekends. Key identified barriers were medical instability, safety concerns of nurses, limited staffing, insufficient equipment, risk of dislodgement of devices or lines, excessive sedation, lack of coordination among providers, slow recognition of when patients should begin EM, inadequate training, conflicting perceptions among physicians about the suitability of EM, and lack of effective communication. The second study involved follow-up exploratory focus group discussions with physiotherapists, nurses, physicians and respiratory therapists to explore their perspectives regarding the barriers, facilitators, and potential solutions for improving EM practice. The key barriers to EM were a lack of conviction or knowledge regarding the available evidence on EM, lack of attention to the provision of optimal care, poor ICU organization, poor communication and the unpredictable nature of the ICU. Other barriers included limited staffing, equipment, time and clinical knowledge. Identified facilitators included individual-level factors such as intrinsic motivation, positive outcome expectations, conscious effort to mobilize early, good planning and coordination, presence of ICU champions and expert support by a physiotherapist; and organizational level facilitators: reminder system, pro-EM culture, implementation of an EM protocol, and improved ICU organization. Based on the results of these two initial studies, knowledge translation interventions were determined to be necessary to help reduce the identified barriers and enhance the identified facilitators. The third study, a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies, evaluated the impact of EM and neuromuscular electrical stimulation on the incidence of intensive care unit-acquired weakness (ICUAW), ventilator dependency, discharge location, ICU and hospital length of stay, and acute mortality. The results indicated that EM and neuromuscular electrical stimulation interventions were associated with a lower likelihood of development of ICUAW and a greater likelihood of being discharged home. The evidence was inconsistent regarding these interventions being associated with reduced ventilator dependency, ICU length of stay, and hospital length of stay. Moreover, these interventions were not associated with an increased odds of acute mortality.Finally, the last manuscript initiated the process of creating a Physical Therapy Critical Care Learning Needs Assessment Tool. This tool will eventually be used to help guide the creation of educational modules in an effort to bridge the knowledge gaps of physiotherapists working in the ICU. ...</description><description>De nombreux patients admis dans l'unité de soins intensifs voient leur niveau de mobilité diminuer, ce qui peut avoir des effets physiologiques préjudiciables sur plusieurs systèmes corporels. La mobilisation précoce est une intervention qui réduit le niveau d'immobilité pendant une maladie grave. Il a été prouvé que la mobilisation précoce est associée à plus de jours sans ventilateur, des soins intensifs de courte durée ainsi que la durée d'hospitalisation, l'amélioration de l'état fonctionnel et une meilleure qualité de vie après la sortie de l'hôpital. Cependant, la mise en œuvre de la mobilisation précoce n'est pas sans défis. L'objectif global de cette thèse, qui contient quatre manuscrits, est de fournir un aperçu des obstacles et des facilitateurs à la mise en œuvre de la mobilisation précoce dans les unités de soins intensifs locaux et de contribuer à l'ensemble des connaissances existantes afin d'améliorer la pratique de la mobilisation précoce.La première étude a consisté en une enquête auprès de 138 cliniciens de trois unités de soins intensifs de la région afin d'identifier les barrières et les modèles de pratique de la mobilisation précoce. Les résultats ont montré que de nombreux cliniciens ne considéraient pas la mobilisation précoce comme une priorité absolue, ne connaissaient pas pleinement les avantages d'une mobilisation précoce et ne se sentaient pas bien formés pour mobiliser des patients ventilés mécaniquement. On a également démontré que la plupart des unités de soins intensifs nécessitaient l'ordonnance d'un médecin pour l'initiation aux soins de physiothérapie, et que les services de physiothérapie n'étaient pas disponibles pendant les heures du soir et limités les fins de semaines. Les principaux obstacles identifiés étaient l'instabilité médicale, les problèmes de sécurité des infirmières, la pénurie de personnel, l'équipement insuffisant, le risque de délogement des appareils ou des lignes, la sédation excessive, le manque de coordination entre les prestataires, reconnaissance tardive du moment où les patients devraient commencer la mobilisation précoce, une formation inadéquate des conflits de perception de mobilisation précoce, et un manque de communication efficace.La deuxième étude comportait des discussions exploratoires de groupe de suivi avec des physiothérapeutes, des infirmières, des médecins et des inhalothérapeutes afin d'évaluer leur point de vue sur les obstacles, les facilitateurs et les solutions possibles afin d'améliorer les pratiques de mobilisation précoce. Les principaux obstacles à la mobilisation précoce étaient le manque de conviction ou de connaissances des preuves disponibles sur la mobilisation précoce, le manque d'attention de prodiguer des soins optimaux, l'organisation médiocre des unités de soins intensifs, la mauvaise communication et la nature imprévisible de l'unité de soins intensifs. Parmi les autres obstacles, mentionnons la ressource en personnel limitée, l'équipement, le temps et les connaissances cliniques limitées. Les facilitateurs identifiés comprenaient des facteurs individuels comme la motivation intrinsèque, les attentes positives en matière de résultats, les efforts conscients pour une mobilisation précoce, une bonne planification et coordination, la présence de champions en soins critiques et le soutien d'un physiothérapeute spécialisé; et des facilitateurs au niveau organisationnel : système de rappel, culture de mobilisation précoce, mise en place d'un protocole de mobilisation précoce et organisation améliorée des unités de soins intensifs. Selon les résultats de ces deux études initiales, les interventions d'application des connaissances ont été jugées nécessaires pour aider à réduire les obstacles identifiés et améliorer les facilitateurs identifiés.La troisième étude, une revue systématique et une méta-analyse d'études contrôlées randomisées, a évalué l'impact de la mobilisation précoce et de la stimulation électrique neuromusculaire sur ...</description><creator>Anekwe, David</creator><contributor>Jadranka Spahija (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Physical &amp; Occupational Therapy</subject><title>Early mobilization of the critically ill</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v0817.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998949</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh89b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'anomalie pré-sturtienne d'Islay est une excursion négative du δ13C qui a été documentée à l'échelle mondiale. Des travaux récents dans le nord du Canada et en Écosse ont suggéré qu'il pourrait y avoir deux anomalies négatives distinctes, une plus ancienne d'environ 739 Ma et une plus jeune d'environ 720 Ma, les deux étant attribuées à l'anomalie d'Islay. Cette étude se focalise sur la litho-chimio-stratigraphie du sous-groupe pré-sturtien Ugab du groupe Otavi situé dans le nord-ouest de la Namibie. Les données isotopiques de carbone des strates du sous-groupe Ugab exposées dans les monts Summas indiquent qu'elles sont plus anciennes que celles présentes aux dômes de Vrede avec seulement ~100 mètres de chevauchement stratigraphique. Nous utilisons des sections mesurées de façon détaillée pour développer un cadre de stratigraphie séquentielle pour le sous-groupe Ugab dans chaque bande d'affleurement. Ce cadre de stratigraphie séquentielle a pour but de corréler les deux affleurements afin de construire une courbe composite isotopique de δ13C. Cette courbe isotopique de carbone du sous-groupe Ugab montre deux anomalies négatives distinctes d'âge pré-sturtienne, ce qui appuie les données obtenues dans le nord du Canada et en Écosse. Nos résultats constituent une contribution importante à l'enregistrement isotopique du carbone pré-cryogénien, car ces données représentent la première documentation des deux anomalies au sein d'un même bassin.</description><description>The pre-Sturtian Islay anomaly is a negative carbon isotope excursion that has been documented globally, and recent work in northern Canada and Scotland has led to the suggestion that there may be two distinct negative anomalies, an older one ca. 739 Ma and a younger one ca. 720 Ma, both being assigned to the Islay anomaly. Here we investigate the litho- and chemo-stratigraphy of the pre-Sturtian Ugab Subgroup of the Otavi Group in northwestern Namibia. Carbon isotope data from two separate outcrop belts, the Summas Mountains and the Vrede Domes, indicate that the Ugab Subgroup strata exposed in the former inlier are older than those of the latter, with only approximately 100 metres of stratigraphic overlap. We use detailed measured sections to develop a sequence stratigraphic framework for the Ugab Subgroup in each outcrop belt, and correlate strata across the two exposures to construct a composite δ13C record. This carbon isotope profile of the Ugab Subgroup shows two separate pre-Sturtian negative anomalies, consistent with the findings in northern Canada and Scotland. Our results are an important contribution to the pre-Cryogenian carbon isotope record, as this data may serve as the first definitive documentation of both anomalies within a single basin.  </description><creator>Lamothe, Kelsey</creator><contributor>Galen Halverson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Earth and Planetary Sciences</subject><title>Stratigraphy and Isotope Geochemistry of the pre-Sturtian Ugab Subgroup, Otavi Group, northwestern Namibia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w04p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh89b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt923</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En raison de l'omniprésence des interactions sociales dans notre vie quotidienne ainsi que de l'importance des relations sociales pour notre bien-être, la recherche a continument étudié les processus permettant la socialité et l'affiliation humaines. Un nombre croissant de preuves neurobiologiques a lié le système ocytocinergique à la promotion de la cognition et du comportement social, mais l'interaction complexe des processus sous-jacents à cette influence reste incertaine. La présente thèse vise à élucider le rôle du système ocytocinergique en ce qui concerne les soins maternels et au développement social-cognitif des enfants dans le cadre de la relation mère–enfant.L'Article 1 est la première étude à établir un lien entre l'ocytocine circulante et la théorie de l'esprit (la capacité à déduire les états mentaux des autres), démontrant que des taux accrus d'ocytocine plasmatique lors du troisième trimestre de la grossesse prédisent une meilleure performance à une tâche travaillant la théorie de l'esprit effectuée durant les premiers stades du postpartum. Cette découverte est en accord avec l'idée que l'ocytocine endogène pourrait représenter un biomarqueur de la sensibilité aux signaux sociaux. La théorie de l'esprit, à son tour, était associée à moins de comportements maternels désengagés et dépressifs (plus engagés et détendus, moins centrés sur l'expérience personnelle). De plus, l'ocytocine plasmatique était indirectement liée à un comportement maternel moins dépressif à 7–9 semaines après l'accouchement, par l'intermédiaire de la théorie de l'esprit. L'Article 2 a confirmé et élargi ces résultats en démontrant que l'ocytocine plasmatique en fin de grossesse était indirectement associée à un comportement maternel plus structurant et moins intrusif à 2–3 ans postpartum, par l'intermédiaire des capacités de théorie de l'esprit des mères. Ensemble, les résultats des articles 1 et 2 suggèrent que la théorie de l'esprit sert potentiellement de mécanisme cognitif social par l'entremise duquel l'ocytocine optimise les soins maternels en améliorant la capacité à reconnaître ainsi qu'à interpréter les signaux sociaux. L'Article 3 a démontré que la méthylation du gène du récepteur de l'ocytocine (OXTR) influence les capacités émergentes de la théorie de l'esprit, qui sont un aspect important du développement social des enfants. Les résultats ont révélé que des niveaux plus élevés de méthylation OXTR, qui régule négativement le fonctionnement du système ocytocinergique en bloquant la transcription des récepteurs et empêchant ainsi la signalisation de l'ocytocine, prédisent une performance plus faible à une batterie de tâches de théorie de l'esprit chez les enfants de 2–3 ans. Cette découverte suggère un impact fonctionnel de la méthylation du gène OXTR sur le fonctionnment cognitif social. De plus, l'exposition à un comportement maternel plus structurant attenue l'impact de l'augmentation de la méthylation de l'OXTR sur la performance en théorie de l'esprit. Dans l'ensemble, les résultats de la présente thèse suggèrent que le système ocytocinergique joue un rôle important et dynamique dans la plasticité liée à la reproduction et dans la plasticité développemental du cerveau social, ce qui permet la socialité et l'affiliation humaines au sein de contextes variés. L'augmentation naturelle de l'ocytocine périphérique en fin de grossesse pourrait refléter une fonction d'amorçage du système ocytocinergique sur les processus cognitifs sociaux facilitant des changements durables dans les soins maternels requis lors de la petite enfance. De plus, au cours des premières années, la méthylation du gène récepteur de l'ocytocine pourrait conférer une susceptibilité différentielle aux influences de soins maternels sur le développement social. Ces résultats ont également des implications cliniques importantes, car ils améliorent l'identification des personnes à risque et indiquent des cibles potentielles de prévention et d'intervention précoce.</description><description>Given the ubiquity of social interactions in our daily lives and the importance of social relationships to our wellbeing, research has persistently investigated the processes that enable human sociality and affiliation. A growing body of neurobiological evidence has implicated the oxytocinergic system in promoting social cognition and behavior (for review see Carter, 2014), but the complex interplay of processes underlying this influence remains unclear. The present thesis aims to elucidate the role of the oxytocinergic system in relation to maternal caregiving and children's social cognitive development within the context of the mother–child relationship.Article 1 is the first study to establish a link between circulating oxytocin and theory of mind (i.e., the ability to infer the mental states of others), demonstrating that increased levels of plasma oxytocin during the third trimester of pregnancy predicted better performance on an experimental theory of mind task in the early postpartum. This finding is consistent with the notion that endogenous oxytocin may represent a biomarker for sensitivity to social cues (Bartz,Zaki, Bolger, &amp; Ochsner, 2011a). Theory of mind, in turn, was associated with less remote and less depressive maternal interactive behaviors (e.g., more engaged and relaxed; less focused on own experience). Moreover, plasma oxytocin was indirectly related to less depressive maternal behavior at 7¬–9 weeks postpartum via theory of mind ability. Article 2 confirmed and extended these findings by demonstrating that plasma oxytocin during late pregnancy was indirectly associated with more structuring and less intrusive maternal behavior at 2–3 years postpartum via mothers' theory of mind ability. Together the results of Articles 1 and 2 suggest that theory of mind may serve as a social cognitive mechanism through which oxytocin promotes maternal caregiving by enhancing awareness of and ability to interpret social cues. Article 3 demonstrated that another component of the oxytocinergic system— methylation of the oxytocin receptor (OXTR) gene—influences early emerging theory of mind abilities, which are an important aspect of children's social development. The findings revealed that higher levels of OXTR methylation, which down-regulates oxytocinergic system functioning by blocking receptor transcription and thus preventing oxytocin signalling, predicted worse performance on a battery of theory of mind tasks among 2- to 3-year-old children. This finding is suggestive of a functional impact of OXTR gene methylation on social cognitive processing. Moreover, exposure to more maternal structuring behavior buffered the impact of increased OXTR methylation on theory of mind performance. This pattern suggests that OXTR methylation may represent a biomarker of differential susceptibility to the influences of optimal and less optimal parenting on theory of mind development. Overall the findings of the present thesis suggest that the oxytocinergic system plays an important and dynamic role in the reproductive-induced and developmental plasticity of the social brain that enables human sociality and affiliation in varying contexts. That is, the natural increase of peripheral oxytocin during late pregnancy may reflect a priming function of the oxytocinergic system on the social cognitive processes that facilitate long-lasting changes in the maternal caregiving that is required during infancy and early childhood. Further, during the early years methylation of the oxytocin receptor gene may confer differential susceptibility to maternal caregiving on social development. The findings also have important clinical implications, as they improve identification of those at risk (e.g., women with low plasma oxytocin during the perinatal period and children with high OXTR methylation) and point to potential targets for prevention and early intervention (e.g., theory of mind and parent training).</description><creator>MacKinnon, Anna</creator><contributor>Phyllis Zelkowitz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Oxytocin and theory of mind in mothers and their children: A longitudinal investigation from pregnancy to 3 years postpartum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n5653.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt923</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr87n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Parce que l'appartenance est un besoin humain fondamental (Baumeister &amp; Leary, 1995), les individus possèdent un système de régulation du sentiment d'appartenance, qui s'applique à maintenir des niveaux stables d'inclusion sociale. Selon la théorie de l'attention sociale dans la régulation du sentiment d'appartenance, lorsque les besoins d'appartenance sont menacés (par exemple, par le rejet social), les individus se mettent à scruter davantage leur environnement social en quête d'opportunités d'inclusion, dans l'objectif d'optimiser leurs chances d'être de nouveau accepter (Pickett &amp; Gardner, 2005). Cependant, les études soutenant cette théorie peuvent manquer de validité écologique étant donné que les signes d'acceptation étaient disponibles et manifestes. Dans le monde réel, l'information sociale est davantage complexe et ambiguë. Au travers de quatre études, j'ai exploré comment les individus rejetés régulaient leurs besoins d'appartenance lorsque les signes d'acceptation ne sont pas disponibles, proposant qu'en l'absence d'indices d'acceptation, les individus diminueraient leur attention sociale afin d'éviter tout nouveau rejet. J'ai également considéré avec attention le rôle de la dysrégulation émotionnelle dans l'altération de l'attention sociale après un rejet, en supposant qu'aussi bien la détresse émotionnelle que l'engourdissement émotionnel s'interposeraient dans la relation entre le rejet et la diminution de l'attention sociale. Dans la première étude, j'ai utilisé un modèle corrélationnel pour évaluer le rapport entre le rejet et la diminution de l'attention sociale, lors d'un test de justesse empathique, et j'ai sondé comment l'humeur pouvait influencer cette relation. Dans l'étude 2, j'ai employé une manipulation expérimentale pour examiner l'influence du rejet sur l'attention sociale, concluant que le rejet entravait l'attention en ce qui a trait aux tâches de justesse empathique, mais que la performance lors de tâches cognitives non sociales, quant à elle s'améliorait avec le rejet plutôt que de se détériorer. Dans l'étude 3, j'ai reproduit les résultats de l'étude 2, en démontrant que le rejet enrayait l'attention sociale lors de l'exécution de deux tâches de justesse empathique différentes, et j'ai trouvé des appuis à l'hypothèse du rôle de la détresse émotionnelle dans la dysrégulation émotionnelle, soit que la relation entre le rejet et l'attention sociale altérée était conditionnée par les affects négatifs. Enfin, l'étude 4 a agrémenté les résultats de l'étude 2, concluant que le rejet améliorait la performance quant aux tâches non sociales, comme mesuré lors de la réalisation de trois tests de créativité complexes, suggérant que l'effet néfaste du rejet ne s'applique qu'à l'attention sociale et ne résulte pas d'une démotivation générale. Les présentes études démontrent qu'il existe des limites à la théorie actuelle de l'attention sociale dans la régulation du sentiment d'appartenance, car en l'absence de signes évidents d'inclusion, le rejet entraine une diminution plutôt qu'une augmentation de l'attention sociale.</description><description>Because belonging is a fundamental human need (Baumeister &amp; Leary, 1995), individuals possess a belonging regulatory system devoted to maintaining stable levels of social inclusion. The social monitoring theory of belonging regulation posits that when belonging needs are threatened (i.e., through social rejection), individuals will increase monitoring of their social environment for signs of inclusion in order to capitalize on opportunities to regain acceptance (Pickett &amp; Gardner, 2005). However, studies supporting this theory may lack ecological validity, as acceptance cues were available and overt. In the real world, social information is more complex and ambiguous. Across four studies, I explored how rejected individuals regulate belonging needs when acceptance cues are unavailable, proposing that in the absence of overt acceptance cues, individuals will decrease social monitoring in order to avoid further rejection. I also examined the role of mood dysregulation in impairing social monitoring following rejection, hypothesizing that either emotional distress or emotional numbness would mediate the relationship between rejection and decreased social monitoring. In Study 1, I used a correlational design to assess the relationship between rejection and decreased social monitoring on an empathic accuracy task, and explored how mood may mediate this relationship. Study 2 used an experimental manipulation to examine the influence of rejection on social monitoring, finding that rejection impaired social monitoring on an empathic accuracy task, but performance on nonsocial cognitive tasks was enhanced rather than impaired by rejection. In Study 3, I replicated the findings from Study 2, showing that rejection impaired social monitoring on two different empathic accuracy tasks, and found support for the emotional distress hypothesis of mood dysregulation, such that the relationship between rejection and impaired social monitoring was mediated by negative affect. Finally, Study 4 extended on the results from Study 2, finding that rejection improved nonsocial task performance as measured by three complex creativity tasks, suggesting that the impairing effect of rejection is unique to social monitoring and not a result of general demotivation. The present studies demonstrate that there are limitations to the current social monitoring theory of belonging regulation, as in the absence of overt signs of inclusion, rejection leads to decreases rather than increases in social monitoring.</description><creator>Quinn, Sara</creator><contributor>John Lydon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Down, but not out: Rejection impairs social monitoring, but enhances performance on nonsocial tasks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139438q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr87n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw81b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les sursauts radio rapides (Fast Radio Bursts, FRB) sont transitoires de durée micro à milliseconde d'origine extragalactique. Malgré des estimations de taux de FRB de milliers par ciel par jour, seulement 30 sources ont été détectés au cours de cette décennie depuis la découverte initiale, et les progéniteurs des FRB restent un mystère. Cela va bientôt changer, des recherches dédiés en temps réel 24/7, devraient détecter des dizaines de FRB tous les jours, sont dans les premiers stades de mise en service. La recherche est hébergée par un télescope piloté par logiciel avec un champ de vision d'environ ~250 degrés carrés et une zone de collection de ~8000 metres carrésca. Le télescope est situé à l'Observatoire Fédéral Radioastrophysique (OFR), et a été conçu pour L'Expérience Canadienne de Cartographie de L'Intensité de l'Hydrogène (Canadian Hydrogen Intensity Mapping Experiment, CHIME). Cette thèse suit le développement des composantes dans les dernières étapes de la CHIME/FRB pipeline, où l'attention est sur la classification. Ces développements comprennent: des algorithmes pour regrouper des détections sur des espaces de recherche multidimensionnels et identifier de façon unique des impulsions uniques; un algorithme pour trier les événements candidats ressemblant aux interférences radio-fréquences, avec des préparations pour l'application de classificateurs d'apprentissage automatique; une méthode pour localiser des éclats lumineux, l'échange de la mémoire et précalcul de temps d'exécution de sous-millisecondes; et une architecture pour le pipeline basé sur les événements, conçu pour évoluer vers un nombre arbitraire de cœurs et de machines. Enfin, un test de contraintes du pipeline basé sur les événements a été réalisé, en utilisant des événements simulés sur la population de pulsars connue. Le pipeline gère confortablement 300000 faux événements couvrant 24 heures de observations simulées.</description><description>Fast Radio Bursts (FRBs) are micro-to-millisecond duration transients of extragalactic origin.  Despite FRB rate estimates of thousands per sky per day, only 30 sources have been detected in the now decade since the initial discovery, and the progenitor of FRBs remains a mystery.  This will soon change, as a dedicated 24/7 real-time search, expected to detect tens of FRBs every day, is in the early stages of commissioning.  The search is hosted by a novel software-driven telescope with a ~250 square degree field of view and a collecting area of ~8000 square metres.  The telescope is located at the Dominion Astrophysical Observatory (DRAO), and was designed for the Canadian Hydrogen Intensity Mapping Experiment (CHIME).  This thesis follows the development of components in the later stages of the CHIME/FRB pipeline, where the focus shifts from detection to classification.  These developments include: algorithms to group detections over multi-dimensional search spaces and uniquely identify single-pulses; an algorithm to sift candidate events resembling radio-frequency interference (RFI), with preparations for the application of machine learning classifiers; a method for localizing bright bursts, exchanging memory and precomputation for sub-millisecond execution time; and an architecture for the event-based pipeline, designed to scale to an arbitrary number of CPU cores and machines.  Finally, a stress test of the event-based pipeline was performed, using simulated events based on the known pulsar population. The pipeline comfortably handles 300,000 fake events spanning 24 hours of fake observation, reaffirming that the FRB search will not suffer the pulsar foreground.</description><creator>Josephy, Alexander</creator><contributor>Victoria Kaspi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Radio transient classification algorithms for CHIME/FRB</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p801.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw81b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v8382852</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:13:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le récent intérêt pour l'utilisation de la fabrication additive en tant que processus de réparation a conduit à la nécessité de segmenter les régions défectueuses à partir de numérisations de « nuages de points » 3D de surfaces aérospatiales endommagées. Cette étude de recherche présente deux nouvelles contributions à la collecte et à la segmentation de nuages de points désorganisés, qui permettent ensemble la localisation de régions défectueuses dans les coordonnées de la machine-outil. D'abord, une méthode est développée pour produire des nuages de points texturés en enregistrant des images par numérisation laser collectées au travers d'une machine à mesurer tridimensionnelle. La méthode est mise en œuvre dans cette étude de recherche pour acquérir des données pour une série d'études de cas. Ensuite, l'algorithme de segmentation par marche aléatoire, initialement développé pour des images 2D en échelle de gris, est étendu pour fonctionner directement sur des données brutes et désorganisées de nuages de points. L'algorithme segmente les numérisations de nuages de points en déterminant la destination la plus probable par marche aléatoire traversant un domaine discret, où le lien fondamental entre les marches aléatoires et la théorie potentielle permet de formuler une solution en termes de minimisation d'énergie sur un réseau de résistance. L'algorithme étendu pour cette étude incorpore à la fois des informations sur la géométrie et la texture obtenues dans le résultat de segmentation, et peut être exécuté sur des données de nuages bruitées contenant des artefacts communs provenant de numérisations réelles. Une série d'expériences sur des données synthétiques analysées par MATLAB démontre que l'algorithme est bien adapté pour une utilisation interactive, et qu'il conserve un avantage significatif par rapport aux algorithmes conventionnels de croissance de régions lors de la segmentation de données bruitées. Cinq études de cas sur de réels composants aérospatiales endommagés confirment que l'algorithme étendu pour cette étude est capable d'identifier avec précision une large gamme de types de défauts surfaciques, même en présence d'effets de numérisation laser indésirables.</description><description>A recent initiative in the use of additive manufacturing for repair has prompted the need to segment defect regions from 3D point cloud scans of damaged aerospace surfaces.  This research presents two novel contributions relating to the collection and segmentation of unorganized point cloud data, that together allow for the localization of defect regions in machine tool coordinates.  First, a method is developed to produce textured point clouds by registering images to laser scans collected using a coordinate measuring machine system.  The method is implemented in this research to acquire data for a series of case studies.  Next, the random walker segmentation algorithm, originally developed for 2D greyscale images, is extended to operate directly on raw, unorganized point clouds.  The algorithm segments point cloud scans by determining the most likely destination of a random walker traversing a discrete domain, where the fundamental link between random walks and potential theory allows for a solution to be formulated in terms of energy minimization on a resistance network.  The extended algorithm incorporates both geometric and texture information into the segmentation result, and can be run on noisy cloud data containing common real-world scanning artefacts.  A series of experiments on synthetic data in MATLAB demonstrate that the algorithm is well-suited for interactive use, and that it maintains a significant advantage over conventional region growing algorithms when segmenting noisy data.  Five case studies on actual damaged aerospace components confirm that the extended algorithm is capable of accurately identifying a wide range of surface defect types, even in the presence of compounding laser scanning effects.</description><creator>Hitchcox, Thomas</creator><contributor>Yaoyao Zhao (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Segmenting surface defects in 3D scans of aerospace components using random walks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd49b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8382852</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4175</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>