<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:08:54Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17375" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q992g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Throughout history, human populations have continuously been challenged by new and emerging infectious diseases. For the past 26 years, sub-Saharan Africa and other countries around the world have been dealing with a pandemic caused by a relatively new pathogen called the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). Although antiretroviral (ARV) therapies effectively reduce morbidity and mortality rates, the long term use in those who have access to treatment inevitably leads to drug-related toxicity and resistance. Even with a strong commitment from governments to expand and finance prevention and treatment programs, transmission rates continue to outpace the benefits of these efforts. Therefore to effectively eradicate the disease, research is focusing on the design of protective and therapeutic vaccines. The first major step in designing these alternative therapies is to define correlates of immune protection. The research presented in this thesis focuses on characterizing the quantitative and qualitative features of T cell immune responses in individuals who spontaneously control viral replication and exhibit a benign course of disease while remaining off ARV therapy. A comprehensive analysis of HIV-specific IFN-gamma secreting immune responses revealed that neither the breadth nor the magnitude of responses directed against the entire HIV proteome accurately predicts the viral load or rate of CD4 decline. Subsequent analyses showed that the preferential targeting of Gag was associated with reduced rates of CD4 decline and was later confirmed in a cohort of individuals in primary infection whereby the relative breadth and magnitude of Gag p24 was inversely correlated with viral load set point. The maintenance of polyfunctional immune responses in HIV-infected subjects with a benign course of disease prompted us to develop a method that could comprehensively assess the breadth, magnitude and specificity of three functionally distinct subsets of HIV-specific lymphocytes (single IFN-gamma, single IL-2 and dual IFN-gamma/IL-2 secretors). Survey of immune responses in chronically infected individuals revealed that only the breadth and magnitude of dual IFN-gamma/IL-2 secreting lymphocytes correlated with reduced viral loads and increased CD4 counts suggesting that secretion of IFN-gamma alone was a poor correlate of protection. We also showed that the contribution of polyfunctional lymphocytes to the total response was greater for epitopes restricted by major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I alleles associated with slow disease progression compared to those restricted by alleles associated with rapid or neutral rates of HIV disease progression. Taken together, this work supports the view that immune monitoring of infected and vaccinated individuals should include methodologies capable of detecting both IFN-gamma and IL-2 secretion from responding T lymphocytes. The studies presented here have furthered our understanding of what constitutes protection from disease progression emphasizing that both specificity and polyfunctionality are features of effective control of viral replication.</description><creator>Peretz, Yoav.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>HIV Long-Term Survivors.</subject><subject>HIV Infections -- immunology.</subject><subject>CD4-Positive T-Lymphocytes -- immunology.</subject><subject>HIV -- immunology.</subject><subject>Interferon Type II -- immunology.</subject><subject>Interleukin-2 -- immunology.</subject><title>Long term non progressors : clues for defining immune correlates of protection from HIV disease progression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr71n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q992g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zc34s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation presents three experiments designed to demonstrate the effects of cognitive, emotional and psychosocial factors on pain perception in humans and to identify potential neuroanatomical substrates of attentional and emotional pain modulation. The first two chapters provide an introduction, including the statement of the rationale and objectives of this Ph.D. project (Chapter 1) and an overview of the relevant background literature (Chapter 2). Chapter 3 presents a voxel-based morphometry study on the neural correlates of attentional and emotional pain modulation. In agreement with the observation that manipulations of emotion and attention differentially affect pain perception, the results of this experiment suggest that separate neuroanatomical substrates may underlie these pain modulations: the right lateral orbitofrontal, left medial prefrontal, and bilateral entorhinal cortices appear to be implicated in emotional pain modulation, while the right putamen appears to be involved in attentional pain modulation. The study described in Chapter 4 shows that the experimental manipulation of mood using emotionally-laden visual stimuli preferentially alters pain unpleasantness, leaving pain intensity unaffected. This study replicates the psychophysical observations presented in the study of Chapter 3 (and in previous reports), which used odors to manipulate emotional state, therefore suggesting the independence of this phenomenon from the mood induction technique employed. The study in Chapter 5 shows that empathy has an effect on pain perception as well, which cannot be explained by mood effects. Participants for whom a state of high empathy was evoked rated painful stimuli applied to themselves as more intense and unpleasant than did those in a state of low empathy; furthermore, the state empathy ratings correlated with the pain ratings. By showing that emotional state, attention and empathy can influence pain perception, the work in this thesis provides evidence demonstrating that the pain experience can be significantly molded by top-down factors, and is therefore far from being solely determined by the physical properties of the noxious stimulation. These observations might partially explain why the pain response in certain situations appears disproportionately large, or surprisingly small, in relation to the noxious stimulation, and support the utility of psychological methods in the management of pain symptoms.</description><creator>Loggia, Marco L.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Pain -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Attention -- physiology.</subject><subject>Pain -- psychology.</subject><subject>Pain Threshold -- psychology.</subject><subject>Emotions -- physiology.</subject><subject>Empathy.</subject><title>Attentional, emotional and psychosocial influences on pain : psychophysics and neuroanatomical correlates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk97t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zc34s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hg794</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le premier but de mon projet de doctorat a ete la caracterisation moleculaire de l'interface entre les recepteurs activateurs des cellules Natural Killer (NK) et de leurs ligands exprimes dans les cellules infectees ainsi que l'implication de cette interaction sur la reponse a l'infection par le cytomegalovirus (MCMV). J'ai tire un avantage de la variation naturelle au sein des membres lies aux recepteurs Ly49C ainsi que de la disponibilite des structures cristallines des Ly49 afin de comprendre les determinants moleculaires des interactions Ly49H-m157 et egalement identifier les residus des acides amines qui permettent de discriminer entre les recepteurs qui se lient et ceux qui ne se lient pas a m157. Mes decouvertes suggerent que le "site 2" du contact entre le CMH de classe I et Ly49 n'est visiblement pas implique dans la liaison avec m157. Au contraire, les residus localises au niveau de l'interface homodimere-recepteur seraient probablement critiques a la reconnaissance fonctionnelle de la glycoproteine m157. Notre approche fonctionnelle et de modelisation tridimensionnelle suggerent que l'architecture du dimere Ly49H est cruciale pour l'accessibilite de m157 mais non pour les molecules de CMH de classe I et relient la variabilite dans l'homodimerisation des Ly49 a la reconnaissance directe des produits pathogeniques. Un autre mecanisme de la reponse de l'hote contre MCMV provient de l'etude de la souche de souris MA/My, laquelle, malgre l'absence du gene Ly49h ainsi que la proteine pour laquelle il code, y est hautement resistant. Des etudes anterieures ont demontre qu'une interaction epistatique entre un gene issu du groupe des genes Ly49 sur le chromosome 6 et le CMH (H2) sur le chromosome 17 est associee avec la resistance au virus. Utilisant une methode de co-culture de cellules reportrices NFAT-GFP exprimant les recepteurs activateurs Ly49 et de fibroblastes primaires infectes, j'ai montre que le recepteur activateur Ly49P des cellules NK reconnait specifiquement les cellules infectees par MCMV et que cette reconnaissance depend de la presence de l'haplotype H2k. Ce signal etait bloque par l'utilisation des anticorps anti-H2-D k mais non par anti-H2-Kk. Ces resultats indiquent l'existence d'un nouveau mecanisme des cellules NK implique dans la resistance au MCMV, lequel depend de l'interaction fonctionnelle entre le recepteur Ly49P et la molecule du MHC de classe I, H2-Dk, dans les cellules infectees par MCMV. Comme contribution directe de ce travail, nous avons demontre que la resistance chez MA/My est au moins partiellement dependante des interactions entre le recepteur Ly49P et la molecule H2-Dk modifiee par le virus dans les cellules infectees. Comme MCMV regule negativement l'expression des molecules du CMH de classe I, j'ai confirme la presence de H2-Dk dans les cellules infectees par l'utilisation d'un virus MCMV recombinant portant un gene rapporteur GFP. En permutant la plateforme peptidique de liaison, les domaines transmembranaires et intracellulaires entre les molecules H2-Db et H2-D k, j'ai demontre que la plateforme peptidique de liaison est critique pour la reconnaissance des cellules infectees. Par le criblage d'un panel de mutants MCMV portant des genes impliques dans l'evasion immune, j'ai demontre que l'infection de fibroblastes par le MCMV depourvu du gene m04 (Deltam04) abolit totalement l'activation de Ly49P. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kielczewska, Agnieszka.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Killer Cells, Natural -- immunology.</subject><subject>Herpesviridae Infections -- immunology.</subject><subject>Lectins, C-Type -- immunology.</subject><subject>Antigens, Ly -- immunology.</subject><subject>Muromegalovirus -- immunology.</subject><title>Natural killer cell receptors and their MHC ligand interactions in innate resistance to mouse cytomegalovirus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579w997.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hg794</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150n63h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multiple Sclerosis (MS) is an autoimmune disease of the central nervous system (CNS) that is characterized by widespread focal areas of inflammation and demyelination. Although the exact cause of the disease is still not known, myelin-reactive T cells that enter the CNS trigger the disease and lead to the recruitment and activation of macrophages and other immune cells. One set of candidates that could serve to mediate these CNS changes is the family of phospholipase A2 (PLA2) enzymes, which consist of secreted (sPLA2) and cytosolic (cPLA2) forms. These enzymes hydrolyze membrane phospholipids to release free fatty acids (arachidonic acid) that can stimulate complex inflammatory cascades, and lysophospholipids that can induce myelin breakdown and demyelination, the two pathological hallmarks of MS. For my Ph.D. research I studied the expression and role of different members of the PLA2 family in 'experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis' (EAE), a widely used animal model of MS. I first generated a relapsing-remitting form of EAE in the C57BL/6 mouse strain that lacks a major form of sPLA2. I showed that cPLA2 is expressed by immune cells in the EAE lesions in the CNS. Furthermore blocking the activity of cPLA2 with a broad-spectrum chemical inhibitor starting at the time of EAE induction reduced the incidence and severity of disease, reduced lesion burden as well as reduced the expression of a number of chemokines and cytokines. Treating mice in the remission phase also prevented further clinical episodes. This showed that some or all members of the cPLA2 family play an important role in the onset and progression of EAE in a strain of mice lacking sPLA2. I next carried out studies to assess the expression of all 14 members of the sPLA2 and cPLA2 families at the onset, peak and remission stages of EAE in the SJL/J mouse strain that expresses all forms of PLA2. The mRNA expression of only 4 of these PLA2s was increased. These include sPLA2 (groups IIA and V) and cPLA 2 (groups IVA and VIA). The expression of these PLA2s in the CNS was also characterized by double-immunofluorescence. The role of these PLA2s was assessed using selective inhibitors and analysed by monitoring the clinical disability scores, chemokine/cytokine protein arrays, lipomics lipid profiling, and histological analysis. Surprisingly, the sPLA2 inhibitor prevented disease remission and worsened the clinical outcome. This was accompanied by an increase in several pro-inflammatory chemokines. Selective inhibitors of cPLA2 group IVA and the calcium independent foam group VIA (iPLA2) reduced severity of EAE when given starting before onset of disease. The cPLA2 inhibitor treatment was effective only while administered, while iPLA2 inhibitor treatment was effective even after treatment was stopped. Furthermore, only delayed treatment with the iPLA2 inhibitor was effective, suggesting that cPLA2 group IVA only plays a role in the initiation of disease, while iPLA 2 plays a role in both disease onset and progression. These effects were also associated with concomitant reduction in chemokine/cytokine expression, reduction of inflammatory lipid mediators, and increase in protective lipids e.g., omega 3 fatty acids. This work has allowed us to dissect out the expression and role of different members of the PLA2 family and has revealed the importance of selectively inhibiting some but not others in EAE. These findings may therefore have important implications for the treatment of MS.</description><creator>Kalyvas, Athena.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Encephalomyelitis, Autoimmune, Experimental -- pathology.</subject><subject>Phospholipases A2</subject><subject>Multiple Sclerosis -- pathology.</subject><title>The role of the phospholipase A₂ family in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt569.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150n63h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gh513</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main focus of my PhD studies was aimed at understanding the general mechanism of nuclear translocation and isolating novel components of the nuclear translocation pathway in neurons. Using the Drosophila visual system as an in vivo model to study nuclear motility in developing photoreceptor cells (R-cells), I have identified a novel role for the Ser/Thr kinase Misshapen (Msn) and the endocytic trafficking pathway in regulating the nuclear translocation process. The development of R-cells in the Drosophila eye disc is an excellent model system for the study of nuclear motility owing to its monolayer organization and the stereotypical translocation of its differentiating R-cell nuclei along the apical-basal plane. Prior to my thesis work, several laboratories had identified dynein and its associating proteins in R-cell nuclear translocation, however nothing was known about the signalling pathway that controlled their function in nuclear migration. Thus, one of my thesis goals was to elucidate the signalling mechanism controlling nuclear translocation in R-cells. Using a combination of molecular and genetic approaches, I identified Msn as a key component of a novel signalling pathway regulating R-cell nuclear translocation. Loss of msn causes a failure of R-cell nuclei to migrate apically. Msn appears to control R-cell nuclear translocation by regulating the localization of dynein and Bicaudal-D (Bic-D). My results also show that Msn enhances Bic-D phosphorylation in cultured cells, suggesting that Msn regulates R-cell nuclear migration by modulating the phosphorylation state of Bic-D. Consistently, my results show that a Bic-D-phosphorylation-defective mutation disrupted the apical localization of both Bic-D and dynein. I propose a model in which Msn induces the phosphorylation of Bic-D, which in turn modulates the activity and/or subcellular localization of dynein leading to the apical migration of R-cell nuclei. In addition to studying Msn, I have also searched for additional players in R-cell nuclear migration. From a gain-of-function approach, I found that the misexpression of the GTPase-activating-protein (GAP) RN-Tre caused a severe defect in R-cell nuclear migration. Since mammalian RN-Tre is involved in negatively regulating Rab protein activity, I speculated that the RN-Tre misexpression phenotype reflected a role for Rab-mediated vesicular transport in regulating R-cell nuclear migration. I systematically examined the potential role of Rab family proteins in R-cell nuclear migration and found that interfering with the function of Rab5, Rab11 or Shibire caused a similar nuclear migration phenotype. I propose that an endocytic pathway involving these GTPases is required for the targeting of determinants to specific subcellular locations, which in turn drive the apical migration of R-cell nuclei during development.</description><creator>Houalla, Tarek.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Eye -- embryology.</subject><subject>Cell Movement -- physiology.</subject><subject>Dynein ATPase -- genetics.</subject><subject>Drosophila Proteins -- genetics.</subject><subject>Protein-Serine-Threonine Kinases -- genetics.</subject><subject>Photoreceptors, Invertebrate -- physiology.</subject><subject>Drosophila melanogaster -- embryology.</subject><title>Nuclear translocation in the Drosophila eye disc : an inside look at the role of misshapen and the endocytic-recycling traffic pathway</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x4959.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gh513</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nq03h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mild head injury or concussion accounts for as many as 90% of all traumatic brain injuries and can sometime result in long-lasting and disabling post-concussion symptoms (PCS), even in the absence of detectable structural damage to the brain by morphological imaging. To date, the nature of persistent PCS following mild head injury remains poorly understood as objective and scientifically valid diagnostic tools are practically absent. This, in turn, likely accounts for missed diagnoses, prevents accurate assessment of the severity of the injury and creates difficulties for achieving proper patient management. This dissertation describes 4 functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) studies designed to establish whether there is a pathological basis to persistent PCS following cerebral concussion in male athletes. Study 1 was intended to evaluate the feasibility of using fMRI to detect changes in brain activation following concussion. The results showed that concussed athletes displayed reduced prefrontal activities compared to a healthy control group when performing a working memory task. In Study 2, we examined the relationship between self-reported PCS and the pattern of brain activity measured by fMRI. The severity of self-reported PCS was found to be associated with blood oxygen level dependent (BOLD) activation patterns in the region of interest: the higher the PCS score the lower the BOLD signal. In Study 3, we used serial fMRI approach to investigate brain activation pattern in the course of injury recovery. The results showed that symptom resolution was accompanied by a return to normal BOLD response patterns. Study 4 was designed to investigate the nature of depression, a common PCS, following concussion. Concussed athletes with depression showed less activation in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, and attenuated deactivation in the medial prefrontal region, consistent with functional neuroimaging findings in major depression. Again, depression severity correlated with the strength of the fMRI signal in the region of interests. Taken together, these results demonstrate the value of functional MRI in the evaluation of cerebral concussion, and provide evidence of an underlying pathology in persistent PCS following concussion.</description><creator>Chen, Jen-Kai, 1971-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Cerebral Cortex -- injuries.</subject><subject>Magnetic Resonance Imaging.</subject><subject>Brain Damage, Chronic -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Brain Concussion -- physiopathology.</subject><title>Neural substrates of persistent post-concussive symptoms : functional and structural neuroimaging studies with concussed male athletes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk983.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nq03h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc26b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>No safe and effective vaccine exists against respiratory syncytial virus (RSV), the main viral cause of lower respiratory tract infections in young children. Proteosome-based adjuvants, derived from the outer membrane proteins (OMP) of Neisseria species are potent inducers of mucosal and systemic immunity in humans and animals. RSV subunit vaccines based on enriched RSV proteins (eRSV) were formulated with proteosomes (Pro) or its S. flexneri LPS-supplemented derivative, Protollin (Prl). Administered intranasally (IN) in BALB/c mice, the vaccines elicited systemic and mucosal RSV-specific antibodies and fully protected against RSV challenge without enhanced pulmonary pathology or evidence of a Th2-biased response (eg: eosinophil infiltation or antigen-specific 1L-5 production by restimulated splenocytes or lung cells). Restimulation of cells from Prl-eRSV immunized mice elicited F peptide-specific CD8+ T cells producing IFNgamma and supernatant IFNgamma, TNFalpha, 1L-2 and IL-10. The Prl-eRSV vaccine was also studied in C57Bl/6 mice, to exploit the TLR2, TLR4 and MyD88-deficient (-/-) animals available on this background. Protection was significantly impaired in both TLR4-/- and MyD88 -/- mice, but not in TLR2 -/- mice following Prl- eRSV immunization and challenge. These studies revealed a role for the LPS component of Protollin in both initial (innate) cytokine release as well as dendritic cell maturation and Th1 polarization. Although antibody levels were sustained in MyD88-/- mice, the IgG1/IgG2a ratio was markedly higher in the absence of this pathway. The MyD88-/- mice also displayed elevated levels of pulmonary eosinophils following challenge, with concomitant reduction of neutrophils compared to wt mice. Using CD1d-iNKT cell-deficient mice (CD1-/-) in our BALB/c model, we also identified a significant role for the lipid component of both the Pro- and Prl-based vaccines. Responses to both vaccines in CD1-/- animals elicited lower antibody titers and reduced restimulated splenocyte supernatant cytokines (IFNgamma, IL-17 and IL-10), with concomitant augmentation of neutrophil recruitment (Prl only). Pro- and Prl-eRSV vaccines may therefore exert their powerful adjuvant effects by exploiting both CD1d-iNKT and, in the case of the Prlbased formulations the TLR4-MyD88-dependant signalling pathway. These pathways not only promote stronger Th1 immune responses but also act to control pulmonary eosinophil (MyD88-dependent) and neutrophil (MyD88 and CD1d-NKT-dependent) recruitment in a murine RSV challenge model.</description><creator>Cyr, Sonya L.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Respiratory Syncytial Virus Vaccines.</subject><title>Novel intranasal proteosome-based respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) vaccines elicit protection in mice without the risk of enhanced pathology or eosinophila by triggering innate immune pathways</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p30d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc26b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qg81d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This doctoral dissertation presents a series of studies that were conducted to investigate the relationship between morphological, as well as functional, changes and clinical disability in multiple sclerosis (MS) using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and functional MRI (fMRI). The extent of macroscopic brain tissue damage, as seen on T2-weighted MRI scans, is poorly correlated with measures of functional impairment in MS. We hypothesized that this might be due to the failure to take lesion location into account. By combining sophisticated lesion segmentation tools with the statistical and stereotaxic techniques of functional neuroimaging, we have shown a relationship between lesion location and the extent and type of physical and cognitive disability. Brain atrophy is another manifestation of MS. We conducted the first large-scale study of focal cortical atrophy in MS that uses cortical thickness measurements across the entire cortex. We present evidence that cortical atrophy occurs relatively early in the course of the disease, despite the lack of severe disability in MS patients, as assessed by the Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS), and follows a pattern of focal thinning that is more pronounced in areas that are heavily inter-connected with other brain regions, such as anterior cingulate cortex and association areas, suggesting that interruption of white matter tracts by MS plaques might play a causative role in cortical atrophy. Finally, we conducted an fMRI study of working memory in controls, cognitively unimpaired and impaired MS patients that revealed significant differences in the regions that were activated between the groups. Most interestingly, while both cognitively unimpaired MS patients and control subjects significantly activated the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex and the left thalamus, cognitively impaired MS patients failed to significantly activate these areas. Levels of deactivation within the medial prefrontal/anterior cingulate cortices and posterior cingulate cortex were inferior in MS patients than in controls. This study suggests that with an increased white matter lesion volume there is an increased damage to a number of afferents and efferents to and from the thalamus (cortico-basal ganglia-thalamo-cortical loops and other thalamo-cortical projections) that ultimately causes the observed cognitive deficits. These cognitive deficits seem also to be dependent on a reduced capacity of MS patients to show task-related deactivations.</description><creator>Charil, Arnaud.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Magnetic Resonance Imaging.</subject><subject>Multiple Sclerosis -- physiopathology.</subject><title>Morphological and functional correlates of disability in multiple sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010t63q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg81d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w3449</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new reactor and a novel in-situ sampling technique were developed for the study of the synthesis of CeO2 powders produced from dissolved cerium nitrate salts. The reactor minimized particle recirculation and provided a highly symmetric and undisturbed plasma flow suitable for the analysis of the phenomena affecting the formation of CeO2 powders. The sampling probe provided in-situ sampling of in-flight CeO2 particles and allowed continuous sampling without cross contamination. The sampled particles were collected using a wet collection system composed of a mist atomizer acting as a scrubber and a custom-made spray chamber. The entire collection system is portable and it was tested in the particle range of 20 nm to 100 mum. This information provided a picture of how CeO2 particles were formed. A numerical simulation of different plasma operating parameters using Fluent was presented. A comprehensive droplet-to-particle formation mechanism was deduced based on calorimetry, thermodynamics of CeO2 formation, numerical simulations and collected particles. The effect of adding water soluble fuels (alanine and glycine) to the original cerium nitrate solutions was investigated. Fuel addition decreased the temperature of CeO2 formation by acting as a local heat source as a result of fuel auto-ignition. The addition of fuel caused "particle size discrimination", and a single mode particle size distribution centered between 50-140 nm was achieved along the centerline of the reactor. Also, heat and mass transfer effects were numerically investigated in evaporating solution droplets (20-40 mum in diameter) containing dissolved hexahydrated cerium nitrate in a stationary rf Ar-O2 thermal plasma. This model was developed to study the evaporation of a solution droplet surrounded by a porous crust in a stagnant rf Ar-O2 thermal plasma under reduced pressure. It considered a three phase system: a liquid core of dissolved Ce(NO 3)3.6H2O in water, a dry porous crust of homogeneously precipitated spherical crystals of equal size, and an Ar-O2 plasma under reduced pressure. The impact of different plasma operating parameters on the temperature and dissolved solid content profiles in the droplet was studied, i.e. surrounding plasma temperature, initial salt content and droplet size, plasma gas composition, and system pressure. Temperature and composition dependant thermophysical properties were used. The model was solved in a moving boundary frame using an ALE approach and considering Stefan flow. It provided the necessary information to understand the droplet to particle transformation steps in regions where in-flight probing was unfeasible, i.e. torch zone.</description><creator>Castillo Martinez, Ian Altri.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Solid oxide fuel cells.</subject><subject>Plasma (Ionized gases) -- Industrial applications.</subject><subject>Cerium oxides.</subject><title>Study of CeO₂ synthesis from liquid precursors in a RF-inductively coupled plasma reactor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784q16m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w3449</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r93q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ivermectin (IVM) is the only safe drug for mass-treatment of onchocerciasis. IVM-resistance has been reported in gastrointestinal nematode parasites of animals. A reduction in response to IVM in Onchocerca volvulus could have significant consequences for the onchocerciasis control programs. Over the last few years, studies have reported genetic selection or reduced responses to IVM in some O. volvulus populations. The risk of a recrudescence of the disease was recently reported with the emergence of resistant adult parasite population in Ghana. It is important to understand the effects of IVM on O. volvulus populations to be able to identify genetic markers to follow IVM selection in the field. In this study, O. volvulus samples were derived from a clinical trial in Cameroon, in which patients were sampled before, and following three years (1994-1997) of IVM treatments. There were four treatment groups: 150mug/kg (1xp.a. or 4xp.a.) and 800mug/kg (1xp.a. or 4xp.a.). DNA from macrofilariae was genotyped for beta-tubulin and P-glycoprotein-like protein (PLP) gene, as well as two control genes and other loci. Reproductive organs of female worms were analyzed by microscopy. A correlation was established between the reproductive status of the female worms and beta-tubulin genotype with the beta-tubulin heterozygous female worms being less fertile than the homozygous female worms. This disadvantage in fertility seemed to disappear after repeated exposure with IVM. We have found evidence that repeated IVM treatment selects for specific alleles of beta-tubulin and PLP. We observed that IVM selection pressure was higher in the female worms than in the male worms. Additionally, loss of polymorphism and selection pressure were higher following thirteen three-monthly doses of IVM compared to annual doses of IVM. Moreover, we found evidence of excess of homozygosity in O. volvulus population, that may be caused by non-random mating and/or subdivision population, which may have implication for the control program. PLP and beta-tubulin genes appear to be promising DNA markers for field use to follow IVM selection. In this perspective, alternative control measures could be considered locally in regions where gene selection is apparent, reducing the likelihood that IVM resistance would develop further and spread.</description><creator>Bourguinat, Catherine.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Onchocerciasis -- Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>Onchocerca volvulus -- Effect of drugs on.</subject><subject>Drug resistance.</subject><subject>Onchocerca volvulus -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Ivermectin.</subject><title>Effects of ivermectin on Onchocerca volvulus adult worms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr72x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r93q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm28v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>G protein coupled receptors, G proteins and their downstream effectors adenylyl cyclase (ACs) were thought to transiently interact at the plasma membrane by random collisions following agonist stimulation. However a growing number of studies have suggested that a major revision of this paradigm was necessary to account for signal transduction specificity and efficiency. The revised model suggests that signalling proteins are pre-assembled as stable macromolecular complexes together with modulators of their activity prior to receptor activation. How and where these signalling complexes form and the mechanisms governing their assembly and maintenance are not completely understood yet. Initially, we addressed this question by exploring AC2 interaction with beta2-adrenergic receptors (beta2ARs) and heterotrimeric G proteins as parts of a pre-assembled signalling complex. Using a combination of biophysical and biochemical techniques, we showed that AC2 interacts with them before it is trafficked to the cell surface in transfected HEK-293 cells. These interactions are constitutive and do not require stimulation by receptor agonists. Furthermore, the use of dominant-negative Rab/Sar monomeric GTPases and dominant-negative heterotrimeric G protein subunits proved that AC2/beta2AR and AC2/Gbetagamma interactions occurred in the ER as measured using both BRET and co-immunoprecipitation experiments, while interaction of the Galpha subunits with the above complexes occurred at a slightly later stage. Both Galpha and Gbetagamma played a role in stabilizing these complexes. Our data also demonstrated that stimulation of AC was still possible when the complex remained on the inside of the cell but was reduced when the GalphaS/AC2 interaction was blocked, suggesting that the addition of the GalphaS subunit was required to render the nascent complexes functional prior to trafficking to proper sites of action. Next, we tackled the issue of higher order assembly of effectors and G proteins, using two different AC isoforms and GalphaS as a model. We demonstrated that AC2 can form heterodimers with AC5 through direct molecular interaction in unstimulated HEK-293 cells. AC2/5 heterodimerization resulted in a reduced total level of AC2 expression, which affected cellular accumulation of cAMP upon forskolin stimulation. The AC2/5 complex was stable in presence of receptor or forskolin stimulation. We provided evidence that co-expression with GalphaS increased the affinity of AC2 for AC5 as monitored by BRET. In particular, the complex formed by AC2/5 lead to synergistic accumulation of cAMP in presence of GalphaS and forskolin, with respect to either of the parent AC isoforms themselves. Finally, we also showed that this complex can be detected in native tissues, as AC2 and AC5 could be co-immunoprecipiated from lysates of mouse heart. Taken together, we provided evidence for stable formation of signalling complexes involving receptor/G proteins/adenylyl cyclase or G proteins/heterodimeric adenylyl cyclases and that G proteins play a crucial role for their assembly and function.</description><creator>Baragli, Alessandra.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Heterotrimeric GTP-Binding Proteins.</subject><subject>Receptors, Adrenergic, beta-2.</subject><subject>Adenylate Cyclase.</subject><title>Assembly and function of multimeric adenylyl cyclase signalling complexes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92gb918.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm28v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp89n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vitamin D is a precursor to a steroid hormone, 1,25 dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D). After its discovery and the characterization of its receptor, the vitamin D receptor (VDR), it was initially thought only to be involved in calcium homeostasis, but further research revealed an important role for vitamin D in the regulation of cell growth and differentiation of such cells as osteoblasts and bone marrow adipocytes. 1,25(OH)2D has also been shown to be a strong inhibitor and pro-differentiator of keratinocytes. The anti-proliferative and pro-differentiative properties of this hormone have led to studies where 1,25(OH)2D anticancer properties were assessed and initial findings that showed a requirement of other factors beyond VDR to induce 1,25(OH)2D signaling led to the identification of the retinoid X receptor, a common heterodimeric partner for several hormone receptors. The focus of thesis was to further elucidate the structure-function relationship of both the vitamin D receptor and the retinoid X receptor. Additionally, contributions to work directed towards further identifying the effects of vitamin D on osteoblast differentiation and survival. Interactions of 1,25(OH) 2D3 with its cognate receptor, identifying a key amino acid (Tryptophan 286) required for ligand contact and transcriptional activation, are described in Chapter 2. Mechanisms of vitamin D action on mesenchymal stem cell differentiation, promotion of osteoblast induction and maturation, and inhibition of adipocyte differentiation, are eluicidated in Chapter 3. Chapter 4 illustrates the effects of RAS/RAF/Mitogen-activated protein kinase mediated RXRalpha phosphorylation on the three-dimensional structure of the RXR/nuclear receptor partner heterodimers. Furthermore, this chapter reveals the inhibitory effect of the phosphorylation of a critical amino acid (serine 260) on the interaction of the AF-2 domain of the RXR with several coactivators, resulting in a decrease in the signaling potential of multiple steroid hormone receptors. The findings of this thesis further the knowledge of several areas of vitamin D biology, including both the canonical areas of bone formation, and the non-canonical area of vitamin D and cancer.</description><creator>Macoritto, Michael.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Bone and Bones -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Retinoid X Receptors -- genetics.</subject><subject>Osteogenesis.</subject><subject>Hormones -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Phosphorylation.</subject><subject>Ligands.</subject><subject>Receptors, Calcitriol -- genetics.</subject><title>Mechanisms of vitamin D receptor and retinoid X receptor mediated hormone resistance and cell differentiation in normal and cancer cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kv001.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp89n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zx92s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studying the biosynthesis, utilization and transport of cholesterol as well as the balance between these pathways may allow us to understand better how to keep its harmful deposition in arteries to a minimum. The goal of my thesis was to identify a novel player, namely the acid sphingomyelinase (ASM), in cellular and plasma cholesterol metabolism by elucidating its regulatory and mechanistic functions. In our families with high-density lipoprotein-cholesterol (HDL-C) deficiency, one kindred was found to have mutations for the sphingomyelin phosphodiesterase-1 (SMPD-1). This gene codes for lysosomal and secretory ASM and its mutations cause the recessive disorder of Niemann-Pick type A/B (NPD-A/B). My thesis, based on the study of the gene and the protein defect in this family, has led to four important discoveries. First, SMPD-1 mutations are significantly associated with low HDL-C. Second, in order to unveil the mechanism by which ASM contributes to the regulation of HDL-C levels, we investigated the cellular lipid transport in NPD-B fibroblasts. We showed that lysosomal ASM defects lead to co-segregation and co-localization of sphingomyelin (SM) and cholesterol. However, the SM accumulation does not rate-limit the efflux ability of NPD-B cells. Third, we set up the electrospray ionization-mass spectrometry to give an in-depth qualitative and quantitative phospholipid characterization of HDL particles generated from NPD-B. We found that their SM content is significantly elevated. We subsequently provided evidence that the SM content of HDL could be modulated by secretory ASM. Together with other plasma enzymes including lecithin-cholesterol acyl transferase, secretroy ASM appears to regulate the maturation and clearance of HDL-C from the plasma. Finally, we examined the molecular nature of the NPD-B pathophysiology by investigating the structure-function relationship of ASM. We demonstrated that the C-terminal region of ASM plays a critical role in the enzyme conformation that dictates its enzymatic function and secretion. In summary, our lessons on NPD-B have enabled us to identify ASM as an important player in lipoprotein cholesterol metabolism. Because HDL-C is inversely associated with coronary heart disease, our findings opened a novel therapeutic avenue in the search of preventive strategies against heart disease in our society.</description><creator>Lee, Karen Ching Yin, 1978-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Sphingomyelin Phosphodiesterase -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Niemann-Pick Disease, Type B.</subject><subject>Cholesterol, HDL -- metabolism.</subject><title>Roles of acid sphingomyelinase in HDL-cholesterol metabolism : lessons from Niemann-Pick disease type I</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tk15n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zx92s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580r309</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The relationship between colorectal cancer (CRC) and folate metabolism is complex. Dietary folate, depending on the timing and dose, may either prevent or enhance tumour initiation and/or growth, and polymorphisms in the genes encoding folate-metabolising enzymes may also modulate risk. In this thesis, the Apcmin/+ mouse model of CRC was used to investigate the effect of nutritional and genetic disturbances in folate metabolism on tumourigenesis and to examine various mechanisms. The reduced folate carrier I (RFC1) is responsible for the cellular uptake and intestinal absorption of folate, primarily the 5-methyltetrahydrofolate (5-methylTHF) derivative. Methionine synthase (MTR) uses 5-methylTHF to remethylate homocysteine to methionine, which may be activated and used to methylate substrates such as DNA. 5-MethylTHF is also the product of the methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR)-catalysed reduction of 5,10-methyleneTHF, which is also used to convert dUMP to dTMP. Adenoma number and load were reduced in Rfc1+/-Apc min/+ mice, compared with Rfc1+/+Apc min/+ mice, but were similar in Mtr+/-Apc min/+ and Mtr+/+ Apcmin/+ mice. Neither Rfc1 nor Mtr genotype affected global DNA methylation, apoptosis or plasma homocysteine (tHcy) levels. In the experiments involving Mtr mice, dietary folate deficiency increased adenoma number, plasma tHcy, and apoptosis, and decreased global DNA methylation. Neither Mtr nor Rfc1 genotype affected the dUTP/dTTP ratio in the intestine of mice not predisposed to adenoma formation. Adenoma number was decreased in Mthfr+/-Apc min/+ mice (compared with Mthfr+/+Apc min/+ mice) and in Mthfr+/+Apc min/+ offspring of Mthfr+/- mothers (compared with Mthfr+/+Apcmin/+ offspring of Mthfr+/+ mothers). A folate-deficient diet, when initiated prior to conception, significantly decreased adenoma number and decreased global DNA methylation. Overall, adenoma number was inversely correlated with plasma tHcy, dUTP/dTTP ratio and apoptosis. When initiated at three weeks of age, a folate-enriched diet significantly increased adenoma number in Apcmin/+ mice. In the intestines of mice not predisposed to adenoma formation, Mthfr deficiency decreased, and folic acid deficiency increased, the dUTP/dTTP ratio. These results support the evidence that MTHFR polymorphisms are protective in CRC tumourigenesis and that depending on stage or predisposition, folate may inhibit or enhance tumour growth.</description><creator>Lawrance, Andrea Karin.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>5-Methyltetrahydrofolate-Homocysteine S-Methyltransferase -- genetics.</subject><subject>Folic Acid -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Colorectal Neoplasms -- genetics.</subject><title>The impact of genetic and nutritional disturbances of folate metabolism on tumourigenesis in a mouse model of colorectal cancer /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rz27f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580r309</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f9709</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bcr-abl expression being associated with anti-apoptotic signaling and expression of DNA repair enzymes, we surmised that single molecules capable of blocking abl tyrosine kinase (TK) function and damaging DNA should lead to compounds with potency superior to that of GleevecRTM. To this end, we designed novel agents termed "combi-molecules" programmed to not only behave as bcr-abl inhibitors on their own, but also to further degrade to another inhibitor and a DNA damaging species. The released inhibitor was designed to sustain bcr-abl inhibition following degradation of the combi-molecule and the DNA damaging species to activate pathways leading to apoptosis. To model this strategy termed "combi-targeting", we synthesized ZRCM5 (a monoalkyltriazene) that showed antiproliferative activity superior to that of the classical DNA damaging agent TemodalRTM, but not to that of Gleevec RTM. This result was imputed to the rather weak bcr-abl inhibitory activity of ZRCM5 and its strong DNA damaging property. Another prototype designed to contain an aniline mustard moiety (AK04) was a strong bcr-abl inhibitor but a poor DNA alkylating agent. Its cytotoxic activity was again stronger than that of the clinical alkylating agent chlorambucil but inferior to that of GleevecRTM. Further chemical studies directed at structural modification of the benzamide moiety led to the synthesis of ZRF1 with strong potency against bcr-abl TK and strong DNA damaging property. This novel optimized combi-molecule showed a 1.6-3-fold greater potency than GleevecRTM against bcr-abl expressing cells. Further investigation with ZRF1, showed that its cytotoxic potency was dependent on the p53 wild-type status of the cells. In cells expressing wild-type p53, p21 transactivation was associated with cell cycle arrest and that of Bax with apoptosis. In addition to, the pro-apoptotic effect of bcr-abl inhibition, these multiple mechanisms of action may synergistically enhance the cytotoxic potency of ZRF1 in p53 wild-type cells. The study conclusively demonstrated that p53 is a major determinant for the cytotoxic advantage of the novel combi-molecular approach in chronic myelogenous leukemia (CML), a disease in which 70-85% of all cases express wild-type p53.</description><creator>Katsoulas, Athanasia.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Leukemia, Myeloid, Chronic -- drug therapy.</subject><subject>Protein-Tyrosine Kinases -- antagonists &amp; inhibitors.</subject><title>Design and mechanism of action of novel agents termed &amp;quot;combi-molecules&amp;quot; engineered for tandem targeting for Bcr-abl expressing leukemia cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k8827.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f9709</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139574s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Entamoeba histolytica, etiological agent of amebiasis, continues to be a significant threat to human health worldwide. The disease affects 10% of the world's population and leads to an estimated 100, 000 deaths a year. The parasite's surface Gal-lectin is an immunodominant protein that also mediates colonization and pathogenicity. The Gal-lectin is the most promising vaccine candidate against amebiasis. However, the immune mechanisms involved in protection against disease remain unclear. The objective of this study was to characterize the immunological basis of the host defense mechanisms using a Gal-lectin based vaccine. Exposure of the Gal-lectin with immature dendritic cells increased cell maturation and activation and upregulated co-stimulatory molecules and pro-inflammatory cytokines production. Dendritic cell activation was dependent on NF-kappaB and MAPK activation. In vaccination studies, the adjuvant effect of CpG-ODN, a synthetic oligodeoxynucleotide capable of stimulating Th1 immune responses enhanced the immune response to the Gal-lectin when administered systemically or mucosally. Protected animals had elevated anti-Gal-lectin serum and stool IgA antibodies capable of blocking parasite adherence in vitro. Analysis of cytokine responses in vaccinated and protected animals revealed increased IFN-gamma production compared to controls. Finally, E. histolytica DNA was shown to activate macrophages in a TLR9 and MYD88-dependent manner. Immunized gerbils with Gal-lectin and E. histolytica DNA induced protective immunity against a challenge infection. Taken together, these findings underscore the importance of multivalent subunit vaccines in Th1 mediated immune responses in host defense against amebiasis.</description><creator>Ivory, Catherine P.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Entamoeba histolytica.</subject><subject>Amebiasis -- Vaccination.</subject><subject>DNA vaccines.</subject><subject>Lectins.</subject><title>The Gal-lectin and innate host defenses against Entamoeba histolytica /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zx932.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139574s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qt626</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The high performance of bone implants depends on the positive response of osteoblasts to the surface of the materials manufactured for the implant. Cell response in turn strongly depends on the nature of the initial interaction of macromolecules involved in cell adhesion and proliferation with the atomic structure of the surface of the material used for the implant. The initial interaction between bone specific extracellular matrix proteins and the solid substrate influences cell response at the cell-implant interface. This interaction is crucial for implant stability, long-term durability, and osseointegration. Despite extensive research undertaken to develop high-quality material for implants in order to improve the cell-substrate interaction, little is known about the significance of the atomic structure of the substrate and the role of molecular machinery involved in cell-substrate interaction. Using a combined approach involving material sciences and cell and molecular biology, the objectives of this research are to evaluate the response of pre-osteoblast and fibroblast cell lines to novel bulk polycrystalline and single crystal titanium based material and assess the role of crystal size and orientation. Novel bulk nano-structured titanium substrates were produced by the process of high-pressure torsion (HPT). These materials have a significant advantage compared to conventional titanium-based materials by having higher surface wettablity, mechanical properties as well as a distinct surface oxide layer and atomic structure. A co-culture system was adapted to investigate the differential response of pre-osteoblast and fibroblast cell lines to titanium and titanium dioxide single-crystal substrates. The results of this study provide clear evidence that crystal size and specific crystallographic orientation can be used to improve cell adhesion and proliferation. The nanostructured titanium substrates show strong interaction with pre-osteoblast cells as evident by the higher expression of fibronectin and the formation of extensive focal adhesion. Differential cell behaviour of pre-osteoblasts and fibroblasts are observed in cultures grown on the substrates with specific crystallographic orientations. The degree of cell attachment of the pre-osteoblasts is considerably higher on Ti-(1120) crystal face compared with the fibroblasts. These findings have profound implications for the improved osseointegration and inhibition of fibrosis leading to long-term implant consolidation and stability.</description><creator>Faghihi, Shahabeddin.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Nanostructures -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Titanium -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Cell Adhesion.</subject><subject>Bone Plates.</subject><title>Effects of crystal size and orientation of novel titanium-based substrates on cell adhesion : implication for medical implants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vc27m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qt626</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c77m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since its identification in 1997 as the common receptor for Coxsackie and adenovirus (CAR) multiple lines of evidence argue in favor of CAR contributing to aspects of cell adhesion in addition to serving as a viral receptor. Nevertheless, a precise biological role for CAR remains to be identified suggesting the receptor may participate in a variety of cellular functions that reflect its tissue specific and developmentally regulated expression. This thesis elucidates aspects of CAR biology in mature striated muscle by providing studies that encompass (i) its physiological cellular/subcellular localization and expression in mature striated muscle (ii) its expression profile in human diseased skeletal muscle and (iii) the potential consequences of its sustained expression in mature striated muscle where its levels would otherwise be highly attenuated. In non-diseased, mature striated muscle despite low and barely detectable levels of the CAR transcript (cardiac and skeletal muscle respectively), we identified CAR as a novel component of the neuromuscular junction and showed its expression to be isoform-specific in contrast to the intercalated discs, where both predominant CAR isoforms are detected. We then investigated the expression of CAR at the level of human skeletal muscle disease. From these studies we observed that in diseases characterized by active necrosis and regeneration, extrasynaptic CAR expression is detectable in regenerating fibers and co-expressed with other previously described markers of regeneration at a high degree of coincidence. Moreover, extrasynaptic CAR expression appears to be a highly reliable indicator of the regenerative process offering potential use at the diagnostic level. Following these investigations, our final studies involved assessing whether sustained CAR expression might affect the normal homeostasis in skeletal and cardiac muscle using a transgenic mouse model. We discovered that transgenic mice expressing sustained high levels of CAR (as seen in the CAR+/+ transgenics) develop a lethal necrotizing myopathy characterized by dual deficiencies in dystrophin and dysferlin, two proteins pivotal in maintaining plasmalemmal integrity, raising the possibility for a previously unrecognized cause of skeletal muscle dysfunction. Collectively these findings argue that in non-diseased mature skeletal and cardiac muscle, CAR expression is restricted to the neuromuscular junction and cardiac intercalated discs but in diseases of skeletal muscle characterized by active necrosis and regeneration, extrasynaptic CAR expression is reexpressed at these sites of injury/repair. In addition they raise the possibility that sustained CAR expression in mature skeletal muscle may be associated with altered muscle homeostasis.</description><creator>Shaw, Christian A.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Enterovirus.</subject><subject>Muscle, Skeletal.</subject><subject>Adenoviridae.</subject><subject>Receptors, Virus.</subject><title>An investigation of the Coxsackie and Adenovirus Receptor in striated muscle /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zf74w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c77m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924g34m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the development of novel methodologies in the template mediated chemical synthesis of lariat and branched nucleic acids. The synthetic branched DNA and RNA may be applicable as probes in the elucidation of the splicing mechanism or as potential therapeutic agents. Furthermore, this body of work describes the novel synthesis of Ru(II) branched DNA as building blocks in the supramolecular assembly of nano-motifs. In general, insight into the utilization of nucleic acids as biological molecules and as nanomaterials is presented at the interface of chemistry and biology. Chapter 2 delineates the regioselective template directed synthesis of Y-RNA via chemical ligation at the branch point of a 5'-phosphate to a 2'-hydroxyl. The branched molecules resemble lariats as they possess the analogous branched architecture. The oligonucleotide components are synthesized from commercially available phosphoramidite building blocks through automated solid-phase synthesis. A unique template directed method in the synthesis of DNA and RNA lariats is proposed in Chapter 3. The regioselective chemical ligation affords wild-type DNA and RNA formed through assembly of a single oligonucleotide strand. A parallel DNA:RNA hybrid association was observed in the preorganized assembly and extensively characterized. Characterization of the Y-RNA and lariat nucleic acids were carried out through techniques such as thermal denaturation analysis, polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis, enzymatic degradation with the RNA lariat debranching enzyme, alkaline treatment as well as MALDI-TOF mass spectrometry. The second part of the thesis exploits DNA as a nanomaterial in the convergent solid-phase synthesis of Ru(II)-DNA conjugates as branched building blocks in the assembly of nanostructures. Chapter 4 describes the synthesis of Ru branched DNA, utilizing cis-[(bpy)2Ru(imidazole) 2]2+ moiety as the vertex tethered to parallel DNA covalently through flexible hexamethylene linkers. Complete physical characterization and preliminary hybridization studies are conducted. The Ru-DNA conjugates presented were found to be unstable to the protocols required for synthesis of mixed sequence derivatives. The stability and scope of synthesis of these molecules are further discussed. As an alternative, Ru-DNA branched complexes of mixed sequences, exhibiting greater stability, were synthesized. The transition metal building blocks of Chapter 5 employ a more rigid branch point, linking two parallel DNA strands through a one methylene spacer to the cis-[Ru(bpy)2 (4,4'-bis(hydroxymethyl)-2,2'-bipyridine)][PF6]2 vertex. Physical characterization and the intrinsic luminescent properties of the transition metal complex were confirmed in both the Ru-branched DNA and hybrized forms. A comparative study of the self-assembly behavior of the Ru-DNA conjugates to that of unmetallated branched DNA was also conducted. Interestingly, results indicate a metal-mediated assembly of almost exclusive formation of one discrete Ru-DNA dimeric cyclic nanostructure, where as unmetallated DNA building blocks produced an array of products. Complete confirmation of these products is presented through PAGE and enzymatic digestions. Finally the synthesis of novel Delta and Λ Ru-branched DNA diastereomers is presented as potential building blocks in the creation of chiral metallo-supramolecular constructs.</description><creator>Mitra, Debbie.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Nucleic acids -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Nanostructured materials.</subject><subject>Nucleic acid probes.</subject><title>Novel synthesis of branched nucleic acids : towards applications in chemical biology and nanotechnology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq593.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924g34m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89db138</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oculopharyngeal Muscular Dystrophy (OPMD) is a late-onset dominant/recessive myopathy caused by the expansion of a polyalanine repeat in exon 1 of the PABPN1 gene. The expression of expanded PABPN1 (expPABPN1) triggers the formation of insoluble nuclear aggregates within muscle fiber nuclei of OPMD patients. These aggregates are enriched in poly(A)RNA and sequester molecular chaperones, ubiquitin and proteasome subunits. In addition to these cellular components, we first identified two novel PABPN1 interacting partners, hnRNPA1 and hnRNPA/B that also localized to the insoluble expPABPN1 aggregates. However, only hnRNPA1 was observed in inclusions of OPMD patients' muscle fiber nuclei. Following this finding, we next established the involvement of the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway in the clearance of misfolded expPABPN1 and provided more insights into the beneficial role of molecular chaperones in OPMD. The inhibition of proteasome correlated with an increase in the aggregation of expPABPN1, suggesting a possible proteasome impairment in OPMD. Conversely, the overexpression of Hsp70 and Hsp40 coincided with a decrease in nuclear aggregates concomitant with a reduced cellular toxicity, suggesting the therapeutic potential of manipulating molecular chaperones levels. Finally, we demonstrated that soluble forms of expPABPN1 are the primary toxic species in OPMD. In the presence of endogenous HSPs, a decrease in expPABPN1 aggregation correlated with an increased cellular toxicity. A defect in polyadenylation or ubiquitination significantly increased expPABPN1 solubility and cell death. Using live-cell imaging, we observed that nuclear aggregates prolonged the survival of expPABPN1-expressing cells, which led us to speculate that protein aggregates are subnuclear structures that preserve cellular homeostasis by depleting the expPABPN1 from the nuclear soluble pool. We propose that the polyalanine expansion in expPABPN1 could enable aberrant protein-protein interactions that would compromise the cellular function of nuclear factors and the expression of genes essential for muscle integrity and differentiation. For instance, expPABPN1 might compromise the function of hnRNP proteins and lead to altered mRNA processing and nucleocytoplasmic export, which can be detrimental to the cell.</description><creator>Messaed, Christiane.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Muscular Dystrophy, Oculopharyngeal -- genetics.</subject><subject>Muscular dystrophy -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Investigation of molecular mechanisms underlying Oculopharyngeal Muscular Dystrophy (OPMD)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602461p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89db138</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nc548</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis summarises research performed with the intent of exploring the many facets of cell death. In the first part of the thesis, the fate of the formin-homology domain containing protein FHOD1 during apoptosis is examined (research performed in the laboratory of Dr. Sophie Roy) and evidence for the cleavage of FHOD1 by caspase-3 at the SVPD616 site is demonstrated. Moreover, the C-terminal FHOD1 cleavage product is shown to translocate to the nucleolus where it inactivates RNA polymerase I transcription. In the second part of the thesis, the role of the RNA-binding protein HuR in cancer cell migration and invasion, as well as in multidrug resistance is determined using RNA interference to knockdown the expression of HuR in HeLa and KB-V1 cells respectively (research performed in the laboratory of Dr. Imed Gallouzi). In this part of the thesis, HuR is shown to promote cancer cell migration and invasion by stabilizing the beta-actin mRNA in a U-rich-dependent manner. Moreover, evidence is shown for the potential involvement of HuR in the phenomenon of multidrug resistance possibly through the post-transcriptional regulation of the multidrug resistance 1 gene.</description><creator>Ménard, Isabelle.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Drug Resistance, Multiple.</subject><subject>RNA-Binding Proteins.</subject><subject>Drug Resistance, Neoplasm.</subject><subject>Apoptosis.</subject><subject>Nuclear Proteins.</subject><subject>Cell Death.</subject><title>Exploring the many facets of cell death</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g3837.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nc548</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032661t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The object of this thesis is to present various applications of the theory of cosmological perturbations. Within are contained a number of manuscripts, each concerned with a separate aspect of the theory. The thesis itself begins with a general overview of cosmological perturbation theory designed to be accessible to the non-specialist. Both the classical and quantum first order theory are considered. Back-reaction, via the formalism of the Effective Energy Momentum Tensor (EEMT) is reviewed. Subsequent chapters are more specialized dealing with various applications of the theory. At first order, topics discussed include the classicalization of cosmological perturbations (chapter 2), and the effects of including the dilaton and its fluctuations on a novel mechanism for the production of inhomogeneities in string gas cosmology (chapter 3). At second order, an original solution to the Dark Energy problem is proposed (chapter 4), and the effects of back-reaction on the power spectrum, including the spectral index and the gaussianity, are examined (chapter 5).</description><creator>Martineau, Patrick.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>String models.</subject><subject>Cosmology.</subject><subject>Dark energy (Astronomy)</subject><title>Topics in cosmological fluctuations : linear order and beyond</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462894h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032661t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cp51j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Restenosis is the major cause of the failure of reconstruction methods to restore the blood flow in atherosclerotic arteries. Restenosis results from neointima formation and consequent constrictive remodelling. Vascular smooth muscle cell (VSMC) migration from the tunica media toward the intima is crucial in neointima genesis. The prerequisite for VSMC migratory activity is the modulation from the differentiated (contractile) to the de-differentiated (noncontractile) phenotype. VSMC phenotype change is associated with the altered expression of integrins. alpha8beta1 integrin is upregulated in cell types with contractile properties, including myofibroblasts and mesangial kidney cells. It is one of the integrins that is intensely expressed in mature VSMCs. alpha8beta1 integrin expression during vascular injury and its role in VSMC function have not been studied so far. In this work, a rat model of carotid angioplasty was used to mimic vascular injury in humans. alpha8beta1 integrin was downregulated in the tunica media concomitantly with loss of the contractile phenotype. In vitro study revealed that it is a differentiation marker of VSMCs. To test the functional significance of the association between alpha8 integrin and the VSMC phenotype, short interference RNA was deployed to silence the alpha8 integrin gene. alpha8 integrin gene silencing heightened VSMC migratory activity as well as modulation of the VSMC phenotype in favour of the noncontractile state. In addition, alpha8 integrin overexpression induced re-differentiation of VSMCs and attenuated their migratory activity. It is, therefore, suggested that alpha8 integrin overexpression after vascular injury might control VSMC migration and neointima formation. On the other hand, alpha8 integrin gene silencing led to a reduced growth rate, which indicated a dichotomy between VSMC migration and proliferation. In the later stages of neointima formation, constrictive remodeling plays a major role in late lumen loss. Our data demonstrated that alpha8 integrin is upregulated in the neointima during constrictive remodeling with concomitant luminal narrowing. The importance of this finding was highlighted by results showing that alpha8 integrin was required for the VSMC contractile phenotype evoked by transforming growth factor-beta (TFG-beta) and TFG-beta-induced myofibroblastic differentiation of Rat1 fibroblasts. Thus, it appears that alpha8 integrin expression blockade might reduce contractile remodeling and late lumen loss. Although the mechanism of alpha8 integrin signaling is not yet clear, our findings demonstrate that the alpha8 integrin-induced contractile phenotype is blocked by RhoA inhibitors. Furthermore, alpha8 integrin and RhoA are co-immunoprecipitated, and alpha8 integrin gene silencing reduces RhoA activity. Hence, it is postulated that alpha8-RhoA signaling might be closely intertwined. Altogether, these studies indicate that alpha8 integrin is a contractile marker of VSMCs and a negative regulator of VSMC migration. Therefore, forced alpha8 integrin expression may be applied to reduce neointima formation. However, alpha8 integrin upregulation during constrictive remodeling concomitant with late lumen loss suggest that it could be involved in lumen narrowing. It seems likely that in therapeutic strategies to reduce restenosis the timeline of interference might be very important. Therefore, alpha8 integrin gene silencing in the later stages of neointima formation might be beneficial.</description><creator>Zargham, Ramin.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Receptors, Fibronectin.</subject><subject>Coronary Restenosis.</subject><subject>Angioplasty, Balloon.</subject><title>Alpha]8[beta]1 integrin and vascular injury : role of [alpha]8[beta1 integrin in restenosis after balloon injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h096j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp51j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623h20x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regulators of G protein signaling (RGSs) are negative regulators of G protein coupled receptors (GPCRs). Our lab has demonstrated that yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae is a useful system to study RGS and G protein signaling. Mammalian RGSs can be expressed in yeast and favored to interact with mammalian GPCRs as well. Based on the observation that human RGS1 causes yeast cell growth arrest, I therefore used RGS1 expressing yeast cells to screen a mouse T cell cDNA library in order to find potential interacting proteins. From the screen, I identified a mouse sphingomyelin synthase 1 (SMS1) cDNA. By using a series of different apoptotic stimuli, such as hydrogen peroxide, osmotic stress, exogenous ceramide and its precursors, high temperature etc., SMS1 expression was found to suppress cell growth arrest and prevent viability decline, indicating that SMS1 represents an anti-apoptotic protein that functions by decreasing the intracellular level of pro-apoptotic ceramide. Gene analysis further indicated that the SMS1 gene consists of 16 exons spread over a 256kb portion of mouse chromosome 19. It is alternatively spliced to produce 4 different transcripts (SMS1alpha1, SMS1alpha2, SMS1beta and SMS1gamma) and encode 3 different proteins (SMS1alpha, SMS1beta and SMS1gamma). Notably, I found that SMS1beta protein does not interfere with SMS1alpha anti-apoptotic function, although both of these two proteins contain the protein-protein interaction domain, sterile alpha motif (SAM), at their N-terminus. I also carried out a study to examine GPCR-RGS interactions using the yeast expression system. Our lab had noticed that there was an extra RGS5 related protein that was detected by western blot analysis in the protein extracts prepared from yeast and HEK293 cells expressing RGS5. The size of the band was approximately 2 times the molecular weight of RGS5, indicating the possibility that RGS5 forms a dimer. To further examine this hypothesis, I, therefore, performed a series of experiments, included yeast 2 hybrid assays, to demonstrate that RGS5 does interact with itself. This is the first report that RGS can form a dimer. The implications for this finding are discussed in detail.</description><creator>Yang, Zhao, 1970-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>RGS Proteins.</subject><subject>Receptors, G-Protein-Coupled.</subject><title>Identification of a novel anti-apoptotic protein and characterization of mammalian regulators of G protein signaling (RGSs) in yeast</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mk088.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623h20x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r18z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:17:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis falls into the field of tactile displays that are meant to produce realistic tactile sensations, which replicate tactile sensations arising naturally when humans interact with the real world. To begin with we need to know the biomechanics of the glabrous skin in human subjects. To this end, small patches of fingerpad skin are tested in vivo for their biomechanical properties under tangential loading. The skin is quasi-statically stretched and sheared to obtain its effective Young's modulus. Moreover, isotonic and isometric testing conditions are implemented to identify the viscoelasticity model of the skin. The results show a great deal of variability across subjects and it is observed that the glabrous skin exhibits nonlinear stiffening in tangential traction. The skin is consistently more elastic across the ridges, compared to along the ridges, regardless of the location of the sample on the fingerpad. The skin behaves visco-elastically but relaxes about twice as fast as it creeps. Finally, it is found that under large deformation, there is consistently 80% of hysteretic loss for a wide range of loading conditions. Based on the results obtained by controlled testing, a high performance distributed display is designed. The display has a compact, yet modular structure. Its 6x10 piezo bimorph actuator array has a spatial resolution of 1.8x1.2 millimeters and a wide temporal bandwidth. The actuator mounting method is improved from conventional cantilever to dual-pinned lever, giving the actuator the capability of optimally coupling with glabrous skin. By using previously measured biomechanical data of the skin, we tune the parameters of the actuators to be optimal in terms of real deflection when they couple with the skin. The blocked force of the individual actuators can be adjusted from 0.15 N to 0.22 N to accommodate different applications. It is self-contained in a 150 cm3 volume and may be interfaced to most computers, provided that two analog outputs and six digital IO lines are available. Both public demonstration and psychophysical experiments have validated its effectiveness in rendering virtual tactile features. The availability of a display raises the question of what signals should be used to drive it in order to render specific sensations. Some progress is made in this direction by analyzing the contact mechanics of fundamental cases, such as isolated indentation and traveling undulation. With the intention of explaining a tactile illusion engendered by straining the fingertip skin tangentially in a progressive wave pattern, resulting in the perception of a moving undulating surface, we carry out a contact mechanics analysis to derive the strain tensor field induced by a sinusoidal surface sliding on a finger, as well as the field created by a tactile transducer array deforming the fingerpad skin by lateral traction. We find that the first field can be well approximated by the second. Our results imply that, first, tactile displays using lateral skin deformation can generate tactile sensations similar to those using normal skin deformation. Second, there is a synthesis approach to achieve this result given constraints on the design of tactile stimulators. Third, the mechanoreceptors embedded in the skin must respond to the deviatoric part of the strain tensor field and not to its volumetric part. Finally, many tactile stimuli might represent for the brain an inverse problem to be solved. Using the results of these investigations, we have demonstrated the feasibility of producing high-fidelity virtual tactile sensations.</description><creator>Wang, Qi, 1971-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Haptic devices -- Design and construction.</subject><subject>Virtual reality.</subject><title>A biomechanically optimized tactile transducer and tactile synthesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602462z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r18z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17400</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>