<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:27:41Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22375" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p571v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:55:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research was designed to provide information concerning the developmental differences in early language production and comprehension between 21 month-old first born and second born children. Furthermore, the study explored the assumption that more opportunities to hear conversations between the parent and the older sibling provide an advantage for second born children in learning personal pronouns. Spontaneous speech productions of 16 first born children were compared to those of 16 second born children while in dyadic interactions with their mothers. First born children were observed in two 25 minute free-play dyadic interactions with their mothers. Second born children were observed in one 25 minute free-play mother-child dyadic interaction and in one 25 minute free-play mother-child-older sibling triadic interaction. All children were administered controlled tasks involving production and comprehension of first and second person pronouns. Compared to first borns, second born children are not significantly delayed in general language development. Second borns' speech productions differ depending on whether or not their older sibling was present. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Letsas, Ranya</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Language acquisition</subject><subject>Children -- Language</subject><title>Developmental differences in early language production and comprehension between 21 month-old first born and second born children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s594b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p571v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk95r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:55:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Green Movement is assumed to introduce a new way to organize society, politics, economics, and technology in such a way that environmental damage will be minimized. This new approach has been called the "New Environmental Paradigm", denoting its holistic character, as much as its antithesis to the dominant "Western Paradigm". My investigation of North American environmental movement led me to conclude that the Green Movement is neither an ideologically nor a socially homogeneous movement. Instead, it consists of two distinct movements. The first one is "politics oriented", influenced by the New Left ideology. The second social movement, previously unnoticed by sociological literature, is "experience oriented", highly activist, influenced by Naturalist philosophies, and the one which really introduces a new societal paradigm.</description><creator>Marangudakis, Manussos</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Green movement -- North America</subject><subject>Environmental protection -- Political aspects -- North America</subject><title>Emerging ideologies in the environmental movement : the N. American case of "deep" and "social ecology"</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz982.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk95r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q748h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:55:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines Quebec public opinion towards the Spanish Civil War. It is based on a systematic analysis of editorials and articles from ten Montreal-based newspapers, representing divergent points of view. It suggests that, contrary to the popular interpretation, Quebec francophones did not unanimously support General Franco during the war; nor did all of the province's anglophones endorse the cause of the Spanish Popular Front. Support for General Franco and the Spanish Republic in Montreal transcended linguistic lines, and cleavages other than language, such as religion, ideology and social class, influenced public opinion towards the war.</description><creator>Charpentier, Marc, 1965-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Foreign public opinion</subject><title>Columns on the march : Montreal newspapers interpret the Spanish Civil War 1936-1939</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sk59v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q748h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f38m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:55:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study is a comparison of two works of German language literature of the 70's, Verena Stefan's Hautungen and Peter Handke's die linkshandige Frau, which examines the background of both works, their themes, structure, style and language, as well as their interpretation of women's emancipation. A study of the literary background of the works will be undertaken, leading to a comparison of literary and social orientations reflected in the works. The central themes of both works will be examined in a parallel fashion to illuminate thematic similarities and differences. An interpretation of both works as women's literature and their emancipatory tendencies (conscious and unconscious) will be undertaken, to analyze the true extent of emancipatory tendencies in both works. Finally the genre, style and language of both works will be analysed, to define essential stylistic differences between the two works.</description><creator>Dargelies, Susanne</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Stefan, Verena. 1947- Häutungen</subject><subject>Handke, Peter. Linkshändige Frau</subject><title>Der Blick von Aussen und Innen : ein Werkvergleich von Verena Stefans Häutungen und Peter Handkes linkshändige Frau</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr98x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f38m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042v03c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:55:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Western aesthetic convention represents an accrual of inherited societal perspectives on the artist, the artifact and its consumer. A review of its history and the etymology of its terminology discloses a twofold problem. The first aspect concerns the separation of the manufacture of aesthetic objects from their economic raison d'etre. The second involves the categorization of these artifacts into art or craft. This problem is compounded when considering Western judgements on non-Western aesthetics. Inuit handicraft provides an appropriate model to illustrate the fact that present convention and nomenclature prove inadequate in addressing both intra and especially extra-cultural concerns. A broader and more inclusive orientation is needed.</description><creator>Esbin, Howard Bennett</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Aesthetics</subject><subject>Art -- Prices.</subject><subject>Inuit art.</subject><subject>Eskimo art.</subject><title>Western aesthetic conventions and valuation of the artisanal production of non-western cultures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505163c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v03c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education in the Arts</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579t340</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the campaign waged against Vichy's National Revolution by Robert Brasillach, Marcel Deat, Jacques Doriot, and Pierre Drieu La Rochelle. It explores the particular issues of contention separating Vichy and the Paris ultras as well as shedding light on the final evolution of a representative segment of the fascist phenomenon in France.</description><creator>Hickey, Sean</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Drieu La Rochelle, Pierre, 1893-1945 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Doriot, Jacques, 1898-1945 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Déat, Marcel, 1894- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>France -- Politics and government -- 1940-1945</subject><subject>Brasillach, Robert, 1909-1945 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>The Vichy regime and its National Revolution in the political writings of Robert Brasillach, Marcel Déat, Jacques Doriot, and Pierre Drieu La Rochelle.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qn10n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579t340</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h560c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possibility of considering the ethical domain as cognitive is a principal concern of contemporary moral philosophy. Following an analysis of Hilary Putnam's internal realism, I discuss how our usual conceptions of truth and factuality should be modified in order to render philosophical discourse free of the fact/value distinction. I then present a response to Gilbert Harman's argument for non-cognitivism in ethics and argue that, within an internal realism that incorporates such modified conceptions, the non-cognitive argument no longer carriers any weight.</description><creator>François, Any Marie-Gérard</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Realism</subject><subject>Knowledge, Theory of</subject><subject>Ethics, Modern -- 20th century</subject><title>Value as part of reality : an internal realist response to non-cognitivism in ethics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kr62d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h560c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw13b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alcoholism is a prevalent multifactorial disease with both genetic and environmental components. Monoamine oxidase (MAO) has been proposed as a susceptibility marker for familial alcoholism but consistent evidence of either specific MAO variants in alcoholics or allelic segregation in at-risk families has not been presented. Two structural genes on the X chromosome encode two forms of the enzyme, MAO-A and MAO-B. Kinetic constants for platelet MAO-B and restriction fragment length polymorphisms for MAO-A were determined in alcoholics with multigenerational family histories of alcoholism, high risk relatives of familial alcoholics and low risk controls with no family history of alcoholism. Mean elevated levels of MAO-B deamination were observed in alcoholics and high risk individuals. Alcoholic and high risk individuals did not differ from non-alcoholics with respect to MAO-B tryptamine affinity or MAO-A polymorphisms. Significant non-genetic factors influence MAO-B activity. MAO variants are unlikely to define a genetic predisposition to alcoholism.</description><creator>Parboosingh, Jillian S.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Alcoholism -- Susceptibility</subject><subject>Monoamine oxidase.</subject><title>Biochemical and molecular analysis of monoamine oxidase in alcoholics, high risk subjects and low risk controls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d5331.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw13b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z655s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis provides an account of the discussions of the "team" concept in health care literature since the early 1920s. It is argued that by adopting a historical, social constructionist stance, this thesis makes an original contribution to the literature. The research consisted of an inductive analysis of the "team" literature aiming to typify the ways in which the "team" concept has been constructed and historical, national or professional differences which have occurred. Historically, claims about "teamwork" in health care have occurred in four phases: (1) a statement of basic issues and themes; (2) the emergence of ideas of flexibility and adaptability; (3) a period of optimism; and (4) the co-existence of positive, sceptical, and critical claims. The professional and national differences in claims-making activities are also discussed. The least challenged claims about, and recent re-evaluations of, the "team" concept are also discussed. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Hermary, Martin Ted</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Health care teams</subject><title>An analysis of the "team" concept in the health care literature /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp45v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z655s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881n112</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We initially adopted the macrophage isolation and culture techniques described by Howard Gendelman et al. for the isolation and study of macrophage-tropic strains of HIV. This work eventually led to the study of cell to cell transmission of virus in the infection of macrophages. To this end, we used chronically infected cell lines expressing virus strains which were unable to establish infection in macrophage cultures in the cell-free state (i.e. by exposure of cells to virus-containing supernatants). In cocultivation experiments, we observed that direct interaction of these chronically infected cells with target macrophages yielded low level infection which was detectable by very sensitive methods such as enzyme immunoassay and indirect immunofluorescence detection of viral antigen, as well as polymerase chain reaction amplification of viral DNA. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>St-Luce, Serena</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>In vitro studies of HIV infection of macrophages by cell to cell transmission of virus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h067t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881n112</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zh88t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Taskell is an instance of the concurrent constraint programming framework cc. The framework is parameterized by a choice of constraint system. The constraint system of Taskell is the set of finite trees with equality. The choice of constraint system makes Taskell similar to concurrent logic programming languages. When computing with partial information the notion of reading and writing memory becomes incoherent. The framework replaces these operations by ask and tell respectively. We hope to understand this new paradigm by studying implementations of cc languages. Taskell is a parallel implementation of a cc language written in Concurrent ML.</description><creator>Pellerin, Clément</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Taskell : a concurrent constraint programming language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp464.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh88t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nm63b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The acoustic characterization of six glasses each doped with one of the following dopants: GeO$ sb2$, P$ sb2$O$ sb5$, F, TiO$ sb2$, B$ sb2$O$ sb3$ or Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ is presented. We have found that a linear variation of acoustic velocities versus dopant concentration for each dopant studied and the addition of Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ increases the acoustic velocity while all the other dopants decrease this velocity. In addition, the acoustic velocity variation is more sensitive than the optical refractive index to the dopant concentration for the doped silica glasses investigated. Furthermore, the F and GeO$ sb2$ doped silica glasses exhibit higher acoustic loss than pure fused silica does. These six doped glasses are widely used as core and cladding material for optical fibers. Their acoustic properties can affect the backward stimulated Brillouin scattering since this scattering involves acoustic disturbances of the material. The SBBS threshold is evaluated theoretically taking the Bragg and the nonlinear coupling of the pump and Stokes into account. Effects of different acoustic profiles of SMOFs on SBBS are experimentally investigated. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Shang, Alain</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Acoustics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Effects of acoustic properties on stimulated backward brillouin scattering in single mode optical fibers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t315d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm63b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zp54r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The expanding Colombian education system has seen the emergence of new state managerial styles. The system was designed originally for a country with one-half of the present population, one-third of the human resources and less than one-fifth of the required financial resources. For this reason, it was necessary to extend and diversify services to include preschool, postgraduate education, nonformal education and services. Cultural activities, recreational activities of all types, and the development of scientific and technological research have also been included. At present this process is coming to an end and there is a tendency toward decentralization at the Ministry of National Education. The general recommendation is to define the role of the state at each administrative level. The ministry should be director, planner, coordinator and evaluator of all education. The regions should be administrators and executors in their specific level in relation to the personnel and the relocation of the personnel. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Naranjo, Fanny Valencia de</creator><date>1991</date><subject>State supervision of teaching -- Colombia</subject><subject>Education and state -- Colombia</subject><title>Educational supervision in Colombia : the role of the supervisor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zp551.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zp54r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085m32z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The lake breeze is shown to develop on 30% of all summer days in the Toronto region, similar to other findings in the Great Lakes area. Simulations with the Colorado State University (CSU) model show that under northwest to north gradient flow the lake breeze is characterized by a broad band of westerlies over the lake, while southwesterly gradient flow produces a broad band of easterlies. A nocturnal mesoscale cyclonic eddy is predicted over western Lake Ontario under west and northwest gradient flow conditions. A statistical model intercomparison of the CSU and Ontario Ministry of Environment models over a 19600 km$ sp2$ domain centred on Pickering, ON revealed the CSU model generally more accurately predicts the temporal and spatial lake breeze characteristics. This is attributed to improved model parameterizations and larger domain size enabling the model to resolve the full-lake scale circulations which develop.</description><creator>Comer, Neil Thomas</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Ontario, Lake (N.Y. and Ont.)</subject><subject>Winds -- Ontario, Lake (N.Y. and Ont.).</subject><title>A climatology and mesoscale model intercomparison of summertime Lake Ontario breezes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w14q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085m32z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816n61m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has often been suggested that bilingual children might have enhanced metalinguistic awareness, as compared to monolingual children. In this paper, the evidence for such a stance was reviewed. In contrast to most previous thinking, it is suggested here that if metalinguistic awareness were enhanced at all by exposure to a second language, it might be the process of learning a second language that draws children's attention to their knowledge about language. Accordingly, a group of preliterate second-language learners was compared with monolinguals and bilinguals on word and phonological awareness tasks. It was found that, for the most part, there were no significant differences among linguistic groups on the performance of these tasks. However, a trend of low performance by the bilingual children was observed. This suggests that if the learning of a second language enhancer metalinguistic awareness, these tasks might not be the most appropriate measures.</description><creator>Nicoladis, Elena</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Bilingualism in children.</subject><subject>Language awareness.</subject><title>Word and phonological awareness in preliterate children : the effect of a second language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c388m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n61m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs011</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this research is to improve the subjective quality of real world imagery encoded with spatial vector quantization (VQ). Improved subjective quality implies that a human perceives less visually objectionable distortion when looking at the coded images. Through study of several basic VQ schemes, the issues fundamental to achieving good subjective quality are uncovered and addressed in this work. Vector quantization is very good at reproducing quasi-uniform textures in an image, but has difficulty in reproducing abrupt changes in textures (edges) and fine detail and can cause a block effect which is subjectively annoying. A second generation coding scheme is developed which takes certain properties of the human visual system into account. A promising method which is developed utilizes omniscient finite state VQ, a new quadratic distortion measure which penalizes the misrepresentation of edges, and brightness compensation based on Steven's power law. The proposed subjective VQ is compared with several classical, first generation VQ methods.</description><creator>Quesnel, Ronny</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Image compression using subjective vector quantization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301240x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs011</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t12g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The partition behavior of aqueous and organic ternary solutions into two immiscible phases at ambient temperatures was studied. A classification system of the types of materials which phase partition water and organic solvents was developed and a comprehensive list of systems for which phase diagram information is available in the literature has been presented. Systems in three different classes of materials were studied. Equilibrium phase diagrams, tie-lines and plait points were generated for the ternary systems: poly(ethylene glycol)-1,000/sodium sulfate/water at 28$ sp circ$C; poly(ethylene glycol)-3,350/sodium sulfate/water at 28$ sp circ$C and 35$ sp circ$C; poly(ethylene glycol)-8,000/sodium sulfate/water at 28$ sp circ$C; poly(vinyl alcohol)/methylcellulose/water at 25$ sp circ$C; and poly(propylene glycol)/polystyrene/cyclohexane at 25$ sp circ$C. All measurements were done at 1 atm. The influence of temperature and polymer molecular weight on the shape and location of the equilibrium phase cure and the location of the critical point was analyzed for the poly(ethylene glycol)/sodium sulfate/water system.</description><creator>Ho Gutiérrez, Iris V. (Iris Violeta)</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Equilibrium compositions in two-phase partition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn32x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t12g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dd57x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several non-living algal and fungal biomass types were investigated for biosorption of cadmium, lead and a number of other heavy metal ions in aqueous solution. Marine algae A. nodosum was identified for the highest uptake for these metals, and even better than commercial ion exchange resin. A. nodosum maximum uptake capacities for lead and cadmium were in excess of 2590 mg Pb/(g dried biomass) and 120 mg Cd/(g dried biomass), respectively (pH:3.5-5.5). The adsorption mechanism for this natural material is reversible. Meal ions can be easily eluted from the biosorbent with dilute mineral acids. The biosorption process was investigated for equilibrium batch as well as dynamic packed bed column modes. Two different sorbent immobilization techniques, cross-linking and entrapment were developed for the packed bed studies. It was observed that A. nodosum cross-lined with formaldehyde give the best results for practical use.</description><creator>Prasetyo, Imam</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Removal of toxic metals from aqueous solutions by biosorption</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t116.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dd57x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n48t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the ever increasing popularity of built-in self-test comes an increasing reliance on pseudo-random patterns for testing. Some faults within a circuit, however, may be hard to detect with pseudo-random patterns. One approach to improve the detectability of these faults involves modifying the circuit by adding test points so that it responds more favorably to the given test set. A method for performing test point insertion in combinational circuits is presented. The method is based on a combination of fault simulation and probabilistic techniques. An implementation of the test point insertion procedure is described and results are presented showing the effectiveness of this method on the ISCAS benchmark circuits.</description><creator>Moscovitch, Michael</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A fault simulation oriented technique for test point insertion /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt246.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n48t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm79z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the last few decades, there has been an increasing worldwide problem of deterioration of reinforced concrete structures, caused primarily by the corrosion of the steel reinforcement embedded within the concrete. Several factors can influence the corrosion process in different types of inservice structures. This thesis reviews the basic principles of the reinforcement corrosion. Various protection and rehabilitation schemes that can be undertaken in the repair of deteriorated concrete structures are presented. In particular, three specific types of structures in the Montreal region which have undergone rehabilitation are presented as typical case studies. Additionally, major research work done in the area of reinforcement corrosion over the last twenty years is reviewed. This thesis reports the results of an experimental research program carried out at McGill University dealing with accelerated electrochemical corrosion testing of reinforced concrete. The main objective of this study is to determine the importance and influence of the depth of the concrete cover thickness on the rate of corrosion of steel reinforcement and thereby, on the resistance of concrete. Appropriate conclusions and recommendations regarding the construction variables affecting the corrosion process are brought forth. These conclusions and recommendations can be summarized.</description><creator>Palumbo, Nicolino</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Accelerated corrosion testing of steel reinforcement in concrete</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm14w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm79z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f41x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the development of a Dominion government telegraph on a portion of the Canadian frontier is analyzed as a formative moment of socialization and cultural expression. It utilizes a socio-cultural framework for understanding the 'experience of space'; notably how changes in presence or access to one another--facilitated by this new mode of communication--are central to this experience. The thesis argues that the telegraph is crucially related to issues of public confidence. Its approach draws upon recent social and cultural treatments of communication technologies which stress the ways that the material reality of such technologies become part of a larger social and symbolic order. The thesis refers to indicators such as reliability, public works, public interest, competence, and trust to investigate a social apprehension of confidence. 'Confidence', in this case, is not treated as fixed and equally understood, but as something that is invested, shared, built-up and worn down. Thus concerns for and with 'public confidence' help to reveal changes in socio-cultural development.</description><creator>Rowlandson, John</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Telegraph -- Canada, Western -- History</subject><title>A socio-cultural case study of the Canadian Government's telegraph service in western Canada, 1870-1904 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g399w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f41x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k369w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental paper calender was designed and built to measure paper strain in the nip of the calender as a function of machine speed, load and calender roll radius. The effect of roll deflection due to bending was eliminated by making the calender as narrow as possible while still reproducing industrial conditions in all other aspects. The width of the new machine is 75 mm. Permanent paper strains measured with the new equipment reproduced previously published results. In-nip paper strains were obtained under a variety of calendering conditions. Paper strains under load have previously been obtained in a platen press; the new data also reproduce these results. The equipment can now be used for a full experimental program to determine an empirical relationship between paper stress (in terms of the calendering variables) and strain (in terms of paper thickness in the nip).</description><creator>Browne, Thomas, 1955-</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Design and construction of an experimental paper calender</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b228n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k369w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117q06k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents Dr. Ali Shariati vis-a-vis the mystical tradition of Islam, focusing particularly on his inner spiritual and mystical orientation. Shariati is well known as a sociologist of religion, as a political activist, and as "the Teacher of Revolution" in Iran. Yet in his much neglected personal writings he reveals quite a different dimension of his being, a dimension which is clearly mystical in character. This study investigates the hidden mystical aspect of Shariati, and analyzes its relation to the other aspects of his personality. What is disclosed is the existence of a continuous struggle between Shariati's intellectual convictions and his spiritual intuitions, or rather between his mind and heart, as well as Shariati's repeated attempts to reconcile these two conflicting dimensions of his person.</description><creator>Vakily, Abdollah</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Sharīʻatī, ʻAlī</subject><subject>Mysticism -- Islam -- Iran.</subject><subject>Sufism -- Iran</subject><title>Ali Shariati and the mystical tradition of Islam</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r4170.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117q06k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m293c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with Freud, Lacan and Faulkner's explorations of psychology and language, regarded as differential versions of common concerns. In the first part, using aspects of the Freudian concept of the unconscious, and reading Faulkner's stream-of-consciousness narrative in The Sound and the Fury, we find that Faulkner seeks to convey the flow of the unconscious. In the second part, we see that Lacan reads Freud through Saussure's linguistics, and renews Freudian psychoanalysis with the Lacanian concept of an unconscious structured like a language. Beyond Freud, with reference to these Lacanian notions, we find that Faulkner produces a narrative structured like a language. In the third part, through the application of Lacanian theories of narration to literary theories, and through a Barthes-inspired comparison of Faulkner's novel with Lu Xun's short story "A Madman's Diary", we see that while Lu Xun gives his readers a world of meaning, Faulkner shows them the world of the word without any meaning by creating a new narrative strategy.</description><creator>Li, Ping, 1947-</creator><contributor>Massumi, Brian</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Faulkner, William, 1897-1962. Sound and the fury</subject><title>Freud and Lacan's psychoanalytic perspective and Faulkner's The sound and the fury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b229x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m293c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278v19h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Marie de' Medici began the 'jardin du Luxembourg' during her Regency for Louis XIII. As Henry IV's queen, she had clung tenaciously to her Italian family heritage and as her upbringing had close associations with the spectacular 'giardino di Boboli', she was thus inspired to utilize it as the prototype for her Parisian garden. The validation of Marie de' Medici's success lies in the investigation of both gardens to determine the recurring features and to ascertain their precise chronology. Evidence suggests that some replicated features were well known to Marie, the 'Grotta Grande', the original layout and the amphitheatre's general form; while other features, the 'Isolotto' and the amphitheatre's stone seating, were not. These were realized either concurrently or even later than similar features at Luxembourg: a factor overlooked by historians who habitually cite the formative role of Boboli at Luxembourg.</description><creator>Coombes, Pamela M.</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Giardino di Boboli (Florence, Italy)</subject><subject>Gardens, Renaissance</subject><subject>Marie de Médicis, Queen, consort of Henry IV, King of France, 1573-1642</subject><subject>Jardin du Luxembourg (Paris, France)</subject><title>The Medici gardens of Boboli and Luxembourg : thoughts on their relationship and development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g400f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v19h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22400</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>