<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:12:57Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):31075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430628m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Approximately 10% of women use cocaine and 20% smoke cigarettes during pregnancy. Animal studies indicate that both cocaine and nicotine are neuroteratogenic agents, although findings with humans are inconsistent. Studies with human infants have been plagued by unreliable subject identification procedures, poor control over confounding factors, and invalid measures of CNS integrity. The literature on prenatal cocaine and nicotine use is reviewed and two studies are presented along with an intriguing case report. The effects of maternal prenatal cocaine use (Study 1) and two levels of cigarette smoking (Study 2) on newborn information processing ability were examined using an auditory habituation-recovery paradigm. Case-control designs were employed in which subjects were individually matched on a number of maternal and infant factors. Cocaine exposure was determined by newborn meconium analysis, urine analysis, and maternal self-report. Maternal smoking was determined by self-report and a variation of the bogus pipeline method. Fetal cocaine- and nicotine-exposure were associated with differential impairments in neonatal information processing. Cocaine-exposed newborns exhibited deficits on measures of habituation and recovery to novelty. Dose-response effects of nicotine-exposure were evident on measures of orientation and habituation, but recovery to novelty was not consistently affected. The results imply that fetal cocaine-exposure severely impairs neonatal auditory information processing ability, whereas fetal tobacco-exposure is associated with deficits in information-processing which may be secondary to impairments in arousal regulation. These auditory processing deficits may be related to the later language impairments reported in follow-up studies with cocaine-and tobacco-exposed infants. Following the two studies, a case is presented of an infant born to a woman who reported using large amounts of cocaine throughout pregnancy, although the infant's meco</description><creator>Potter, Susan M.</creator><contributor>Zelazo, P. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Cognition in infants.</subject><subject>Drug abuse in pregnancy.</subject><subject>Pregnant women -- Tobacco use.</subject><title>Effects of fetal cocaine and tobacco exposure on newborn information processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd030.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430628m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qd675</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this research was to gain an understanding of how music education students come to think of themselves as music educators. Guided by the thematic framework, "learning from experience", which draws upon research relating to constructivist theory and biographical inquiry, as well as literature pertaining to construction of images of self, this study explored four music education students' perceptions of themselves as musicians and as educators. Believing that self-perceptions are rooted in personal biographies, autobiographical and journal writings were investigated to establish links between participants' perceptions and biographies. Issues encountered by participants as they began to think of themselves as music educators were uncovered. Participants' perceptions of their "selves" were rooted in childhood memories and models of practice. They interpreted, internalized and practised the tacit expectations of their models of practice. Subsequently, participants' images of self-as-musicians and self-as-educators were connected by a common thread, that of image of self. Participants who viewed self-as-performer encountered conflict between their identities as musician and as educator. Other participants constructed images of self-as-participants. As such, they experienced a sense of unity and resonance between their identities as musicians and as educators. Issues directly related to their self-perceptions surfaced as participants began to think of themselves as music educators. The study considered the implication of these issues for teaching practice, and the relationship between these issues and preservice teacher training. This study concludes with a discussion of research implications and directions for reforming music teacher education.</description><creator>Prescesky, Ruth.</creator><contributor>Dillon, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Music teachers -- Training of.</subject><subject>Music -- Instruction and study.</subject><title>A study of preservice music education students : their struggle to establish a professional identity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq00n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd675</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xn21d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Physiological and compositional changes in Pseudomonas aeruginosa (ATCC 9027) were monitored during, growth on various petroleum compounds in a chemically-defined medium. Growth of P. aeruginosa was observed when furnace oil, kerosene, aviation fuel, light crude oil and hexadecane were used as carbon and energy sources. A variable and extended lag period before active growth was achieved was characteristic of petroleum-grown cells as compared to glucose-grown cells. Growth on the petroleum hydrocarbons, compared with that on glucose, resulted in changes in cell lipid composition, outer membrane proteins, cell-surface hydrophobicity, surface-tension, and pH changes in the growth medium during transition from early to late-log phase. Cell composition and physiology of cells grown in the petroleum mixtures varied due to differences in the chemical composition of the material. Production of an exopolymer (characterized as a peptidoglycolipid) was associated with petroleum-grown cells but not with glucose-grown cells. The above differences illustrate some of the dynamic and physiological and biochemical changes the microorganism undergoes to access its hydrophobic carbon and energy source.</description><creator>Pietrantonio, Frank A.</creator><contributor>Greer, C. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Petroleum products -- Biodegradation.</subject><subject>Pseudomonas aeruginosa -- Growth.</subject><subject>Pseudomonas aeruginosa -- Physiology.</subject><title>Physiological changes and responses of pseudomonas aeruginosa ATCC 9027 when grown on petroleum compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs50z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn21d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t05n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The treatment of acid mine drainage (AMD) by sulfate-reducing bacteria (SRB) has been reported in the literature as a possible alternative to chemical treatment. The overall objective of this study was to implement such a treatment process at the mine site and specifically within the open mine pit itself. The first step of this study was to characterize process parameters. To accomplish this, a reactor was designed and built to simulate hydrodynamic conditions found in the mine pit. This reactor contained a 6$ sp{ prime prime}$ deep gravel bed in which a mixed population of SRB was inoculated. The operation of this reactor demonstrated that treatment of a continuous flow of AMD by SRB was possible, however, the response to changes in the composition of the AMD and to flow conditions was limited. The results indicated that further studies should be directed at the gravel bed itself since this was where the SRB are located and is the active site within the system. The role of various physical parameters of a gravel bed in the biological treatment of AMD by SRB was examined. This was accomplished by using gravel of different sizes (0.25$ sp{ prime prime}$ vs. 0.5$ sp{ prime prime})$ and composition (granite vs limestone) to form 12$ sp{ prime prime}$ beds in a series of column reactors. The difference in size results in variations in the total surface area, the void volume and various volume ratios within the system. The effect of potential geological buffering by limestone was examined by using and comparing with beds composed of granite. The gravel beds were inoculated with a mixed culture of SRB and overlaid with 6 L of AMD. After the SRB were established, a series of experiments were performed in which 16.7%, 25%, 75% and 100% of the water column was replaced with an equivalent quantity of fresh AMD. Changes in pH, ORP, electric conductivity, and concentrations of metal and sulfate were monitored for at least 28 days. Sulfate and metal removal at days 7 and 28 of each experiment were compared. The SRB can tolerate a wide range of disturbances, however, an increase in the load of fresh AMD decreased the performance of the system. The results indicated that the total surface area is of greater importance than the void volume in the overall treatment process by SRB. A dimensionless number was constructed to describe the relationships between the physical parameters of the gravel bed. A plot of the proportion of sulfate removed and this dimensionless number could provide essential information for the sizing of a gravel bed for the purposes of sulfate reduction. This was done for each type of gravel and comparison of the two curves indicated that there was no significant difference between the two gravels. The importance of the physical substrate for the SRB has been reported in the literature. However, no known attempt has been made to quantify the relationships between the physical parameters and the biological activity. Such information would be useful for the sizing of wetlands and other passive treatment system that uses SRB activity for the purposes of treating AMD. This study is a step towards filling this void.</description><creator>Lyew, Darwin J.</creator><contributor>Sheppard, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Sulphur bacteria.</subject><subject>Acid mine drainage -- Design.</subject><subject>Acid mine drainage.</subject><title>The characterization of physical parameters of a gravel bed reactor used for the treatment of acid mine drainage (AMD) by sulfate reducing bacteria (SRB) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35695983.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t05n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p862x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the response and design of reinforced concrete core-slab-frame structures subjected to monotonically increasing earthquake and gravity loads throughout the entire load range until failure, presenting findings from three separate studies by Manatakos and Mirza (1995) continuing the M. Eng. thesis research by Manatakos (1989). A typical building is selected consisting of a central core substructure composed of elevator, staircase and infilled slab cores, with coupling and lintel beams, and surrounding slabs joining to a frame substructure composed of slab-band girders, slabs and columns. Stage 1 concentrates on the elastic response and Stage 3 examines the nonlinear response of the core-slab-frame structure considering the effects of cracking and crushing of concrete, strain-hardening of the reinforcement, and tension-stiffening. Analyses involve three-dimensional elastic and nonlinear finite element modeling techniques of the structure to investigate the contribution and influence of the various structural components. The structural response is examined for the deformations, the concentrated reinforcement strains and concrete stresses in the cores, the force and stress distributions in the structural members, and the failure mode. Stage 2 focuses on the design and detailing of the core-slab-frame structure following seismic provisions of building code requirements for reinforced concrete structures where applicable as given in the CSA Standard CAN3-A23.3-MS4 (1984), the ACI Standard ACI 318M-83 (1983) and the New Zealand Standard NZS3101 (1982). Assumptions made in the conventional design procedures and any shortcomings encountered are examined. Suitable design procedures and reinforcement details are suggested where no provisions exist in the codes. Findings demonstrate complex three-dimensional interaction among the cores, beams, slabs and frames in resisting the lateral and gravity loads, and show considerable strength, ductility and energy absorption capability of the structure. Critical areas for design include the joints and junctions near the vicinity of core wall-slab-beams ends and corners. Plastic hinging extends over the lower 2.5% to 33% height of the structure with the majority of inelastic action and damage concentrated in the bottom 10% to 15% height, predicting an ultimate load of 3.4 to 5.9 times the design earthquake load with top drifts of the structure between 750 mm to 1375 mm.</description><creator>Manatakos, Kyriakos, 1960-</creator><contributor>Mirza, M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Urban and Regional Planning.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Behaviour and design of reinforced concrete core-slab-frame structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg54c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p862x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000158m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermal conductivity is an excellent probe of quasiparticle excitations in superconductors both in the normal and superconducting state. We have applied this technique to the study of two unconventional superconductors, namely the heavy fermion superconductor UPt$ sb3$ and the high-$T sb{c}$ cuprate $ rm YBa sb2Cu sb3O sb{7- delta}.$ In the case of UPt$ sb3,$ after reviewing previous low temperature thermal conductivity measurements, we show that, for our high quality single crystals, the thermal conductivity is totally dominated by electrons and therefore provides a direct probe of the superconducting gap structure. We demonstrate that our measurements of the anisotropy of heat conduction between b-axis and c-axis in this hexagonal crystal provide strong constraints with respect to the possible gap structures inferred by group theoretical arguments. By comparing our results with recent theoretical calculations, we show that a hybrid II gap structure provides good agreement between theory and experiments favoring an order parameter of $E sb{2u}$ (strong spin-orbit coupling) or $A sb{2u}$ (weak spin-orbit coupling) symmetry. For $ rm YBa sb2Cu sb3O sb{7- delta},$ the thermal conductivity typically consists of both a phononic and an electronic contribution. After reviewing low temperature thermal conductivity measurements that address this question, we demonstrate the presence of electronic quasiparticles even at temperatures of ${ sim}T sb{c}/1000,$ a clear indication of an unconventional gap structure. We then proceed to discuss zinc doping studies in $ rm YBa sb2Cu sb3O sb{7- delta}$ and show that we find a universal residual linear term at $T=0$ of a magnitude very close in value to that predicted by recent theories. These results validate the approach of resonant impurity scattering in the high-$T sb{c},$ and our excellent agreement with theory reinforces the view that the gap structure in $ rm YBa sb2Cu sb3O sb{7- delta}$ is of $d sb{x sp2-y sp2}$ symmetry. Finally, we present neutron scattering results in UPt$ sb3.$ In this chapter, we study the magnetic field dependence of the antiferromagnetic moment lying in the basal plane. We find that magnetic fields of order 3 Tesla have no effect on the magnetic order: it can neither make the sample a magnetic monodomain in field cooling nor can it rotate the moment. The results, very simple in appearance, have profound consequences for the superconducting phase diagram of this heavy-fermion compound.</description><creator>Lussier, Benoit.</creator><contributor>Taillefer, Louis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Heat conduction in unconventional superconductors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8382097.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000158m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gh88f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A model was developed to account for the static elastic behaviour of the lung tissue strip in terms of distributions of collagen and elastin fibers. Distributions of collagen fiber lengths and elastin fiber stiffnesses were determined by fitting the model to data from dog lung tissue strips. These distributions followed 1/f power-laws for more than 95% of the data. Computer simulations of two dimensional tissue strip models with 1/f distributions of collagen fiber lengths also predicted realistic stress-strain curves. The simulations illustrated the gradual development of geometric and stress heterogeneity throughout the tissue as the collagen fibers were recruited during stretch. This model suggests a mechanistic basis for the shape of the pressure-volume curve of whole lung. It also indicates how this curve may be affected by changes in tissue collagen and elastin similar to the changes occurring in the diseases of pulmonary emphysema and fibrosis. Nonparametric block-structured nonlinear models for describing both the static and dynamic stress-strain behaviour of the lung were applied to dog lung tissue strips and to whole rat lungs in vivo. Both the Wiener and Hammerstein models accounted for more than 99% of the tissue strip data, although the Hammerstein model was more consistently accurate across a range of perturbation amplitudes and operating stresses. Plastic dissipation of energy within the lung tissue strip was estimated at less than 20% of the total dissipation during slow sinusoidal cycling. The Hammerstein model was also the best of those investigated for describing the rat lung data in vivo, although there were dependencies of the model parameters on perturbation amplitude and operating point that indicate that a more complicated model is required for the whole lung. Finally, construction of a fiber recruitment model for the dynamic mechanical behaviour of lung tissue strips was attempted. However accurate reproduction of measured behaviour was no</description><creator>Maksym, Geoffrey N.</creator><contributor>Bates, Jason H. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Modelling lung tissue theology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j2625.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gh88f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r9329</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glucoamylase, a saccharifying enzyme, is applied in the brewing industry to hydrolyse the dextrins of malted barley into simple sugars which can then be fermented by brewer's yeast. In order to establish the potential of glucoamylase from Lactobacillus amylovorus for application in the brewing industry, the main objectives of this study were: (1) to determine the cultural conditions for growth and glucoamylase production, (2) to purify the enzyme to homogeneity using chromatography and electrophoretic techniques, (3) to study biochemical properties of the purified enzyme, and (4) to clone the gene coding for glucoamylase, and characterize the recombinant glucoamylase. The actively amylolytic Lactobacillus amylovorus ATCC 33621 produced an intracellular glucoamylase activity. Conditions for growth and glucoamylase production were maximized by using dextrose free MRS medium supplemented with 1% dextrin, at pH 5.5 and 37$ sp circ$C. Enzyme production was maximal during the late logarithmic phase of growth from 16-18 h. Crude cell extract showed optimal activity at pH 6.0 and 55$ sp circ$C. Native and SDS-PAGE of the purified enzyme showed a monomeric protein of 47 kD. Glucoamylase activity was confirmed by activity staining using a starch/polyacrylamide gel where a zone of clearing was visible on a blue/black background stained with Kl/I$ sb2.$ Optimal pH, pl and temperature of purified glucoamylase were 4.5, 4.39 and 45$ sp circ$C, respectively. The enzyme was rapidly inactivated by temperatures above 55$ sp circ$C and was inhibited by heavy metals, e.g. Pb$ sp{2+}$ and Cu$ sp{2+}$ at 1.0 mM. EDTA did not inhibit the enzyme activity at a final concentration of 10 mM. Enzyme inhibition by 1 mM of p-chloromercuribenzoic acid (pCMB) and iodoacetate suggested that a sulfhydryl group was present in the enzyme active site. Kinetic studies of glucoamylase confirmed that the enzyme reacted preferentially with polysaccharides. HPLC analyses of the end products of enzyme action showed that glucose was the major end product of enzyme action and this glucose was responsible for end product inhibition. The gene coding for glucoamylase was cloned into Escherichia coli using the STA2 glucoamylase gene of Saccharomyces diastaticus as a probe. Three glucoamylase producing transformants were identified as the insert sizes of about 5.2 Kb, 6.4 Kb and 5.9 Kb, respectively. When the characteristics of both recombinant and purified wild type glucoamylases were compared, both enzymes showed a similar pH range of 3.0-8.0, and temperature optimum of 45$ sp circ$C. The recombinant enzyme pH profiles were broader than that of the wild type and an optimum pH of 6.0 was obtained. This study has shown that glucoamylase from Lb. amylovorus is less heat stable than other bacterial glucoamylases and thus may be suitable for application in the brewing industry. Successful cloning of this gene coding for glucoamylase in brewer's yeast, Saccharomyces cerevisiae, would reap the advantageous properties of the enzyme while eliminating the costs of adding commercial enzymes.</description><creator>James, Jennylynd Arlene.</creator><contributor>Lee, Byong H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Brewing -- Microbiology.</subject><subject>Glucans.</subject><subject>Lactobacillus -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Hydrolysis.</subject><subject>Amylases.</subject><title>Production, characterization and cloning of glucoamylase from Lactobacillus amylovorus ATCC 33621</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw058.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r9329</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv93d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study examined psychosocial variables as predictors of psychological distress and well-being in gay men with Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) and the Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS). The psychosocial variables investigated included communal and agentic personality variables, social support, as well as social hindrance, and self-determination variables. The total sample comprised 126 gay men. Forty-eight were seropositive for the HIV infection, 40 received a diagnosis of AIDS, and 38 were seronegative for the HIV infection. The participants with HIV and AIDS were recruited from Immunodeficiency clinics and the HIV$-$ participants were friends and acquaintances of the HIV+ and AIDS participants. The three groups of participants completed questionnaires assessing stable personality traits such as dependency and self-criticism, intimacy, affiliation, achievement, and power strivings, perceived and received social support, social hindrance of personal strivings, and levels of self-determination such as introjective and identified striving motivation. Multiple hierarchical regression analyses were conducted to assess the predictive utility of each independent variable in predicting psychological distress and well-being. Perceived social support, striving intimacy, and striving achievement were found to be negatively associated with distress and positively associated with well-being across the three groups. Dependency, self-criticism, social hindrance, social hindrance of striving power, and introjective striving motivation were positively associated with distress and negatively with well-being. When all significant independent variables were entered in a regression analysis and simultaneously predicted the outcome variables, perceived social support, self-criticism and social hindrance of strivings significantly predicted psychological distress, and perceived social support, self-criticism, identified and introjective striving motivation predicted psychological well-being. Several independent variables were stronger predictors of distress in the HIV+ group than in the AIDS group: striving power, social hindrance of striving power, dependency, and perceived social support. Results suggest that the HIV+ group is distinct psychologically from the AIDS group. The self-concept theory and the cognitive adaptation theory were discussed in order to explain these group differences. The findings of the present study highlight the important impact psychosocial variables can have on the psychological adjustment of gay men with HIV and AIDS.</description><creator>Igreja, Isabel.</creator><contributor>Zuroff, David C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>HIV-positive persons -- Mental health.</subject><subject>Gay men -- Mental health.</subject><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Patients -- Mental health.</subject><title>Psychosocial variables as predictors of psychological distress and well-being in gay men with HIV and AIDS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139354w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv93d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sk960</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>By combining numerical simulations with different diagnostic tools, this thesis examines the various aspects of two explosively deepening cyclones--the superstorm of March 12-14 1993 and a storm that occurred during the Intensive Observation Period 14 (IOP-14) of the Canadian Atlantic Storm Program (CASP). Using conventional observations, the general aspects of the storms are documented and the dynamical and physical mechanisms are discussed. Then the life cycles are simulated with the Canadian Regional Finite-Element model. To improve the model initial conditions, a methodology is proposed on the basis of potential vorticity thinking, and is tested to be successful in the simulation of the March 1993 superstorm. Using the successful simulations as control runs, a series of numerical sensitivity experiments are conducted to study the impacts of model physics on the development of the two rapidly deepening cyclones. The deepening mechanisms of both storms are examined within the context of PV thinking, i.e., using piecewise potential vorticity inversion diagnostics. In both cases, the upper-level PV anomalies contribute the most to the surface cyclone, followed by the lower-level thermal anomalies and diabatic heating related moist PV anomaly. It is found that a favorable phase tilt between the upper- and lower-level PV anomalies allows a mutual interaction between them, in which the circulations associated with the upper-level anomalies enhance the lower-level anomalies, which in turn feedback positively into the upper-level PV anomalies. In addition to the vertical interactions, there also exist lateral interactions between the upper-level PV anomalies for the March 1993 superstorm. The upper-level PV features (troughs) are isolated with the piecewise PV inversion. By removing or changing the intensity of the trough in the initial conditions, the RFE model is integrated to examine the impact of each trough and its interaction with the other trough on the superstorm development.</description><creator>Huo, Zonghui.</creator><contributor>Zhang, Da-Lin (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gyakuin, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Numerical prediction and potential vorticity diagnosis of extratropical cyclones</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg41d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk960</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr97h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation responds to a recent zeitgeist and climate of controversy surrounding issues of "virtuality" and "simulation" Such terms are treated as problematic and essentially contested when framed in reference to notions of a fixed observable "reality" rather than considered in terms of socially constructed facts, relationships and identities. The concept of the "virtual stage" advanced in this thesis, refers to the current historical moment in communications technology development as well as to the dramaturgical perspective which informs the theoretical approach and argument. In this dissertation, virtual reality is treated not as a single technology or corpus of machines, but following conventions established in recent telepresence research as an experience which can obtain in varying degrees by means of a host of communications media. Several complementary approaches are proposed and examined as a provisional framework for the study of emerging contemporary discourses of virtuality. Issues of virtuality are discussed from the perspective of historical cases which invite comparison and suggest a palimpsest of earlier technological modes of communication within contemporary situations. The social construction of technology approach is introduced following recent suggestions for marrying this approach to the Canadian tradition of socio-historical study of communication technology. Finally, play and dramaturgical theory are offered as a model for understanding how community and individual identity are constructed and maintained in some forms of computer mediated communication (video games, MUDs, and IRC) while allowing for potentially plausible notions of human agency.</description><creator>Hunter, Jesse.</creator><contributor>Crowley, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Telematics -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Virtual reality.</subject><subject>Social interaction.</subject><subject>Play (Philosophy)</subject><title>The virtual stage : play, drama, and agency in communications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx37s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr97h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mn79t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The control of B lymphocyte production in bone marrow is of central importance in maintaining a supply of new B cells for primary humoral immune responses throughout life, while its perturbation may underlie states of immunodeficiency, neoplasia and autoimmunity. Molecules expressed by developing B cells and stromal cells within bone marrow, as well as systemic factors, may all play key roles in regulating proliferation and survival of precursor B cells in bone marrow. Candidate regulatory molecules investigated in the present work include surrogate light chains (SL) of immunoglobulin (Ig) expressed intracellularly by precursor B cells before and during the synthesis of CI heavy (H) chains of IgM, and interleukin (IL)-1, a systemic pleiotropic macrophage-derived factor. In vivo administration of radiolabeled mAbs specific for SL and IL-1 receptors type I and type II revealed that both SL and IL-1 receptors are normally expressed in bone marrow, displayed on the surface of lymphoid precursors and stromal cells, respectively. Ex vivo analysis of the DNA content of SL/$ mu$H$ sp+$ pre-B cells revealed a low incidence of apoptosis. Systemic administration of rIL-1 followed by analysis of precursor B cell dynamics using double immunofluorescence labeling and stathmokinetic techniques revealed that systemic IL-1 can either stimulate or depress B lymphopoiesis in a dose-dependent manner. Stimulation of cytoplasmic (c) $ mu sp+$ pre-B cell proliferation following activation of systemic macrophages by injecting sheep red blood cells (SRBC) is partially abrogated by rIL-1ra. Bone marrow IL-1 receptors, assayed by binding of radiolabeled anti-IL-1R monoclonal antibodies to plasma membrane fractions, undergo changes in levels of expression following SRBC administration. The work supports the hypotheses that surface SL is involved in the positive selection of precursor B cells with productively-rearranged $ mu$ chain genes, and suggests that the elevated proliferative level o</description><creator>Fauteux, Lucy J. (Lucy Jacinthe)</creator><contributor>Osmond, Dennis G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Regulation of B lymphopoiesis within bone marrow microenvironment : in vivo role of IL-1 and expression of surrogate light chains by precursor B cells in the mouse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm97n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn79t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff3656776</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Evidence on comparative quality of life and housing of Italians at origin, and emigrants in two destinations was gathered from field research, and from three surveys: one, of residents of the town of origin (n = 153), Larino, in the province of Campobasso, and the other two, of residents of major destinations of Larinesi emigrants--Montreal (n = 118), and Milano (n = 73). The main working hypothesis was tested that the best quality of life is found among emigrants living in Montreal. The research also explicated the historical connection between policies of migration and housing concerns in Canada and in Italy. Quality of life was measured using a battery of structural, objective and subjective indicators that were calibrated for relative comparisons between the two cities of destination by the re-analysis of two large surveys (Milano n = 966; Montreal n = 461), and by the use of of official statistics. Multivariate analysis results showed that in comparison to the town of origin, Montreal produced the best and most distinguishable socio-demographic context and Milano the best geographic context. The objective indicators based on the ratios of income to need and those based on income relative to each city, are most influential in Montreal. Subjective indicators such as attitudes and lifestyles are more consistently related to levels of education than to place of residence. High rates of house ownership among the Larinesi in Montreal, and changes in their patterns of use of space which accompany permanent resettlement--especially those regarding the use of an extra kitchen--were found to be explainable in terms of the "housing culture" of the town of origin.</description><creator>Fainella, John G.</creator><contributor>Masi, A. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Italians -- Québec (Province) -- Montreal -- Housing.</subject><subject>Migration, Internal -- Italy.</subject><subject>Quality of life -- Québec (Province) -- Montreal.</subject><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><subject>Home ownership -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Quality of life -- Italy -- Larino.</subject><subject>Italy -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><subject>Milan (Italy) -- Social conditions.</subject><subject>Larino (Italy) -- Social conditions.</subject><subject>Housing -- Italy.</subject><subject>Quality of life -- Italy -- Milan.</subject><title>Destination, housing and quality of life in the migrant experience from Larino (Molise, Italy) to Milano and Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc155.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3656776</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107061s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chicken genomic DNA containing 5 kb of the 5$ sp prime$ end of the growth hormone (GH) receptor gene and 12 kb of the region up-stream was cloned and a restriction map was constructed. Using subcloned fragments as probes, a HindIII polymorphism was detected in both egg layer and in meat-type chickens. This polymorphic site was mapped at 7 kb up-stream of the coding region of the GH-receptor gene and a PCR assay for the polymorphism was developed to facilitate genotyping of large numbers of chickens. Alleles of the GH-receptor gene and the GH gene were analyzed for association with traits in chicken strains of different genetic origins. In egg layers, association was significant for juvenile body weight, egg weight, feed consumption and feed efficiency for egg mass (P $&lt;$ 0.05). In meat-type chickens, the GH-receptor allele associated with high juvenile body weight in egg layers was co-selected with leanness. A comparison of the genotype classes revealed that for several traits there was significant interaction between the GH and GH-receptor genotype. The results indicated that there are variants of the genes of the GH-axis which affect traits in White Leghorns and that the effect of a genetic variation in one gene may depend on the variation in another gene.</description><creator>Feng, Xiaopeng.</creator><contributor>Kuhnlein, Urs (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Somatotropin.</subject><subject>Somatotropin -- Receptors.</subject><subject>Chickens -- Genome mapping.</subject><subject>Chickens -- Growth.</subject><title>Chicken growth hormone receptor and growth hormone : search for genetic variants which affect commercially important traits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh77n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107061s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t355c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The increasing incidence of adolescent depression calls for the study of individual difference factors that may impinge on psychosocial adjustment. Researchers have identified depressive personality styles, namely dependency and self-criticism, that represent distinct vulnerability orientations. A series of four studies was conducted to (1) examine the relation of the depressive styles to adolescent dysphoria and interpersonal functioning; (2) assess the Personality-Event Congruence Model of Depressive Vulnerability in youngsters; and (3) explore how dependency and self-criticism relate to the regulation of negative affect using an experience sampling methodology. Findings provide evidence for heightened vulnerability of adolescent self-criticism in terms of increased dysphoria and interpersonal problems, demonstrate the vulnerability of dependency during attachment-related transitions, and reveal the relation of depressive styles to distinctive patterns of poor mood management. Together, these studies highlight the need to help youngsters adopt strategies that may be effective in forestalling dysphoria, enabling healthy adaptation to developmental challenges.</description><creator>Fichman, Laura.</creator><contributor>Koestner, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Adjustment (Psychology)</subject><subject>Mood (Psychology)</subject><subject>Depression in adolescence.</subject><title>Depressive styles in adolescence : investigating psychosocial adjustment and daily mood regulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn78j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t355c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vm56d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goals of the research work presented in this thesis were (i) to determine the accuracy of lateralization of temporal lobe epilepsy (TLE) by proton magnetic resonance spectroscopic imaging (MRSI) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) based volumetric measurements (MRIVol) in comparison with the current "gold standard" of clinical-EEG lateralization, (ii) to optimize the sensitivity of the MRSI and MRI methods (iii) to examine the surgical outcome in groups of patients undergoing surgical treatment, and (iv) to provide insights into the pathogenesis of partial epilepsies. Early on we confirmed the usefulness of measuring hippocampal formation (HF) volumes in the lateralization of TLE, and showed, for the first time, that the additional determination of amygdala (AM) volumes improves lateralization (paper 1). These findings were specific for temporal lobe epilepsy (TLE), as patients with extra-temporal partial seizures did not have atrophy of the AM or HF (paper 1). In several subsequent original studies we focused on the pathophysiology and clinical manifestations of TLE, including the relationship of mesial temporal atrophy (MTA) to seizure frequency and duration (paper 6); the association of MTA with early childhood prolonged febrile convulsions (paper 7); the relation of MTA to scalp (papers 4 and 5) and intracranial EEG findings (paper 3); the relationship between atrophy of the amygdala and ictal fear in TLE (paper 9); the frequency and characteristics of dual pathology (paper 8); the correlation of MTA with surgical outcome (paper 10) and the question of qualitative vs. quantitative assessment of MTA (paper 2). The work on MRSI included the development of a new protocol for assessment of neuronal metabolic abnormality in vivo in TLE based on the N-acetylaspartate (NAA) resonance measured in anatomically defined regions of the temporal lobes (paper 11). Subsequently, we were the first to show the advantages of combining proton MRSI and MRIVol for lateralization of TLE (paper 12). We also demonstrated that MRSI could be used to discriminate between different types of nonconvulsive seizures (paper 15) and to monitor the progression of chronic encephalitis and focal seizures (Rasmussen's syndrome) (paper 14). More recently we began developing new protocols for the use of MRSI in the lateralization and localization of non-lesional extra-temporal epilepsies (paper 13). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Cendes, Fernando.</creator><contributor>Arnold, Douglas L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>The use of proton MR spectroscopic imaging and MRI volumetric measurements in the clinical evaluation of partial epilepsies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Fernando Cendes, 1996</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289k64c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm56d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418p743</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three studies were conducted in which Quebec French, first grade children's ability to categorize vowels was examined. The children were tested on several aspects of vowel phoneme representation before they had any literacy skills, at the beginning of the school year, and again sis months later, after they had learned all of the spelling-sound correspondences for vowels. In Study 1, the focus was on children's phonemic and orthographic representation of nasal vowels. Performance on an AXB categorization task revealed that six-year-olds have considerable difficulty in discriminating the nasal feature on minimal and near-minimal oral-nasal vowel pairs. This ability did not improve after six months of schooling. In contrast to their performance on AXB, these same children performed very well on nasal vowel spellings. These results suggest that perceptually-based categorization ability and the ability to represent nasal vowels in spelling develop independently of each other. Study 2 examined children's categorization of self-generated productions of front-unrounded, nasal, and, back-nonhigh vowels. The influence of a number of variables on vocalic representation, such as articulatory complexity, spectral proximity, and syllable structure, was also examined. The children's performance on this explicit task varied as a function of the vowel set. Specifically, whereas articulatory complexity did not have a negative effect on categorization ability, spectral proximity of vowels did appear to hinder performance; syllable structure negatively affected oral but not nasal vowel categorization performance. Schooling, and exposure to literacy evidently had a strong impact on this type of phoneme categorization/representation ability as children's overall performance improved significantly from the first to the second testing period. In Study 3, children's ability to categorize vowel allophones which were spoken in two dialects was examined. Again, performance varied by the typ</description><creator>Caravolas, Markéta.</creator><contributor>Bruck, Maggie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Language awareness in children.</subject><subject>Children -- Language -- Testing.</subject><subject>French language -- Vowels.</subject><title>Six-year-olds' phonological and orthographic representations of vowels : a study of 1st grade Québec-French children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f746t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p743</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26xz924</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Matrix factorizations are among the most important and basic tools in numerical linear algebra. Perturbation analyses of matrix factorizations are not only important in their own right, but also useful in many applications, e.g. in estimation, control and statistics. The aim of such analyses is to show what effects changes in the data will have on the factors. This thesis is concerned with developing new general purpose perturbation analyses, and applying them to the Cholesky, QR and LU factorizations, and the Cholesky downdating problem. We develop a new approach, the so called 'matrix-vector equation' approach, to obtain sharp results and true condition numbers for the above problems. Our perturbation bounds give significant improvements on previous results, and could not be sharper. Also we use the so called 'matrix equation' approach originated by G. W. Stewart to derive perturbation bounds that are usually weaker but easier to interpret. This approach allows efficient computation of satisfactory estimates for the true condition numbers derived by our approach. The combination of these two approaches gives a powerful understanding of these problems. Although first-order perturbation bounds are satisfactory for all but the most delicate work, we also give some rigorous perturbation bounds for some factorizations. We show that the condition of many such factorizations is significantly improved by the standard pivoting strategies (except the L factor in the LU factorization), and provide firmly based theoretical explanations as to why this is so. This extremely important information is very useful for designing more reliable matrix algorithms. Our approach is a powerful general tool, and appears to be applicable to the perturbation analysis of any matrix factorization.</description><creator>Chang, Xiao-Wen, 1963-</creator><contributor>Paige, Chris (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Pertubation analysis of some matrix factorizations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b477p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26xz924</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x18q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the emergence of revisionism in the foreign policies of the great powers: it is concerned with the rise of 'challenger' states. Current approaches to the rise of challengers (arguments from 'structure', 'prudence', and 'historical sociology') are if generally useful also incomplete, leaving the emergence of several great power challengers not fully explained. This dissertation offers a new explanation, not as a replacement but as a complement to these theories, and in doing so accomplishes two tasks: first, it explains cases previously unaccounted-for; and second, it does so in a fashion that acknowledges the co-determination of domestic and international politics. The new model suggests that the seeds of challenges to international orders are often found in the wartime experience itself, in social pacts between elites and societal groups struck to achieve mobilization requirements. Violation of these pacts in the postwar period can in turn generate powerful political movements for the overthrow of both the domestic and international postwar orders. The explanation offered by this model is then applied to five cases of great power behaviour after major wars. While imperfect in its ability to account for great power behaviour in all these cases and thus requiring refinement, the model obtains sufficient support to warrant further exploration of these and other cases in future studies.</description><creator>Castle, Allan.</creator><contributor>Brawley, Mark R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Great powers.</subject><subject>International relations -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>War (International law)</subject><subject>World politics -- 19th century.</subject><subject>World politics -- 20th century.</subject><title>Collusion and challenge : major wars, domestic coalitions and revisionist states</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935450m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x18q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv967</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Birth in our Canadian society is a daily phenomenon that occurs approximately 1,100 times per day, but unfortunately not always within the normal time frame, after 39-40 weeks of pregnancy. The present thesis addresses the question: What factors initiate premature labour? Although the process is incompletely understood, it is known that immune and endocrine factors as well as the fetus itself contribute to the initiatory signals that bring about parturition. Indeed, cytokines, oxytocin, and steroids have been shown to affect the tone, amplitude and frequency of myometrial contractions. Given that their effects can be abolished by the addition of cyclooxygenase (Cox) inhibitors, the changes, in vivo, of Cox-1 and Cox-2 gene expression during pregnancy and the effects of cytokines and oxytocin on prostaglandin synthesis were examined. Analysis by Polymerase Chain Reaction and Northern blotting indicated that uterine Cox-2 transcript levels increased approaching delivery and that the Cox-1 mRNA levels remained relatively unchanged throughout pregnancy. Immunohistochemical staining for the Cox-2 and OTR proteins revealed both to be co-expressed in the myometrium and in endometrial epithelial cells. Within the stroma, no OTR staining was found but intense staining for Cox-2 was noticed during labour. Following the in vivo work, the effects of cytokines and oxytocin on various cell lines were tested. When IL-1$ beta$ and TNF-$ alpha$ were added to CUS-V2, a stromal cell line I developed, an increase in Cox-2 mRNA levels and an approximately 2 fold increase in PgF$ sb{2 alpha}$ released per 24 hours was observed. Under the same conditions, no changes in the levels of Cox-1 or GAPDH mRNA were observed. The effect of oxytocin was more pronounced. Its addition to CHO cells expressing constitutively the rat oxytocin receptor led to a 107 fold increase in the amount of PgE$ sb2$ released in a 24 hour period and a increase in Cox-2 protein levels as determined by Western blot analysis. Therefore, since uterine oxytocin and oxytocin receptor, in the rat, are regulated by estrogen and progesterone, and these steroids are in turn regulated by placental born factors, a clearer understanding is emerging of their interaction. These three systems might synergistically or additively interact to produce an amplified signal that initiates strong synchronous contractions and a delayed, but a parallel, increase in cervical compliance by inducing prostaglandins.</description><creator>Arslan, Ali.</creator><contributor>Zingg, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Parturient hormones : cytokine, and oxytocin effects on prostaglandin synthesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hd707.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv967</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w899t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several twentieth century archaeological expeditions to Lower Nubia recovered the skeletal and cultural remains of C-Group populations mainly from cemetery sites between Shellal and the Second Cataract. Along with the remains of the more or less contemporary Pangrave and Kerma peoples, the C-Group archaeological sequence was assigned to the Middle Nubian Period which lasted from the Sixth to the Eighteenth Egyptian Dynasties and is dated from ca. 2200 B.C. to ca. 1500 B.C. Conflicting interpretations of C-Group socioeconomic conditions are inevitable since no systematic analysis of the data resulting from the excavations of Middle Nubian cemeteries has ever been undertaken. In an attempt to assess the extent of C-Group economic contact with the Egyptians and to resolve the issue of possible growing social differentiation within the C-Group community, a quantitative analysis of the mortuary remains from fifteen C-Group cemeteries was undertaken. The results indicate that the flow of a small number of Egyptian artefacts into Lower Nubia was relatively constant and that contact between Lower Nubians and Egyptians was probably quite limited. Egyptian portrayals of constant fluctuation in Egyptian-Nubian political relations do not correspond with the evidence from the Nubian archaeological record. The analysis also indicated that economic inequality amongst the Middle Nubian population was present in each date category and tended to increase over time. Socioeconomic differences were greatest during the middle of the Second Intermediate Period. These findings indicate that the Middle Nubian socioeconomic system tolerated increasingly conspicuous differences amongst its members. They are not consistent with the hypothesis that no increase in differential access to burial resources occurred between ca. 2100 and ca. 1550 B.C. and that C-Group social and economic conditions remained virtually unchanged throughout their 800-year history.</description><creator>Anderson, Wendy R. M.</creator><contributor>Bisson, Michael S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Tombs -- Nubia.</subject><subject>Nubians -- Funeral rites and ceremonies.</subject><subject>Nubia -- Antiquities.</subject><subject>Excavations (Archaeology) -- Nubia.</subject><subject>Social classes -- Nubia -- History.</subject><title>The significance of Middle Nubian C-Group mortuary variability, ca. 2200 B.C. to ca. 1500 B.C. /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107063b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w899t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk27p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The anchoring effect influences clinicians to give undue diagnostic importance to client data gathered during the initial appraisal period. Moreover, client data consistent with the earlier diagnostic hypotheses may be given disproportionate credence. Extending research on the anchoring effect, 40 counsellors were presented with a written casefile in which the order of specific client information (that is, client material characterized as healthy and ailing) was systematically sequenced. A questionnaire was administered to evaluate the impact that the order of presentation of client information had on participant ratings of client functioning, and a "think-aloud" methodology was employed to examine the actual clinical inferences that participants generated as they read through the case material. These approaches unveiled divergent results. Questionnaire data revealed an anchoring effect associated with the presentation of healthy client material. "Think-aloud" data revealed an anchoring effect associated with the presentation of pathognomonic client material. A number of strategies are proposed to call clinicians' attention to the processes by which they encode details about their clients, and then generate and test hypotheses pertaining to them.</description><creator>Aronoff, Derek N.</creator><contributor>Dumont, Florent Frank (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Diagnosis.</subject><subject>Counselors.</subject><title>Errors in clinical judgment : the effect of temporal order of client information on anchoring, adjustment, and adjustment mitigation and category of clinical inferences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg36p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk27p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579t782</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the concept of an intelligent system for the design and planning of electric power systems is developed. Such a system serves to preserve the vast body of power system design knowledge by identifying, structuring and consolidating it into one easily accessible source. The intelligent system can then be used to support experienced power system planners or for training purposes. The main planning and design activities considered include the design of a complete power system or of specific subsystems such as a substation or a transmission corridor. The principal features and main components of this general intelligent system, called PSIDE, are delineated. A general methodology and a design tool were then devised for modelling and using this kind of knowledge. The object-oriented strategy was found to be the most suitable due its powerful capabilities to naturally represent the structure and behaviour of power systems. Thus, PSIDE is based on object-oriented knowledge models for design tasks such as point-to-point transmission design, insulation coordination as well as protection system and substation design. In order to validate the proposed concepts as well as the object-oriented paradigm adopted for their realization, a substation design module (SIDE) was fully developed and tested.</description><creator>Atanackovic, Djordje.</creator><contributor>Galiana, F. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>intelligent power system design</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg56x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579t782</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr16p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Modelling, analysis and control of networks of strings: using Hamilton's principle, a nonlinear system of partial differential equations describing the dynamics of a network of vibrating strings joining point masses is derived. The existence of equilibrium configurations is established and some properties are obtained. Linearizing around equilibria one obtains linear hyperbolic systems. The existence of solutions in appropriate spaces is proved. Various results concerning exact controllability are obtained. This work involves variational methods, semigroups, theory of uniform distribution of sequences and hyperbolic estimates. We also get an optimal energy decay rate for a nonlinear feed-back problem.</description><creator>Wei, Ming</creator><contributor>Schmidt, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Controllability of networks of strings and masses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236368g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr16p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b5919865</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The kinetics of the reduction of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$ by H$ sb2$ in a model mixture of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$-$ rm Fe sb2O sb3$, and by H$ sb2$-CO in a model mixture of kraft black liquor ash (KBLA) as well as in actual KBLA, both mixed with $ rm Fe sb2O sb3$, was investigated in a thermogravimetric analysis system. $ rm Fe sb2O sb3$ is a catalyst for the reduction of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$. The kinetics of the reduction of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$ mixed with $ rm Fe sb2O sb3$ by H$ sb2$ was well described by the second-order nucleation and growth model (NGM) for X $ leq$ 0.80 and by the shrinking-core model subject to product layer diffusion control (SCM-PLD) for X $ geq$ 0.80 over a temperature range of 655-700$ sp circ$C. The rate of conversion of the reduction of pure $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$ at 685$ sp circ$C without the presence of $ rm Fe sb2O sb3$ was smaller, and could be described by the conversion-time (X-t) expression valid for the phase boundary reaction controlled model for a solid-solid reaction of spherical particles. The kinetics of the reduction of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$ in a model mixture of KBLA was well described by the third-order NGM for 0.15 $ leq$ X $ leq$ 0.90 and by the SCM-PLD for X $ geq$ 0.90 over a rather narrow temperature range of 720-730$ sp circ$C. The reducing H$ sb2$-He feed gas contained 10% CO to suppress the decomposition of $ rm Na sb2CO sb3$ by H$ sb2$. The X-t curves in the temperature range of 675-715$ sp circ$C are described by SCM-PLD kinetics during the deceleratory period. The kinetics of the reduction of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$ by H$ sb2$-10% CO in actual KBLA is well described by the third-order NGM for 0.20 $ leq$ X $ leq$ 0.95 over a temperature range of 700-725$ sp circ$C. The conversion range described by the NGM is smaller between 680 and 700$ sp circ$C and a long induction period is observed. The change in color of the reduced samples from red-burgundy to black-grey indicated that $ rm Fe sb2O sb3$ had been changed chemically during the reduction. The formation of mixture of FeS and possibly FeS$ sb2$ during the reduction is proposed based on XPS/ESCA analysis of the actual KBLA. Although SEM micrographs showed that local sintering/fusion occurred to a certain extent in the reduced samples, complete reduction of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$ could be obtained. Based on these observations and the kinetics, the possible mechanisms for the catalytic effect of $ rm Fe sb2O sb3$ and that of the H$ sb2$/H$ sb2$-CO reduction of $ rm Na sb2SO sb4$ involving both solid-solid and gas-solid reactions are proposed.</description><creator>Tiwari, Akhilendra Kumar</creator><contributor>Kubes, G. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Heiningen, A. R. P. Van (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Kinetics of the reduction of sodium sulfate in kraft black liquor ash</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tg98s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b5919865</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):31100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>