<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:58:05Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27125" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d102g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Heart sounds recorded on the surface of the thorax can be significantly distorted due to the varying properties of the transmission paths between the heart chambers and body surface. For diagnostic purposes, it is desirable to obtain the sounds at the source. In this thesis, an algorithm has been developed to recover the left-ventricular component of the second heart sound from externally recorded phonocardiograms. The algorithm uses a model of the heart-thorax system and is derived from deconvolution techniques developed for analogous problems in speech processing and seismology. The algorithm has been tested on data acquired from dogs. The recovered sounds are compared with the intracardiac heart sounds by using the normalized crosscorrelation sequence, the mean squared error, and the coherence function. The results show that the recovered sounds exhibit a high degree of match to the intracardiac heart sounds.</description><creator>Yong, Stephen</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>An algorithm to recover the left-ventricular intracardiac second heart sound from externally recorded phonocardiograms /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t40w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d102g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dw68d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The way I approached this analysis was to start with two general statements, one on the form and the other on the harmony. This was so the reader could get a sense of the direction of the piece. Then I did a fairly detailed analysis of the introduction since most of the ideas originate from there. The rest of the piece is discussed in less detail, but occasionally there were places that needed a little more detailed explanation. In the postscript I describe some of my influences.</description><creator>McManaman, Steve</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Music -- Manuscripts -- Facsimiles</subject><subject>McManaman, Steve -- Manuscripts -- Facsimiles</subject><subject>Chamber orchestra music -- Scores</subject><title>High wire : for chamber orchestra</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010r311.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw68d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dd607</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was (i) to generate proteolytic enzyme-derived fragments of murine alpha-fetoprotein (AFP); (ii) to characterize some of their physicochemical and immunological properties; and (iii) to isolate the fragments from proteolytic digests of mouse AFP. Significant differences in digestion patterns produced by the limited proteolysis of AFP were apparent. Proteolysis under denaturing conditions was most efficient and yielded smaller peptide fragments of narrower molecular weight range. Similar findings were observed for larger scale digests using milligram amounts of AFP. Some of the cleavage products were found to possess antigenic properties of the parent AFP molecule as demonstrated by immunoblotting experiments. Attempts were made to isolate individual AFP peptides from digests of 20-40 mg of the glycoprotein. Only partial separation of the proteolytic fragments was accomplished. Experiments were performed which involved testing the immunoregulatory activity of synthetic AFP peptides on an in vitro lymphocyte reaction known to be sensitive to AFP-mediated suppression. Anti-proliferative activity was observed with one of the peptides, AFP-34/48, which represents an amino acid sequence near the N-terminus of the parent molecule.</description><creator>Pozzulo, Gina</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Analysis of proteolytic enzyme-derived fragments of murine alpha-fetoprotein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s76n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dd607</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010r329</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reproductive success of American kestrels (Falco sparverius) infected with Trichinella pseudospiralis was significantly reduced when compared with uninfected controls. Egg laying was delayed, and infected females produced fewer eggs than uninfected controls. Infected females were more aggressive and copulated less frequently. Egg breakage among infected birds was greater than among controls. Infected females tended to lay eggs outside the nest box. Infected females did not incubate as frequently as the controls, thus accounting for the higher prevalence of embryo mortality among these birds. The above effects translated into a mean production of 2.1 hatchlings per control pair and 0.6 per infected pair of kestrel. Both in breeding and non-breeding kestrel, T. pseudospiralis infections gave rise to a general decline in mobility. Behavioural effects are primarily attributable to the presence of muscle larvae. The parasite showed no predilection for specific muscle groups.</description><creator>Saumier, Michèle Dominique</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Agriculture, Forestry and Wildlife.</subject><subject>Biology, Zoology.</subject><title>The influence of experimental Trichinella pseudospiralis infections on the reproduction and behaviour of captive American kestrels (Falco sparverius) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr262.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010r329</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mn361</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A computer-coupled fermentation system has been developed for advanced research in fermentation technology. Application software programs were developed as concurrent task programs to perform data acquisition, process monitoring and feed stream manipulation. Another software program was also developed to support the application programs in a concurrent programming environment. This program supports generalized menu-driven operator interface and is application independent. The menu is reconfigurable by utility programs. Its well-defined parameter passing and input/output protocols enable the application software modules to be reused in different applications in a convenient way. A chemical solutions delivery system was also developed to some extent to allow fermentations to be studied in well controlled, unconventional modes of operation based on fed-batch or continuous-flow culture systems. Performance of the system components and new software were tested in operation simulations and one batch and three fed batch fermentations employing the acetone-butanol-ethanol process with Clostridium acetobutylicum.</description><creator>Leung, Wing K. (Wing Keung)</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Development of a computer-coupled fermentation system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg18h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn361</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pr48b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The imbibition of hexane, ethanol, and aqueous solutions of ethanol into packed beds of granular solids was studied at 25$ sp circ$C by measuring the time variation of the weight of the beds. The increase in weight was converted to meniscus height using the measured bed void fraction and the density of the liquid. The packed beds consisted of either glass beads or sand which were treated with trimethylchlorosilane (Si(CH$ sb3$)$ sb3$Cl) to provide a consistent surface. The contact angles of the liquids were measured directly on flat glass plates which had received the same chemical treatment as the granular solids. Twenty-four sets of imbibition data were obtained. The meniscus height-time data were correlated by a modified form of the Washburn equation, called the GW model. It provided excellent correlation of all experimental imbibition data with a minimum R$ sp2$ of 0.981. The best value of the adjustable parameter in the GW model, $ beta$, was 0.93, with a standard deviation of 0.36. Although some literature sources suggest values of $ beta$ of 3 to 6 on theoretical grounds, the value of 0.93 fits literature imbibition data.</description><creator>Liberman, Tom</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Capillarity and liquid imbibition in granular solids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh48g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pr48b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t321j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Early hypertrophy has justified the clinical use of vascularized bone grafts. This hypertrophy has not been established in experimental models, possibly because stress-shielded grafts were used. Our model allowed the grafts to bear weight. In 14 dogs we replaced the diaphysis of the radius with a vascularized fibula, and the diaphysis of the ulna with a conventional fibula (Group I). In 10 dogs we reversed the positions of the grafts (Group II). External fixation was used. The grafts were evaluated radiographically, mechanically and histologically. The vascularized grafts hypertrophied early, and were stronger than conventional grafts, particularly in Group I, where the former were stressed more. A previously unreported repair pattern was observed: vascularized grafts increased in size by peripheral apposition of new bone, there was no creeping substitution or weakening resorption. Conventional grafts remodeled by creeping repair, and hypertrophied slower, never reaching the size or the strength of the vascularized grafts.</description><creator>Welter, Jean F.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Vascularized vs. conventional bone grafts : an experimental comparison in large defects of weight-bearing bones</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462665n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t321j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sb37h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to study six of Taha Husayn's books in order to determine the factors which inspired him to write on Islam. For this reason, the thesis employs the study of Husayn's concept of Islam as a means to this end. Against the background of Husayn's liberal and humanistic ideas, the thesis examines his understanding of Islam as a religion and as a civilization. For additional insights, the methodology of the books and the general attitude of the author have been given consideration. The conclusion is that Taha Husayn was motivated by a strong desire to modernize and transform the cultural and social life of Egypt.</description><creator>Mohammed, Baba Gidado</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Islam -- Historiography</subject><subject>Ḥusayn, Ṭāhā, 1889-1973 -- Religion and ethics</subject><title>Ṭāhā Ḥusayn, a study of his six books with historical content on Islam</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bc83f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sb37h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gx34z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The documentary credit or letter of credit is and has been for many centuries a fundamental instrument of international commerce. The characteristics of simplicity of use and of legendary reliability found in this mechanism of payment have induced the parties involved in world trade to use it as a guarantee to the execution of all kinds of legal obligations such as the full completion of construction work, financing, payment of customs duties or taxes, judicial bonds and even promises of marriage. This master's thesis specifically concerns letters of credit used as a guarantee which are called in the trade "stand-by letters of credit". The first title presents the instrument in a practical context illustrating its principles with examples. The second title examines the legal aspects as such of the stand-by letter of credit while trying to circumscribe the nature of the instrument in law. Finally, in the third title, the cases where the functions and integrity of the instrument are tested are studied thereby identifying the legal strength of stand-by letters of credit recognized by the courts of different jurisdictions. This study has enabled me to discover that this instrument is not as well suited to be a guarantee than it is to be a payment mechanism. In fact, its principles of function which are assets when used as a payment can become sources of flagrant injustice in the eyes of courts of certain jurisdictions when used as a guarantee.</description><creator>Trudeau, Paul R.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Economics, Finance.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>La lettre de crédit stand-by en droit commercial international privé /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d722.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gx34z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278v25n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the ego development of a group of dropouts who had returned to school. The specific purpose was to explore and evaluate, systematically, the ego development of the former dropouts, and to compare their levels of ego development and their school performance to a group of students who were considered to be at risk to drop out of school. A group of students who were not considered to be at risk to drop out served as a control group. Seventeen high school students served as the subjects in this investigation. The main sources of data were: the results of the Washington University Sentence Completion Test for Ego Development that was developed by Dr. Jane Loevinger, grade and attendance reports, and interviews with the students and their teachers. The findings indicated that while the former dropouts had levels of ego development that were higher than the at risk subjects, the difference was not great enough to be statistically significant. The interviews were examined for indications of the subjects' levels of ego development in the manner in which they spoke about their experiences. The limitations of this investigation are considered, and some suggestions for further research are offered.</description><creator>Whalen, Thomas</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Ego (Psychology)</subject><subject>High school students</subject><subject>High school dropouts -- Psychological aspects</subject><title>Ego development in high school dropouts who have returned to school</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246t19d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v25n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n514</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lease, charter and interchange have become more and more important throughout the last decades. The International Civil Aviation Organization could not ignore that reality. In 1980 after a long preparatory work Article 83bis, an amendment to the Chicago Convention on International Civil Aviation was adopted by the 23rd Assembly without any negative votes. Yet, in 1990, this amendment, which enables the State of Registry, which is responsible for the operation of the aircraft even if flying with an operator of another state, to transfer its functions and duties to the State of the Operator. This thesis takes a closer look on the history of that amendment. The reasons why Article 83bis is still not in force shall also be discussed. An attempt shall further be made to analyze the provisions of Article 83bis more thoroughly and to explain why states should no longer hesitate to ratify that amendment. Article 83bis has no controversial content and is very important for the safety of international air transportation, in establishing clearly who is responsible for a leased, chartered or interchanged aircraft.</description><creator>Von Erlach, Burkhart</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Public law aspects of lease, charter and interchange of aircraft in international operations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw190.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n514</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d541q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to further the study of women's political participation by examining involvement in the Montreal Citizens Movement from approximately the time of its founding in the early 1970s to just after its achievement of power in 1986. Three approaches--resource mobilization, sexual division of labor and role conflict--are used to analyze critically the individual determinants, structural foundations, and nature of this participation, while a brief historical background provides the context for the movement and for its participants' actions. While authors have studied the MCM's structure and programs in general and have noted women's involvement primarily in its early stage as a social movement, there has been only limited discussion of women's participation. This thesis builds upon the latter by documenting and analyzing the nature of such participation using content analysis, participant observation, and personal interviews.</description><creator>Van der Veen, Paula Louise</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Rassemblement des citoyens et des citoyennes de Montréal</subject><subject>Women in politics -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Women and political participation : the Montreal Citizens Movement, 1974-1989</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r2248.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d541q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t60m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Intelligent tutoring systems (ITS) are expert systems united with computer-aided instruction. The psychological issue of human-computer interfacing combines aspects of education, cognitive science, human performance and psycho-sociolinguistics. This study presented a situation in which physicians used their reasoning to solve a computer-simulated medical case, embedded in the NEOMYCIN ITS. Experiments were designed to assess how their anthropomorphisation of the systems affected their medical reasoning in a complex ill-defined problem-solving domain. The study examines the subjects' interpretation of textual case materials, specifically their ascription of meaning and intelligibility to the form and usage of natural language. The results indicate that these factors affect their interpretation, not only of case materials, but also of their evaluation of the program's medical reasoning. This has implications for the interactive man-machine interface and its relationship to interpersonal communication is discussed.</description><creator>Williams, David C. (David Charles)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Intelligent tutoring systems</subject><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Observations of medical professionals' interactions with an intelligent tutoring system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n452t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t60m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z900j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the influence of polls and pollsters on politicians. The analysis reviews the American literature, which suggests that electoral technology is used by private political consultants to assist the politician in manipulating the voter. Six hypotheses are identified from the electoral manipulation literature, focusing specifically on the influence of political consultants on politicians. These hypotheses are tested with an historical analysis of the use of polls in the political organization of the Liberal Party of Canada from 1943 to 1984. Secondly, in-depth interviews were conducted with prominent Liberals, and are reviewed to further test the hypotheses as they relate to the influence of polling on politicians. The study concludes by examining the rise of electoral technocracy in the party, and by assessing the pollsters' influence on political decision-making.</description><creator>Drews, Ronald C.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Canada -- Politics and government</subject><subject>Liberal Party of Canada</subject><subject>Politicians -- Public opinion.</subject><title>Electoral manipulation and the influence of polling on politicians : a study of political organization in the Liberal Party of Canada up to the 1984 election campaign</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp74g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z900j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mw42s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The works of Sir Thomas Browne are often described in terms of the contradictions and paradoxes which seem to exist both within his work as a whole and also within the individual essays themselves. The primary focus of this thesis is the relationship between seemingly opposed forms of discourse and systems of thought in the Religio Medici, Hydriotaphia and The Garden of Cyrus. The emergence of analytic discourse in the seventeenth century is presented through the study of changing concepts of religious, political and epistemological mediation. Browne's 'mediate' position within the conflicts of his era is seen as representing a desire to unite apparent opposites and arrive at a 'complete' way of thinking which combines the medieval and the modern. The unified vision he advocates is of interest in both modern science and literary theory, where the premise of objectivity fundamental to analytic thinking is now being questioned.</description><creator>Lynch, Marianne</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Browne, Thomas, Sir, 1605-1682 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>That great and true Amphibium : mediation and unity in the works of Sir Thomas Browne</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz30z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw42s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kh576</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The author proved independently, every 2-tough graph is hamiltonian (3), that if G is a K-tough graph with n vertices and if kn is even then G has a k-factor (4) is best possible by showing that for every positive integer k and for every positive $ varepsilon$ there is a (k-$ varepsilon$)-tough graph G with no k-factor; furthermore, if k is odd then G can be made to have an even number of vertices; this result makes chapter 1 of the present thesis. Enomoto elaborated further on the subject and gave two results, in (4) and (5) respectively, which are improvements over (4): (5) provided that k$ vert$G$ vert$ is even and $ vert$G$ vert sbsp{=}{&gt;}$ k + 1, G has a k-factor if, for each set S of vertices, G-S has at most $ vert$S$ vert$/k + 7/8 components; and (6) provided that k$ vert$G$ vert$ is even and $ vert$G$ vert sbsp{=}{&gt;}$ k$ sp{2}$ + 1, G has a k-factor if, for each set S of vertices, G-S has at most $ vert$S$ vert$/k + 1 components. The proofs of (4), (5) and (6) make chapters 2, 3 and 4 respectively.</description><creator>Tsikopoulos, Nicholas</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Toughness and factors in graphs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f711q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kh576</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s1355</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Education represents one of Isabelle de Charriere's favourite topics. In her novels, the author has expressed her concerns on the matter, but her comments refer particularly to women's education. The present study will therefore be dedicated to the gathering of these observations, in order to show the author's position regarding the education of women. Afterwards, it should be possible to see whether Madame de Charriere's ideas may be compared to those of her time. In the case of women, moral education is preponderant, but knowledge is also important. In addition to her pedagogical advice, the writer provides some thoughts on the status of women in general.</description><creator>Bruneau, Louise</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Education in literature.</subject><subject>Charrière, Isabelle de, 1740-1805 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Women in literature</subject><title>L'education des femmes dans les romans de Madame de Charrière</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107023c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s1355</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m2966</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abstract Not Available.</description><creator>Radford, Laurie, 1958-</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Electronic music.</subject><subject>Choruses, Secular (Mixed voices) with percussion -- Scores.</subject><title>Origophonie : for 2-12 voice choirs (SATB), 6 percussion and tape</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c208.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m2966</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c01v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this paper, the mathematical theory of languages is used to investigate and develop computer systems for music analysis, composition, and performance. Four prominent research projects in the field are critically reviewed. An original grammar-type for the computer representation of music is introduced, and a computer system for music composition and performance based on that grammar is described. A user's manual for the system is provided as an appendix.</description><creator>Diener, Glendon</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Formal languages</subject><subject>Computer music</subject><subject>Music theory</subject><title>Formal languages in music theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n180.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c01v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mw45m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a generic model for crossflow heat exchangers with one fluid mixed, suitable for dynamic process simulation. A finite difference technique is used to formulate the coupled flow and energy solutions for arbitrary transients in pressure drop and temperature. The solution algorithms are presented in two forms: one-way dependence and two-way dependence: for the constant and variable property version of the model, respectively. Variable time step algorithms are also developed to predict the optimal time step for the finite difference solution. The first one uses a first order predictor method and the second one uses a combined first/second order predictor method. Finally, the generic model is configured to model the economizer and tubular air preheater of an existing boiler. Steady-state tests validate the numerical solution against available theoretical relations and transient tests investigate the parameters in the solution and time step algorithms to determine their effect on simulation speed and accuracy.</description><creator>Vaitekunas, David A.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>A generic dynamic model for crossflow heat exchangers with one fluid mixed /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m37k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw45m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tq49s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis challenges the way feminist literary criticism has been represented as a field polarized between American and French positions. As an alternative to the American/French distinction, I propose one between feminist criticism oriented to research and feminist criticism oriented to aesthetics. In keeping with this alternative distinction, I relocate the shift in feminist criticism within American feminism. The "aesthetic turn" inaugurated by American "gynocriticism" is itself identified in relation to a more general philosophical shift from discovery to creation. While the relativistic and voluntaristic tendencies which distinguish the latter pole are exemplified by French feminism, I argue that they are anticipated by American feminism's "aesthetic turn." Finally, this thesis not only relocates and redefines the shift in feminist literary criticism, but provides arguments in favour of a research-oriented feminist criticism.</description><creator>MacKeen, Alison</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Feminist literary criticism -- United States</subject><subject>Feminist literary criticism -- France</subject><subject>Feminist literary criticism</subject><title>From discovery to creation : feminist literary criticism's aesthetic turn</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nf77g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tq49s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mw44b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A diagnostic study using the CASP (Canadian Atlantic Storm Program) dataset and available precipitation data is performed to examine the thermodynamics of melting-induced mesoscale circulations. Various terms of the thermodynamic equation were evaluated. The horizontal and vertical advection terms were calculated using the rawinsonde data while the diabatic term due to melting was parameterized using surface precipitation observations. The effects of evaporation and dissipation were neglected in the calculation of the diabatic terms. The importance of the melting term was clearly shown although direct evidence of a melting-induced circulation was not found due to the relatively low resolution of the datasets used.</description><creator>Jarrett, Philip Lionel</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A diagnostic study of the thermodynamic equation in rain/snow boundaries /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w811.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw44b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vh85h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present work is divided in two parts: the first part contains analysis of some writings from Feria d'agosto among which "Il nome", narration that opens the series in the book, has retained our particular attention and its analysis brings us to discover "classic" origins not yet identified by critics. "Il nome" is the key to finding out about the essence of Pavese's poetics. In the second part we approach the Croce-Pavese's affinities. The relation arises from Pavese's controversial writing on Proust. We also give an idea of reviews which reflected various tendencies of the Arts during the 20th century. We are trying to place Pavese in his "time" and we are searching out how many of those ideological aspirations are in our writer's poetics.</description><creator>Guardo Siino, Lina, 1936-</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Pavese, Cesare -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>"Il nome" : per una poetica "classica" di Cesare Pavese</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jp92f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh85h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h304x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nociceptive component of the flexion reflex (FR) has been observed by several investigators to be a reliable physiological manifestation of pain perception in man. It has thus been used as an index of spinal nociceptive activity to study analgesic mechanisms. Vibration is one analgesic procedure which has been reported to decrease subjective pain report in certain pain conditions. The objective of this study was thus to quantitatively investigate the behavior of the human FR during segmental peripheral conditioning with high-frequency vibration. A first study was undertaken to determine the relationship between pain sensation and the FR under the paradigm developed in this laboratory. Visual analogue scale (VAS) ratings of subjective sensation were found to bear a high, linear correlation with stimulus intensity (r = 0.95) and with FR area (r = 0.91). In the main study, we found segmental vibration to inhibit the FR in 5 of 9 subjects. The modulatory effects displayed a slow onset and decay, lasting beyond the 30 min vibration period. Maximum modulation occurred late into vibration, and in some cases after vibration. The direction and magnitude of modulatory effects were basically the same in both biceps femoris (BF) and tibialis anterior (TA) muscles. Our results raised the possibility that prolonged vibration could influence spinal nociceptive reflexes in ways similar to the vibration-induced pain relief described in the clinical literature.</description><creator>Dallaire, Michel</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The influence of vibratory stimulation on the nociceptive component of the lower limb flexion relfex in man /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50ts803.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h304x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bm800</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:56:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Current technology and the planning of ambitious programs for the next decade tend to transform the stakes inherent in space activities. In effect, the launching of space stations and platforms pave the way towards new industrial prospects previously unheard of to date. Thus, the objective of this thesis is to present an outline of these new prospects and to undertake a legal analysis motivating the transition from basic research to commercial applications. Consequently, the preliminary chapter will describe the general characteristics of those future trends towards commercial and industrial space activities. Legal provisions of Public International Space law are examined in the first chapter, notably those which are indicative of the difficulties encountered in this process. A second chapter will conduct the study of the questions regarding Registration, Jurisdiction and Choice of Law which hopefully lead to a successful regulation of Outer Space activities. The US/International Space Station project will provide an example which will underline the deficiencies and ambiguities of the applicable law. Finally, the development of a legal framework favouring the commercial viability of these future commercial production processes will be produced in the third chapter.</description><creator>Nordlund, Frédéric</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Le régime juridique des activités industrielles et commerciales conduites dans l'espace extra-atmosphérique : nouvelles orientations</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q518w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bm800</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27150</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>