<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:55:00Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225g347</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Large caldera-forming eruptions are among the greatest hazards faced by mankind. Eruptive sequences from caldera-forming eruptions at Ossipee ring complex, New Hampshire, and Lake City caldera, Colorado, reveal that magmas underwent crystal fractionation to produce a zoned silicic magma chamber in each case before caldera formation. At Ossipee, magmatic inclusions with resorbed phenocrysts and positive Eu anomalies demonstrate that magma replenishment caused chamber rejuvenation and the initiation of caldera collapse. At Lake City, two ignimbrite units associated with episodes of caldera collapse have mafic-rich bases; this indicates that these collapse events were initiated by mafic magma replenishment. A numerical model is developed that describes how magma chamber rejuvenation causes a reduction in crystal content, a decrease in gas pressure, and hence caldera collapse. During caldera formation at Ossipee and Lake City, magmas from progressively deeper levels in the chambers were erupted and intruded to shallower levels. Periods of reverse compositional zonation and lateral compositional variation at the top of ignimbrite units and in post-collapse intrusions indicate that a period of accelerated magma interaction occurred in the chambers towards the end of subsidence. Scaled analogue experiments of caldera collapse into density-stratified magma chambers reveal a similar period of reverse zonation and dynamic fluid interaction as the subsiding block approaches the chamber base. Additionally, the experiments indicate that piecemeal or asymmetric collapse cause vortices to develop in the chamber which efficiently disrupt stratification. After caldera collapse at Ossipee and Lake City, replenishing magma caused mixed residual magma to intrude along caldera faults to shallow levels and drive resurgence. The work illustrates how particular magmatic processes influence caldera collapse, and in turn, how caldera collapse affects particular magmatic processes.</description><creator>Kennedy, Ben.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Magmatic processes associated with the development of large silicic calderas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Ben Kennedy, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f7879.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225g347</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149t879</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the 1990s, Turkey has started to develop an extensive interest in its Ottoman past. The view of the Ottomans as "backward" and "pre-modern" that once held sway has given way to a view that grasps the Ottoman past as "open," "tolerant," and "cosmopolitan." Food is one of the areas in which Turkey's Ottoman past is negotiated. This dissertation attempts to trace the revival of Ottoman cuisine through experiences of production, representation, and commodification in Istanbul. It seeks to understand multiple discourses involved in the relationship between the past and the present, within a context where history implicates both continuity and novelty. Ottoman cuisine has developed not only as the foundation of traditional Turkish cuisine, but also as its "other." This dissertation examines the revival of Ottoman cuisine through an analysis of diverse sources, such as cookbooks, media, culinary institutes, cultural and social organizations, the cultural policies of the state, and mainstream restaurant and festival venues. Finally, it asserts that the revival of Ottoman cuisine in particular seems to feed multiple discourses of cosmopolitanism. The turn back to the Ottoman period is both nationalistic and cosmopolitan, such that cosmopolitanism is turned into a national image and a national cultural asset. As a result, the past becomes a utopian project for the future, and cosmopolitanism of the past haunts Turkey and Istanbul as a progressive image for the contemporary world.</description><creator>Karaosmanoǧlu, Defne.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Cooking, Turkish.</subject><subject>Turkey -- Civilization.</subject><title>Cooking the past : the revival of Ottoman cuisine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Defne Karaosmanoǧlu, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494d60d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t879</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d412b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The insulin-like growth factor-II/mannose-6-phosphate (IGF-II/M6P) receptor is a multifunctional single transmembrane glycoprotein which mediates the trafficking of M6P-containing lysosomal enzymes from the trans-Golgi network to endosomes-lysosomes (EL). IGF-II/M6P receptors located at the cell surface also function in the internalization and subsequent degradation or activation of extracellular IGF-II and other M6P-bearing ligands. However, very little is currently known about the significance of the receptor in the function of the central nervous system. Results from this thesis project indicate that IGF-II/M6P receptors are widely, but selectively distributed throughout the adult rat brain and spinal cord, and that a subset of receptors is found to be expressed in cholinergic neurons/fibers. We have also found that the IGF-II/M6P receptor in the rat brain couples to a G protein and that its activation by Leu27IGF-II, an analog which binds preferentially to the IGF-II/M6P receptor, potentiates acetylcholine release from the adult rat hippocampal formation. Additionally, we have shown that Leu27IGF-II can cause a significant reduction in whole-cell currents and depolarization of dissociated basal forebrain cholinergic neurons. These effects are mediated by a pertussis toxin-sensitive, protein kinase Ca-dependent pathway. Furthermore, we have also demonstrated that selective in vivo degeneration of basal forebrain cholinergic neurons by 192 IgG-saporin, which is mediated in part by an increase in glycogen sythase kinase-3beta activity, results in an up-regulation of IGF-II/M6P receptor levels in surviving neurons of the basal forebrain and frontal cortex. This is accompanied by a parallel time-dependent increase in other EL proteins, including Rab5, LAMP2 and the lysosomal hydrolase cathepsin D. Given the critical role of the EL system in regulating cell viability, it is likely that the increase in the level of the IGF-II/M6P receptor and other components of the EL system in surviving neurons represents an adaptive mechanism to restore the metabolic and structural abnormalities which follow 192 IgG-saporin-induced toxicity. We also report that IGF-II/M6P receptors levels are decreased in the hippocampus of Alzheimer disease (AD) brains as a function of apolipoprotein epsilon4-allele number. Moreover, immunoreactive IGF-II/M6P receptors are found to colocalize with a subset of beta-amyloid-positive neuritic plaques and tau-positive neurofibrillary tangles in the frontal cortex and hippocampus of the AD brain. Taken together, these results suggest that IGF-II/M6P receptors which are widely expressed in the adult brain, can serve a multifunctional role, including the maintenance of cellular homeostasis, modulation of neurotransmitter release and possibly in the restoration of metabolic and structural abnormalities in neurons which survive toxicity/injury.</description><creator>Hawkes, Cheryl.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Distribution and significance of the insulin-like growth factor-IIMannose-6 phosphate receptor in the central nervous system with special emphasis on the cholinergic system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Cheryl Hawkes, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t67d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d412b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945w22h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Excessive activity has been a prominent feature in the symptomatology of attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) for more than four decades. While overactivity has helped to identify persons with ADHD, the movement skill proficiency and physical activity experiences of children with ADHD have been overlooked (Harvey &amp; Reid, 1997). This dissertation is a series of four original manuscripts that explore relationships between adapted physical activity (APA) and ADHD. The first manuscript, a review paper, discusses important issues related to ADHD. It suggests many children with ADHD experience poor levels of physical fitness and movement skill difficulties when compared to children without ADHD (Harvey &amp; Reid, 2003). Numerous reference citations for seminal review articles on ADHD were provided. The second manuscript, another review paper, explored research methods used in movement performance studies about ADHD. Twenty new APA research questions about ADHD were posed (Harvey &amp; Reid, 2005). Issues surrounding identification of ADHD, data collection procedures, and strategies to improve APA research about ADHD were also provided. The two review papers, when combined, are a substantial and original contribution to the ADHD literature. The third manuscript is a study about the effects of stimulant medication on the fundamental movement skill performance for 22 children with ADHD and a comparison of their movement skills to age- and gender-matched peers without ADHD. Multivariate statistical analyses revealed no significant effect of methylphenidate on the performance criteria of the TGMD-2 (Ulrich, 2000) for the children with ADHD. Significant differences between the children with and without ADHD were found on both locomotor skills and object control skills. A movement skill profile was developed for each group and they are unique contributions to the movement performance literature. The fourth manuscript is a study that explores the lived physical activity experiences of six boys with and without ADHD. Semi-structured interviews revealed some similarities among both groups about their physical activity experiences. However, qualitative differences were apparent on key aspects of skill proficiency. It is concluded that more in-depth APA research about people with ADHD is necessary to gain a clearer understanding of the children's unique physical activity needs.</description><creator>Harvey, William J., 1964-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physical education and training.</subject><subject>Hyperactive children -- Education.</subject><subject>Movement education.</subject><title>Fundamental movement skills and associated physical activity experiences of children with ADHD</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© William J. Harvey, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t68p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945w22h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451n87p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is about the life of David McCord and the contribution he made to Canadian public memory as founder of the McCord Museum of National History. In his McGilI-sponsored museum, founded in 1921, McCord sought to promote a myth of Canadian origins with narration provided by the objects of his personal collection. Integral to this history was the story of the McCord family, their arrival on this continent and their rise to social prominence. In McCord's version of Canadian history, family and personal myth were conflated with that of nation. Viewed through the prism of his collecting and museum work, McCord's life does not easily fit the Carlylean frame adopted by most biographers. In Canadian biographical writing by historians, the 'truth' about a person's life is revealed by following the modernist recipe of painstakingly recreating a detailed chronology of the individual's life. The approach followed here is an important departure from traditional political biography. Entry into McCord's life does not occur at his biological birth date, but at the moment of his own self-fashioned 'birthing', with the opening of the museum realized near the end of his life. In this biographical strategy, McCord's museum acts as a theatre of memory, where fragments of his life story are reassembled to create a narrative of national origins and of personal redemption. In his selection of objects and their display, and in the creation of an archive and the museum itself, McCord left a very elaborate and lasting record of his response to a set of changes associated with industrialization, a process which, in his lifetime, radically transformed the Montreal of his parents' generation. This thesis traces the connection between the creation of a public museum, founded to promote a collective vision of the Canadian past, and the private world of one collector whose collecting practice was defined as much by his own desire to remember and be remembered as it was by the kinds of objects he collected. What makes David McCord's life and collection so compelling is the opportunity it provides from understanding national history from the intimate perspective of one individual.</description><creator>Harvey, Kathryn Nancy.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>McCord, David Ross, 1844-1930.</subject><subject>McCord Museum.</subject><title>David Ross McCord (1844-1930) : imagining a self, imagining a nation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kathryn Nancy Harvey, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gs446.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451n87p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tr187</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the educational inequalities facing Black high school students, particularly working-class youths in Ottawa's educational system. In consultation with several community organizations, educators, parents and students, several concerns were identified as barriers that impacted the educational achievement of Black youths in Ottawa's schools. They identified issues such as the continued negative stereotyping of Black students, particularly Black males as being aggressive, violent, low achievers, and lacking respect for authority, which often results in their suspensions and/or expulsion. Most importantly, they argue that in addition to the high rate of suspensions and expulsions, there also appears to be a funneling of Black working-class males into the criminal juvenile justice system, by schools, which results in the criminalization of Black youths by Ottawa schools. This study was framed within a Black antiracist feminist framework that employed an oppositional and critical pedagogy aimed at interrogating the educational experiences of Black youths. The study examined the impact of race and class on educational outcome, and the ways in which the current educational arrangement benefits some students while disadvantaging others. Critical to the study is the denial of racism within Ottawa schools by educators and administrators. The problem is further complicated by the fact that neither the Ottawa Carleton District School Board nor the Carleton Roman Catholic Separate School Board compiles statistical database on students' race, ethnicity and/or social class, which is a necessary tool in determining the existence of educational inequality. Due to the lack of educational statistics educators have avoided accountability, thus preserving the status quo.</description><creator>Haynes, Janet M.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Youth, Black -- Ontario -- Ottawa.</subject><subject>Discrimination in education -- Ontario -- Ottawa.</subject><subject>Racism -- Ontario -- Ottawa.</subject><subject>Ottawa (Ont.) -- Race relations.</subject><subject>Education -- Ontario -- Ottawa.</subject><title>The impact of race and class on the educational experience of Black students in Ottawa's educational system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Janet M. Haynes, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r276b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tr187</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h853k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Canada, prostate cancer is the most frequently diagnosed cancer in man and the third leading cause of cancer related death. In order to identify genes implicated in prostate cancer progression, we used microcell-mediated chromosome transfer to introduce chromosomes 10, 12, 17 and 18 into human PC-3-derived cells lines called PC-3M-Pro4GP1 and PC-3M-LN4GP2. The properties of the hybrids were determined by invasion assay, growth in soft agar and injection into nude mice (either subcutaneously or orthotopically). After the transfer of chromosome 18 in our cell lines, we have identified two sets of hybrids that show opposite phenotypes. Genotyping studies indicated that one locus on chromosome 18 (D18S51) contains an additional allele in the less tumorigenic hybrids. This allele is absent in the highly tumorigenic hybrids as well as in tumors derived from the injection of less tumorigenic cells into nude mice. Preliminary microarray data analysis showed that two genes located in the D18S51 region (ERK4 and BCL2) were differentially expressed in the less tumorigenic hybrids compared to the tumorigenic hybrids. We examined publicly available microarray data sets and found that ERK4 was down regulated in prostate, adrenal and lung cancers. We have also examined the possibility that the metastasis suppressor gene MASPIN (also located in the D18S51 region) could be responsible for the less tumorigenic phenotype seen in our hybrids. Real-time PCR studies showed that ERK4 and MASPIN were up regulated in the less tumorigenic hybrids and that BCL2 was down regulated in these same cells. However, Western immunoblot experiments did not show any difference in the MASPIN or the BCL2 protein levels. Thus, MASPIN or a BCL2 repressor are most likely not responsible for the less tumorigenic phenotype of our hybrids. Interestingly, re-introduction of ERK4 in our tumorigenic hybrids completely abolished their ability to form colonies in soft agar and to invade through Matrigel. However, there is no difference in tumor growth rate upon injection of ERK4-over-expressing cells compared to mock-transfected controls. We also found a non-synonymous polymorphism in the coding sequence of the ERK4 gene. This polymorphism is present at the same frequency in Asian, European and Ashkenazi Jewish populations but less frequently in the African (Yoruba) population. This is the first report of a non-synonymous polymorphism in the coding sequence of the ERK4 gene. However, based on a limited number of prostate cancer cases, the presence of this poylmorphism is not associated with the disease. Taken together, these results demonstrate that ERK4 is a good candidate for a tumor suppressor gene implicated in prostate cancer progression.</description><creator>Gagnon, Audrey.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>ERK4, a new tumor suppressor gene candidate implicated in prostate cancer progression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Audrey Gagnon, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687n508.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h853k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r75k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High field strength elements (HFSE) are geologically and economically important. These elements were once thought to be immobile during metasomatic processes, however, a growing body of empirical evidence indicates that HFSE can be mobilized under certain conditions. Despite this evidence, little is known about the factors controlling solubility, transport and deposition of HFSE by aqueous fluids, apart from some theoretical estimates and rare experimental studies. Therefore, the study of natural systems (e.g., HFSE ore deposits) provides an excellent opportunity to evaluate HFSE mobility by aqueous fluids. Five localities where evidence of hydrothermal transport of HFSE has been previously documented were included in this study: Gallinas Mountains, New Mexico; South Platte, Colorado; Rock Canyon Creek, British Columbia; St. Lawrence, Newfoundland; and Strange Lake, Quebec/Labrador. Minerals and, in the case of South Platte, fluid inclusions from these localities were analyzed using petrography and laser ablation inductively-coupled plasma mass spectrometry (LA-ICPMS) to evaluate the source of the HFSE and the hydrothermal fluids responsible for HFSE transport, and factors controlling HFSE and gangue mineral (e.g., fluorite, quartz) precipitation. Analysis of some of the important gangue minerals, which are also the primary host of fluid inclusions in many of these deposits (e.g., fluorite), is difficult using 266 nm Nd:YAG-based LA-ICPMS. Furthermore, complex mineral intergrowths and the desire to quantify the chemical composition of unknown minerals required the development of analytical and data reduction protocols for LA-ICPMS. Methods for conducting traversed opening of fluid inclusions, removing the host mineral contribution to fluid inclusion signals by calculating count rate ratios, and quantifying the composition of minerals without using an internal standard are presented. In general, hydrothermal enrichment of HFSE in these deposits appears to have resulted from interaction of an HFSE- and F-bearing magmatic fluid with another, Ca-bearing fluid or with Ca-bearing wall rocks or preexisting minerals. In most cases, HFSE appear to be derived locally, within the associated igneous intrusion.</description><creator>Gagnon, Joel Edward.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Genesis of hydrothermal high field strength element mineral deposits : evidence from laser ablation--inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Joel Edward Gagnon, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558j344.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r75k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd376192z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Thesis explores the properties and potential applications of 4-(dimethylamino)pyridine-capped gold (DMAP-Au) nanoparticles. The binding mode of the DMAP ligand to the gold surface was investigated in detail and the factors that make this substituted pyridine an effective protective ligand for gold nanoparticles were determined. DMAP-Au nanoparticle samples have a mean diameter between 5 and 6 nm and narrow size dispersity. DMAP is noncovalently bound to the nanoparticle surface via the endocyclic nitrogen. The positively charged nanoparticles are stable in aqueous solution over a wide pH range (5 to 12). The interactions of DMAP-Au nanoparticles with the anionic polyelectrolytes poly(acrylate) and poly(styrene sulfonate) were investigated by following changes in the optical properties of the nanoparticles. The enhanced stability of the nanoparticles at low pH values observed in the presence of polyelectrolytes is attributed to the wrapping of the polyelectrolyte chains around the small nanoparticles. The study of the composition of the polyelectrolyte-coated nanoparticles reveals that the polyelectrolyte chains adsorb onto the DMAP protective monolayer rather than displace it at the nanoparticle surface. The details of the interactions of the polyelectrolytes with a DMAP monolayer were further elucidated by using surface plasmon resonance (SPR) spectroscopy. This surface-sensitive technique allows the in situ study of the adsorption of the two polyelectrolytes on a 2D DMAP-modified gold surface and of their conformational changes as a function of pH. The results obtained correlate well with those of analogous 3D-systems. The polyelectrolyte chains are found to adsorb onto, and stabilize, the DMAP layer. Finally, the use of DMAP-Au nanoparticles as a starting material in ligand exchange reactions was investigated. DMAP-Au nanoparticles prove to be excellent precursors to water- and organic-soluble nanoparticles. Relatively small amounts of incoming ligand are sufficient to fully replace the initial DMAP capping layer and the narrow size dispersity of the nanoparticles is maintained upon ligand exchange.</description><creator>Gandubert, Valérie J.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>4-(Dimethylamino)pyridine-capped gold nanoparticles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Valérie J. Gandubert, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jw34g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd376192z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107329n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pervasive developmental disorders are a group of neurodevelopmental-neuropsychiatric disorders that are characterized by variable and severe pervasive impairments in several areas of child development, notably social interaction, communication and imagination. They all share clinical features but differ in the severity and age of onset of the impairments. Except for Rett Syndrome (RTT), the etiology of these disorders is unknown, but there is strong evidence that genetic factors contribute to their pathogenesis. While no major genes have been linked to theses disorders linkages, association and chromosomal studies suggest that many loci may be involved. One aim of the present study was to search for genetics variants associated with autism and other related disorders. This study represents the first family-based association study looking at the entire X chromosome using a French-Canadian autistic population, a genetically homogenous group. We found association between autism and markers at two loci. Our results support the existence of a putative gene located on the X chromosome and moreover the founder effect, in the French-Canadian population, may provide greater power to fine map disease genes especially in complex traits. The second aim of the present thesis was to confirm the involvement of the MECP2 gene in our RTT group of patients. While we confirm the presence of mutations in this gene in our cohort of RTT patients we also demonstrated that clinical stringency greatly influences the mutation detection rate for this disorder.</description><creator>Gauthier, Julie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Autism -- Québec (Province) -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Rett syndrome -- Québec (Province) -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Developmental disabilities -- Québec (Province) -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Genetic investigation of pervasive developmental disorders in the Quebec population</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Julie Gauthier, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j3205.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107329n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nk00p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Low-rise buildings, constructed using wood, are vulnerable to extreme wind storms and earthquakes. While several experimental measurements of the environmental loads (mostly wind) on the building envelope have been made at full scale, none of these studies directly linked these external loads with the internal forces and displacements of the structure, as achieved in this research. The thesis presents the experimental and analytical work on two light-frame wooden structures, where one already existed (Forintek shed in Quebec City) and the other (UNB house) was built specifically for the research project on the University of New Brunswick campus in Fredericton. The research goal was to devise and demonstrate methods of identifying load paths in light-frame wood buildings subject to environmental loads. The objectives were also to improve the knowledge on the magnitude of the forces generated by environmental loads on typical low-rise buildings; to measure forces and deformations in test buildings and correlate them with the applied loads; and finally to develop accurate numerical whole-building structural models. These goals were achieved by carrying out experiments at the element level (studs, sheathings), subsystem level (shear walls) and on the whole-building level (finished and "realistic" light-frame timber buildings). The responses of these buildings to controlled static tests as well as natural environmental loads were observed and compared with a wind tunnel study and with detailed finite element models with good agreement. Shear walls were tested in isolation and as a part of the whole structure. The tests indicated that neither the strength nor the stiffness decreased by the same magnitude as the wall effective length is reduced. Therefore, the simple concept of effective length, being used presently, is invalid. For the Forintek shed, the structural monitoring was based on measurements of deformations within a representative segment of the wall and roof surfaces and a matching grid of wall and roof wind pressure taps supplemented with a wind tunnel study at Concordia University. In general, it was shown that the building surroundings had a great effect on the pressure distribution of the surface on the structure and that these effects are cannot always be determined intuitively. Both mean and peak pressure coefficient were measured and they compared well with corresponding values obtained in the wind tunnel tests. In general, the peak pressure coefficients from the full-scale tests were higher than those obtained from the wind-tunnel tests. The results from controlled static loads on the UNB house indicated that the load was distributed to all walls, and significant load sharing was observed. Mostly, this reflected not only the rigidity of the roof, but also the rigidity of transverse walls. The stiffness of the roof was sufficient to distribute load to walls farthest away from the load application point. Also, the expected vertical paths for load were not observed. It was also found that the internal forces are concentrated near the corners of the building. Under vertical loading on the roof, the load at the roof-to-wall interface was concentrated in a small region of the building plan around the application point. This was not the case at the superstructure-to-foundation interface. The test results also showed that the load was transferred to the transverse walls, even though there were only nominal connection between the wall and the roof trusses. The results from the analytical modeling showed good agreement with the full-scale test results for shear walls as well as for the whole building. The 3-D model was able to simulate the sharing of racking forces between shear walls, based on experiments reported in the literature. It was also able to reproduce static test results and predict the force measurements obtained from load cells underneath the house structure. In general, the errors in the numerical prediction were small. The model was able to predict the interaction between the roof system and the walls and the interactions amongst walls. The research relied on the collaboration of several researchers in industry and academia, and was funded by a CRD grant of the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada.</description><creator>Doudak, Ghasan.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Field determination and modeling of load paths in wood light-frame structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ghasan Doudak, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c4814.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nk00p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc89m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the representation of the erotic body in the works of the most important authors of French sixteenth-century poetry, particularly those of the Pleiade. By "erotic body" we mean a body that is involved in activities of carnal love, a type of love which is considered, during the Renaissance, as the opposite of a more chaste and spiritual kind of love. Our hypothesis is that the textual representation of such a body is coherent throughout the sixteenth century. Since poetic expression is governed by rules of decency during this period, description of the erotic body cannot be direct; its expression depends on analogy and attenuation techniques. Analogy, besides its allusive quality, creates the image of a body "open" to the cosmos rather than one that is fragmented and hermetic. Beauty holds a central position in the imagery of the erotic body. It is a very conventional beauty whose qualities (white, round, hard and smooth) transform the female form into a veritable statue. On the contrary, ugliness and disease are used to sanction behaviour that would otherwise be seen as reprehensible. The erotic art shown in poetry is framed by orthodox morals that condemn certain acts such as sodomy. The guiding principle is one of moderation. Erotic art is also based upon gestures that are fluid and capricious, quite the opposite of a fixed posture. Gestures are made in varied ways, from biting to tickling. However, kissing is the most important practice; it literally kills and resurrects the lover. The center of Renaissance erotic art is the loving couple, whose relations consist of requital and sometimes also of restraint. The game of feigned resistance allows lovers to reconcile these two extremes and to create an erotic relationship that embraces opposition and collaboration between the sexes. The most sought-after locations in Renaissance eroticism are always the same: bucolic surroundings offering a corner away from others' eyes. Temporality on the other hand is variable: stages of life, seasons, holidays, all lend themselves to carnal love. However, the instant reveals itself as the most erotic moment, not because it allows direct pleasure but because it concentrates desire under the guise of a call to carpe diem or of fictitious times (wishes, prayers), thus offering an imaginary satisfaction.</description><creator>Dorais, David, 1975-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Human body in literature.</subject><subject>French poetry -- 16th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Eroticism in literature.</subject><title>Le corps érotique dans la poésie française du seizième siècle /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© David Dorais, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806433t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc89m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n543b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The modelling of contaminant transport in porous media is an important topic to geosciences and geo-environmental engineering. An accurate assessment of the spatial and temporal distribution of a contaminant is an important step in the environmental decision-making process. Contaminant transport in porous media usually involves complex non-linear processes that result from the interaction of the migrating chemical species with the geological medium. The study of practical problems in contaminant transport therefore usually requires the development of computational procedures that can accurately examine the non-linear coupling processes involved. However, the computational modelling of the advection-dominated transport process is particularly sensitive to situations where the concentration profiles can exhibit high gradients and/or discontinuities. This thesis focuses on the development of an accurate computational methodology that can examine the contaminant transport problem in porous media where the advective process dominates. The development of the computational method for the advection-dominated transport problem is based on a Fourier analysis on stabilized semi-discrete Eulerian finite element methods for the advection equation. The Fourier analysis shows that under the Courant number condition of Cr=1, certain stabilized finite element scheme can give an oscillation-free and non-diffusive solution for the advection equation. Based on this observation, a time-adaptive scheme is developed for the accurate solution of the one-dimensional advection-dominated transport problem with the transient flow velocity. The time-adaptive scheme is validated with an experimental modelling of the advection-dominated transport problem involving the migration of a chemical solution in a porous column. A colour visualization-based image processing method is developed in the experimental modelling to quantitatively determinate the chemical concentration on the porous column in a non-invasive way. A mesh-refining adaptive scheme is developed for the optimal solution of the multi-dimensional advective transport problem with a time- and space-dependent flow field. Such mesh-refining adaptive procedure is quantitative in the sense that the size of the refined mesh is determined by the Courant number criterion. Finally, the thesis also presents a brief study of a numerical model that is capable to capture coupling Hydro-Mechanical-Chemical processes during the advection-dominated transport of a contaminant in a porous medium.</description><creator>Dong, Wenjun, 1969-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Modelling of advection-dominated transport in fluid-saturated porous media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Wenjun Dong, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j533b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n543b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mh262</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Women's access to micro credit has increased substantially worldwide. International organizations, non-governmental organizations, commercially-oriented institutions and governments support the proliferation of micro credit programs through diverse funding arrangements, and specifically target women to participate in such initiatives. This dissertation explores women's experiences in a micro credit program in Cairo, Egypt, funded by Save the Children (USA) in order to contribute to the growing debate on women's poverty reduction and empowerment potential. Because women's voices are critical the issues are raised through questions regarding women's situation in micro credit and what factors assist women in meeting their choices and concerns, and empowerment outcomes. A qualitative research study of women's micro credit groups based in Cairo's Abdeen and Imbeba neighbourhoods was used in order to address women's experiences. In the literature reviewed on micro credit and micro finance, international development paradigms for women, and the socio-economic context in Cairo served to identify important influences. Women's sources of power based in the household were used to develop a conceptual framework. Women's triple roles in production, reproduction and community managing, women's practical and strategic gender needs, and theories of women's empowerment formed the principal elements. Findings were based on interviews and observation with 69 project participants, including 54 women borrowers, of which 11 interviewed women agreed to a second interview, and 4 key staff members of the Group Guaranteed Lending and Savings program. Numerous assumptions regarding the role of micro credit in the lives of low-income women are reported and analyzed. An exploration of women's experiences reveals that, social issues in micro credit are as important, perhaps even more so, than the economic concerns of the projects. Only through building a more complete picture of women's lives can micro credit programs achieve their objective: to contribute to greater gender equity in society.</description><creator>Drolet, Julie L.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Bank loans -- Egypt -- Cairo.</subject><subject>Microfinance -- Egypt -- Cairo.</subject><subject>Women -- Egypt -- Cairo -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Women -- Egypt -- Cairo -- Social conditions.</subject><title>Women and micro credit : towards an understanding of women's experiences in Cairo, Egypt</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Julie L. Drolet, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2366594.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mh262</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x5484</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My PhD work focuses on the study of the layer-specific targeting of photoreceptor (R-cell) axons in the developing Drosophila visual system. More specifically, I have studied the roles of two molecules, the receptor tyrosine kinase Off-track (Otk) and the transmembrane protein Semaphorin1a (Sema1a) in R-cell axon guidance and target selection. The Drosophila adult visual system is comprised of the compound eye and the optic lobe. The compound eye is comprised of ~800 ommatidia, each containing eight different R-cells. As the visual system develops, R-cells project axons through the optic stalk toward two different layers of the optic lobe. R1-6 axons innervate the superficial lamina layer while R7 and R8 axons project through the lamina into the deeper medulla layer. Previous studies demonstrated that the SH2/SH3 adapter protein Dock and two receptor protein tyrosine phosphatases LAR and PTP69D are required for the termination of R1-6 axons in the lamina, indicating that protein tyrosine phosphorylation is a key signaling event in regulating this process. However, nothing was known about the molecular nature of protein tyrosine kinases involved. By taking a testing-candidate-gene approach, I identified Otk as a key player in regulating Rl-R6 axon targeting. Otk protein is expressed in R-cell axons and is predominantly localized to R1-6 growth cones. Phenotypic analysis of otk mutants using a set of developmental markers indicates that otk is specifically required for R1-6 growth-cone targeting. That R1-6 targeting defect in otk mutants could be rescued substantially by eye-specific expression of an otk transgene, together with the results from genetic mosaic analysis, indicates that otk is required in R1-6 growth cones for the lamina-specific termination. I propose that Otk functions as a receptor for a target-derived stop signal to terminate R1-R6 growth cones in the lamina. Previous studies had implicated Sema1a as an upstream activator of Otk in Drosophila embryonic motor axon guidance. I compared the loss-of-function phenotypes of both sema1a and otk in order to test whether sema1a may also function upstream of otk in the visual system. We found that loss of sema1a caused an R-cell projection phenotype different from that in otk mutants, suggesting that sema1a plays a different role in R-cell axon guidance. Our immunohistological analysis demonstrated that Sema1a is present on R-cell axons and growth cones. Loss-of-function analysis reveals a requirement for sema1a in the association of R1-R6 growth cones in the lamina. Consistently, overexpression of sema1a caused the formation of abnormal thicker bundles in a dosage-dependent manner. Interestingly, we found that the cytoplasmic domain of Sema1a is absolutely required for its function in R-cell axon guidance, suggesting a model in which Sema1a functions as a guidance receptor to mediate R-cell growth-cone interactions during R-cell axon projections.</description><creator>Cafferty, Patrick William.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The roles of Off-track and Semaphorin-1a in Drosophila visual system development /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Patrick William Cafferty, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs56x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x5484</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fs96d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alexithymia is a personality construct characterized by a deficit in the cognitive processing and regulation of emotion. The well documented association of alexithymia with illness has prompted investigations into pathways that might explain this association, such as physiological mechanisms or increased illness behaviour. The first aim of the present research was to explore the hypothesis that alexithymia has the potential to lead to disease because of peculiarities in physiological reactivity to emotional stimuli. The second aim was to examine the influence of alexithymia on self-report of somatic symptoms associated with a controlled medical event, and to extend assessment of cardiovascular reactivity to a qualitatively different emotional stressor in a quasi-naturalistic setting, thereby increasing generalizability. In Study One, film clips selected to induce positive and negative emotions were presented to high- and low-alexithymia men and women while physiological and cognitive-experiential facets of emotional responding were monitored. High-alexithymia males displayed reduced respiratory sinus arrhythmia in response to emotion induction, significantly different from the increase shown by others. This effect was independent of emotional valence or specificity. High-alexithymia individuals also reported lower ratings of positive emotions, greater confusion, and differences in thoughts related to evaluating and regulating their affective state. In Study Two, investigation of cardiovascular and emotional reactivity was extended beyond the laboratory to the blood donation clinic, which also provided a unique opportunity to evaluate the association between alexithymia and self-report of vasovagal symptoms. Alexithymia was positively associated with reported anxiety, pain, and vasovagal symptoms, and also with greater increases in systolic blood pressure in anticipation of blood donation. Objective indices of vasovagal reactions did not concur with self-report, suggesting an increased tendency in individuals higher in alexithymia to report more somatic complaints. In sum, while these data provide support for associations between alexithymia and differences in autonomic reactivity, these associations do not all fit neatly within a hypo- or hyperarousal model. Further research is recommended using methods such as ambulatory monitoring to examine response to more naturally occurring emotional events. Continued investigation of illness behaviours such as symptom reporting as they relate to alexithymia is also warranted.</description><creator>Byrne, Nelson J.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Alexithymia.</subject><title>Exploring the relationship between alexithymia and illness : individual differences in physiological reactivity and symptom reporting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Nelson J. Byrne, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r749w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fs96d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fd47j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation builds on two recent developments in attitude research, first the distinction made between two types of attitudes, i.e., explicit (deliberate, controlled) and implicit (unconscious, automatic) attitudes, and second, that made between two types of attitude conflicts, i.e., ambivalence (conflict between strong explicit positive and negative evaluative basis of the same attitude object) and duality (conflict between explicit and implicit attitudes). It uses the context of food for both its theoretical and empirical developments because there were reasons to expect that, in Western cultures, explicit attitudes are often ambivalent (i.e. positive on taste but negative on health dimensions), but might also be dual (e.g. for restrained eaters, resulting from the motivated overriding of positive attitudes toward tempting but forbidden food). A first study (N = 199) focuses on the differences between ambivalent and dual attitudes and the influence of these conflicts on spontaneous and deliberate behavior. Results demonstrate that holding dual and ambivalent attitudes are two different constructs, although both ambivalence and duality lead to a subjective experience of conflict. Also, attitudes are weaker when ambivalent (i.e. less accessible, less stable and held with less certainty), and duality is a moderator at high levels of ambivalence, with explicit attitudes being even less accessible but nonetheless more certain when dual. Finally, the influence of, on one hand, both implicit and explicit attitudes in driving spontaneous choice and, on the other hand, the explicit attitude in determining deliberate choice (behavioral intention as proxy) is corroborated. It also appears that the influence of the implicit attitude on spontaneous behavior is increased in presence of an attitude conflict. In a second study (N = 120), the hypothesis that the existence of dual attitudes stems from inhibitive processes is tested in the context of restrained eating, through a cognitive load manipulation. Results demonstrate that the influence of the implicit attitude on spontaneous choice is stronger for restrained eaters when cognitive capacities are impaired. The second study also highlights that implicit attitudes are stable and resistant to change despite direct experience manipulations (i.e. comparative and repeated tasting). Theoretical, methodological and practical contributions are discussed.</description><creator>Cervellon, Marie-Cécile.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Ambivalence.</subject><subject>Conflict (Psychology)</subject><subject>Attitude (Psychology)</subject><subject>Decision making.</subject><title>Ambivalent and dual attitudes : attitude conflicts and their impact on decision making and behavior</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Marie-Cécile Cervellon, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s9040.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fd47j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bn68g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two research problems involving the class of discrete-time signals bounded in magnitude are addressed in this thesis. The first problem concerns robust stability of systems with repeated, structured, linear time-varying, and induced-ℓinfinity-norm bounded perturbations. The second problem consists in the design of an ℓ₁-optimal controller that allows for flexible management of the tradeoff between the ability of a system to attenuate disturbance signals versus its expected worst peak-to-peak amplification. Original solutions to both problems are provided and their efficiency is assessed with examples and applications.</description><creator>Cadotte, Patrick.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Robust bounded-input bounded-output stability of systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Patrick Cadotte, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k2311.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bn68g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xk02b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Al-Jazeera asserted itself in the global media scene shortly after the attacks of September 11th, 2001 in the United States. The station's regional prominence had already been entrenched in the new Arab media environment before it was overshadowed by the station's newfound global fame. Subsequently, al-Jazeera was considered an Arab media ambassador and the "voice of the Arab world." This dissertation provides an analysis of al-Jazeera's programming in Arabic that is lacking in the burgeoning English language academic literature. The dissertation furthermore highlights the way treatment of global current affairs informs a sense of Arab identification on a regional level. Moreover, it argues that, apart from competitive broadcast journalists, al-Jazeera offers an oppositional discourse of identification that does not necessarily challenge the hegemony of Western media discourses. By employing an oppositional stance expressed in typical anti-colonialist and anti-imperialist terms, it constructs an overarching notion of "Arabness" that is predominately discursive. The dissertation analyzes three live talk shows: al-Ittijah al-Mu'akis (The Opposite Direction), Bila Hudoud (Without Boundaries), and Li-Nisa' Faqat (For Women Only). These talk shows are ideal sites for examining this oppositional discourse because they constitute important forums in which perceptions of identity are cultivated in the discussion of current affairs. In my analysis, each episode is treated as a media "text" that contributes to the formation of a discourse of "Arabness." The objective of the analysis is to identify the recurrent discursive patterns and strategies in providing the basis for this discursive category of identification across Arab state borders. In constructing an oppositional discourse, the United States and Israel are employed as necessary rhetorical references; Islam is infused into "Arabness" as a homogenizing constituent in identity formation; and finally, a culturally-threatened "Arabness" converges upon a context in which the world is marked by globalization. The dissertation concludes by indicating that al-Jazeera offers merely a representation of "Arabness" that, despite its power to influence, remains one way of perceiving Arab identity.</description><creator>Awwad, Julian M.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Arabs in mass media.</subject><subject>Al Jazeera (Television network)</subject><subject>Television talk shows -- Arab countries.</subject><title>Al-Jazeera's discourse of 'Arabness' : an examination of the discursive construction of identity in talk show programming</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Julian M. Awwad, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860c12g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xk02b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042z383</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis consists of four essays. The first essay looks at pollution taxation under capital mobility, and analyzes the role of pre-commitment by countries to their pollution tax rate. A polluting firm sells its product in two countries, and can locate and produce in a single country or in both countries. Due to the discrete-choice nature of the firm's location problem, the countries' welfare functions are discontinuous in their pollution tax rate. We show that when the countries cannot pre-commit to their pollution tax, the firm can still engender tax competition between them by strategically locating in both the countries. Moreover, pre-commitment pollution taxation may not be welfare improving for the countries, although it always makes the firm better off. The second essay studies the effect of liberalization on corruption. Corruptible inspectors enforce an environmental regulation on firms, and are monitored by an honest regulator. Liberalization not only increases the variety of goods and the marginal utility of accepting a bribe, but also puts pressure on the regulator to curb corruption. The interaction of these two effects can cause corruption to initially increase with liberalization, and then decrease beyond a threshold. Moreover, equilibrium corruption is lower when the regulator is able to pre-commit to her monitoring frequency. The third essay analyzes optimal labeling (information revelation) procedures for hidden attributes of credence goods. Consumers are heterogeneous in their preference for the hidden attribute, and producers can either self-label their products, or have them certified by a third party. The government can impose self or third-party labeling requirements on either the "green" or the "brown" producers. When corrupt producers can affix spurious labels, the government needs to monitor them. A mandatory self-labeling policy is shown to generally dominate mandatory third-party labeling. The fourth essay develops formulas for computing the economy-wide energy intensity decline rate by aggregating sectoral energy efficiency improvements, and sectoral shifts in economic activities. The formulas are used to (i) construct plausible scenarios for the global rate of energy intensity decline, and (ii) show the restraining role of the "electricity generation" sector on the energy intensity decline rate.</description><creator>Baksi, Soham.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Labels.</subject><subject>Free trade.</subject><subject>Energy consumption.</subject><subject>Corruption.</subject><subject>Pollution -- Taxation.</subject><title>Essays on environmental policies, corruption, and energy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Soham Baksi, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sf88m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042z383</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956m197</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Computational and experimental investigations of fluid flow and heat transfer aspects of loop heat pipes (LHPs) are presented in this thesis. The overall goal is to formulate and develop cost-effective mathematical models and numerical solution methods for computer simulations of LHPs. This work has five distinct parts. First, a basic network thermofluid model of conventional LHPs operating under steady-state conditions is proposed, implemented, tested, and applied. It illustrates the main steps in the formulation of such models. The capabilities of this basic model are assessed by applying it to an LHP for which experimental results are available in the literature. The results show that this model is capable of at least qualitatively accurate predictions and could serve as a tool in preliminary designs of LHPs. Second, experimental apparatus and procedures are designed and implemented for measurements of the following properties of sintered powder-metal porous plates that are used as wicks in LHPs: Porosity; maximum effective pore size; effective permeability; and effective thermal conductivity when saturated with a liquid (distilled water in this work). The aforementioned experimental apparatus and procedures are applied to two sintered powder-metal porous plates, one made of nickel 200 and the other of stainless steel 316, and the results are presented and discussed. Third, an LHP with a flat (plate-type) evaporator and a fixed active mass of the working fluid (distilled water) is designed and constructed, and an experimental investigation of its steady-state operation is conducted. Full details of this LHP and the experimental setup and procedures are presented. The experimental results augment the available repertoire of experimental data on LHPs. They are used to test the predictions of the proposed network thermofluid model. Fourth, an enhanced version of the aforementioned basic network thermofluid model is proposed and adapted for computer simulations of the above-mentioned LHP operating under steady-state conditions. Fifth, results of experimental and computational investigations of the abovementioned LHP, operating with a stainless steel 316 wick and distilled water as the working fluid, are presented, compared, and discussed. The proposed network thermofluid model provides predictions that are within +/-10% of the experimental results.</description><creator>Atabaki, Nima.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Experimental and computational studies of loop heat pipes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nima Atabaki, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b2937.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956m197</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021k40n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During development of the mammalian cerebral cortex, precursor cells in the ventricular zone sequentially produce neurons and glial cells. This process clearly involves a complex interplay between intrinsic cellular machinery and extrinsic cues. Remarkably, embryonic cortical precursor cells isolated at the onset of neurogenesis, and cultured under serum-free conditions, will mimic the temporal differentiation pattern observed in vivo, producing neurons first, and then glia. In the studies presented here, I have used this system to identify critical components of the intracellular machinery that co-ordinately control two essential steps in neuronal differentiation, exit from the cell cycle (via the retinoblastoma family) and induction of neuronal gene expression (via the basic helix-loop-helix transcription factors). I then demonstrate that endogenously produced neurotrophins are crucial autocrine/paracrine extracellular factors that regulate the precursor-to-neuron transition by promoting precursor survival (through the PI3-kinase-Akt signaling pathway) and neuronal differentiation (through the MEK-ERK pathway). Finally, I identify the nature of the "cortical timer mechanism" for sequential generation of neurons and glial cells: increasing levels of cytokines are produced by newly born neurons, which act to instruct the remaining precursors to produce glial cells. This neuron-based feedback mechanism was verified by using in utero electroporation to alter levels of cytokine signaling components within the developing cortex, and by analysing mice deficient for the cytokine cardiotrophin-1, which in both cases impaired the onset of gliogenesis. Taken together, our findings have led to a better molecular understanding of cortical precursor biology and cortex development, which could ultimately lead to the design of novel therapeutic strategies for neurodegenerative disorders.</description><creator>Barnabé-Heider, Fanie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Molecular mechanisms regulating cortical precursor differentiation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Fanie Barnabé-Heider, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h591p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021k40n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xk03m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Apoptosis is executed by caspase-mediated cleavage of various proteins. Elucidating the consequence of substrate cleavage provides us with insight into cell death and other biological processes. In this study, we applied the diagonal gel approach, a proteomic strategy, to identify substrates of the inflammatory caspase, caspase-1 and the cell death executioner caspase, caspase-3. Our results showed significant overlap between the substrates cleaved by both caspase-1 and -3. Such substrates are implicated in common cellular functions, including maintenance of the cytoskeleton, folding of proteins, translation, glycolysis, bioenergetics, signaling and trafficking. An important finding is that many glycolysis enzymes were targeted specifically by caspase-1. Processing of these glycolysis enzymes by caspase-1 was confirmed by cleaving in vitro transcribed and translated substrates with recombinant caspase-1. We have focused our further analysis on certain glycolysis enzymes. We have characterized the caspase-1 cleavage site in GAPDH. Point mutation of the Aspartic acid at position 189 to Alanine (D189A) in GAPDH blocked its cleavage by caspase-1. In vivo, in a mice model of septic shock, characterized by hyperactivation of caspase-1, we observed depletion of the full-length forms of these glycolysis enzymes in the diaphragm muscle. Further studies in caspase-1 deficient mice will confirm whether this depletion, in caspase-1 proficient mice, was due to caspase-1 processing of the glycolysis enzymes. This provides a direct link between caspase-1 activation and inhibition of glycolysis, which might have important implications on loss of muscle contractility in septic shock.</description><creator>Shao, Wei, 1970-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Apoptosis.</subject><subject>Glycolysis.</subject><subject>Caspase 1.</subject><subject>Caspase 3.</subject><title>Identification of caspase-1 and caspase-3 substrates and study on caspase-1 substrates in glycolytic pathway</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Wei Shao, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526h448.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xk03m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848v60g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since vitamin D deficiency is common at birth, the objective of this study was to test if postnatal vitamin D supplementation would normalize bone mineralization. Forty guinea pigs were randomized to receive a diet with or without vitamin D3 during pregnancy. Newborn pups were randomized to receive 10 IU of vitamin D3 or a placebo daily until d28. Measurements at birth and d28 included whole body and regional bone mass, osteocalcin and deoxypyridinoline, plus biomechanical testing of excised tibias and femurs. Offspring from deficient sows had lower body weight, whole body and tibia bone mineral content (BMC) and lower osteocalcin and biomechanical integrity. By d28 this group had lower whole body bone density and femur BMC, unless supplemented. Interactions with gender showed males continued to have low 25(OH)D despite supplementation. Therefore, neonates born to sows with dietary vitamin D deficiency require supplemental vitamin D to support normal bone mineral accretion.</description><creator>Finch, Sarah L.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Vitamin D deficiency -- Treatment.</subject><subject>Vitamin D -- Therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Guinea pigs.</subject><subject>Vitamin D deficiency -- Complications.</subject><subject>Bones -- Growth.</subject><title>Postnatal vitamin D supplementation normalizes neonatal bone mass following maternal dietary vitamin D deficiency in the guinea pig</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sarah L. Finch, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nd21x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v60g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bq74g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Roughly speaking, a group G is omnipotent if orders of finitely many elements can be controlled independently in some finite quotients of G. We proved that pi1(S) is omnipotent when S is a surface other than P2,T2 or K2 . This generalizes the fact, previously known, that free groups are omnipotent. The proofs primarily utilize geometric techniques involving graphs of spaces with the aim of retracting certain spaces onto graphs.</description><description>Approximativement, on peut dire qu'un groupe G est omnipotent si les ordresquantité d'élements d'une quantite finie d'elements peuvent etre controles independamment dans unquotient fini de Nous avons prouve que 7Ti(5) est omnipotent quand S estune surface autre que P2, T2 ou K2. Cela generalise le fait, deja connu, que lesgroupes libres sont omnipotents. La preuve utilise principalement des techniquesgeometriques impliquant des graphiques d'espaces ayant pour but de retractercertains espaces en graphiques.</description><creator>Bajpai, Jitendra.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Free groups.</subject><subject>Group theory.</subject><title>Omnipotence of surface groups</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jitendra Bajpai, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569846z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bq74g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>