<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:25:28Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34100" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w867</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our brain is involved in processing pain, whether it is superficial cutaneous pain, caused by a scratch or a burn, or deep internal pain, caused by heartburn or gas in the intestines. Moreover, activation of a common cortical network is suggested during different types of pain in humans, implying that as long as the stimulus is painful it will be processed similarly in the cerebral cortex. However, no one has yet made direct comparison between superficial and deep pain of similar intensity and location; direct comparison is necessary in order to see how superficial pain relates to a more clinically relevant deep pain and to further our understanding of the latter. In three separate studies, the perception of visceral and cutaneous pain in humans was examined using psychophysical, brain imaging and pharmacological approaches, respectively. The first study revealed that for a similar given intensity, duration and location, visceral pain is more unpleasant, more varied qualitatively, more diffuse and more persistent after stimulation has ended, suggesting that there are some significant distinctions in the neural processes of external and internal pain in humans. The second study examined such processes with functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI), disclosing substantial differences in cortical processing of sensory information from skin and viscera, including limbic areas associated with the emotional component of pain (anterior cingulate and insular cortices), and sensory areas (primary somatosensory cortex). In addition, several similar cortical areas were activated by both superficial and deep pain, consistent with the existence of a common pain network independent of the nature of pain. The final study examined a possible divergence in pharmacological processes underlying deep and superficial pain, which could arise from differences in neuronal processing. The findings revealed that NMDA-receptors mediate both visceral and cutaneous pain in humans, yet the affect of visceral pain might be more susceptible to their blockers, which may be a potential explanation for different treatments of visceral and cutaneous pains. Together these studies provide direct evidence of the differences and similarities between visceral and cutaneous pain in humans within the perceptual, physiological and pharmacological domains.</description><creator>Strigo, Irina A.</creator><contributor>Bushnell, M. Catherine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Visceral and cutaneous pain : neural correlates and pharmacological intervention</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv353.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w867</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r517</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Searching for information pervades a wide spectrum of human activity, including learning and problem solving. With recent changes in the amount of information available and the variety of means of retrieval, there is even more need to understand why some searchers are more successful than others. This study was undertaken to advance our understanding of expertise in seeking information on the Web by identifying strategies and attributes that will increase the chance of a successful search on the Web. A model that illustrated the relationship between strategies and attributes and a successful search was also created. The strategies were: Evaluation, Navigation, Affect, Metacognition, Cognition, and Prior knowledge. Attributes included Age, Sex, Years of experience, Computer knowledge, and Info-seeking knowledge. Success was defined as finding a target topic within 30 minutes. Participants were from three groups. Novices were 10 undergraduate pre-service teachers who were trained in pedagogy but not specifically in information seeking. Intermediates were nine final-year master's students who had received training on how to search but typically had not put heir knowledge into extensive practice. Experts were 10 highly experienced professional librarians working in a variety of settings including government, industry, and university. Participants' verbal protocols were transcribed verbatim into a text file and coded. These codes, along with Internet temporary files, a background questionnaire, and a post-task interview were the sources of the data. Since the variable of interest was the time to finding the topic, in addition to ANOVA and Pearson correlation, survival analysis was used to explore the data. The most significant differences in patterns of search between novices and experts were found in the Cognitive, Metacognitive, and Prior Knowledge strategies. Based on the fitted survival model, Typing Keyword, Criteria to evaluate sites, and Information-Seeking Kno</description><creator>Tabatabai, Diana</creator><contributor>Shore, Bruce M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>World Wide Web</subject><subject>Problem solving</subject><subject>Information storage and retrieval systems</subject><title>Modeling information-seeking expertise on the Web</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp44b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r517</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj735</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the last twenty years, the People's Republic of China has exhibited behaviour consistent with that of a great power attempting to elevate itself to a global power, with monumental effects on the evolving international order. Unlike rising global powers of the past, China faces two powerful constraints, which have prevented the country from taking the traditional paths of territorial expansion and political-economic domination in order to develop as a global power. The first obstacle has been the presence of the United States, which became the world's only superpower after the cold war. The second is the existence of nuclear weapons, which has made direct great-power conflict unacceptably costly. Faced with these barriers, China has chosen a more distinctive path to greater power acquisition via a post-cold war international system containing more institutions than ever before. The main argument of this thesis is that China's opening to international institutions has developed into a key component, more than that of previous rising global powers, in that country's multilateral approach to foreign policy and to the advancement of state power. This method of power acquisition is in opposition to traditional realist theories, which have not recognised such cooperation as being crucial to global power development. Within the analyses of this thesis, four case studies of international institutions with which China aligned itself will be assessed using six "goods" which Beijing has been determined to pursue through these institutions (state security, regime security, information acquisition, economic benefits, an improved position vis-a-vis other great powers, and prestige). Two cases are primarily economic institutions, the World Trade Organisation and two "exclusive economic regimes", the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation Forum (APEC) and the newer, more informal "ASEAN-plus-three" (AP3) grouping. The other two cases, primarily strategic organisations, are the ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF) and the embryonic Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO). These case studies illustrate the growing importance which China has placed on international institutions as a means of developing a more effective foreign policy, while simultaneously protecting valuable domestic interests, all in the name of reaching for global power status.</description><creator>Lanteigne, Marc</creator><contributor>Paul, T. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>International agencies</subject><subject>China -- Foreign relations -- 1976-</subject><title>Doorways and mirrors : Chinese power and international institutions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw27j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj735</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m8276</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the central problems of molecular electronics is to understand electron conduction properties when a functional molecule is interfaced with external electrodes and put under external bias and gate potentials. These properties are influenced by the molecule-electrode interaction as well as by the structure of the functional region of the device. In this thesis, we investigate from first-principles the transport properties of a number of molecular-scale systems, and try to relate the observed features to both the atomic and electronic structure. We start with a detailed analysis of transport through carbon atomic wires, and find that the equilibrium conductance is sensitive to charge transfer doping, and that the I-V characteristics exhibit negative differential resistance at high bias due to a shift of conduction channels relative to the states of the electrodes. Using a Sc3N C80 metallofullerene device, we address several general questions about quantum transport through molecular systems and provide strong evidence that transport in such molecular devices is mediated by molecular electronic states which have been renormalized by the device environment. The possibility of inducing nuclear dynamics in single-molecule Au-C 60-Au transistors via inelastic, resonance-mediated tunneling current is examined using a method based on the combination of a theory of current-triggered dynamics[1] and our nonequilibrium Green's function approach of computing electron transport properties. We investigate several single molecule field-effect transistors consisting of conjugated molecules in contact with metallic electrodes. The source-drain current is found to be sensitive to the external gate potential and the molecular structure; with modulations of the current as large as several thousand fold. Given a proposed operation principle, we obtain quantitative results on the rectification properties for an organic molecule rectifying diode. The I-V characteristic shows clear rectification behavior, and is explained from the simple picture of shifting of molecular levels due to substituents and an externally applied bias voltage. Finally, we report a formulation combining density functional theory with the Keldysh nonequilibrium Green's function, for calculating quantum mechanical forces under external bias and during electron transport. We present an example force calculation consisting of a single atom point contact.</description><creator>Larade, Brian</creator><contributor>Guo, Hong (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Theory of molecular electronics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng28r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m8276</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c466</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transparency is used routinely as part of a host of visualisation functionalities in software applications for image-guided procedures, though little research is devoted to the rigorous validation of the use of transparency in clinical visualisation. This thesis presents three psychophysical studies aiming to understand how the human visual system interacts with transparent stimuli. The first sets out to measure the performance of users in a 3-D manual segmentation task. Visualising the stimuli in stereo improved performance, though no effect of transparent surface rendering was revealed. In addition, subjects performed better using a standard 2-D mouse compared to a 3-D tracking device. The next two studies explore the intensity and figural conditions for perceptual transparency using a novel six-luminance stimulus. While a number of models of intensity conditions have been previously proposed, it was found that the luminance-based formulation of Metelli's episcotister model, and a model based on ratios of Michelson contrasts best predicted the subjects' settings, which were found to be very precise. The results also showed that there exists a reasonably wide range of stimuli that give rise to at least some degree of perceived transparency. It was demonstrated that the relative arrangement of the colours around contour crossings (X-junctions) was a salient feature indicating to the visual system the plausibility of a transparent filter and the depth ordering of layers. In addition, the occlusion of X-junctions and perturbation of the orientation of a transparent filter's contours at the junction gave rise to reductions in performance, indicating the importance of junctions in transparency perception.</description><creator>Kasrai, Reza</creator><contributor>Peters, T. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kingdom, F. A. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>On the perception of transparency : psychophysics and applications to medical image visualisation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602247f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c466</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s639g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In early 1505, at twenty-nine years of age, Michelangelo began work on a massive tomb for Pope Julius II. The formal, temporal, and constructional intertwinings of this project are plumbed to create the foundation of this text. Finding its only full manifestation in the narratives of Vasari and Condivi, this tomb was the site of Michelangelo's first engagement with the making of architecture. The execution of this project would go on to intermittently occupy nearly half of Michelangelo's lifetime, making it a pivotal and paradigmatic work in the understanding of his opera. Explored as an embodied architectural treatise, the tomb reveals Michelangelo's dynamic process of creative making. Problematic issues in the prevailing Twentieth Century analyses and reconstructions of the tomb are called into question and alternative approaches to establish a deeper understanding of the project are proposed. Conjectures on the relevance of history, the hegemony and limits of analysis, the physical manifestation of ideas, what it means to "finish" a project, and what constitutes a "work," are projected from the foundations of the tomb onto the making of architecture today.</description><creator>Kelly, Robert Louis</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Michelangelo Buonarroti, 1475-1564 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Mausoleo di Giulio II (Rome, Italy)</subject><subject>Julius II, Pope, 1443-1513 -- Tomb</subject><subject>Sepulchral monuments, Renaissance -- Italy -- Rome.</subject><title>In search of Michelangelo's tomb for Julius II : reconstructing that for which no fixed rule may be given</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397982k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s639g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vv87r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the course of the twentieth century, art became increasingly dominated by market forces. Private corporations and public administrations, including cities, used art as a development tool. In the post-industrial era, art was assimilated to a cultural industry and those whom we label "black collars" succeeded to the blue collar workers of the industrial era and to the white collar workers of the modern city. In the late 1960s, public sculpture spread in the urban landscape. In the same period, a new generation of artists was trying to create ecological works of art, forms that are associated with post-modernism in art. But there were few works of art that were linked to nature, when compared with the quantity of sculptures exhibited in the plazas of skyscrapers. Why? To answer this question, this research uses the sociology of art as a methodology, particularly the methodology developed by Pierre Bourdieu. The thesis presents the case of Montreal, and compares it to that of New York City. It includes case studies of Viger Square and of the Canadian Centre for Architecture (CCA) Garden, two public spaces designed by Montreal artists. We examine the factors that contributed to the predominance of a specific art form, the sculpture in a plaza, and to the rarity of the garden: the characteristics of the genre (garden versus sculpture); the relationships between the main actors; the art market and the manipulation of demand; the various policies associated with art/culture and with urban development; the interests of patrons (be they public or private). All these factors had an influence on the art forms in the city, often labelled "public art" or "art integrated with architecture." The study reveals that the post-modern economy exhibited works of art that are seldom associated with post-modernism in art. The model of the sculpture in a plaza did not dominate the modernist urban development, but it reflects more a post-modernist morphology.</description><creator>Boyce, Margaret</creator><contributor>Fischler, Raphael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Goulet, Michel, 1944-</subject><subject>Charney, Melvin.</subject><subject>Public art -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Théberge, Claude, 1934-</subject><subject>Daudelin, Charles, 1920-</subject><subject>Gnass, Peter, 1936-</subject><subject>Vazan, Bill, 1933-</subject><title>Visual art / public art and urban development : a case study of Montreal (1967-1992)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg52x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv87r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Urban Planning</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj74f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Based on a joint process of analysis and translation, this research explores the challenges of translating into French a novel by Samuel Selvon titled The Lonely Londoners (1956), one of the first and few English Caribbeans novels entirely composed in a vernacular style and sold to an international English-speaking audience. Using a Bourdieusian methodology of praxis, the thesis analyses the interaction between the various levels of decision-making and the linguistic, political and aesthetic factors that interfere with the translation process, from the interpretation of the text to its rephrasing. It consists of six chapters that, from the second to the fifth, trace the stages of the translation process. Through a review of the critical reception of Selvon's novel, the second chapter examines the stakes of translating The Lonely Londoners from a theoretical perspective. Via a close reading of the text, the third delves into some of the interpretative suggestions made by recent critics. In a discussion leading to the layout of a translation project, the fourth explores the relation between the linguistic and cultural constituents interacting in Selvon's text and those that are likely to play a role in translation. Commenting on some of the translation strategies chosen, the fifth presents part of the formal realization of this project. The opening and closing chapters enlarge the framework by inscribing the object in a wider perspective. While the first chapter offers a panorama of the place of English Caribbean fiction in French translation, the final chapter reflects on the translation process undertaken in order to address more political/ethical issues. In the final analysis, the author concludes that for linguistic and political reasons as much as aesthetic ones, it is necessary to refocus the ongoing debate on the ethics and politics of translation, a debate traditionally dealt with in terms of particular translation strategies, on the interpretative process</description><creator>Buzelin, Hélène</creator><contributor>Mercier, Gillian Lane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Selvon, Samuel -- Translations into French -- History and criticism</subject><subject>Translating and interpreting</subject><title>Sur le terrain de la traduction</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k6808.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj74f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt679</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of swimming was investigated in zebrafish aged 1.5 to 5 days postfertilization by examining both the swimming behavior and its generation by the nervous system. Upon hatching (at day 2), swimming is undirected and occurs in sustained bursts of high frequency (mean = 67 Hz) tail undulations. By 4 days, the swimming pattern matures to a more directed, less erratic, beat-and-glide pattern where slower (mean = 35 Hz) tail undulations, lasting ~200 ms, alternate with longer gliding rest periods. Swimming is powered by two classes of embryonic muscles (embryonic red, ER and white, EW) that are electrically coupled within (but not between) classes and have physiological properties similar to vertebrate tonic and twitch muscle, respectively. ER fibers have a lower chloride ion permeability than EW fibers and do not have sodium dependent action potentials. In paralyzed preparations, motoneurons and muscle fibers received coordinated excitatory synaptic activity (with left to right alternation and head to tail propagation) corresponding to either burst or beat-and-glide swimming. ER muscle was de-recruited at the fastest swimming rates and EW fibers dropped out at the slowest swimming rates. Rhythmic motoneuron output was generated by a phasic glutamatergic and a largely tonic glycinergic synaptic drive. Glutamatergic synapses had either or both AMPA/kainate and NMDA receptors and the kinetics of these synaptic currents were fixed throughout the developmental period examined. When depolarized, motoneurons fired high frequency (up to 800 Hz) bursts of action potentials that rapidly accommodated (within ~20 ms) due to voltage and calcium dependent outwardly rectifying conductances. These intrinsic motoneuron properties are hypothesized to interact with the rhythmic synaptic drive to pattern motor output (at ~25--75 Hz) to locomotor muscles. The neural generation of swimming in developing zebrafish is thus fundamentally similar to locomotion in adu</description><creator>Buss, Robert R.</creator><contributor>Drapeau, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Zebra danio -- Nervous system</subject><subject>Zebra danio -- Locomotion</subject><subject>Zebra danio -- Development</subject><title>Development of the zebrafish motor unit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n025p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt679</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237ht41x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The experiments in this thesis examined the roles of stimulus configuration on conditioned cue preference (CCP) learning by asking what information is processed and by which neural substrates. Results from Experiments 1 and 2 showed that lesions of the lateral nucleus of the amygdala (LNA) but not of fimbria-fornix (FF) impaired CCP learning when the cues paired with food during training were distinct from those not paired with food in either of two different apparatuses. In Experiments 3 and 4 LNA lesions increased the size of the CCP when the cues paired with food and no food were ambiguous in two different apparatuses. Learning the ambiguous cue CCP required at least one session of unreinforced pre-exposure to the cues and was eliminated by FF lesions. In the last series of experiments, a latent learning effect of unreinforced pre-exposure on ambiguous cue CCP learning on the radial maze was found in normal animals that received at least 3 sessions of unreinforced pre-exposure. FF lesions made before, but not after, pre-exposure eliminated the latent learning effect. Hippocampus lesions made either before or after pre-exposure eliminated the CCP learning. Taken together, the results are consistent with the hypothesis that distinct cue CCP learning is based on conditioned approach responses to cues paired with food, mediated by a neural system that includes the LNA. The results also suggest that ambiguous cue CCP learning takes place in two phases. First spatial learning occurs during unreinforced pre-exposure, a process that requires an intact FF. Subsequently, information about the location of the reinforcer is added to the spatial information during the reinforced training trials by a process of "reconsolidation". An intact hippocampus is required for this process. The implications of these results and interpretations for latent learning and latent inhibition are considered.</description><creator>Chai, Sin-Chee, 1969-</creator><contributor>White, Norman W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Hippocampus (Brain)</subject><subject>Classical conditioning</subject><subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects</subject><subject>Amygdaloid body</subject><title>The functions of amygdala and hippocampus in conditioned cue preference learning /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0968700.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht41x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sv37n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We identified two large French-Canadian (FC) pedigrees with idiopathic partial epilepsy. Family studies of over 500 members from these two families revealed over 63 individuals reported to have seizures or seizure-like histories. Pedigree analysis confirmed an autosomal dominant inheritance with reduced penetrance. Most of the affected individuals shared a number of clinical characteristics compatible with the definition of a novel genetic form of epilepsy syndrome. We termed it as familial partial epilepsy with variable foci (FPEVF), which was recently described by Scheffer et al. (1998) in one Australian family with eight possibly affected individuals. The most prominent clinical feature of FPEVF is the presence of variable seizure foci in different affected individuals within the same family. Most affected individuals in the two FC families present infrequent, brief, non-clustering, nocturnal, partial seizures. Age of onset is between 5 and 25 years. Affected individuals are neurologically intact without any detectable pathological lesion(s). These two families were then subjected to a full-scale molecular genetic study. No linkage to any known loci for idiopathic partial epilepsy was detected, including the suggested chromosome (Chr) 2q locus for FPEVF in the Australian FPEVF family, the Chr 20q13.2 and 15q24 loci for autosomal dominant nocturnal frontal lobe epilepsy (ADNFLE) and the Chr 10q locus for autosomal dominant temporal lobe epilepsy with auditory symptoms (ADTLEAS). Significant linkage (LOD score = 8.60) was detected with markers on Chr 22 q12 during a genome scan. Collaborating with a group from Australia, we confirmed another two FC families and two non-FC families with compatible linkage to the same locus and a cumulative LOD score of 14.79 with marker D22S689. The minimum candidate region of FPEVF has been finally defined to an interval of 3.8 cM between markers D22S 1163 and D22S 1686 on Chr 22q12. We proceeded to search for the gene mutation by directly sequencing the coding regions of all candidate genes within the FPEVF region, an interval of 5.04 Mb harboring approximately 100 known or predicted genes. So far, 77 candidate genes have been sequenced, and no mutation has yet been found. Since there is no known ion channel gene mapped to this region, FPEVF is probably the first non-ion channel gene causing human idiopathic epilepsy*. *After submission of this thesis for examination, Kalachikov et al. (2002) identified LGI1 (leucine-rich gene, glioma inactivated), a possible tumor suppressor, as the gene for ADTLEAS. This is the first evidence for a non-ion channel gene causing idiopathic epilepsy in humans.</description><creator>Xiong, Lan, 1966-</creator><contributor>Andermann, Eva (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Pandolfo, Massimo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Identification, clinical characterization, and molecular genetic studies of familial partial epilepsy with variable foci</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c2200.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv37n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js82h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction. Preliminary studies found that discordance between the patients' and physicians' assessments of disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) exists. We investigated the factors associated with discordance and explored the impact of discordance on medication adherence and complementary/alternative medicine (CAM) use. Methods. Part I investigated the factors associated with discordance, defined as the patient visual analog scale (VAS) minus the physician VAS for global disease activity. Data were extracted from the Montreal General Hospital Lupus Registry. Potential covariates included the Medical Outcomes Studies SF-36, the Systemic Lupus Activity Measure (SLAM), and a lupus damage index. The first visit data were analyzed using multiple regression. Unbalanced repeated measures analysis of variance was used to analyze follow-up data and to investigate the influence of time. Part II used a patient questionnaire to measure adherence and CAM use, which was then linked to discordance data from the Registry. The associations between discordance and non-adherence and CAM use were tested using multivariable logistic regression. Non-linear relationships were tested by generalized additive models (GAM). Results. Clinically important discordance occurred in nearly 30% of the visits. The SF-36 scales for Bodily Pain and Vitality were important variables for predicting discordance. SLAM-Skin and -Musculoskeletal components were also associated with discordance. The mean discordance tended to increase over time. While both the patients' and physicians' VAS scores tended to decrease over time, the decrease was more pronounced in the physicians' VAS scores. Non-adherence and CAM use occurred in 32% and 55% of the subjects, respectively. Patients who scored much lower disease activity than their physicians were more likely to be non-adherent than concordant patients (odds ratio = 2.25, 95% confidence interval: 0.32, 15.96). GAM testing supported this finding. Odds ratios for discordance and use of CAM therapies ranged from 0.89 to 1.48 (all non-significant), and GAM showed a non-linear relationship represented by an inverted U-shaped curve. Conclusion. Patient-physician discordance exists in SLE. Factors such as bodily pain and fatigue increase discordance while clinically visible signs, such as skin manifestations, reduce discordance. Clinically important discordance appears to be associated with patient self-care behaviour, particularly, medication nonadherence.</description><creator>Yen, Jim C., 1967-</creator><contributor>Battista, Renaldo N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Patient-physician discordance in systemic lupus erythematosus and its impact on medication adherence and alternative medicine use</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r943t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js82h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s19b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>SHP-1, a SH2 domain-containing protein-tyrosine phosphatase, plays a critical role in regulation of cell signal transduction. SHP-1 is expressed not only in cells of hematopoietic lineages, but also in many non-hematopoietic cells under the control of a tissue-specific promoter, P1. In the first part of this thesis, the activity of the P1 promoter was analyzed in a region spanning 3.5 kb upstream of the major transcription start site in non-hematopoietic MCF-7 cells. An upstream Sp1 element (-126 to -118) positively regulated this TATA-box-lacking promoter. Two inverted CCAAT-elements (-332 to -328 and -66 to -62) played the important, but opposite roles, and transcription factor NF-Y predominantly bound to the two CCAAT-elements to control SHP-1 gene expression. Furthermore, incubation of MCF7 cells with 100 ng/ml trichostatin A (TSA), an inhibitor of histone deacetylase, significantly increased the activity of the P1 promoter. Mutation in the proximal CCAAT-element, however, eliminated the activating effect of trichostatin A on the promoter. In the second part of this thesis, the mechanism by which SHP-1 modulated TSA-induced MCF-7 cell apoptosis was elucidated. Analysis of cell survival signaling pathways revealed that overexpression of SHP-1 inactivated Akt ( eg. diminished phosphorylation resulted from modulation of PI3K expression) and increased caspase-9 and caspase-7 activities. Interestingly, a parallel decrease was observed in the phosphorylation of the pro-apoptosic Bcl-2 family member Bad at Ser112 as well as in the stress-activated MAP kinase JNK, both of which have been implicated in Akt- as well as ERK1/2-mediated functions. It was not surprising, therefore, to detect a diminished level of phosphorylated ERK1/2 in SHP-1-overexpressiog cells and that this effect was exacerbated by TSA treatment. Taken together, the data presented in this thesis suggest that SHP-1 expression is regulated by Sp1 and NF-Y factors, and SHP-1 sensitizes MCF-7 cells to TS</description><creator>Xu, Yan, 1958-</creator><contributor>Zhao, Xin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Genetic regulation.</subject><subject>Protein-tyrosine phosphatase.</subject><subject>Estrogen -- Receptors.</subject><subject>Apoptosis.</subject><title>Human protein tyrosine phosphatase SHP-1 : gene regulation and role in apoptosis in MCF-7 cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t91m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s19b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010r817</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The follicle stimulating hormone receptor (FSHR) is an essential G-protein-coupled receptor expressed in granulosa cells of the ovary and Sertoli cells of the testis. Upon hormone binding, the FSHR activates G-proteins, initiates gonadotropin signals and triggers granulosa cells and oocyte or Sertoli cells and germ cells communication that is required for gonadal development and maturation. This hormone signaling also participates in the biosynthesis of progesterone and estradiol in females and testosterone in males. The expression of FSHR reaches higher levels in mature follicles and in stages XIII-I of the seminiferous epithelial cycle. Little is known on the mechanisms by which cell- and stage-specific expression of FSHR is regulated. In the present studies, we have characterized four cis-elements in an ovine FSHR (oFSHR) promoter, and identified the corresponding DNA binding proteins. The first cis-element at +32 to +54 of the proximal oFSHR promoter was characterized as an E-box overlapping an orphan receptor response element (ORRE) to which upstream stimulatory factors (USFs) and chicken ovalbumin upstream promoter transcription factors (COUP-TFs) can compete for their binding. The second element was mapped at -46 to -67 as a CACC box that Krupple-like transcription factors recognize. The third cis-element at -117 to -197 was found to be a composite activator protein-1 (AP-1) binding site embedding an E-box and an ORRE that a group of proteins including AP-1, steroidogenic factor-1 (SF-1) and COUP-TFs can competitively occupy depending on their availability and activity. The fourth element from -284 to -303 was identified as a composite retinoic acid response element (RARE) that is recognized by retinoic acid receptors (RARs) and SF-1. Functional studies revealed that USFs, AP-1 and SF-1 were activators whereas COUP-TFs and RARs were repressors in the presence of retinoic acid (RA). Our data suggest a mechanism by which activators and repressors compete for</description><creator>Xing, Weirong, 1961-</creator><contributor>Sairam, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Identification and characterization of Cis elements of the ovine follicle stimulating hormone receptor promoter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z944m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010r817</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj75q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The growth of computer-mediated communication (CMC) has generated great interest among researchers. Although perspectives vary, the anonymity inherent in textual communication and the reduction of social markers are often described as the characteristics that distinguish CMC from other forms of communication. These arguments have resulted in unprecedented optimism regarding the potential of this technology to eliminate social inequalities and increase access to institutional power. While critics have provided substantial evidence to the contrary, especially in regards to gender inequalities, CMC continues to be promoted and accepted. Critical responses on the issue of gender have concentrated on behavioral issues. As exemplified by the work of Herring, these issues include, among others, the use of adversarial rhetorical strategies, topical control, representation in electronic communities, and the phenomenon known as "flaming". Surprisingly, no effort has been made to address the role of gender in the cognitive aspects of CMC or directly question the claims advanced by supporters of this technology in relation to the anonymity of electronic texts. With the exception of Herring's peripheral remarks on this issue and limited work on the problem of gender judgements by Savicki and his colleagues, research is non-existent. Given the importance of this area for the information professions, this research explores the role of gender in the cognitive processes associated with identification and impression formation. More specifically, this research addresses two concerns. The first is whether CMC users can identify the gender of those they have never met face-to-face by relying exclusively on the detection of gender cues. The second centers on the role of gender in the evaluation of electronic communicators. Against the perspectives outlined in the feminist critique of technology, this research's theoretical framework is derived from the work of Hymes as well as literature from cognate fields. Thus, Hymes' theoretical model on the concept of communicative competence, which allows competent speakers to pass judgement on the appropriateness of linguistic events, is central to the investigation. The results provide convincing evidence regarding the implications of gender in the cognitive dimension of CMC. Data from 133 research participants (91 females and 42 males) associated with the study of librarianship or its professional practice suggest that CMC simply recreates existing gender asymmetries. Women are less likely to remain anonymous, more likely to be described stereotypically, and more likely to be evaluated negatively.</description><creator>Sierpe, Eino.</creator><contributor>Mittermeyer, Diane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Communication -- Sex differences.</subject><subject>Computer networks -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Sociolinguistics.</subject><subject>Language and languages -- Sex differences.</subject><title>Gender and its relationship to perception in computer-mediated communication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg19g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj75q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate School of Library and Information Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171z82s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The motivation of the research presented in this thesis was to investigate the potential of using a commercial 2.3 kW heat pump dehumidifier (HPD) simultaneously as a dryer for high-moisture agricultural products and for other domestic dehumidification/heating applications. A drying system incorporating the HPD was designed and constructed, along with instrumentation to gather data on the properties of process air as well as real-time weight of the material being dried. The HPD was equipped with an external water-cooled condenser that rejected excess heat out of the system. The design of the system allowed for conducting drying with recirculation of air as well as use of electrical heaters. In an open mode, the drying could be carried out simultaneously with room dehumidification and water heating in the secondary condenser. The drying experiments were conducted with apple, tomato and agar gels. The system was found to be more effective in drying of material with higher amount of free moisture such as tomato. Comparisons were made between HPD assisted drying (partial and complete) and hot air drying (at 45°C and 65°C) in the same system using apple as the test material. Colour changes (L*a*b* values) in the samples were compared between treatments. It was observed that the degree of undesirable colour change was least in case of the HPD assisted system. The HPD dried fruit exhibited better rehydration properties than the hot air dried samples. Water activity of the HPD dried samples was noticeably lower than that of the hot air dried samples at the same water content, indicating that the residual moisture was probably held under higher tension. Histological observation indicated that there was a lesser degree of damage to the cellular structure of apple when dried with the HPD than when dried with hot air alone. In terms of energy consumption, the process of HPD assisted drying is more expensive. Much of the energy input is rejected at the secondary condenser as excess heat. Unless this heat is recovered for another purpose, or the system is modified to reuse it for drying, the drying process must carry this loss entirely. The specific moisture extraction rate (SMER) for apple was as low as 0.1 kg per kWh with the HPD assisted system. The SMER values for drying at 45°C was 0.5 kg per kWh and was almost 0.8 kg per kWh at 65°C. The HPD assisted drying system demonstrated the ability of heat pumps to link different energy related activities viz., drying, space dehumidification and water heating. The energy expenditure is expected to be impressive when considered for all the related applications. The concept of utilizing heat pumps on farms to link up different energy streams for better utilization of the low-grade heat sources is discussed. A possible drying efficiency assessment in the form of energy-based evaluation is proposed.</description><creator>Sosle, Venkatesh.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Food -- Drying -- Equipment and supplies.</subject><subject>Heat pumps.</subject><subject>Dried foods.</subject><title>A heat pump dehumidifier assisted dryer for agri-foods /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q313d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z82s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881n643</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A detailed analysis of the crystallization behaviour of poly(dimethylsiloxane) (PDMS) was undertaken. Determination of the equilibrium melting temperature showed a six degree difference between the equilibrium melting of a hydroxy terminated polymer (PDMS-OH, Tmo = 266 K, M w = 92.9 kg mol-1) over that of a trimethylsilyl terminated polymer (PDMS-CH3, Tmo = 260 K, Mw = 100 kg mol-1). The inherent flexibility of the Si-O linkage of these polymers caused crystallization to be first detected at Tmo - 35 K, and was recorded down to 177 K, i.e., Tg + 30 K. Both systems followed well behaved regime III surface nucleation kinetics. The average fold interfacial surface free energy, sigmae, was calculated to be 17.6 erg cm -2 and resulted in a very low value for the work of chain folding, q, calculated to be 14.6 kJ mol-1. This is in accord with the small rotational barrier of the siloxane backbone. In addition, PDMS-OH crystallized with slower kinetics than PDMS-CH3, verified by chemical conversion from the hydroxy to trimethylsilyl end group. The first reported detection of two different PDMS solid state morphologies is presented. A small population of very low birefringent (Deltan ) spherulites was observed to nucleate simultaneously with a majority of bright positive Deltan spherulites throughout the accessible crystallization temperature range. The sign of Deltan of these darker spherulites varied with growth, and this growth rate was depressed from that of the bright spherulites. Calorimetric annealing experiments indicate that the PDMS system attains very high percent crystallinities very early after nucleation. Coupled with the results of small angle laser light scattering (SALLS) during slow (1 deg/min) melting, secondary crystallization processes were observed to be non-negligible very soon after primary crystallization. SALLS of the crystallizing PDMS system was sensitive to the concurrent effects of (i) the presence of dark spherulites, (ii) secondary crystallization, and (iii) the distribution of spherulite sizes. These combined effects generated significant non-ideality within V v and Hv scattering envelopes. The effects of (i) and (ii) caused both the Vv pattern to remain circularly symmetric throughout the entire crystallization timeframe, and the 4-leaf clover pattern of the Hv mode scattering to contain multiple intensity maxima not restricted to an azimuthal angle of 45°. The effect of (iii) was to lower the calculated SALLS average radial growth rate relative to that observed optically.</description><creator>Singh, Shanti.</creator><contributor>Brown, G. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Lennox, R. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Studies of the crystallization and morphology of poly(dimethylsiloxane)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh12q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881n643</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236380r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Montreal, salsa dancing is both an expression of Latin identity and a cultural commodity. Many Montrealers of Latin descent adopt salsa dance as part of their cultural heritage only after arriving in Canada, connecting, through salsa, to a transnational Latin identity that crosses the Americas. This situation illustrates how cultural affiliations are not necessarily fixed, but can be acquired in response to changing circumstances. Since salsa is not indigenous to the city, residents of Montreal can only access it through cultural institutions and community media outlets. This commodification influences the manner in which salsa expresses Latin identity in the city. At the same time that salsa dancing proclaims Latin identity for certain individuals in the city, the practice thrives in a multicultural context: the Montreal salsa scene comprises diverse individuals who promote, teach, and dance salsa. This dissertation addresses points of division and cooperation among diverse cultures, ethnicities, races, and both sexes, as they are played out in aspects of salsa dancing in the city. The unfolding of these relationships is influenced by both the commodification of salsa dancing and its link to Latin culture. This analysis seeks to provide a theoretical account of the tension between salsa's expression of identity and its status as a commodified cultural practice. This perspective integrates various approaches to the study of dance and culture stemming from anthropology, sociology and cultural studies. Analyzing the Montreal salsa scene, I draw from in-depth interviews with individuals involved in the promotion of Latin dance and music, as well as participant observations in salsa dance classes, clubs and events. The methodology of this research combines ethnography with various areas of concern: the history of salsa, Latin immigration patterns in Montreal, theories of multiculturalism, transnationalism and diaspora, the Latin influence in ballroom dance, Europe</description><creator>Pietrobruno, Sheenagh</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Dance -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Sociological aspects</subject><subject>Popular music -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Salsa (Music) -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Salsa and its transnational moves : the commodification of latin dance in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td78f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236380r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732db62p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In spite of the growing interest of Russian and Western scholars in Sergei Dovlatov and his art, his place in Russian literature has not yet been clearly defined. His position as a writer in Russia in the 1960s and early 70s was ambiguous due to his opposition to the traditional Soviet canon and rejection by the current literary establishment. However, he later gained recognition and popularity as an emigre writer in the United States. The concept of 'marginality' colours his biography and art, for his life itself was a succession of marginal experiences and marginality is the key topic of his writings. Marginality unifies Dovlatov's art. This is evident in his marginal status as a writer in and outside the Soviet Union, and in his writing which uses the underappreciated short form of narration (the novella and short story), develops a non-traditional conversational style, pursues the themes of non-conventional behaviour and introduces eccentric characters. However, it is not possible to discuss Dovlatov's status as a marginal writer without contextualizing his life and art in the ambience of the entire generation of Leningrad writers of the sixties. Writers and poets such as Brodskii, Goliavkin, Gubin, Vakhtin and Ufliand do not only represent the culture of Leningrad's artistic non-conformists, they are also Dovlatov's prototypes and protagonists. Apart from their marginal status, all these writers shared the determination to make independent choices in life and in art. They refused to be viewed as marginal authors by the dominant canon, which disregarded their works as insignificant. Here as well marginality emerges as a literary concept and a behavioural model, shaped by societal norms (the positive type of citizen or official Soviet writer) and traditional canons (the Russian didactic tradition or Soviet ideological writing). This literary concept includes an orientation towards American literature, the creation of marginal characters and themes as well as an exploration of different styles. The works of writers of the Leningrad circle laid the foundation for the emergence of a literary phenomenon such as Dovlatov. It is in delineating this context that this dissertation demonstrates Dovlatov's original approach to marginality, as well as the way he turned his life experience into literature and became a spokesman for neglected fellow writers and citizens.</description><creator>Pakhomova, Natalia.</creator><contributor>Beraha, Laura (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Dovlatov, Sergeĭ -- Characters.</subject><subject>Russian literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Marginal voices : Sergei Dovlatov and his characters in the context of the Leningrad literature of the 1960s and 70s</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s6407.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732db62p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0968718</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The bipolar budding pattern of a/a Saccharomyces cerevisiae cells appears to depend on persistent spatial markers. Genetic analysis reported here indicates that BUD8 and BUD9 potentially encode components of the markers at the distal and proximal poles, respectively. Mutants deleted for BUD8 or BUD9 bud exclusively from the proximal and distal poles, respectively, and the double-mutant phenotype suggests that the bipolar budding pathway has been totally disabled. Moreover, overexpression of these genes can cause either an increased bias for budding at the distal (BUD8) or proximal (BUD9) pole or a randomization of bud position, depending on the level of expression. Both molecules are related plasma membrane glycoproteins that are both N- and O-glycosylated. Each protein was localized predominantly in the expected location, with Bud8p delivered to the presumptive bud site just before bud emergence, and Bud9p delivered to the bud side of the mother-bud neck just before cytokinesisis. Promoter-swap experiments revealed the importance of time of transcription in localization: expression of Bud8p from the BUD9 promoter leads to its localization predominantly in the sites typical for Bud9p, and vice versa. Moreover, expression of Bud8p from the BUD9 promoter fails to rescue the budding-pattern defect of a bud8 mutant but fully rescues that of a bud9 mutant. However, although expression of Bud9p from the BUD8 promoter fails to rescue a bud9 mutant, it also rescues only partially the budding-pattern defect of a bud8 mutant. Using a collection of mutants individually deleted for almost every yeast gene, I undertook a genome-wide phenotype analysis for altered sensitivity to a yeast antifungal protein, the K1 killer toxin. Mutations in most genes have no effect on toxin sensitivity, with less than 10% having a phenotype. Only 4% of these were previously known to have a toxin phenotype. There is a markedly non-random functional distribution of mutants with a toxin phenotype. Many genes fall into a limited set of functional classes or modules, which define specific areas of cellular function. These include known pathways of cell wall synthesis and signal transduction, and offer new insights into these processes and into cell wall morphogenesis.</description><creator>Page, Nicolas.</creator><contributor>Bussey, Howard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Fungal cell walls.</subject><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Cytology.</subject><title>Comprehensive phenotype analysis and characterization of molecular markers of the poles of Saccharomyces cerevisiae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn90t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0968718</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p19w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation investigates intra-clausal relations, namely, the relations that obtain between the elements in a clause. This investigation is based on a detailed study of copular sentences in Russian and Italian. In particular, three types of intra-clausal relations are investigated here: phrase-structural relations, thematic relations, and case relations. With respect to phrase-structural relations, it is argued that not all syntactic structures are asymmetrical. Rather, it is proposed that under certain conditions---when the two input phrases have the same features---Merge will result in a symmetrical structure. This requirement for matching features leads to a more parsimonious analysis of equative sentences where the interpretation derives directly from the syntactic structure, without postulating a special "identity copula". As for thematic relations, it is claimed that there is no one-to-one correspondence between thematic positions and structural positions (contra the strong version of UTAH, Baker 1988). Instead, a more flexible theory of thematic relations is proposed. It is also proposed that theta-assignment is not a necessary condition for DP interpretation. Rather, a DP can be interpreted if it establishes a certain relationship with another theta-marked DP. This analysis extends to Left Dislocation, Pronoun Doubling and sound like -construction. Finally, case relations are said to be tied to thematic relations. A version of the Visibility Condition is thus argued for. It is maintained that non-argument DPs---namely, those that are merged as neither complements nor specifiers of a lexical head---need not be case-marked in syntax at all and appear with the morphological default (i.e., nominative) marking. The alternative "agreement in case" analysis of NOM-NOM sentences is argued against; various conceptual and empirical problems for this analysis are identified and discussed. The analysis developed in this dissertation accounts for a number of properties of copular sentences, including their interpretation, case-marking patterns, and such syntactic properties as extraction, inversion, binding possibilities and unaccusativity diagnostics.</description><creator>Pereltsvaig, Asya.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa deMena (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Italian language -- Syntax</subject><subject>Russian language -- Syntax</subject><title>On the nature of intra-clausal relations : a study of copular sentences in Russian and Italian</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634545d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p19w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010r83s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this research was to explore the use of machine learning to assist in the development of knowledge-based systems (KBS) in dairy farming. A framework was first developed which described the various types of management and control activities in dairy farming and the types of information flows among these activities. This framework provided a basis for the creation of computerized information systems and helped to identify the analysis of group-average lactation curves as a promising area of application. A case-acquisition and decision-support system was developed to assist a domain specialist in generating example cases for machine learning. The specialist classified data from 33 herds enrolled with the Quebec dairy herd analysis service, resulting in 1428 lactations and 7684 tests of individual cows, classified as outlier or non-outlier, and 99 interpretations of group-average lactation curves. To enable the performance analysis of classifiers, generated with machine learning from these small data sets, a method was established involving cross-validation runs, relative operating characteristic curves, and analysis of variance. In experiments to filter lactations and tests, classification performance was significantly affected by preprocessing of examples, creation of additional attributes, choice of machine-learning algorithm, and algorithm configuration. For the filtering of individual tests, naive-Bayes classification showed significantly better performance than decision-tree induction. However, the specialist considered the decision trees as more transparent than the knowledge generated with naive Bayes. The creation of a series of three classifiers with increased sensitivity at the expense of reduced specificity per classification task, allows users of a final KBS to choose the desired tendency of classifying new cases as abnormal. For the main interpretation tasks, satisfactory performance was achieved. For the filtering tasks, performance was fai</description><creator>Pietersma, Diederik.</creator><contributor>Wade, K. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Dairy farming -- Management.</subject><subject>Dairy farming -- Québec (Province) -- Management.</subject><subject>Machine learning.</subject><title>Machine-learning assisted development of a knowledge-based system in dairy farming</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999833k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010r83s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j279b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Margaret of Austria (1480--1530) ruled the Burgundian Netherlands for over twenty years and was an integral member of the joint Houses of Burgundy and Habsburg. She was also one of the most prolific patrons and collectors of her time. This dissertation examines Margaret's patronage in relation to her contemporary environment with the aim of extending and deepening our understanding of her commissions within the dynamics and discourses of the culture of the early sixteenth century. Margaret of Austria was a highly conscientious patron and the art and architecture she commissioned intimately reflected her life. Chapter one introduces the historical facts of Margaret's life as well as issues affecting her patronage. Chapter two considers the monastery of Brou in Savoy as Margaret's architectural autobiography. Drawing on documentation and the building itself, it examines Margaret's involvement in Brou's creation. Chapter three looks at several of Margaret's other commissions such as her residence, the Palace of Savoy in Mechelen and the Convent of the Annunciate in Bruges. This chapter considers the potential goals of these projects, as ambitious as founding a capital city, embellishing her authority as a ruler, or attaining sainthood. Chapter four turns to Margaret's self-portraits, that is, images she commissioned of herself. Created in several mediums for a variety of audiences (including herself), Margaret's self-portraits portray her as everything from a widow to a goddess to a saint. Each image was designed for a specific audience and demonstrates Margaret's understanding of the function of images in negotiating a place in the contemporary world and history. Chapter five presents Margaret's view of herself as one of the rulers of a New World Empire with her pioneering collection of artefacts from the Americas. The conclusion considers the unique image of Margaret of Austria that emerges from her commissions.</description><creator>MacDonald, Deanna.</creator><contributor>Boker, Hans (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Architecture -- Netherlands</subject><subject>Margaret, of Austria, Regent of the Netherlands, 1480-1530.</subject><subject>Architecture -- France</subject><subject>Art patronage -- Netherlands -- History -- 16th century</subject><subject>Art patronage -- France -- History -- 16th century</subject><title>Acknowledging the "Lady of the house" : memory, authority and self-representation in the patronage of Margaret of Austria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b83p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j279b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s408n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Human T cell Leukemia Virus (HTLV) is the etiologic agent of adult T cell leukemia (ATL), an aggressive and fatal leukemia of CD4+ T lymphocytes, and is also associated with a neurological demyelinating disease called Tropical Spastic Paraparesis (TSP) or HTLV-I Associated Myelopathies (HAM). The oncogenic potential of HTLV-I resides in the viral Tax oncoprotein, a positive regulator of viral and cellular gene transcription. Interestingly, all HTLV-1 infected cells and Jurkat cells transiently transfected with the HTLV-I Tax gene, express constitutively the Interferon Regulatory Factor-4 (IRF-4), a lymphoid-specific member of the IRF family of transcription factors, indicating that Tax may function as an indirect transactivator the IRF-4 gene. The overexpression of IRF-4 in HTLV-1 infected cells may play a role in viral-mediated cellular transformation and thus in adult T cell leukemia. IRF-4 expression studies revealed its presence in B cells, activated T cell, macrophages and T cells infected with HTLV-I or HTLV-II. In attempt to understand the regulation of IRF-4 expression, promoter analyses were undertaken using genomic footprinting and EMSA. These promoter analyses revealed the involvement of the NF-kappaB and NF-AT family members in IRF-4 regulation. Using IRF-4 as bait in a yeast two hybrid screen, a novel interaction between IRF-4 and the FK506 binding protein 52 (FKBP52), a 59kDa member of the immunophilin family with peptidyl-prolyl isomerase activity (PPIase) as well as chaperone-like functions, was characterized. Inhibition of IRF-4 DNA binding activity as well as transcriptional potential was shown to require functional PPIase of this immunophilin. FKBP52 seems to induce a conformational change in IRF-4 by cis-trans prolyl isomerization which interferes with IRF-4 DNA binding and transactivation. These studies suggest the direct involvement of the immunophilin FKBP52 in the regulation of IRF-4 function by a novel post-translational modification.</description><creator>Mamane, Yael.</creator><contributor>Hiscott, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Lymphocytes.</subject><subject>Human T-lymphotropic virus 1.</subject><title>The regulation of IRF-4 activity in lymphoid cells and involvement in HTLV-I-induced T cell leukomogenesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr25n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s408n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz30g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following research developed an approach and methodology to simultaneously gather and integrate social and natural science farm system data of developing countries into one data base. The overall approach was based on Weber's theory of abstraction, which requires the identification of the broadest number of variables as possible. The first step to understanding the farm system was to overview a number of the key variables which represented a number of key farm components; the second step was to juxtapose and blend together the various forms of data in linear forms against a test variable of Striga infestation levels; the third step was to evaluate if the amount of knowledge gained in predicting Striga infestation levels was statistically significant by cross correlating soil nutrient levels, crop management approaches, farmers' perceptions of Striga infestation and spatial distances; the fourth step was to use parametric and non-parameterc analytical tools in conjunction with data compression to locate the best combination of parameters to better manage Striga. The final part of the process was to identify and integrate the crop, field and social data into a profile of farmer's who have the highest and lowest likelihood of being infested by Striga by using a soil nutrient concentration baseline as the indicator. The results were that natural and social science data could be successfully combined, integrated and have statistically significant cross correlations. These correlations indicate that specific spatial parameters combined with specific soil components, farmer's management and crop placement could be used as predictors of Striga infestation levels. As well the farmers' perception could be validated using natural science data.</description><creator>MacLean, Roger R.</creator><contributor>Barrington, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Agricultural systems -- Mali.</subject><subject>Traditional farming -- Mali.</subject><subject>Purple witchweed -- Control -- Mali.</subject><title>A trans-disciplinary approach integrating farm system data to better manage and predict Striga infestations /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z026.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz30g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34125</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>