<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:33:06Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35950" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214p80w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermoplastics injection molding involves plastication followed by the injection of the melt into a cold cavity. Packing is employed to compensate for shrinkage due to cooling. Ultimately, the solidified part is ejected from the mold without damage. The successful operation of an injection molding machine requires control of the process variables during each of the consecutive stages in addition to correctly identifying the points of transition from one stage to the next. Pressure and its variation during the injection molding cycle play an important role with regard to productivity, product quality, and product reproducibility. From the practical point of view, it is necessary to consider simultaneously hydraulic pressure, nozzle pressure, and the distribution of pressure in the cavity. Control of each phase of the injection molding process is best achieved by controlling one or a combination of the above pressure parameters. The present work describes a comprehensive study of the dynamics and control of pressure during each stage of the injection molding cycle. Deterministic models were obtained for cavity gate pressure during the filling and packing stages. Dynamic model predictions were in good agreement with experimental data. The response of cavity gate pressure exhibited nonlinear behavior which was investigated and rectified by a gain scheduling control strategy. Stochastic models were obtained for cavity gate pressure response in the filling stage for the purpose of comparison and future design of more advanced control algorithms The dynamic models were employed to design and evaluate control schemes for the injection molding cycle. Nozzle and cavity pressures were used in conjunction with PI, PID and Dahlin controllers. The hydraulic system of the injection molding machine was redesigned to incorporate two servovalves in order to achieve control over the cavity pressuretime profile during the packing stage as well as over peak cavity and hold pressures. The control loops were designed through a simulation study which also gave good indications of system limitations. On the basis of this study, very good and reliable integrated control over the filling, packing, and holding stages was achieved by a general control scheme which allows the transfer of control from one variable to another during the various stages of the process.</description><creator>Abu Fara, Dib I.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Control of nozzle and cavity pressure during filling and packing in thermoplastics injection molding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb534.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214p80w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pr01f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Past studies of the Tuareg have been chiefly concerned with nomadic or semi-nomadic pastoral society. This work is an examination of a sedentary community of former vassals or slaves of the Tuareg who reside at Aouderas, a village of the Saharan Air Massif of northern Niger (West Africa). The economy of Aouderas is multi-sectoral, and is composed of: small-scale irrigated agriculture (which has been analytically separated into subsistence and cash crops); stock-raising of camels, small ruminants, and cattle; and a caravan trade based on the exchange of salt and grain. An analysis of more recent economic developments, namely migration to wage work and expanding urban markets for garden produce, is also undertaken. The principal social institutions which govern production and reproduction are examined. The relative importance of each sector to household welfare is quantified and analysed by means of a model which shows the revenues derived from each sector in terms of millet, the local staple food.</description><creator>Brusberg, Frederick E.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Aoudéras (Niger) -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Aoudéras (Niger) -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Tuaregs -- Niger -- Aoudéras -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Tuaregs -- Niger -- Aoudéras -- Social conditions</subject><title>Economy and society of Aouderas : a community of the Saharan Aïr Massif (Niger)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bh92q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pr01f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qc865</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I studied the onshore migrations of Atlantic cod (Gadus morhua) in the northern Gulf of St. Lawrence to test the predictability of the distributions and catches of a migratory predatory fish relative to physical oceanographic processes and the distributions and abundances of its prey. To survey daily fish distributions and abundances by species, hydroacoustic signal discriminant methods were developed which classified schools of cod, capelin (Mallotus villosus), and mackerel (Scomber scombrus) with 93% success. Physical oceanographic processes along the 150 km of coastline studied were characterized by Ekman-type upwellings and downwellings forced by alongshore winds at periods $&gt;$3 d. Physical elements of this system (principally currents and temperature) were associated with cross-shore movements of cod and accounted for as much as 83% of the variance in mean trap catch. Cod and capelin formed coherent spatial distributions when capelin were congregated where sea temperatures were most favorable to cod (1 to 5$ sp circ$C) and mean capelin densities were above 100/10$ sp5$m$ sp3$. Coherences were in phase at larger scales ($&gt;$10 km) but became increasingly out of phase at smaller scales. Cod distributions fit the predictions of an "ideal" distribution (allometric constant = 0.67) when two constraints were put on the relationship: (1) capelin densities above 100/10$ sp5$m$ sp3$, and (2) temperatures between 1 and 9$ sp circ$C.</description><creator>Rose, George A.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Codfish -- Behavior -- Climatic factors.</subject><subject>Capelin -- Geographical distribution.</subject><subject>Codfish -- Migration.</subject><title>Temporal and spatial variability in onshore cod (Gadus morthua) migrations : associations with atmosphere-ocean dynamics and capelin (Mallotus villosus) distributions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nr66p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qc865</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720d487</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent research has shown the Canadian peasantry of the eighteenth century to be less homogeneous than was once thought. Beyond the ebb and flow of the family cycle, the striking differences in productive resources from one household to the next can only have furthered accumulation among the peasants. Set in Riviere-du-Sud, a seigneury fifty kilometres downstream from Quebec on the south shore of the St. Lawrence, the present study is concerned with the forms and limits of that process. By 1720, the seigneury had entered what might be called the second phase of colonization; the population had taken root, but throughout the period land for the children who departed would continue to be available farther afield. In this setting, it is suggested, both production and markets were too uncertain to permit even the largest producers to lose their subsistence orientation and break through the traditional limits to scale. At the same time, such peasants had no choice but to invest most of their appreciable surplus in land, which they eventually distributed to their children. A muted differentiation process, in which the most prosperous continually pushed the vulnerable off their valuable land to inferior holdings elsewhere, resulted.</description><creator>Wien, William Thomas</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Québec (Province) -- Social conditions -- To 1867.</subject><subject>Land settlement -- Québec (Province) -- Rivière-du-Sud Region -- History -- To 1867.</subject><subject>Agriculture -- Québec (Province) -- Rivière-du-Sud Region -- History -- 18th century</subject><subject>Rivière-du-Sud Region (Québec) -- Social conditions -- 18th century</subject><title>Peasant accumulation in a context of colonization : Rivière-du-Sud, Canada, 1720-1775</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860768h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720d487</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053g815</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the underlying factor structure of second language (L2) cloze test performance as explained by a theoretical model including the following hypothetical constructs: cloze-taking ability, knowledge of language, knowledge of text content, and knowledge of contextual constraints. Eight cloze tests reflecting the posited factors were constructed and administered to 182 Francophone, university-level students. The factors were examined separately and in combination through a causal model building process. A model composed of three orthogonal factors was confirmed and accepted as the best explanation of the data. The results indicate that cloze performance is dependent upon knowledge of a specific language (second language or first language) and nonlinguistic-specific knowledge related to close-taking ability that crosses over linguistic boundaries. Cloze has been considered as an overall L2 proficiency measure. This study empirically demonstrates that factors other than language are significantly contributing to cloze performance. It also demonstrates the potential of a causal modeling approach.</description><creator>Turner, Carolyn E. (Carolyn Elizabeth), 1951-</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Second language acquisition -- Research</subject><subject>Cloze procedure -- Research</subject><subject>Bilingualism -- Research</subject><title>The underlying factor structure of L2 cloze test performance in francophone, university-level students : causal modeling as an approach to construct validation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rx333.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053g815</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education in Second Languages</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042t680</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research concerns the alternate melting and freezing of a phase change material (PCM) to simulate cyclic operation of phase change energy storage systems. A one-dimensional conduction-controlled phase change model was derived for a PCM slab. One surface of the slab is subjected to successive periods of constant temperature above and below the fusion temperature while the other surface is adiabatic. A front-tracking, self-marching finite-difference scheme was developed to solve the resulting multiple moving boundary problem. Temperature fields within each solid and liquid region were decoupled with an explicit treatment of the interfacial energy balances. Temperatures at all grid points were obtained by an explicit finite-difference scheme except for the grid points in the immediate neighborhood of each phase front. Temperatures at the latter points were computed from a quadratic temperature profile with time-dependent coefficients. Dynamic simulations were carried out until a periodic steady state was attained when the energy stored during a melting period and the energy recovered in the following freezing period were equal and remained invariant for subsequent periods. The cumulative energy transferred, the instantaneous heat flux, the interface locations and the temperature profiles were obtained for three modes of operation: (1) equal thermal swings with equal melting and freezing periods, (2) equal periods with unequal swings and (3) equal swings with unequal periods. Experiments were carried out by alternately melting and freezing n-octadecane in a thin rectangular cell. When the cell was horizontal and heat was transferred from above, the moving interfaces were planar and there was excellent agreement between numerical and experimental results. When the cell was tilted, the interfaces were not planar and the energy transferred at the periodic steady state increased with the angle of inclination, reaching a maximum with heat transfer from below.</description><creator>Hasan, Mainul</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Cyclic phase change : energy storage and recovery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm36f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042t680</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278t71j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents an extensive study of the kinematics of parallel manipulators. The latter are considered here as a subset of a more general class of kinematic chains called complex kinematic chains which are defined as chains in which there exists at least one link having a degree of connectivity greater than or equal to three. The degree of connectivity of a link is defined here as the number of rigid bodies that are directly attached to this link by kinematic pairs. The first portion of the thesis is devoted to the study of simple kinematic chains which are the basic elements from which complex kinematic chains, and hence parallel manipulators, are constructed. The analysis of complex kinematic chains is then pursued through their graph representation and through the derivation of the associated Jacobian matrix. The three types of singularities pertaining to this class of kinematic chains are identified using the latter concept. They are illustrated with some examples. This also leads to an unambiguous definition of parallel manipulators based on their graph representation. Parallel manipulators are then analyzed in detail. The analysis includes the solution of the direct and inverse kinematic problems, the velocity and acceleration inversions and an investigation of the singularities. These problems are discussed in a general framework before special cases are introduced. The kinematic design optimization of parallel manipulators is then undertaken using some performance criteria such as symmetry, workspace, local dexterity and global dexterity. A new performance index called global conditioning index (GCI) is also defined. Finally, the kinematic inversion of redundant parallel manipulators is approached as a local dexterity maximization problem. The concept of trajectory map is introduced and an algorithm for the generation of smooth trajectories is given.</description><creator>Gosselin, Clément</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Kinematic analysis, optimization and programming of parallel robotic manipulators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bh930.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t71j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v58k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sclerotinia sclerotiorum is a pathogen of crops grown in the muck soil regions of Quebec. Soil baiting tests indicated that the sclerotia of S. sclerotiorum are attacked and destroyed by the larvae of Bradysia coprophila and mycoparasites. Sclerotia with rinds partially damaged by the larvae were found to be more susceptible to mycoparasitism by Trichoderma viride. Increasing the organic matter content and porosity of soils resulted in increased damage to sclerotia when larvae were present. Studies conducted to determine if larvae could be reared on diets of various fungi and plant tissue showed that mycelia and sclerotia of S. sclerotiorum were the most successful food sources, followed by mycelia and sclerotia of Botrytis porri and Rhizoctonia solani. Adults produced on mycelia and sclerotia of Sclerotinia minor, Fusarium solani f. sp. pisi, and Botrytis cinerea seldom were fertile. Larvae generally failed to survive when reared on cultures of Trichoderma viride. Larval development occurred on all plants inoculated with the above pathogens but failed to occur on noninoculated healthy plants. Salivary gland secretions of the larvae were found to inhibit the germination of sclerotia. Analyses of the secretion determined that it contains 4.3% protein and had chitinase activity. Mechanically damaged and undamaged sclerotia exhibited an increase in eruptive mycelial germination when treated with 1.5 $ mu$g ml$ sp{-1}$ chitinase but germination decreased at 50, 100 and 150 $ mu$g ml$ sp{-1}$ chitinase concentrations. Noneruptive mycelial germination and carpogenic germination occurred when sclerotia were treated with acetate buffer and distilled water.</description><creator>Anas, Osama</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Fungi.</subject><subject>Pests -- Integrated control.</subject><subject>Sclerotinia sclerotiorum.</subject><subject>Sciaridae.</subject><subject>Trichoderma.</subject><title>Interactions between Sclerotinia sclerotiorum (Lib.) de Bary, Bradysia coprophila Lintner (dark-winged fungus gnat) and mycoparasitic fungi</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p07g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v58k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z526</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The concept of Built-In Self-Test (BIST) has recently become an increasingly attractive solution to the complex problem of testing VLSI chips. However, the realization of BIST faces some challenging problems of its own. One of these problems is to increase the quality of fault coverage of a BIST implementation, without incurring a large overhead. In particular, the loss of information in the output data compressor, which is typically a multi-input linear feedback shift register (MISR), is a major cause of concern. In the recent past, several researchers have proposed different schemes to reduce this loss of information, while maintaining the need for a small area overhead. In this dissertation, a new BIST scheme, based on modifying the output data before compression, is developed. This scheme, called output data modification (ODM), exploits the knowledge of the functionality of the circuit under test to provide a circuit-specific BIST structure. This structure is developed so that it can conveniently be implemented for any general circuit under consideration. But more importantly, a proof of effectiveness is provided to show that ODM will, on the average, be orders of magnitude better than all existing schemes in its capability to reduce the information loss, for a given amount of area overhead. Moreover, the constructive nature of the proof will allow one to provide a simple trade-off between the reduction tolerated in information loss to the area overhead needed to affect this reduction.</description><creator>Zorian, Yervant</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Error-correcting codes (Information theory) -- Computer simulation</subject><subject>Integrated circuits -- Masks</subject><subject>Fault-tolerant computing</subject><title>Optimized error coverage in built-in self-test by output data modification</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pg933.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z526</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67314666</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurofilament (NF) proteins were purified on hydroxylapatite and reassembled to yield filaments with subunit ratios of 8 low (NF-L), 3 middle (NF-M) and 3 high (NF-H) molecular weight subunits. This unit of 8L:3M:3H was used in calculations of Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding capacity. Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding to untreated and in vitro dephosphorylated NFs was assayed by partition centrifugation. Both types of NFs were shown to contain high affinity and low affinity Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding sites. Four sites with a Kd = 4.1 uM and 126 sites with a Kd = 293 uM were contained per unit of untreated NFs and 8 sites with a Kd = 15 uM and 54 sites with a Kd = 332 uM were contained per unit of dephosphorylated NFs. The decrease by half in the amount of low affinity Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding sites correlated with the removal of 50% of the phosphate moieties in dephosphorylated NFs. The Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding profile was altered in the presence of physiological concentrations of Na$ sp+$ (10 mM), K$ sp+$ (150 m) and Mg$ sp{2+}$ (2 mM). Under the latter conditions only one class of 126 sites with a Kd = 740 uM was contained per unit of untreated NFs, whereas in vitro dephosphorylated NFs contained 2 Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding sites with a Kd = 11 uM and 46 suites with a Kd = 620 uM. The use of $ sp{22}$Na, which bound to low affinity Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding sites, allowed the determination of dissociation constants for Na$ sp+$, K$ sp+$ and Mg$ sp{2+}$ at these sites. The results indicated that in the presence of physiological concentrations of these cations, the sites would be occupied by Na$ sp+$ and K$ sp+$ in the case of untreated NFs, but only by Na$ sp+$ in in vitro dephosphorylated NFs. Comparison of the amino acid sequences of porcine NF-L and NF-M with known Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding sequences revealed one region suggestive of a high affinity Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding site in the coiled-coil II b region of each subunit. The enrichment of coiled-coil domains by chymotryptic cleavage of NFs indicated that this Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding site has a Kd = 3.6 uM. Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding to NF preparations with different subunit compositions demonstrated an effect of adjacent domains on the high affinity Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding sites in NF subunits as well as intersubunit interactions which altered the affinity of phosphate moiety-containing binding sites located in the carboxy-terminal domain. The competitive interaction of Al$ sp{3+}$ with both classes of Ca$ sp{2+}$-binding sites on NFs demonstrated that any Ca$ sp{2+}$-related functions of NFs would be impaired in the presence of Al$ sp{3+}$. This finding has important implications regarding the neurotoxicity of Al$ sp{3+}$.</description><creator>Lefebvre, Suzie</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Study of the cation binding properties of porcine neurofilaments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jr897.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67314666</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296wz73b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A standard methodology was developed for performing avoidance-preference tests, using Rainbow Trout (Salmo gairdneri) as the test organism. Experiments were conducted in a hydraulic channel, 9.15 m long by 0.30 m wide, partly divided along its length, and at a flow depth of 0.30 m. The design combined steep and shallow gradient characteristics. The toxicants investigated included Cu(II), Cr(III) and Cr(VI). The lowest avoidance threshold values were established at 2.1 $ mu$g/l for Cu(II) and 0.0026 mg/l and 0.026 mg/l for Cr(III) and Cr(VI) respectively while avoidance reactions increased with levels of toxicant in the channel. Similar experiments were performed with rainbow trout which were pre-exposed at sublethal levels to the toxicant, in order to assess the influence of toxic pre-exposure to the subsequent fish avoidance response. The length of pre-exposure varied between 7-20 weeks. Avoidance threshold values were correlated with safe levels of toxicant exposure. Pre-exposed fish exhibited decreasing avoidance reactions compared to non-exposed populations. Increased tolerance to the toxicant, was suggested by the increase in avoidance threshold values with pre-exposure levels. Fish exposed to test concentrations matching their pre-exposure levels, clearly preferred this same concentration over the adjacent lower or higher test concentration. A two mechanism avoidance model was proposed independent of toxicant used or level of pre-exposure. The toxicant concentration where the second mechanism begins to dominate was referred to as avoidance breakpoint, and was correlated to a MATC level for the toxicant in question. Olfactory responses were proposed to be associated with fish avoidance responses below the avoidance breakpoint, while hypoxic stress along with osmo- and iono regulatory stress appeared to be responsible for driving fish avoidance reactions beyond the avoidance breakpoint. A clearance period of 7 days was sufficient to allow fish to recover normal avoidance behaviour following pre-exposure to Cr(VI) below the avoidance breakpoint.</description><creator>Anestis, Ioannis D.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Copper -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Chromium -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Environmental engineering</subject><subject>Rainbow trout</subject><title>Preference avoidance reactions of rainbow trout (Salmo gairdneri) following long term sublethal exposure to chromium and copper</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc701.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296wz73b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526d03d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The classic theories dealing with vocational choice (Holland, Super) have not satisfactorily predicted the career choices of women. Indeed, several (Psathas, Zytowski, Ben Dor, Fassinger) have questioned their ability to explain women's career development and have indicated the need for alternatives. The present work takes up this challenge and raises the question: "What are the factors which influence young women to continue to choose careers classified as typically 'feminine' when, as a result of societal and academic changes of the last two decades, all programs are now open to them?" In 1984 a study was made of 401 women students enrolled in traditional female disciplines within the sciences (nursing, physiotherapy, occupational therapy) and in non-traditional fields (architecture, engineering, dentistry). An analysis of the data collected from this sample, representative of students registered in these programs at a large, metropolitan, English-speaking university in Canada (McGill), found that there were statistically significant differences between the two groups. These differences derive from place of birth, socio-economic status (SES), work experience, aspirations, significant others, work values and conception of the role of women. Women students with a traditional (T) profile are more likely to be born in Quebec, come from a family of lower SES, work part time, have lower academic aspirations, have been influenced by a woman in their chosen field, value work more highly for its intrinsic worth and qualitative environment, and are willing to accept interrupted careers. Women students with a non traditional (NT) profile are more likely to be born outside Canada, come from a family of higher SES, do not work part time, have high academic aspirations, have been influenced by a man in their career choice, value work less highly for its intrinsic worth and qualitative environment, and expect to have continuous careers.</description><creator>Guilbert, Céline</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Student aspirations</subject><subject>Women college students -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes</subject><title>Charactéristiques d'étudiantes choisies dans des disciplines traditionnelles et non traditionnelles, à l'Université McGill (Montréal)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fs008.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d03d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602135f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neuroendocrine sites and mechanisms of action whereby testosterone (T) regulates LH, FSH and prolactin signals in male rats were investigated by determining the effects of orchidectomy and graded T replacement on the secretion patterns of these hormones in blood. A chronic jugular catheter system was established to obtain blood samples at 5-10 min intervals from unrestrained, unanesthetized rats; this enabled moment to moment changes in plasma hormone concentrations, and thus hormone patterns, to be determined. In intact rats the patterns of LH and prolactin in plasma are pulsatile, but exhibit no synchrony; the FSH pattern shows no pulses. Post-orchidectomy LH concentrations rise due to increases in pulse amplitude and frequency; FSH also rises, but still no pulses are detected. Decreased prolactin pulse amplitudes result in lower plasma concentrations, despite an increase in pulse frequency. Treatment of orchidectomized rats with low doses of T increases mean LH and FSH concentrations, thus demonstrating that T is capable of exerting a positive feedback effect in males. The effect on LH is due to a stimulation of LH pulse amplitude which is not mediated at the pituitary. The FSH pattern becomes pulsatile and is synchronized with that of LH. Higher doses of T exert negative feedback on LH and FSH; LH pulse amplitude and frequency are decreased and the FSH pattern once again shows no pulses. These effects of T are partially due to inhibition of the pituitary response to LHRH. Low doses of T completely block the effects of orchidectomy on prolactin pulse amplitude, but T levels similar to those in intact animals are required to reverse the accelerated pulse frequency. The results suggest that gonadotropins and prolactin are regulated by separate pulse generators, each responsive to changes in plasma T. Furthermore, T, depending on its concentration, regulates gonadotropin and prolactin secretion by exerting stimulatory and/or inhibitory effects on various neur</description><creator>Grosser, Peter M.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Testosterone modulation of plasma gonadotropin and prolactin patterns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h023r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602135f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g558</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Soviet literature of the twenties and thirties is examined in the present study in its relationship to other verbal genres, primarily, the speeches of Party leaders, newspaper rhetoric and political posters. The first four chapters of the dissertation focus on such topics as the reception of Marxist-Leninist discourse by peasants and workers as well as its representation in fiction; the refraction of official discursive formulas in characters' speech and the dialogization of Party rhetoric; the integration of political documents into fiction and their structural function. Particular attention is paid to the way the contamination of Party rhetoric by substandard language and its contextual defamiliarization lead, depending on the overall authorial intention, either to a parodic subversion of official cliches or to the internalization of didactic discourse and the enhancement of its communicative effectiveness. The theme of industrialization is examined in the last two chapters of the thesis in its dialectic interaction with various Neo-Rousseauist conceptions, which either reflect the authors' own ambivalence about socialist construction, or constitute a rhetorical device used in order to reinforce dialogically industrialist ideology.</description><creator>Elbaum, Henry</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Russian literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism</subject><title>Rhetoric and fiction : interaction of verbal genres in the Soviet literature of the twenties and thirties</title><language>rus</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s319z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g558</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fs01j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the concept of revelation in the writings of Ahmad Khan, Azad, and Mawdudi Using as its framework the development of modern Western thought on revelation, it raises questions related to religious epistemology and finds that the Muslims studied offer three interpretations of revelation: (1) part mystico-subjective and part natural intuitive, (2) part traditional and part mystico-subjective, and (3) traditional. The thesis concludes that out of a preoccupation with apologetics, all three authors failed to develop a coherent theory of revelation: Mawdudi did not understand modern problems surrounding revelation and hence did not feel the need for a solution to them; Azad, because of an ambivalent position regarding modernity, contradicted his own views; only Ahmad Khan was able to appreciate the modern threat to revelation and attempted a new interpretation. However, his interpretation was expressed in medieval philosophic molds and found little acceptance among Muslims at large.</description><creator>D'Souza, Andreas Felix</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Maudoodi, Syed Abul ʻAla, 1903-1979.</subject><subject>Revelation -- Islam.</subject><subject>Aḥmad Ḵẖāṉ, Sayyid, Sir, 1817-1898</subject><subject>Āzād, Abūlkalām, 1888-1958.</subject><title>The concept of revelation in the writings of three modern Indian Muslims : a study of Aḥmad Khân, Abû al-Kalâm Âzâd and Abû al-Aʻlâ Mawdûdî</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p102v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fs01j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042t698</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this thesis is to develop empirical models of the stable catch of brook trout in the Laurentian lakes of Quebec. Current estimators of fish yield are biased and predict poorly. A model resulting from this study shows that catch increases with fishing effort, but that the rate of increase is smaller at higher effort. For a given effort, the catch-per-unit of effort (CPUE) is greater in larger lakes. Catch is also greater in phosphorus rich lakes and smaller in acid lakes. Catch of bigger fish is associated with a lower CPUE. No dome-shaped relationship between catch and effort, standardized for the effects of lakes characteristics, could be established. Thus the maximum sustainable yield (MSY) concept provides no guidelines for management of the fishery. However, an early warning of overexploitation is an exceptionally high rate of fishing success. In addition logistic regression based on easily obtained variables can predict the likelihood of stability of the fisheries.</description><creator>Godbout, Lyse</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Fishery management -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Brook trout fishing.</subject><subject>Fish populations -- Research.</subject><title>Empirical models predicting catch of brook trout (Salvelinus fontinalis) in Québec sport fishery lakes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hs616.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042t698</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36tz23z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A nonlinear wave equation invariant with respect to unitary representations of the Lorentz group is considered in an attempt to describe extended particles with spin and positive definite energy by means of a self-confined classical field. The wave function has an infinite number of components and, in the specific representations used, the corresponding internal degree of freedom is identified with the spin. A fractional power of the scalar bilinear invariant appears as an appropriate choice for the nonlinearity in order that all the stationary states be localized. Two approximation methods are proposed and both lead to results that bear a resemblance to the results of the MIT bag model.</description><creator>Girard, Réjean</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Lorentz groups</subject><subject>Nonlinear theories</subject><subject>Solitons</subject><title>Relativistic nonlinear wave equations with groups of internal symmetry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn83t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tz23z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d0427</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A decade ago Bizzi and collaborators proposed the "linear summation" hypothesis mainly based on the vestibulo-ocular reflex to explain how subjects move their eyes and head simultaneously to acquire a peripheral visual target. We asked human subjects to make rapid horizontal gaze shifts to unpredictable visible or remembered targets situated at offsets ranging from 30$ sp circ$ to 160$ sp circ$. Different experimental paradigms were used to dissociate crucial variables and different perturbations were imposed to our subjects' head movements to test the interaction between the saccadic eye movement and the head displacement. Several assumptions of the "linear summation" hypothesis were questioned by the analysis of results and we proposed a more elaborated gaze control model to explain how subjects could reach a target accurately with their gaze shifts whatever the conditions, even when the target was beyond the subject's oculomotor range. In parallel with human experiments we developed a technique to record vestibular units in head-free cats during orienting eye-head movements. Preliminary results on several electrophysiologically identified cells show some particular discharge patterns in the head-free condition. They bring some insights to the behavioral results.</description><creator>Volle, Michel A.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Contributions a l'etude des coordinations oculo-cephaliques chez l'homme et l'animal</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h0241.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d0427</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f896n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis examines the phenomenon of the positive philosophy of exile in contemporary literature on the basis of Stefan Themerson's fiction. Themerson's positive attitude to exile and its antecedents--the Stoic ideal of "cosmopolis" and its eighteenth-century transformations--are compared to the views on expatriation expressed by another exiled writer, Witold Gombrowicz, to the moral philosophy of Bertrand Russell, and to the ideology of the twentieth-century avant-garde. Within emigre literature the works marked by the positive philosophy of exile are treated as a separate form to be distinguished from the works in which exile is only a theme. The positive philosopher of exile bases his optimism on scepticism and the recognition of the arbitrariness of human values. The thesis claims that, although far from being universally true and free from weaknesses, the positive philosophy of exile has a genuine claim to validity as an attempt to contribute to the process of bridging cultural differences without compromising cultural diversity.</description><creator>Stachniak, Ewa</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Exiles in literature</subject><subject>Exiles' writings.</subject><subject>Themerson, Stefan -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>The positive philosophy of exile in contemporary literature : Stefan Themerson and his fiction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z596t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f896n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dg395</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A route to the synthesis of arabino and xylonucleosides is described. This route takes advantage of highly selective ribonucleoside hydroxyl protection procedures which have recently been developed. The route is straightforward and broadly applicable. It may be applied to both purine and pyrimidine nucleosides. Synthesis, deprotection, and characterisation of the target compounds are described. The work is compared to that of others in the field. A novel class of oligonucleotide analogues is described. In this group, the phosphorus atom of the internucleotide link is replaced by silicon. The synthesis of both oligothymidine and oligo-2$ sp prime$-deoxyadenosine nucleotide analogues of this class is described. Various substituents at silicon are employed, and oligonucleotide analogs of up to six units long are synthesised, characterised and deprotected. The circular dichroism spectra of the deprotected hexamers is presented.</description><creator>Cormier, James</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Nucleotides</subject><subject>Nucleosides</subject><title>The synthesis of nucleoside and silyl nucleotide analogues /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n1851.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dg395</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r1641</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A non-linear finite element computer program capable of predicting the complete response of two-dimensional reinforced concrete members was developed. This tool which accounts for the stress strain characteristics of cracked concrete was used to predict the responses of a number of members containing discontinuities. These members included corbels, dapped end beams, beams with web holes, and deep beams. The results of tests performed by the author as well as tests performed by other researchers were compared with the non-linear predictions. In addition, simple strut and tie models suitable for designing regions near discontinuities were developed. The predictions obtained by these models were compared with the non-linear finite element predictions and with the test results.</description><creator>Cook, William Digby</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Reinforced concrete -- Cracking -- Computer programs</subject><subject>Concrete beams</subject><subject>Finite element method</subject><title>Studies of reinforced concrete regions near discontinuities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f415f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r1641</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq25f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pathway of internalization of insulin and asialoglycoprotein into rat liver parenchymal cells was through the same endosomal components. At no time was either ligand associated with the biosynthetic Golgi apparatus. Rat liver Golgi fractions were found to be contaminated by endosomes, hence their redesignation as Golgi-endosome fractions (GE). Proton translocation activity of different GE fractions showed a gradient of progressively decreasing activity which correlated with increasing time, of ligand accumulation therein. Based on the distinctive kinetics of proton translocation activity and ligand accumulation the endosomal components of the Golgi intermediate and light fractions, which fractionate coincidently on percoll gradient centrifugation, have been considered to be distinct components of the endocytic apparatus. The activity of the EGF receptor kinase has been assessed in plasmalemmal and GE fractions isolated from untreated animals as well as those injected with EGF in vivo. In untreated animals receptor kinase activity was readily detected in plasmalemmal fractions, but was latent in GE fractions, suggesting an intraluminal orientation of the EGF binding region of the receptor in endosomes. Consequent to the administration of EGF in vivo a majority of the receptor kinase translocated from plasmalemma to endosomes. Receptor kinase activity remaining on the plasmalemma was activated. Endosomally located receptor kinase activity was no longer latent following EGF administration, was maximally stimulated with respect to autophosphorylation activity and at later times following internalization, may become activated. These data are consistent with a role for both plasmalemmal and endosomally located EGF receptor kinase in transmembrane signalling.</description><creator>Kay, Denis G.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Biology, General.</subject><title>Studies on the pathway and significance of the receptor mediated internalization of insulin and epidermal growth factor in rat liver parenchyma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f1863.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq25f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r43f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus (SON) in the rat contains neurons that synthesize either vasopressin (VP) or oxytocin and that receive prominent afferent connections of cardiovascular origin. In vivo electrophysiological studies were undertaken to characterise the selective depression of VP-secreting cell activity consequent to activation of peripheral baroreceptors. Electrical stimulation of the diagonal band of Broca evoked a similar selective inhibition of supraoptic VP neurons. Extracellular recordings in the diagonal band confirmed the involvement of this site in the baro-reflex input to the SON. Local application of bicuculline, a GABA antagonist, abolished both the diagonal band-evoked and the baroreceptor-induced inhibition of VP-secreting neurons. Anatomical observations at the ultrastructural level indicated that the diagonal band projection to the SON is indirect and involves an GABAergic interneuron located in the perinuclear zone adjacent to the SON. Another input to the SON that was studied arises in the subfornical organ, a circumventricular structure known to contain angiotensin II immunoreactive neurons. Electrical stimulation of the subfornical organ evoked an excitatory response in SON neurons that could be selectively attenuated by locally applied saralasin, an angiotensin II antagonist. This finding suggests a role for the peptide angiotensin II as a neurotransmitter in this projection. The collective results are discussed in the context of the three major neurocardiovascular pathways that influence vasopressin secretion from the neurohypophysis.</description><creator>Jhamandas, Jack H.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Characterization of cardiovascular afferents to the hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus in the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm37q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r43f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nx675</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The asymptotic properties of discrete time stochastic systems operating under feedback is addressed. It is assumed that a Markov chain $ Phi$ evolving on Euclidean space exists, and that the input and output processes appear as functions of $ Phi$. The main objectives of the thesis are (i) to extend various asymptotic properties of Markov chains to hold for arbitrary initial distributions; and (ii) to develop a robustness theory for Markovian systems. A condition called local stochastic controllability, a generalization of the concept of controllability from linear system theory, is introduced and is shown to be sufficient to ensure that the first objective is met. The second objective is explored by introducing a notion of convergence for stochastic systems and investigating the behavior of the invariant probabilities corresponding to a convergent sequence of stochastic systems. These general results are applied to two previously unsolved problems: The asymptotic behavior of linear state space systems operating under nonlinear feedback, and the stability and asymptotic behavior of a class of random parameter AR (p) stochastic systems under optimal control.</description><creator>Meyn, S. P. (Sean P.)</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Markov processes</subject><subject>Stochastic systems</subject><title>Asymptotic behavior of stochastic systems possessing Markovian realizations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w54m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nx675</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375x05t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:55:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is composed of two parts, the first of which treats nonlinear three-dimensional flow of a thin viscous liquid layer down an inclined plane. Isotropic length-scales along the plane have been employed previously in the derivation of equations governing the free surface; a limiting case is shown herein to possess obliquely interacting 2-solitons as exact solutions. A governing equation based on anisotropic length-scales is also derived; in the dispersive limit, this equation is solved exactly, and the long-wave limit is considered both analytically and numerically. The second part of this thesis consists of two other nonlinear studies. In the first, equations are derived governing the evolution of long waves and wave packets in a model boundary layer. In the second, an equation which has been employed previously in studies of the stability characteristics of unbounded parallel flows is shown to exhibit subcritical instability.</description><creator>Melkonian, Sam</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Thin films</subject><title>Nonlinear waves on thin films and related phenomena</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fm208.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375x05t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35975</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>