<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:29:24Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10275" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289n05m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pentylenetetrazol administered to rats was metabolized to a derivative. This derivative was excreted in the urine along with unchanged pentylenetetrazol. Pentylenetetrazol and its metabolite can be separated on paper chromatograms developed in water-saturated isobutanol. Both substances, however, are chromatographically inseparable with water as the mobile phase. Distribution of tritium-labelled pentylenetetrazol in the rat after intraperitoneal injection indicated that it was readily taken up by tissues, especially the liver. Perfusion of the isolated rat liver with citrated blood containing tritiated-pentylenetetrazol demonstrated that the metabolite of this central nervous system stimulant drug was formed in the intact liver. In vitro formation of the metabolite by the perfused rat liver was inhibited by SKF 525-A. No metabolite was formed, however, when the agent was incubated with rat liver homogenates. A simple column chromatographic method using the neutral resin Amberlite XAD-2 was developed to enable isolation of the metabolic derivative of pentylenetetrazol for further chemical analyses.</description><creator>Ko, Gregory K.</creator><contributor>Hosein, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The metabolic fate of pentylenetetrazol in the rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hs69n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289n05m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vt96s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electron Spin Resonance measurements on lyophilized biopsy and mastectomy samples from 132 cases of human breast diseases showed a highly significant increase (P &lt; 0.00l) in mean g-factor gm, for the malignant diseases (gm = 2.0068 ± 0.0004) compared to the benign diseases (gm = 2.0050 ± 0.0002). All g-factors for malignant diseases were greater than 2.0037, whereas 20% of g-factors for benign diseases were less than 2.0037. The mean BSR absorption line width from malignant tissues (10.7 ± 0.4 gauss) was significantly narrower (0.01 &gt; P &gt; 0.005) than from benign tissues (12.5 ± 0.4 gauss). The line widths and relative spin densities were positively correlated (P &lt; 0.001) for all malignant diseases. [...]</description><creator>Kalomiris, Constantine G.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Electron spin resonance activity in human breast cancer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q522.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vt96s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Investigative Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vm03n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Seventeen antigens were detected in saline extracts of bovine brain by immunodiffusion and immunoelectrophoretic experiments. The antisera were produced by intensive immunization of rabbits with saline extracts of whole bovine brain emulsified in complete Freund's adjuvant. Ten of the antigens were species specific and shared by other bovine organs, five antigens were organ-specific and common to the brains of other mammals, and two antigens had specificities that were both organ- and species restricted (OSR antigens). One of the major organ-specific antigens, designated alpha - BOSAB, has been purified from bovine brain by ammonium sulfate precipitation, DEAE-cellulose chromatography, and preparative polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis. The purified antigen had an electrophoretic mobility of an alpha - globulin, a molecular weight determined by gel-filtration of about 84,000, and contained approximately 2% hexose (Anthrone method). alpha - BOSAB contained about 20% of glutamic and aspartic acid. alpha - BOSAB was found in bovine glia and in embryonic human and bovine brains.</description><creator>Hatcher, Victor B.</creator><contributor>MacPherson, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>A survey of the water soluble antigens of bovine brain together with the purification and characterization of a major organ-specific antigen.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw893.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm03n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462842r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glucose addition to Novikoff ascites hepatoma cells causes a rapid depletion of ATP and a decrease in total adenine nucleotides. Reestablishment of the steady state concentrations of ATP requires 50 to 60 minutes. Decreased rates of protein synthesis, glycogen synthesis, ion transport, PRPP synthesis, and incorporation of adenine and hypoxanthine into the acid soluble fraction are associated with the decrease in ATP concentration. During the first 6 minutes following glucose addition fructose diphosphate accumulates and the concentration of inorganic phosphate decreases. Glycolysis and glucose utilization decrease in the interval between 1 and 6 minutes after the addition of glucose. After preincubation of the cells, addition of glucose does not cause large changes in ATP levels and the period of decreased metabolic activity is eliminated. The maximum rates of PRPP synthesis, glycolysis, and adenine incorporation are greater in non-preincubated than in preincubated cells. Partial replacement of sodium by potassium ions in the incubation medium causes a prolongation of the period of ATP recovery and of decreased metabolic activity. Possible factors involved in the regulation of the above events are discussed.</description><creator>Gurd, James W.</creator><contributor>Scholefield, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The effects of glucose on the energy metabolism of Novikoff ascites hepatoma cells.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f908t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462842r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mj61k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rabbit and human lymphocytes were studied for their capacity to respond with blastogenesis and mitosis to various stimuli in vitro. The circulating lymphocytes of two agammaglobulinemic subjects responded to PRA but not to anti-immunoglobulin serum. The cells of all the rabbit lymphoid organs tested (thymus, bone marrow, sacculus rotundus, appendix, lymph node and blood) responded to stimulation with PRA and mitomycin-C inactivated leucocytes. Only the thymocytes failed to respond to stimulation with goat-anti-rabbit immunoglobulin serum (GARIG). They also adsorbed much less GARIG-I125. Pretreatment of normal rabbit lymphocytes with GARIG and complement resulted in a loss of responsiveness to GARIG but not to PRA. Immune rabbit cells pretreated with GARIG could not respond to stimulation with antigen in vitro nor could they synthesize antibodies following their transfer into irradiated recipients. There was an additive effect in vitro between PRA and antigen or PRA and GARIG.</description><creator>Daguillard, Fritz.</creator><contributor>Richter, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The functional heterogeneity of the lymphocyte.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t524s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mj61k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236528x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The uptake of ascorbic acid in the rat adrenal gland in vitro is dependent on aerobic conditions, Ca++, K+ and Na+ ions. There is a correlation between endogenous adrenal ascorbic acid levels and the ability of the glands to transport ascorbic acid -I-14 C in vitro in a variety of species. The transport system is specific for L-ascorbic acid. ACTH, cyclic AMP, and a number of corticosteroids inhibit ascorbic acid uptake but do not alter a variety of other transport systems. ACTH, and cyclic AMP inhibition of ascorbate transport parallels the stimulation of steroidogenesis in response to these agents. ACTH and cyclic AMP inhibition of ascorbate transport is dependent on protein synthesis but not on RNA synthesis. Inhibition by corticosteroids is not dependent on protein or RNA synthesis, indicating that the corticosteroids produced in response to ACTH and cyclic AMP are responsible for the observed inhibition of ascorbic acid transport. Ascorbic acid -I-14 C is actively transported in the rat pituitary gland in vitro. The transport is not dependent on prote in or RNA synthesis, and is not affected by cyclic AMP or corticosteroids.</description><creator>Clayman, Michael.</creator><contributor>Johnstone, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Ascorbic acid transport and steroidogenesis in the rat adrenal gland 'in vitro'.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp081.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236528x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb69x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The metabolism of labelled cholesterol (Chol) was studied in homogenized (human, rat) and mitochondrial (rat) adrenal preparations in presence and absence of metopirone. Comparable incubations were conducted with labelled 20alpha-OH-chol, pregnenolone (delta5p) , progesterone (delta4p) and ll-deoxycorticosterone (DOC). Results indicated that in addition to the interference with 11beta-18- (and probably 19-) hydroxylases, metapirone inhibits the cleavage of Chol. Inhibition was net relieved by an excess of NADP plus G6P but was dose re1ated: 17% (2.5 x 10-5 M) to 80% (1 x 10-3 M). [...]</description><creator>Cheng, Su C.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>'In vitro' biosynthesis of corticosteroids from radiocholesterol and the effects of metopirone on various enzymatic reactions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w10k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb69x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Investigative Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547v60x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An auditory naming test consisting of meaningful nonverbal sounds and a visual naming test consisting of pictures illustrating these sounds were presented to 118 children between 3-1/2 and 16 years of age. Auditory naming improved rapidly until the age of 8, with only slight improvement occurring thereafter. At all ages, auditory naming was poorer than visual naming. It was concluded that nonverbal visual stimuli may be more salient than nonverbal auditory stimuli in the perceptual world of children, as a result of more experience and more opportunities for perceptual-motor interaction with visual stimuli. Auditory naming was also assessed in blind children and found to be significantly inferior to that of control subjects, suggesting that the superiority of visual naming in seeing children cannot be attributed to factors of attention or set. Results were interpreted with respect to the concept of modality dominance, and related to two important types of human communication disorders, childhood dyslexia, and aphasia.</description><description>Un test de dénomination auditive composé de sons nonverbaux significatifs et un test de dénomination visuelle composé d'images correspondant aux sons, furent présentés aux ll8 enfants la âgés entre 3-1/2 et 16 ans. L'habilité de nommer les sons nonverbaux se développe rapidement jusqu' à l'âge de 8 ans avec seulment une légère améloriation après cet âge. [...]</description><creator>Bartholoméus, Bonnie.</creator><contributor>Doehring, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Human Communications Disorders.</subject><title>Development of auditory naming behaviour.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w84m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547v60x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860994j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Normal rabbit bone marrow cells, but not cells of the other normal lymphoid organs could transfer immunocompetence to lethally irradiated or tolerant allogeneic recipients. However, bone marrow cells of rabbits immunized 24 hours previously could not transfer immunocompetence with respect to the immunizing antigen. The bone marrow immunocompetent cell was identified as the antigen reactive cell (ARC) and not the antibody forming cell (AFC) by the use of allotypic markers. The ARC which were morphologically small lymphocytes, could be isolated by passage of the normal bone marrow cells through an antigen-sensitized glass bead column. Immunocompetence following irradiation correlated with the reappearance of the bone marrow ARC. Furthermore, the ARC activity could be initiated by incubation of the cells with the antigen in vitro. The results suggest that rabbit bone marrow is the main source of ARC and that they migrate out of the bone marrow following immunization.</description><creator>Abdou, Nabih I.</creator><contributor>Richter, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The role of the bone marrow in the immune response.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cx220.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860994j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429d477</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the foreign policy images of two Indian decision-makers, Jawaharlal Nehru and V.K. Krishna Menon, from 1948 to 1962. It reviews the general foreign policy literature and outlines a research framework for foreign policy analysis. The literature on elite images is also explored and several hypotheses are selected for testing. The quantitative method of content analysis is employed in the research design. The components of the foreign policy images of Nehru and Menon are analysed quantitatively. The salient actors, levels of the international system, domestic variables, symbols, values and issues are examined and patterns of intensity and association are explored. The views of the world of Nehru and Menon are systematically compared and contrasted. Hypotheses from the literature are tested and several new hypotheses are generated from the data. Methodological techniques are evaluated and guidelines for further research are suggested.</description><creator>Stein, Janice G.</creator><contributor>Brecher, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Economics and Political Science.</subject><title>Elite images and foreign policy Nehru, Menon and India's policies.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n06w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429d477</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics and Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wq862</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The optimal requirement for Na+ for the uptake of alpha-aminoisobutyric acid (AIB) was found to be quantitatively similar to the requirement for Na+ to prevent the release of AIB from the preloaded cells of marine pseudomonad B-16 and Photobacterium fischeri. The uptake required Na+ specifically whereas the retention could be partially effected by other cations. At optimal Na+, the cells of B-16 could maintain an accumulated intracellular AIB level of 0.6 M. Omission of Na+ from the medium caused a rapid leakage of intracellular AIB, fo1lowed by a slower decrease in cell viability. [...]</description><creator>Wong, Paul T.</creator><contributor>MacLeod, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Studies on the mechanism of Na+-dependent transport in marine bacteria.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qm94r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wq862</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634679f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A multidisciplinary study of the vascular wall aimed at a better insight into the mechanism of increased peripheral resistance has been designed. This thesis is concerned with the establishment of sensitive techniques needed for the determination in the vascular wall of norepinephrine, water, sodium, potassium, magnesium, calcium and renin contents. The study of the normal distribution of norepinephrine and renin has pointed out a vascular territory particular in its markedly high content compared with any other territory studied. The importance of this finding for explaining the important hemodynamic role of the splanchnic territory has been emphasized. In congestive heart failure a significant increase in the norepinephrine content of the branches of superior mesenteric veins was found. Simultaneous determination of several parameters was made in the investigation of anesthesia, adrenalectomy and hemorrhage effects, and in the study of reserpine, angiotensin and hydralazine mechanism of action. An experimental hypertension on rat disclosed an interesting sequence of cation changes in the vascular beds submitted to hypertensive and to hypotensive influence.</description><creator>Simard, Sylvain.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on norepinephrine and cation content of the vascular wall and some observations on renin content.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pd685.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634679f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Investigative Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w777v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>These experiments with anti-lymphocyte serum were carried out in the search for a potent, relatively non-toxic agent for prolonging survival of renal allografts in bilaterally nephrectomized dogs. Antisera with immunosuppressive activity and also toxic side effects were produced by injecting a horse with a homogenate of either canine lymph node or thymus. Sera drawn at intervals between five and fifty-six days had immunosuppressive effects. Sera drawn later in the course of immunization had pronounced acute toxic effects. The immunosuppressive activity of a toxic serum was retained after absorption with canine liver homogenate to remove toxicity. Prolonged storage of an immunosuppressive serum at - 20°C resulted in loss of immunosuppressive activity with retention of titres of lymphocyte agglutinins. A given amount of serum was considerably more effective when given pre-operatively rather than post-operatively. Permanent survival occurred in three dogs treated with a limited course of ALS. There was no correlation between prolongation of survival and lymphopenia or lymphoid depletion.</description><creator>Shanfield, Isidore.</creator><contributor>MacLean, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Anti-lymphocyte serum-effect of canine renal allograft survival.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q53b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w777v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494c39z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nuclear spectra of A = 14, 18, 38, 42, 206 and 208 nuclei were calculated using free reaction matrices as effective interactions and Woods-Saxon single-particle wavefunctions. The calculations show that, in most of the cases considered, realistic single-particle wavefunctions must be used in the determination of realistic effective interaction matrix elements. The results are especially interesting in the A = 18 nuclei where it is found that the use of realistic single-particle wavefunctions produce changes in spectra comparable to those introduced by corepolarization. In heavier nuclei it appears that a simple harmonie oscillator calculation is out of the question at least for states involving both neutrons and protons. Wavefunctions deduced for a single value of the oscillator parameter hw cannot adequate1y describe the states in nuclei such as Pb 206 and Pb 210 possessing a large neutron excess.</description><creator>Scott, C. Keith.</creator><contributor>Kahana, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Nuclear spectra calculations using realistic interactions and realistic single-particle wavefunctions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w7784.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c39z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:028710135</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aqueous adsorption of sodium oleate on copper and iron precipitates, commonly termed cupric and ferric hydroxide, was investigated over a pH range of 8.5 to 12.5. The adsorption isotherms can be described by a Freundlich type equation, r = kCon where n ranged from 1.19 to 3.92 at low oleate concentrations and 0.28 to 0.65 at high concentrations. Adsorption decreases with increasing pH, and iron does not adsorb above pH Il.5. At low oleate concentrations adsorption is chemisorption and the adsorbed species have been interpreted as, cupric hydroxy mono-oleate and ferric hydroxy di-oleate. At high concentrations sodium oleate physically adsorbs in reverse orientation to form a hydrophilic surface. Maximum flotation recovery is obtained at oleate concentrations below that required for the completion of the chemisorbed layer. Adsorption of the second layer seriously depresses flotation.</description><creator>Paterson, John G.</creator><contributor>Salman, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Metallurgical Engineering.</subject><title>The adsorption of sodium oleate on metal hydroxides.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bm40k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/028710135</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92gb366</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies were made of in vitro cytotoxicity of human serum on rat bone marrow and spleen cells (xenogeneic system) as well as human lymphocytes (allogeneic system). Cytotoxicity was measured by trypan blue staining and C14-uridine incorporation. Human serum donors were classified into two categories: (a) those without previous exposure to human tissue antigens and (b) those possibly presensitized by means of pregnancy, blood transfusion, hemodialysis or renal allograft. All sera from the first group showed natural xenogeneic cytotoxicity but no allogeneic lymphocytotoxicity. Among sera from the second group, some exerted excessive xenogeneic cytotoxicity (heterophile phenomenon) as well as allogeneic lymphocytotoxicity. Allogeneic lymphocytotoxic antibodies present in renal allograft recipients were found extremely detrimental to grafts when a crossmatch with donor's lymphocytes was positive, but seemed to reveal a high degree of histocompatibility when the test was negative. A panel of allogeneic lymphocytotoxic sera originated from multiparous females was found re1iable in determining individual lymphocyte alloantigen profiles.</description><creator>Oh, Jung H.</creator><contributor>Dossetor, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Allogeneic and xenogeneic cytotoxic antibodies in man.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s3331.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb366</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff93m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clinical and histological findings are presented showing that acute and subacute nephritis can be produced in rabbits following injection of 120 mg of Lancefield Group A, type 12 streptococcal 60-75 percent polypeptides. Administration of booster injections appears to advance the disease to the chronic stage. Fractionation studies conducted on type 12, 60-75 percent nephrotoxic polypeptides using continuous flow and horizontal electrophoretic techniques are also presented. Injections of as little as 2.5 mg per rabbit of fractionated polypeptides caused both hypertension and kidney lesions ranging from acute to subacute nephritis. A method is presented utilizing ultraviolet spectrophotometry to measure the concentration of polypeptides fractionated by continuous flow and horizontal electrophoresis by extrapolation from density-concentration curves of type 12, 60-75 percent polypeptides.</description><creator>Micklea, George D.</creator><contributor>Matheson, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Further studies on streptococcal nephrotoxin.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q7324.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff93m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wt53k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pathways of steroid biosynthesis have been explored in interrenals from the American bullfrog (Rana catesbeiana) and the painted turtle (Chrysemys picta picta). In 'in vitro' studies by both interrenals: 1) acetate-l-l4C is not incorporated into cholesterol or corticosteroids, 2) cholesterol-4-l4c is metabolized into C2l steroids. The cleavage mechanism is NADPH dependent and mitochondrial-bound, 3) delta-5-pregnenolone-4-l4c is converted into delta-4-3keto metabolites. This reaction is effected by all subcellular fractions. [...]</description><creator>Mehdi, Afzal Z.</creator><contributor>Carballeira, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>'In vitro' corticosteroid biosynthesis by frog and turtle interrenals.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b911c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt53k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Investigative Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm41v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The chronic administration of non-toxic doses of thyroxine to rats bearing established mammary tumors resulted in significant regression of tumor growth. Histologically tumor regression resulted from massive cell autolysis, while other cells persisted with the formation of irregular acinar spaces containing a milk-like fiuid histochemically similar to normal rat milk. Electron microscopy revealed structural differentiation in these tumor cells similar to that found in lactating breast cells, but the cellular secretory mechanism and cytomorphological characteristics of this tumor milk were unlike that of a normal lactating rat breast. Furthermore, mammary tumor mitochondria of the thyroxine treated host revealed both structural and functional abnormalities. Although tumor regression occurred despite the endocrine milieu in a hyperthyroid rat favouring tumor growth, it was concluded that thyroid hormone acts directly on the tumor mitochondria to induce a form of wasteful oxidative metabolism, thereby interfering with the energy requirements of the mammary tumor.</description><creator>Mitmaker, Benjamin.</creator><contributor>Kalant, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Effects of throxine on endocrine dependent mammary tumors in rats.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773z705.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm41v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg98s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study has been made of the mechanism of action of 8-azaguanine and the possible use of this analogue, together with other inhibitors of protein biosynthesis in the study of cellular controls operating through polyribosomes. The results indicate that 8-azaguanine causes a preferential breakdown in vivo of the membrane-free polyribosomes in normal, regenerating and neoplastic rat liver to inactive monomers and dimers, with a concomitant inhibition of protein biosynthesis. 8-Azaguanine-2-C14 is incorporated into components of the polyribosomes; although the transport of ribosomes to the cytoplasm is inhibited, the synthesis of nuclear RNA does not appear to be significantly inhibited. The kinetics of incorporation of 8-azaguanine into nucleotides and into RNA support the theory that 8-azaguanine acts through the formation of defective messenger RNA. The free and membrane-bound polyribosomes are equally active in vivo. Most of the polyribosomes in Hepatoma 7800 appear to be functional in vivo.</description><creator>Kwan, Sau-Wah.</creator><contributor>Webb, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Mechanism of action of azaguanine and use of inhibitors of protein biosynthesis in the study of cellular controls.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bp748.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg98s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322h68h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An ultramicro radioassay based on the principle of competitive protein-binding was adapted for use in the determination of plasma corticosterone and urinary corticosteroids of high leukemia AKR and low-leukemia C57 mice. Tests of precision, accuracy, specificity and of stimulation with ACTH revealed that the technique was suitable for this purpose. Mice of both sexes, a wide range of ages, healthy or sick with spontaneous lymphatic leukemia in its incipient or advanced stages or ill with a transplanted lymphatic leukemia, or sick with diseases other than leukemia were investigated. One series of animals was investigated under conditions not involving stimulation by exogenous ACTH while another was studied before and after stimulation by the hormone. [...]</description><creator>Khalid, Rauf A.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Adrenal cortical function in murine leukemia.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zk72b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322h68h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Investigative Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vt972</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Airway resistance was partitioned in lungs obtained at autopsy. In adult lungs the bronchi accounted for the bulk of the airway resistance but in children below 5 years the contribution of the bronchioles rose sharply. Additional studies suggested that the bronchioles develop at a slower rate than the parenchymal surface of the lung and that this anatomic fact causes bronchiolitis to be more serious in young children than adults. Organic disease of the small airways was the major cause of airway obstruction in emphysematous lungs and collateral pathways were important in ventilating the parenchyma beyond this obstruction. The centrilobular emphysematous spaces were found to have a decreased compliance and their anatomy suggested that they may be ventilated both from the atmosphere and collaterally from surrounding parenchyma. Regional lung volumes and the pleural pressure. gradient were estimated in dogs using measurements of lung density and these data are used to discuss the support of the lungs within the thorax.</description><creator>Hogg, James C.</creator><contributor>Macklem, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Thurlbeck, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Flow and ventilation distribution in the lung.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010t13h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vt972</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n1621</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Monteregian petrographic province of southern Quebec consists of eleven alkalic intrusive stocks, and associated dikes and sills. The latter consist of lamprophyres (camptonite, fourchite, alnoite), leucocratic dikes (bostonite, tinguaite, ijolite) and mesocratic dikes of intermediate composition. The lamprophyres are distributed in three zones bounded by faults: an eastern camptonite zone, a central fourchite zone, and a western alnoite zone. The westward transition represents chemically a progressive decrease in Si02, Al203, Ti02 and total Fe, and a progressive increase in MgO, CaO, K20/Na20 and volatiles content of the respective lamprophyres, and is interpreted as generation of separate magma batches at increasingly greater depths within the upper mantle westward. [...]</description><creator>Hodgson, Christopher J.</creator><contributor>Philpotts, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Monteregian dike rocks.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq92z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n1621</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f9093</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of upright posture and sodium restriction on Plasma Renin Activity (PRA) were studied in 60 patients with essential hypertension. 23% had a suppressed PRA. Two of these patients were not cured by adrenalectomy. The incidence of adrenocortical adenomas, nodules and hyperplasia in 2425 autopsied patients further supported the rare occurrence (7%) of primary aldosteronism. [...]</description><creator>Granger, Pierre.</creator><contributor>Genest, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on the renin angiotensin system in human and dog with special reference to primary aldosteronism and heart failure.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jp751.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f9093</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Investigative Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429d48h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:26:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Enzyme changes in benign and malignant prostatic tissues were studied in an attempt to introduce new criteria of malignancy. Total lactate dehydrogenase activity was not significantly different between benign and malignant prostatic tissues. Lactate dehydrogenase isoenzyme pattern showed remarkable differences. The ratio of L.D.R.v/L.D.R.I &gt; l was considered to be suggestive of malignancy and the results were analyzed according to this index. A high index was detected in 77.6% of malignant tissues and a low index in 86.1% of benign tissues. The change was not localized to the malignant focus but was generalized within the gland harbouring a focus of malignancy. This was confirmed in 80% of malignant cases on multiple specimen analysis. [...]</description><creator>ElHilali, Mostafa M.</creator><contributor>Sherwin, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Enzymatic changes in prostatic carcinoma.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q733d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429d48h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10300</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>