<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:56:38Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wg47g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction. Human papillomavirus (HPV) has been detected with  varying frequency in oral cancers and in normal oral tissues. The main objective of  the present study was to examine the association between HPV infection and risk of  developing oral cancer. Methodology. This investigation, as a component of an  international multi-centre study coordinated by the IARC, followed a hospital-based  case-control design. Cases consisted of newly diagnosed patients with primary  squamous cell carcinoma of the oral cavity, including mouth and oropharynx. Controls  were frequency matched to cases by sex, age, and hospital. All subjects were  interviewed to elicit detail information on known and putative risk  factors. Oral exfoliated cells were collected from all subjects for  detection of HPV DNA using the PGMY09/11 PCR protocol. Antibodies against HPV 16,  18, and 31 capsids were detected in patients' plasma using an immunoassay technique.  Logistic regression was used for estimation of odds ratios (ORs) and 95% confidence  intervals (CI) of oral cancer for HPV and other candidate risk  factors. Results. A total of 72 cases and 129 controls were recruited.  HPV DNA was detected in 19% of cases (14 out of 72), and in 5% of controls (6 out of  129). Analysis for cancers related to Waldeyer's ring (palatine tonsil and base of  tongue) showed that the OR of disease for detection of high risk HPV types was 19.32  (95%CI:2.3--159.5), after adjustment for socio-demographic characteristics, tobacco  and alcohol consumption. The adjusted OR of disease for HPV 16 seropositivity was  31.51 (95%CI:4.5--219.7). Analysis for non tonsillar oral cancers showed that the OR  for detection of high risk HPV DNA in oral cells and for seropositivity were 2.14  (95%CI:0.4--13.0) and 3.16 (95%CI:0.8--13.0), respectively. Discussion. The results from this study provide evidence  supporting a strong association between HPV infection and cancers of the oropharynx,  especially those arising from Waldeyer's ring. On the other hand, the association  with non tonsillar oral cancers was of much lower magnitude. The biological evidence  establishing a firm etiologic link remains to be established for the latter  subsites, whereas the association between HPV and Waldeyer's ring carcinomas is  consistent with a causal link.</description><creator>Pintos Vega, Luis Javier</creator><contributor>Franco, Eduardo L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Human papillomavirus infection and oral cancer : a case-control study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795821g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wg47g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n166t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stable mine backfill is necessary for safe working conditions,  maximum ore recovery and underground and surface stability. Due to the fact that  cement costs can be a significant part of the operating costs in large underground  mines, the consumption of cement (or binder) should be minimized. Therefore,  developing a safe and economical backfilling method for the large underground mining  operations is very significant. In this thesis, first laboratory tests and in-situ tests are  implemented to determine backfill material properties and backfill stress  distribution. The laboratory tests include high sulphide paste fill property tests  and layered backfill tests. Second, a backfill finite element model is presented and  it is validated by the results of laboratory tests and in-situ tests. Finally, by  using this model, the following subjects are studied, (1) backfill stress  distribution; (2) influences of backfill material properties and dimensions on  backfill stability; (3) stress distribution of layered backfill; (4) optimum layered  backfill. The results show that: (a) The variation of backfill material properties  is quite large, the compressive strength of the layered backfill model is much  higher than that of the non-layered backfill model, and the backfill vertical stress  is much less than that anticipated by the formula, rhogH; (b) During the process of  adjacent pillar recovery, the minor principal stress inside a backfill is tensile,  and this tensile principal stress causes backfill failure and spalling near the  exposed surfaces. The spalling size progressively increases with the height of the  exposed surface, and a sliding zone creates and leads to backfill collapse; (c)  Optimum backfill material should be high elastic modulus, high Poisson's ratio and  low density. Optimum backfill size should be large depth and small width; (d) For  layered backfill, no sliding zone occurs during the process of adjacent pillar  recovery, so layered backfill can improve backfill stability. The optimum layered  backfill should consist of strong layers distributed evenly with thicknesses of  1~2m and weak layers 2~2.5 times the thickness of the strong layers.  This can save binder consumption by about 11%.</description><creator>Zhu, Zheming, 1965-</creator><contributor>Mitri, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hassani, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Ouellet, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Analysis of mine backfill behaviour and stability</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf42c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n166t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zb58w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this ethnographic inquiry, I examine how a selected group of  Chinese immigrant children in Montreal, Quebec negotiate literacy practices in three  languages, Chinese, English and French. I collected data between 1998--2002 through  participant observations in different socio-cultural-linguistic contexts that  include a Chinese Heritage Language school and the students' home domains. Data  sources also include interviews, classroom discourses, field-notes and the students'  written texts in the three languages. I draw on Vygotskian socio-cultural theory as  an overarching framework to conceptualize my understanding of Chinese immigrant  children's triliterate actions. I use Wertsch's concept of "mediational  means", Bakhtin's notions of "utterance, voice, dialogicality" and  Ivanic's theory of "writing and identity" to present portraits that  illustrate the complex relationships among the children's contexts, agency, cultural  positionings and uses of literacy as mediational means. I examine the children's  perceptions of their multiple school experiences, their school and language  affiliations and identity. Lightfoot's concept of "portraiture" is a  useful methodology to illustrate how multilingual children present and negotiate  their life worlds in the three languages and spaces---from home to school and from  heritage language school to formal public school. The reflective understandings that  emerge from this inquiry are integrated within the contexts of the historical role  of Confucianism and the characteristics of the written Chinese language. The results  of my inquiry suggest that multilingual children's literate actions are interwoven  with issues of agency, access, choice, identity, power and status in different  contexts. Results further indicate that maintenance of a heritage language in its  written form is possible when children receive appropriate parental support and  guidance and have access to literacy materials. The development of multili</description><creator>Curdt-Christiansen, Xiao Lan</creator><contributor>Maguire, Mary H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Chinese Canadians -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Multilingualism in children -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Growing up in three languages : triliteracy practices of Chinese immigrant children in Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj88v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb58w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jr71s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the process of endochondral bone formation, Indian  Hedgehog (Ihh), a member of the hedgehog (Hh) family of secreted morphogens, and  parathyroid hormone-related peptide (PTHrP) play key roles in the regulation of  cartilage cell (chondrocyte) differentiation. Previous studies have established that  Ihh coordinates chondrocyte differentiation indirectly by activating PTHrP  expression, which in turn delays their transition to the terminal hypertrophic  state. In the present study, using an in vitro system of cultured CFK-2 chondrocytic  cells, we have explored the possibility that Ihh may also influence chondrocytic  differentiation directly and investigated how this process is modulated by PTHrP,  Engrailed-1 (En-1), and heparan sulfate glycosaminoglycans (HS-GAG). We show that  Ihh signaling enhances, rather than inhibits, expression of markers of chondrocytic  differentiation and that an inactivating missense mutation mapping to its  NH2-terminal domain (N-IhhW160G) abolishes this capacity. Moreover, activation of  protein kinase A (PKA) by PTHrP-signaling also perturbs Ihh-mediated  differentiation. Indicative of a novel regulatory mechanism, Ihh in turn  downregulates PKA activity downstream of the PTH/PTHrP-receptor (PTH1R). En-1,  detected in prehypertrophic growth plate chondrocytes in situ, influences  chondrocytic differentiation and impedes Hh-signaling in vitro, suggesting a novel  role for this protein in cartilage development. Finally, we show that HS-GAGS are  required for proper mediation of Hh-signaling and thus also participate in  modulating chondrocytic differentiation. Taken together, this study provides  experimental evidence that Ihh harbors the capacity to directly induce rather than  impede chondrogenic differentiation, and that this function is modulated by the  cellular actions of PTHrP, En-1, and HS-GAG.</description><creator>Deckelbaum, Ron Avi</creator><contributor>Goltzman, David (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Karaplis, Andrew C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Regulation of chondrocyte differentiation by Indian hedgehog : modulation by parathyroid hormone-related peptide, engrailed-1, and heparan sulfate glycosaminoglycans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hq13c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr71s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vb84s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The communicative competence of bilingual children involves a  large array of skills---they must not only acquire the full range of communication  skills of monolinguals but also learn when, how and with whom to use each language.  This dissertation features three studies on the communication skills of bilingual  children (French-English bilinguals aged 2.5 and 3 years from the Montreal area).  Studies 1 and 2 explored these children's ability to make appropriate language  choices by studying their responsiveness to two types of cues: The first study  investigated whether children's language choice is influenced by their  interlocutor's code-mixing; the second study examined whether children change their  language in response to their interlocutor's requests for clarification following  the children's use of the inappropriate language. The children demonstrated that  they were capable of making on-line adjustments in their language choice in response  to both types of cues, thereby showing that sensitivity to cues for language change  is part of bilingual children's communicative competence from a young age. Study 3  compared bilingual and monolingual children's responses to requests for  clarification following breakdowns in communication due to problematic aspects of  their utterances such as speaking too softly or mispronouncing words. The findings  revealed no significant differences between the bilingual and monolingual children's  responses and suggest that the acquisition of conversational repair skills is not  influenced by the simultaneous acquisition of two languages. Together, these three  studies contribute to the understanding of the skills underlying children's ability  to make appropriate language choices and suggest that the unique demands of  bilingual interpersonal communication do not interfere with the acquisition of more  general communication skills.</description><creator>Comeau, Liane</creator><contributor>Genesee, Fred (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Bilingualism in children.</subject><subject>Communicative competence in children.</subject><subject>Language acquisition</subject><title>The communicative competence of young French-English bilingual children /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f70j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb84s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580n09f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A phantom-embedded extrapolation chamber (PEEC) made of Solid  Water(TM) was used for studying the buildup region of megavoltage radiation beams.  We investigated the polarity effect produced in the PEEC and found that radiation  induced currents, called the Compton current, were the dominant cause of the  polarity effect in the PEEC. In the dose build-up region of megavoltage photon  beams, the collecting electrode is the primary Compton current source and the  magnitude of the current depends on the measurement depth, field size, and photon  beam quality. The connecting cable acts as a secondary Compton current source that  produces a very small Compton current which depends on the field size and the photon  beam quality, becoming the dominant source when the PEEC is placed at depths greater  than the depth of maximum dose. A study of the dose build-up region of megavoltage  photon beams showed that the percentage depth ionizations obtained from measurements  are higher than the percentage depth doses obtained with Monte Carlo (MC)  techniques. To validate the MC-calculated percentage depth doses, the design of the  PEEC was incorporated in the simulations. While the MC-calculated and measured  percentage depth ionizations in the dose build-up region agreed with one another for  the 6 MV, a non-negligible difference is observed for the 18 MV x-ray beam. A number  of experiments and theoretical studies of various possible effects which could be  the source of this discrepancy is investigated. We show that the contribution of  contaminating neutrons and protons to the doses in the 18 MV x-ray beam is  negligible. Moreover, the MC calculations using the XCOM photon cross sections  database and the NIST bremsstrahlung differential cross sections do not explain the  discrepancy between the MC calculations and measurement in the dose build-up region  for the 18 MV and this discrepancy is yet to be further  investigated.</description><creator>Abdel-Rahman, Wamied</creator><contributor>Podgorsak, Ervin B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>A study of the build-up region megavoltage radiation beams /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tm47v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n09f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bc07m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to increase vehicle fuel efficiency while improving  safety and performance and maintaining affordability, the global steel industry has  initiated the use of advanced high strength steels that ultimately result in the  design of stronger, lighter and more energy efficient vehicles. Tubular steel  columns are extensively used in the automotive body structure due to their inherent  capacity to absorb energy on impact. Hence, the objective of this research work is  to study the crashworthiness performance of columns made from advanced high strength  steels. To conduct this study, computational simulations are developed  to accurately assess the influence exerted in the crush response of the columns by  different types of materials as well as geometrical characteristics of the  thin-walled structural sections. Furthermore, it is well known that spot-welding is the primary  method of joining in the ground vehicle industry. Therefore, the strength of the  spot weld under impact is extremely important to the safety design and durability of  automobiles. Thus, in this project such an essential factor is addressed by  developing a reliable and practical finite element model to predict the dynamic  failure of spot-welds in the sheet metal structures. It is shown that numerical results of the developed robust  finite element model give fairly good agreement with experimental data in terms of  collapse profile, deformed column shape, final crush length, and impact peak  force. Throughout the investigation, the finite element model permits  the study of several structural and material variables that can be validated by a  moderate set of destructive tests. Moreover, the current finite element crash model  and the findings in this work can eventually be used to improve the crashworthiness  efficiency of steel column specimens and to help meet society's demands for  affordable, fuel efficient, environmentally responsible, and safe  vehicles.</description><creator>Portillo Martínez, Oscar</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Automotive.</subject><title>Impact modeling of spot-welded columns fabricated with advanced high strength steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d0231.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc07m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p770d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The deregulation movement affecting the industrialized countries  forced the governments to refocus their prescribed standards. In some jurisdictions,  the difficulty raised by this practice resulted in the establishment, with the  industry, of a negotiation plan for environmental agreements. In this document, we  will explore the problematic of the characterization in law of environmental  agreements reached by the administration and the industry. Furthermore, we will  evaluate the pros and cons of using this system in the public  administration. The subject of this research is mainly based on the depollution  attestation adopted in 1988 by the Assemblee Nationale du Quebec to oversee  industrial wastes. In effect since 1993, the implementation of this authorization  plan has been affected by the various discussions that took place between the pulp  and paper industry and the ministere de l'Environnement (MENV). The Protocole  d'entente sur la mise en oeuvre des attestations d'assainissement, negociated  between the MENV and the Quebec Forest Industries Association in 2000, initiated the  licensing procedure of the first depollution attestations to the paper manufacturers  targeted by section IV.2 of the Quebec Environment Quality Act. Qualified as a  gentlemen's agreement, we will define the obligations of all the parties involved  according to the terms of this Memorandum of Understanding. In closing, we will  analyze the operating licence systems based upon the integrated approach of the  European Union and the United States of America. We will therefore be able to  compare the openness to consensus with the industrial sectors of those plans with  that of the depollution attestation.</description><creator>DesMarchais, Pierre-Olivier</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Pollution -- Law and legislation -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Deregulation.</subject><subject>Pollution -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>Les attestations d'assainissement au Québec : des ententes environnementales avantageuses pour les industries ou l'environnement?</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j615c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p770d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j1484</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Winter storms affect all Canadians and many of their impacts are  associated with precipitation. This precipitation can occur as rain, snow, freezing  rain or ice pellets. Some research has been conducted on all of these types of  precipitation but the least attention has been paid to ice pellets. The atmospheric  environment conducive to ice pellets is known in general but the detailed nature of  the actual particles is not. To begin to address this issue, a high resolution digital camera  was used to photograph ice pellets for 4 hours during a winter storm at Mirabel,  Quebec in November 2003. A total of 1023 images were analyzed to determine the  morphology, shapes, and size distributions of the ice pellets. Some ice pellets were  opaque, others were clear, and some had bands of varying opacity. At most, 7% of the  particles were spherical. Many particles exhibited bulges, fractures, and spicules.  The occurrence of such features suggests that much or all of the initial freezing  occurred on the surface as opposed to the drop interior. Approximately 9% of the  particles observed were aggregates of 2-5 smaller particles. The ice pellets ranged  up to 5 mm in diameter for aggregate particles and up to 3 mm in diameter for  individual particles. The average diameter of all particles was 1 mm. A range of  different particle characteristics were observed to be occurring simultaneously  throughout the storm. Collectively, such observations as well as process model  results imply that different freezing mechanisms were occurring simultaneously, and  that collisions between semi-frozen ice pellets must have been occurring to produce  aggregates.</description><creator>Gibson, Steven R.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Atmospheric Sciences.</subject><title>Detailed observations of ice pellets and an analysis of their characteristics and formation mechanisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451j05k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j1484</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v843c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tax competition between tax sovereignties is a fact. We focus  here on the international tax competition. Taxation is one of the tools of  governance that States use to direct their policies. Tax authorities try to diminish  the burden of their taxpayers to improve the national economic and social welfare.  To aim this objective, Governments intensify the competitiveness of the domestic  trade and/or attract foreign investments. Because every States share the same goal,  Governments compete with each other on the tax field. This tax competition is  qualified as beneficial on the one hand, and one the other hand---ever more  often---the adjective used to qualify this competition would be "harmful".  At first, this thesis exposes the situation of tax competition, presenting the  opposing views and the concurring ones. Then, we look at the position of the  Organization of Economic Cooperation and Development and the position of the  European Union on this issue of tax competition. Historic summaries explain the  point of view of these two organizations that are the leaders in the fight against  the "harmful" tax competition. Finally, we give subjective ideas to  re-think tax competition in a fair way.</description><creator>Delechat, Aude Simonne Emilie</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Competition.</subject><subject>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development</subject><subject>Intergovernmental tax relations -- European Union countries</subject><subject>Taxation -- Law and legislation -- European Union countries</subject><subject>Intergovernmental tax relations</subject><subject>Taxation -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Competition -- European Union countries.</subject><title>Une concurrence fiscale loyale (un compte de fée?) /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nb730.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v843c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rt90c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is standard practice in radiation therapy to have two  independent calculations for the number of monitor units used in patient treatment  plans. The relationship between monitor units and absorbed dose to water is  sophisticated for MLC-based IMRT. Verification measurements of absorbed dose to  water with ionization chambers in MLC-based IMRT fields remains uncertain and the  accuracy of computer modeling is limited by the physics assumptions used. In this  thesis, point dose measurements from three cylindrical ionization chambers of  different collecting volumes are evaluated against the CORVUS (NOMOS Corporation,  Cranberry, PA) finite-size pencil beam algorithm and the PEREGRINE (NOMOS  Corporation, Cranberry, PA) Monte Carlo calculation engine. After establishing the  characteristics of the chambers and treatment planning system under various beam  geometries, dynamic and step and shoot MLC deliveries were evaluated. Between  detectors, the smallest volume chamber measured the greatest dose. Compared to  measurements, CORVUS and PEREGRINE both underestimated the dose in IMRT fields by  approximately 5%. On average PEREGRINE yielded better agreement than CORVUS by  2%.</description><creator>Fraser, Danielle J.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Characterizing ionization chamber dosimetry in inverse planned IMRT fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x450d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rt90c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859g17m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sutural distraction osteogenesis (SDO) has been proposed as a  novel approach for cleft palate closure in an effort to avoid the shortcomings of  traditional surgical repair. In this thesis, we present data that confirms that  attempted distraction of the palatomaxillary suture (PMS) achieves cleft closure  preferentially by alveolar arch collapse, and not by intended SDO. To that end, we  have designed a novel custom-fit intraoral splint that successfully prevents  maxillary collapse while facilitating cleft defect approximation via sutural  distraction. Preservation of maxillary dimensions was confirmed via intraoral  measurements and craniometrics. New bone deposition secondary to SDO was quantified  with histomorphometry and microCT, while the effects of distraction on the PMS and  palatal bone were assessed with histology and Dual-energy Xray Absorptiometry (DXA).  In summary, approximation of palatal defects via SDO in a canine model without  maxillary collapse is possible, and may be a promising therapeutic approach for the  repair of cleft palates in human infants.</description><creator>Gilardino, Miroslav S.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Prevention of maxillary collapse during sutural distraction osteogenesis for cleft palate closure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt28q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859g17m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s074n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of this thesis is to present an analysis of  the issue of hate crimes and the manner in which the Canadian criminal justice  system is currently addressing this problem. In doing so, certain inherent concerns  with the current Canadian criminal legislative response to hate crimes will be  highlighted and discussed in detail. More precisely, the introduction of how recent Canadian criminal  legislation has dealt with hate crimes will serve as the basis for the consideration  of two of the main areas of concern as they relate to the effective application of  hate crime legislation, namely the areas of prosecutorial discretion and evidentiary  burden. The detailed survey of these two areas will provide the reader with a  greater understanding of the dynamics behind the factors that currently hinder the  potential effectiveness of hate crime legislation in Canada and will ultimately  allow for the consideration of possible solutions.</description><creator>Climaco dos Santos, Patrick</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Hate crimes -- Canada.</subject><subject>Criminal law -- Canada.</subject><title>The Canadian criminal legislative response to hate crimes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc701.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s074n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17ct41k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Solar Tower Atmospheric Cherenkov Effect Experiment (STACEE)  is a ground based gamma-ray telescope. An array of mirrors allow the detection of an  astronomical Cherenkov light signal in an large background light flux. This  background flux need to be carefully characterized in order to eliminate its  contribution and recover the precious Cherenkov signal. This thesis describes an  instrument to study the photon flux from the night sky in the wavelength region  relevant for the atmospheric Cherenkov telescopes. The integral photon flux as well  as its wavelength dependence can be measured by a baffled tube defining a solid  angle viewed by a photomultiplier tube.</description><creator>Gagnon, Jean-Phillipe, 1980-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><title>An instrument to study the photon flux from the night sky in the wavelength region relevant for atmospheric Cherenkov telescopes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c226.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct41k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nh604</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study proposes to analyze the phenomenon of tax treaty  abuse and the use of tax treaties as tools to avoid or minimize the taxation by  residents doing business in a foreign jurisdiction. This study analyses a particular  strategy using tax treaties known as "treaty shopping." This paper will  argue that treaty shopping constitutes an abuse of the tax treaty regime. However,  this study rejects the traditional arguments against treaty shopping and proposes a  different basis to challenge the legitimacy of this practice and to explain why this  strategy constitutes an improper use of tax treaties.</description><creator>Cruceru, Luiza Brindusa</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Double taxation -- Treaties.</subject><subject>Tax evasion (International law)</subject><title>Treaty shopping and the abuse of income tax conventions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw59v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh604</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wn419</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the 1980s and 1990s, lesbian and gay politics and queer  theory problematized the concept of heteronormativity in order to denounce and call  into question the normative system that privileges and rewards heterosexual  identities and lifestyle. However, conceptualisations of heteronormativity have  failed to destabilize heterosexuality as a norm. In this thesis, I argue that the  concept of heteronormativity is insufficient to subvert the heterosexual system  because it fails to acknowledge the complexity of heterosexual identities. Far from  being uniform and homogenous, heterosexuality is organized as a hierarchical system.  The regulation of heterosexuality is ensured by heterosexual masculine and feminine  gender identities within which the acquisition of privilege and power depend on many  variables and criteria. I argue that the regulatory effects of these discourses are  constantly challenged in practice and that to overcome the limits of the concept of  heteronormativity we have to investigate the practices and arrangements of  heterosexual masculine and feminine gender identities. Moreover, we have to observe  heterosexuality in 'place', specifically in places other than the home or workplace  that do not reproduce the hegemonic heteronormative division between the public and  private spheres. Because, if heteronormative discourses police spaces according to  specific norms, heterosexuality is practised everywhere. To do so, I went to a heterosexual cruising bar in Montreal, Le  Minuit, where the clientele is typically single (divorced or never married) and 39  years old. The discourse of the 'cruising bar' label is significant in two ways.  First, it gives a striking representation of what is perceived and constructed at  the founding moment of heterosexuality: the meeting of women and men. Second, the  discourse of the cruising bar, because of the specific characteristics of its  clientele, illustrates non hegemonic heterosexuality. In Quebec, the discourse  surrounding the label 'cruising bar' brings to mind images of 'losing' heterosexual  identities that are seen as inadequate and lacking. In this sense, the label  'cruising bar' is heteronormative since it also defines, by default, its  opposite---'winning' identities that are privileged. In the face of contemptuous  discourses that devalorize their personal experiences, the patrons of Le Minuit  engage in a process of reconstruction. During the interviews, informants would  incessantly go back and forth between the norms and their own experiences in an  attempt to both conform to and detach themselves from heteronormative discourses. At  the Minuit, informants, night after night, in becoming regulars, distance themselves  from their negative perceptions about 'women in bars' and men in bars, perceptions  they acquire long before going out. In order to understand heterosexuality and end its privileges we  have to know how heteronormativity organises, produces and reproduces itself.  Therefore, it is necessary to observe how heteronormativity organizes gender  identities in everyday life. It is equally important to reveal that there are  multiple perceptions and experiences of the arrangements that define heterosexual  practices, which can simultaneously conform to and confront heteronormative  discourses. To know heterosexuality, we must observe and listen to those who, though  marginalized, are in fact at the heart of heterosexuality; those who through  incessant efforts to achieve norms take part in their maintenance.</description><creator>Lebrun, Aurélie</creator><contributor>Ray, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Interpersonal relations -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Heterosexuality -- Social aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Gender identity -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Bars (Drinking establishments) -- Social aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies</subject><title>Prendre et trouver sa place : discours hétéronormatifs et pratiques hétérosexuelles dans un cruising bar de Montréal</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm20j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wn419</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j38607545</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Masks, actions, words. These three elements provide a starting  point for a study of the devil figure as represented in Middle French saint's plays  (mysteres hagiographiques). An urban, popular art, mediaeval French theatre addressed a  broad public that it was considered useful to both edify---particularly in the case  of the mysteres---and divert. The mysteres represented and interpreted the world. In  this theatre, the devil figures embody Evil and adversity, but also alterity. Placed  in opposition to the saints and the sublime inhabitants of Heaven, they appear  grotesque, crude and carnivalesque. Often the mainspring of the action, they are  essential to the plot of the saint's play; noisy and garrulous, they are a no less  necessary element of the mysteres' discourse on the world (tangible or intangible,  earthly or celestial). The devil, ever ill-intentioned, concocts evil plots and  engages in infernal dialogues---which the mystere presents in order to further its  edifying goals and propagate its unifying and didactic message. This dissertation examines some of the most important aspects,  in terms of the mystere's reception, of the devil figure. The first part, which  deals with diabolical masks, discusses their external features (scenery, costumes,  gestures, disguises) and certain of their linguistic characteristics. The second  part studies the actions of the devils themselves. Their principal activities are  identified and defined, and divided into three broad categories, according to  whether the devils attempt to draw human beings and their activities into their  sphere of influence, or commit evil deeds, or fail in their baleful plans and end up  serving God despite themselves. The third part of the thesis studies diabolical  discourse. More specifically, it analyses the relationship between the speech of  devils (traditionally perceived as deceitful) and truth. Using the concepts of place  and authority, we can read certain instances of this speech as illegitimate, while  an examination of the workings of the discourse of diabolical seduction reveals the  twisted nature which the mysteres attributed to devils. A study of the devil figure thus provides an opportunity to  understand in some measure the role the mysteres hagiographiques played in relation  to the mediaeval public, whose perception of the other (as well as of the same) the  saint's plays represented even as they helped construct it.</description><creator>Dupras, Elyse</creator><contributor>Di Stefano, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Mysteries and miracle-plays, French</subject><subject>Demonology in literature</subject><subject>Devil in literature</subject><title>Rôle des diables dans les mystères hagiographiques français (de la fin du XIVe siècle au début du XVIe siècle)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kq94g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38607545</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g37b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Compilation to bytecode paired with interpretation is often used  as a technique to easily build prototypes for new programming languages. Some  languages, including Java, push this further and use the bytecode layer to isolate  programs from the underlying platform. Current state-of-the-art commercial and  research Java virtual machines implement advanced just-in-time and adaptive  compilation techniques to deliver high-performance execution of Java bytecode. Yet,  experimenting with new features such as adding new bytecodes or redesigning the type  system can be a daunting task within these complex systems, when new features  invalidate assumptions on which the internal dynamic optimizing compiler depends. On  the other hand, simpler existing Java bytecode interpreters, written purely in  high-level languages, deliver poor performance. The main motivation behind this  thesis was to answer the question: How fast can a portable, easily modifiable Java  bytecode interpreter be? In order to address this question, we have designed and  developed the Sable VM research framework, a portable interpreter-based Java virtual  machine written in portable C. In this thesis we introduce innovative techniques for  implementing an efficient, yet portable Java bytecode interpreter. These techniques  address three areas: instruction dispatch, memory management, and synchronization.  Specifically, we show how to implement an inline-threaded engine in the presence of  lazy code preparation, without incurring a high synchronization penalty. We then  introduce a logical partitioning of runtime system memory that simplifies memory  management, and a related sparse interface virtual table design for fast  interface-method invocation. We show how to efficiently compute space-efficient  garbage collection maps for verifiable bytecode. We also present a bidirectional  object layout that simplifies garbage collection. Finally, we introduce an  improvement to thin locks, eliminating busy-wait in case of contention. Our  experiments within the Sable VM framework show that inline-threading [PR98] Java  delivers significant performance improvement over switch and direct-threading, that  sparse interface tables cause no memory loss, and that our map computation algorithm  delivers a very small number of distinct garbage collection maps. Our overall  performance measurements show that, using our techniques, a portable interpreter can  deliver competitive interpretation performance, and even surpass that of a  less-portable state-of-the-art interpreter on some benchmarks.</description><creator>Gagnon, Etienne</creator><contributor>Hendren, Laurie J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A portable research framework for the execution of Java bytecode /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b180p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g37b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xs173</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Wilms' tumor (WT) is an embryonic renal neoplasm which affects 1  in 10,000 children. It has long been considered an excellent model for studying the  relationship of cancer to development. A tumor suppressor gene wt1 , implicated in  predisposition to WT, is known to play an essential role in regulating development  of the kidney and of the genitourinary system. A number of genes involved in growth  regulation and cellular differentiation are modulated by WT1 and a number of  proteins are known to associate with WT1. Some of these proteins are able to alter  the transcriptional properties of WT1 influencing whether WT1 acts as a repressor or  activator. We demonstrate that WT1 represses different classes of  activation domains previously shown to stimulate the initiation and elongation steps  of transcription in vivo. We also showed that WT1 can repress transcription over a  significant distance. Nuclear run-on assays revealed that the mechanism of  repression by WT1 occurs at the level of transcription initiation. We identified a novel WT1-interacting protein named Bone Marrow  Zinc Finger 2 (BMZF2). The BMZF2·gene encodes a potential transcription  factor harboring 18 zinc fingers and mainly expressed in fetal tissues. In vivo and  in vitro pull-down experiments showed that WT1 and BMZF2 associate. This interaction  inhibits WT1-mediated transcriptional activation. Additionally, BMZF2 harbors a  transcriptional repression domain. These results suggest that BMZF2 interferes with  the transactivation properties of WT1. We performed an expression array screen utilizing WT1 inducible  cell lines and found the human vitamin D receptor (VDR) as a major target. Nuclear  run-on experiments, transient transfection assays, deletion mutagenesis,  electrophoretic mobility shift assays, and chromatin immunoprecipitation assays  suggested that the WT1(-KTS) isoforms bind directly to the VDR promoter and activate  VDR gene expression. Our results suggest that the human VDR gene represents a  downstream target of WT1. We discuss the potential regulation of VDR by WT1 in  normal and malignant tissues.</description><creator>Lee, Tae Ho, 1968-</creator><contributor>Pelletier, Jerry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Transcriptional regulation by the Wilms' Tumor suppressor gene (WT1)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x025.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs173</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jr77f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study empirically examined physiological, social, and  emotional variables in order to extend the understanding of the vulnerability-stress  interaction in relation to adolescent problem gambling behaviour. Specifically, the  relationship between coping styles, life stress, depressive symptomatology,  dissociative states, drug and alcohol use, and youth gambling problems were  investigated from the framework of Jacobs' General Theory of Addictions . The  current study also examined several potential protective factors (socioeconomic  status, social support, and adaptive coping styles) that are believed to buffer  against possible negative outcomes associated with youth gambling behaviour.  Students consisted of 2,156 students in grades 7 to 12 (ages 11 to 19) recruited  from various elementary and high schools in Ontario, Canada. Participants completed  a questionnaire regarding gambling activities, social support, dissociation, drug  and alcohol use (GAQ), gambling severity (DSM-IV-MR-J), arousal (AISS), stressful  life events (APES), depressive symptomatology (RADS), and coping styles (CISS).  Socioeconomic status was based on parental level of education and occupation. With  respect to gambling severity as assessed by the DSM-IV-MR-J gambling screen, 2.7% of  adolescents were found to be probable pathological gamblers, and 6.6% at-risk  gamblers. Problem gamblers demonstrated significantly higher scores on measures of  arousal, dissociation, and drug and alcohol use. Emotionally, they demonstrated  increased problems related to depression, suicide ideation and attempts, and  emotion-focused coping. This study expanded on Jacobs' General Theory of Addictions  by investigating several protective factors thought to mediate between different  types of life stressors and potential gambling problems. This study also sought to  identify a set of predictor variables that would increase risk for youth gambling  difficulties, including intensity seeking behaviour,</description><creator>Kaufman, Felicia D.</creator><contributor>Derevensky, Jeffrey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Adjustment (Psychology)</subject><subject>Gamblers.</subject><subject>Stress in adolescence.</subject><subject>Youth.</subject><title>The relationship between gambling activity, the occurrence of life stress, and differential coping styles in an adolescent sample /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk149.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr77f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bh78w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nuclear receptors are transcription factors that regulate gene  expression in response to small lipophilic molecules, including steroid hormones,  thyroid hormone, and vitamin A and D metabolites. RORalpha is an orphan nuclear  receptor that was initially cloned based on its similarities with the retinoic acid  receptor. The term orphan was coined in reference to a nuclear receptor whose  discovery has preceded that of its ligand. Genetic ablation of the Rora gene in mice  leads to severe cerebellar ataxia, known as the staggerer phenotype. RORalpha  regulates a myriad of genes involved in cellular differentiation, including  myogenesis and adipogenesis, as well as various metabolic pathways. Nuclear  receptors control the expression of their target genes by binding to short DNA  sequences, referred to as hormone response elements, as monomers, homodimers, or  heterodimers with the common partner RXR. RORalpha is strictly a monomeric DNA  binding protein, lacking key molecular determinants in its DNA binding domain  essential for cooperative homodimer formation. This orphan receptor is a potent  transcriptional activator, whose activity is dependent on an endogenous ligand and  is controlled by the concerted action of coactivator and corepressor proteins. The  product of the thyroid hormone-regulated mammalian gene hairless (Hr) is a strong  repressor of RORalpha transcriptional activity. In contrast to other  corepressor-nuclear receptor interactions, Hr utilizes LxxLL motifs to mediate  interaction with RORalpha, a mechanism associated with coactivator interaction.  Strikingly, Hr specificity is dictated by the RORalpha AF-2 helix. Moreover,  corepressor action is maintained in the presence of ligand, suggesting that Hr is a  ligand-oblivious corepressor. The RORalpha AF-2 helix plays a dynamic role in  controlling both corepressor and coactivator interactions. The interaction of Hr  with RORalpha provides a molecular link converging the thyroid hormone and  RO</description><creator>Moraitis, Anna-Nectaria</creator><contributor>Giguere, Vincent (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of the molecular mechanisms regulating the transcriptional activity of the ROR [alpha] orphan nuclear receptor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bc095.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bh78w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pn47q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"The Makeover and Other Consumerist Narratives" is an  interdisciplinary work in both approach and scope, and reads the construction of  feminine desire and identity through what is popularly known as the makeover.  Bringing together such diverse areas as film, literature, women's magazines,  psychoanalysis, historical analysis and cultural theory, this research is  particularly concerned with visual communications media (mostly film and  advertising) and spectatorship. Of central import is the relationship of consumerism  to feminine identity, desire, and the historical emergence of popular entertainments  aimed directly at women. The narrative of the makeover---so prevalent in women's  magazines and advertising---works to effectively orient women's desires in a  consumerist direction through product promotion and self-commodification. In  addition, the makeover is explored in terms of how it might be seen to provide a  model by which to understand the workings of late consumer capitalism as a whole.  From an excavation of the official commodity-oriented origins of the makeover in the  history of women's magazines, the project then moves through a reading of several  print advertisements and the phenomenon of the consumer tie-in, and finally to what  I call the "Transformation Film." Questions of narrative, desire and class  are key here, especially insofar as these films make explicit the connection between  self-transformation, commodity consumption, feminine desire and the promise of  identity in consumer culture. At issue is the peculiar problematic of feminine desire as  negotiated by Freudian and Lacanian psychoanalysis, as well as the historical  implications of female identity as explainable by Marxian commodity theory. It is  only by means of examining the objects which cater to feminine desire that we may be  able to understand this "culture of the makeover" and women's identity  therein.</description><creator>Fraser, Kathryn</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Wallace, Jo-Ann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Self-perception in women</subject><subject>Consumer behavior</subject><subject>Beauty culture -- Social aspects</subject><subject>Women in mass media</subject><title>The makeover and other consumerist narratives /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9030469.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn47q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881m50j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In mammals, Nck, represented by two genes, is a 47kDa protein  lacking intrinsic enzymatic function. It is composed solely of three N-terminal  Src-homology 3 (SH3) domains and a single C-terminal Src-homology 2 (SH2) domain.  Nck is classified as an adapter molecule that links cell surface receptors, via its  SH2 domain, to downstream effectors, through its SH3 domains. Two cDNAs coding for  the carboxy-terminal region of the beta subunit of the eukaryotic initiation factor  2 (eIF2beta) were isolated from a two-hybrid screen to identify new effector  molecules interacting with the SH3 domains of Nck. eIF2beta is a component of the  molecular complex eIF2 responsible for one of the early steps in the initiation of  protein synthesis. In this thesis, I determined in vivo that the first and the third  SH3 domains of Nck were both required for its interaction with eIF2beta.  Furthermore, Nck and eIF2beta colocalized in an enriched ribosomal fraction. The  localization of Nck in this compartment is enhanced upon insulin stimulation. I also  established that Nck-1 overexpression is concomitant with an increase in protein  translation. Interestingly, the effect of Nck on translation was dependent on its  first and third SH3 domains originally found to mediate its interaction with  eIF2beta. To elucidate how Nck modulates protein translation, I examined whether Nck  maintains its positive effects under ER stress conditions where protein synthesis is  normally inhibited. Interestingly, my data revealed that Nck-1 overexpression  antagonized ER stress-induced inhibition of translation. Furthermore, I demonstrated  that overexpression of Nck-1 prevented PERK activation, eIF2alpha phosphorylation,  BiP induction and cell survival in response to ER stress treatments. This integrates  Nck in the regulation of the ER unfolded protein response (UPR). I also provided  evidence that the effects of Nck on the UPR involve its second SH3 domain and a  phosphatase-dependent mechanis</description><creator>Kebache, Sem</creator><contributor>Larose, Louise (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>A role for the Nck adapter in protein translation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rh526.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m50j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tv590</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our visual world contains both luminance- (first-order) and  contrast-defined (second-order) information. Distinct mechanisms underlying the  perception of first-order and second-order motion have been proposed from  electrophysiological, psychophysical and neurological studies. In this thesis  psychophysical and human brain imaging (fMRI) experiments are described that support  the notion of distinct mechanisms, but extend the previous studies by providing  evidence for a functional dissociation and a relative cortical specialization for  first- and second-order motion. Using psychophysical methods, a directional anisotropy was found  for second-order but not first-order motion in peripheral vision. This anisotropy is  interpreted as a functional dissociation implicating the second-order mechanism in  optic flow processing. Identification of early visual cortical areas is a prerequisite  to any functional assessment of these visual areas. To this aim a novel human brain  mapping method has been developed which automatically segments early human  retinotopic visual areas. Unlike previous methods this procedure does not depend on  a cortical surface reconstruction and thereby greatly simplifies the  analysis. In a combined psychophysical and fMRI study, distinct cortical  regions, in occipital and parietal lobes, were preferentially activated by either  first- or second-order motion. These results provide evidence for the idea that  first-order motion is computed in V1 and second-order motion in later occipital  visual areas. In addition the results suggest a functional dissociation of the two  kinds of motion beyond the occipital lobe consistent with a role for the  second-order mechanism in optic flow analysis.</description><creator>Dumoulin, Serge O.</creator><contributor>Hess, R. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Baker, C. L., Jr. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Evans, A. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Motion mechanisms and cortical areas in human vision : psychophysics and fMRI</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c262.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv590</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623hz16k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of data assimilation is to find the optimal estimate of the state of the atmosphere at a given time using all the available observational data and the knowledge of the physical and dynamical laws that govern the system's motion. A variety of methods are used for this purpose, and most of them are based on statistical estimation theory, such as variational methods that are widely used in operational numerical weather prediction applications. Two forms can be used to solve the variational assimilation problem: the primal (3D/4D-Var) defined in the model space and the dual (3D/4D-PSAS) defined in the ``observation" space. Both variants are theoretically equivalent {\em at} convergence and in the linear case, are expected to have similar convergence properties. In this thesis, the equivalence is confirmed in an operational setting for the three and four dimensional cases, and the convergence properties are studied. While results at convergence confirm the theoretical equivalence, the convergence of the dual method exhibits a spurious behaviour at the beginning of the minimization which leads to less probable states than the background state, and it takes a number of iterations to retrieve states of comparable probability to that of the background state. This is worrisome since operational implementations can only afford a limited number of iterations. Investigation of this problem showed that it could be avoided by using a minimization scheme, such as the minimum residual (Minres) algorithm, that monotonically decreases the norm of the gradient instead of the functional itself. The iterates of a dual minimization with Minres lead to increasingly probable states. A relationship is established showing that the primal functional is related to  the  value of the dual functional and the norm of its gradient. This holds for the incremental forms of both the three and four dimensional cases. The intercomparison of the primal and dual forms is also examined in a two dimensional weak-constraint framework to account for model errors within the assimilation system. A dual form of the weak-constraint 4D-Var is formulated and results showed that both methods converge to the same solution and with similar convergence rates. As in the three and four dimensional cases, the dual algorithm is still sensitive to the choice of the minimization algorithm, and benefits from Minres properties to avoid the non-physical increments in the first iterations. Singular vectors of primal and dual Hessians are used to improve the preconditioning of the minimization and to establish a connection between the Hessians which is key to cycling the dual Hessian to the next analysis window. This holds also in the weak-constraint case and the significantly lower dimension of the control variable in the dual case may be beneficial then. This is an attractive proposition as the length  of the assimilation window is extended.</description><description>L'objectif de l'assimilation de données est de trouver une estimation optimale de l'état de l'atmosphère à un moment donné en utilisant toute l'information disponible à travers et les observations et les connaissances sur les lois dynamiques et physiques qui gouvernent l'atmosphère. Différentes méthodes sont utilisées à cette fin, dont la majorité sont basées sur les principes de l'estimation statistique. Les méthodes variationnelles en sont un exemple et sont actuellement implémentées dans les grands centres de prévision numérique du temps.  Deux formes peuvent être utilisées pour résoudre le problème d'assimilation variationnelle : la primale (3D/4D-Var) qui est définie dans l'espace du modèle et la duale (3D/4D-PSAS) qui est définie dans l'espace des observations. Les deux variantes sont en théorie équivalentes à la convergence  et dans le cas linéaire, et sont supposées avoir un comportement de convergence similaire. Dans cette thèse, l'équivalence est confirmée dans un cadre opérationnel, et les propriétés de la convergence étudiées pour les cas tri- et quadri-dimensionnels (3D et 4D). Alors que les résultats à la convergence confirment l'équivalence théorique, la convergence de la méthode duale présente un comportement étrange pendant les premières itérations de la minimisation, ce qui produit des états moins  probables que l'ébauche et cela prend quelques iterations avant de retrouver des états dont la probabilité est comparable à celle de l'ébauche. Ce comportement est inquiétant puisque les implémentations opérationnelles ne peuvent se permettre qu'un nombre limité d'itérations. L'examen de ce problème a montré qu'il peut être évité en utilisant des schémas de minimisation tels que les méthodes à résidu minimum (Minres) qui réduisent monotoniquement la norme du gradient au lieu de la fonction objective elle même. Ainsi, les itérés de la minimisation duale avec Minres conduisent à des états de plus en plus probables. Une relation est formulées montrant que la fonction primale est liée à la valeur de la fonction duale ainsi que celle de la norme de son gradient. Cela est valide pour les formes incrémentales  dans les cas 3D et 4D. Aussi, la comparaison entre les formes primale et duale a-t-elle été effectuée dans le cadre d'un système bi-dimensionnel en contrainte faible pour tenir compte des erreurs modèle dans le processus d'assimilation. Une forme duale du 4D-Var contrainte faible a été formulée et les résultats montrent que les deux méthodes convergent à la même solution et avec un taux de convergence similaire.  Comme dans les autres cas précédents, l'algorithme dual est encore sensible au choix du minimiseur, et profite des propriétés de Minres pour éviter de produire des incréments non physiques pendant les premières itérations. Les vecteurs singuliers des Hessiennes des méthodes primales et duales sont utilisés pour améliorer le pré-conditionnement de la minimisation et pour établir un lien entre les Hessiennes, ce qui s'avère être déterminant dans la solution de cyclage de la Hessienne duale à la fenêtre d'assimilation suivante. Cette propriété reste aussi valide dans le cas de la contrainte faible où la dimension réduite de la variable de contrôle dans le cas dual peut être bénéfique. Cela est d'autant plus intéressant que  la fenêtre d'assimilation est appelée à s'élargir.</description><creator>El Akkraoui, Amal</creator><contributor>Peter Bartello (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Pierre Gauthier (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>The primal and dual forms of variational data assimilation in the presence of model error</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322d716.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623hz16k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>