<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:07:42Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4550" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204150q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The case of Inuit broadcasting is fundamental for federal communications law and policy. The first part of this thesis explores Inuit attempts to establish a broadcasting presence in Canada. It concludes that Canadian northern aboriginal language broadcasters have positive rights to self-governance and self-survival over their cultural and linguistic institutions using modern communications technologies. In international law, a minority group communications model for such self-governance exists and could be effectively applied in Canada. […]</description><description>Le cas de la radio Inuit est fondamental pour la politique et le droit de communications fédéral. La première partie de cette thèse recherche les efforts Inuits d’établir une présence de radio au Canada. Cette thèse arrive la conclusion que les parleurs la radio aborigènes du nord du Canada ont des droits positives de gouverner et de régir leurs propres institutions culturelles et linguistiques travers la technologie moderne de communication. Un modèle de communication pour des groupes mineures pour un tel gouvernance qui existe déjà dans le droit international peut-être appliqué effectivement au Canada aussi. </description><creator>Herringer, Jay A.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Broadcasting -- Law and legislation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Indigenous peoples -- Canada.</subject><subject>Minorities in broadcasting -- Canada.</subject><title>Communications Law and Aboriginal Broadcasting Rights in Canada: The Case of Inuit Broadcasting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h414c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204150q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nn91q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A major limitation in analyzing collagen degradation in articular cartilage in arthritis has been the lack of a technique for identifying collagen breakdown in situ. A new methodology is described which utilizes immunochemical and immunohistochemical protocols and a well characterized antiserum that permits the detection and analysis of type II collagen degradation in human and bovine articular cartilages. The antiserum R181 specifically reacts with unwound alpha chains and the CNBr-derived peptides a 1 (II)CB 11 and a l(II)CB8 of human and bovine type II collagens and not with helical collagens. Increased degradation of type n collagen was detected in bovine cartilage cultured with IL-l. Increased extractable a chains and smaller collagen fragments were detected immunochemically. Immunohistochemically, an increase in type II collagen degradation was detected in human cartilages cultured with interleukin-1. This could be inhibited by addition of a metalloproteinase inhibitor. All human arthritic cartilages showed more staining for type II collagen degradation than was seen in normal cartilages. Using light and electron microscopic analyses, distinct patterns of collagen degradation were seen in rheumatoid arthritic compared with osteoarthritic cartilages. The results suggest that type 11 collagen degradation is a significant and early event in cartilage pathology. </description><creator>Dodge, George Raymond</creator><contributor>Poole, A. Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Articular cartilage</subject><title>Immunochemical Studies of Type II Collagen Degradation in Bovine and Human Articular Cartilage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp76z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn91q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rr213</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On a étudié l'absorption de l'anhydride sulfureux dans des suspensions aqueuses de deux types de cendres du charbon canadiennes (lignite et subbitumineuses) dans un réacteur agite semi-continu. On a trouvé que seuls les compose de calcium et de magnésium avaient l'alcalinité nécessaire à l'absorption du S02. L'alcalinite des cendres de lignite était environ deux fois celle des cendres subbitumineuses. La concentration de calcium et de magnésium dépendait de la densité de la suspension, de la grosseur des particules, du pH et de la température. Initiallement, on a observé une dissolution très rapide et la concentration des métaux dissous était proportionnelle à l'aire superficielle totale des particules. Il fallait un pH de 3,5 pour obtenir une dissolution maximale. La quantité de S02 absorbe dépendait, en général, de l'alcalinité disponible dans le liquide. Celle-ci augmentait selon la densité de la suspension et la concentration d'arrivée du so2, mais indépendamment de la température et de la grosseur des particules. Pendant les 45 à 60 premières minutes de l'expérience, l'ajout de calcaire n'affectait pas l'absorption. Cette dernière dépendait de la concentration d'arrivée du gaz, mais pas du type d'absorbeur. Par la suite, avec une faible alcalinité disponible, le taux de dissolution contrôlait le taux d'absorbtion. </description><description>The absorption of sulphur dioxide into aqueous slurries of two Canadian coal fly ashes (subbituminous and lignite) was studied using a semi-batch stirred tank reactor. The dissolution of alkaline metal compounds from both types of fly ash was also investigated. Only calcium and magnesium compounds were found to be important in providing soluble alkalinity for S02 absorption. Lignite ash provided approximately twice as high alkalinity as subbituminous ash. The concentrations of dissolved calcium and magnesium were dependent of slurry density, particle size, pH and temperature. Initial dissolution was very rapid and the initial concentration of dissolved metals was proportional to the total surface area of particles. A pH lower than 3.5 was essential for maximum dissolution. The amount of S02 absorbed was generally dependent of the amount of available alkalinity in the liquid. It increased with increasing slurry density, and inlet S02 concentration but was not affected by temperature or particle size. Limestone addition did not affect the absorption in the first 45 to 60 minutes. Initial absorption was a function of gas inlet concentration and independent of the type of absorbent. At later stages, the absorption rate was controlled by the rate of dissolution at low available alkalinity.</description><creator>Al-Haj Ali, Ahmad M.</creator><contributor>Berk, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Sulphur dioxide</subject><subject>Alkaline metal</subject><title>Characterization of the Alkaline Metal Dissolution and Sulphur Dioxide Absorption of Fly Ash Slurries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v314.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rr213</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193c251</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire présente des algorithmes pour l'approximation d'un ensemble den points par une droite minimisant la norme L1 des distances verticales et orthogonales. Les algorithmes trouvent des solutions exactes basées sur les propriétés géométriques des problèmes par opposition aux solutions approximatives basées sur des techniques numériques existantes. La complexité algorithmique de ces problèmes ne semble pas avoir été étudiée. Le premier résultat est un algorithme prenant un temps optimal O(n) pour le problème vertical pondère base sur une modification d'une technique de recherche multi-dimensionelle qui rend possible l'application de la technique de base à une plus vaste classe de problèmes. En second lieu, un algorithme O(n 1.5 log2 n) est présenté pour le problème orthogonal non-pondéré ainsi qu'un algorithme O(n2) pour le problème orthogonal pondéré; les deux constituent une application intéressante des "k-rubans" (pondérés) d'un arrangement de droites. Également, une borne inferieure de 0(n log n) pour le problème orthogonal L1 est démontrée avec un certain modèle decalcul.</description><description>This thesis presents algorithms for approximating a set of n points by a. line which minimizes the L1 norm of vertical and orthogonal distances. The algorithms find exact solutions based upon geometric properties of the problems as opposed to approximate solutions based upon existing numerical techniques. The algorithmic complexity of these problems appears not to have been investigated. The first result is an 0(n) optimal time algorithm for the weighted vertical problem based upon a modified multidimensional search technique which extends the applicability of the basic technique to a wider class of problems. Second, an O(n1 •5 log2 n) algorithm is presented for the unweighted orthogonal problem, and an 0(n2) algorithm is presented for the weighted orthogonal problem; both algorithms provide an interesting application of the (weighted) k-belts of an arrangement of lines. Also, an 0 (n log n) lower bound for the orthogonal L1 problem is shown under a certain model of computation. </description><creator>Yamamoto, Peter J.</creator><contributor>Imai, Hiroshi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Linear approximation</subject><title>Vertical and Orthogonal L1 Linear Approximation: Analysis and Algorithms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d665h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193c251</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999899p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire propose des méthodes analytiques originales pour établir le tirant d’ancrage relatif à ses applications dans les domaines du génie minier et de la géotechnique. Les domaines spécifiques de recherche et les résultats observés sont les suivants. Le soutènement du sol en mode de rupture circulaire, et le soutènement du socle rocheux en mode de rupture plane sont analysés utilisant le critère de défaillance de Mohr-Coulomb. Ceci permet de déterminer la force d’ancrage minimum, pour les cas actifs et passifs, en fonction de l'angle d'ancrage. La méthode du calcul des variations, de concert avec les critères de défaillance de Mohr-Coulomb et de Hoek et Brown, est utilisée pour établir le facteur de sécurité minimum pour la stabilité des talus avant le renforcement. Un avantage du calcul des variations réside dans le fait que la distribution de la contrainte normale le long de la courbe potentielle de rupture peut être calculée. Le critère de défaillance de Bieniawski est utilisé pour déterminer l'enveloppe de rupture en cisaillement dans les massifs rocheux. Cet aspect compte plusieurs applications dans l’ancrage du socle rocheux, dans le renforcement des pilliers et dans plusieurs autres domaines du génie minier. […]</description><description>This research considers original analytical methods to design ground anchoring and their applications in the fields of mining and geotechnical engineering. Specific areas of the investigation and results are as follows: Soil slope support with circular failure and rock slope support with planar failure are analyzed using the Mohr-Coulomb failure criterion to determine the minimum anchor force for the active and passive cases as a function of the anchor inclination. A variational approach is introduced to analyze the minimum safety factor for slope stability before reinforcement utilizing Mohr-Coulomb and Hoek-and-Brown failure criteria; this variational approach is compared to conventional methods. One advantage of the variational approach is that the normal stress distribution along the potential failure curve can be calculated. The Bieniawski failure criterion is used to determine the shear failure envelope in rock masses. The results have many applications in rock anchoring, pillar reinforcement, and other areas of mining engineering. […]</description><creator>Ucar, Roberto</creator><contributor>Hassani, F. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Ground anchoring</subject><title>New Design Methods for Ground Anchoring</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk60v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999899p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hx84r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:19:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This essay provides an account of the philosophical difficulties involved in specifying the content of singular thoughts. Chapter one introduces Frege's theory of thought and shows how it can accommodate Kaplan's objection from psychological redundancy. This defence of Frege gives rise to the account of sense due to Peacocke, Evans, and McDowell, which is presented in chapter two. This exposition is followed by a critique of their central claim, that most singular thoughts are reference-dependent, such that in case of the non-existence of the object of a putative singular thought, there is no thought. In chapter three, an attempt is made to steer a middle course between rejection of reference-dependence and endorsement of Cartesianism. Considerations concerning the role of thought in the explanation of behaviour, and the possibility of sense for objectless singular expressions, suggest a modified Fregean theory that guarantees context-sensitive singular thought. </description><description>Cet essai a pour objet la clarification de certaines difficultés philosophiques concernant le contenu des pensées-objets. Le premier chapitre est une introduction à la théorie de la pensée de Frege et cherche à montrer comment celle-ci peut constituer une réponse à l'objection de Kaplan concernant le rôle joue par le contexte vis-à-vis du contenu sémantique. Cette défense de Frege annonce l'interprétation du sens présentée dans le second chapitre, interprétation que l'on trouve notamment chez Peacocke, Evans, et McDowell. Cet expose est suivi d'une critique de leur thèse principale, à savoir que la plupart des pensées-objets dépendent de leur référant dans le cas de la non-existence de l'objet d'une pensée-objet donnée, il n'y a pas de pensée. Dans le troisième chapitre, nous essayons d'adopter une position à mi-chemin entre ceux qui nient la dépendance du référant et ceux qui affirme une doctrine cartésienne. Certaines considérations concernant le rôle de la pensée afin d'expliquer le comportement humain ainsi que la possibilité de parler du sens des expressions singulières sans objets, suggèrent une nouvelle théorie de Frege qui guarantit la sensibilité du contexte pour les pensées-objets. </description><creator>Smith, Steven Darrell</creator><contributor>McGilvray, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Solipsism.</subject><subject>Thought and thinking.</subject><subject>Behaviorism (Psychology)</subject><title>Singular Thought and Explanation of Behaviour</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924f07h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx84r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr96m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le but de la présente étude était d'examiner les effets de différentes intensités d'exercice sur l'attention et sur l'activité de l'EEG. Quinze sujets voluntaires, droitiers et sains dont les consommations d'oxygène maximales se situent entre 45ml/kg/min et 55 ml/kg/min ont été sélectionnées. Les sujets ont été à trois sessions de 20 minutes chacune sur bicyclette ergométrique à des intensités de 30%, 50%, et 70% de leurs capacité aérobique maximale (V02 max) respectives. Les sujets ont aussi été soumis au test de Génération de Nombres au Hasard (RNG) de concentration avant, pendant et après l'exercice. L'activité de l'EEG des régions frontales, temporales et pariétales des hémisphères gauche et droit a été enregistrée pour une durée de 30 secondes de chaque période de 30 minutes durant les niveaux de repos, d'exercice et de récupération de l'expérience. L'index d'alpha et l'amplitude maximum d'alpha ont été utilisés afin d'évaluer l'activité de l'EEG. […]</description><description>The purpose of the study was to examine the effects of various intensities of exercise on attention and EEG activity. Fifteen right handed male volunteers whose oxygen uptake values ranged between 45 ml/kg/min and 55 ml/kg/min were selected. The subjects cycled for three sessions of 20 minutes at 30%, 50% and 70% of their maximal oxygen uptake values respectively. The Random Number Generation test (RNG) of concentration was given before, during and after the exercise. EEG activity was recorded from the frontal, temporal and parietal regions of the left and right hemisphere for a 30 second segment of each 3 minute time period during the baseline, exercise, and recovery stages of the experiment. Alpha index and maximum alpha amplitude were used to assess EEG activity. […]</description><creator>Papathanasopoulou, Kalliopi</creator><contributor>Marisi, D. Q. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1989</date><subject>Attention -- Testing.</subject><subject>Exercise tests.</subject><title>Effects of Various Intensities of Exercise Induced Activation (EIA) on Attention and EEG Activity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j267.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr96m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278w67c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A novel touch (tactile) sensing device is presented. The sensor has several advantages over those currently available on the market. It is completely digital and based entirely on standard VLSI technology and is, in addition, sensitive to both the normal and tangential components of the pressure. The sensor has the potential to achieve high resolutions and can be inexpensively mass produced. The sensor has many applications ranging from a force sensor for a robot to a mouse-like input device. This thesis outlines the design, fabrication and testing of this unique tactile sensor. </description><description>Le but de cette thèse est de présenter un nouveau capteur tactile qui offre de nombreux avantages par rapport à ceux disponibles sur le marché présentement. Les caractéristiques les plus uniques de ce "tactomètre" est de n'être fabrique qu'en utilisant la technologie 'VLSI', d'être entièrement digital et de ne pas faire appel à des techniques très particulières. Le principe de fonctionement simplifie l'interface avec un ordinateur et aussi rend possible l'obtention de hautes resolutions. De plus, le tactometre peut detecter les composantes normales et tangentielles de la force de contact, ce qui n'est pas le cas pour la plupart des tactomètres. Le but de cette thèse est donc d'exposer le principe de fonctionement, la procédure de fabrication et de discuter les résultats d'essais expérimentaux de ce dispositif unique au monde. </description><creator>Nilakantan, Ajit</creator><contributor>Hayward, Vincent (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Tactile sensor</subject><title>The Design and Implementation on an all Digital Shear Sensitive Tactile Sensor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tp35g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w67c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n68j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The myofibrillar and connective tissue protein contents of the costal bovine Diaphragm have been determined by use of analytical chromatographic methods developed to quantitate the unique amino acids that occur in these proteins. Myosin and actin were determined from the amounts of Nt methylhistidine found in the acid hydrolysates of the intracellular muscle protein fraction which was separated from the extracellular matrix of the Diaphragm in sodium dodecyl sulphate (2%) and CaCl 2 (0.05M). The costal Diaphragm contained 11.4% actin, and 23.6% myosin corresponding to 17.5 and 36.3% of the myofibrillar proteins. The content of collagen (2.61%) in the SDS.-insoluble extracellular fraction was determined from the amounts of 5 hydroxylysine and the elastin content (0.19%) from the amounts of desmosine and isodesmosine present. […]</description><description>Le contenu en protéine des tissus myofibrillaires et conjonctifs du Diaphramme costal bovin a été déterminé en utilisant des méthods analytiques développées pour exprimer en termes quantitatifs les acides aminés uniques composant ces protéins. Les taux de myosine et d'active furent déterminés à partir des quantités de NT-methylhistidine des hydrolysates de l'acide de la fraction de la protéine musculaire intracellulaire. Cette fraction a été séparée de la matrice extracellulaire du Diaphramme avec du sulfate dodécyl de sodium (2%) et du CaCl 2 (0.05 M). Le Diaphramme costal contenait 11.4% d'actine et 23.6% de myosine correspondant respectivement à 17.5% et 36.3% de la protéine myofibrillaire. Le contenu en collagène (2.61%) de la fraction extracellulaire non-soluble de SDS peut être calcule à partir des quantités de 5-hydroxylysine et celui de l'élastine, de la quantité de desmosine présente. […]</description><creator>Karatzas, Constantinos N.</creator><contributor>Zarkadas, C. G.  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Connective tissues.</subject><subject>Muscle proteins.</subject><subject>Meat -- Composition.</subject><title>The Quantitative Determination of the Myofibrillar and Connective Tissue Proteins in Skeletal Muscles and Composite Meats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b66d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n68j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz87m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I consider the problem of planning collision-free trajectories for a robot in time-varying environments (among stationary or moving obstacles). I then propose a framework and show how it leads to fast and efficient algorithms for trajectory planning. The key idea behind this framework is a space-time representation that leads to a natural decomposition of the spatial and temporal aspects of the problem. The basic approach is to partition the whole problem into two sub-problems: (i) planning a path to avoid collisions with stationary obstacles, and (ii) planning the velocity along this path to avoid collisions with the moving obstacles. The first sub-problem is called the Path Planning Problem, and the second sub-problem is called the Velocity Planning Problem. I call this the Path-Velocity decomposition. […]</description><description>Cette thèse considéré le problème de la planification de trajectoire avec évitement d'obstacles pour un robot dans un environnement dynamique (les obstacles sont mobiles). Une méthode conduisant à des algorithmes efficaces est proposée pour ce problème. L'idée de base consiste à introduire une décomposition du problème spatio-temporel en ses deux composantes naturelles. La démarche est donc la suivante: (i) planification d'un "chemin" sans collision parmi des obstacle stationnaires, et (ii) planification de la vitesse le long de long de cet chemin de façon à éviter les obstacles mobiles. Le premier sous-probleme est appele "Path Planning Problem" (PPP), et le second sous-problème est appelé "Velocity Plannning Problem" (VPP). On peut qualifier cette décomposition de décomposition "Chemin-Vitesse" (Path-Velocity). […]</description><creator>Gupta, Kamal Kant</creator><contributor>Zucker, Steve  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Trajectory optimization.</subject><subject>Robots -- Motion.</subject><title>Trajectory Planning in Time-varying Environments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c95z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz87m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q654z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce travail fait partie d'une étude élaborée sur les propriétés mécaniques et physiques de différents types de remblais monolithiques (monolithic packs) utilisés dans les mines de charbon. Un programme intensif d'essais en laboratoire a aussi été mis en marche dans le but de développer un remblai utilisant les ressources locales de la Nouvelle-Ecosse qui puisse être employé dans la houillère de Sydney. Cette étude donne un bref compte-rendu des différents types de remblais, des systèmes disponibles et couramment utilisés dans les plus importantes mines de charbon du monde. Une étude de cas faite en Angleterre y est décrite afin d’appuyer l'efficacité d 'un tel système de support en ce qui a trait au contrôle des strates. Les propriétés mécaniques et physiques de certains remblais monolithiques disponibles sur le marché, comme l'Aquapak, le Tekpak et l'Astrapak, y sont abordées en portant une attention spéciale au temps de cure, a la température de l'eau de minage ainsi qu'à la température de cure. Une étude approfondie de l'Astrapak, présentement utilise dans les mines de Sydney, a, pour la première fois, examine la température exothermique de différentes grosseurs (volume) d'échantillons par rapport au temps et a la température de cure. […]</description><description>This work is part of an overall research investigation into the mechanical and physical properties of different types of monolithic packs used in coal mines as well as conducting an intensive testing programme to attempt to develop a pack material from the local resources of Nova Scotia to be employed in the Sydney Coalfield. This study gives a brief review of different packing materials and systems available and currently employed in major coalfields in the world. A case study in England has been outlined to substantiate the effectiveness of such a support system from a strata control point of view. The mechanical and physical properties of commercially available monolithic packs mainly Aquapak, Tekpak, and Astrapak is discussed with special reference to curing time, mixing water temperature as well as curing temperature. A comprehensive study of Astrapak material currently employed in the Sydney Coalfield has for the first time investigated the exothermic temperature development within different sizes (volume) of samples with respect to curing time and temperature. […]</description><creator>Farsangi, Parvis N.</creator><contributor>Hassani, F. P.  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Concrete -- Pump placing.</subject><subject>Concrete stoppings (Mining)</subject><title>An Investigation into Monolithic Pack Materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k963n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q654z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p057h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been said, not without some justification, that Camille Roy was the father of modern French-Canadian literary criticism. This study, which covers Roy's formative years (1870-1901) and the first ten years of his career as critic (1902-1912), attempts to account for his decision to become a critic and for his rapid rise to a position of authority in the field. Factors taken into consideration include, in addition to Roy's own activities as a critic, priest and teacher, the socio-historical conjuncture and the nature of the French-Canadian literary system in the first years of the twentieth century. Based upon certain concepts fundamental to the sociology of literature and of the literary institution, this thesis relies to a considerable extent on the unpublished material contained in the Fonds Camille Roy of the Archives of the Seminary of Quebec. </description><description>On a dit de Camille Roy, non sans quelque justification, qu'il est le père de la critique littéraire canadienne-française moderne. Cette thèse, qui porte sur la formation de Roy (1870-1901) et sur la première décennie de sa carrière critique (1902-1912), tente de rendre compte de son choix de carrière et de son accession rapide a une position d'autorité dans le domaine. Les principaux facteurs étudiés comprennent, outre les activités de Roy lui-même en tant que critique, prêtre et professeur, la conjoncture socio-historique et la nature du système littéraire canadien-français au début du vingtième siècle. Cette étude s'inspire de certains concepts fondamentaux de la sociologie de la littérature et de l'institution littéraire et se fonde dans une assez grande mesure sur les documents inédits conserves dans le Fends Camille Roy des Archives du Séminaire de Québec. </description><creator>Everett, Jane</creator><contributor>Ricard, François  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Critics -- Québec (Province) -- Biography.</subject><subject>Roy, Camille, 1870-1943.</subject><title>Camille Roy : Formation et Ascension d’un Critique, 1870-1912</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv083.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p057h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx77k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On a étudié, ches les procelets de 37 portées, le comportement a la tétée pendant les premieres heures après la naissance. La fréquence des épisodes de tétées par heure a diminué à mesure que la période d'allaitement progressait alors que le synchronisme a la tétée a augmenté entre les procelets. La fréquence des disputes aux mamelles n'a pas été influencée par la taille de la portée. Toutefois, les procelets qui tétaient plusieurs mamelles ont participé à plusieurs disputes. Pendant les 8 premières heures suivant la naissance, les procelets tétaient en moyenne 7 mamelles différentes. […]</description><description>Piglet suckling behaviour during the first hours after birth was investigated in 37 litters. As the litter aged the number of suckling bouts per h decreased and there was a continuous and gradual increase in synchrony of the suckling behaviour as the litter progressed towards a cyclical suckling pattern. Teat dispute frequency and duration remained high during the first 10 h. Teat dispute frequency was not affected by litter size but piglets that suckled from many teats were involved in many disputes. During the first 8 h after birth, a piglet suckled an average of 7 different teats. […]</description><creator>de Passillé, Anne Marie B.</creator><contributor>Fraser, D.  (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kramer, D.  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Swine -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Swine -- Food.</subject><subject>Piglets.</subject><title>Suckling and Related Behaviour of Piglets: Ontogeny and Implications for Production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dj02x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx77k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hx851</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'existence de dialectes chez les oiseaux, c'est-à-dire de regroupments régionaux d'individus aux chants structurellement similaires, a été attribuée a plusieurs mécanismes adaptatifs, entre autres la sélection pour l'efficacité de la transmission acoustique du chant dans différents habitats (ou hypothèse d’adaptation à l'environnement). Jusqu'à présent, l'ensemble des résultats appuxant cette hypothèse n'a pu être considéré comme une réfutation de l'hypothèse nulle de distribution aléatoire des dialectes entre les divers habitats; la principale raison étant que très peu de données accumulées jusqu'ici l'on été suivant des méthodes scientifiques appropriées. Dans ce présent mémoire, je teste les prémisses de l'hypothèse d'adaptation à l'environnement et trouve que, malgré l'existence d'une variation de la transmission acoustique due aux conditions climatiques variables, il existe un potentiel pour une sélection « déstabilisante » agissant sur la structure du chant chez la fauvette flamboyante que serait reliée aux contraintes acoustiques typiques aux différents habitats. […]</description><description>The occurrence of dialects in birds, that is, the regional clustering of individuals with songs of similar structure, has been attributed to several adaptive mechanisms, including selection for 'efficiency of song transmission' in different habitats (environmental adaptation hypothesis). To date, evidence supporting the mechanisms has not successfully refuted the null hypothesis for the occurrence of dialects by chance, because few data have been collected using appropriate scientific methods. I test assumptions of the environmental adaptation hypothesis and find that, despite variation in sound transmission with weather, there is potential for the disruptive selection of song structure in American Redstarts by the acoustic constraints of different habitats. […]</description><creator>Date, Elizabeth M.</creator><contributor>Lemon, Robert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Wood warblers -- Habitat.</subject><subject>Wood warblers.</subject><subject>Birdsongs.</subject><title>The Influence of Environmental Acoustics on the Structure of Song in American Redstarts (Setophaga ruticilla)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk614.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx851</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc19c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'utilisation du groupement ß -cyanoethyle comme fonction protectrice du phosphate pour la synthèse en solution de ribonucléotides par les méthodes de triesters de phosphate et de phosphite a été étudiée a fond. Ce groupement protecteur a été employé en conjonction avec la méthode des phosphodichloridures pour la synthèse d'un pentaribonucléotide (APG£APUPC) correspondant aux positions 45 a 49 du N-formyle methionine tARN d'E.coli. La RMN 2 Si INEPT a été utilisée dans l'étude de chaines de ribonucléotides substituées par des groupements t-butyldimethylsilyle et triisopropylsilyle.La synthèse d'un tétranucléotide et d'une série de trinucléotides d'ARN ramifies, par la méthode des triesters de phosphite, est décrite. Ces molécules furent caractérisées par méthodes spectroscopiques, analyse par CLHP de digestions enzymatiques et électrophorèse sur gel. L'effet de ces produits sur l'efficacité de l'épissage des molécules précurseurs d'ARN messager a été examiné. De plus, l'absorption UV, la RMN et le dichroïsme circulaire ont été employés pour déterminer la structure tridimensionnelle de ces produits. […]</description><description>The ß -cyanoethyl group has been thoroughly investigated as a phosphate protecting group in the phosphate and phosphite triester synthesis of ribonucleotides in solution. This protecting group was used in conjunction with the phosphodichloridite procedure in the synthesis of the pentaribonucleotide APGPAPUPC, corresponding to base positions 45 to 49 of N-formyl methionine tRNA of E.coli. 29si INEPT NMR was used to study t-butyldimethylsilyl and triisopropylsilyl substituted ribonucleotide chains. The phosphite triester synthesis of a series of branched RNA trinucleotides and a tetranucleotide is reported. Spectroscopic methods, HPLC analysis of enzymatic digest, and gel electrophoresis were used to characterize these molecules. The effect of these compounds on the splicing efficiency of messenger RNA precursors was examined. In addition, UV absorption, NMR, and circular dichroism were used to determine the three-dimensional structure of the branched trinucleotides. […]</description><creator>Damha, Masad J.</creator><contributor>Ogilvie, Kelvin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Nucleic acids -- Synthesis.</subject><title>Developments in the Chemical Synthesis of Nucleic Acids and their Analogues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nh13b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc19c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977x270</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les prostaglandines (PG) sont considérées comme les médiatrices finales des évènements qui mènent à la mise basse. Quinze truies ont été divisées au hasard en 3 groupes de 5 chacun selon le stage gestationel (GA; j 109, j 114 et pendant le travail). Du sang de l'artère ombilicale (FA), de la veine ombilicale (FV), de l'artère utérine (MA) et de la veine utérine (MV), et du liquide amniotique (AMF), de l'urine fétale (U), l'amnios (AM), l'allantochorion (ALC) et l'amniochorion (AMC) ont été prélevées sur deux fetus par truie pour chaque GA. Les concentrations des prostaglandines dans le plasma sanguin (PL), AMF, U et des incubations de 0 à 4 heures de cellules placentaires dispersées ont été mesurées par essai radioimmunologique. En plus de liquide amniotique d'avant-terme (PAMF), de l'urine de fetus d'avant-terme (FU) et à pa terme (TFU) ont été ajoutés au ALC et à des microsomes de vesicules séminales bovines (BSVM) afin d'évaluer leurs effets sur la synthèse des prostaglandines. […]</description><description>Prostaglandins (PG) are considered to be mediators of the events that lead to parturition.Final Fifteen sows were randomly divided into 3 groups of 5 each according to gestational age (GA; d 109, d 114 and at labor). Blood from the umbilical artery (FA), umbilical vein (FV), uterine artery (MA) and uterine vein (MV), and amniotic fluid (AMF), fetal urine (U), amnion (AM), allantochorion(ALC) and amniochorion (AMC) were  collected from two fetuses per sow per GA. Prostaglandin concentrations in blood plasma IPLl, AMF, U, and 0-4 h incubates from dispersed placental cells were measured by radioimmunoasay. In addition, pre-term amniotic fluid (PAMF), pre-term CFU) or term-fetal urine ITFVI were added to ALC and to bovine seminal vesicle microsomes (BSVM) to assess the effect of these fluids on PG synthesis. […]</description><creator>Burchard, Javier F.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Sows -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Prostaglandins.</subject><title>In Vitro and In Vivo Prostaglandin Production by the Gravid Uterus during Late Gestation in the Sow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g689.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977x270</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k95z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse porte principalement sur l'étude de l'adsorption de la bilirubine en milieu tampon par des peptides greffes à un support polymérique. Des séquences cibles et identiques au fragment 136 - 148 de la structure primaire de la protéine d'albumine humaine ont été greffées, via la technique de synthèse en phase solide des peptides, a un support de polyacrylamide réticule. Certains des polymères obtenus sont d'excellents adsorbants pour la bilirubine, i. e., ils démontrent une capacité et une affinité relativement élevées. Les interactions électrostatiques ont été démontrées comme étant largement responsables de l'adsorption de la bilirubine mais des facteurs relies à la structure du ligand sont également importants. […]</description><description>This thesis concerns a study of the binding characteristics of immobilized· peptides in the adsorption of bilirubin from aqueous buffer solutions. Strategic peptide sequences patterned on the fragment 136 148 of the primary structure of human serum albumin (HSA) have been immobilized on a cross-linked polyacrylamide support by solid phase peptide synthesis. Certain of the synthesized materials are efficient adsorbents, exhibiting relatively high capacities and strong affinities. The binding is driven mainly by salt linkage interactions but structural factors are also of importance.Site binding constants, derived graphically from Scat chard plots using a binding model developed for these systems, are in the range (0.31 - 9.6) X 104 M- 1. This is comparable to that for the binding of bilirubin by a large fragment of albumin that encompasses the replicate fragment and gives insight concerning the location of the high-affinity binding site on HSA. […]</description><creator>Bouvier, Marlene</creator><contributor>St-Pierre, L. E.  (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Brown, G. R.  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Bilirubin.</subject><subject>Polymers in medicine.</subject><title>The Binding of Bilirubin by Peptide-Containing Polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cd22j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k95z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hv09c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La thèse développe un modèle de classification des images qui fait appel à des catégories conventionnelles reconnues, autant qu'a d'autres issues de théories complexes sur la cognition, la représentation, la séméiotique et la perception. Le modèle consiste en sept dimensions (personnalité, signifie, signifiant, achromatique/chromatique, structural, technique et naturo-social), subdivisées en échelles et niveaux. En premier lieu, nous avons teste le modèle avec un set de 72 images, auprès d'un groupe de 18 sujets, en utilisant le différenciateur sémantique d’Osgood (1957). Cette étape, en délimitant un « profil sémantique affectif'" pour chaque image par rapport à un groupe homogène de sujets, a établi une base nous permettant d'examiner la signification des autres échelles et catégories. […]</description><description>The thesis develops a model for the classification of images, employing conventionally recognized categories as .well as categories derived from complex theories on cognition, representation, semiotics, and perception. The model consists of seven dimensions (personality, signified, significant, achromatic/chromatic, structural, technical, and naturo-social), subdivided into scales and categories. Using 72 images the model was first tested with a group of 18 subjects, employing Osgood's (1957) semantic differential. This step provided an ''affective semantic profile'' (signified) for each image for a homogeneous group of subjects and established a basis for examining the significance of the other scales and categories. […]</description><creator>Bouchard, Louise</creator><contributor>Crowley, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>Cognition -- Research.</subject><subject>Semiotics -- Research.</subject><subject>Perception -- Research.</subject><title>Vers un modèle Génératif de Classification des Images</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2041510.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hv09c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Communications</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pg30b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated cat vernier acuity with a two-choice jumping-stand paradigm. In Experiment 1, vernier acuity was measured in normal adult cats using three types of stimulus targets. In normal cats, vernier acuity was 3-5', about two times better than resolution acuity. Experiment 2 reports pre- and post-operative vernier thresholds in cats which had sustained lesions of areas 17-18 in adulthood. The observed deficit confirmed the involvement of striate cortex in vernier acuity. The normal development of vernier acuity was investigated in Experiment 3. Vernier acuity developed rapidly from initial values of about 40' at 46 days to 2-5' at about 85 days. Experiments 4 and 5 examined the effect of neonatal removal of areas 17-18 on the development of vernier acuity and on resolution acuity. Whereas resolution acuity remained relatively normal, Vernier acuity was severely disturbed. This confirms that the functional plasticity that follows neonatal cortical lesions is task-specific. </description><description>Cette étude examine l'acuité vernier du chat à l'aide d'un appareil "Jumping-Stand". L'expérience 1 mesure l'acuité vernier de chats adultes normaux avec trois types de stimuli. Les seuils d'acuité sont de 3-5', environ 2 fois meilleurs que le seuil de résolution du chat. L'expérience 2 mesure l'effet de lésions adultes des aires 17-18 sur l'acuité vernier. Les déficits observes confirment l'implication du cortex strie dans l'acuité vernier. L'expérience 3 examine le développement normal de l'acuité vernier. L'acuité vernier se développe rapidement et atteint des seuils de 2-5' vers 85 jours. Les expériences 4 et 5 examinent l'effet de lésions périnatales des aires 17-18 ou 17-18-19 sur le développement de l'acuité vernier et sur l'acuité de résolution. Alors que l'acuité de résolution demeure relativement normale, l'acuité vernier est sévèrement déficiente. Ces résultats confirment que la plasticité fonctionnelle qui suit une lésion corticale périnatale dépend de la tâche.</description><creator>Belleville, Sylvie</creator><contributor>Wilkinson, Frances (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Visual acuity.</subject><subject>Cats -- Physiology.</subject><title>Studies of Vernier Acuity in the Cat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v32d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pg30b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft87b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Binary decision machines (BDMs) are high speed programmable automata which evaluate switching functions by means of decision rather than Boolean logic. This thesis describes research on the theory, design and applications of BDM based controllers carried out between January 1984 and May 1987. A theoretical model was developed to deduce the computational properties of the BDM. This model was used as the basis of a rationalized re-design of the BDM and of a fast algorithm for converting Boolean expressions to decision programs. This algorithm is presented as a self contained document in Appendix 1. A 10 MIPS prototype machine was constructed and tested and various applications demonstrated. The most promising of these applications is the high speed execution of Graphical Function Chart (GRAFCET) control programs for use in industrial automation. </description><description>Les machines à décision binaire sont des automates programmables qui évaluent les fonctions combinatoires et séquentielles au moyen d'un programme à l’décision et non à logique booléenne. La recherche présentée dans cette thèse a été réalisée entre janvier 1984 et mai 1987 et traite principalement de la théorie, de la conception et des applications de ces machines. Un modèle théorique a été développé dans le but d'analyser les propriétés mathématiques de la machine à décision binaire. Ce modèle a également servi de base à un algorithme rapide utilisable pour la conversion des expressions booléennes en programmes de décision et à la conception d'une nouvelle génération de machines à décision binaire. Un prototype, d'une vitesse de 10 MIPS (millions d'instructions par seconde), a été construit et son fonctionnement vérifié. Une variété d'applications a été explorée, la plus prometteuse étant l'exécution ultra-rapide de programmes pour l'automatisation industrielle, écrits dans le langage GRAFCET. </description><creator>Baracos, Paul Constantine</creator><contributor>Vroomen, Louis J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Zsombor-Murray, Paul J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Machine theory.</subject><subject>Sequence controllers, Programmable -- Design and construction.</subject><subject>Microprogramming.</subject><title>Sequential Binary Decision Machines : Theory, Design and Applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp77g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft87b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xp057</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Data from breeding records maintained on the colony of American Kestrels (Falco sparverius) from 1973 to 1985 were analyzed to examine environmental influences and to obtain heritability estimates for egg length, width and volume. All dimensions varied significantly (p &lt; 0.01) with year, female age, laying sequence and date of laying. Egg width and volume also varied significantly (p &lt; 0.01) between clutches. […]</description><description>Les résultats provenant du rapport de l’élévage de la colonie des Crécerelles Américaines (Falco sparverius) ont été analysés de 1973 à 1985 pour pouvoir examiner les effets de milieu ainsi qu’obtenir l’héritabilité des paramètres de production : la longueur, la largeur et le volume de l’œuf. Toutes les dimensions varient significativement (p &lt; 0.01) avec l’année, la date de ponte, l’âge de la femelle, et la séquence de la ponte. La largeur et le volume de l’œuf varient significativement (p &lt;0.01) entre les couvées. […]</description><creator>Stewart, Katherine Glenna</creator><contributor>Bird, David M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>American kestrel -- Eggs.</subject><subject>Variation (Biology)</subject><title>Heritability of Egg Size in Captive American Kestrels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k964x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xp057</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064823q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des boues d'épuration municipales digérées à l'air ont été appliquées à un taux de 0, 200 et 400 Mg/ha (état de base humide) sur un sable graveleux de Grande Ligne et une argile de Bearbrook pendant une période de deux ans. Ces deux sols étaient plantés de peupliers hybrides (Populus deltoides cv. 'angulata' X Populus trichocarpa). Un traitement d'addition d'engrais de 30-60-30 Mg/ha de N-P-K a aussi été testé mais n'a enregistré que peu de changement sur les variables mesurées. Toutes les variables ont été mesurées annuellement durant trois ans. On notait au site de Grande Ligne que les concentrations de N, P et Mg du sol avaient augmenté d'une manière significative al ors qu'au site de Bearbrook la plupart des éléments nutritifs n'avaient subi aucun changement. Les autres variables mesurées sur le sol comprenaient: Ca, K, C organique, pH et densité apparente. Le N et P du feuillage répondaient très fortement au traitement de boues à Grande Ligne, cependant les concentrations de K, Ca et Mg étaient considérées soit non limitantes ou diluées par la croissance. Du site de Bearbrook, le traitement de boues n’avait pas changé le feuillage de façon significative. Après trois ans, la biomasse au site de Grande Ligne avait augmenté de 246% avec le traitement de boues le plus élevé, mais seulement de 35% à Bearbrook. La hauteur et les diamètres des souches montraient des résultats similaires.</description><description>Aerobically-digested municipal sewage sludge was applied at 0, 200, and 400 Mg/ha (wet basis) for two years to a Grande Ligne gravelly sand and a Bearbrook clay that were planted with hybrid poplar (Populus deltoides cv. 'angulata' X Populus trichocarpa). A fertilizer treatment of 30-60-30 Mg/ha N-P-K was also tested but caused few changes to measured variables. All variables were measured annually for three years. Soil N, P, and Mg were significantly increased at the Grande Ligne site, while most nutrients showed no change at the Bearbrook site. Soil Ca, K, pH, org. C and bulk density were the other measured variables. Foliage N and P responded dramatically to sludge treatment at Grande Ligne while K, Ca, and Mg were considered either non-limiting or diluted by growth. Bearbrook foliage did not change significantly due to sludge treatment. Biomass after three years increased by 246% in the highest sludge treatment at Grande Ligne, but only by 35% at Bearbrook. Heights and stump diameters showed similar results.</description><creator>Schwan, Terrence D.</creator><contributor>Jones, A. R. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Fertilizers -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Poplar -- Québec (Province) -- Fertilizers.</subject><subject>Sewage as fertilizer -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>The Effect of Sewage Sludge and Chemical Fertilizer Application on Soils and on the Growth and Yield of Hybrid Poplar</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h999.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064823q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p844</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aspects of the nesting ecology of the Eastern Bluebird (Qialig sigli§) were studied during 1984 and 1985. An analysis of egg measurements revealed that clutch correlated with egg length (p &lt; 0.001), size is significantly width (p &lt; 0.01) and weight (p &lt; 0.001). Egg size decreased as clutch size decreased.Hatching success and egg width were significantly correlated in 1984, with wider eggs being more likely to hatch. This relationship did not exist in 1985. Eggs in 1984 were significantly (p &lt; 0.001) wider than eggs in 1985, but egg lengths were the same in both years. Egg sizes for the study area were similar to those recorded in the literature. […]</description><description>L’écologie de la nidification de Merle Bleu (Sialia sialis) a été étudié au cours des étés 1984 et 1985. Des analyses de variance ont montré une association significative entre la taille de la couvée et la longueur de l'oeuf (p &lt; 0.001), la largeur de l'oeuf (p &lt; 0.01) et le poids de l'oeuf (p &lt; 0.001). La taille des oeufs a diminué avec une diminution de la taille de la couvée. En 1984, une relation significative a toutefois été établie entre la largeur de l'oeuf et le succès d'éclosion. Les oeufs les plus larges ont eu un plus haut succès d'éclosion. Cette relation n'a pas été trouvée en 1985. Les œufs étaient significativement (p &lt; 0.001) plus larges en 1984 qu'en 1985, mais il n'y avait aucune différence entre les longueurs. Les dimensions des oeufs recueillis au site étudié sont semblables aux valeurs présentées dans la littérature. […]</description><creator>Schultz, Birgit C. </creator><contributor>Titman, Rodger D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Eastern bluebird -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Eastern bluebird -- Nests.</subject><subject>Birds -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Aspects of the Nesting Ecology of the Eastern Bluebird (Sialia sialis) in Southwestern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd55g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p844</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795b06s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to investigate the physiological functions of monoamines in the regulation ofsympathetic output at the spinal level. These monoamines are among the various neurochemicals present in the lateral horn, the main site of localization of sympathetic preganglionic neurones, and these chemicals are believed to originate from supraspinal structures. Very little has been done to elucidate the physiological significance of monoaminergic pathways and we have studied the roles of these monoamines in the regulation of sympathetic output using the intrathecal technique. Noradrenaline, adrenaline, dopamine and serotonin were administered at the second or ninth thoracic level and the effects on heart rate and arterial pressure were determined. […]</description><description>Le sujet de cette thèse concerne le rôle physiologique de monoamines dans la régulation des efférences sympathiques au niveau spinal. Ces monoamines coexistent avec d'autres éléments, neurochimiques présents dans la corne latérale, site principal de la distribution des neurones préganglionnaires sympathiques. Ces mêmes monoamines semblent être libérées aux extrémités de voies prenant leur origine dans des structures supraspinales. Peu de travaux ont été consacrés à l'étude du rôle physiologique des voies monoaminergiques. Nous avons choisi d'utiliser la technique intrathécale afin d'étudier le rôle de ces monoamines dans la régulation des efférences sympathiques. La noradrénaline, l'adrénaline, la dopamine et la sérotonine ont été administrées à la hauteur de la seconde (T2) et de la neuvième (T9) vertèbres thoraciques pour en observer les effets sur la pression artérielle et de le rythme cardiaque. […]</description><creator>Romita, Vito Vittorio</creator><contributor>Henry, James Lorne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>Monoamines</subject><title>Effects of Intrathecal Administration of Noradrenaline, Adrenaline, Dopamine and Serotonin on Heart Rate and Arterial Pressure in the Rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m649b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b06s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pz44n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:20:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le littoral de la Barbade offre une occasion excellente pour l’étude des rapports entre l’homme et son environnement. La présence de l’homme depuis la colonisation a entrainé l’elimination de flore indigène et de marécages. Elle a également entraine la construction éventuelle de structures diverses le long des côtes. Par l’an 1900, un payasage largement conçu et aménagé par l’homme s’est substitué au littoral qui existait avant la colonisation. […]</description><description>The Barbados coast affords an excellent opportunity for studying man-environment relationships. Man's presence since settlement led to the elimination of indigenous flora and swamps, and the erection of various structures along the coast. By 1900 the pre-settlement littoral was replaced by a largely roan-made landscape. […]</description><creator>Nurse, Leonard Alfred</creator><contributor>Bird, J. Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>Coastal ecology -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Coast changes -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Barbados -- Population -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Development and Change in the Barbados Leeward Coast: A Study of Human Impact on the Littoral Environment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149s04b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pz44n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4575</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>