<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:55:07Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj35m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A group of five HIV-positive gay men were compared with a group of five HIV-negative gay men. All participants were currently engaged in therapy. Participants completed the Session Evaluation Questionnaire (SEQ) and the Session Impacts Scale (SIS) in order to determine what these different groups of individuals felt was helpful or hindering in therapy. Results indicated that both groups of participants found therapy to be powerful, valuable, and helpful in that they: (a) learned something new about themselves or others, (b) changed their ways of thinking, (c) acquired insight into issues, (d) were more clear about their feelings, (e) were able to define their problems, and (f) were feeling understood, supported, and close to their counsellor. In comparison to the HIV-negative group, the HIV-positive group experienced many hindering aspects to counselling. Seropositive participants felt: (a) less understood, supported, and close to their counsellor, (b) more confused, or distracted in counselling, (c) more bothered by unpleasant thoughts in counselling, (d) more impatient or doubting of the value of therapy, and (e) felt more angry, more afraid, and less confident during and as a result of therapy. Implications for counselling are discussed.</description><creator>Dionne, Gordon R.</creator><contributor>Anastassios, Stalikas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>HIV-positive persons -- Counseling of</subject><title>Helpful and hindering events in therapy with HIV-positive gay men</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk642.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj35m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795971w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Literary criticism has attacked more than once the romantic historical novel condemning it because it was presenting both at a time historical events and historical fiction, what was, according to some critics, encroaching upon the verisimilitude of the historical facts introduced in this kind of novel as well as diminishing the quality of the fictional story while hindering the process of creativity of the writers. Of course, the historical Spanish novel has also suffered from these pessimistic judgements, but it has been accused too of being in no way original for it was taken mainly as an imitation of Scott's works. We do not share this opinion, however, and think on the contrary that Spain has produced great historical fictions which are original from the standpoint of their plots and their characters. In the first part of this thesis we will show how the Spanish hero of the historical, romantic novel is far from the model of hero typically depicted by Scott. The main objective of this study will be to define the entity or the masculine Spanish protagonist of the genre in question. For this purpose, we will compare three protagonists, Usdrobal, Macias and Jimeno, from three chosen Spanish novels, between each other and with other secondary characters, especially with their antagonists. The physical and moral aspects will be particularly underlined as we examine, for example, Lavater's science and, at the same, time, the actions, reactions and attitudes of these protagonists. As a result, we will be able to establish their profile and personality. Parallels will also be made, whenever useful, with other significant Spanish and European characters. In this analysis it will be made clear that these romantic beings who suffer terribly throughout their lives are vulnerable and original in opposition to both the traditional and the Scottian heroes.</description><creator>Dionne, Chantal</creator><contributor>Gaguellon, Perez (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Navarro Villoslada, Francisco, 1818-1895. Doña Blanca de Navarra.</subject><subject>Historical fiction, Spanish -- History and criticism</subject><subject>Romanticism -- Spain</subject><subject>Larra, Mariano José de, 1809-1837. Doncel de don Enrique el doliente</subject><subject>Heroes in literature</subject><subject>Espronceda, José de, 1808-1842. Sancho Saldaña</subject><title>El héroe en la novela histórico-romántica Española : (Macías, de Larra; Sancho Saldaña, de Espronceda, y Doña Blanca de Navarra, de Navarro Villoslada)</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j7505.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795971w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s217f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to answer the following question: Is it ever morally permissible to use a minor child as a tissue or organ donor for the benefit of a family member? Those sceptical of using minors as tissue or organ donors for the benefit of a sick family member will highlight two points: the donor will be subject to risks that are not counterbalanced by possible medical benefits, and the minor cannot consent to the procedure herself. This thesis will present a review of the medical risks associated with bone marrow and kidney donations, as well as a review of the common law dealing with donations by minors and incompetent persons. The final chapter then makes a case for the permissibility of minor donation based on the interests of the family.</description><creator>Crouch, Robert Alan</creator><contributor>Elliott, Carl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc. -- Moral and ethical aspects</subject><subject>Minors</subject><subject>Family -- Moral and ethical aspects</subject><title>The child as tissue and organ donor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r43d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s217f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj2364108</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the connections between three frequently associated nineteenth-century texts, Carlyle's Sartor Resartus, Melville's Moby Dick, and Thoreau's Walden. It begins by reviewing the contexts normally offered for them, and then proposes an alternative one, "dialogic irony," that is based upon the complementary theoretical models of Friedrich Schlegel and Mikhail Bakhtin. After this conceptual background is outlined, the various modes of dialogic irony presented in the three works are discussed. That of Walden arises out of a close analogy between self and text: both are a series of inner voices juxtaposed with and often contradicting one another. Sartor complicates this relatively unobstructed form of selfhood through the inclusion of the Editor, whose unitary voice represents a challenge to the kind of selfhood sanctioned by Walden. Moby Dick also challenges dialogic irony, but its forms of opposition are more penetrating and various: while in Carlyle's text dialogic irony is ultimately affirmed through the figure of Teufelsdrockh, Ishmael is left stranded and displaced by the multitude of voices in his text. Melville's work therefore provides an excellent way to review and critique some of the prevailing assumptions about dialogue in contemporary criticism, a task sketched in the conclusion.</description><creator>Chodat, Robert</creator><contributor>McSweeney, Kerry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Irony in literature</subject><subject>Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881. Sartor resartus</subject><subject>Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862. Walden</subject><subject>Melville, Herman, 1819-1891. Moby Dick</subject><title>Games of circles : dialogic irony in Carlyle's Sartor resartus, Melville's Moby Dick, and Thoreau's Walden</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365730h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj2364108</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr64b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following survey of the literature on the subject of internship, this study reports the findings on a Canadian-wide survey of organizations providing internship to cooperating educational institutions. The findings point clearly to the high degree of importance these organizations attach to internship and the high level of attention and resources that they commit to supervision of interns. They also point to an absence of full understanding of the role of internship and what it can potentially accomplish for both the interns and the participating organizations. In order to fully realize these potentials, the study proposes suggestions to coordinate internship amongst the cooperating institutions as well as interns.</description><creator>Cheong Peng, Niouk Ping</creator><contributor>Lin, Jing (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Internship programs</subject><subject>Supervision of employees</subject><title>Workplace supervision of interns : roles, responsibilities &amp; effects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc30s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr64b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb867</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This exploratory research examines the wage effects of a variety of measures thought to be important in the employment income determination process. It does this by using ordinary least squares multiple regression techniques to construct wage equations for two samples of blue-collar workers in Montreal. Blue-collar wage equations are constructed for: (i) the Montreal labour market and (ii) the Montreal food processing industry. The results of this study show that Montreal blue-collar wages are determined by a variety of factors. Most importantly, however, are the wage effects exhibited by a worker's gender, union membership status and whether or not a worker has received a promotion from his/her present employer. These factors show statistically significant effects on the wages of blue-collar workers in the Montreal labour market as well as on the wages of blue-collar workers in the Montreal food processing industry. The present research also finds that certain factors have distinct wage effects on the different samples of blue-collar workers examined. Data from the present study indicates that the wages of Montreal blue-collar workers are influenced primarily by: (i) on-the-job training, (ii) promotions received, (iii) job opportunities available, (iv) an interruption in one's studies, (v) trade union membership and (vi) gender. While the wages of blue-collar workers employed specifically in the Montreal-area food processing industry are affected principally by: (i) the use of computers, (ii) the use of machines, (iii) promotions received, (iv) a varied work experience, (v) trade union membership, (vi) marital status and (vii) gender. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Calabrese, Tony, 1968-</creator><contributor>Masi, A. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Wages -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Econometric models.</subject><subject>Wages -- Food industry and trade -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Econometric models.</subject><title>The determination of blue collar wages in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn56m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb867</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m883j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From 900 to 1150, major institutional and political changes took hold in Europe. With the advent of the castellans and consolidation of the agnatic noble family, new terms of reference were deployed by writers to reflect these changes. Contributing to the militarization of the aristocracy were exempla and descent myths in house histories and hagiography. Public recitation of this literature thus familiarized the arms-bearer with his heroes, nourished his martial piety and motivated him to defend his patria. Patria also carried an anagogical significance: the heavenly Jerusalem. This permitted its earthly counterpart--Palestine and the literal Jerusalem--to be incorporated into this concept of patria. With the unforseen taking of Jerusalem in 1099, clerical chroniclers in France took the opportunity to cast the pilgrimage and victory in epic terms, reverting to the use of certain conventions of epic intended to motivate arms-bearers in the twelfth century and beyond to defend the Holy Land.</description><creator>Bouskill, Robert H. (Robert Howard)</creator><contributor>Wallis, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Crusades -- First, 1096-1099</subject><subject>Europe -- History -- 476-1492</subject><title>Exempla and lineage : motives for Crusading, 900-1150</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v35g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m883j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t83h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to determine how Galician Jewish emigration during the period 1869-1880 was affected by the Austrian Constitution of 21 December 1867, and in particular by Article IV of said constitution's Fundamental Law Concerning the General Rights of Citizens which granted freedom of movement for the first time to Habsburg subjects. Various demographic, economic, political and societal factors particular to migration, to Galicia and to Galician Jewry are examined in order to establish the effect of the 1867 Constitution on Galician Jewish emigration.</description><creator>Bornstein, Robert J. (Robert Jay)</creator><contributor>Hundert, A. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Galicia (Poland and Ukraine) -- Emigration and immigration -- History -- 19th century</subject><subject>Jews -- Galicia (Poland and Ukraine) -- History -- 19th century</subject><title>Galician Jewish emigration, 1869-1880</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd71v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t83h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz62k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Life for nineteenth century American women was full of restrictions and limitations. Frowned upon or simply not permitted to enter "male" spheres of activity such as professions, business and politics, many middle class women turned to philanthropy and reform work as the sole acceptable outlet for their energy, talents, and time. American Jews of German descent adopted the "Victorian ideal of womanhood" popular in the United States at this time, propelling many German-Jewish women to engage in charitable Zionist activity despite the general lack of support for Zionism in America earlier in this century. Among this group of bourgeois German-Jewish women involved in American Zionism was a poet, Jessie Ethel Sampter, whose contributions to the movement far exceeded those of the norm. Despite her limited Jewish education and upbringing, and extreme physical limitations, Sampter emerged as a pioneer feminist and Zionist, both in America and in her adopted country, Palestine.</description><creator>Blanshay, Susan</creator><contributor>Orenstein, Eugene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Sampter, Jessie E. (Jessie Ethel), 1883-1938</subject><subject>Jewish women -- United States -- Biography</subject><subject>Zionists -- United States -- Biography</subject><title>Jessie Sampter : a pioneer feminist in American zionism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs984.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz62k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032503q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyzes the text of Genesis Rabba, one of the largest and most important of the rabbinic midrashim. It pays particular attention to its use of the term miyyad ("immediately"). Two specific patterns of usage are identified. Through these patterns, the thesis demonstrates how Genesis Rabba's midrash is simultaneously a work of narrative and of exegesis, and comments on some aspects of these two functions. It also traces the lexical evolution of the word miyyad in Hebrew.</description><creator>Aster, Shawn Zelig</creator><contributor>Levy, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>Between exegesis and narrative : the use of miyyaḏ in Genesis Rabba</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763911j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032503q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v36r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores issues of subjectivity and gender around ritual activity in Xianyou county, Fujian Province, China. It focuses on three groups of women: Buddhist nuns, mediums and village women engaged in the ritual caretaking of their families. It also examines a spirit writing text from the late Qing dynasty (1644-1911). It is suggested that subject positions and kin positions are to a certain extent coextensive and that participation in certain rituals is what constitutes one as a gendered subject (as a "woman") and in certain kin roles (as wife, daughter-in-law, etc.). Other gendered subject positions (such as that of melancholic lover) are explored in an attempt to complicate any simple determinism that might accompany to easy a correspondence of kin position with sex role.</description><creator>Anderson, Samantha</creator><contributor>Dean, Kenneth (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Sex role -- China</subject><subject>China -- Social life and customs</subject><title>Gender performativity and ritual performance in South-east China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf903.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v36r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z980g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the outstanding scholars of his time, Sayyid Haydar Amuli (719-787/1319-1385) played an important role in the development of Shii 'Irfan, a tradition which traces its roots back to the Prophet Muhammad and the Imams. He gave his attention to the subject at a time when the Shia Islam began to develop its characteristic set of doctrines through the efforts of 'Allama Hilli and his son Fakhr al-Muhaqqiqin in Iran and Iraq. Sayyid Haydar lived at a time of great political and social upheaval. This thesis places Amuli within this context and describes his life in some detail. Moreover, a number of problems surrounding the corpus of his writings are resolved by a complete listing of his works. Finally, we provide an overview of his doctrines, most especially his ideas concerning the people of sharia, tariqa and haqiqa. Amuli puts great effort into reconciling these three groups, although he consistently maintains a mystical approach in his works. While Amuli accepts Ibn 'Arabis metaphysical doctrines he criticizes his teachings on walaya and Imama. This thesis deals with the issue of Imama from the point of view of Amuli in detail.</description><creator>Agha Tehrani, Morteza</creator><contributor>Landolt, Hermann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Islam -- Doctrines.</subject><subject>Āmulī, Ḥaydar ibn ʻAlī, 14th cent.</subject><title>Sayyid Ḥaydar Āmulī (719-7871319-1385) : an overview of his doctrines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204122j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z980g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z943</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ubiquitous settlement pattern of the American suburb is in fact a carefully constructed reality. Because the vision of the home in the suburbs is very deeply rooted, any development which is considered threatening to this image is met with a defensive reaction. Too often, however, when these NIMBY ("Not In My Back Yard") sentiments are permitted to dictate what is acceptable in a community, housing affordable to low- and moderate-income households is purposely excluded. This thesis explores the processes by which discriminatory NIMBY sentiments are realized as legal development regulations in contemporary suburbs. The historic evolution of the suburbs and the psychological foundations behind their typical characteristics are presented as the sources of a suburban value structure which esteems NIMBY. Suburban governments are mandated to represent their constituents' values, but exclusionary development controls are a complex product of constituent demands, fiscal constraints, and constitutional limits. This analysis reveals that legislative responsibility often bows to political weakness. NIMBY groups use political pressure to manipulate municipal governments into using their vast discretionary powers over development as a weapon for exclusion. In response to either political or fiscal motivations, legislators pressure planners to validate discriminatory legislative agendas with their plans, thus undermining their abilities to guide growth effectively. Although the process of development regulation is well-grounded in historic and legal precedents, when legislation is used for discriminatory ends, citizens' civil and property rights are jeopardized. This thesis explains how regulations such as zoning ordinances can be used for exclusion when municipal government disregards its mandate to be the guardian of the general welfare. Increased awareness of both the motivations and the manifestations of the NIMBY phenomenon may enable individuals as well as lawmakers to create a more equitable suburbia.</description><creator>Steffel, Jennifer Elaine</creator><contributor>Friedman, Avi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Suburbs</subject><subject>Suburban life</subject><title>Storming the suburban fortress : understanding the NIMBY phenomenon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg52k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z943</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375z44q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the aftermath of the succession of abortive planning schemes and the indiscriminate destruction of war (1975-1991), it is the self-inflicted pattern of destruction that has caused the most damage to the urban fabric of Beirut, Lebanon: the reconstruction process itself. Through the examination of pre- and postwar plans and strategies, this study establishes destruction as a framework in the urban history of Beirut. The eradication of cultural heritage and urban memory is evident in the demolition of half the city fabric and the privatization of reconstruction, and continues through the implementation of the proposed market-led rebuilding strategy. This thesis frames the reconstruction of Beirut within comparative methodologies of urban rebuilding in the twentieth century, namely those of post-W.W.II Europe (as manifested in Warsaw and Rotterdam) and those of contemporary market-led urban regeneration (as exemplified by London Docklands). As a critique of the proposed rebuilding of Beirut, it contributes to the re-negotiation of the process and policy of urban reconstruction at the national and international levels.</description><creator>Samara, Rana</creator><contributor>Adams, Annmarie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Urban renewal -- Lebanon -- Beirut</subject><subject>Urban renewal -- Europe</subject><title>Urban reconstruction in the twentieth-century : the postwar deconstruction of Beirut, Lebanon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989558.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z44q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k64z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The CoHousing movement was formed in Denmark in the late 1960's, and has since become established in Scandinavia, central Europe, Australia, and North America. Through collective development and management of pedestrian-oriented housing with shared facilities that supplement individual dwellings, CoHousing fosters the sense of community lacking in other housing options. This increased contact and interaction with neighbors is seen to be particularly beneficial to two of the fastest growing household types--single parents and the elderly. CoHousing units are typically not affordable to a large proportion of these and other groups, however, and thus have tended to be an option primarily reserved for double-income professional households. This paper explores the potential for reducing unit prices in the United States and Canada by identifying and examining five key stages of the CoHousing development process: group formation; development structure; site selection; financing and ownership; and planning, design, and construction. Research was guided by: visits to eight of the thirteen completed CoHousing projects in Canada and the United States; guided interviews with CoHousing developers, architects, builders, and residents; examination of financial proforma and construction drawings; and comparison of CoHousing development procedures with conventional affordable housing development procedures. Results of the study show that while cost-saving strategies in general are more frequently employed than initially anticipated, many are often under-utilized or ineffectively employed. Foremost among the strategies which are infrequently or ineffectively employed are: hiring professional consultants from within the group; selecting sites targeted for redevelopment subsidies; utilizing infill housing strategies; increasing the degree of unit standardization; and increased use of sweat equity in the development of common facilities. The extent to which the measurement of a strategy's effectiveness can be transferred (from one project to another) is limited by the unique location, size, development history, and small number of completed projects. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Reuer, John-Phillip</creator><contributor>Friedman, Avi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Housing, Cooperative -- Canada</subject><subject>Housing, Cooperative -- United States</subject><title>Strategies for reducing costs in the development of cohousing in the United States and Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r87m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k64z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d03t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to explore the concepts of privacy and to propose design patterns for providing privacy for individuals and families in the context of Montreal row houses. The study examines and explores the notion of privacy through a multidisciplinary literature review and links this notion to the row houses. The morphogenesis of row houses, the role of occupants and the built environment in the evolution of privacy issues in this housing type is investigated through a broad historical review and site surveys. The research leads to a series of proposed design patterns which can be used as tools for provision and maintenance of privacy in row houses. Specific consideration is given to present and future housing requirements.</description><creator>Rahbar, Mehrdad</creator><contributor>Sheppard, Adrian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Row houses -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Privacy</subject><title>Privacy in row houses of Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz585.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d03t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838256m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rehabilitation and reconstruction of dilapidated houses in the Old City is now the central issue of urban development of Beijing. On the one hand, it relates to the life of 800,000 people who live in old and dilapidated houses in the old residential quarters; on the other hand, it directly deals with the issue of preservation of the image of the old city. Starting with three pilot projects in 1988, 37 Stage One projects have been completed and some projects of further Stages are in the process of being built within the urban renewal program. However, the result is not so satisfactory in fulfilling its ends. This study is conducted in two main stages: first it attempts to demonstrate the rather complex circumstances which the urban renewal program is encountering. The redevelopment process is examined from the perspectives of political intention, economic limitation, professional dedication as well as concerns of the powers-that-be at different levels. Second, through the in-depth study on the process, preservation of the old city and re-accommodation of the original residents are raised to be the two key issues to evaluate the performance of the program. Detailed discussions are thus held around these two topics. Efforts have also been made to find where the problems lie in order to direct the change of the political intention and consequently result in the adjustment of the policies and practice. Only then is it possible for the redevelopment program not to deviate from its main goals, which are to improve the living conditions of people and to preserve the image of the ancient capital.</description><creator>Lian, Zheng</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Urban renewal -- China -- Beijing</subject><title>Housing renewal in Beijing : observation and analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p392.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838256m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763912t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Postwar North America saw a fundamental change in the function, layout, and location of the parents' bedroom and bathroom in the typical middle-class home. This thesis argues that the representations of bedrooms and bathrooms in house plans published by the Central Mortgage and Housing Corporation (CMHC), in bathroom advertisements which appeared in women's magazines, trade periodicals, and architectural journals, and, in the 1959 film Pillow Talk, point to women's increased power in the immediate postwar years and constitute a foreshadowing of the Women's Liberation Movement of the 1960s. By revisiting the domestic landscape of postwar North America, this thesis provides an account of women's changing role in postwar society and suggests that architecture played a part in this transformation.</description><creator>James, Susan Helen</creator><contributor>Adams, Annmarie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Architecture and women -- North America</subject><subject>Bathrooms -- North America</subject><subject>Bedrooms -- North America</subject><title>"Bedroom problems" : architecture, gender, and sexuality, 1945-63</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365731s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763912t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt71b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Much debate on the conceptualization of race and racism currently exists in the literature. By applying a critical approach to the study of the racism, it will be the basis from which to embark on a theoretically informed review of the literature, and to be able to apply my theoretical framework, which is composed of the following concepts: culture, power and dominance to the problem of racism in social service agencies. Specifically, an examination of current approaches, and the introduction of anti-racism strategies as a viable solution will be documented. It is concluded that there is a need to (1) challenge and modify the current knowledge base on racism in social service agencies; and (2) a need to provide social workers and policy-makers with the necessary tools to combat racism in social service agencies.</description><creator>Yee, June Ying</creator><contributor>Swift, Karen (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Maioni, Antonia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Social service and race relations.</subject><title>A theoretical analysis of racism in social service agencies from a critical perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© June Ying Yee, 1995</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236411j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt71b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117q903</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Astrocytes respond to injury of the central nervous system (CNS) in a process termed reactive astrogliosis. While classically considered detrimental to CNS function, the purpose of reactive astrogliosis is now considered by some to promote CNS recovery. The functional role of reactive astrocytes may be clarified if the molecular mediators of astrogliosis can be identified. This thesis explores the role of cytokines in modulating parameters of astrogliosis both in vitro and in vivo. Studies with astrocytes isolated from uninjured adult mouse brains suggest that these cells have different biological characteristics as compared to neonatal murine astrocytes. On the other hand, IFN-$ gamma$ promotes DNA synthesis in both fetal and adult human astrocytes and inhibits that of neonatal and adult mouse astrocytes. Collectively, these results suggest that both age- and species-specific differences may determine the response of glial cells to cytokines. In addition, the presence of one cytokine may influence the response of astrocytes to another; the simultaneous administration of TNF-$ alpha$ with more potent cytokine mitogens to adult human astrocytes abrogates the effects of the latter. Finally, experiments on neonatal mice in vivo demonstrate their ability to mount an astrogliotic response given an adequate injury stimulus. The presence of cytokines within the lesion site uperegulates this reaction.</description><creator>Tejada-Bergés, Trevor</creator><contributor>Yong, Voon Wee (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Modulation by cytokines of parameters of astrogliosis in vitro and in vivo</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537308m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117q903</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t84s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A model of an artificial ecosystem has been formulated for use as a tool to investigate the dynamics of autonomous biosystems. The model is part of a composite model of an EcoCyborg which consists of an ecosystem and its control system, both of which are contained inside a cylindrical space station. The objectives of this project were to design a model of the ecosystem, and to develop a method for its creation and implementation within the overall framework of the EcoCyborg Project. The modeling approach that has been adopted for the ecosystem model is individual-based and object-oriented. This enables the inclusion of a description of the abiotic environment, as well as of the organisms that inhabit it. A total of 1000 species representing a range of taxonomic groups may be modeled. Individuals in each species are described by their behaviours and phenotypic traits. The ecosystem model will be linked with the other components of the EcoCyborg model in a multi-process simulation under OS/2 Warp. The behaviour of the system will be studied to elucidate preliminary guidelines for the design, maintenance and control of complex systems.</description><creator>Parrott, Lael</creator><contributor>Kok, Robert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biotic communities -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Biological systems -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>The EcoCyborg project : a model of an artificial ecosystem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k657.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t84s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k272</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study concerns the isoform-specific effects of activation of protein kinase C (PKC) and protein kinase A (PKA) on sodium pump activity of HeLa cells transfected with the individual isoform subunits $ alpha$1, $ alpha$2$ sp*$ and $ alpha$3$ sp*$ of the rat Na/K-ATPase, and a truncated mutant of the rat $ alpha$1 isoform, $ alpha$1M32. The asterisks denote forms mutated to be ouabain resistant as described by Jewell, E. A. and Lingrel, J. (1991) J. Biol. Chem. 266, 16925-16930. After activation of PKC it was observed that (i) the activity of the endogenous (human) $ alpha$1, the rat $ alpha$1, $ alpha$2$ sp*$ and $ alpha$3$ sp*$ isoforms, as well as the $ alpha$1M32 truncated mutant were inhibited by $ sim$20%; (ii) no change in the K$ sp+$ response profiles of Na$ sp+$-ATPase activity at low (1 $ mu$M) ATP concentration of the $ alpha$1, $ alpha$2$ sp*$ and $ alpha$3$ sp*$ could be detected and (iii) $ sp{32}$P-labeling of the $ alpha$1 subunit could not be detected. After activation of PKA, it was observed that activity the transfected rat $ alpha$1, $ alpha$2$ sp*$ and $ alpha$3$ sp*$ isoforms was inhibited by $ sim$20%, the rat $ alpha$3$ sp*$ isoform has a reduced apparent affinity for intracellular sodium and the rat $ alpha$2$ sp*$ isoform has a small decrease in apparent affinity for extracellular potassium.</description><creator>Nestor, Nestor Benjamin</creator><contributor>Blostein, Rhoda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Regulation of the NaK-ATPase by protein kinases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b47p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k272</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p9225</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A critical culture requires that the site of appearance, the temporal coincidence of the subject, the object and the site, be acknowledged as a ground for meaning. Through a built investigation and a theoretical address this thesis examines the site of appearance for contemporary creative practice; the extent to which it continues to be defined by and contained within the conceptual frame of the Enlightenment aesthetic as the privileged discourse of the object. In a detailed analysis of the architecture of the exhibition, the 18th century Academy Salon and the Parisian bourgeois hotel are juxtaposed with examples from the late 20th century practice of site-specific exhibition. This comparison reveals an essential connection between art and architecture, between architectural form and social representation. An alternative concept of the exhibition as a site of appearance thereby acknowledges individual, temporally specific interpretation as a potential ground for critical discourse within the contemporary art institution.</description><creator>Bernie, Victoria Clare</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Architecture and society</subject><subject>Art and society</subject><subject>Exhibition buildings</subject><subject>Art exhibition audiences</subject><title>The art of disappearance : the architecture of the exhibition and the construction of the modern audience</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pz03d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p9225</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx46k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Social workers are increasingly being called upon to work with clients who wish to have a child but are unable to do so without medical intervention. This study, a cross-sectional survey design, examines the attitudes of couples towards donor insemination (DI), in vitro fertilization (IVF), contractual pregnancy, adoption and living child free. A random sample of 200 names was drawn from the membership of the Infertility Awareness Association of Canada, Toronto Chapter. Surveys were completed by 74 participants (37 couples). Participants were generally well educated, affluent and ranged in age from 26 to 63 years. Women were one third more likely to report feeling pressure to have children than were men. The source of this pressure was most often reported to be external/interpersonal relationships (e.g., friends, family, partner). Women were significantly more likely to strongly agree that they would use DI or IVF if they were infertile; whereas, men were more likely to only agree when considering DI, and to be unsure or neutral when considering IVF. The possibility of living child free was an alternative that very few participants had seriously considered, as many were still pursuing one or more reproductive alternative. Although significant differences were found within couples for DI, IVF and living child free in the vignettes, unexpectedly an overall theme of agreement between women and men was found as well. In addition, participants revealed a desire for support in their consideration of, and decision making regarding, the reproductive alternatives they may pursue. Clearly, the findings point to the need participants have to receive counselling, and/or follow-up to help them cope with their infertility and the possibility that they may not be able to have children.</description><creator>Ross, Dianne May.</creator><contributor>Cumming-Speirs, Carol (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Human reproductive technology -- Public opinion.</subject><subject>Human reproductive technology -- Ontario -- Toronto.</subject><subject>Infertility Awareness Association of Canada.</subject><title>Infertile couples' attitudes towards reproductive alternatives : a survey of the members of the Infertility Awareness Association of Canada, Toronto Chapter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dianne May Ross, 1996</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333439g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx46k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj4306750</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A numerical model is being developed for ice forecasting which is based on a granular dynamics approach. This model is intended to analyse the movements of broken ice fields at the mesoscale; i.e. for length scales of the order of 100 km and time scales of the order of a few days. It will therefore be useful for navigation, for the operation of offshore drilling platforms and for commercial fishing. At the mesoscale, the forces governing the motion of ice floes are wind drag, water drag, Coriolis force and the contact forces arising from internal collisions. Expressions are developed to evaluate in the most accurate manner the drag exerted by the water and by the wind on individual ice floes by considering non-linear effects. The second aspect of the present work is to modify the inter-particle contacts such that their tangential contribution involves elastic deformation of the ice floes. The effects of an incrementally slipping friction force model are studied for a system where the conditions vary from a quasi-static to a rapid flow regime. Under these circumstances the model is found to adequately reproduce the behaviour of small scale laboratory experiments using aluminum cylinders. Computations performed with tangentially rigid particles yield a system which is very unstable in its behaviour. The analysis of the macroscopic variables, made in order to determine how a broken ice field is affected by the shearing effects of the particles, shows that for a rapidly flowing field the elastic contribution to the contact shear force is minor, if not negligible, when one considers long time averages or instantaneous values. It appears from these investigations that attention must be paid to the problem of ice floes flowing under quasi-static or transitional conditions.</description><creator>Renaut, Nathalie.</creator><contributor>Savage, Stuart B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Granular dynamics simulations of wind-driven, broken ice fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x94s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj4306750</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>