<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:34:11Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37900" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63t0869</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une étude préliminaire menée dans notre laboratoire a démontré que chez des volontaires sains, le conditionnement contextuel peut conduire à une augmentation de l'anxiété et de la sensibilité à la douleur (hyperalgésie dépendant du contexte). Ainsi, la mémoire d'une douleur antérieure peut affecter la sensibilité douloureuse ultérieure. De plus, il a été démontré que la consolidation de la mémoire émotionnelle nécessite l'activation noradrénergique de l'amygdale. Le but de ce projet est d'étudier comment le conditionnement contextuel et la réduction de l'activation noradrénergique affecte la perception ainsi que la tolérance à la douleur. Au cours de cette étude, réalisée par des mesures répétées en double-aveugle, nous avons examiné la possibilité de bloquer l'hyperalgésie contextuelle par l'utilisation du propranolol, β-bloquant adrénergique central, qui réduit l'activation sympathique durant la consolidation de la mémoire douloureuse chez des volontaires sains. Les participants ont assisté à deux sessions psychophysique expérimentales et on été assignés au hasard au groupe contrôle placebo (n=21) ou au groupe expérimentale propranolol (n=20). Tous les sujets ont répondus au questionnaire « Profile of Mood State » et ont subi les mêmes tests douloureux aux deux sessions afin d'évaluer et comparer leurs sensibilité à la douleur. Les capsules de propranolol ou placebo ont été données aux sujets à la fin de la première session. Quoiqu'on ait enregistré leurs réponses physiologiques à la douleur, nos critères d'évaluation principaux des résultats étaient les cotations du caractère désagréable et l'intensité des stimuli douloureux. Nous avons émis l'hypothèse qu'une réduction de l'activation noradrénergique avec le propranolol pendant la phase de conditionnement diminuera l'hyperalgésie dépendant du contexte. En terme de nos critères d'évaluations principaux, nous anticipions que les cotations du caractère désagréable et l'intensité des stimuli douloureux resteraient stable ou diminueraient dans le groupe expérimental, tandis que le groupe placebo reviendrai plus sensible et coterait les stimuli en tant que plus désagréables et douloureux. Bien que notre manipulation n'ait pas augmenté l'anxiété, nos sujets contrôles sont revenus plus énervés à la seconde session. De plus, tous nos participants étaient physiologiquement plus réactifs aux stimuli douloureux malgré le fait que le conditionnement au contexte n'a pas causé d'hyperalgésie dépendant du contexte. Au lieu, les cotations de l'intensité et du caractère désagréable ont diminués aient d'une session à l'autre dans les deux groupes. Malgré l'effet d'habituation, il est clair que la mémoire d'évènements douloureux et le contexte dans lequel ces mémoires sont acquises peuvent affecter les individus sur le plan psychologique et physique. Enfin, notre étude démontre que la modulation de l'activation sympathique par le propranolol peut avoir un effet sur le phénomène d'hyperalgésie contextuelle. Quoiqu'il soit utile d'être sur ses gardes lorsqu'on revient dans un contexte ou nous avons subi de la douleur, à long terme ces réactions poseraient un désavantage puisque l'individu pourrait être plus sensible aux futurs stimuli douloureux.  Ceci pourraient peut-être une des causes de la douleur chroniques.  </description><description>In a previous pilot study an experimental paradigm in healthy volunteers was developed, which indicated that context conditioning leads to increased anxiety and increased pain sensitivity (i.e. context dependent hyperalgesia). This evidence suggests that the memory for pain influences subsequent pain perception. Additionally, it has been demonstrated that the consolidation of memories for emotionally arousing experiences involves noradrenergic activation of the amygdala. The aim of this study was to investigate how context conditioning and decreased noradrenergic activation affects the perception of pain unpleasantness and intensity in addition to pain tolerance. This double-blind, repeated measures study investigated whether we could obstruct the phenomenon of context-dependent hyperalgesia by using the centrally acting β-adrenergic blocker propranolol to decrease sympathetic activation during the consolidation for pain memories in healthy volunteers. Participants underwent two psychophysical testing sessions and were randomly assigned to the experimental propranolol group (n=20) or the placebo control group (n=21). All subjects filled out the Profile of Mood State questionnaire and underwent the same experimental pain tests in both sessions in order to assess and compare their pain sensitivity. Propranolol or placebo capsules were given to the subjects at the end of the first session. Although we recorded subjects' physiological response to pain, our main outcome measure of interest were unpleasantness and intensity ratings. We hypothesized that decreasing sympathetic activation with propranolol during the conditioning phase would inhibit context-dependent hyperalgesia from occurring. In terms of our outcome measures, we expected unpleasantness and intensity ratings to remain the same or decrease in the propranolol group while the placebo group would return more reactive and rate the pain as more unpleasant and intense.Although our manipulation did not increase feelings of anxiety, control subjects did return more aroused. Furthermore, all subjects were more reactive to painful stimuli on an implicit physiological level despite the fact that context-conditioning did not create context-dependent hyperalgesia.  Instead, most pain ratings of intensity and unpleasantness decreased from one session to the next in both groups. Despite the effect of habituation, it is clear that memories of pain and the context in which they were acquired do affect individuals in a psychological and physical manner. We have also demonstrated that modulating the sympathetic tone with propranolol can affect these changes in an experimental setting. Although it might be helpful to be on guard when returning to an environment where you've experienced pain, this experiment highlights that pain memories could be maladaptive by making individuals more sensitive and reactive to future noxious stimuli. In many chronic pain states, it is still unknown how enhanced pain sensitivity is generated and maintained. Perhaps pain memories could be one of the driving forces creating chronic pain. </description><creator>Laferrière, Audrey</creator><contributor>Petra Schweinhardt (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>The effects of contextual conditioning and inhibition of sympathetic activation on pain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m6006.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t0869</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85ng26f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chronic low back pain is one of the most common problems of all age groups worldwide. If conservative treatment fails, the following surgical options – depending on the underlying cause - currently apply: lumbar discectomy, disc arthroplasty or fusion surgery as the ultimate procedure. An emerging technique, nucleoplasty, aims at targeting early stages of disc degeneration. There are various mechanical, polymeric or tissue engineered devices for nucleus pulposus replacement, some of which have been subjects of studies and clinical trials. We are already looking back at a history of failed devices; as well, complications have been reported such as migration, extrusion and subsidence. On most devices, no long-term data are available yet. Our theory is that for any successful nucleus pulposus replacement in order to stabilize, delay or even improve lumbar disc degeneration, an appropriate cavity has to be created prior to injection or implantation of a new device. The current gold standard procedure to get nucleus pulposus material out of the intervertebral disc is the classic open microdiscectomy which is performed with pituitary rongeurs. Another surgical procedure of a percutaneous nuclectomy via arthroscopic shavers was investigated and the outcome – size and location of the created cavity - compared with the established rongeur-method, using three different approaches: anteriolateral, posteriolateral and posterior access to the intervertebral disc. The cavities were larger when created with the rongeurs, however, after some modification of instruments, for example curved shavers, nuclectomy via automated shavers might be a good and less invasive surgical alternative. </description><description>Les lombalgies chroniques sont l'un des problèmes les plus communs de tous  les groupes d'âges dans le monde entier. Dans le cas d'un échec du traitement conservateur, les options chirurgicales suivantes - dépendamment des causes sous-jacentes - s'appliquent couramment : une discectomie lombaire, une arthroplastie du disque ou une arthrodèse comme procédure ultime. Une technique émergeante, la nucléoplastie, vise à cibler les stades précoces de la dégénération des disques. Il existe plusieurs implants variés pour le remplacement du nucléus pulposus tels que mécaniques, polymériques ou la régénérescence tissulaire, dont certains ont été le sujet d'études et d'épreuves cliniques. L'histoire nous ramène à une série d'implants ayant échouées puisqu'en effet, plusieurs complications ont été rapportées telles que la migration, l'extrusion et la rémission de l'implant. Présentement, aucune donnée à long-terme n'est disponible sur la plupart des procédures. Notre théorie est qu'une cavité appropriée doit être créée afin d'injecter ou d'insérer de façon optimale un nouvel implant pour qu'ainsi les remplacements de nucléus pulposus puissent stabiliser, retarder ou même améliorer la dégénération des disques intervertébraux. La procédure courante préconisée pour extraire la matière du nucleus pulposus du disque intervertébral est la microdiscectomie classique performée avec des rongeurs pituitaires. En utilisant les trois approches suivantes; antérolatérale, posterolatérale et l'accès postérieure au disque intervertébral, une autre procédure chirurgicale; nucléectomie percutanée via lames d'arthroscopies a été étudiée. Ses résultats – la grandeur et la localisation de la cavité créée- ont été comparé à la méthode-rongeur déjà établie. Les résultats démontrent que les cavités étaient plus larges lorsque créées avec les rongeurs. Toutefois, la modification de certains instruments,comme par exemple des lames plus incurvées, pourrait rendre la nuclectomie via lames automatisées une alternative chirurgicale meilleure et moins envahissante.</description><creator>Huemmer, Carmen</creator><contributor>Thomas B Steffen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Evaluation of a novel surgical procedure for removal of the nucleus pulposus in lumbar intervertebral discs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494d441.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85ng26f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kx95f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>July 2007 saw the opening of Canada's largest Hindu temple. The monumental structure, located in a suburban-industrial neighbourhood of Toronto, Ontario, cost nearly forty million dollars to build, every dollar of which was raised by the temple's congregants, and was constructed largely through the efforts of volunteers. Built according to ancient architectural principles prescribed in Hinduism's oldest sacred texts, and made almost entirely of marble stones individually handcrafted in India, it is the fourth temple of its kind in North America, and the fifth in the Western World. Prime Minister Stephen Harper attended the opening, and declared Canada's new "architectural wonder" a symbol of our country's ethnic and religious pluralism. As the Canadian public celebrated the construction of the BAPS Mandir, they simultaneously chronicled the story of another Hindu community in the Greater Toronto Area in a much less reverential tone: the campaign led by the Hindu Federation to secure a waterfront site in one of GTA's parks for Hindu funeral ceremonies. The campaign was roundly criticized in the name of environmental concerns and multiculturalism's failure to promote integration. This thesis explores the complex and often contradictory ways in which Canadian multiculturalism is constructed in official and public discourse with these two sites as a focusing lens. Determining how, in one moment the Hindu community is a source of pride, and in another, a source of pollution and anxiety, I look at the role of emotions and feelings in processes of inclusion and exclusion, and I trace the emergence of a new articulation of the relationship between ethno-cultural minorities, the nation and national citizenship. Further, I explore the way in which these two sites mediate discourses and articulations of multiculturalism by addressing the suburban locales in which they are situated, and the modes of urban citizenship these sites make possible. I develop the concept of "suburban multiculturalism" to account for the new realities and challenges posed by the transformations in Canada's urban, cultural and political environment.</description><description>En juillet 2007 le Canada a vu l'ouverture du plus grand temple Hindou. Cette structure monumentale qui se trouve dans un banlieu industriel de Toronto (en Ontario), a coûté presque quarante millions de dollars pour construire. Cette somme assez spectaculaire a été recueilli par les congregants du temple et le batîment a été construit en grand parti par les efforts des bénévoles. Construit suivant des principes architecurales préscrit par les anciens textes sacrées de l'Hindouisme, et bâti presque entièrement de pierres marbrés faites individuellement par la main en Inde, c'est le quatrième temple de ce type en Amérique du Nord et le cinquième dans le monde occidentale.  Le Premier Ministre Stephen Harper qui était présent à son ouverture a déclaré le temple la nouvelle "merveille architecturale" du Canada, un symbole du pluralisme culturel et religieux du pays. En même temps que le public canadien célébrait la construction du BAPS Mandir comme un testament du succès du multiculturalisme au Canada, les demandes d'une autre communauté Hindou dans le Greater Toronto Area (GTA) ont reçu un traitement considérablement moins révérentiel: la Fédération Hindou de la GTA cherchait à établir un site  au bord du lac dans un des parcs publics de la ville pour ses cérémonies funérailles. Cette demande a été extrêmement critiquée au nom de concernes environmentaux et a suggérée l'échec du multiculturalisme dans la promotion de l'intégration. En mobilisant ces deux examples phares dans les communautés Hindou à Toronto, cet thèse considère les façons complexes et souvent contradictoires dont le multiculturalisme est construit au Canada dans le discours public et officiel. Considérant comment, dans un instant, la communauté Hindou est une source de fièreté, et dans un autre, une source de la pollution et de l'anxiété, j'éxamine la place des émotions et des sentiments dans les processus de l'inclusion et l'exclusion et je trace l'émergence d'une nou  velle articulation dans les relations qui se manifestent entre les minorités ethno-culturelles, la nation, et la citoyennété nationale. De plus, ma thèse considère les façons par lesquelles ces deux sites négocient les discours et les articulations du multiculturalisme en étudiant les quartiers des banlieues dans lesquels ces discours se situent, et les modes de la citoyennété urbaine que ces sites rendent possible. Dans cette thèse je dévéloppe le concept du "multiculturalisme des banlieues" pour répondre à des nouveaux réalités et défis posés par les transformations dans l'environnement urbain, culturel et politique au Canada.</description><creator>Lista, Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Jennifer C Burman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Social Sciences - Canadian Studies </subject><title>Encountering multiculturalism in suburban Ontario: sacred Hindu space, citizenship and Canadian multiculturalism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418s369.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx95f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vw05r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a particular set of spheres as new representation of the shape of a 3D solid. The spheres considered are maximal inscribed spheres in the solid and their centres are chosen in such a way that at most one sphere centre lies in a cubic region of space.The shape representation proposed is a discretization of the medial surface transform of a solid. Part I of this thesis presents algorithms for the computation of this representation given a boundary representation of a solid by approximating its medial surface transform. Properties of those medial spheres that are not detected by our algorithm in 3D are described and a complete characterization of those medial circles that are not detected by a 2D version of our algorithm is given. In Part II, recent results from differential geometry are used to compute principal curvatures and principal curvature directions on the boundary of the smooth solid represented using the union of medial spheres.  This computation is performed using only the medial sphere centres and a pair of points on each medial sphere that lies on the surface of the solid being modeled. It is shown how the union of medial spheres allows a part-based description of the solid, with a significance measure associated with each part. In Part III, it is shown that our shape representation can offer a tight volumetric fit to a polyhedron, using a small number of spheres. The spheres used in our representation can be quickly updated as the solid undergoes a certain class of deformations. It is shown how our set of medial spheres allows efficient and accurate proximity queries between polyhedra.</description><description>Cette thèse présente une nouvelle représentation de la forme de solides 3D, décrite par un ensemble spécifique de sphères.  Les sphères de cette représentation sont des sphères inscrites maximalement dans le solide et leur centre est choisi de telle manière que tout au plus un seul centre de sphère occupe une région cubique de l'espace. La représentation de forme proposée est une discrétisation de la surface médiane d'un solide. La première partie de cette thèse présente des algorithmes pour le calcul de cette représentation à partir d'une description de la frontière d'un solide, en approximant sa surface médiane. Certaines propriétés des sphères médianes qui ne sont pas détectées par notre algorithme en 3D sont décrits, ainsi qu'une caractérisation complète des cercles médians qui ne sont pas détectés par une version 2D de l'algorithme.En deuxième partie, des résultats récents en géométrie différentielle sont utilisés pour calculer les courbures principales et les directions principales de courbure sur la surface d'un solide lisse représenté par une union de sphères médianes. Ce calcul est effectué en utilisant seulement le centre et une paire de points relatifs à chaque sphère médiane qui se trouve sur la surface du solide. Il est aussi démontré comment l'union des sphères médianes permet une description par partie du solide, tout en donnant une mesure de l'importance associée à chaque partie.En troisième partie, il est démontré que notre représentation de forme peut servir à l'ajustement volumétrique serré d'un polyèdre, tout en utilisant un nombre restreint de sphères. Les sphères utilisées dans notre représentation peuvent être rapidement adaptées au solide lorsqu'il est sujet à une certaine classe de déformations.  Notre ensemble de sphères médianes permet d'effectuer des requêtes de proximité efficaces et précises entre des polyèdres.</description><creator>Stolpner, Svetlana</creator><contributor>Kaleem Siddiqi (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Sue Whitesides (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Medial spheres for shape representation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89db59w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vw05r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95054605</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les simulateurs physiques et informatiques sont fréquemment utilisés pour aider les résidents et étudiants en médecine à pratiquer les techniques chirurgicales. Dans la salle d'opération, il y a souvent des distractions auditives. Actuellement, il y a peu d'études qui examinent l'effet de la complexité des tâches et la capacité de faire plusieurs choses à la fois sur la performance des chirurgiens experts et des novices dans la salle d'opération. Nous avons étudié comment l'entrainement à l'aide d'un simulateur chirurgical peut aider à développer l'automaticité. Avec le simulateur informatique LapSim, nous avons examiné l'effet d'une tâche supplémentaire sur l'exécution de tâches laparoscopiques. Nous avons augmenté le niveau de difficulté de la tâche chirurgicale pour amplifier  tout effet de la distraction sur la performance et pour  déterminer si les participants pouvaient réaliser deux choses simultanément. Une étude de cohorte de 24 participants (étudiants en médecine et chirurgiens experts) ont complété la tâche technique de couper un vaisseau sanguin sur la LapSim au début. Ensuite, on a posé des questions mathématiques aux participants (tâche cognitive). Durant la phase d'évaluation, les participants ont complété la tâche technique sur le simulateur et la tâche cognitive en même temps. Cette étude s'ajoute à un nombre croissant d'expertises concernant la capacité qu'ont les chirurgiens résidents d'effectuer plusieurs tâches simultanément et de manière automatique lors de procédures chirurgicales. </description><description>Physical and computer-based simulators are used to help residents and medical students practise various surgical techniques. Within the operating room, auditory cognitive distractions often occur. Currently, limited studies examine the effect of increasing task complexity and multi-tasking on expert and novice performance in the operating room. We studied how training on a surgical simulator leads to the development of automaticity. With the LapSim computer simulator, the effect of a secondary dual task on performance of laparoscopic skills tasks was examined. We increased the level of surgical task difficulty to amplify any effects of distraction on performance and to see whether participants could dual-task. A cohort study of 24 participants (undergraduate medical students and expert staff) completed the technical task of cutting a blood vessel on the LapSim at baseline. Participants were then asked only math questions (cognitive task). In the evaluation phase, participants completed both the technical task on the simulator and the cognitive task of answering math questions. We found that expert surgeons were able to dual task at both easy and medium levels of difficulty. This study adds to the growing literature of how dual-tasking and automaticity are achieved as residents learn surgical tasks. </description><creator>Thakkar, Vidhi</creator><contributor>Gerald M Fried (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Measuring the effect of an auditory cognitive distraction on technical and cognitive performance during a simulated laparoscopic procedure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p228g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95054605</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29bb05f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With a superior transmittance in the mid-infrared, fluoride fibers such as ZBLAN fibers can be used to develop fiber-based components for that spectrum. In this thesis, we investigate the fusion splicing of ZBLAN fibers as well as the fabrication of long-period gratings and Mach-Zehnder interferometer structures. Average losses in the range of 0.23-0.31 dB are achieved for the fusion splicing among multi-mode and single-mode ZBLAN fibers. In the C- and O-bands, notches of depths ranging from 6-17 dB are obtained with mechanically induced long-periog gratings. All-fiber Mach-Zehnder interferometers are also demonstrated by cascading the long-period gratings. An equation used to calculate the relation between the fringe spacing and the separation length shows that the smallest and the largest difference compared to the measurements are 1.81% and 7.37%, respectively.</description><description>Avec une transmission supérieure dans l'infrarouge moyen, des fibres de fluorure telles que des fibres de ZBLAN peuvent être employées pour développer les composants à fibres pour ce spectre. Dans cette mémoire, nous étudions les épissures ainsi que la fabrication des réseaux à long pas et des interféromètres Mach-Zehnder. Des pertes moyennes dans la gamme de 0.23-0.31 dB sont obtenues pour les épissures parmi des fibres multi-modales et unimodales. Dans les bandes C et O, la profondeur des bandes atténuées varie entre 6-17 dB avec des réseaux à long pas. Des interféromètres Mach-Zehnder sont également démontrés en cascadant les réseaux à long pas. Une équation pour calculer la relation entre l'espacement de frange et la longueur de séparation prouve que la plus petite et la plus grande différence comparée aux mesures sont 1.81% et 7.37%, respectivement.</description><creator>Lu, Hsin-yu</creator><contributor>Lawrence R Chen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Development of ZBLAN fiber-based components</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784q541.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29bb05f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w635q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dynamic processes in nonequilibrium liquid-solid systems are studied over mesoscopic time scales and atomistic length scales using phase-ﬁeld crystal (PFC) models. Various freezing and melting transitions are examined in two and three dimensions, and microscopic phenomena responsible for solid-phase plasticity are investigated. A primary focus is on the issue of describing atomistic dynamics over time scales that are generally inaccessible to conventional approaches. Glass forming dynamics in supercooled liquids near a glass transition are studied numerically, and the central features of the transition, including a number of behaviors previously undemonstrated within PFC / classical density functional theory simulations, are successfully reproduced. A connection between the liquid dynamic correlation length and transition fragility is identiﬁed, and a physically motivated time scaling applied to the simulation data is shown to generate qualitative agreement with basic glass transition phenomenology across 12 orders of magnitude in time. The competing processes of amorphous precursor nucleation and crystallization in diffusion-dominated spinodal and non-spinodal simple liquids are also examined. Melting and premelting transitions in defected body-centered cubic solids are studied numerically, and a localized melting theory based on defect elastic energies is formulated. Basic features of the dynamic phase separation patterns that develop in growing heteroepitaxially strained alloy ﬁlms are also outlined based on numerical simulations of a binary PFC model. Finally, dislocation dynamics are examined in strained periodic systems. The central features of dislocation glide, climb, and annihilation are shown to naturally emerge within PFC models, and the dynamics of individual dislocations are found to reduce to a simple generalized equation of motion.</description><description>Des procédés dynamiques dans des systèmes liquide-solide non-équilibrés sont étudiés au cours d'échelles de temps mésoscopiques et d'échelles de longueur atomistiques en utilisant des modèles « phase-field crystal » (PFC). Diverses transitions de congélation et de fusion sont examinées en deux et trois dimensions, et les phénomènes microscopiques responsables de la plasticité des phases solides sont étudiées. Un accent est mis sur la problématique des dynamiques atomistiques au cours d'échelles de temps qui sont généralement inaccessibles aux approches conventionnelles. Les dynamiques de formation vitreuse dans les liquides metastables surfondus près d'une transition vitreuse sont étudiés numériquement, et les caractéristiques centrales de la transition, y compris un certain nombre de comportements qui n'ont pas été démontrées précédemment par les modèles PFC / simulations de la théorie classique densité fonctionnelle, sont reproduites avec succès. Un lien entre la longueur de corrélation dynamique liquide et la fragilité est identifié, et il est démontré par une normalisation de temps physiquement motivé, appliquée aux données de simulation, qu'il y a une correspondance qualitative avec des bases phénomènes de transition vitreuse sur 12 ordres de grandeurs de temps. Les procédés concurrentiels de la nucléation de précurseurs amorphes et de la cristallisation dominées par la diffusion dans les liquides simples spinodaux et non-spinodaux sont aussi examinés. Les transitions de fusion et pré-fusion dans des solides cubiques centrés ayant des défauts sont étudiés numériquement, et une théorie de fusion localisée basée sur les énergies élastiques des défauts est formulée. Des caractéristiques de base des motifs de la séparation de phase dynamique qui se développent pendant la croissance des films tendus heteroepitaxiellement sont également etudiés en utilisant des simulations numériques d'un modèle binaire PFC. Enfin, les dynamiques des dislocations sont examinées dans les systèmes périodiques tendus, ainsi il est démontré que les caractéristiques fondamentales des procédés de glisse, d'escalade, et d'annihilation émergent naturellement des modèles PFC.</description><creator>Berry, Joel</creator><contributor>Martin Grant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Physics - Solid State</subject><title>Liquid-solid systems out of equilibrium: phase-field crystal studies of solidification, melting, and plasticity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x7900.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w635q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r67w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente thèse étudie le processus d'extraction de valeur des systèmes de gestion intégrée (ERP). La prémisse principale de cette thèse est que la différence de performance entre les organisations qui investissent dans des systèmes ERP similaires puisse être attribuée à la façon dont le système est intégré avec l'infrastructure technologique actuelle et les processus d'affaires de l'organisation. Basé sur la littérature en entrepreneuriat et en intégration, cette thèse fait le point sur les antécédents et les impacts de l'intégration d'un module ERP. Pour mieux comprendre ce phénomène, cette thèse adopte une approche multi-méthode repartie sur trois articles. Le premier article examine comment l'intégration est accomplie à travers le niveau d'alerte et de recherche des gestionnaires, ce dernier dépendant du gap perçu entre le système et les processus d'affaires actuels. Le deuxième article développe et propose une mesure d'intégration dans un contexte ERP au niveau du module. Finalement, le dernier article applique la notion d'intégration pour mieux comprendre ses antécédents et son effet sur la performance des processus d'affaires. Tous les articles sont empiriques : études de cas pour le premier et enquête pour les deux autres articles. Ces articles peuvent être vus comme les composantes formant une vision complémentaire de l'investigation de la création de valeur des systèmes de gestion intégrée à travers le processus d'intégration. </description><description>This thesis studies the process of extracting business value from Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) through integration. The main premise is that performance differences across firms investing in similar ERP systems can be attributed to differences in the way the technology (ERP) is integrated with the actual IT infrastructure and business processes of the firm. Drawing on the entrepreneurship and integration literature, this thesis focuses on the antecedents of integration and its impact on business process performance. To better understand this phenomenon, this thesis adopts a multi-method and multi-essay approach. The first essay looks at how different degrees of integration are achieved by looking at the effect of managers' alertness and search activity on integration. It also demonstrates the influence of perceived gap as a trigger of search. The second essay develops and proposes a measure of integration in an ERP context at the module level. Finally, the last essay applies the notion of integration to better understand its effect on business process performance by looking at its antecedents and how different degrees of integration influence the performance of the business processes. All essays are empirical; case studies for the first one and survey for the last two essays. These essays can be seen as components of an integrative investigation of the issue of ERP value creation through integration, which is likely to help us understand how and under which circumstances ERP systems can produce value for the firms implementing them. </description><creator>Gagnon, Elisa</creator><contributor>Alain Pinsonneault (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Business Administration - General</subject><title>Extracting value from enterprise resource planning: a closer look at integration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612s73x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r67w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451n68g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Grâce à plusieurs applications prometteuses---en particulier dans le champ de l'informatique quantique---les points quantiques (PQ) auto-assemblées ont récemment merité beaucoup d'attention. Tandis que tels structures presentent des obstacles aux méthodes traditionnelles de characterization, des nouveaux avancements théoriques et expérimentals démontrent l'utilization d'un oscillateur d'une microscope à force atomique (AFM) pour characterizer la dynamique des electrons dans l'échantillon.  Cette technique profite du fait que la force électrostatique entre l'AFM et le PQ dépend de la charge, qui change selon la position de l'oscillateur. Le résultat est une force variable qui produit des changements dans la fréquence résonante et la dissipation méchanique de l'oscillateur. Dans cette thèse, une exploration theorique considère le cas où l'oscillateur interagit avec deux points quantiques à la fois.  En plus de la charge totale du système, il faut maintenant considérer sa distribution entre les deux points quantiques. Cette distribution, qui peut changer par l'entremise des effets tunnels et cohérents et incohérents, répond à la motion de l'oscillateur, produisant des effets dynamics qui devraient être mesurables dans une large étendue des régimes expérimentals.</description><description>Self-assembled quantum dots have attracted recent interest because of their broad potential applications to quantum information processing and fundamental research. While such structures present many obstacles to standard electronic characterization, recent experimental and theoretical work has demonstrated the use of a capacitively coupled AFM cantilever as a sensitive probe of quantum dot charge dynamics. The work in this thesis extends previous theoretical results to explore the case of an AFM tip coupled to a double quantum dot. Compared to single dot results, the DQD system involves significant new physical phenomena. In addition to fluctuations in the total charge, the double dot system can respond to the cantilever through changes in the distribution of a single electron. In particular, new features arise due to coherent interdot tunneling. After presenting the theoretical approach to this problem, we will discuss the results in the context of current experimental efforts using InAs dots. These effects should be accessible in a wide variety of experimental regimes.</description><creator>Gardner, Jamie</creator><contributor>Clerk, Aashish (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Physics - Theory</subject><title>Mechanically probing charge dynamics in double quantum dots</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c659s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451n68g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b951</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse s'intéresse aux films tamouls portant sur Ammaṉ «ammaṉ paṭaṅkaḷ», genre cinématographique propre au sud de l'Inde consacré à la figure terrifiante de la déesse Māriyammaṉ. Ce travail analyse ces films dans le contexte des classes et des castes qui caractérisent le sud de l'Inde. Il s'agit en particulier d'étudier la manière dont la classe moyenne indienne émergente participe aux transformations qui touchent la représentation de la femme et les pratiques religieuses de cette région. Le statut de la classe moyenne est un thème dominant et récurrent dans les films portant sur Ammaṉ, ces derniers exploitant et négociant constamment les idées de «tradition» et «modernité». Je montre que les films exposent aussi bien qu'ils consolident les conceptions de la classe moyenne sur les pratiques de la religion et les femmes, tout en ayant une portée pédagogique pour les spectateurs, autrement dit tout en proposant une manière d'être classe moyenne.</description><description>This thesis examines Tamil Ammaṉ films (ammaṉ paṭaṅkaḷ), a specific genre of South Indian cinema that centres on the figure of the fierce goddess Māriyammaṉ. The study analyzes the films in the context of class and caste in South India, focusing specifically on how India's emergent middle class has shaped changing constructions of womanhood and religious practice in South India. Middle-class status is an overarching and recurrent theme in Ammaṉ films, which also consistently deploy and negotiate ideas about "tradition" and "modernity". I argue that the films themselves both represent and reify middle-class notions of religiosities and womanhood, while simultaneously serving a pedagogical purpose for audiences, namely, articulating a way of being middle class.</description><creator>Blake, Lisa</creator><contributor>Davesh Soneji (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Religion - Religion General</subject><title>Visualizing Amman: womanhood, the goddess, and middle-class modernity in Tamil religious cinema</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd65d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b951</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fn26q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the field of bioethics, the relatively recent phenomenon of cognitive enhancement—the idea that one might improve upon their typical, or "healthy," level of intellect through the use of pharmaceuticals developed to treat medical conditions—has garnered considerable interest from bioethicists and the popular media. The high level of coverage related to this phenomenon has prompted concern that a misrepresentation of the scientific facts related to the safety and efficacy of the drugs involved may encourage public interest, with potentially negative effects on social conformity and loss of diversity.One drug in particular, donepezil, has become known as a "cognitive enhancement agent" based mainly on the findings of one small-scale study. Its genesis from contested Alzheimer's drug to revolutionary "smart-pill" has provoked questions related to the level of evidence driving this reconceptualization. Recent reviews have determined that the findings of the primary study were limited, and additional analysis of a possible link between donepezil and a cognitive enhancement effect have also found the study to be lacking. This thesis characterizes how media and bioethics literature has shaped the discourse of donepezil as a cognitive enhancement agent in the absence of solid scientific evidence. A systematic content analysis was conducted to determine how media and bioethics articles portray donepezil and present the results of the landmark study. We found much hype of the possibility that donepezil could produce cognitive enhancement effects in typical individuals. Additionally, we identified a complex interaction between high expectations for a cognitive enhancement effect and ambiguous conclusions at the level of the primary paper. Together, these factors contribute to the portrayal of donepezil as a cognitive enhancement agent in secondary literature and point to important consequences for individual decision making, clinical care, and policy development. Further, hype of the phenomenon of cognitive enhancement implies that there is general interest in the goal of increasing intelligence and inspires interest in further examining why we are so involved in this end. Propagating the ideology driving those captivated by cognitive enhancement may negatively affect people with intellectual disabilities. To explore the connection between the desire to enhance cognition in typical individuals and a potential negative effect on people with intellectual disabilities, we introduce a distinct example of media hype related to drugs that target intelligence in this population. Failure to question the underlying assumptions that are driving the cognitive enhancement debate amongst individuals with typical intelligence risks further devaluing the lives of people with intellectual disability and subverting current social movements to empower these individuals and build a truly accepting and diverse society.</description><description>L'utilisation, par des individus sains, de médicaments pour améliorer leurs fonctions cognitives suscite l'attention autant des bioéthiciens que des médias. L'importante couverture médiatique de ce récent phénomène soulève la préoccupation qu'une fausse représentation des données scientifiques, relativement à la sécurité et à l'efficacité de ces médicaments, pourrait, par conséquent, éveiller l'intérêt du public. Potentiellement, cela pourrait causer des effets négatifs au plan social, par exemple, en encourageant la conformité et donc une perte de la diversité.Un médicament en particulier, le donépézil, s'est vu reconnu comme étant un « produit d'amélioration des fonctions cognitives ». Cette affirmation est basée essentiellement sur les résultats d'une seule étude, marquante dans le débat entourant le donépézil. L'évolution de ce médicament, passant d'un traitement contesté pour la maladie d'Alzheimer à une « pilule d'intelligence » (ou smart-pill), a soulevé des questions relativement aux données probantes justifiant ce nouvel étiquette de « produit d'amélioration des fonctions cognitives ». Par ailleurs, des articles de revue de littérature ont récemment conclu que les résultats de l'étude en question sont limités, et le lien entre le donépézil et l'amélioration des fonctions cognitives n'est pas clair.Le présent mémoire a pour objectif d'examiner comment la couverture médiatique et le débat bioéthique a influencé le discours sur le donépézil en tant que produit d'amélioration des performances cognitives, et cela, malgré l'absence de données probantes. Pour ce faire, nous avons procédé à une analyse systématique du contenu des médias et d'articles spécialisés en bioéthique afin d'examiner comment le donépézil et les résultats de l'étude y sont présentés. Nous avons identifié un enthousiasme débordant concernant la possibilité que le donépézil puisse améliorer les fonctions cognitives d'individus sains ainsi qu'une interaction complexe entre les attentes élevées et des conclusions ambigües au niveau de l'étude principale. Ensemble, ces facteurs ont contribué à la représentation du donépézil en tant qu'agent d'amélioration des fonctions cognitives dans la littérature et laissent supposer des conséquences importantes pour la prise de décision, les soins de santé et le développement de politiques.L'engouement entourant l'effet du donépézil au niveau de l'amélioration des performances cognitives démontre un intérêt général par rapport à la possibilité d'accroître l'intelligence et confirme ainsi la nécessité d'un examen plus approfondi à savoir pourquoi un tel but est recherché. L'augmentation, au sein de la population, du désir d'accroître l'intelligence pourrait avoir comme conséquence de nuire aux personnes atteintes d'une déficience intellectuelle. Afin d'établir le lien entre le phénomène de l'amélioration des fonctions cognitives d'individus sains et l'effet négatif potentiel sur les personnes atteintes d'une déficience intellectuelle, nous présentons dans ce mémoire un exemple d'engouement des médias autour de médicaments qui cible l'intelligence chez cette population. Ne pas s'interroger sur les présomptions sous-jacentes qui motivent le phénomène de l'amélioration des fonctions cognitives chez des individus sains risque de causer plus de tort dans le débat du « traitement » de la déficience intellectuelle et de rendre impuissants les mouvements sociaux qui visent à améliorer l'acceptabilité sociale et à promouvoir la diversité au sein de la société. </description><creator>Wade, Lucie</creator><contributor>Eric Racine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Ideologies of intellect: a critical examination of the hype surrounding cognitive enhancement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784q56k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fn26q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sf72q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The blood oxygen level dependent (BOLD) functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) signal is one of the most recently developed imaging techniques used to identify localized changes in brain activity. The BOLD signal is a function of cerebral blood flow (CBF), the cerebral metabolic rate of oxygen consumption (CMRO2), and cerebral blood volume (CBV). Normally coupled changes in these physiological parameters during regional increases in neural activity will result in BOLD signal increases. This makes the BOLD signal useful as a tool for identifying areas of increased neural activity. Moreover, it can also be used to infer changes in neurophysiology as a response to certain stimuli in the healthy brain, in individuals with certain neurological conditions affecting the cerebrovasculature and under the effect of some types of drugs. There is a major challenge to be faced when using the BOLD signal to study neurophysiological changes that occur under the effect of certain drugs or in the case of neurovascular disease. Under these circumstances, the underlying physiology and normally coupled vascular/metabolic response to a stimulus will be altered. Consequently, changes seen in the BOLD signal during regional increases in neural activity may not be associated with the same neurovascular changes that would occur in the healthy brain. Caffeine is an example of a widely used drug which has been shown to elicit such changes in the neurophysiological state. Two experiments were performed on a group of healthy volunteers in order quantify the effects of caffeine on both baseline neurophysiology and the BOLD signal changes evoked during a visual stimulus. The first involved the measurement of the oxygen extraction fraction(OEF) by performing venous blood magnetic resonance (MR) relaxometry and the second, the measurement of the BOLD and CBF response to a visual stimulus. The results obtained demonstrate that after caffeine consumption there is an increase in baseline OEF (OEF0) and a decrease in baseline CBF (CBF0), but a non-significant change in baseline CMRO2 (CMRO2,0). The caffeine-induced change in the individual BOLD and CBF response to a visual stimulus was found to correlate negatively with individual caffeine-induced change in CBF0. However, the average percent change in visually evoked BOLD and CBF signals across all subjects remained unaltered following caffeine consumption, whereas the CMRO2 response to a visual stimulus was found to increase.</description><description>L'effet BOLD (blood oxygenation level dependent) est l'une des plus récentes techniques d'imagerie par résonance magnetique (IRM) utilisée pour identifier les changements localisés d'activité cérébrale. Le signal BOLD varie en fonction de la circulation sanguine cérébrale (CBF), du taux métabolique cérébral de la consommation d'oxygène (CMRO2), et du volume sanguin cérébral (CBV). Les changements normalement-couplés de ces paramètres physiologiques lors d'une augmentation régionale d'activité neurale causeront une augmentation du signal BOLD. Cela rend le signal BOLD utile comme outil pour identifier les régions d'augmentation de l'activité neuronale. Deplus, le signal BOLD permet de déterminer quels changements neurophysiologiques suivent certains stimulus dans les cas suivants : le cerveau sain; le cerveau de personnes atteintes d'affections neurologiques affectant la cérébrovasculature; et le cerveau sous l'effet de certains types de médicaments. Un défi majeur se présente lorsque le signal BOLD est utilisé pour étudier les changements neurophysiologiques se produisant sous l'effet de certains médicaments ou en cas de maladie neuro-vasculaire. Lors de ce type d'utilisation, la physiologie sous-jacente et la réponse normalement-couplée vasculaire/métabolique à un stimulus est altérée. Par conséquent, les changements observés dans le signal BOLD au cours des augmentations régionales d'activité neuronale ne correspondent pas aux changements neurovasculaires qui se produisent normalement dans le cas du cerveau sain. La caféine est un médicament couramment utilisé qui a suscité de tels changements dans l'état neurophysiologique. Deux expériences ont été réalisées sur un groupe de volontaires sains dans le but de quantifier les effets de la caféine sur la neurophysiologie de base et les changements évoqués sur le signal BOLD lorsd'un stimulus visuel. La première expérience mesure la fraction de l'extraction d'oxygène (OEF) en effectuant de la relaxométrie par résonance magnetique sur le sang veineux. La deuxième expérience mesure la réponse du signal BOLD et CBFà un stimulus visuel. Les résultats montrent que, après la consommation de caféine il y a une augmentation de l'OEF, une augmentation de la réponse du CMRO2 au stimulus visuel, une diminution de la CBF de base (CBF0) et un changement non-significatif du CMRO2 de base (CMRO2,0). On observe une corrélation négative entre les changements générés par la consommation de caféine sur les réponses du signal BOLD et de la CBF au stimulus visuel et les changements générés par la consommation de caféine sur la CBF0. Néanmoins, en moyenne, la consommation de caféine ne génére aucun changement sur la réponse du signal BOLD et de la CBF au stimulus visuel.</description><creator>Alonso Ortiz, Eva</creator><contributor>Gilbert Bruce Pike (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biophysics - Medical</subject><title>Quantitative functional MRI based evaluation of caffeine's effects on brain physiology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225g23q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sf72q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687n32b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les recherches dans les domaines de la qualité de vie et du soutien social suggèrent une relation complexe avec le trauma. La plupart des études ont montré une relation inverse entre la qualité de vie et le soutien social après avoir eu une expérience traumatique. Cependant, il n'est pas encore certain que ces résultats s'appliquent à des personnes présentant un diagnostic actuel ou passé de trouble de stress post-traumatique (TSPT), ou à des personnes qui ne présentent pas de TSPT. Par ailleurs, ces résultats se rapportent à des indices globaux, qui négligent des domaines spécifiques qui pourraient donner davantage d'information, obtenus à partir d'échantillons de commodité. Nous cherchons ici à remédier à ces limites en analysant les données d'une grande base communautaire issue d'une étude épidémiologique du sud-ouest de Montréal (N =2399) répartis selon leur état de TSPT courant: (i) le TSPT courant, (ii) le TSPT passé, (iii) aucun diagnostic de TSPT en dépit des événements traumatiques, et (iv) aucune exposition à un événement traumatique à vie. La relation inverse de la diminution de la qualité de vie, spécifiquement quand les symptômes de TSPT augmentent, a été reproduite dans notre échantillon. Contrairement à de nombreuses études antérieures, nous montrons que le soutien social n'a pas été significativement différent en comparant les groupes avec TSPT et les groupes sans TSPT. Les résultats des sous-échelles ont été également examinés pour la qualité de vie et le soutien social, avec des résultats montrant que même lorsque le TSPT est passé, le fossé entre le groupe avec TSPT et le groupe sans TSPT s'élargit. Cette recherche permet d'améliorer grandement notre compréhension de la qualité de vie des personnes souffrant de TSPT courant et remis.</description><description>Research in the areas of quality of life and social support suggests a complex relationship with trauma. Most studies have found inverse relationships between both quality of life and social support posttrauma. However, it remains unclear how these findings apply to individuals with a current or past diagnosis of posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD), or to individuals who do not meet the criteria for PTSD. Furthermore, previous research has been limited to global index outcomes, which overlook specific domains that could reveal more information, obtained from convenience samples. We seek here to address these limitations by analysing data from a large community-based epidemiological catchment area study conducted in the south west of Montreal (N = 2399) broken down according to current PTSD diagnostic status: (i) Current PTSD, (ii) Past PTSD, (iii) No lifetime PTSD in spite of trauma exposure, and (iv) No lifetime trauma exposure. The inverse relationship of decreased quality of life posttrauma, specifically as PTSD severity increases, was replicated within our sample. In contrast to many previous studies, we show that social support was not significantly different between PTSD and No PTSD groups. Subscale scores were examined in depth for both quality of life and social support, with outcomes showing that even after PTSD remits, the gap between PTSD and No PTSD groups widens. This research allows for a much needed broadening of our understanding of quality of life for individuals with current and remitted PTSD.</description><creator>Monson, Eva</creator><contributor>Alain Brunet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Psychology - Clinical</subject><title>Quality of life and social support in relation to trauma and posttraumatic stress disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jq650.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687n32b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064983c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depuis la publication en 1979 d'images d'étudiants iraniens, en colère et les poings levés, attaquant l'ambassade américaine, la jeunesse iranienne est devenue un sujet captivant dans l'imaginaire et une source d'incertitude pour bon nombre de gens à travers le monde. Aujourd'hui, « les enfants de la révolution iranienne » sont assez âgés pour avoir leurs propres enfants. Par conséquent, un moyen unique et original d'étudier ce groupe est d'examiner sa transition de la jeunesse vers la parentalité. Cette étude se fera par le biais de conversations avec trois couples iraniens résidant à Montréal qui seront bientôt parents et qui tombent dans cette cohorte communément connue comme «le fruit de la révolution iranienne », en d'autres mots, ces jeunes qui ont vécu toute leur vie sous le régime postrévolutionnaire. Je regarderai la parentalité en tant que projection imaginaire et étudierai comment mes interlocuteurs envisagent de mener leurs nouvelles vies de parents. Je propose de regarder la parentalité, avec la société comme toile de fond, comme un cadre adéquat pour mieux saisir la jeunesse iranienne, sujet complexe et souvent insaisissable. </description><description>Since the publication of images of Iranian students' raised angry fists storming the American embassy in 1979, the idea of Iranian youth has captured the world's imagination and has been a source of puzzlement. The children of the Iranian revolution are today old enough to have their own children. Thus, one unique and original window from which to study Iranian youth is to investigate as they undergo the significant transition from youth to parenthood. This study will be in conversation with three expecting Montreal-based Iranian couples who fall in the cohort known as "the fruit of Iran's revolution;" in other words, youth that have lived entirely under the post revolutionary regime. I will examine parenting as an imagined projection and investigate ways in which my interlocutors envision their life as a first time parent. I suggest that the institution of parenting, with its focal point in society, presents a suitable framework for disentangling the complex and elusive understanding of Iranian youth. </description><creator>Shafiei, Mehrnoush</creator><contributor>Setrag Manoukian (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Anthropology - Cultural</subject><title>Conceiving Iran's future: youth and the transition to parenthood</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78th27k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064983c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429f57p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mesurer l'amortissement structurel causé par friction interne dans les films minces déposés permet d'établir des recommandations pour le design de résonateurs micro/nanomécaniques ayant un facteur de qualité élevé, ainsi qu'apporter une meilleure compréhension de l'effet de la taille et du confinement sur le mécanisme d'amortissement de ces films minces. Ce type de résonateurs est utilisé dans les microsystèmes électromécaniques de détection, de communication et de récupération d'énergie vibratoire. Ces mesures d'amortissement sont réalisées en déposant un film mince sur un substrat ayant une forme de poutre en porte-à-faux et d'épaisseur relativement élevée, et en mesurant le changement d'amortissement de l'ensemble substrat/film. Cependant, l'amortissement global a des origines multiples, notamment des pertes provenant du support, du système de fixation, de l'amortissement thermoélastique, et de la friction interne dans l'ensemble substrat/film. Identifier avec précision l'amplitude de la friction interne dans le film est une difficulté de connue de longue date dans le milieu de la recherche scientifique. Cette thèse présente le design et le développement d'une plateforme en silicium ayant une micro-poutre en porte-à-faux afin de résoudre ce problème. L'intérêt principal de cette plateforme est que l'amortissement dans les micro-poutres en porte-à-faux faites en silicium monocristallin est réduit à un faible niveau approchant les limites théoriques de la dissipation établies par les lois de l'amortissement thermoélastique. Cela démontre que les autres sources d'amortissement (amortissement visqueux, pertes liées au support ou à la friction interne du substrat) sont suffisamment faibles. Par la suite, ces poutres peuvent être recouvertes par le film mince étudié et l'amortissement de l'ensemble substrat/film est mesuré. Cette mesure provient à la fois de l'amortissement thermoélastique dans l'ensemble substrat/film et de la friction interne dans le film mince. Cette dernière peut être calculée grâce à ces modèles précis, et l'amortissement initial du substrat peut être soustrait de l'amortissement mesuré pour l'ensemble substrat/film afin d'en déduire une estimation précise de la friction interne dans le film mince uniquement.Les poutres en porte-à-faux en silicium monocristallin fabriquées dans le cadre de cette thèse avaient une épaisseur comprise entre 8 et 130 µm, et une fréquence fondamentale comprise entre 80 Hz et 40 kHz. En utilisant la plateforme de mesure évoquée précédemment, le faible amortissement approchant la limite thermoélastique théorique de ces poutres est démontré. Ce type de poutres est ensuite utilisé pour mener les premières mesures calibrées portant sur l'effet de l'épaisseur et de la fréquence sur la friction interne dans les films minces d'aluminium, d'or, et d'argent à température ambiante. Les films minces avaient une épaisseur comprise entre 60 nm et 450 nm, et furent testés à des fréquences comprises entre 100 Hz et 1,5 kHz. Les résultats de cette étude établissent deux recommandations pour le design de résonateurs à couches minces à faible dissipation (haut facteur de qualité) : l'or induit une augmentation de l'amortissement qui est plus faible que celle induite par l'aluminium ou l'argent, et l'amortissement des résonateurs peut être diminué en réduisant l'épaisseur de la couche mince. Une troisième recommandation est donnée sous la forme d'une stratégie pour contrôler et minimiser l'amortissement en déposant le film mince sur le résonateur selon un certain motif au lieu d'une couche continue. Dans ce travail de recherche, un modèle simple est développé pour prédire l'amortissement des poutres en porte-à-faux partiellement recouvertes de métal. Ce modèle est ensuite validé expérimentalement grâce à la plateforme en silicium. Cette plateforme ainsi que les résultats obtenus en l'utilisant établissent les fondements de l'étude de la friction interne dans les films minces.</description><description>Measuring structural damping due to internal friction in deposited thin films can provide useful guidelines for the design of high-Q micro/nanomechanical resonators utilized used for sensing, communications and vibration energy harvesting. Such measurements can also generate valuable insights into the effects of size and confinement on the mechanisms of damping in these films. Typically, these measurements are carried out by depositing a thin film on a relatively thick cantilevered substrate and measuring the change in damping in the substrate/film composite. However, the measured damping is due to losses from several sources including support losses, clamping losses, thermoelastic damping (TED) and internal friction losses in the substrate/film composite. Accurately identifying the magnitude of internal friction in the film has been a long-standing difficulty in this field. This thesis presents the design and development of a silicon microcantilever platform to resolve this difficulty. At the core of the platform is the ability to reduce the damping in single crystal silicon microcantilevers to low levels of damping approaching the fundamental limits of dissipation established by thermoelastic damping (TED). This demonstrates that all other sources of damping (viscous losses, support losses and internal friction losses) are sufficiently low. These cantilevers can then be coated with the thin film of interest and the damping in the substrate/film composite measured. The measured damping is comprised of the thermoelastic damping in the substrate/film composite and the internal friction in the film. The former can be calculated using accurate models and the initial damping can be substracted from the measured damping in the composite to obtain an accurate estimate of the internal friction in the film. In this dissertation, single crystal silicon cantilevers ranging from 8 to 130 micrometers in thickness, and fundamental frequencies ranging from 80 Hz to 40 kHz were fabricated. Using the measurement platform, these beams are demonstrated to have low damping with values approaching the TED limit. Subsets of these beams are then used to carry out the first calibrated measurements on the effects of thickness and frequency on internal friction in thin films of aluminum, gold and silver at room temperature. The films ranged in thickness from 60 nm to 450 nm and were studied over frequencies from 100 Hz to 1.5 kHz. The results of this study provide two valuable guidelines for the design of low dissipation (high Q) layered composite resonators: gold leads to a smaller increase in damping than either aluminum or silver, and damping in the composite resonators can be decreased by reducing the film thickness. As a third design guideline, a strategy to control and minimize the damping by selective patterning of thin films on the resonator  is described. In this work, a simple model is developed to predict the damping in partially metalized cantilevered beams and experimentally validated using the platform. The silicon microcantilever platform, and the results obtained using this platform establish a foundation for studying internal friction in thin films.</description><creator>Sosale, Guruprasad</creator><contributor>Srikar Vengallatore (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Luc Fréchette (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>A microcantilever platform for measuring internal friction in thin films using thermoelastic damping for calibration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cz37t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429f57p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm714</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'épididyme est un tubule unique, replié maintes fois sur lui-même, reliant les canaux efférents des testicules au canal déférent. L'épididyme est le site de maturation des spermatozoïdes; là où ils acquièrent leur mobilité et leur habileté à fertiliser. Cette maturation est le résultat d'une dynamique complexe d'interactions entre les spermatozoïdes et un microenvironnement hautement spécialisé, continuellement entretenu par l'épithélium de l'épididyme. L'expression régionalisée des gènes de cet organe est primordiale pour le maintien de ce microenvironnement. Le but de ces travaux de thèse était d'étudier la famille des régulateurs de transcription que sont les inhibiteurs de liaison à l'ADN (IDs), dans l'épididyme ainsi que leur rôle en reproduction mâle. Le premier objectif, était d'établir le profil d'expression longitudinal et cellulaire des IDs dans l'épididyme et d'observer comment l'orchidectomie et l'âge pouvaient affecter ces profils d'expression et de localisation. Les protéines IDs montrent une expression longitudinale unique le long du tissu, un profil régionalisé précis, et sont exprimées dans des cellules différentes. Alors que l'âge ne montre aucun effet notable, nous avons observé que l'expression de la protéine ID3 est modifiée après orchidectomie dans l'ensemble de l'épididyme. Le second objectif était de déterminer les conséquences fonctionnelles d'une déficience en ID3 (Id3tm1Cmu/Id3tm1Cmu) sur l'histologie et sur les profils d'expression génétique de l'épididyme, ainsi que les paramètres de numération et de mobilité des spermatozoïdes. Bien que la déficience en ID3 n'ait aucun impact histologique, la mutation affecte les paramètres de mobilité des spermatozoïdes. Pour élucider l'effet de la mutation sur le profil régionalisé d'expression des gènes, nous avons entrepris une analyse du profil d'expression génomique et avons mis en évidence que l'effet de la mutation prédomine dans la partie caudale de l'épididyme, là où l'expression de plusieurs facteurs de transcription était affectée. Enfin, le dernier objectif était d'évaluer la fertilité et la descendance des animaux déficients en ID3. La descendance des souris mâles Id3-/- et leurs phénotypes développementaux sont anormaux. Ces derniers étant caractérisés par un taux élevé de mort fœtale, un poids de naissance faible, un taux de malformations externes anormalement haut, et un développement du squelette anormal. L'ensemble de ces études indique que ID3 contribuerait à la base moléculaire de l'expression régionalisée des gènes de l'épididyme, fournit de nouvelles données sur le rôle de ID3 en reproduction chez le mâle, et offre de nouvelles perspectives pour de futures pistes de recherche.</description><description>The epididymis is a single, highly convoluted tubule linking the efferent ducts of the testis to the vas deferens. It is the site where sperm mature, acquiring forward motility and fertilizing ability. Spermatozoal maturation is the result of complex, dynamic interactions between spermatozoa and the highly specialized, continuously changing luminal microenvironment established by the epididymal epithelium. Regionalized gene expression is paramount to the establishment of this microenvironment. The goal of this thesis was to examine the ID family of transcriptional regulators in the epididymis and their role in male-mediated reproduction. The first objective was to establish the longitudinal expression profiles and cellular distribution of the four IDs along the epididymis and how expression was affected by orchidectomy and by aging. IDs display unique longitudinal expression profiles along the tissue, having highly regionalized expression, and are primarily expressed in non-overlapping cell types. While aging resulted in no noticeable effect, we observed that the expression of ID3 is differentially regulated in response to orchidectomy along the tissue. The next objective was to determine the functional consequences of Id3 deficiency (Id3tm1Cmu/Id3tm1Cmu) on epididymal histology and gene expression, as well as spermatozoal counts and motility parameters. Although Id3 deficiency had no noticeable impact on epididymal histology, the targeted mutation altered several sperm motility parameters. We undertook genome-wide expression profiling to elucidate region-specific effects and found that the predominant effect of the Id3 null mutation is in the cauda epididymidis, where the expression of many transcription factors was significantly affected. The final objective was to assess the fertility status and progeny outcome of animals deficient in Id3. Matings with Id3-/- males resulted in abnormal reproductive outcomes and developmental phenotypes in gestational day 18 fetuses. These were characterized by an elevated rate of fetal death, reduced body weights of live fetuses, a higher rate of external malformations, and aberrant skeletal development. Collectively, these studies indicate that Id3 may contribute to the molecular basis of regionalized gene expression in the epididymis, provide novel insights into the role of Id3 in male-mediated reproduction, and afford new perspectives for future avenues of research.</description><creator>Carroll, Michelle</creator><contributor>Bernard Robaire (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</subject><title>Inhibitor of DNA binding (ID) proteins in the epididymis and the impact of Id deficiency on gene expression, spermatozoal motility, and progeny outcome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408216z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm714</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b969</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fasciolosis is an economically important veterinary parasitic disease. Of the two causative agents, Fasciola hepatica and Fasciola gigantica, F. hepatica has a greater ability to effectively establish a primary infection and resist the host defences. Certain host species, such as cattle, are more resistant to reinfection than others, such as sheep. In order to gain a greater understanding of the host response to infection, proteomic analyses of sera from sheep and cattle infected with F. hepatica were undertaken. Twenty-six indicators of infection were validated by SELDI-TOF mass spectrometry (MS) in sheep with a single-dose F. hepatica infection. Two of these markers were identified and their increase in the chronic stage of infection was validated using Western blot analysis. SELDI-TOF MS profiling of sera from trickle-infected cattle did not provide descriptive information, but tandem MS analysis of immunodepleted sera provided a more descriptive view of the host-parasite interaction. This technique was sufficiently sensitive to detect markers of inflammation during the acute stage of infection and markers of liver fibrosis during the chronic stage of infection, but was not sufficiently sensitive to detect parasite proteins. Finally, the excretory-secretory products (ESP) of F. hepatica and F. gigantica were profiled. The similarities between the two species were greater than the similarities between newly excysted juveniles (NEJ) and adults. The most notable differences between NEJ and adults were the profile of proteases released and the specific isotypes released by the parasites. NEJ expressed relatively equal amounts of cathepsin L, B, and legumain, whereas adults expressed predominantly cathepsin L. NEJ- and adult-specific cathepsin L clades were identified as well as a potential F. gigantica NEJ-specific cathepsin L clade. Antioxidant defence enzyme levels were higher in adult ESP than NEJ ESP, with higher relative abundance in F. gigantica than F. hepatica. The analysis suggests that stage-specific expression and isotype diversity should be considered when developing a vaccine targeted to the early stage of infection and when studying broad-spectrum chemotherapeutic targets. These studies contribute to the understanding of the basic biology of the causative agents of fasciolosis and the use of proteomics in studying host-parasite interactions.</description><description>La fasciolase est une infection vétérinaire importante. Entre les deux agents causals, Fasciola hepatica et Fasciola gigantica, f. hepatica a une meilleure capacité pour établir une infection primaire et pour résister aux défenses de l'hôte. Certaines espèces hôtes, tels que les bovins, résistent une seconde infection mieux que d'autres espèces, tels que les moutons. Afin de mieux comprendre la réaction de l'hôte pendant l'infection, des analyses protéomiques de sérums de moutons et de bovins affectés par f. hepatica ont été entreprises. Vint-six marqueurs d'infection ont été validés par spectrométrie de masse de temps de vol à désorption-ionisation laser potentialisée par surface (SM TDV-DILPS) chez les moutons avec une seule dose infectieuse de f. hepatica. Deux de ces marqueurs ont été identifiés et leur hausse dans la phase chronique de l'infection a été validée par buvardage de western. Le profil SM TDV-DILPS de bovins infectés à plusieurs reprises n'a pas fourni des détails descriptifs, mais une analyse SM en tandem de sérums immunodéplétés a fourni un portrait descriptif de l'interaction hôte-parasite. Cette technique était suffisamment sensible pour détecter des marqueurs d'inflammation pendant la phase aigüe de l'infection et des marqueurs de la fibrose hépatique pendant la phase chronique de l'infection, mais n'était pas suffisamment sensible pour détecter des protéines parasitaires. Enfin, les produits d'excrétion-sécrétion (PES) de f. hepatica et f. gigantica ont été profilées. Les deux espèces partageaient plus de similitudes que parmi les phases de juvéniles nouvellement excystés (JNV) et des adultes. Les différences les plus notables entre les JNV et les adultes étaient le profil des protéases et les isotypes de ces protéases retrouvés. Les montants de cathepsine L, B et de legumain chez les JNV étaient relativement égaux, tandis que la majorité des protéases chez les adultes étaient cathepsine L. Des clades de cathepsine L spécifiques aux JNV et aux adultes ont été identifiés ainsi qu'un clade potentiellement spécifique aux JNV de f. gigantica. Les niveaux d'enzymes antioxydants de défense dans les PES étaient plus élevés dans chez les adultes que les JNV, ainsi qu'une abondance plus élevées chez f. gigantica que f. hepatica. Ces analyses suggèrent que l'expression des protéines spécifique aux phases de développement et la diversité des isotypes devraient être considérées lors de l'élaboration d'un vaccin ciblé à un stade précoce de l'infection et lors du développement de cibles chimiothérapeutiques à large spectre. Ces études contribuent aux connaissances fondamentales des agents causals de fasciolase et l'usage d'outils protéomiques dans l'étude des interactions hôte-parasite.</description><creator>Rioux, Marie-Claire</creator><contributor>Timothy Geary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>A study of the proteomics of fasciolosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225g240.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b969</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vs68z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>BACKGROUND: Multiple studies have demonstrated increased risk of lung cancer in the presence of emphysema, independent of smoking history and airflow obstruction, but the relationship of emphysema to specific histologic subtypes remains uncertain. OBJECTIVE: To determine the extent to which emphysema on chest computed tomography (CT) is associated with lung cancer histology. METHODS: Cross-sectional analysis of consecutive lung cancer patients referred to the Jewish General Hospital was performed (2001-2009). All those with demographic data, smoking history (pack-years), documented histology and chest CT were included. Emphysema was graded on CT by three readers, using a standardized rubric. Odds of each lung cancer subtype were compared between patients with and without emphysema, and adjusted for age, sex and smoking history by multiple logistic regression. RESULTS: Complete data were available for 498 lung cancer patients (mean age 68 years; 221 [44%] female; 78 [16%] never smokers; 263 [53%] without emphysema on CT). The most common histologies were adenocarcinoma (242 [49%]), squamous (71 [14%]), undifferentiated (48 [10%]) and small cell carcinoma (42 [8%]). The remaining 19% included bronchioloalveolar, large cell, pleomorphic and basaloid carcinomas. Presence of emphysema was associated with increased odds of squamous (OR 3.1 95%CI 1.8-5.3) and small cell (OR 2.1 95%CI 1.1-4.1) carcinoma. After adjustment for age, sex and smoking history, emphysema was associated with squamous (OR 2.7 95%CI 1.5-4.9) but not small cell (OR 1.5 95%CI 0.8-3.1) carcinoma. CONCLUSIONS: Relative to other histologic subtypes, the odds of squamous carcinoma were significantly increased among lung cancer patients with emphysema after adjustment for smoking history.   This was not true of small cell carcinoma, although confidence intervals were wide so an association cannot be entirely excluded.  Other common subtypes were not independently associated with emphysema.</description><description>CONTEXTE: Plusieurs études ont démontré un risque accru de cancer du poumon en présence d'emphysème, indépendamment des antécédents de tabagisme et d'obstruction, mais la relation entre l'emphysème et les types histologiques spécifiques demeure incertaine. OBJECTIF: Déterminer la mesure dans laquelle l'emphysème sur la tomodensitométrie thoracique (TDM) est associé à l'histologie du cancer du poumon. MÉTHODES: L'analyse transversale de patients consécutifs de cancer du poumon référés à l'Hôpital général juif a été réalisée de 2001 à 2009. Tous ceux avec des données démographiques, des antécédents de tabagisme (paquets-années), une histologie documentée et un TDM thoracique ont été inclus. L'emphysème a été évalué sur TDM par trois lecteurs, en utilisant une méthode standardisée. Les proportions de chaque sous-type de cancer du poumon ont été comparées entre les patients avec et sans emphysème, et ajustées selon l'âge, le sexe et les antécédents de tabagisme par régression logistique multiple. RÉSULTATS: Des données complètes étaient disponibles pour 498 patients atteints de cancer du poumon (moyenne d'âge 68 ans; 221 [44%] des femmes; 78 [16%] qui n'ont jamais fumé; 263 [53%] sans emphysème sur TDM). Les histologies les plus fréquentes étaient l'adénocarcinome (242 [49%]), l'épidermoïde (71 [14%]), les indifférenciées (48 [10%]) et le carcinome à petites cellules (42 [8%]). La présence de l'emphysème était associée à une probabilité accrue de carcinomes épidermoïdes (OR 3,1 IC 95%: 1,8-5,3) et de carcinomes à petites cellules (OR 2,1 IC 95% 1,1-4,1). Après ajustement selon l'âge, le sexe et les antécédents de tabagisme, l'emphysème était associé au cancer de type épidermoïde (OR 2,7 IC 95%: 1,5-4,9), mais pas au cancer à petites cellules (OR 1,5 IC 95%: 0,8-3,1). CONCLUSIONS: Comparativement à d'autres sous-types histologiques, la probabilité de carcinome épidermoïde est  significativement augmentée chez les patients atteints de cancer du poumon avec emphysème, après ajustement selon les antécédents de tabagisme. Ce n'est pas le cas pour le carcinome à petites cellules, bien que les intervalles de confiance étaient larges, donc une association ne peut pas être entièrement exclue. D'autres sous-types de cancer pulmonaire n'ont pas été indépendamment associés à l'emphysème.</description><creator>Smith, Benjamin</creator><contributor>Kevin Schwartzman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Which lung cancer histologies are associated with emphysema on chest computed tomography?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g422q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vs68z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w392z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude a pour l'objectif d'évaluer l'éducation à la citoyenneté actuelle en Indonésie, celle qui a été conçue et réalisée en pensant à une Indonésie démocratique et multireligieuse. Les deux premiers chapitres sont des sources d'informations sur la société indonésienne contemporaine et ils mettent en évidence les trois caractéristiques sociales particulièrement significatives en ce qui concerne cette analyse : la grande diversité des groupes religieux ; la reconnaissance officielle de la part de l'État de la tolérance inter-religieux ; et l'introduction de démocratie en 1998.Dans le troisième chapitre, l'auteur examine trois théories libérales de modèles d'éducation à la citoyenneté : le libéralisme de l'autonomie, le libéralisme de la diversité et le libéralisme politique. Ces théories contiennent des aperçus importants qui peuvent aider à assurer une évaluation des politiques et des pratiques d'éducation à la citoyenneté qui est tournée vers l'avenir, malgré que l'Indonésie ne soit pas une démocratie libérale et laïque comme celle connue à l'Ouest. L'auteur met l'accent sur l'argument que l'idée centrale du libéralisme politique—la capacité des citoyens de se comporter et de juger d'une manière raisonnable aux yeux des sociétés pluralistes—est essentiel de cultiver dans une Indonésie multireligieuse.  Les deux prochains chapitres sont centrés sur deux études de cas d'écoles secondaires à Jakarta. En général, bien que le système éducatif se concentrasse sur la transmission du civisme, l'auteur a découvert que les pratiques spécifiques employées dans les écoles pour transmettre des connaissances civiques ont mené à des succès mitigés dans l'atteinte des objectifs nécessaires d'une éducation à la citoyenneté efficace pour une Indonésie multireligieuse. Du côté positif, les deux écoles avaient des corps étudiant relativement divers et ils créaient un espace de partages des connaissances civiques à travers les différences religieuses. Dans certains cas, il a paru que des amitiés et des relations coopératives se formaient parmi des étudiants de différentes appartenances religieuses. Du côté négatif, il est arrivé des incidents de discrimination inter-religieuse (des sentiments de méconnaissance, de tension et de conflit) qui avaient émané d'un manque de communication et d'ignorance. De plus, dans le cadre du curriculum et dans les pratiques formelles de la salle de classe, les deux écoles accentuaient une éducation religieuse confessionnelle ; ils se montraient peu insistant sur une démocratie libérale ; ils ignoraient la diversité à l'intérieur des religions ; et ils s'opposaient au dialogue inter-religieux. S'appuyant sur les principes du libéralisme politique discutés dans le troisième chapitre, l'auteur souligne que le manque de la raison publique dans ces deux milieux scolaires représente une défaillance de l'éducation à la citoyenneté.  Cette dissertation suggère qu'afin d'assurer que le peuple indonésien sera prêt à apporter des réponses aux défis de la diversité religieuse, du désaccord général et de l'interaction respectueuse, l'éducation à la citoyenneté en Indonésie devrait incorporer les caractéristiques suivantes : (1) la protection (et, si possible, l'augmentation) de la diversité religieuse aux milieux scolaires, (2) l'équité dans l'accommodation de la diversité religieuse, (3) la maximisation de l'interaction sociale et les pratiques de la démocratie et du dialogue, (4) le développement des connaissances civiques profondément partagées et (5) l'encouragement des conversations inter-religieuses et l'importance de l'enseignement de la culture religieuse. C'est essentiel que chaque citoyen s'engage à communiquer et à négocier ouvertement sur ces points. Sinon, les conflits résultants produiront les effets adverses pour tous les Indonésiens, pas seulement ceux d'une certaine affiliation religieuse.</description><description>Concerned with interreligious conflict in Indonesia, this study seeks to describe and evaluate the current citizenship education that has been designed and implemented for a democratic multireligious Indonesia. The context for the study, outlined in Chapters 1 and 2, is contemporary Indonesian society. Three features of this society are highlighted as especially significant. First, it is characterized by a wide diversity of religious groups. Second, it is governed by the state which acknowledges religious diversity with an official (constitutionally guaranteed) stance of interreligious tolerance. Third, since 1998 it has adopted a democratic political system. The study begins by outlining how the state and national education has tried to meet demands of national unity (citizenship) and those of religious acknowledgment. The remainder of the study combines philosophical and qualitative empirical methods. In Chapter 3, I critically examine three contemporary liberal theories of citizenship education models (autonomy liberalism, diversity liberalism, and political liberalism). I suggest that these theories contain important insights relevant to a forward looking assessment of Indonesian citizenship educational policy and practice even though Indonesia is not a secular liberal democracy in the 'Western' mould.  Specifically, I argue that what is critical to cultivate in multireligious Indonesia is the core idea of political liberalism – that is, the capacity for "public reasonableness" which involves the attitude and capacity to think, to judge and to behave in a way reasonable to pluralist societies.  Chapters 4 and 5 focus on two case studies of public senior high schools in Jakarta and provide examples of citizenship education taking place in the education system.  Overall, I found that although educational policy and the public schools I studied did indeed focus on civic knowledge transmission, the specific practices indicated mixed results for achieving the desired aims of citizenship education for a multireligious Indonesia. On the positive side, school settings were relatively diverse and facilitated a good deal of social interaction and created the potential for shared civic knowledge across religious differences. In some cases, friendships and cooperative relationships among religiously diverse students seemed to occur. On the negative side, there were cases of interreligious discrimination, misunderstanding, tension and conflict and these seemed to originate from a lack of open communication, and interreligious misunderstanding and ignorance. Furthermore, when it came to the official curriculum and classroom practice (as opposed to informal within school contexts), both schools emphasized confessional religious education, ignored the internal diversity of religion, lacked exposure to religious diversity, deemphasized democratic deliberation and opposed interreligious dialogue.  As such, I argue that the schools are missing a crucial element of citizenship education for "public reasonableness" as proposed by the political liberalism model studied in Chapter 3. I conclude that in order to meet the demands of creating  a citizenry prepared to address the challenges of religious diversity, disagreement, and respectful interaction, Indonesian citizenship education should seek to encourage the following characteristics: 1) maintain and increase, where possible, religiously diverse school settings, 2) ensure fairness in accommodation of diversity, 3) intensify social interaction and practice of democracy and dialogue, 4) focus on the development of deep shared civic knowledge, and 5) develop interreligious conversation and knowledge of religious diversity (religious literacy). It is important to start talking about these issues or otherwise as Indonesians we will continue to combat one another, with all Indonesian citizens being the losers in the end. </description><creator>Syafruddin, Didin</creator><contributor>Kevin Michael McDonough (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Claudia A Mitchell (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Education - Philosophy of</subject><title>In search of a citizenship education model for a democratic multireligious Indonesia: case studies of two public senior high schools in Jakarta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70n042k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w392z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vg580</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectif: L'efficacité de l'usage de médicaments pour traiter les symptômes de Trouble de déficit d'attention avec ou sans Hyperactivité (TDAH) est bien établie. (Spencer et al 2000) Malgré cela,  les taux d'adhésion aux médicaments est bas, variant entre 34% et 91%. (Gau et al., 2006).  Étant donné qu'une adhésion assidue a étée associée à l'amélioration des symptômes (Corkum, Rimer, &amp; Schachar, 1999), augmenter cette adhésion pourrait mener à de meilleurs résultats de traitement. La présente étude a examiné, chez les enfants vivant avec le TDAH, la relation entre  leur adhérence à la pharmacothérapie et les conaissances ainsi que les attitudes de leurs parents sur la médicamentation du TDAH. Cette étude a aussi exploré l'efficacité d'une intervention en particulier, qui pour objectif d'augmenter le niveau de connaisances des parents sur ces médicaments.  En particulier, l'impact de cette 'intervention sur l'adhérance a été étuidié. Méthodes: Les parents de 24 enfants diagnostiqués de TDAH pour qui un traitement pharmacologique avait été recommandé, ont reçu un assignment alléatoire soit au visionnement d'un film contenant de l'information spécifique sur la médication du TDAH (groupe d'intervention spécifique n=12); soit au visonnement d'un film contenant de l'information générale sur le TDAH (groupe d'intervention non-spécifique n=12). Les connaissances et attitudes des parents furent évaluées avec l'usage du Attitudes, satisfaction, connaissances, expériences avec les médicaments pour le traitement du TDAH avant le visonnement du film, après le visonnement du film et après que l'enfant ait été médicamenté pour une période de trois mois. Lors de ces trois mois d'évaluation, l'adhésion aux medicaments à été suivie par la biais d'un journal de bord de médicamentation hebdomadaire. Résultats: L'attitude face à la médicamentation s'est accru suivant l'intervention spécifique (pré-intervention: 23.64  ± 2.50; post-intervention: 27.18 ± 3.71; p &lt; .0005), et cet acroissement s'est avéré maintenu à la fin du trois mois de prise de medicaments (27.33 ± 3.08).  Aucun changement d'attitude ne fut enregistré suite à l'intervention non-spécifique (pre-intervention: 23.20±4.02; post-intervention: 23.20 ± 3.97; p = 1.00).  Aucune des intervention n'a eu d'impact considerable sure le niveau de conaissance des parents. Au suivit, 12 semaines plus tard, le niveau d'adhérance pour les deux groups était considérablement plus élevé (groupe avec internvetion 98.21% ± 4.00,  groupe sans intervention 96.33% ± 6.91) que les résultats rapportés plus tôt (34% to 91%), mais il n'y avait pas de difference d'adhérance entre les deux groupes lors de ce suivit (p = 0.524).  Attitudes et connaissances sur le sujet, à touts les points d'évaluation, n'étaient pas relies à l'adhérance. (ps &gt; 0.05).Conclusion: L'intervention spécifique s'est avérée efficace à augmenter l'attitude positive des parents envers les medicaments pour traiter le TDAH. par contre, l'efficacité de l'intervention spécifique à l'augmentation de l'adhérance en comparaison d'avec l'intervnetion non-spécifique, n'est pas significativement différente. Cela pourrait être du à un échantillon relativement petit. De plus, le niveau d'adhérance était particulièrement plus élevé que l'adhérence généralement rapportée, ce qui pourrait être expliqué par des facteurs non-spécifiques et inhérents au deux groups de l'étude, tel que le contact hebdomadaire avec les membres de l'equipe de recherché, l'accès aux services d'une institution de santé terciaire et finalement, l'utilisation d'une intervention video.</description><description>Objective: Despite the established effectiveness of medication in improving symptoms of attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) (Spencer et al 2000), rates of adherence to pharmacotherapy are low, ranging from 34% to 91% (Gau et al., 2006).  Since higher adherence rates are associated with more symptomatic improvement (Corkum, Rimer, &amp; Schachar, 1999), increasing adherence may result in better treatment outcomes.  This study examined the relationship between adherence of children with ADHD to pharmacotherapy and their parents' knowledge, and attitudes regarding ADHD medication.  It also investigated the impact of an intervention aimed at increasing parental knowledge regarding medication on children's adherence. Methods: Parents of 24 children diagnosed with ADHD and recommended for pharmacological treatment were randomly assigned to watch either a video containing specific information about ADHD medication (specific intervention group, n=12) or a video containing general information about ADHD (non-specific intervention group, n=12).  Their knowledge and attitudes regarding medication were assessed using the Attitudes, Satisfaction, Knowledge and Medication Experiences scale prior to the video session, after the video session, and after their child had been on medication for three months. During the 3-month evaluation period children's medication adherence was monitored using weekly medication logs. Results: Attitudes towards medication became more positive following the specific intervention (pre-intervention: 23.64  ± 2.50; post-intervention: 27.18 ± 3.71; p &lt; .0005), and remained more positive at the end of the 3-month evaluation period (27.33 ± 3.08).  There was no change in attitudes following the non-specific intervention (pre-intervention: 23.20±4.02; post-intervention: 23.20 ± 3.97; p = 1.00).  Neither intervention had an appreciable effect on knowledge.  At the 12-week follow-up, the adherence levels for both groups were substantially higher (intervention group 98.21% ± 4.00, non-intervention group 96.33% ± 6.91) than those previously reported (34% to 91%), but there was no difference in adherence between the groups (p = 0.524).  Knowledge and attitudes at all three assessment points were unrelated to adherence (ps &gt; 0.05).Conclusion: The specific intervention was successful at increasing positive attitudes of parents towards medication. However, the effectiveness of the specific intervention relative to the non-specific intervention at improving adherence was not significantly different. This may be in part due to the relatively small sample size. In addition, the adherence rates in this study were markedly higher than those reported previously, which may be due to non-specific factors inherent to both intervention groups, such as, weekly contact with research staff, service provided at tertiary medical facilities and the utilization of video interventions.  </description><creator>Gomes, Paul</creator><contributor>Lily T Hechtman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Psychology - Clinical</subject><title>Pharmacotherapy of childhood attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: the impact of information interventions on parental knowledge, attitudes and their child's adherence to medication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579x543.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vg580</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322j818</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the past decades, the population in Canada has become increasingly culturally diverse. Therefore, helping professionals are required to provide services that are culturally appropriate and effective. The main purpose of this research project was to understand the experiences and perceptions of practitioners in the field of social work intervening with clients from different cultural backgrounds, the challenges, barriers and facilitators they encounter, as well as their views on how services can be improved. A qualitative approach was used, where in-depth, semi-structure interviews were conducted with nine front-line psychosocial workers from a local government agency in Montreal. Findings demonstrated how cultural and ethnic differences shape the psychosocial intervention process, as well as how participants defined cultural competence. Findings are discussed in reference to existing academic research on culturally competent practice. Participants' conceptualization of cultural competence paralleled some of the most common definitions in the literature, where awareness of one's own values and biases, as well as knowledge about the different cultures was essential. Moreover, the results showed a significant need for support and training for workers when intervening with culturally diverse clients. Implications for practice, policy and future research are presented.</description><description>Depuis les dernières décennies, la population au Canada est devenue de plus en plus diversifiée. Les intervenants sociaux doivent offrir des services qui sont culturellement appropriés et efficaces. L'objectif principal de cette étude était d'explorer les expériences et les perspectives des intervenants dans le domaine du travail social travaillant avec des clients provenant de différentes cultures, les défis, les barrières, et les facilitateurs rencontrés, ainsi que leurs suggestions pour améliorer les services. Une approche qualitative fut utilisée, où des entrevues semi structurées ont été réalisées avec un échantillon de neuf intervenants de première ligne œuvrant dans une agence gouvernementale de Montréal. Les résultats démontrèrent comment les différences culturelles et ethniques influencent le processus d'intervention psychosociale, ainsi que la façon dont les participants définissent la compétence culturelle. Les résultats sont examinés en lien avec la recherche académique existante sur la pratique culturellement compétente. Les définitions proposées sont semblables aux définitions présentes dans la littérature, où il est essentiel d'être conscient de ses propres valeurs et biais, ainsi que une connaissance des différentes cultures. En outre, les résultats indiquent un besoin important de soutien et de formation pour les intervenants qui travaillent avec des clients de diverses cultures. Les implications pour la pratique, les politiques et la recherche future sont présentées. </description><creator>Cisternas Cid, Sonia</creator><contributor>Nicole Ives (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</subject><title>The impact of culture and ethnicity in psychosocial work</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n70h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j818</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60d168t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mon étude porte sur le b-boying (break boy, danseur), archétype de la danse hip-hop, pour dégager l'enseignement et les procédés d'apprentissage informels inhérents aux cercles de danse improvisée – création libre (freestyle ou raw cipher). Ma méthodologie intègre certains aspects d'observation participante selon la trajectoire de recherche s'intéressant à l'influence des pratiques hip-hop sur les façons de faire et de penser. Ceci oriente mon observation participante de 13 événements et mon entrevue en profondeur avec Buddha, de la plus ancienne troupe de breaking du Canada, Canadian Floor Masters. Mon cadre théorique s'appuie sur l'apprentissage situé de Lave et Wenger, et la création du savoir de Nonaka. J'analyse le cercle de danse comme lieu permettant de s'ouvrir consciemment au changement, constatant que : 1) il existe une corrélation entre l'apprentissage situé et la création du savoir; 2) la création du savoir et les pratiques hip-hop sont interreliées; 3) la culture b-boy évoque une communauté de savoir novatrice partageant des connaissances personnelles pour générer et faire progresser un savoir collectif. Mon approche aiderait les éducateurs à mieux comprendre comment cette activité de quartier créée il y a trente ans, par et pour des jeunes du South Bronx, s'est transformée en pratique réalisée et consommée à l'échelle du globe par les jeunes et les adultes contemporains.</description><description>My study focuses on b-boying, the archetype of hiphop dance, to better understand the informal teaching and learning processes embodied in the freestyle or raw b-boy cipher (improvisational dance circle). I draw from an ethnographic approach to investigate how hiphop aesthetic practices influence people's ways of doing and habits of mind. In particular, participant observation structures my activities at 13 hiphop events. These observations are complemented by an in-depth interview with Buddha, co-founder of the Canadian Floor Masters, Canada's oldest b-boy dance crew. The theoretical framework uses Lave and Wenger's concept of situated learning in tandem with Nonaka's organizational theory of knowledge creation. By analyzing the cipher as a potential site for dancers to experience a conscious readiness to change I find that 1) situated learning and knowledge creation are closely related; 2) knowledge creation and hiphop practices are connected; 3) b-boy culture resembles an innovative knowledge community that shares personal knowledge to create and advance communal knowledge. The research approach I practice may help educators better understand how a neighbourhood activity created over 30 years ago by and for some South Bronx youth has developed into a global practice produced and consumed by many of today's youth and adults.</description><creator>Lefebvre, Haidee</creator><contributor>Bronwen Low (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Education - Curriculum and Instruction</subject><title>B-boy (dance) cipher: an innovative knowledge community's shared activity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s893p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d168t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c465r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our sensory systems are continually confronted with the task of differentiating sensory inputs due to external events (exafference) from sensory information due to our own actions (reafference). Discriminating between these two types of stimuli is critical in order to achieve accurate perception and motor control. The current mechanism that explains how the vestibular system deals with this issue states that during an active movement, a prediction of the sensory consequences of motor commands computed by an internal model is compared to the actual sensory feedback; if the internal model's prediction and sensory feedback match, the vestibular signal is cancelled, if they do not, the vestibular signal is left unaltered. The studies presented in this thesis were aimed at understanding this fundamental mechanism. In particular, I investigate 1- the rules that govern the cancellation of vestibular reafference, 2- the adaptability of the internal model that underlies vestibular reafference cancellation and 3-the role of the vestibular cerebellum in the processing of passive and active motion. First, I establish that disrupting sensory feedback during an active movement affects the ability of central vestibular neurons to suppress vestibular reafference. Specifically, when proprioceptive feedback is disrupted during an active movement, vestibular reafference is no longer suppressed. In addition, I demonstrate that vestibular reafference due to active body movements are suppressed at the first central stage of vestibular processing. Second, I demonstrate that the internal model underlying the suppression of vestibular reafference adapts such that vestibular neurons regain the ability to suppress vestibular reafference in conditions when the relationship between motor commands and the actual head movements are altered. My findings strongly suggest that indeed the internal model used to predict the sensory consequences of motor commands is quickly updated when faced with new relationships between expected and actual sensory feedback.Finally, I examine the role that the cerebellum plays in the encoding of passive versus active motion. I found that in the passive condition, neurons in the rostral fastigial nucleus (FN) encode two separate representations of motion; half the neurons encode head motion and the other half encodes body motion. The neurons in the rostral FN that encode body movements provide the first neuronal correlate for the perception of body motion. Then I address how vestibular information is processed by the rostral FN during active movements. We found that neurons in the vestibular cerebellum were attenuated during active head and body motion and demonstrate for the first time that the primate cerebellum explicitly encodes the detailed time course of exafference. Taken together the results in this thesis provide firm evidence that vestibular reafference is suppressed during active head and body motion by a mechanism that compares the brain's internally generated expectation of the consequences of voluntary movements with the actual incoming sensory information.</description><description>Nos systèmes sensoriels doivent continuellement faire la différence entre des sensations dues aux événements extérieurs (exaférence) et des sensations provoquées par nos propres actions (réafférence). Faire la différence entre ces deux types de stimuli est essential pour permettre une perception et un control moteur précis. Cette distinction est possible, au niveau du système vestibulaire, grâce au fait qu'une prédiction des conséquences sensorielles de la commande motrice évaluée par un modèle interne est comparée avec le retour sensorielle réel; si la prédiction du model interne est similaire au retour sensoriel, le signale vestibulaire est supprimé; si ils sont différent, le signal vestibulaire n'est pas altéré. Les études présentées dans cette thèse ont pour but de comprendre ce mécanisme fondamental. Plus particulièrement, je cherche a établir 1- les règles qui gouvernent la suppression des réafférences vestibulaire, 2- l'adaptabilité du modèle interne qui sous-tend la suppression des réafférences vestibulaire et 3- le rôle du cervelet vestibulaire dans le processus de différentiation des mouvements actif et passif.Premièrement, j'ai montré que déranger le retour sensoriel pendant un mouvement actif perturbe la capacité des neurones vestibulaire centraux à supprimer les réafférences vestibulaire. Plus précisément, quand le retour proprioceptif est perturbé pendant un mouvement actif, le retour vestibulaire n'est plus supprimé. De plus, j'ai démontré que le retour vestibulaire due à des mouvements du corps est aussi supprimé au premier niveau central du traitement vestibulaire.Deuxièmement, j'ai démontré que le model interne sous-tendant la suppression des réafférences vestibulaire s'adapte pour que les neurones vestibulaire retrouvent leur capacité à supprimer les réafférences vestibulaire dans des conditions ou la relation entre la commande motrice et le mouvement de la tète sont perturbé. Mes résultats suggèrent fortement que le model interne utilisé pour prédire les conséquences sensorielles de la commande motrice est rapidement mis a jour quand il est en présence de nouvelles relations entre retour sensoriel attendu et réel. Finalement, je me suis intéressé au rôle que joue le cervelet pour encoder les mouvements passif et actif. J'ai trouvé qu'en condition passive, les neurones du noyau rostral de fastigial  (FN rostral) encodent deux représentations différentes du mouvement; la moitié des neurones encodent les mouvements de la tète et l'autre moitié encode les mouvements du corps. Les  neurones du FN rostral qui encodent les mouvements du corps fournissent le premier corrélat neural de la perception des mouvements du corps. Puis j'aborde la question de comment l'information vestibulaire est traite par le FN rostral pendant les mouvements actifs? Nous avons trouvé que la réponse des neurones dans le cervelet vestibulaire est atténuée pendant les mouvements actifs de la tète et du corps. Cela démontre pour la première fois que le cervelet des primates encode les exafférences.Dans leur ensemble les résultats de cette thèse fournissent des évidences solides en faveur de la suppression des réafférences vestibulaire pendant les mouvements actifs de la tète et du corps. Cette suppression est possible grâce à un mécanisme qui compare les prévisions des conséquences d'un mouvement volontaire générées par le cerveau avec le retour sensoriel réel. </description><creator>Brooks, Jessica</creator><contributor>Kathleen E Cullen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>How actions alter sensory processing: reafference cancellation in the vestibular system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j516p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c465r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nz63k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les oligodendrocytes (OLs) sont les cellules myélinisantes du système nerveux central (SNC). Les OLs matures formant la myéline sont dérivés des précurseurs d'OLs, qui se différencient pendant le développement. La myélinisation engendre la formation de différents domaines axonaux autour des nœuds de Ranvier, zones non-myélinisées de l'axone. Le maintien de ces domaines est essentiel pour la conduction axonale saltatoire, et plusieurs protéines de la myéline contribuent au maintien de la structure et de la fonction de la myéline. La nétrine-1 et son récepteur DCC sont impliqués dans le maintien des jonctions paranodales in vitro, mais leur rôle in vivo n'est pas encore établi. La myéline est également une source majeure d'inhibition après une lésion du SNC. Dans cette thèse, différents aspects de la biologie des OLs seront couverts. Premièrement, les voies de signalisation impliquées dans la differentiation des OLs seront étudiées. Dans la première partie, je démontre une synergie de facteurs de croissance sur la voie de signalisation PI3K/Akt/mTor, agissant sur la différentiation morphologique des OLs in vitro. Dans la seconde partie, en utilisant des souris knockout conditionnelles, je présente des preuves de l'implication de DCC dans le maintien des paranodes, de la myéline, et de la composition protéique de la myéline. De plus, l'absence d'expression de DCC par les OLs mène au développement d'un déficit moteur de coordination et d'équilibre. Ces résultats montrent que l'expression de DCC par les OLs est requise pour le bon maintien et la stabilité de la myéline in vivo. Finalement, nous avons investigué la source de l'expression de la nétrine-1 dans les lésions du SNC. Nos résultats démontrent que la nétrine-1, en plus d'être potentiellement un inhibiteur associé à la myéline, est aussi exprimée par les fibroblastes et certains astrocytes réactifs dans les lésions de la moelle épinière. L'expression de nétrine-1 pourrait donc contribuer à l'inhibition de la regénération et l'échec de la remyélinisation après une lésion du SNC. Une meilleure compréhension des mécanismes de formation et de maintien de la myéline peut contribuer à développer des stratégies thérapeutiques pour le traitement de maladies démyélinisantes comme la sclérose en plaques, ou à promouvoir le rétablissement des fonctions après les lésions du SNC.</description><description>Oligodendrocytes (OLs) are the myelinating cells of the central nervous system (CNS). They develop from oligodendrocyte precursor cells and differentiate into mature myelin forming OLs. Once myelin is formed, myelinated axons are segregated into different domains around the myelin-devoid nodes of Ranvier. Maintenance of these domains is essential for efficient saltatory conduction, and several myelin proteins contribute to the maintenance of myelin structure and function. Netrin-1 and its receptor DCC were shown to be involved in the maintenance of paranodal axoglial junctions in vitro, but their role in vivo is not established. Myelin is also a major source of inhibition in the injured CNS, and several myelin proteins have been shown to inhibit axonal regeneration. In this thesis, different aspects of OL biology will be considered. First, signaling pathways involved in OL differentiation will be studied. I demonstrate a synergistic combination of growth factors that promotes late stages of OL differentiation via the PI3K/Akt/mTor pathway in vitro. In the second part, I present in vivo evidence of the involvement of DCC in paranodal and myelin maintenance, and in myelin protein composition. Furthermore, absence of DCC expression by OLs leads to the development of a balance and coordination deficit in mice. These results show that expression of DCC by OLs is required for proper maintenance and stability of myelin in vivo. Finally, I investigate the source of netrin-1 expression in the injured CNS. Our findings demonstrate that netrin-1, in addition to being a potential myelin-associated inhibitor, is also expressed by fibroblasts and some reactive astrocytes in the injured CNS. Netrin-1 expression might contribute to the inhibition of regeneration and failure of remyelination in the injured CNS. Understanding the mechanisms of myelin formation and maintenance will help to develop therapeutic strategies for the treatment of demyelinating diseases like multiple sclerosis, and to promote functional recovery following CNS injury. </description><creator>Bull, Sarah-Jane</creator><contributor>Timothy E Kennedy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Mechanisms promoting myelin formation and maintenance under normal and pathological conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547w53q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nz63k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702qb47v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:47:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse propose un questionnement sur la notion de culture diplomatique durant les années 1650, en France et en Angleterre, à l'aide d'un échantillon de 10 ambassades françaises et anglaises et grâce à une source inédite dans le domaine de l'histoire diplomatique : les périodiques. Au fils des pages du Mercurius Politicus et de la Gazette, la culture diplomatique apparaît sous une nouvelle forme, modifiée en partie par les objectifs des gouvernements français et anglais lorsqu'ils faisaient écrire ces articles, mais aussi par les idéaux des lecteurs de ce nouveau médium. Présentant tout d'abord les menus détails de sa méthodologie et l'évolution de l'historiographie des différents sujets abordés ici, cette thèse offre ensuite une série de parallèles entre le contenu de la correspondance diplomatique et des articles de ces deux périodiques, pour cette période. De telles comparaisons permettent de découvrir que la correspondance diplomatique laissa une image plus personnalisée, détaillée et souvent réaliste des missions diplomatiques de l'époque. À l'inverse, les périodiques eurent plutôt tendance à associer les diplomates à des objets utiles, quoi qu'impersonnels, dont l'usage ultime était d'appuyer différentes politiques, valeurs ou idéaux. Les agents publics, au travers de ces pages, n'ont pas à défendre leur honneur ou celui de leur État : leur présence à l'étranger se veut à elle seule une garantie de la puissance de leur pays. De telles tangentes obligent à reconsidérer la définition de la culture diplomatique, principalement en fonction des acteurs qui en affectèrent l'évolution.Une telle perspective prouve qu'au milieu du 17e siècle, la sphère publique représentative existait, mais conjointement aussi à une certaine sphère publique civile, où le poids de ce public pensant se faisait déjà sentir à certains niveaux. Ce public ne se limitait pas à simplement lire ces divers articles : il en affecta aussi le contenu par ses intérêts et ses valeurs. La culture diplomatique ne se voulait donc pas seulement limitée au monde clos des élites étatiques et des diplomates eux-mêmes, mais s'étendait jusqu'à ce nouveau public, évoluant ainsi en partie selon ses vues.  </description><description>This dissertation aims at redefining the term diplomatic culture in the 1650s in France and England. This task will be done via a data of 10 French and English embassies and with the help of a unique source in the field of diplomatic history: the newspapers. While analyzing the articles of both the Mercurius Politicus and the Gazette, the diplomatic culture of this period seems to change in form, influenced by both the goals of the French and English governments in writing these newspapers, but also shaped by the views of the readers of this new medium.Beginning with a description of its methodology and the evolution of the different types of historiographies used in here, this dissertation then moves towards a parallel analysis of both the content of diplomatic correspondence and the articles of these two newspapers for this period. Such comparisons suggest that the diplomatic correspondence offers a more detailed, personal and even down to earth accounts of diplomatic missions. On the other hand, newspapers prefer to use diplomats as tools to promote various policies, values, and ideas. Diplomats, in such articles, do not have to defend their honor or the honor of their country: their presence abroad already symbolizes such an honor, according to the editors of these newspapers. Confronted with these two different perspectives, the definition of diplomatic culture needs to be reconsidered, mainly based on the actors affecting the evolution of this notion.Such a perspective demonstrates that by the middle of the 17th century, the representative public sphere did exist, but was also shared by a certain civil public sphere, where the voice of the public was starting to have its own weight. This public did not just limit itself to reading newspapers; it also affected their content by its own interests and values. Therefore, diplomatic culture was not only limited to the selected world of the diplomats and state leaders, but also spread to this new public and even evolved partly according to its own views.</description><creator>Cote, Marie-Helene</creator><contributor>Brian Cowan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>History - European</subject><title>La culture diplomatique des années 1650, ou son imaginaire</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78th30w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702qb47v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37925</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>