<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:32:24Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182p22c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:37:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study attempts to describe and account for the overall lung cancer mortality pattern, by ethnic group and religion, of the City of Montreal from 1956 to 1966. Lung cancer mortality appeared high for Jewish females relative to her non-Jewish equals and low for Jewish males compared with non-Jewish males. The Jewish male and female lung cancer cases had lower proportions of “epidermoid or anaplastic” cell types comprising their total pathologies, higher proportions of nonsmokers, and they consumed fewer cigarettes, on the average, than did their non-Jewish counterparts.</description><creator>Horowitz, Isadore</creator><contributor>McDonald, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Epidemiology and Health.</subject><title>Lung cancer among the Jewish and non-Jewish of Montreal, Quebec, 1956-1966: mortality rates, and cigarette smoking behaviour</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nc02h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182p22c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x2378</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:37:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We studied various indices of ventilation distribution before and after airway occlusion (AO) was produced by insufflation of beads into bronchi of excised dog lobes. AO delayed multiple breath N2 washouts and markedly increased the slope of the alveolar plateau of the single breath N2 curves. To detect diffusion gradients, the HE/SF6 ratio was measured during expiration following a single breath of these gases. Before AO we found small gradients. However, after AO, we consistently found the initial gas HE rich and later samples SF6 rich. Absolute concentrations of both gases fell during expiration. Breathholding reversed both effects. Gas sampled from a catheter wedged into an airway of a normal lobe was consistently SF6 enriched. Thus, HE and SF6 must separate during inspiration, possibly by radial diffusion of HE, allowing SF6 to penetrate deeper into the alveoli. Diffusion equilibration across collateral channels is slow and the distribution of ventilation to the collaterally ventilated space is abnormal even though its tidal volume is normal.</description><creator>Hogg, William E.</creator><contributor>Macklem, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The effects of experimental airway obstruction on the distribution of ventilation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4307781.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x2378</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z129z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:37:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The peristaltic reflex is regulated by complex nervous and hormonal mechanisms. It can be elicited in vitro by stimulation of the intestinal mucosa, but the functional relationships between the mucosa and the motor activity of the intestine are virtually unknown. Such a relationship is suggested by the frequent association of paralytic ileus with the stress ulcer syndrome. This problem was investigated in vivo in the awake dog. Elective stimulation of the mucosal peristaltic reflex was attempted by instillation of 0.1 N HCl into the intestine. Such a stimulation was followed by a reproducible motor response.</description><creator>Guisan, Yves J.</creator><contributor>Hreno, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>A study of intestinal motility: (with comments on post-operative paralytic ileus)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225f33r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z129z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pd79p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thrombosis initiated by intravascular prosthetic devices remains a major complication of cardiovascular surgery. Blood coagulation mechanisms are reviewed with respect particularly to initiation and propagation of thrombus formation on prosthetic surfaces. The platelet' s role in thrombogenesis is emphasized. Standardization of in vivo thrombogenic models must be achieved before testing new local methods of thrombus inhibition. In this project a polished quarts ring implanted in the mongrel dog’s interior vena cava or abdominal aorta served as a thrombogenic model. Evaluation of the dog's thrombosis response to this intravascular ring revealed a highly variable response.</description><creator>Foster, Eric D.</creator><contributor>Dobell, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The development of a nonthrombogenic surface utilizing surface photopolymerization of platelet inhibitors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q60r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pd79p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602407w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Enterochromaffin cells were investigated in the jejunum of adult mice using electron microscope radioautography at various times during continuous infusion of 3H-thymidine. Enterochromaffin cells were classified into three types: biconcave granule cells or type I (60%), large spherical granule cells or type II (13%), and small spherical granule cells or type III (24%). Uncommon spherical granule cells accounted for about 3%. Typical enterochromaffin cells do not divide, but undergo renewal by differentiation of unrecognized precursors in the lower half of intestinal crypts. Labeled enterochromaffin cells appear in crypts by 1-1/2 days, and in villi by 3 days after the infusion started. At 8 days, 80 percent cells were labeled both in crypts and villi. And 8 days after stopping a 4-day infusion most labeled cells had disappeared from crypts and villi. Enterochromaffin cells migrate from crypt to villus, and are presumably extruded from villus tips. The turnover time would he less than eight days.</description><creator>Ferreira, Mário N.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Renewal of enterochromaffin cells in the mouse jejunum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg028.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602407w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jh65b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The VLDL of both human and rat sera can be dissociated by heparin into an a- and a β-Iipoprotein-containing component of reproducible composition. The heparin precipitable β-containing component of human and rat VLDL contains more than 90% of the triglycerides and cholesterol of that fraction, consistent with the role of the β-lipoproteins as the main triglyceride and cholesterol carriers in the circulation. The heparin soluble a-containing component contains a higher phospholipid to protein ratio than that of any of the other serum lipoprotein fractions, suggesting that it may contain a peptide with high affinity for phospholipids such as the "C" protein, known to be present in human VLDL. Only about 10% of the protein of human and rat VLDL was found in the heparin soluble fraction, while 90% was recovered in the heparin precipitable fraction. The lipid composition of the β-containing component of the VLDL does not resemble that of the β-protein of LDL, nor does the a-containing component of the VLDL resemble the a-protein of the HDL in this respect.</description><creator>Eckhaus, Anita I.</creator><contributor>Rubinstein, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Aspects of the chemical structure and metabolism of serum lipoproteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb53p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jh65b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rs01t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plasma converting enzyme activity (PCEA) and plasma renin activity (PRA) were measured simultaneously by the Boucher's methods. PCEA was similar in 13 control subjects and 33 essential hypertensive patients on 135 mEq Na and 90 mEq K diet in recumbent position. The renin-stimuli upright posture, furosemide, and sodium depletion did not modify PCEA in control subjects and essential hypertension, while PRA increased (p &lt; 0.01) in all control subjects and essential hypertension but 7 patients with suppressed renin. We found a slight decrease of PCEA with pressor doses of angiotensin II or nor-epinephrine in normal subjects on sodium depletion.</description><creator>Dewailly, Philippe</creator><contributor>Boucher, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies of plasma converting enzyme activity and plasma renin activity in human plasma in various physiological and pathological states</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp449.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rs01t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wb644</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nature of the association between pulmonary atherosclerosis and pulmonary hypertension was investigated by inducing les ions ln the pulmonary arteries of rabbits and examining the material for evidence of a coincident pulmonary hypertension. Two techniques were used to induce the lesions, one mechanical and the other dietary. In the first, the lung was embolized with segments of polyethylene tubing in a feasibility study whose purpose was to induce fibrin-platelet thrombosis. In the second, lesions were induced by cholesterol feeding and, in a sub-group, modified by the administration of synthetic surface-active agents.</description><creator>Child, Geoffrey V.</creator><contributor>Thurlbeck, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Experimental pulmonary atherosclerosis in the rabbit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547v63r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb644</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r452</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies with human subjects show that aluminum workers in refining and reduction plants have a significant increase in serum aluminum and in prothrombin time. Serum intestinal alkaline phosphatase, serum acid phosphatase, and blood ATP levels are significantly decreased.</description><creator>Chan, Peter W.</creator><contributor>Waldron-Edward, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Some metabolic effects of aluminum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s124.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r452</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064903f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The competitive binding of oleate and bilirubin to albumin was evaluated in vitro using three different methods: reserve albumin binding capacity by HBABA dye, Sephadex G-25 gel filtration, and bilirubin spectral curves in a bilirubin-albumin solution of molar ratio 1.6. Both the Sephadex G-25 and spectral curve techniques showed no bilirubin displacement until the concentration of oleate exceeded 1.5 mEq/L. At this concentration of oleate, there was already a 40 - 50% depression in HBABA dye binding, suggesting nonspecificity of the dye for bilirubin and its competitive and non-competitive anions for sites on albumin, a finding confirmed by drug-bilirubin binding studies. Lesser improvement in HBABA dye binding in heparinized as opposed to ACD exchanges was associated with a high rise in free fatty acids (FFA), the result of post-heparin lipolytic activities: FFA was non-competitive with bilirubin in this situation.</description><creator>Chan, George Y.</creator><contributor>Stern, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Competitive binding of bilirubin to albumin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860b05v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064903f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p7807</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A soluble factor, capable of inducing blastic transformation of leukocytes in culture has been described. This substance (BF) was obtained from culture medium derived from mixed leukocyte cultures: its activity was tested in cultures derived from one donor. Leukocytes subjected to 2,000 r x-irradiation were still capable of producing BF. In contrast, mixtures of purified lymphocytes, untreated or irradiated, did not release factor. The response of purified lymphocytes to BF was also much reduced compared to the reaction of non-fractionated leukocytes. Interaction between lymphocytes and BF was however demonstrated by culturing cells preincubated with phytohaemagglutinin and by the capacity of purified lymphocytes to absorb out BF activity. The degree of stimulation of leukocytes depended on the concentration of the BF in the medium: the optimal BF concentration was independent of the number of responding cells in the culture. Subjecting target cells to stimulation simultaneously to BF and mitomycin-treated allogeneic cells indicated that BF is probably not transplantation antigen.</description><creator>Chan, Estella S.</creator><contributor>Gordon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Studies on a ‘blastogenic factor’ produced by lenkocytes in mixed culture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc437.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p7807</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r180q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Local anaesthetics with different combinations of CO2 and pH were applied to sheathed and desheathed frog nerves during conventional stimulation and recording of the compound action potential. While CO2 (1-50%) or local anaesthetic (1 mM) caused a small degree of block, together they had much greater effect, greater at a higher pH (7.3). The permeability of the nerve sheath to radioactive lidocaine and sucrose was measured by perfusing these solutions through a tube of isolated sheath. Samples were taken from a bath surrounding the sheath. The permeability to the anaesthetic was proportional to the fraction of non-ionized lidocaine. It was not changed by CO or H+. It was concluded that CO potentiates the action of local anaesthetics by 1) a direct effect of CO on the axon, 2) concentrating local anaesthetic inside the nerve trunk, 3) converting local anaesthetic to cation through its effect on H+ and 4) summation of effects of CO2 and local anaesthetics on the axon membrane.</description><creator>Catchlove, Richard</creator><contributor>Krnjevic, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>The influence of CO2 and pH on local anaesthetic action</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qm98v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r180q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676z86t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Deoxynucleoside triphosphate pools in bath asynchronous and synchronous cultures of mammalian cells were examined. The pools were examined in asynchronous cultures of HeLa, Chinese hamster and mouse L-cells, and it was found that the absolute amounts of the four triphosphates varied between the cell lines, and that the ratios of the amounts of the four triphosphates varied within each cell line. In a highly synchronous population of HeLa cells it was found that the pools of all four aeoxynucleoside triphosphates fluctuated in a similar, cyclic manner. The nature of these fluctuations was determined, and it was shown that in all probability the deoxynucleoside triphosphate pools do not significantly increase in size just prior to the onset of DNA synthesis.</description><creator>Bray, Geraldine M.</creator><contributor>Brent, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Studies on Deoxynucleoside Triphosphate Pools during the mammalian cell cycle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj65p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676z86t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pr01q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The learning effects under filtered and unfiltered listening conditions for ten severely hearing-impaired children were investigated using minimal pair distinctions. Significant learning occurred under both listening conditions, but there was no significant difference between performance with filtered and unfiltered speech. Subjects were able to learn distinctions based on gross spectral and durational cues, but no learning occurred when minimal pair distinctions depended on relatively subtle spectral differences. It was concluded that these deaf children did not have access to compensatory cues apparently used by hard-of-hearing adults in speech discrimination.</description><creator>Aston, Carletta H.</creator><contributor>Ling, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Human Communications Disorders.</subject><title>Hearing-impaired children’s discrimination of filtered speech</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n4213.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pr01q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Communication Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gh04q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Emergency revascularization may be the treatment of choice in selected cases of acute myocardial infarction, but its benefits and the time available to carry it out have not been well documented.</description><creator>Arnold, Ian M.</creator><contributor>Blundell, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The effects of temporary versus permanent coronary occlusion on the nature of myocardial infarcts in cats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g098j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gh04q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172129v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Seven monkeys were injected with 3H-thymidine (1 µc/gm bw). The testes from three monkeys were removed three hours after injection, and of the remaining four animals twelve days and three hours after injection. By using the relative duration of the stages of the cycle of the seminiferous epithelium (expressed as % of their frequency) and the percentage of tubular cross-sections containing the most evolved labelled germ cells, the duration of the cycle was calculated and found to be equal to 11.6 days. The duration of spermatogenesis which extends over the duration of 3.9 consecutive cycles, is therefore approximately equal to 45 days. On this material, the mode of the renewal of spermatogonia was also studied.</description><creator>Antar, Michael E.</creator><contributor>Clermont, Y. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Duration of the cycle of the seminiferous epithelium and spermatogonial renewal in the monkey (Macaca speciosa)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qm994.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172129v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c374h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the intense conflict in Norman Mailer's development between a naturalistic and a romantic impulse. Hailer develops from his naturalistic first novel to the romance form of his later novels in an effort to solve the problem of the paradoxical nature of power. This central problem is posed in terms of an oedipal struggle between a young man and his father-symbol. Mailer 's turn toward the romance genre can be seen in his later heroes who resemble the Adamic heroes of the nineteenth century American romance; and, in the shift from an objective to a subjective view of nature in his fiction. This increasingly subjective point of view leads to a private mythic framework characteristic of the romance tradition in American literature.</description><creator>Linder, Andras G.</creator><contributor>Reichertz, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>English.</subject><title>Romance and naturalism in Norman Mailer’s development as novelist</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw950.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c374h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967680n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study concerns several aspects of the environmental design of the psychiatric hospital and the organization of mental health services in a semi-rural area of the Province of Quebec. The following aspects are studied: - Study of illness and methods of treatment so as to evaluate needs of the patient. - Comparative study of existing psychiatric services in Canada and Québec. - Geographical study of existing mental health facilities on the island of Montreal and their interrelations. - Conceptual study of the community mental health center and the architecture of similar existing centers. - Study of planning and design criterias for mental health services as applied to a region of Quebec and a program for the community mental health center.</description><creator>LeFriant, René</creator><contributor>Anderson, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Architecture.</subject><title>Centre communautaire regional de santé mentale--plantification et design</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j855r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967680n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f919b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to assess the possible relationship between attitudes held by fathers and sons toward physical education and to determine the relationship between the two sets of measured attitudes with the physical performance of sons. Subjects involved in the study comprised the total grade VIII population of one high school and their fathers. Data were obtained through the use of a battery of physical fitness-performance tests selected from the CANADIAN ASSOCIATION FOR HEALTH, PHYSICAL EDUCATION AND RECREATION MANUAL and the WEAR PHYSICAL EDUCATION ATTITUDE INVENTORY (Short Form). Test results showed that the attitudes of the fathers and sons toward physical education were favourable. A positive and significant relationship was shown to exist between the attitudes of the fathers and sons toward physical education which was acceptable at the .01 level of confidence. However, correlations between the two measured sets of attitudes and the physical performance of sons were not shown to be significant.</description><creator>Jones, William J.</creator><contributor>Pedersen, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Education.</subject><title>The relationship between attitudes held by fathers and sons toward physical education and the relationship between attitudes and physical performance of sons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qg384.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f919b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795b95p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of the present work is to study the deformation of polycrystalline materials when subjected to a general force field using the classical field and probability theories. Fundamental relations related to the proposed theory of deformation will be treated first. Two basic assumptions are made, e.g. that the medium is composed of a finite number of grains or crystals which are randomly distributed in the configuration space, and that each grain can be treated as a finite continuum obeying the laws of the classical field theory. Continuum field theories and some essential points of statistical and probabilistic mechanics are discussed first. The probabilistic model upon which the proposed theory is based is then developed. In its light the kinematic relations for the deformation process are formulated. Finally, the measurable or macro-quantities are evaluated in terms of first moments of the deformation field. Spatial correlations of the random fields are also formulated.</description><creator>Haller, Julian K.</creator><contributor>Axelrad, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>Kinematics of deformation of inhomogeneous solids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278x50d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b95p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c375s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this experiment was to study cytological changes in the thymus of neonatal mice during hydrocortisone induced involution and regeneration with the light and electron microscopes. Neonatal mice of strain ICR/Ha were used in this study. They were injected subcutaneously with 0.1 mg hydrocortisone within 24 hours after birth. The weights, mitotic indices, and histology of the treated thymuses were compared to the control groups at 6 hours, 24 hours, and 3, 15, and 30 days post-treatment. An analysis of the ratio of the thymic weight to body weight in the treated group showed a significant decrease at 24 hours, and 3 days after treatment.</description><creator>Wowchuk, William</creator><contributor>Joneja, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Light and electron microscopic studies on the effect of hydrocortisone on the thymus of neonatal ICR/Ha inbred mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rc07c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c375s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d570080f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the aspect of the metropolis/satellite relationship of the United States and Canada that exists between their respective stock exchanges. The analysis is not limited to an examination of the stock market out is more directed to the economic, psychological, and social factors that are revealed about these two countries’ relationship by the operations of their stock exchanges. This research was carried out to determine how capital gets drained out of Canada and is thus not available for investment in Canadian enterprises. The date revealed that this occurs because the New York market offers many advantages to Canadian investors, such as very profitable growth stocks that are unavailable in Canada and liquidity to deal in large blocks of stock. </description><creator>Fulop, Michael</creator><contributor>Dixon, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Sociology.</subject><title>The organizational structure of the stock exchange and the availability of capital in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn48b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570080f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1619367</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette brêve description du comportement ambivalent de Laurent le Magnifique contient plus que le simple mépris de l'auteur à l'endroit de cet illustre représentant de la famille Médici. L'illusion entretenue qui nous est fournie comme exemple signifie plus pour l'observateur attentif et retiré qu'un simple passage biographique; elle est une nouvelle rencontre avec l'éternelle mauvaise foi qui, elle, n'est pas illusoire parce qu'historique, avec ce déguisement que la conscience opère au niveau de l'agir humain et qui a toujours offensé les honnêtes gens en plus de faire rougirmles tenants de la discussion spéculative.</description><creator>Arcand, Gabriel</creator><contributor>DiGiovanni, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Philosophy.</subject><title>Sur le caractère moral de la méthode prescrite dans Le Prince de Nicholas Machiavel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn00p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1619367</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537413p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The immunoglobulins G, A and M run chiefly in the beta and gamma regions on cellulose acetate electrophoresis. Observations suggest that in most instances the immunoglobulins G and A can be predicted on a semiquantitative basis from the electrophoretic densitometer pattern by inspection using simple parameters and that elevated values in many patients can be excluded with a considerable degree of confidence. It is not possible to predict effectively the value of immunoglobulin M. Data for analysis have been derived from thirty-five healthy subjects and two hundred patients. Protein fractionation was performed by electrophoresis on cellulose acetate membranes using the Beckman Microzone system and an Analytrol densitometer-integrator. The immunoglobulins G, A and M were determined using an agar gel immunodiffusion technique with commercially prepared plates and standards (Hyland). Multiple correlations were made with the aid of a computer, to determine the best parameters for predicting the immunoglobulins.</description><creator>Hsieh, Shelton H.</creator><contributor>Gault, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Predicting immunoglobulins from electrophoretic patterns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sk45s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537413p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172130m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:38:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The etiology and pathogenesis of pancreatitis remain a very-controversial problem despite a large amount of clinical and experimental work. Among the numerous factors that have been found more or less associated with pancreatitis, alcoholism and biliary tract diseases are the most frequent 43, 66, 145. The present study is concerned principally with so called "gallstone pancreatitis”.</description><creator>Poncelet, Paul</creator><contributor>Thompson, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The role of infected bile in experimental pancreatitis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1395175.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172130m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>