<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:51:23Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25575" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nx64b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Dory, Ladislav.</creator><date>1978</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>The catabolism of human and rat very low density lipoproteins by perfused rat hearts /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb3978970.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nx64b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139257h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Dixit, Bharat</creator><date>1978</date><subject>Oceanography -- Beaufort Sea.</subject><title>Some mesoscale flow features in the Beaufort Sea during AIDJEX 75-76</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw547.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139257h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407x886</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>C. elegans worms with mutations in the gene CLK-1 develop slowly  and have an extended lifespan. CLK-1 encodes a mitochondrial protein that is  responsible for the hydroxylation of 5-demethoxyubiquinone (DMQ), the penultimate  step of ubiquinone (Coenzyme-Q or UQ) biosynthesis. Structural homologues of CLK-1  are found in mammals, fruit flies, yeast and some types of bacteria. Interestingly,  however, there is no structural homologue of CLK-1 in the Arabidopsis genome and no  plant homologue can be found in other sequence databases. Yeast with the CLK-1  homologue COQ7 deleted fail to grow on non-fermentable carbon sources. To identify a  plant functional homologue of COQ7/CLK-1, an Arabidopsis cDNA expression library was  screened for complementation of a yeast coq7 deletion mutant. A clone was identified  that rescued the coq7 respiratory deficiency. Although the sequence of the encoded  protein has no structural similarity to proteins in the COQ7/CLK-1 family, it  contains a monooxygenase/hydroxylase domain that has sequence similarity with the E.  coli DMQ hydroxylase encoded by the UBIF gene. Like the structural homologues of  COQ7/CLK-1 found in other eukaryotes, the gene (AQX for 'Alternate  Quinone monooXygenase') contains a likely mitochondrial  targeting presequence at its N-terminus. HPLC analysis of quinone extracts from  rescued cog7 strains does not detect ubiquinone, but instead shows another peak that  may be DMQ. It is likely that AQX does not hydroxylate yeast DMQ effectively enough  to generate detectable levels of UQ. A unique pathway for UQ biosynthesis in plants  is proposed that is defined by AQX and Arabidopsis genes identified on the basis of  homology to known E. coli and yeast UQ biosynthesis genes.</description><creator>Storey, Benjamin, 1973-</creator><contributor>Brown, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Plant enzymes -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Ubiquinones -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Arabidopsis -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>AQX : a novel gene in plant ubiquinone biosynthesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd54h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x886</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676w16q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>AI planning benefits greatly from the use of temporally-extended  or macro-actions. Macro-actions allow for faster and more efficient planning as well  as the reuse of knowledge from previous solutions. In recent years, a significant  amount of research has been devoted to incorporating macro-actions in learned  controllers, particularly in the context of Reinforcement Learning. One general  approach is the use of options (temporally-extended actions) in Reinforcement  Learning [22]. While the properties of options are well understood, it is not clear  how to find new options automatically. In this thesis we propose two new algorithms  for discovering options and compare them to one algorithm from the literature. We  also contribute a new algorithm for learning with options which improves on the  performance of two widely used learning algorithms. Extensive experiments are used  to demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed algorithms.</description><creator>Stolle, Martin</creator><contributor>Precup, Doina (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Automated discovery of options in reinforcement learning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm58m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676w16q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472x04s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study assessed the diets of participants in the Kahnawake  Schools Diabetes Prevention Project (KSDPP). Data were gathered from three  cross-sectional surveys of students in grades four to six in the Mohawk community of  Kahnawake. Single 24-hour recall interviews were conducted in 2002 (n = 151), 1998  (n = 153) and 1994 (n = 164). Mean number of servings of Vegetables and Fruits (3.6  per day), Milk Products (1.6 per day), and Meat and Alternatives (1.5 per day) were  found to be below ranges recommended by Canada's Food Guide to Healthy Eating.  Correspondingly, mean intakes of fibre, calcium and vitamin D were found to be below  Adequate Intake references. Positive changes detected include a decrease in soda  consumption and a shift toward whole grains. Results indicate that improved nutrient  intakes will require closer adherence to the principles of Canada's Food Guide to  Healthy Eating. KSDPP intervention staff are using results as a basis for  intervention.</description><creator>Salmon, Laura</creator><contributor>Gray-Donald, Katherine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Diet -- Québec (Province) -- Kahnawake Indian Reserve.</subject><subject>School children -- Québec (Province) -- Kahnawake Indian Reserve -- Nutrition</subject><subject>School children -- Food -- Québec (Province) -- Kahnawake Indian Reserve</subject><subject>Mohawk Indians -- Québec (Province) -- Kahnawake Indian Reserve -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Mohawk Indians -- Food -- Québec (Province) -- Kahnawake Indian Reserve.</subject><title>Contribution of foods to nutrient intakes of grades 4-6 students participating in Kahnawake Schools Diabetes Prevention Project 1994, 1998 and 2002</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x89g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472x04s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pd55s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis was to evaluate the construct  validity, the inter-rater reliability and the prognostic potential of the Gross  Motor Function Classification System (GMFCS). The analysis was carried out in a  cohort of 111 children with cerebral palsy who participated in the HBO Study for  children with cerebral palsy; a randomized multicentre clinical trial. Construct  validity was examined by correlating the results from the GMFCS with that of the  Gross Motor Function Measure (GMFM), the Pediatric Evaluation of Disability  Inventory (PEDI) and the JEBSEN test of hand function. The inter-rater reliability  of the GMFCS was explored by comparing the GMFCS values calculated by one therapist,  using the HBO Study pre-trial patient charts, with those of another physical  therapist who was blinded to the initial scores done earlier on the same records,  and who was well-versed in the GMFCS. The prognostic properties of the GMFCS were  examined by comparing, within each of the GMFCS levels, the mean change over time,  for the GMFM, the PEDI, and the JEBSEN.</description><creator>Salib, Sherif</creator><contributor>Boivin, J. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Collet, J. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Psychology, Psychometrics.</subject><title>Psychometric properties of the gross motor function classification system for children with cerebral palsy : validity, reliability and prognostic value</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h010p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd55s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w23c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Organotin compounds are used for a variety of applications  including antifouling paints for ship hulls, wood preservatives, and UV stabilizers  in plastics. When they are released into aquatic environments, they easily  accumulate in various marine organisms. Organotin compounds are considered endocrine  disrupting chemicals since numerous marine organisms exhibit sexual abnormalities  when exposed to dibutyltin. Singe certain bacteria show resistance to these  compounds, we screened for genes that are induced by organotins. 3000 Escherichia  coli clones were genetically engineered to contain the luxAB reporter genes from  Vibrio harveyi in single, yet different, chromosomal locations. We screened these  3000 clones in the presence and absence of organotins, and identified a uniquely  responsive clone designated TBT3. Luminescence was measured in liquid media and in  solid media. Upon addition of tributyltin and dibutyltin, luminescence greatly  increased. The transcriptional activity was measured by RNA dot blotting, and two  potential genes ygaP and b2667, were identified as induced by organotins. Also, TBT3  transcriptional activity was measured and compared with the transcriptional activity  of MG1655, the parent strain of TBT3. The measured transcriptional activity of the  two strains was different, although the conditions in which the measurements were  taken were identical, which gives place to interesting arguments what determines  this difference.</description><creator>Vitos, Gabriella</creator><contributor>Marczynski, G. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>DuBow, M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Identification and characterization of organotin inducible bacterial genes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qq156.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w23c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vb96k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fluoxetine is a selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor, which is  used to treat depression during pregnancy. The aim of this study was to test if  treatment of pregnant guinea pigs with fluoxetine affects serotonin (5-HT) receptors  or behaviors modulated by 5-HT in the resulting offspring. The first experiment  consisted of injecting pregnant guinea pigs with 7 mg/kg/day of fluoxetine or  vehicle through gestation, or delivering no treatment. Hippocampal 5-HT1A receptor  densities were measured in male offspring at 2 weeks of age, and 5-HT2A receptor  densities were measured in the striatum and frontal cortex of male offspring at 9  weeks of age. There were no significant effects of treatment on receptor densities  in these offspring. Secondly, pregnant guinea pigs were administered fluoxetine  (mmg/kg/day) or vehicle using osmotic mini-pumps through gestation, or no treatment  was delivered. In this study, pregnancy characteristics and maternal and pup weights  were assessed. Acoustic startle responses, prepulse inhibition of acoustic startle  and nociception using a hot-plate test were analyzed in the offspring. No  significant treatment effects were found for all outcome measures except in the  hot-plate test where the vehicle group had significantly lower nociceptive  thresholds compared to both fluoxetine and no treatment controls, when data for 9  week-old males and females were combined. The reduced nociceptive threshold after  prenatal vehicle treatment is consistent with previous reports that prenatal stress  can reduce pain threshold. Our finding that fluoxetine exposure in the pregnant dam  has anti-nociceptive effects in offspring as adults is a novel finding, and is  consistent with previous reports that fluoxetine administered to adult animals has  antinociceptive properties.</description><creator>Vartazarmian, Raphael</creator><contributor>Boksa, Patricia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Effects of fluoxetine administration to guinea pigs during pregnancy on serotonin receptors and behavior in resulting offspring</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr005.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb96k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kg944</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the potential of developing in-season  crop yield forecasting and mapping systems based on interpretation of airborne  hyperspectral remote sensing imagery by machine learning algorithms. The data used  for this study was obtained over a corn (Zea mays L.) field in eastern  Canada. The experimental plots were set up at the Emile A. Lods Agronomy  Research Center, Montreal, Quebec. Corn was grown under the twelve combinations of  three nitrogen application rates (60, 120, and 250 kg N/ha), and four weed control  strategies (Broad leaf weed, Grass weed, Broad leaf and grass weed control, and no  weed control). The images of the experimental field were taken with a Compact  Airborne Spectrographic Imager (CASI) at three times (June 30 for early growth  stage, August 5 for tassel stage, and Aug 25 for mature stage) during the year 2000  growing season. Two machine learning algorithms, Artificial Neural Networks  (ANN) and Decision Tree (DT) were evaluated. The performance of ANNs was compared  with four conventional modeling methods. For the DT algorithms, two different  aspects, (i) DT as a classification method, and (ii) DT as a feature selection tool,  were explored in this study.</description><creator>Uno, Yoji</creator><contributor>Prasher, S. O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Agriculture -- Remote sensing.</subject><subject>Crop yields -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Decision trees.</subject><subject>Neural networks (Computer science)</subject><title>Application of machine learning methods and airborne hyperspectral remote sensing for crop yield estimation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qs614.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kg944</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r9674298</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The warped braneworld picture introduced by Randall and Sundrum  provides new ways of solving long-standing problems in physics, like the gauge  hierarchy problem. If the warp factor is different for the time and space components  of the metric, new effects may arise. We concentrate on this possibility and show  that the speed of gravity may differ from that of electromagnetism, while Lorentz  invariance is preserved for the standard model fields. A charged black hole in a 5  dimensional bulk provides the necessary background. Its properties are studied in  detail to ensure correct embedding of the brane. Computation of the speed of gravity  in this setup is done both perturbatively and numerically. The results are compared  with experimental bounds to constrain the parameters of our  scenario.</description><creator>Valcárcel, Luis, 1979-</creator><contributor>Cline, James M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><title>Gravitational Lorentz violations in 5D black hole background : a numerical investigation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k782f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9674298</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20st144</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The family of proprotein convertases has been recently  implicated in tumorigenesis and metastasis in animal models. However, these studies  have not yet been completely corroborated in human tumors. Here, we show that mRNA,  protein expression, and protein cleavage profiles of proprotein convertases 1 and 2  are altered in liver colorectal metastasis, compared to unaffected and normal liver.  Active PC1 is overexpressed in tumor, correlating with its mRNA profile. Moreover,  the enhanced PC2 processing pattern in tumor correlates with the overexpression of  its specific chaperone 7B2, which in turn may represent a target for early diagnosis  and treatment. The increased PC2 maturation, as well as the overexpression and  altered processing of PC1 may be either a cause or a consequence for the observed  metastasic phenotype. Nevertheless, they may result in the alteration of the  secretory pathway, which could therefore, modify the cellular microenvironment and  thus favor tumor growth and/or metastasis.</description><creator>Tzimas, George N.</creator><contributor>Metrakos, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Proprotein convertase 1 and 2 profiles in human liver colorectal metastases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n1762.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20st144</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708x14z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction. In their work towards chronic disease prevention,  public health practitioners need valid tools to survey trends in dietary intake.  Currently the Rapid Risk Factor Surveillance System includes an optional six-item  vegetable and fruit intake food frequency questionnaire (FFQ module. Our objectives  are (1) to evaluate the potential for the frequency or occasions of consumption from  the FFQ to stand as a reasonable proxy for quantified servings collected through a  reference method and, (2) to compare each method's assessment of the proportion of  the sample averaging five or more occasions or servings of vegetables and fruit per  day. Methods. Dietitians administered the reference method, three 24-hour recalls,  to each of 174 adult respondents who had completed the FFQ as part of the Rapid Risk  Factor Surveillance System. Recalls were conducted over the phone using an  adaptation of the Multiple Pass Method. Tools were mailed to respondents to aid with  portion estimation. Results. The average of total vegetable and fruit intake for the  group was 4.8 servings/day from the recalls and not significantly different from the  4.6 occasions/day from the FFQ. Thirty five percent of respondents were classified  as consuming five or more servings/day by the recall method and 37% were classified  as consuming vegetables and fruit five or more occasions/day by the FFQ. Discussion.  Results indicate this brief questionnaire can be used as a proxy for quantified  intake. The classification of those consuming five or more servings/day by each  method appeared close. Conclusion. Given the limited funding available for nutrition  promotion, surveying trends using this type of food frequency questionnaire can  contribute to decisions regarding the distribution of funds for program  planning.</description><creator>Traynor, Marie</creator><contributor>Gray-Donald, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Nutrition surveys.</subject><subject>Fruit</subject><subject>Vegetables.</subject><title>Validation study of a vegetable and fruit food frequency questionnaire used to survey trends</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8370.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708x14z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000000638</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Commercial positron emission tomography scanners that use block  detectors have additional blurring on spatial resolution, referred to as block  effect. We studied the origin of the block effect, using experiments in which all  other blurring effects were minimized and precisely determined. Bismuth germanate  crystals (1 mm width) and a small (1 mm) 68Ge source were used to probe the spatial  resolution of a CTI HR+ block detector and two precise translation stages to move  detectors. Coincidence aperture functions for crystals in the block and for single  crystals were compared. The central crystals in the block showed an additional  blurring of 0.8 mm whereas the edge ones showed no additional blurring. The apparent  centroids of the crystals in the block are not located at the geometric centers,  which gives errors in the reconstruction algorithm assumed uniform sampling. Our  results suggest that the additional blurring in scanners with block detectors is not  only due to the use of block detectors.</description><creator>Tomic, Nada</creator><contributor>Thompson, Cristopher (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>The origin of the "Block effect" which blurs images in positron emission tomography /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wq78t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000000638</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sd327</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interactions between plant and virus proteins play pivotal roles  in many processes during the viral infection cycle. Analysis of protein-protein  interactions is crucial for understanding virus and host protein functions and the  molecular mechanisms underlying viral infection. Several interactions between  virus-encoded proteins have been reported. However, few interactions between viral  and plant proteins have been identified so far. To examine interactions between  Turnip mosaic potyvirus (TuMV) proteins and plant proteins, recombinant proteins  were produced and used in ELISA-type assays and in in vitro co-immunoprecipitation  experiments. An interaction between TuMV P1 proteinase and wheat poly(A)-binding  protein (PABP) was identified. An interaction between P1 protein and the plant  Arabidopsis thaliana eukaryotic initiation factor (iso)4E [eIF(iso)4E] was also  found. Finally, potential interactions between both TuMV CI and P1 proteins and  between TuMV CI protein and eIF(iso)4E were identified.</description><creator>Thivierge, Karine</creator><contributor>Fortin, Marc G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Protein-protein interactions.</subject><subject>Turnip mosaic virus.</subject><title>Protein-protein interactions in turnip mosaic potyvirus replication complex</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg512.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sd327</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pg82k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Pain after knee surgery has been reported as a  common problem. It is highly ranked in terms of intensity and has important  consequences on both quality of life and psychological well-being. However,  assessment and management of postoperative pain remain a key clinical  problem. Objectives. To describe the occurrence of pain after total knee  arthroplasty (TKA) and knee arthroscopy; identify the predictors of postoperative  pain and evaluate the consequences of pain on quality of life and on depression  status. Methods. Patients were recruited from nine university and  regional hospitals in the province of Quebec and were followed for three months  after knee surgery. Time points of postoperative day 7 and month 3 were our prime  interest. We used a prospective cohort design to investigate characteristics of  postoperative pain and a case-control design to identify the impact of postoperative  pain on quality of life and on depression. Both logistic regression and multiple  linear regression models were used to analyze postoperative pain intensity and the  impact of postoperative pain respectively. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</description><creator>Xu, Daquan, 1965-</creator><contributor>Collet, Jean-Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Epidemiology of pain and pain management after knee surgery : arthroplasty and arthroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193966v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pg82k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247ds70d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>XML, the eXtended Markup Language, is well believed to be the  most common tool of the future for all data manipulation and data transmission. As a  result, a lot of research and work have been done on XML. However, the current  efforts on XML only focus on data queries. So far, there does not exist an XML data  manipulation language that has reached its maturity to be accepted widely. Most of  the existing XML databases only implement some kind of XML data query language and  do not support data update operations. This thesis tries to make up the absence of  XML data updates, and it begins with a through study on topics such as XML language  features, its history and development, the existing XML query languages and update  languages, XML database management systems, and XML indexing structures, etc. Based  on the research, McXML, a native XML database management system, is proposed, which  supports both data queries and data updates, with emphasis on data updates. In order  to optimize the performance of McXML, some indexing structures are developed on it,  which overcome the difficulties incurred by the support of data updates and make  McXML work more efficiently and flexibly.</description><creator>Wu, Jiafeng, 1971-</creator><contributor>Kemme, Bettina (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Information Science.</subject><title>Data indexing and update in XML database</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm41p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247ds70d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mv77p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hurricane Hazel struck North America on 15-16 October 1954, leaving a pattern of heavy rainfall and flooding in its wake. A complete analysis of  the synoptic-scale conditions associated with the transformation of Hazel from its  tropical phase into an extratropical cyclone was first undertaken to discern the  dynamic and thermodynamic elements crucial to the intensification of this  storm. An analogue search was then conducted for Hazel using linear correlations of anomaly sea level pressure and 1000-500 hPa thickness. Three cases were found in 1985, 1995 and 1999. A comparison of these analogues to Hazel yielded  the conclusion that Hazel is a unique event in recent meteorological history, as  none of the analogues produces the extreme precipitation values in Hazel. The lack  of significant hurricane circulations in all of the analogues is the important  difference, as Hazel provides important moisture and latent heating that are absent  in the analogues. Finally a mesoscale modeling study was carried out to test the  sensitivity of Hazel to improved surface vortex structure and increased horizontal  resolution. Specification of the vortex led to a dramatic improvement in the  simulation results, as precipitation and track closely mimicked the observed values.  Enhancing the horizontal resolution to 12 km did not improve upon the 36 km  specified vortex simulation. The movement of the storm slowed considerably as the  development of an upper tropospheric cutoff circulation was diminished in the 12 km  run. The parameterizations governing the interaction between the diabatic outflow  from Hazel and dynamics of the midlatitude trough are poorly modeled in this  situation, and lead to the severe time lag in the path of Hazel.</description><creator>Weese, Scott R.</creator><contributor>Gyakum, John R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A reanalysis of hurricane Hazel (1954) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk174.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv77p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kg93v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study, we have demonstrated that inoculation of bean  seeds with non-pathogenic binucleate Rhizoctonia (np-BNR) at sowing protected bean  seedlings from infection of R. solani. Using quantitative real-time RT-PCR  (QRT-PCR), transcript levels of defense genes encoding 1,3-beta-glucanase (GLUC),  phenylalanine ammonia-lyase (PAL), chalcone synthase (CHS) in one-week old bean  seedlings was monitored during np-BNR and R. solani interaction. The results  revealed that protection effect of np-BNR correspond to a systemic suppression of  these three defense genes' expression from significant higher level elicited by R.  solani to the level of non-infected plants. This indicates that bio-protection by  np-BNR isolates is not correlated to activation of these three defense genes'  expression. Similar suppression was achieved for pre-colonization of bean seedlings  with arbuscular mycorrhizal (AM) Glomus introradices on GLUC gene expression,  although the AM fungus did not significantly reduce rot symptoms. Possible  mechanisms implicated in down-regulation during plant-pathogen and np-BNR or AM  interaction are discussed.</description><creator>Wen, Kui</creator><contributor>Jabaji-Hare, Suha (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizas.</subject><subject>Glomus intraradices.</subject><subject>Rhizoctonia solani -- Biological control.</subject><subject>Beans -- Disease and pest resistance -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Down-regulation of defense gene transcripts of Rhizoctonia solani-infected bean seedlings in response to inoculation with non-pathogenic fungi</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j625m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kg93v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1616759</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The relationship between habitat preferences and rates of  dispersal and directional orientation across different vegetations was investigated  using captures from an array of drift fences for Pseudacris triseriata , at a  breeding pond near Boucherville, Quebec. Growth rates for juveniles were similar  across the study area, suggesting that food was not limiting and movement is related  to habitat preference. Frog residence time in habitat enclosures, and between fence  arrays was significantly longer for frogs in humid prairie vegetation compared to  those in shrubby vegetation. The number of frogs caught per metre of fence in humid  prairies was also on average higher than either shrubby or arid prairie vegetations.  Together both migration rates and captures per metre of fence suggest that the  preferred habitat for P. triseriata is humid prairie vegetation (e.g. Phalaris  grass). Target-oriented dispersal may explain why similar numbers of P. triseriata  were captured in both shrubby and humid prairie vegetation, despite the perceived  preference for humid prairies over shrubby vegetation. The continued persistence of  this population appears to be based on the recruitment of juveniles from the larval  stage, and is also sensitive to the fecundity of the first time  breeders.</description><creator>Whiting, Arthur</creator><contributor>Green, David M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Frog populations -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Striped chorus frog -- Habitat -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Striped chorus frog -- Dispersal -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Population ecology of the western chorus frog, Pseudacris triseriata</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qs60v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1616759</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848r151</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Initiating the muscle differentiation pathway typically results  in activation of muscle-specific genes previously maintained in a silenced state.  One of the processes controlling changes in gene expression during differentiation  is a global demethylation event. The mechanisms involved in this global  hypomethylation are not fully understood. Promoter methylation is one of the normal mechanisms  inactivating gene expression. A single CpG site in the 5' flanking region of  myogenin is reported to undergo demethylation during C2C12 differentiation.  Considering the demethylase feature of MBD2b and its expression profile during C2C12  differentiation, I propose the hypothesis that MBD2b/demethylase is involved in  C2C12 differentiation by demethylating the promoter of the myogenin gene as well as  other genes involved in myogenic differentiation. To test this hypothesis, I determined the consequences of  up-regulation and down-regulation of MBD2b/demethylase in C2C12  cells. The state of the myogenin promoter was also altered as  determined using a probe recognizing a single HpaII site, which was previously  reported to become demethylated during C2C12 differentiation. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</description><creator>Ren, Huiping</creator><contributor>Szyf, Moshe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>MBD2bdemethylase is involved in the myogenesis of C2C12 myoblasts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fp530.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r151</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pg844</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective. To identify predictors of injection cessation among  Montreal active injection drug users (IDUs). Design. Subjects were selected from the St. Luc Cohort, a  prospective study that has accrued IDUs since 1988. Subjects were eligible if they  completed at least 3 visits between 1995 and 1999. Predictors of sustained and of  short injection cessation were examined using logistic and Cox proportional  regression. Results. Sustained injection cessation was negatively associated  with injection frequency, a surrogate marker of addiction severity. Getting syringes  at needle exchange programs or pharmacies impacted positively on the ability of  moderate users to initiate and sustain injection cessation. Recent exposure to  addiction treatment predicted the occurrence of a short injection cessation episode.  This association was stronger among participants reporting longer exposure to  treatment. Conclusion. These findings suggest that harm reduction and  addiction treatment interventions can influence the occurrence of injection  cessation. This information is important for social and health policy  planning.</description><creator>Bruneau, Julie</creator><contributor>Franco, Eduardo L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Investigation of injection cessation in a cohort of injection drug users in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tp91k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pg844</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kg96p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pristane, a pure alkane, is known to induce plasma cell  dyscrasias in BALB/c mice. The present study aimed to investigate the effect of  long-term dietary administration of Echinacea purpurea on immune and hemopoietic  cell populations of the spleen and bone marrow, of normal and plasmacytoma-bearing  mice. The results revealed quantitative cell lineage-specific changes in both the  spleen and bone marrow of pristane-exposed animals. Moreover, the consumption of  Echinacea resulted in cancellation of the pristane-mediated negative effects on NK  cells and nucleated erythroid cells. Echinacea administration over the long-term  resulted in a prolongation of the onset of old age mediated deaths by 120 days, and  indeed resulted in a 30% increase in survival at age of 400 days when 55% of normal  mice, consuming an untreated diet, were dead. In contrast, however, Echinacea did  not improve the lifespan of plasmacytoma-bearing animals.</description><creator>Brousseau, Mélanie</creator><contributor>Miller, Sandra (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>The effects of echinacea purpurea on immune and hemopoietic cell populations in a plasmacytoma mouse model /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g5681.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kg96p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g080s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Soil properties and their spatial variability was measured to  provide a strong database to assess the modification in soil properties associated  with future changes in land use. Surface (0--10 cm) soil samples were collected from  a 9 ha, 46-year-old pasture being converted to a native tree plantation and a  neighboring control pasture near Sardinilla, Panama. A small-scale nested grid of  surface soil samples was replicated in the future plantation and a primary forest in  the region to evaluate the spatial variability of soil properties. Seven 1 m  profiles were sampled in the future plantation and litter samples were collected at  the forest and the future plantation. Assuming the three sites were identical before the conversion to  pasture, the difference in surface soil organic carbon (SOC) was 0.75 kg m-2 or  equivalent to a loss of 0.017 kg m-2 yr -1 since the original land-use change. The  control pasture is higher in bulk density but lower in percent SOC than the future  plantation, which is critical to future comparisons. The pasture soils showed signs of soil compaction and of the  homogenization of soil properties. For the 7 profiles in the future plantation,  total SOC mass ranged from 13.45 to 23.80 kg m-2, and stable isotopes revealed that  82% of the SOC in the top 10 cm is derived from the pasture vegetation, down to 23%  at 1 m depth. Spatially, the full scale of spatial variability was not  determined from the nested grids alone. In addition, the 15 x 15 m grid in the  future plantation generally over-estimated the semivariance at the scales below 3 m.  The nested grids assessed the minimum measurable semivariance below 5  m. The precision of surface estimations from point observations can  be improved by adding a 5 x 5 m grid to any large-scale sampling  scheme.</description><creator>Abraham, Muriel</creator><contributor>Moore, Tim (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Soils -- Organic compound content -- Panama</subject><subject>Deforestation -- Environmental aspects -- Panama</subject><subject>Soils -- Tropics</subject><title>Spatial variation in soil organic carbon and stable carbon isotope signature in a pasture and a primary forest in central Panamá</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n87z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g080s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848r17k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The steady two-dimensional compressible Navier-Stokes equations  are solved using an iterative pseudo-time relaxation technique. An implicit  first-order accurate Euler scheme is implemented after augmenting the steady  governing equations by pseudo-time derivative terms, including artificial  compressibility in the continuity equation and preconditioning in the energy  equation. These augmented equations are modified by lagging certain flow variables  in pseudo-time and by applying approximate factorization and an alternating  direction implicit (ADI) method to split the solution procedure into two successive  sweeps. Spatial discretization is performed on a stretched staggered  grid using central differencing. Then, the momentum equations are decoupled with the  elimination of the pressure terms using the continuity equation. The problem is thus  reduced to the solution of a series of scalar tridiagonal systems of  equations. The computational method is validated for laminar incompressible  flows in channels with downstream-facing steps and for laminar compressible flows  past symmetric airfoils.</description><creator>Zuppel, Eddy</creator><contributor>Mateescu, Dan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>A numerical method for compressible viscous fluid flows /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w170.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r17k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wd31q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis is the analysis, implementation and  testing of a binocular active vision system. The robotic head has six degrees of  freedom: two independently actuated eyes can perform yaw and pitch movements. They  are both mounted on a head also capable of yaw and pitch. The system uses both  visual inputs, from two CCD cameras, and inertial input, from an angular velocity  sensor, to track targets and hold gaze. This work is centered on the robotic head's  binocular gaze controller: a simple method to modify the controller's parameters to  reach specified dynamics is provided. The gaze controller, based on biological gaze  control, can accommodate a wide range of movements: smooth pursuit, version,  vergence, saccades, vestibulo-ocular reflex, gaze holding, and gaze control with an  added head. Unlike other controllers that independently model each movement, the  bilateral controller fuses sensory error signals to drive a single controller; the  output drives to the different motors are also shared. All that is required is a  simple switching strategy for transitions from slow phase to fast phase. Results  illustrate the similarity between simulation and experimentation: this allows easy  modification to the controller.</description><creator>Séjean, Joseph</creator><contributor>Galiana, Henrietta L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Implementation of a biologically relevant gaze controller using sensory fusion and shared motor drives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8388.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wd31q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25600</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>