<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:59:45Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2525" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860904c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research examined the toxicity of complex industrial effluents as measured by chemical analyses, whole effluent toxicity (WET) tests and surveys of the receiving water biota. Toxicity of final effluents from 45 diverse facilities was examined to determine whether inferred toxicity based on presence and concentration of priority substances could predict WET, calculated from a battery of bioassays on bacteria, cladocerans and algae. Following corrections of inferred toxicity for particle-bound contaminants and adjustment for free ion activity, correlation between inferred and whole effluent toxicity was highly significant. Effluents with elevated metal concentrations exhibited lower WET than predicted, likely due to negative interactions among trace metals; kraft mill effluents exhibited higher WET than predicted which is consistent with findings in the literature. The ability of laboratory WET tests to predict thresholds of invertebrate community response to a complex industrial effluent was examined. Patterns in invertebrate community structure were detrended for environmental factors and compared to measured instream effluent concentrations. Laboratory effect thresholds, reported as Maximum Allowable Toxicant Concentrations (MATC), were calculated from a battery of toxicity tests on bacteria, algae, cladocerans and fish. Declines in taxonomic richness corresponded to calculated lab thresholds, while changes in abundance of total taxa and sensitive taxa, (Ephemeroptera, Plecoptera, Trichoptera) occurred at lower concentrations than predicted from MATCs. The tendency for invertebrate abundance to decline at lower instream effluent concentrations than richness supports findings in the literature. Lack of correspondence between lab and field thresholds may be ameliorated by the addition of behavior endpoints, (e.g. avoidance) to toxicity tests.</description><creator>Sarakinos, Helen C.</creator><contributor>Rasmussen, J. B. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Water -- Pollution -- Toxicology.</subject><subject>Benthos -- Effect of water pollution on.</subject><subject>Water quality bioassay.</subject><title>The use of chemical analyses, bioassays and benthic biomonitoring in the toxicity assessment of complex industrial effluents /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd31w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860904c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257h10r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies on Al85Yx Ni15-x glasses established a correlation between crystallization mode (pure growth versus nucleation and growth) and crystallization product. Glasses with approximate compositions x = 5, 7, 8, 10 were studied in order to accurately ascertain the nature of the structural variance which gives rise to different crystallization modes and the identity of the resulting crystallization products. Glasses with x = 5, 10 have a clear distinction: x = 5 contains quenched-in Al nanocrystals which act as nucleating centers leading to alpha-Al as the first crystalline product; equilibrium crystalline phases are alpha-Al, Al3Ni and a stacking variation of Al4YNi. x = 10 is a homogeneous glass which undergoes a glass transition prior to crystallization; first crystalline product is an unstable FCC structure which breaks down via Al segregation; equilibrium phases are alpha-Al, beta-Al3Y and Al16YNi 3. x = 7,8 share these characteristics: x = 7 contains quenched-in Al-nanocrystals and follows the initial x = 5 pattern of primary Al crystallization; however it undergoes a glass transition prior to first stage crystallization and equilibrium phases are alpha-Al, beta-Al3Y and Al16YNi3. x = 8 crystallizes by nucleation and growth yet has identical crystallization products as the corresponding x = 7 crystallization stages. Isothermal annealing prior to first two crystallization stages of x = 8 yields alpha-Al and the unstable FCC structure. Isothermal crystallization is complex, frequently involving the overlap of multiply nucleating phases and the sequential nucleation of successive crystallization stages at the same annealing temperature. The results of these crystallization studies imply that Al-Y-Ni glasses obey the cluster model (Al-Y versus Al-Ni clusters) where cluster-cluster correlation establishes the degree of medium-range order and presence or absence of Al nanocrystals. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Saini, Sajan.</creator><contributor>Altounian, Z. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>A crystallization study of Al-Y-Ni glasses /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r057q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257h10r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jw77r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cystinuria is an autosomal recessive disorder of the kidneys and intestine with defective luminal transport of cystine and other dibasic amino acids (ornithine, arginine, and lysine). Three phenotypes have been described, based on urinary excretion of these amino acids in obligate heterozygotes: Type I (silent carriers); Type II (moderate elevation); and Type III (mild elevation). The SLC3AI (D2H) protein has been shown to enhance cystine reabsorption and mutations in D2H have been reported in cystinuria. The aims of this study were to characterize D2H gene structure and to identify mutations in Quebec patients. The D2H cDNA was used to isolate five genomic clones and to characterize the entire gene. The gene spans over 40 kb and contains 10 exons. SSCP and Southern blotting techniques were successful in identifying six novel mutations (2 large deletions, 3 missense mutations, and one 2bp deletion) in twenty cystinuric patients (8 Type I/I, 9 Type I/III, and 3 Type II/N). Our group has identified mutations in the SLC3A1 gene on 15 of 25 cystinuria chromosomes. All but one of these mutations have been found on patients with Type I/I phenotype (the remaining mutation was identified on a Type I/III patient). These studies have revealed eight mutations unique to Quebec and indicate population-specificity and genetic heterogeneity. Furthermore, SLC3A1 mutations only account for Type I cystinuria. However, since only 1 SLC3A1 mutation was identified in 9 Type I/III patients, the data suggest that another gene(s) is (are) responsible for the Type I/N phenotype in some patients.</description><creator>Saadi, Irfan.</creator><contributor>Rozen, R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Cystinuria -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Characterization of the SLC3A1 (D2H) gene and mutation analysis of cystinuria patients in Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g722t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw77r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j113b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human papillomavirus (HPV) is the sexually-transmitted etiologic agent of cervical cancer. Despite screening programs, cervical cancer remains too common, particularly in developing countries. Various correlates of prevalent infections have been identified. However, the determinants of incident infections have never been studied. Data were collected during a prospective cohort study conducted in Brazil. Incidence density rates of infection were calculated and determinants of incident infection were identified using Cox regression models. Analyses were done for HPV types classified into low-risk and high-risk depending on their association with cervical neoplasia. The incidence density rates were 9.3 and 7.6 per 1000 women-months respectively for low-risk and high-risk HPV infection. Independent positive associations were found between the time of first occurrence of low-risk infection and age, number of sexual partners in the past 5 years, education level and use of non-commercial hygienic absorbents. The first occurrence of high-risk infection was independently predicted by age, age at first sexual intercourse, condom use (negative associations) and by the number of sexual partners in the past year (positive association). Elucidation of the dynamics of infection is a first step towards implementation of public health programs for reducing the risk of cervical cancer.</description><creator>Rousseau, Marie-Claude, 1969-</creator><contributor>Franco, Eduardo L. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Obstetrics and Gynecology.</subject><title>Risk factors for incident cervical human papillomavirus infection in women in a high-risk area for cervical cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989647.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j113b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wz003</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A low-temperature atomic force microscope has been designed and built. The instrument will operate at liquid helium temperatures, and will be used to investigate a number of phenomena observable only at low temperatures, including flux pinning mechanisms in superconductors, as well as domain structure dynamics in microfabricated ferromagnetic particles. This thesis provides a general review of force microscopy, including a summary of the forces to which the instrument is sensitive, as well as the most common modes of operation of the force microscope. An overview of our newly constructed low temperature microscope is then presented, examining each of the components in detail. In addition, the problems of mechanical vibration isolation, thermal properties of materials at low temperatures, as well as remote in-situ manipulation are discussed.</description><creator>Roseman, Mark A.</creator><contributor>Grutter, P. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Design and characteristics of a low temperature atomic force microscope</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps71b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wz003</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r0580</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mechanical weeders were tested on both mineral and organic soils in 1995 and in 1996, to measure their impact on soil physical properties. The weeders were tested in three crops, carrots in mineral and organic soil, beans in mineral soil, and lettuce in organic soil. Soil bulk density and water content were measured at regular intervals during the weeder trial period, and samples for soil structural analysis were collected in the mineral soil at the beginning and at the end of each season. No significant results were found in differences in mean weight diameters of dry and water-stable aggregates. Soil moisture did not vary significantly due to treatment. There was significant compaction caused by the first pass in the field (i.e., seeder) in all the crops at both sites in the 0--10 cm layer, and in some cases, to a depth of 25 cm. Additional field passes with the weeders caused some compaction in the tractor wheel at the 0--10 cm depth, and sometimes in the 10--25 cm layer, in all trials in mineral soil, yet no significant effects of treatments were detected in the trials at the organic soil site. No conclusions could be drawn as to the benefits and/or negative impacts of mechanical versus chemical weeding in mineral soil, with respect to the relative compaction caused by the mechanical weeders. This is because in this experiment spraying of herbicides did not involve tractor traffic in the field.</description><creator>Richman, Jacinda.</creator><contributor>Mehuys, G. R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Soil physics.</subject><subject>Weeds -- Control -- Equipment and supplies.</subject><subject>Cultivators.</subject><title>Soil physical properties under the influence of different mechanical weeders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t849q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r0580</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j282</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A PCR approach using degenerate primers specific for the highly conserved pore and S6 transmembrane domains of K+ channels was used to assess the diversity of K+ channels in the electric fish Apteronotus leptorhynchus. DNA sequence analysis has identified nineteen K+ channel genes, each of which can be classified into one of the four major families in a similar distribution to that in mammals. Also, an Apteronotus brain cDNA library was constructed and screened with mammalian K+ channel probes. The first K+ channel clone obtained displays remarkable amino acid sequence homology to rat Kv1.3 and Northern blot analysis and RNase protection assays have suggested that this channel may play similar roles in both fish and mammals. The results indicate that the duplications which gave rise to multiple genes within each of the K+ channel families predate the divergence of the Actinopterygii and Sarcopterygii lineages during early vertebrate evolution and the function of these K+ channel genes has been conserved between the two lineages.</description><creator>Rashid, Asim J.</creator><contributor>Dunn, Robert J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Molecular characterization of voltage-gated K+ channels in the weakly electric fish Apteronotusleptorhynchus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w196n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j282</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nd28k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although there exists a plethora of studies in the field of addictions treatment examining the factors that predict successful treatment outcome, the profile of persons who benefit the most from treatment has not yet emerged. The present investigation was conducted to evaluate treatment outcomes of various groups of individuals with different substance related disorders, to determine the prevalence of psychiatric comorbidity among these groups and to examine predictors of treatment outcome. Two hundred and thirty-nine substance abusing males and females were extensively assessed at admission with regards to demographic characteristics, substance use variables, psychiatric comorbidity and cognitive functioning. Six-month in-treatment performance was evaluated by monitoring length of stay in treatment, rates of abstinence, attendance in therapy sessions and completion status at discharge. Results indicated that clients with opiate addiction had the worst prognosis and outcome profiles. Elevated rates of psychiatric disorders and moderate to severe psychological distress were observed among these individuals. High levels of depression were found among females and persons abusing alcohol. Outcome data showed that the primary drug of abuse, frequency of use and reason for entering treatment were the most significant predictors of outcome. Even though these variables predicted treatment outcome, their predictive validity was minimal thus limiting interpretability of findings and dictating a need for more research.</description><creator>Paraherakis, Antonios.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Substance-related disorders and associated psychopathology : predicting addictions treatment outcome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1682.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd28k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff025</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:22:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The notion of cartesian closed bicategory is presented, and use of the resulting entities is made to reinterpret, in a uniform and consistent way, the standard work of Lambek and Scott in categorical proof theory [LS]. (Cartesian closed) bicategories are a two-dimensional analogue, or extension, of (cartesian closed) categories. We study them in quite a bit of detail, carefully showing for instance how all the relevant properties of cartesian closed categories can in fact be naturally lifted to their two-dimensional counterparts. They (cartesian closed bicategories) are also shown to allow for a purely algebraic (inference rules based) definition, being models of a certain generalised algebraic theory, in the same way that cartesian closed categories can themselves be entirely specified via Lambek's equational calculus [LS]. After a review of the pertinent pieces of work in categorical logic (mostly based on [LS] and [HM]), we set out to reinterpret all of it within the new framework in a uniform and consistent manner (in the sense that there will be natural injections and projections between the corresponding one- and two-dimensional entities preserving all the relevant features and properties).</description><creator>Ouaknine, Joël.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A two-dimensional extension of Lambek's categorical proof theory /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h37x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff025</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nd29v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The potential of Smicronyx umbrinus Hustache and Smicronyx guineanus Voss (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) as biocontrol agents of Striga hermonthica (Del) Benth was investigated at both population levels of Striga and Smicronyx spp. in the field in Burkina Faso. High population levels of Smicronyx spp. resulted in higher percentages of seed-pod galls although the weevils' adult populations decreased during S. hermonthica seed capsule production. Smicronyx spp. were observed galling Striga aspera (Willd) Benth capsules ca. 60 days before S. hermonthica emerged in sorghum fields. The weevils also galled S. hermonthica stems at soil level and Sm. umbrinus was found to be the main species causing this symptom. Smicronyx spp. also galled Alectra vogelii Benth stems, Smicronyx dorsomaculatus Cox being the main species attacking this parasitic weed. Another Smicronyx species not yet described was collected on A. vogelii. Stem galls appeared to be more effective nutrient sinks than fruit galls. The weevils alone did not have sufficient impact to be considered successful biocontrol agents for S. hermonthica but they could contribute to an integrated control strategy against Striga. Smicronyx spp. have a good potential as biocontrol agents for A. vogelii.</description><creator>Otoidobiga, Lenli Claude.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Smicronyx -- Burkina Faso.</subject><subject>Alectra vogelii -- Biological control -- Burkina Faso.</subject><subject>Purple witchweed -- Biological control -- Burkina Faso.</subject><title>Potential of Smicronyx spp. (Coleoptera:Curculionidae) as biological control agents of Striga hermonthica (Del) Benth and Alectra vogelii Benth (Scrophulariaceae) in Burkina Faso (West Africa)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505255w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd29v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w957h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since glucose is an essential nutrient for normal fetal growth and development, the impact of reduced maternal dietary glucose supply, on amniotic fluid (amf) amino acid composition was investigated. Furthermore, this study investigated whether any resulting changes in the concentrations of amf amino acids could be predictive of fetal growth and metabolic status. Pregnant rat dams were fed isocaloric diets containing graded levels of dietary glucose (0, 12, 24 and 60%) and the amf amino acid content was analysed on gestational days (gd) 18.5 to 21.5. Carbohydrate restriction produced significant increases in the concentrations of amf isoleucine (on gd 21.5), tryptophan (on gd 18.5 and 21.5) and 3-methylhistidine (on gd 20.5 and 21.5). An interaction between diet and day of gestation modified amf taurine levels such that dams fed low carbohydrate diets showed significant increases in amf taurine as pregnancy progressed. Specific amf amino acids correlated with fetal growth parameters and fetal tissue glycogen reserves indicating the ability of amf composition to reflect fetal distress under conditions of compromised maternal nutritional status. A greater statistical predictability of amf constituents was obtained with fetal growth parameters than with fetal tissue glycogen reserves. These results suggest that amf amino acids are better predictors of fetal growth status than of fetal metabolic status.</description><creator>Miniaci, Sandra A.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Pregnancy -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Glucose -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Amino acids -- Metabolism.</subject><title>Maternal dietary glucose restriction and its effect on amniotic fluid amino acid composition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g10q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w957h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz68d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A two-dimensional hydrodynamic model is used to simulate the flow field and the concentration distribution of a conservative tracer in shallow basins. A series of numerical test are performed to evaluate different numerical schemes and problems which arise for the use of the Second Moment Method (SMM) in diffusion dominated flows are reported. The results of the basin simulations are compared with experimental data. The model predicts the location and the size of the dead zones, bypassing, recirculation, and local concentrations within the basin. The positioning of the inlet and outlet, and the presence of baffles are important parameters for the location and size of dead zones. The model gives results which are in agreement with the experimental data. The results show that the hydrodynamic model is quite powerful in terms of predicting correctly the residence time distribution for ponds of various dimensions and shapes.</description><creator>Marchand, Philippe, 1972-</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Hydrodynamics -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Sewage lagoons -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Hydrodynamic modeling of shallow basins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999880z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz68d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117r072</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>SarCNU, a novel chloroethylnitrosourea analogue, is transported by the extraneuronal uptake2 transporter (uptake2). SK-MG-1 human glioma cells are sensitive to SarCNU cytotoxicity and express uptake 2 whereas SKI-1 glioma cells have no detectable transporter, and are relatively resistant. To clone uptake2, we detected differences in RNA expression utilizing differential display. With differential display, we detected a novel sequence expressed in SK-MG-1 cells but not in SKI-1 cells, having 62% homology to an expressed sequence tag clone from human brain, and could be a partial sequence of uptake2. In the treatment of SF-295 glioma xenografts in athymic mice, SarCNU had superior activity than 1,3-bis-(2-chloroethyl)-1-nitrosourea. This suggested that SF-295 cells express uptake2. We determined if expression of uptake2 in the established SF-295 cell line correlated with the enhanced activity of SarCNU in vivo. Transport of [3H]SarCNU was not decreased by inhibitors of uptake2 in the SF-295 cell line and its steady state accumulation was similar to that of SKI-1. The increased stability of SarCNU versus BCNU may account for its enhanced activity in vivo or the expression of uptake2 in vivo may differ from its expression in vitro.</description><creator>Marcantonio, Daniela.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>The catecholamine extraneuronal uptake, transporter is associated with the increased sensitivity of gliomas to sarcosinamide chloroethylnitrosourea /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht914.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117r072</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765373304</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alternative splicing from a single gene or transcription from distinct genes are the two most important genetic mechanisms used to generate protein isoforms. This study concerns the ascidian Ciona intestinalis and the genetic mechanism used in this primitive chordate organism to produce differentially expressed isoforms of the muscle protein troponin I (TnI). Through cDNA cloning and reverse-transcription PCR approaches, the mRNA sequences encoding two distinct Ciona ThI isoforms were determined. These mRNAs were found to be tissue-specifically expressed; one in the heart and the other in body-wall muscle. They encode long (229-residue) and short (182-residue) TnI protein isoforms homologous to vertebrate heart and skeletal muscle TnI isoforms, respectively. By sequence comparison, allelic polymorphism analysis, and gene structure determination, the two mRNAs were shown to be produced from a single gene by inclusion/exclusion of two serial internal exons. This tissue-specific alternative splicing mechanism contrasts with the vertebrate strategy of TnI isoform. production by differential transcription of a multigene family. This is the first reported case in which homologous tissue-specific protein isoforms are produced by non-homologous molecular mechanisms in related organismal lineages, implying that the molecular mechanism of isoform generation was entirely reworked in one of these lineages. An evolutionary scenario is presented that can account for such a reworking through a series of reasonable steps.</description><creator>MacLean, Darren.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Ciona intestinalis -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Muscle proteins.</subject><title>Evolution of the troponin I gene family : generation of heart and body-wall muscle troponin I isoforms in the ascidian Ciona intestinalis by alternative splicing from a single gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x12c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765373304</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h396n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Low density lipoprotein receptor-related protein-2, LRP-2 (gp330/megalin) is a cell surface receptor involved in the internalization of apolipoprotein J (apoJ/clusterin). Apo J is found in the luminal fluids of the testis and epididymis, as well as on the plasma membrane of the sperm. It has already been suggested that an apo J/LRP-2 interaction may be involved in sperm maturation whereby apo J redistributes cholesterol on the sperm membrane which is necessary for the capacitation and acrosomal reaction in the oviduct. This research examined the postnatal developmental localization of LRP-2 in the efferent ducts and in the epididymis as well as the developmental localization of LRP-2 in the oviduct, and the uterus. The pattern of immunolocalization. was then analyzed in terms age dependent factors. Immunocytochemistry was performed using polyclonal antibody to LRP-2 on the efferent ducts and epididymides of male rats (aged 7--90 days) and the oviduct and uterus of female rats (aged 7--56 days). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lustig, Marc.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Postnatal developmental localization of LRP-2 in the efferent ducts and epididymis of the male rat and the oviduct and uterus of the female rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b61h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h396n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246v147</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study focuses on analyzing the interaction between Portland type I cement and motor oil, and its influence on the hydration of the cement. The Portland type I cement was tested by using a Viscosity meter, a Zeta potential meter and by Fourier Transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR). The tested samples containing increasing concentration of motor oil were subjected to Viscosity, Zeta potential and Infrared spectroscopy (IR) tests. Ultimate compressive strength (UCS) and Chemical oxygen demand (COD) tests, which signify the leachability of the oil from the cement, are also included. The results show that oil (1) retards hydration, (2) reduces bonding in the cement, and (3) leaches from the hydrated cement. The presence of calcium silicate polymerization, indicated by the appearance of Si-H, CO3-2, and SiO4 -4 after 90 minutes of hydration, shows that cement hydration was inhibited both by oil and by one freeze-thaw cycle. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lu, Chen-Hong.</creator><contributor>Mohamed, A. M. O. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Evaluation of oil and freeze-thaw effects on cement hydration for waste solidification</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x96v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246v147</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg18v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The lack of a relevant and responsive health-related quality of life (HRQoL) measure for lung transplantation has prevented the estimation of HRQoL changes during the prolonged wait for donors and post-operatively in the long-term. The objective of this thesis study was to streamline 58 existing patient-generated items into a short and reliable lung transplant module for use with the Medical Outcomes Study Short Form 36-Item Health Status Survey (SF-36) which would improve the measurement of change. Seventy-six patients responded to both SF-36 and 58-item inventory at intervals pre- and post-operatively. Data were used to reduce the inventory. Concurrent clinical data were obtained to enable validation. Reliability was assessed through a simple replication study involving 39 patients. Content was verified with a group of lung transplant specialists who had no prior contact with the study. Two resulting scales were proposed: a 10-item "Functions and Feelings" and an 8-item "Symptom" scale. Preliminary psychometric properties, including responsiveness to change, were excellent for the "Functions and Feelings," however, the "Symptom" items could not be aggregated. With further testing of the proposed module, it can become a clinically-useful HRQoL measure for lung transplantation.</description><creator>Lu, Ann Jeannette.</creator><contributor>Dauphinee, Sharon Wood (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Psychology, Psychometrics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Completion and psychometric testing of a lung transplant module for use with a generic quality of life measure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hr88n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg18v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268734c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the scope of physicians' legal and ethical duties of disclosure in an era marred by decreasing available medical resources. Using three hypothetical case scenarios, it examines the scope of physicians' obligations to disclose information about medical interventions that patients might wish to consider but that are not available in their immediate community. The legal analyses focus on Canadian and Quebec law. Discussion of the ethical considerations centres on the concept of 'benefit' and issues of 'communication' and 'trust' in the physician-patient relationship. It integrates, as well, empirical knowledge about patients' desire for information and participation in decision-making. The thesis demonstrates the broad scope of the legal and ethical disclosure obligations that physicians owe patients, regardless of conditions of economic scarcity. It further highlights areas where law and ethics would suggest different conclusions with respect to disclosure obligations.</description><creator>Lotan, Gurit.</creator><contributor>Elliott, Carl (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Philosophy.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Physicians and cost containment : issues of disclosure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t610.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268734c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q82g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A variety of extractants were used to fractionate the trace metals Cd, Cu, Mn, Ni, Pb, and Zn in contaminated urban soils. The metals were mostly held in soil solid phases but not in soluble and exchangeable forms. Except for Mn, extractability of metals by selective chemicals was mainly a function of the contamination level. The speciation of these elements in water, 0.01 M CaCl2, and pH-adjusted water extra was calculated using the chemical equilibrium model MINEQL+. The free ions of Cd, Ni, and Zn were the predominant species in most of the water and 0.01 M CaCl2 extracts while PbCO30 was the main form of Pb. Organically complexed Cu accounted for over of the total dissolved Cu. The solubility of trace metals increased as solution pH was decreased. Metals Cd, Ni, Pb and Zn combined with Cl- at low pH (&lt;5). Organically complexed Cu was shifted to Cu2+ when pH was decreased. Except for Mn, the activities of the other metals in water, 0.01 M CaCl 2 extracts, and pH-adjusted water extracts were undersaturated with respect to established minerals in soils. MnHPO4 seems to be controlling the solubility of Mn in these extracts.</description><creator>Li, Juan, 1963-</creator><contributor>Hendershot, William H. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Soil pollution -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Metals -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Trace elements -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Fractionation and speciation of trace metals in contaminated urban soils from Montreal, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv85j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q82g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv86t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Physicians have traditionally withheld opioid analgesics from patients with acute abdominal pain due to concerns of masking physical findings. No study has examined morbidity and mortality after narcotic administration. The purpose of this study was to determine: (1) frequency of abdominal pain requiring narcotic analgesics, and (2) rate of serious outcomes, (death, infection, perforation, obstruction or hemorrhage of abdominal organs), in order to assess the feasibility of a randomized clinical trial on the safety of narcotics. Of 860 patients with acute abdominal pain, 477 (55%) completed a pain questionnaire, and 321 met study criteria for need of narcotic analgesia (37.3%). Of these, 36 (11.2%) experienced a serious outcome as assessed by telephone contact 2 to 3 weeks after initial visit. The overall rate of serious outcomes was 67 of 860 (7.8%). A clinical trial using serious outcomes as the primary endpoint is possible, but would need to randomize approximately 3200 patients.</description><creator>Lee, Jacques Simon.</creator><contributor>Shapiro, S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacy.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Acute abdominal pain in the emergency department : physicians' use of opioid analgesics and the incidence of serious outcomes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3371.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv86t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m23b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The structural and magnetic properties of Diamagnetic/Ferromagnetic: Cu/Fe multilayers, prepared by DC-magnetron sputtering, were studied as a function of Fe layer thickness tFe. Structural characterization reveals the successful growth of high-quality layered structures along the film growth direction. However, the increasing contribution of the interface roughness was visible with decreasing tFe . X-ray diffraction data indicate the dissolution of Fe atoms in fcc Cu medium due to interfacial mixing. The magnetic transition from ferromagnetism to paramagnetism with decreasing tFe was confirmed by conversion-electron Mossbauer spectroscopy (CEMS), vibrating sample magnetometry, and magnetotransport measurements. The monotonic decrease in the average hyperfine field with t Fe indicates that the transition is a gradual process as t Fe decreases from 34 A down to 7 A. The isomer shift of the singlets in the CEM spectra suggests the presence of fcc Fe, while the observed doublet is assigned to the Cu-Fe alloy phase at the interfaces. The variation of magnetoresistance (MR) with t Cu indicates that for a nominal t Fe of 20 A the multilayer has a well-defined superlattice structure, whereas multilayers with nominal tFe, of 5 A have a granular-alloy-like structure. AC susceptometry provided direct evidence for island formation for nominal tFe = 5 A by exhibiting the blocking characteristics of superparamagnets. The temperature-dependence of the magnetization suggests that for nominal tFe = 5 A, 75% of the Fe atoms are in the superparamagnetic bcc phase, leaving the remaining 25% in the Cu-Fe alloy and fcc Fe phases. The observed magnetic transition is likely due to superparamagnetic relaxation rather than a structural transition from bcc Fe to fcc Fe as t Fe decreases below a critical thickness tC at which a multilayer structure becomes an island structure.</description><creator>Lee, Dok Won.</creator><contributor>Altounian, Z. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Structural and magnetic properties of copperiron multilayers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21th62m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m23b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806204z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Squamous intraepithelial lesions (SIL) are believed to be precursors of in situ cervical neoplasia and of invasive cervical cancer. Though the burden of this disease has been greatly reduced thanks to the availability of an effective screening test, the worldwide morbidity and mortality remain high. On the basis of a classic approach to analysis of data from a prospective cohort study, I correlated HPV status at enrollment with subsequent risk of incident SIL during up to three years of follow-up among women of Brazil enrolled to the Ludwig-McGill cohort. The risk of occurrence of a first instance of SIL among women was strongly associated with HPV infection. After adjustment for a number of socio-demographic factors that have previously been established as risk factors for cervical cancer, the magnitude of association with high-risk HPVs remained unchanged while the association with low risk types was dampened, furthering the evidence for the role of oncogenic HPV types in the development of cervical cancer. Parity was found to have an independent positive association with cervical precursor lesions, after adjustment for HPV status, age, previous history of Pap screening, number of sexual partners, age at first intercourse, and income. Income was also positively associated with the development of lesions.</description><creator>Kulaga, Sophie.</creator><contributor>Franko, Eduardo (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Obstetrics and Gynecology.</subject><title>Determinants of incident precursor lesions of cervical cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw781.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806204z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462760g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental laboratory study was undertaken to investigate the convective airflow which develops in compost masses and the effect of passive and active aeration on nitrogen (N) and carbon (C) losses of compost at three different levels of dry matter (d.m) with four different C sources (pine shavings, grass hay, oat straw and wheat straw). Each bulking agent was individually mixed with swine slurry and composted at 40, 32 and 28% d.m. Duplicate mixtures were aerated for 21 days (14 days for one of the pine shavings trials) both in active and passive conditions in 100L composters and their temperature was monitored every 3 hours. The passively aerated compost demonstrated temperature regimes similar to that of the actively aerated compost reaching and exceeding 55°C for 3 days. The initial airflow resistance of the composts was found to be lower than the final. The convective airflow of the compost was correlated with time and to the difference in ambient and compost temperature. The 32% d.m. content and the wood shavings compost produced higher convective airflows. The statistical significance of the effects of aeration method, d.m. level, and C source on N conservation was tested. Only the C source had a significant effect (P &lt; 0.05). The hay amended with urea had the lowest N losses (22.4%), followed by oat straw, hay, wood shavings amended with soybeans, wheat straw and wood shavings with losses of 41.4, 53.4, 53.6, 55.2% and 68.5% respectively. The C losses were strongly related to the N losses, except for the hay amended with urea compost. The oat straw loss the most C (51.4%), followed by hay, wheat straw, wood shavings amended with and without soybeans, and hay amended with urea with losses of 37.4, 35.8, 25.4%, 13.5% and 12.19% respectively. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Knight, William, 1965-</creator><contributor>Barrington, S. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Compost.</subject><subject>Heat -- Convection.</subject><title>Compost convective airflow, N and C conservation with passive and active aeration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf19q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462760g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc00n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bioavailability of trace metals in urban contaminated soils was investigated to relate chemical extraction efficiencies with biological effects. Results from a Collembola reproduction bioassay showed minimal toxicity suggesting limited bioavailability. Chemical extractions were carried out on these urban soils. The sodium acetate extraction was the best predictor of the biological effects of Cd while the biological effects of Zn were best explained by a water extraction. An earthworm uptake bioassay was done to quantify the bioavailable fractions. Cadmium, Cu, Pb and Zn accumulated in Lumbricus terrestris L. The sodium acetate extraction was the best predictor of Cd uptake while calcium chloride extraction best predicted Zn uptake by earthworms. Treatments were made to urban soils to immobilize the metals and reduce their bioavailability. The metal concentrations were so low in the soils that the effects of the treatments could not be measured. Collembola and earthworms are good indicators of trace metal bioavailability and should be included in the evaluation of contaminated soils.</description><creator>Kennette, Debra.</creator><contributor>Hendershot, William (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Soil pollution -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Soil invertebrates -- Effect of pollution on.</subject><subject>Trace elements -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Metals -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>The bioavailability of trace metals to soil invertebrates in urban contaminated soils /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698965h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc00n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988n26r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have identified receptor protein tyrosine kinases (PTKs) that are expressed and/or activated during kidney development. mRNA from fetal rat kidneys in late gestation (embryonic day 21), was used to prepare cDNA template for polymerase chain reaction amplification with primers based on conserved regions of PTKs, and products were subcloned and sequenced. Among 346 clones, we identified epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFr), Tie 2, platelet derived growth factor receptor (PDGFr)-alpha, PDGFr-beta, Flk-1, Flt-4, fibroblast growth factor receptor (FGFr)-1, FGFr-3, FGFr-4, Met, and RYK//Nbtk-1. PTK expression was studied by immunoprecipitation and immunoblotting of kidney membrane proteins with specific antibodies. EGFr, PDGFr-alpha, FGFr-1, FGFr-3, Met, and in some cases Tie-2 protein expression was greater in fetal kidneys, as compared with kidneys from 12 week adult rats, (controls). Flk-1, PDGFr-beta, and FGFr-4 proteins were expressed comparably; Flt-4 was not detected. As a reflection of receptor PTK activity, we assessed endogenous tyrosine phosphorylation, and in vitro autophosphorylation. EGFr and PDGFr-alpha displayed activity in fetal, but not adult kidneys. FGFr-3 and Flk-1 were active in some fetal kidneys; the other PTKs were not active. Thus, in late gestational rat kidney, there are distinct patterns of receptor PTK expression and activity. EGFr, PDGFr-alpha, FGFr-3 and Flk-1 are among PTKs that are activated, and they may mediate perinatal development of renal epithelial, interstitial, or vascular structures.</description><creator>Kee, Nohjin.</creator><contributor>Cybulsky, Andrey (advisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Receptor protein tyrosine kinases in perinatal developing rat kidney</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km86r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n26r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2550</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>