<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:33:38Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vr780</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The perineural space of the peripheral nerve has been investigated periodically since its discovery by Domenico Cotugno in 1770. The study of Key and Retzius in 1876 suggested that it might be of more than anatomical significance. Weed’s findings published in 1914 proved that, under practically physiological conditions, the subarachnoid space and the perineural space communicated. Orr and Rows in their reports published from 1903 to 1918 concluded that it provided a pathway by which infectious agents and their toxic products reached the spinal cord. Interest in the perineural space has again been aroused by the possible role the space may play in providing the pathway by which viruses pass from the periphery to the central nervous system. Recent reports, such as the one by Horan, Johnston, Halliday, O’Brien and Burst in 1944, presented clear circumstantial evidence to suggest that this is the case. Peripheral nerve injuries of this war have raised important questions regarding the perineural space. [...]</description><creator>Chen, Chao-jen.</creator><contributor>Cone, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgey.</subject><title>The perineural space of the peripheral nerve.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182p24x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vr780</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sg79j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contains brief historical summary; outline of theory of water hammer; graphical method of analysis; theory of piezo-electric pressure indicator; results of tests of pressure rise due to instantaneous valve closure; analysis of pressure wave produced by indicator; discussion; bibliography.</description><creator>Clark, Robert Harry.</creator><contributor>Wood, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Experiments on water-hammer using a piezo-electric pressure indicator.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q63k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sg79j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xw180</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A storage rot due to the fungus Gloeosporium album Osterw. was described in Switzerland by Osterwalder (12) in 1907. This storage rot was reported from Switzerland by Schne1der-Orelli (17) in 1912, from Belgium by Marchal and Marchal (10) in 1921, and from England by Kidd and Beaumont (7) in 1924. Ogilvie (11) reported in 1935 that its occurrence in England was on the increase. An apple storage rot, since identified as caused by Gloeosporium album was observed by the writer in 1934-35 at the Dominion Experimental Station, Fredericton, New Brunswick. A preliminary note dealing with investigations conducted at Fredericton was published by Clarkson and Howatt (4) in 1938. This rot of apples was reported from Czecho-Slovakia by Baudys (3) in 1937, from Denmark by Esbjerg (5) in 1936-37, from England by Wilkinson (20) in 1939, from Switzerland by Osterwalder (13) in 1941 and from Sweden by Lyckas (9).</description><creator>Clarkson, Scott Foreman.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>A storage rot of apples due to gloeosporium album osterw.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795b96z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw180</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fv868</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this historical review is essentially to record the results of experimental investigations into the effect of addition agents on the electrodeposition of metals, particularly the effect of gelatin on the deposition of copper from acid copper sulphate solutions, since it is with this type of system that the majority of the recorded work has been concerned. [...] As a rule, each investigation has been restricted to the study of one or two variables over a comparatively narrow range of experimental conditions, followed either by an explanation of the results on the basis of available theories or, very frequently, by formulation of a new hypothesis. As a result, many of the published papers are restricted in scope and frequently conflicting. The task of welding the whole into one framework, to correlate the many data available, is comparable to the task of fitting together a jig-saw puzzle from which pieces are missing and in which apparently erroneous pieces have been included. It is hoped, nevertheless, that the present report might serve to trace in barest outline some of the stronger figures in the pattern, and thus perhaps to indicate some of its many aspects still to be constructed. [...]</description><creator>Gauvin, William H.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Investigation of polarization and effects of addition agents during the electrodeposition of copper.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z4035.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv868</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rh56w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The simplification of thermodynamical analysis by the use of Jacobians is extended to systems determined by three independent variables. The detailed analysis is carried out for the case of a system in which all the component masses but one are constant. Tables are given which simplify considerably the problem of deriving relations between first partial derivatives for systems of this type. The results are applied to a single component system of variable mass, and to other special systems of practical importance. [...]</description><creator>Kaufman, H. (Hyman)</creator><contributor>Shaw, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>New methods for the derivation of thermodynamical relations for certain complex systems.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m721v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh56w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q937d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Forest entomological control is primarily dependent on a thorough knowledge of the interrelationships of all insects existing in the forest. Some of these insects rise and fall in population and periodically are capable of causing much damage when a high population is attained. To these we devote our greatest attention. (Quite often, however, we mistakenly pass over other forest insects which appear to remain at a more or less constant level of population and which give us no economical concern. The biological importance of this latter group is axiomatically almost unknown. We know very little of the part played by such invertebrates in the forest insect community and of their probable importance as reservoirs of parasites and pathogens for other more destructive pests in infestation status. The green spruce looper, Semiothisa granitata Gn. is a forest insect which may be classed in the latter group. Throughout the forests of Canada and the United States it is exceedingly common. [...]This perplexing problem— why granitata had not increased in the past—was one of the reasons which instigated the writer to undertake a study of this insect as a subject of a thesis. [...]</description><creator>Morgan, Cecil V. G.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The life history and morphology of the green spruce looper, Semiothisa Granitata GN (Lepidoptera, Geometridae).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zx487.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q937d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qq366</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The initial stimulus to the search for microorganisms which produce therapeutically effective antibacterial compounds was given when Fleming discovered penicillin in 1929. Clinical and laboratory studies have shown that penicillin is usually as active in vivo as it is in vitro against a large number of Grampositive bacteria. The therapeutic value of this antibacterial compound has its limitations, however, in that it is quite ineffective in combatting diseases which are produced by Gramnegative bacteria. A search for a new microbiologically produced antibacterial compound, complementary to penicillin, was initiated as soon as the limitations of penicillin therapy were realized. As a result of this work, a number of fungus-produced antibiotics were isolated. All these compounds which have been examined since 1929 have proved to be either inactivated by ascitic fluid or toxic to the animal body. Their therapeutic value, then, was practically negligible. [...] The antibacterial compounds which are elaborated by microorganisms are collectively referred to as antibiotics. [...] With this in mind, the following studies have been undertaken: (a) To isolate antibiotic-producing fungi from substrates normally having a high population of fungi. (b) To identify the antibiotics produced by those isolates considered worth of further study. (c) To determine the optimum nutritional requirements of fungi with respect to antibiotic production.</description><creator>Robinson, John.</creator><contributor>Thatcher, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Agricultural Bacteriology.</subject><title>The isolation and culture of fungi that produce antibacterial substances.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290d76z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq366</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd68x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>About seven hundred specimens have been collected and examined. They belong to six genera, Lingulops, Lingulasma, Trigonoglossa, Pseudolingula, Lingula and Ectenoglossa, the latter new. Nineteen new species are described and figures and notes are given of four previously described species which were represented in the collection. In addition, six of Billings’ species were restudied. A bibliography of the American species since 1915 is included.</description><creator>Sinclair, G. Winston (George Winston)</creator><contributor>Wynne-Edwards, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Brachiopoda, Fossil -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Brachiopoda, Fossil -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Paleontology -- Ordovician.</subject><title>Some Ordovician lingulid brachiopods from Ontario and Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn48r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd68x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732dd178</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ever since the recognition of mitosis as the mechanism of nuclear division, its importance in biological development, whether normal growth and reproduction or pathological production of tumours and cancers, has led to a great deal of inquiry into its nature. The manner or treatment at any period was determined, to a large extent, by the available techniques of investigation and, to a lesser but still important degree, by the facility with which known and utilizable material lent itself to a given type of approach. Accordingly, early research workers concentrated their attack upon the morphology of mitosis, a study which now provides a very detailed and fairly complete description of the microscopically visible structural characteristics of cell and nucleus during their cycle of division. Recent research has, in a sense, leap-frogged to the more ultimate constituents or the cell, namely the protein molecules and their allied substances, and has by means of techniques adapted from those of physics and chemistry investigated molecular structure and orientation in protoplasmic constituents, and analyzed the chemical components of nucleus and cytoplasm. The gap between these mutually remote techniques is one that has to be filled by a study of the cell - “in vivo”, that is, by means of physiological data. Not that such knowledge is entirely lacking, but as a bridge between the other two approaches it is still highly inadequate. [...]</description><creator>Stern, Herbert.</creator><contributor>Scarth, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Trilliums.</subject><subject>Mitosis.</subject><subject>Meiosis.</subject><title>Physiological and physical changes of protoplasm during meiosis and mitosis in pollen mothercells of Trillium.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g46m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732dd178</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx18r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>After damage there is a disturbance or protein metabolism the extent of which has been shown to be influenced by the previous state of health or nutrition of the animal. As yet the underlying mechanisms regulating these post-traumatic metabolic processes is unknown, but it has been suggested that the endocrine system, particularly the adrenal cortex may occupy an integral role. The experiments to be described arose out or the observation by Cuthbertson that rats on a protein-free diet for 14 days did not show any increase in the excretion of urinary nitrogen after fracture of the left femur on the 14th day, while still eating the same diet; whereas, other rats eating diets of different protein levels did show an increase in the nitrogen excretion curve. In view of the findings in man, that accompanying the high output of urinary nitrogen after damage of a previously healthy individual was an increased output of gluconeogenic substances, presumably from the adrenal cortex, it was desired to investigate the possible role that the adrenal cortex might play in the metabolic behaviour after damage, of the animals eating the protein-free diet. A review of those features of protein metabolism pertinent to the subject, follows together with a discuss ion regarding the behaviour of protein metabolism after trauma and the possible factors influencing this behaviour.</description><creator>Cohen, Herman.</creator><contributor>Hoffman, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Medicine.</subject><title>Some aspects of nitrogen metabolism in the rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj677.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx18r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qg430</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acute postoperative aseptic leptomeningitis is a complication which appears in some patients during the period following a wide surgical opening of the cerebral ventricles or the cisterna magna, and rarely the spinal meninges. The syndrome consists of recurrent bouts of fever, rigidity of the neck associated with an increase of the white blood cells contained in the cerebrospinal fluid, although it is shown to be sterile according to the ordinary bacteriological methods. The term aseptic postoperative meningitis was introduced into the medical literature by Finlayson and Penfield in 1941, when they delineated the clinical entity and traced its importance. In the present work, which is clinical and experimental, further study into the clinical description and pathogenesis of this disorder has been attempted to find methods for its prevention and treatment. In the second part of this work, some of the previous cases reported by Finlayson and Penfield (1941) have been subjected to a critical analysis, as well as all the cases present in the hospital during the time of this study. Finally, on the basis of the experimental observations and conclusions, certain methods of treatment for this disorder are suggested.</description><creator>Corona, Carlos.</creator><contributor>Penfield, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgey.</subject><title>Acute aseptic leptomeningitis postoperative.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752m031.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg430</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892f132</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The social drama of the Thirties constitutes a large body of American Literature, but the valuable material is actually a comparatively small distillate of the entire production. There are two outstanding reasons why the Thirties saw such a great interest in the presentation of social problems in the theatre. In the first place, these were hurried years for Americans, and the drama presented education, entertainment and propaganda in a very convenient capsule-like form. In the second place, the Thirties were one of the most interesting and eventful decades; from the social point of view, that mankind has seen since the first growing pains of the Industrial Revolution. Seen in their present perspective as inter-war years, they followed the climax of a catastrophic economic depression; and they built, at the same time, to the crescendo of another climax - the outbreak of a second world war in 1939. The choice of plays made for this thesis may not be the choice of some other readers. The authority for their selection is explained in Chapter Two, and the prerequisite for choice as a “social play” is explained in Chapter One. But regardless of the validity of the dramas chosen, we see here as clearly as we do in any epoch, that the great literature of our time is the vital reflection of the life that goes on about us.</description><creator>Dando, John A.</creator><contributor>Macmillan, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>American drama -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Some aspects of social drama in America during the thirties.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g5735.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892f132</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977z17z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aujourd'hui les Acadiens ferment un peuple d'environ un million dames, dont plus  de soixante-six mille se trouvent en Nouvelle-Ecosse, descendants des premiers, colons du pays d’Évangeline. Dans quelle mesure les Acadiens de la Nouvelle-Ecosse  ont-ils conservé leur culture française? Comment ont-ils pu maintenir jusqu’à nos  ours leur langue et leur civilisation? Quel est  l'avenir du peuple acadien comme  groupe ethnique en Nouvelle- Ecosse? Le présent travail base non seulement sur  ce  qui a déjà été écrit, mais surtout sur les développements récents et sur la situation  actuelle des Acadiens de la province, répond a ces questions. […] </description><creator>Edwards, Clifford Edward.</creator><contributor>Darbelnet, J (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Acadia.</subject><subject>Nova Scotia -- History.</subject><title>La survivance de la culture française en Nouvelle-Ecosse.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pd820.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977z17z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913s99m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The interest in the problem of the French Canadian habitant who, upon entering industry, comes into conflict with a system of principles and practices so entirely different from his own, was derived from the experience gained through working in the Medical Department of Canadian Industries Limited and of its wartime subsidiary, Defence Industries Limited, where the writer was employed during the course of this study. [...]</description><creator>Ferencz, Agnes Maria.</creator><date>1945</date><subject>Public health -- Canada.</subject><subject>French-Canadians -- Attitudes.</subject><title>The impact of urbanization on French Canadian medical attitudes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579w47g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s99m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74ct80h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The discovery of the insecticidal properties of D.D.T. (2, 2 bis parachlorophenyl 1, 1, 1, trichlorethane) revealed tremendous possibilities for its use in the control of mosquitos, bedbugs, lice, roaches and many other insect pests. It was found, however, by several groups of workers in the United States, Great Gritain, and Canada, that D.D.T. was toxic to laboratory animals, which meant that it had to be used very cautiously until all aspects of its toxicity to mammals (maximum tolerated dosages, possible cumulative or carcinogenic effects etc.) had been thoroughly investigated. The acute effects of single toxic doses of D.D.T. on various laboratory animals have been described by several groups of investigators. The first visible signs of poisoning appear from 6 to 24 hours after administration of large doses of D.D.T. orally. The animal is cold, its fur ruffled, and it is hypersensitive to sudden noise. Continual muscular tremors then begin in the muscles of the back and hind limbs. Later the tremors become more acute and involve all the muscles of the body, so that voluntary movements are unsteady. From this stage the animal may recover spontaneously. If it does not, the tremors usually increase in severity, until the animal is unable to stand. It usually lies on its side showing continual convulsive shaking, which grows weaker until the animal dies. During the convulsive stage, which may be as long as 48 hours, the animal loses weight rapidly.</description><creator>Shapiro, Stanley K.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>DDT (Insecticide) -- Toxicology.</subject><subject>DDT (Insecticide) -- Physiological effect.</subject><title>Studies on the toxicity of D.D.T. to mice.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634686v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74ct80h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gp188</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The morphology, both normal and pathological, of the kidney has been widely investigated. Pathologists, biochemists, physiologists, pharmacologists, and more recently, endocrinologists have all contributed much valuable information which has led to a better understanding of the structure as well as of the function of this vital organ. Many techniques and experimental approaches have been employed, and a wealth of data has been accumulated. Among these techniques may be found those of the nutritionist. Effects of both overdosages and deficiencies of numerous elements and compounds have been investigated. Unfortunately, this work has been done by so many different investigators under various conditions and for a variety of reasons, that it has proven difficult to collect and to correlate all this huge volume of experimental data concerning the effect of diet on the kidney. It is the aim of this thesis to provide a critical review of the effects of dietary constituents upon renal size and structure. Many of the experimental results obtained to-date (1945) will be enumerated, correlated and commented upon. In order first to present as clear a picture as possible of what we know to-day about this subject and second, to act as a guide for further reading and experimental investigation in this field. [...]</description><creator>Welt, Isaac D.</creator><contributor>Selye, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><subject>Kidneys.</subject><title>Influence of dietary constituents upon renal size and structure.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sg809.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp188</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698b86g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>What is humour? From what sources does it proceed, and what are its functions? These are questions which many philosophers and psychologists have endeavoured to answer, but with no unanimity of opinion. The history of the word shows us something of its origin and evolution, but is perhaps of not much value in an appraisal of humour in the world today. The word humour has had many meanings, and has grown by no sudden or simple process. Every student of English literature knows that the earliest use of the word was physiological, denoting one of the four bodily fluids which were supposed to determine the characters and temperaments of men. An exact balance of these four primary “humours’’ -- blood, phlegm, choler, and melancholy -- made up the properly constituted man. Not always, however, an exact balance was maintained. One or other of the humours might predomdinate, in each case producing its corresponding disposition or temper of mind, the sanguine, the phlegmatic, the choleric, or the melancholy. Thus the word came to be applied to temperaments, being used to signify any pronounced tendency or eccentric behaviour on the part of the individual in question. This identifying of the word humour with the consistently individual or exaggerated had been reached by the time of Ben Jonson, whose Every Man in His Humour is equivalent to every man according to his peculiar personal bias. In the comedies of Ben Jonson we meet with a set of eccentrics [...]</description><creator>Woolner, Evelyn Flora.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>HARDY, THOMAS, 1840-1928</subject><title>Humour in the Wessex novels.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z404f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b86g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569746r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is not an addition to the overwhelming number of guide-books to the town of Quebec. Nor is it a survey of Canadian history in the seventeenth century. All I have tried to do here is to make an impartial study of the life and growth of Quebec from 1608 to 1703, and to reach my own conclusions on the genuine importance of the town. My research has necessarily been confined to sources located in Canada. This means that many documents which might have thrown light on Quebec’s importance to France and to the French West Indies have been beyond my reach. Hence I have confined myself very largely to estimating the importance of Quebec in the colony of New France, and to gleaning such information as I could find on the place of Quebec in the French colonial system of the seventeenth century. [...]</description><creator>Reid, Allana Gertrude.</creator><contributor>Adair, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Québec (Québec) -- History -- 17th century.</subject><title>The importance of the town of Quebec, 1608-1703.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf299.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569746r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zx49h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There are a series of mutants of melanogaster which affect body coloration. Kalmus (41) has stated that he has found a relationship among these mutants between colour and susceptibility - namely that the darker cuticle - (a) gives better protection from desiccation. (b) absorbs and loses more heat. (c) is less easy to wet. (d) is tougher and mechanically more resistant. Kalmus (42) has shown experimentally that the yellow mutant of Drosophila melanogaster is more susceptible to dessication, and that the black mutant is more resistant than the wild type to - (a) dessication (b) exposure to a mixture of pyrethrum extract and sulphuric acid. If this is so, we might expect a similar situation when a contact insecticide is applied to these various mutants. This might be so, particularly in the case of D.D.T. (2.2. bis dichlorophenyl 1.1.1. Trichlorethane) as - (a) it has been shown to act by penetration of the chitin, and (b) flies killed by D.D.T. appear extremely dessicated at death. Evidence that D.D.T. acts as a contact insecticide has been derived from several lines of investigation. [...]</description><creator>Glickman, Irwin.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>DDT (Insecticide)</subject><subject>Chromosome abnormalities.</subject><subject>Drosophila melanogaster.</subject><title>An investigation of relationship of body colour and susceptibility to DDT in Drosophila melanogaster.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214s41t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zx49h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bj08p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present educational program in the forces has been much more extensive than that which existed in any previous war. Not only has it been necessary for the Army, Navy and Air Force to introduce an educational program of their own, but there have been available as well other educational facilities. Millions of dollars have been spent on education for young people in uniform. This expenditure is, in itself, an indication that much educational work has gone on and that it is worthy of notice by educators everywhere. This has been the first extensive adult education program financed by the Federal Government and it has been the most generously financed adult education program in Canada. If the experience gained in the education of those on active service is to be of value in any proposed adult education scheme following the war, then an essay such as this, which attempts to describe and evaluate it, will have some contribution to make to the success of these plans. The Canadian Government has provided generous educational benefits for men returning to civilian life. Many who are entitled to these benefits will seek admission to educational institutions in Canada, but they will not have in certificate form the requirements necessary for entrance. [...] It is hoped, therefore, that this essay will provide a clue for evaluating the educational program in which enlisted men have participated. [...]</description><creator>Hamilton, Lorne Daniel.</creator><contributor>Hughes, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Soldiers -- Education, Non-military.</subject><subject>Education -- Canada.</subject><title>The education of Canadian service men.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p3516.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bj08p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h7591</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] The following study has been undertaken as a result of the bewilderment engendered by widely varying critical verdicts as to Mr. Cabell’s place in American literature as well as to the nature and purpose of his writings. It need not be emphasized that an awareness of the disagreement evident in such conflicting interpretation must inevitably lead to the conclusion that much of it is misinterpretation. Because of the remarkable variety of critical judgments, an attempt has been made in the following pages to present, as nearly as possible in his own words, Mr. Cabell’s intention. For the same reason certain passages in the chapter on Mr. Cabell’s books have been directly quoted rather than paraphrased. In other words, in this attempt to analyse and evaluate Mr. Cabell’s writings it has been considered necessary to present, wherever possible, the original passages from which the conclusions of the present study were derived. The method appears justified for two reasons. It emphasizes the fact that the interpretation which follows is based on the author’s works and remains unbiased by the opinions of former critics. It provides, too, for the reader of the follov1ing paper, first hand material for use in the formation of a judgment as to whether or not the conclusions of this study are valid.</description><creator>Homer, Kenneth Churchill.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>CABELL, J. B., 1879-</subject><title>James Branch Cabell : an interpretation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s61j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h7591</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838370n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although Whitman is often called the father of modern American poetry, we might more correctly ascribe the position to Emerson, for it was Emerson’s rallying charges which inspired Whitman. Emerson’s call for intellectual freedom, self-trust, self-culture and self-development was heard by Whitman who developed his message. In his Phi Beta Kappa address at Cambridge, Emerson shocked his listeners by declaring that they had gathered together, not for games of strength or skill, or for literary recitations, but simply as “a friendly sign of the survival of the love of letters amongst a people too busy to give to letters any more.” He chastized men for becoming parrots of other men’s thinking, for studying too exclusively the writers of the past instead of acting and learning from personal experiences. He extolled labor as virtuous for learned as well as for unlearned hands. Emerson declared that Americans had listened too long to the courtly muses of Europe; the American Scholar must feel confidence in the unsearched and unrevealed might of man. [...]</description><creator>Howe, Margaret Gwendolen.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.</subject><title>The place of Robert Frost in modern American poetry.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v915.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838370n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816q64v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This book, when originally conceived, was part of a much larger plan. I began some time ago to analyse the functions of government in the international society. I wanted to demonstrate that the problem of government in that society is the same as it is within States. In the international as in the national sphere, the effective performance of any one of the functions of government (i.e. the legislative, the judicial, the executive and the administrative functions) depends upon the effective performance of each of the other functions. There can be no effective supra-national or world government, and hence no real international order, until all the processes or functions of government have been organized and institutionalized in the international sphere as they have been within States. Before analyzing the four functions of government in the international society, however, it seemed desirable to analyze them as they operated in more highly developed societies. This would throw strong light on the inadequacies of existing international organization and provide criteria for assessing the degree to which the world society has nevertheless been organized. It would also indicate the steps that must be taken if world government is to be achieved [...]</description><creator>Humphrey, John P.</creator><contributor>Brady, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>LAW -- PHILOSOPHY.</subject><subject>POLITICAL SCIENCE.</subject><title>The functions of government and the nature of laws.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fg02c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q64v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096b25k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This survey attempts to form a connected picture of the history of some eighteen centuries of the Education of Englishwomen. The phenomenal success of the nineteenth and twentieth centuries in achieving the right of all girls to elementary education at least has been frequently recorded of late, for the sources are full and abundant. They are considerably less so in the case of the first eighteen hundred years. As far as the writer is aware there has been no official history of women’s education written of the ages preceding 1800. Such information as has been used here was drawn from the literature of those years. Since the writer has not been able to read all the works which might have been useful, this thesis is capable of expansion, and perhaps re-interpretation, at a later date.</description><creator>MacLean, Mona Gillian.</creator><contributor>Hughes, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Women -- Education -- History.</subject><subject>Women -- Education -- Great Britain.</subject><title>A survey of the education of British women to the nineteenth century : or, Britannia goes to school.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d54n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b25k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505365b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:04:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Home and School movement is widely known throughout Canada as a non-partisan, non-sectarian and non-commercial voluntary educational agency engaged chiefly in the promotion of home-school co-operation in the training of children. It has, roughly, thirteen hundred local units in connection with public and, to some extent, private schools, chiefly at the elementary and secondary levels. Its members are parents and teachers of the children attending these schools, plus a few other interested persons including, in some instances, school board members, representatives of other community agencies, and parents of children of pre-school age. The Canada and Newfoundland Education Association, in a recent Survey Report, summarizes the functions of the movement as follows: It recognizes that parents and teachers are partners in a common undertaking; it provides to parents and teachers an opportunity of studying common problems and of working jointly to attain common ends. These ends are the discovery of suitable school procedures to enable children to develop to their highest capacity and the promotion of school experiences which will result in the development of vigorous citizenship. [...]</description><creator>Penrose, George Henry.</creator><contributor>Currie, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Parents’ and teachers’ associations.</subject><subject>Home and school.</subject><title>The educational significance of the home and school movement.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j213j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505365b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>