<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:57:49Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43275" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:474299584</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente étude examine le travail et les partenariats d'une organisation non gouvernementale environnementale située au Sénégal afin de comprendre les façons dont le pouvoir est exercé et son impact sur les activités des gens au sein des réseaux multilatéraux des institutions de développement et des intervenants à l'échelle internationale, nationale, régionale et locale. Portant particulièrement sur les relations discursives au sein de ces réseaux, l'étude vise à dévoiler les cultures de discipline, de pouvoir et de contrôle complexes et à paliers multiples au sein du développement; à décrire sommairement les stratégies conçues pour aider à resituer les notions d'autorité, de reddition de comptes et de pouvoir dans le cadre de la gestion et de l'évaluation du développement; et à suggérer des façons dont l'apprentissage et la pratique réflexive pourraient être utilisés pour révéler les relations de pouvoir au sein de l'appareil de développement, s'engager dans celles-ci et les transformer. L'étude s'articule autour d'un examen théorique du développement et des pratiques discursives qui le constituent et le soutiennent. Elle est suivie de trois études de cas portant sur différentes dimensions de l'engagement et des enjeux au sein d'une organisation. La première étude de cas met l'accent sur les enjeux internes relatives aux mesures prises au sein de l'organisation, la deuxième étude de cas est axée sur l'engagement entre l'organisation et l'un de ses partenaires financiers, tandis que la troisième étude de cas porte sur les relations de pouvoir et d'autorité entre l'organisation et une fédération communautaire qu'elle vise à appuyer. Sur le plan méthodologique, les trois études de cas comportaient des entrevues en profondeur semi-structurées, des observations sur place et des analyses du discours (écrit et oral). Les deux dernières études de cas comprenaient une approche en matière de recherche centrée sur l'action au sein de laquelle les questions et les enjeux soulevés au fil du temps par la communauté (ou l'institution) ont jeté les bases de l'enquête et ont permis de façonner son orientation. L'étude se termine par un examen des limites et des possibilités liées à la prise de pouvoir dans ces sites particuliers, et tient compte de la façon dont des approches en matière d'apprentissage informel critiques, réflexives et dialogiques peuvent agir à titre de véhicules pour cet engagement. Fondée sur l'examen des trois études de cas, l'étude propose des conditions précises requises pour que les intervenants participent aux méthodes d'apprentissage collectif susceptibles de donner voix et vie et d'étendre les limites de ce qui est jugé possible dans ces sites particuliers et dans les cas d'enjeux.</description><description>This study examines the work and partnerships of a Senegal-based environmental non-governmental organisation (NGO) to understand the ways that power is exercised and coordinates peoples' activities within multilateral networks of international, national/regional, and local development institutions and actors. Looking specifically at the discursive relations within these networks, the study sought to reveal the complex and multi-layered culture of discipline, power and control that exists within development; outline strategies to help re-situate notions of authority, accountability and power in development management and evaluation; and suggest ways that learning and reflective practice might be used to uncover, critically engage with, and transform power relations within the development apparatus. The study is structured around a theoretical examination of development and the discursive practices that constitute and sustain it, followed by three case studies drawing upon different dimensions of engagement and struggle within one organisation. The first case takes as a point of focus the internal struggles around action within the organisation, the second considers engagement between the organisation and one of its funding partners, while the third considers relations of power and authority between the organisation and a community based Federation it aims to support. Methodologically, all three of these cases involved the use of extended semi-structured interviews, on-site observation, and discourse (textual and oral) analysis. The final two cases involved an action-oriented approach to the research where lines of questioning and points of struggle arising from the community (or institution) over time formed the basis of the investigation and helped to shape the direction it took. The study concludes by exploring the limits and possibilities of engaging with power at these particular sites, and considers how critical, reflexive and dialogical approaches to informal learning can serve as vehicles for this engagement. Drawing upon an examination of the three case studies, it suggests specific conditions needed to for actors to engage in the forms of collective learning which might strengthen collective voice and agency and expand the limits of what is deemed possible at the specific sites and instances of struggle.</description><creator>Harvey, Blane Leslie</creator><contributor>Steve Jordan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Social Sciences</subject><title>Speaking to power: the discursive shaping of Southern communities and institutions in international development cooperation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365564x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/474299584</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jv07v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In high-dose-rate iridium-192 brachytherapy, the radiation dose received by the patient is calculated according to the AAPM Task Group 43 (TG-43) formalism. This table-based dose superposition method uses dosimetry parameters derived with the radioactive iridium source centered in a water phantom. It neglects the dose perturbations caused by inhomogeneities, such as the patient anatomy, applicators, shielding, and radiographic contrast solution. In this work, we evaluated the dosimetric characteristics of a shielded rectal applicator with an endocavitary balloon injected with contrast solution. The dose distributions around this applicator were calculated by the GEANT4 Monte Carlo (MC) code and measured by ionization chamber and GAFCHROMIC EBT film. A patient-specific dose calculation study was then carried out for 40 rectal treatment plans. The PTRAN_CT MC code was used to calculate the dose based on computed tomography (CT) images. This study involved the development of BrachyGUI, an integrated treatment planning tool that can process DICOM-RT data and create PTRAN_CT input initialization files. BrachyGUI also comes with dose calculation and evaluation capabilities. We proposed a novel scatter correction method to account for the reduction in backscatter radiation near tissue-air interfaces. The first step requires calculating the doses contributed by primary and scattered photons separately, assuming a full scatter environment. The scatter dose in the patient is subsequently adjusted using a factor derived by MC calculations, which depends on the distances between the point of interest, the iridium source, and the body contour. The method was validated for multicatheter breast brachytherapy, in which the target and skin doses for 18 patient plans agreed with PTRAN_CT calculations better than 1%. Finally, we developed a CT-based analytical dose calculation method. It corrects for the photon attenuation and scatter based upon the radiological paths determined by ray tracing. The scatter dose is again adjusted using our scatter correction technique. The algorithm was tested using phantoms and actual patient plans for head-and-neck, esophagus, and MammoSite breast brachytherapy. Although the method fails to correct for the changes in lateral scatter introduced by inhomogeneities, it is a major improvement over TG-43 and is sufficiently fast for clinical use.</description><description>En curiethérapies à haut débit de dose, la dose aux patients est évaluée selon le protocole AAPM Task-Group 43 (TG43), qui utilise des paramètres dosimétriques obtenues avec une source dans l'eau. Cependant, le patient, l'applicateur et le contraste ont des propriétés radiologiques différentes de l'eau; ces inhomogénéités sont donc négligées dans TG43. Dans ce travail, nous utilisons le programme Monte Carlo (MC) GEANT4 pour évaluer les propriétés dosimétriques d'un applicateur rectal muni d'un blindage radio-protecteur et d'un ballon intra-cavitaire. Ces résultats sont confirmés par des mesures d'une chambre d'ionisation et des films GAFCHROMIC EBT. Une étude des calculs de dose a été faite avec le programme PTRAN_CT avec l'aide des images scanner de 40 patients de cancer rectal. Ceci a conduit au développement de BrachyGUI, un programme de planification de curiethérapie, capable de traiter les données DICOM-RT des patients et générer les paramètres d'entrée pour PTRAN_CT. BrachyGUI dispose d'outils de calcul, d'extraction et d'analyse de dose. Nous proposons une nouvelle méthode de calcul qui tient compte des effets de diffusion au voisinage des interfaces tissus-air. Cette méthode calcule séparément la dose due aux photons primaires et diffusés, ensuite la composante diffusée est ajustée par un paramètre extrait des calculs MC incluant les contours du patient, la source et sa position. Nos résultats s'accordent avec une incertitude inferieure à 1% avec les calculs de dose à la surface et dans la cible effectués avec PTRAN_CT pour 18 patients en curiethérapie du sein. Enfin, nous avons conçu une méthode analytique de calcul de dose qui incorpore l'atténuation et la diffusion des photons, et qui est basée sur les chemins radiologiques déterminées par traçage des trajectoires. Cet algorithme est validé par l'utilisation de fantômes, des données de patients traités pour divers cancers (oesophage, tête et cou), et par la curiethérapie MammoSite du sein. Bien que cette méthode ne reproduise pas bien les diffusions latérales induites par les inhomogénéités, elle représente une amélioration majeure par-rapport-à TG43 et est rapide pour une implémentation clinique.</description><creator>Poon, Emily Sau Chee</creator><contributor>Frans Verhaegen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Physics - Radiation</subject><title>Patient-specific dose calculation methods for high-dose-rate iridium-192 brachytherapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j6118.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jv07v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb22c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les virus ont de petits génomes qui codent pour un nombre limité de protéines et dépendent conséquemment des facteurs de l'hôte pour compléter leur cycle de réplication. Dans ce projet, nous avons utilisé différentes méthodes pour identifier des partenaires protéiques de la polymérase virale à ARN (RdRp), de la VPg-Pro et de la protéine P3 du virus de la mosaïque du navet (TuMV). Premièrement, nous avons trouvé que le facteur eucaryote d'élongation de la traduction 1A (eEF1A) interagit avec la RdRp et la VPg-Pro en utilisant une stratégie de purification en tandem in planta et/ou des essais in vitro. Nous avons montré que ces interactions se produisent en association avec les membranes du réticulum endoplasmique, plus précisément dans les vésicules induites par le polypeptide 6K-VPg-Pro. Nous avons aussi démontré que ces mêmes vésicules contiennent les protéines Hsc70-3 et PABP, deux partenaires connus de la RdRp. Afin de poursuivre la caractérisation du contenu de ces vésicules, nous avons créé un vecteur infectieux du TuMV permettant d'étiqueter les vésicules avec la GFP et d'être utilisé en microscopie confocale. À l'aide de ce vecteur, nous avons observé la présence du facteur eEF1a, de la PABP, de la Hsc70, du facteur eucaryote d'initiation de la traduction (iso) 4E et de la VPg-Pro dans les vésicules induites par le TuMV. Il est bien établit que le complexe de réplication des virus à ARN positif est associé aux membranes cytoplasmiques, généralement sous forme de  vésicules. Pour le TuMV, nos données semblent indiquer que les vésicules induites par la protéine 6K contiennent le complexe de réplication viral (VRC). De plus, la présence d'éléments participants à la réplication ainsi qu'à la traduction dans ces vésicules suggère que ces deux processus sont possiblement couplés dans le VRC du TuMV. Deuxièmement, le système du double-hybride en levure a été utilisé pour rechercher des partenaires protéiques de P3. Le criblage de P3 contre une banque d'ADNc d'Arabidopsis thaliana a révélé une interaction entre P3 et une lipase. Lorsque exprimées ensembles dans Nicotiana benthamiana, les deux protéines co-localisent au cytoplasme. Étant donné le rôle des lipases dans les réponses des plantes aux attaques pathogènes, cette interaction renforce le rôle suggéré de la protéine P3 dans la pathogenèse et les mécanismes de résistance des plantes.</description><description>All viruses are gene poor relative to their host, thus, most steps in virus infection involve interactions between viral components and host factors. Identification of these factors represents one of the major frontiers in current virus research. In this study, protein-protein interaction methodologies were used to find host interactors of Turnip mosaic virus (TuMV) RNA-dependent RNA polymerase (RdRP), VPg-protease (VPg- Pro) and P3 protein. First, eukaryotic elongation factor 1A (eEF1A) was shown to interact with TuMV RdRp and VPg-Pro using tandem affinity purification in Arabidopsis thaliana and/or in vitro assays. Interaction of eEF1A with both viral proteins was shown to take place within 6K-VPg-Pro-induced vesicles. The same vesicles were also shown to contain poly(A)-binding (PABP) and heat shock cognate 70-3 proteins (Hsc70), two previously identified RdRp interactors. To further characterize the content of these vesicles upon TuMV infection, a fluorescently labeled 6K-GFP TuMV infectious clone was constructed and used in confocal microscopy experiments. The inclusion of eEF1A, PABP, Hsc70, eukaryotic initiation factor (iso)4E and VPg-Pro in TuMV-induced vesicles was demonstrated. It is well establish that positive-strand RNA viruses assemble their RNA replication complexes on intracellular membranes, usually in association with vesicle formation. For TuMV, our data suggest that it is the 6K-induced vesicles that house the viral replication complex (VRC). Moreover, the presence of replication and translation elements in these vesicles indicates that both processes might be coupled in TuMV VRC. Secondly, the yeast two-hybrid system was used to identify plant P3-interacting proteins in a cDNA library from A. thaliana. A lipase was recovered from the screen and shown to interact with P3 in vitro. Both proteins were also demonstrated to partially co-localize in the cytoplasm of the cell. Given that lipases play important roles in the plant response to biotic stress, this interaction reinforce the role of TuMV P3 in plant resistance and/or pathogenesis.</description><creator>Thivierge, Karine</creator><contributor>Jean-Francois Laliberte (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Suha Jabaji (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Virology</subject><title>Host proteins involved in «turnip mosaic virus» life cycle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vb75t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb22c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603qx948</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depuis une décennie, les semences font l'objet d'une lutte acharnée au niveau international. C'est une guerre rhétorique, menée devant les tribunaux, à travers des campagnes de publicité et dans le cadre de négociations commerciales et environnementales au niveau international; mais c'est également une lutte « sur le terrain », menée dans les champs des agriculteurs à travers le monde. En effet, avec l'introduction de plantes issues de l'ingénierie génétique, les semences ont subi une formidable transformation. Auparavant un bien commun, produit par les paysans et agriculteurs et échangées librement entre eux, les semences sont devenues une marchandise sur le marché global, assujetties à des brevets étendus. En tant que premier maillon de la chaîne alimentaire et base de notre approvisionnement alimentaire, les semences revêtent une énorme importance matérielle et symbolique. Il n'est donc pas surprenant que ces développements soient hautement controversés, et le Brésil est l'un des terrains où se mène la lutte globale autour des semences. Cette thèse présente à la fois une analyse ethnographique de la façon dont le génie génétique transforme les pratiques semencières des petits agriculteurs au Sud du Brésil, et une analyse plus ample du paysage brésilien des semences transgéniques. Elle comprend un exposé de l'évolution récente de l'industrie semencière et de la législation en matière de droits de propriété intellectuelle et de semences; un compte-rendu détaillé de la controverse autour des semences transgéniques au Brésil; ainsi qu'une étude du rôle joué par la société civile dans le débat sur les semences transgéniques. Je soutiens dans cette thèse que le droit des agriculteurs de sauvegarder, utiliser et échanger les semences — et non le génie génétique en soi — est au coeur de la résistance opposée par les agriculteurs aux semences transgéniques dans le Sud du Brésil. En effet, leur réa</description><description>For the past decade, seeds have been at the centre of a relentless global war. This is a war of rhetoric—fought in courts, in corporate publicity campaigns, and in international environment and trade negotiations; but it is also a "down-to-earth" struggle, fought in farmers' fields around the world. Indeed, with the advent of plant genetic engineering, seeds have undergone a formidable transformation. Formerly a common good, produced by peasants/farmers and exchanged freely among them, seeds are becoming a tradable commodity on the global marketplace covered by extensive patent rights. As the first link in the food chain and the basis of our food supply, seeds carry tremendous material and symbolic importance. Not surprisingly, these developments have proven highly controversial, and Brazil is one of the terrains where the global struggle over seeds is being played out. This dissertation combines an ethnographic analysis of how genetic engineering is transforming small farmers' seed practices in Southern Brazil with a broader analysis of the Brazilian transgenic seed landscape. It includes a discussion of the recent evolution of Brazilian seed industry, and intellectual property rights (IPRs) and seed legislation; a detailed account of the transgenics controversy in Brazil; and an examination of the role played by civil society in the transgenics debate. I argue that the right of farmers to save, use and exchange their seeds—and not genetic engineering per se—is at the heart of farmers' resistance to genetically engineered organisms in Southern Brazil. Small farmers' response to transgenic seeds does not reflect so much a distrust of a new technology as an acute awareness of the power relations intrinsic to the current biotechnological revolution. Indeed, small farmers are aware that recent technological developments open the way to the heightened commodification of seeds, and that, in this process, they are being dispossessed of the right to seeds, the mos</description><creator>Peschard, Karine Eliane</creator><contributor>Vinh-Kim Nguyen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Anthropology - Cultural</subject><title>Biological dispossession: an ethnography of resistance to transgenic seeds among small farmers in Southern Brazil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c12q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qx948</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z823n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently, factors influencing avian community composition and nest survival in an increasingly urbanized landscape have received much attention. Despite this research, much is still unknown regarding the capacity of privately owned and managed golf courses to support diverse breeding bird communities and provide safe nesting grounds. My overall objective was to compare avian communities and nest success rates of open-cup nesting passerines on golf courses and green spaces to determine whether golf courses support breeding bird communities as effectively as other types of suburban green space. Breeding bird communities were assessed on six golf courses and six green spaces in Montreal, Quebec, Canada. There was no difference in the mean number of bird species between golf courses and green spaces. However, species composition differed and was most correlated with site size, housing density surrounding the site, and the extent of coniferous tree, grass, and vegetated water cover. Nesting density, survival rates, productivity data and nest-site characteristics of several common open-cup nesting passerines were also compared between a subset of these sites (four golf courses and two green spaces) from 2003-2005. Species-specific differences in nest success rates were found between golf courses and green spaces. Nest survival of upland-nesting species was influenced by year, the type of nesting substrate and its arrangement, and the interaction of these two variables. American Robin (Turdus migratorius) nest success was not influenced by any of the measured variables, whereas Red-winged Blackbird (Agelaius phoeniceus) nest survival showed variation based on nest age and nest concealment. Non-viable eggs of five species were analysed for organochlorine and polychlorinated biphenyl compounds to determine if they contained traces of these historically used chemicals. Thirty-two of the 191 compounds measured were detected in all egg samples, though most compounds were fou</description><description>Récemment, plusieurs projets de recherche ont étudié les facteurs influençant la composition des communautés aviaires et leur succès de nidification dans le milieu urbain. Malgré ces études, peu est connu sur la diversité des espèces d'oiseaux nichant sur les terrains de golf et sur leur succès de nidification. Mon objectif principal était de comparer les communautés aviaires et les succès de nidification de plusieurs espèces passériformes à nids ouverts sur des terrains de golf et des espaces verts. Le but était de déterminer si les terrains de golf peuvent supporter des communautés d'oiseaux nicheurs comme les autres types d'espaces verts en banlieue. Les communautés d'oiseaux nicheurs et les caractéristiques d'habitats ont été étudiées sur six terrains de golf et six espaces verts à Montréal, Québec, Canada. Il n'y avait pas de différence significative entre le nombre moyen d'espèces se trouvant sur les terrains de golf et sur les espaces verts. Cependant, la composition en espèces était différente, les facteurs expliquant le mieux cette différence étant la grandeur du site, le nombre de maisons autour du site, et les superficies occupées par les conifères, le gazon et les étendues d'eau couvertes de végétation. Les densités de nids, les taux de survie, les données sur la productivité et les caractéristiques des sites de nidification de plusieurs espèces passériformes à nids ouverts ont aussi été comparés entre quelques sites (quatre terrains de golf et deux espaces verts) entre 2003 et 2005. Des différences au niveau du succès de nidification de plusieurs espèces ont été observées entre les terrains de golf et les espaces verts. Le succès de nidification des espèces des terres émergées était influencé par l'année, le type de substrat utilisé pour le site de nidification, son agencement et l'interaction entre ces deux variables. Le succès de nidification du merle d'Amérique (Turdus migratorius)</description><creator>Hudson, Marie-Anne</creator><contributor>David M Bird (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Factors affecting avian communities breeding on golf courses and green spaces in Montreal, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj826.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z823n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gd42h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une nouvelle famille de protéine de jonctions lacunaires, les pannexines (Panxs), a récemment été  découverte chez plusieurs espèces, incluant chez les vertébrés. Pour évaluer le rôle des Panxs dans le système reproductif mâle (SRM), l'expression et la distribution de Panx1 et Panx3 ont été étudiées dans le testicule, les canaux efférents et l'épididyme de rats adultes. Dans le testicule, Panx1 était présente dans les cellules de Sertoli, dans la région basale des canaux séminifères, tandis que Panx3 était exprimée par les cellules de Leydig. Dans les canaux efférents, les deux Panxs étaient exprimées dans l'épithélium, principalement dans la région apicale des cellules ciliées. Finalement, dans l'épididyme, Panx1 et Panx3 étaient localisées dans les cellules principales. Panx1 se retrouvait dans la région latérale et basale entre les cellules principales adjacentes en plus d'être présente à l'interface entre les cellules principales et basales. Panx3 était présente dans la région apicale des cellules principales et à la membrane plasmique des cellules halo. Les analyses de RT-PCR et d'immunobuvardage de type Western ont confirmé la présence des deux Panxs dans le SRM. Ces analyses ont mis en évidence plusieurs bandes spécifiques pour chaque Panxs dans les différentes régions, ce qui corrobore avec de récentes évidences démontrant la glycosylation post-traductionnelle des Panxs. Des résultats préliminaires de RT-PCR démontrant un épissage alternatif de Panx1 suggère aussi une régulation au niveau de l'ARNm et certaines des bandes obtenues en immunobuvardage pourraient être dues à ce processus. La testostérone et d'autres facteurs testiculaires semblent jouer un rôle dans la régulation des Panxs, car une augmentation du nombre de bandes pour Panx1 et un changement dans l'expression des bandes pour Panx3 au niveau de la protéine ont été observés suite à la castration des animaux, et ces changement</description><description>Recently, a novel family of gap junction (GJ) proteins, the pannexins (Panxs), has been identified in vertebrates. To evaluate the role of Panxs in the male reproductive tract (MRT), we investigated the expression and distribution of Panx1 and Panx3 in the testis, efferent ducts (EDs), and epididymis of adult rats. In the testis, Panx1 localized to Sertoli cells in the basal compartment of seminiferous epithelium, while Panx3 was expressed in Leydig cells. In the EDs, both Panx1 and Panx3 were expressed in the epithelium, notably at the apical region of ciliated cells. In the epididymis, both Panxs were expressed in principal cells. Prominent labelling for Panx1 was also observed laterally and basally between adjacent principal cells and at the interface between principal and basal cells. Panx3 was noted apically in principal cells and at the plasma membrane of halo cells. RT-PCR and Western blots analyses confirmed the expression of both Panxs in the MRT, with multiple species being detected in western blots and observed to be expressed in a region-specific manner, corroborating previous reports of post-translational glycosylation of Panxs. Preliminary RT-PCR results suggested that Panx1 may be regulated at the mRNA level since alternative splicing may account for some of these species. Testosterone and other testicular factors appear to regulate expression of Panxs, as an increase in the number of Panx1 species and a change in the expression of Panx3 species were observed with orchidectomy, and these were partially inhibited by testosterone supplementation. In conclusion, Panxs are present throughout the MRT where they are expressed in a cell type- and region- specific manner and appear to be regulated in terms of expression levels, subcellular localization and post-translational modification. Taken together their wide spread distribution suggest an important role for Panxs in the MRT.</description><creator>Turmel, Patrick</creator><contributor>Louis Hermo (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Daniel G Cyr (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Anatomy</subject><title>Molecular characterization of Pannexin-1 and Pannexin-3 in the male reproductive tract of adult rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nv052.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gd42h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mv59r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two species of mountain ash (Sorbus decora and S. americana) distributed in Eeyou Istchee (James Bay, Quebec) were assessed for differences in their DNA, gene expression and antioxidant capacity to determine if environment or genetic variation contributed to previously observed differences in medicinal, and possibly antidiabetic, activity. Samples of both species were taken from 20 populations throughout Eeyou Istchee. Quantitative real time PCR analysis showed species and tissue specific expression for two likely antidiabetic genes. Significantly higher expression was observed in samples from coastal communities, along with increasing expression with latitude. Similar patterns were observed when antioxidant capacity of bark samples were tested using ORAC and DPPH assays. Analysis of genetic differences using nuclear microsatellites did not show significant structuring among populations. These results suggest that it is not genetic dissimilarities which led to these differences, but likely plants responding to immediate stresses in their environment.</description><description>Deux espèces de sorbiers (Sorbus decora et S. americana) sont réparties dans Eeyou Istchee (Baie James: Québec). Elles ont été évaluées pour  leurs similarités dans leur ADN, leur expression génique et leurs propriétés antioxydantes afin de déterminer si l'environnement ou la génétique contribue aux différences déjà observées dans l'activité médicinale des sorbiers. Des échantillons de vingt populations ont été récoltés à travers Eeyou Istchee. Les analyses de PCR en temps réel ont démontré que l'expression de deux gènes liés à des métabolites secondaires était spécifique aux espèces et aux tissus. Une expression plus élevée a été observée dans les échantillons en provenance des communautés côtières et avec la latitude. L'analyse de la capacité antioxydante a démontré des patrons similaires.  L'analyse des différences génétiques à l'aide de microsatellites n'a pas révélé de groupes bien délimités. Ces résultats suggèrent que ces différences sont liées à la réponse des plantes au stress immédiat provenant de leur environnement.</description><creator>Bailie, Anna</creator><contributor>Timothy A Johns (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Alain Cuerrier (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Botany</subject><title>Phytogeography, genetic variation and antioxidant phytochemistry of «Sorbus» spp. in the Eeyou Istchee, James Bay, region of Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j634.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv59r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m701v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis compares the health care systems in Canada and the UK with a particular focus on equity of access and equity of outcomes. It explores causal factors such as organization, financing and delivery of care. The paper presents background and historical context on the two health systems, a review of current national and comparative international studies on health equity in each country, and qualitative analysis from four key informant interviews. Overall, the paper finds greater equity in Britain's NHS in terms of access to services and pro-poor allocation of resources than in Canadian Medicare. The Labour government is actively working to redress inequalities in health, while in Canada there are numerous barriers to system reform. Additionally, the current Conservative federal government has not made improving health equity a primary concern in Canada, and creeping privatization of the system is likely leading to further inequity.</description><description>Ce mémoire compare les systèmes de santé canadien et britannique en apportant une attention particulière aux questions d'équité d'accès et de soin. On y explore les facteurs causals tels que l'organisation, le financement et l'offre de soins. Une mise en contexte historique, un état de la littérature et une série de quatre entrevues avec des acteurs clés dans les deux pays sont offertes. Ce mémoire conclut à une plus grande équité dans le système public britannique tant en terme d'accès que d'allocation de ressources au profit des plus démunis. En effet, le Parti travailliste britannique s'efforce activement de redresser les iniquités alors que le gouvernement canadien est confronté à de nombreuses difficultés dans ses tentatives de réforme. De plus, le gouvernement Conservateur canadien n'a pas fait de l'amélioration des conditions d'équité une priorité tout en tolérant une privatisation rampante du système qui mènera surement à davantage d'iniquités.</description><creator>Lightman, Naomi</creator><contributor>Antonia Maioni (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Comparative health policy in Canada and the UK: an equity perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62f862t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m701v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k542n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA methylation is an epigenetic phenomenon catalysed by a  family of DNA methyltransferases (DNMTs) and is tightly regulated throughout  spermatogenesis. In these studies, I employed pharmacological and genetic means to  disrupt DNA methylation in the male germ line. First, to lower levels of DNMT  activity, I treated adult wild-type (Dnmt1+/+) and DNMT-deficient (Dnmt1c/+) male  mice with the anticancer agent 5-aza-2'-deoxycytidine (5-azaCdR), which incorporates  into DNA and inhibits methylation. Dnmt1+/+ males treated with clinical doses of  5-azaCdR for 7 weeks, to expose germ cells throughout their development, exhibit  abnormal testicular histology, as well as dose-dependent reductions in testis  weight, sperm count, fertility, and sperm motility. In contrast, Dnmt1c /+ males are  evidently partially protected from the deleterious effects of 5-azaCdR, likely  because of lowered levels of DNMT1. Although 5-azaCdR-treated Dnmt1c/+ males display  reduced testis weight, they do not have altered sperm number or testicular  histology; these males also have greater changes in sperm DNA methylation relative  to treated Dnmt1+/+ males. Interestingly, elevated preimplantation loss is observed  in females mated with treated males of either genotype. This preimplantation loss  appears to result from a reduction in oocyte fertilisation, perhaps because of  altered sperm motility. Moreover, higher levels of blastocyst loss were observed in  embryos derived from matings with treated Dnmt1 +/+ males. I suggest that the  testicular effects and reduced fertility of treated Dnmt1+/+ males are the result of  both the cytotoxic and hypomethylating effects of 5-azaCdR, whereas the changes  observed in 5-azaCdR-treated Dntnt1c /+ males may be due more to hypomethylation and  its consequences. Our second genetic model targetted the methyl supply necessary  for DNA methylation. Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) is integral to the  folate pathway and is necessary for methionine and S-adenosylmethionine formation;  levels of MTHFR are highest in the testis, which suggests a role for this enzyme in  spermatogenesis. Indeed, severe MTHFR deficiency (Mthfr -/-) results in severely  abnormal spermatogenesis and infertility. Within my studies, I showed that maternal  administration of betaine, an alternative methyl donor, throughout gestation and  nursing, results in reduced germ cell apoptosis in male pups soon after birth. When  betaine supplementation is maintained post-weaning, spermatogenesis is partially  restored and fertility increases significantly. Here, I provide evidence that  perturbation of the components of the DNA methylation pathway detrimentally affects  male germ cell development and fertility.</description><creator>Kelly, Tamara Lee Jocelyn</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Pharmacological and genetic approaches to altering DNA methylation in the mouse male germ line : effects on spermatogenesis and embryogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w778v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k542n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xf751</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plasticizers are widely used as additives for the production of  PVC and other types of plastics. They have been observed to leach out of the solid  matrix over the course of the lifetime of the finished product. These compounds have  now been observed across the globe and in different environments. The main focus of  this work is the study of the interactions of industrial plasticizers with soil  microorganisms including bacteria, yeast and fungi. This research is concerned with the microbial degradation of  plasticizers such as di-2-ethylhexyl phthalate (DEHP) and di-2-ethylhexyl adipate  (DEHA). In particular, the study has focused on the stable metabolites produced  during biodegradation, including 2-ethylhexanol and 2-ethylhexanoic acid. The first  step was to show that these toxic metabolites were found in significant  concentrations in the environment. In addition, a series of experiments with a  variety of organisms showed how wide spread the ability to produce these metabolites  was. Most organisms tested were capable of interacting with the plasticizers and  many of these produced the metabolites. It was apparent that these metabolites could have appreciable  stability and an in-depth study with one species of bacteria, R.rhodochrous , showed  that the entire initial 2-ethylhexanol component incorporated in the original  plasticizers could be accounted for. Some of this was volatile and found in the exit  gas of the reactor. This included all of the 2-ethylhexanol and some of the  2-ethylhexanol. These compounds may contribute to the impairment of the quality of  indoor air. An overall mass balance showed that while the bacterium could eventually  oxidize the 2-ethylhexanol released by hydrolysis to 2-ethylhexanoic acid, it could  not degrade this acid. Thus, a summation of the quantities of each of the various  metabolites generated equaled the original amount of 2-ethylhexanol in the  plasticizer. A mathematical model was then constructed to include all of the  above features of the interaction of R.rhodochrous with the plasticizers DEHA and  DEHP. This model included terms for the biological interactions and enzyme kinetics  as well as the toxicity and inhibition of bacterial growth by the plasticizers and  their metabolites. The increased understanding of the interaction of microbes with  plasticizers will lead to a better understanding of the environmental impact of  these compounds and their metabolites. The results of this study also demonstrate  that when assessing the environmental impact of a compound, it is essential that not  only should the impact of the parent compound be considered, but it is essential  that the assessment process must also account for impacts associated with  degradation products.</description><creator>Nalli, Sandro</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Biological degradation of plasticizers and their metabolites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591897g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xf751</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k3085</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Increasingly, knowledge-based tasks such as new product  development and market research are being conducted by geographically dispersed  teams. Early evidence from knowledge-based view of the firm and geographically  dispersed work literatures suggests that at least four kinds of knowledge  gaps---transactive memory system, mutual knowledge, categorization and situated  knowledge---exist because of the (dispersed) structure of the knowledge management  context . Dispersed members therefore cannot take for granted that they have a  common context, making dispersed collaboration problematic. The dissertation - a qualitative, theory-generating exercise -  seeks to address the question, 'how do dispersed teams collaborate to create useful  knowledge?' Specifically, the research question examines the integral elements of  the knowledge creation process, the negotiation of knowledge gaps for co-creating a  common context, and the association between the negotiation of these gaps with the  efficiency of the knowledge creation process, effectiveness of new knowledge  created, and cohesion in the team. This research has been conducted in two phases -  an exploratory ethnographic study followed by a replication study. Analysis of the data instead directed my attention to the  critical role of moderating variables such as degree of familiarity among dispersed  team members, degree of redundancy of knowledge structures among them and the nature  of task on the perceived presence or absence of gaps. These findings clarify the  literature by differentiating between the structure and the properties of the  knowledge management context and therefore develop a more comprehensive model of  these moderating variables that have the potential to affect the dispersed knowledge  creation process. Specifically, the findings demonstrate that degree of redundancy  is positively associated with the efficiency of the knowledge creation process.  These studies also suggest that dispersed collaboration may be less different from  collocated collaboration than previously thought. Finally, these studies contribute  to the dispersed work literature by suggesting that all kinds of dispersed work are  not alike and face-to-face meetings may not be necessary for all types of dispersed  work. These findings are used to develop a theory of dispersed  knowledge work and have implications for determining whether and in what contexts  geographic distance matters for conducting knowledge work. One implication is that  perceptions of distance may be at least as important as the objective aspects of  distance. Another implication is that whether geographic distance matters will  actually depend upon the competitive strategy of the firm.</description><creator>Assudani, Rashmi H.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Teams in the workplace.</subject><subject>Virtual work teams.</subject><subject>Virtual corporations.</subject><title>Creating knowledge in a geographically dispersed context : process and moderating variables</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf03f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k3085</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88ch00j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A central tenet of democratic theory is that the exercise of  governance be both legitimate and accountable. Elections constitute the fundamental  means through which these ends are met. Critical to this process is the ability of  the citizen to correctly assign responsibility for government action. Institutional  arrangements are central to defining the pathways of accountability. In  institutional contexts with only one level of government, assigning responsibility  is relatively straightforward. However, in situations of multiple and overlapping  levels of government, the process of correctly assigning responsibility and  ultimately holding governments accountable for their actions is much more difficult.  In comparative contexts, there has been and continues to be a long-term trend  towards the decentralization of political authority to sub-national levels of  government. Despite this widespread current, little is known about the effects these  processes have on democratic accountability. The central proposition tested in this dissertation is that  decentralized multi-level governance undermines democratic accountability. This  proposition is tested through drawing on the reward and punishment calculus of  economic voting: incumbent governments are rewarded (punished) for good (bad)  economic conditions. When lines of accountability are clear, the individual voter  can easily apportion blame (credit) to the government for economic conditions by  voting against (for) the government. Where multiple levels of decentralized  authority cloud responsibility, accountability for economic outcomes (either  positive or negative) is likely to be undermined. This proposition is tested comparatively using cross-national  aggregate economic and election statistics as well as cross-national  individual-level data. Case studies of institutional change towards multi-level  governance in Belgium, Scotland and Spain are examined for the theorized effects on  accountability for economic conditions. Finally, a case study of federal and  provincial economic voting in Canada is conducted using individual-level data from  recent Canadian Election Studies. Both comparatively and in case studies, the  findings of this dissertation consistently indicate that accountability for economic  conditions is undermined by the presence of decentralized multi-level  governance. This dissertation makes an important contribution to the study  of multi-level governance, economic voting and comparative politics through  uncovering institutional effects of decentralized multi-level governance that  undermine political accountability and, ultimately, the health of  democracy.</description><creator>Anderson, Cameron D.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Decentralization in government.</subject><subject>Administrative responsibility.</subject><title>Multi-level governance and economic voting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mm73z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch00j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j02r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Type 1 Diabetes (T1D) is characterized by the autoimmune  destruction of the insulin producing beta cells of the pancreas. Linkage with Type 1  Diabetes has been reported on chromosome 2q31-33. Within this 23 cM interval, T1D  association with CTLA4 polymorphisms has been localized to a linkage disequilibrium  (LD) block covering the D2S72- CTLA4-D2S116 interval. Within this interval, T1D is  associated with a haplotype in the CTLA4 gene, containing several potentially  functional polymorphisms. Due to the extent of LD in the region, genetics studies  alone are not sufficient to identify the causative polymorphism(s). To this end, we  undertook a systematic analysis of each of these polymorphisms and their functional  relevance in the pathogenesis of Diabetes. We investigated the role of the only coding polymorphism in the  CTLA4 gene, a Threonine to Alanine substitution in the N-terminal signal sequence.  The Ala17 (+49G) allele is associated with increased risk to T1D. Since the major  function of the signal sequence is to direct trafficking of the pre-protein to the  Endoplasmic Reticulum (ER), we hypothesized that a substitution could alter these  events. The Ala17 is inefficiently N-glycosylated in the ER and its expression is  lower than the Thr17 at the cell surface in COS1 cells. Using the family-based transmission disequilibrium test, (TDT)  we report an association of the -318C-allele at the proximal promoter polymorphism  and T1D. Conditional TDT analysis dissected the contributions of the linked  -318C&gt;T and +6230G&gt;A polymorphisms, as independent contributors to the genetic  effect. We report transcriptional effects of the promoter alleles in vitro , and in  vivo with the -318T allele inducing stronger transcriptional activity. This effect  may be mediated by alternative transcription factor binding at the Single Nucleotide  Polymorphism (SNP). We confirmed association of the 3'+6230G&gt;A SNP with T1D. In  evaluating its contribution to the expression of soluble and full-length CTLA4  isoforms in an allele-dependent manner, we found no correlation between alleles at  +6230 and levels of either isoform. The 3' SNP does not alter in cis the expression  of the downstream ICOS gene. We propose that susceptibility at the CTLA4 locus is mediated by  a haplotype exerting both transcriptional and post-translational  effects.</description><creator>Anjos, Suzana M.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>A functional analysis of the association of Type 1 Diabetes with the cytotoxic T-lymphocyte antigen-4 (CTLA4) gene /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s06z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j02r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w7794</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The morphogenetic plasticity of adult pancreatic islets of  Langerhans has been implicated in the development of pancreatic adenocarcinomas and  in islet transplant failure. The objective of this doctoral work was to investigate  the extent of this plasticity and to characterize the unknown cell types and  intracellular mechanisms involved in changes of adult islet  phenotype. In the first published study, isolated adult canine islets were  induced to undergo a phenotypic switch into highly proliferative duct-like  structures through a two-stage process entailing beta-cell death and the  dedifferentiation of the resulting cells. The transformed islets were no longer  immunoreactive for islet cell hormones, but now expressed markers of pancreatic duct  epithelial cells. Pharmacologic inhibition of signal transduction demonstrated that  the balance in signalling activity between ERK/Akt and JNK/caspase-3 appears to be  an important regulator of islet cell death and differentiation. In the second published study, quiescent adult human islets were  induced to undergo a similar phenotypic switch into highly proliferative duct-like  structures in a process that implicated glucagon- and somatostatin-expressing cells,  and was characterized by a loss of expression of islet-specific hormones and  transcription factors as well as a temporally-related rise in expression of markers  of stermness and duct epithelium. Short-term treatment of these primitive duct-like  structures with the islet neogenic factor INGAP 104-118 induced their scalable  reversion back to islet-like structures in a P13-kinase-dependent manner. These  neoislets resembled freshly isolated human islets with respect to the presence and  topological arrangement of the four endocrine cell-types, islet gene expression and  hormone production, insulin content and glucose-responsive insulin secretion. The  demonstration that adult human islets are able to regenerate themselves establishes  a new paradigm in the context of tissue regeneration and diabetes  therapy. These original findings may have important clinical implications  for understanding and controlling pancreatic carcinogenesis and islet neogenesis in  the adult human pancreas.</description><creator>Jamal, Al-Maleek</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Studies of pancreatic islet plasticity : a new paradigm in tissue regeneration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s65j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w7794</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903041x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is associated  with considerably elevated rates of coronary heart disease (CHD). Understanding the  reasons for this is crucial for developing effective CHD prevention and treatment in  SLE patients. Objective. To gain insights into biological mechanisms  underlying the accelerated atherosclerosis in SLE, this thesis examines (i) the  longitudinal evolution of traditional coronary risk factors and global coronary  risk, and (ii) the independent effects of corticosteroid use and lupus disease  activity on this evolution. Methods. First, a systematic comparison between alternative  approaches to global coronary risk assessment was performed based on data from the  Framingham Heart Study to determine the optimal method of representing the aggregate  impact of individual risk factors. Next, data on up to 30 years of follow up of 310  lupus patients of the Montreal General Hospital Lupus Clinic and 26 years of  follow-up of 4,367 control subjects from the Framingham Offspring Study were used to  investigate, in separate analyses, the independent associations of lupus disease  duration with the global coronary risk and each conventional risk factor. Finally,  the lupus cohort was used to study the associations of recent corticosteroid use and  recent lupus disease activity with a series of CHD risk factors and global CHD risk.  Main analyses relied on multivariable linear mixed models for longitudinal  data. Findings. Updated risk factor values improved the predictive  ability of the multivariable coronary risk score compared with prediction based on  baseline values. Longer lupus disease duration was associated with increased blood  glucose levels, systolic blood pressure and total cholesterol. Recent corticosteroid  use and recent lupus disease activity were both positively associated with increases  in the levels of conventional risk factors and the global risk. Conclusions. Conventional coronary risk factors play an  especially important role in the etiology of CHD in lupus patients. The accelerated  atherosclerosis in SLE could be mediated by conventional coronary risk factors,  which are affected by both lupus disease activity and corticosteroid  therapy.</description><creator>Karp, Igor</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><title>Risk factors for coronary heat disease in systemic lupus erythematosus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472w926.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903041x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tv54m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Buxheim Organ Book, the largest fifteenth-century manuscript  of keyboard tablature, has never before been examined as a whole in light of musica  ficta issues, although it contains far more accidentals than any contemporaneous  source in mensural notation. Although tablature has been used by various scholars to  examine accidentals in sixteenth-century music, studies of fifteenth-century  accidentals have focussed on theoretical evidence and small groups of pieces from  mensural sources. The author uses the Buxheim Organ Book to extend the  investigations of accidentals in tablature back into the fifteenth century,  combining the large data set provided by this manuscript with a statistical approach  modelled on that of Thomas Brothers's smaller-scale study of the chansons of  Binchois. Specialised computer programs are introduced, which detect musical  structures relevant to the analysis of Renaissance music such as different types of  cadential voice leading. These programs function as extensions to David Huron's  Humdrum Toolkit. With these tools, signing practises in the intabulations are  statistically compared with all of the concordances of the models. Conclusions are  suggested pertaining to issues of signature accidental transmission, partial  signatures, mode, and musica ficta, which can be used as a contextual backdrop for  the analysis of individual pieces. The evidence provided by the accidentals in  Buxheim and its concordances draws a clear picture of how a group of  fifteenth-century musicians added accidentals to polyphonic music. For the first  time, this study provides us with principles and guidelines for musica ficta  -decisions based on actual practice.</description><creator>Jürgensen, Frauke</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Performance practice (Music) -- History -- To 1500.</subject><subject>Musica ficta.</subject><subject>Buxheimer Orgelbuch.</subject><subject>Musical analysis -- Data processing.</subject><title>Accidentals in the mid-fifteenth century : a computer-aided study of the Buxheim organ book and its concordances</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096755p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv54m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35t905k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Implicit self-esteem is the automatic and unconscious component  of self-esteem, which is generally not correlated with more traditional measures of  explicit self-esteem. The goal of the research presented in this dissertation was to  test a cognitive model of implicit self-esteem. Drawing from interpersonal theories  of self-esteem and from theories of evaluative learning, I hypothesized that  implicit self-esteem is developed through repeated exposure to pairings of the self  with interpersonal rejection or acceptance, leading to unconscious and automatic  self--rejected or self--accepted cognitive associations. I tested this theory using  a computer-based conditioning task designed to enhance implicit self-esteem through  the repeated pairing of self-relevant information (e.g., first name, birthday) with  interpersonal acceptance (i.e., photographs of smiling faces). Support for this  hypothesis was found in four studies. Overall, participants who completed the  computer-based conditioning task generally had higher scores on the self-esteem  Implicit Associations Test compared to participants in a control condition.  Furthermore, the conditioning task had no effect on explicit self-esteem scores,  providing support for the distinct nature of implicit self-esteem relative to  explicit self-esteem. Finally, exploratory analyses showed that contingency  awareness was not needed for evaluative conditioning to occur. These findings  support the proposed cognitive model of implicit self-esteem and provide a novel  computer-based conditioning task for enhancing implicit self-esteem.</description><creator>Baccus, Jodene Robin</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Self-esteem.</subject><title>Testing a cognitive model of implicit self-esteem through evaluative conditioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nv08w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35t905k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zf01t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Damage from large hail is a costly problem in Canada and other  parts of the world. With continuous increase in computer power, numerical weather  prediction (NWP) models are getting closer to resolving the convective scale, where  it is appropriate to employ explicit microphysics schemes. This dissertation examines the potential to predict hail using  an explicit microphysics scheme in an NWP model. To this end, the requirements of a  bulk scheme to model the hydrometeor size distribution are investigated. A number of  schemes in the literature use the double-moment method with a three-parameter gamma  distribution function to represent the size spectrum. In general, two of the  parameters vary with the predicted moments while the third, normally the shape  parameter, is held constant. In a simple 1D context, the role of the shape parameter  is analyzed by comparing results from bulk schemes using different numbers of  predicted moments and an analytic bin model. It is shown that this parameter is  important in the overall prediction of the size distribution by affecting both the  instantaneous growth rates and the sedimentation. In view of this, two alternatives  to the fixed-value approach are presented. One is a double-moment method, where the  shape parameter is diagnosed from the predicted moments; the other is a  triple-moment approach, where all distribution parameters are fully  prognosed. A new microphysics scheme using the proposed approaches has been  designed and interfaced with the Mesoscale Compressible Community model (MC2).  High-resolution (1 km) simulations of a severe hailstorm are conducted. The control  simulation using the full triple-moment version of the scheme is compared to radar  observations and is shown to realistically simulate the observed storm, including  the spatial distribution and sizes of hail at the ground. Experiments are performed  to determine the sensitivity of the different approaches on the simulation of hail.  The results indicated that the triple-moment scheme gives the best results. For a  double-moment scheme, the diagnostic approach for the shape parameter exhibits  distinct improvement over the fixed-value approach. It is also shown that  double-moment schemes are dramatically better in reproducing the control simulation  than single-moment schemes, owing largely to the ability of multi-moment schemes to  account for the effects of size-sorting.</description><creator>Milbrandt, Jason</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A triple-moment bulk microphysics scheme for the explicit simulation of hail /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h488v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zf01t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk316</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation focuses on learning how to control the  physico-chemical properties of multilayer thin films containing weak  polyelectrolytes by gaining an understanding of the films from a fundamental  perspective. This information is then used, as a proof of principle concept, to  assemble films with desired properties for a model application. Multilayer thin  films were prepared using the layer-by-layer deposition technique, which involves  the sequential adsorption of oppositely charged polymers onto a charged substrate  from dilute aqueous solutions. The charge density of weak polyelectrolytes is highly  sensitive to the pH and ionic strength of the solution environment. In turn, the  solution behavior of such polymers influences their properties when adsorbed on a  surface. An extensive investigation of the acid-base equilibria of the  polyelectrolytes polyallylamine hydrochloride and poly(acrylic acid) upon  incorporation into the film was carried out and the result compared to the  dissociation behavior of these polymers in dilute solution. The study of the acid-base chemistry in weak polyelectrolyte  multilayer films was extended to a more complex biopolymer combination of  poly(L-lysine) and hyaluronic acid. These polymers are able to adopt secondary  conformational ordering in the form of alpha-helices and beta-sheets. The acid-base  equilibria of the polyelectrolytes were investigated as a function of solution pH  and the total number of layers in the film. These results were correlated with those  obtained from the study of some of the surface and bulk properties of the films such  as surface wettability, friction, film thickness, and the degree of film  swelling. The extent to which polymer films can swell depends on both the  properties of the film matrix and the swelling medium. The hydration of  polyelectrolyte multilayer films is of importance in the potential applications of  the films. This promoted an investigation of the effect of the assembly conditions  (i.e. solution pH and the total number of layers assembled), and properties of the  swelling medium such as pH and ionic strength on the overall swelling of  polyallylamine/hyaluronic acid multilayer films. In turn, this information was used,  in part, to understand the pH-dependent loading and release behavior of small  hydrophilic molecules in the films as a model application for polyelectrolyte  multilayer assemblies.</description><creator>Burke, Susan Elizabeth</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Preparation, characterization, and application of pH-responsive polyelectrolyte multilayer films</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z5795.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk316</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cd627</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is aimed at understanding and fully characterising  the association mechanism of an alternating copolymer in water and the effect of the  association in solution on the conformation of the polymer chains at the air/water  interface. Self-assembly is an elegant and efficient method to obtain well  defined and usually defect-free nano-architectures. The association, variety of  shapes and properties of block copolymers have been extensively studied. The present  study led to a precise understanding of the complex behaviour of large molecules.  The polymer studied is an alternating copolymer; poly(styrene- alt-maleic anhydride)  (SMA). This polymer has various applications ranging from surface sizing of paper,  to nanotechnology and pharmaceutical applications. The detailed theoretical investigation of the SMA association  led to the discovery of a novel way to self-assemble polymer chains, and the  prediction and characterisation of a tubular structure formed by this association.  The nanotubes are several micrometers long and their conformation shows that the  hydrophobic groups are mainly located inside the tube and the hydrophilic groups are  mainly on the exterior surface of the tube. The predicted tubular structure of SMA in solution was also  confirmed by neutron scattering experiments. This study showed that the tubes  interact forming two-dimensional sheets of tubes and higher order structures. In  addition, the SMA association has been shown to be thermally stable. Furthermore, neutron reflectivity experiments were performed on  the SMA solution to determine the influence of the association in solution on the  conformation of the polymer at the air-water interface. This study revealed an  equilibrium between the conformation of the polymer in solution and at the  interface. Using the knowledge of the association mechanism obtained from  the complete theoretical and experimental characterisation of the association of  poly(styrene-maleic anhydride) in water and at the air-water interface, a novel  application for the polymer has been developed. This application uses the template  formed by the nanotubes to form nanowires of intrinsically conducting polymers.  Neutron scattering, neutron reflectivity, cryo-TEM and AFM experimental studies  characterised the synthesis of the nanowires.</description><creator>Malardier-Jugroot, Cécile</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Novel self-assembly of an alternating copolymer into nanotubes : theoretical investigation and experimental characterisation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v358s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cd627</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f8676</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the effect of early parental care and  environmental experience on hippocampal development and cognitive function in the  adult rodent. Maternal care in the rat contributes to cognitive function through  effects on neural systems known to mediate certain forms of learning and memory. The  offspring of mothers that exhibit a low frequency of licking/grooming (Low-LG  mothers) over the first week of life show decreased hippocampal synaptogenesis and  N-Methyl-D-aspartate (NMDA) receptor mRNA expression, and poor spatial learning;  relative to the offspring of mothers that exhibit high levels of maternal care. The  results of cross-fostering studies provide evidence for a direct relationship  between maternal behaviour and hippocampal development in the offspring of Low-LG  mothers (Liu et al., 1997; 2000). Indeed, peripubertal environmental enrichment reversed the  effect of reduced maternal care on hippocampal-dependent learning and memory,  synaptic density, and several genes encoding for glutamate receptor subunits. For  example, hippocampal NR2A, NR2B, GluR1 and GluR3 mRNA expression was reversed, with  the strongest effects occurring in area CA1 of the hippocampal formation.  Interestingly, the effect of enrichment on GluR1 and GluR3 mRNA expression was  lateralized to the right hippocampus. Environmental enrichment did not reverse the  effect of reduced maternal care on NMDA receptor binding or long-term potentiation  in the dentate gyrus. In every instance where reversal occurred after exposure to  enrichment during adolescence, the effect was specific to the offspring of Low-LG  mothers, with little or no effect on the offspring of High-LG mothers. It is  suggested that an increased level of astrocyte expression in the hippocampus of  Low-LG offspring at the time of weaning could account for the individual differences  in sensitivity to environmental enrichment. The findings are extended with the  presentation of a new model where the issue of a paternal contribution towards  offspring cognitive development is addressed in the monogamous California mouse  (Peromyscus californicus).</description><creator>Bredy, Timothy W.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Parental care, environmental enrichment, and hippocampal development and function in the adult rodent</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354f73v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f8676</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w040k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:21:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Signaling molecules play essential roles in communication  between cells. Wnt signaling molecules are critical for embryonic development of  several organisms. I examined the involvement of Wnt signaling during two major  developmental processes, namely embryo implantation and formation of the embryonic  body axes. Using RT-PCR analysis, I showed that multiple Wnt genes are expressed in  the blastocyst at the time of implantation. Moreover, expression of Wnt 11 requires  both estrogen produced by the mother and the uterine environment. Using a transgenic  approach, I showed that beta-catenin-regulated transcriptional activity, which is a  major transducer of Wnt signaling, is activated in the uterus specifically at the  site of implantation in an embryo-dependent manner. These results introduce Wnts as  candidate signaling factors that may mediate the communication between the embryo  and uterus that initiates implantation. Wnt/beta-catenin signaling triggers axis formation in Xenopus  and zebrafish embryos. I showed that, during embryonic development,  beta-catenin-regulated transcriptional activity is first detected in the prospective  primitive streak region prior to gastrulation. This demarcates the posterior region  of the embryo. This activity then becomes restricted to the elongating primitive  streak and to the node. In Xenopus embryos, beta-catenin participates in the  formation of the organizer through the activation of the homeodomain transcription  factors Siamois and Twin. I obtained evidence that a Siamois/Twin-like binding  activity exists in mouse embryos and is localized in the node. These results  strongly suggest that, as the case in Xenopus and zebrafish, the Wnt/beta-catenin  pathway is involved in establishing embryonic body axes. Furthermore, using the transgenic mouse line that I generated  for these studies, I mapped the transcriptional activity of beta-catenin during  mouse embryonic development. These results revealed when and where this activity,  and presumably Wnt signaling, is active during the development of several organs and  embryonic structures.</description><creator>Mohamed, Othman</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Morphogenesis.</subject><subject>Cellular signal transduction.</subject><subject>Wnt proteins.</subject><subject>Mice -- Embryology.</subject><title>Identification of multiple roles for Wnt signaling during mouse development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s533m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w040k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859g13h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phylogenetic relationships of the subfamily Dolichopodinae  were investigated based on the examination of over 340 species from all  zoogeographic regions. Sixty-five exemplar species were included in cladistic  analysis based on 74 morphological characters of adult specimens. Twenty genera are  recognized in the Dolichopodinae: Allohercostomus Yang, Saigusa and Masunaga,  Anasyntormon Parent, Argyrochlamys Lamb, Cheiromyia Dyte, Dolichopus Latreille,  Ethiromyia gen. nov., Gymnopternus Loew, Hercostomus Loew, Metaparaclius Becker,  Muscidideicus Becker, Ortochile Latreille, Paraclius Loew, Parahercostomus Yang,  Saigusa and Masunaga, Pelastoneurus Loew, Platyopsis Parent, Poecilobothrus Mik,  Prohercostomus Grichanov, Stenopygium Becker, Sybistroma Meigen, and Tachytrechus  Stannius. Eleven genera are newly synonymized: Halaiba Parent (= Argyrochlamys  Lamb); Lichtwardtia Enderlein (= Dolichopus Latreille); Phalacrosoma Becker (=  Hercostomus Loew); Steleopyga Grootaert and Meuffels (= Hercostomus Loew); Proarchus  Aldrich (= Pelastoneurus Loew); Sarcionus Aldrich (= Pelastoneurus Loew);  Pterostylus Mik (= Poecilobothrus Mik); Ludovicius Rondani (= Sybistroma Meigen);  Nodicornis Rondani (= Sybistroma Meigen); Gonioneurum Becker (= Tachytrechus  Stannius); Syntomoneurum Becker (= Tachytrechus Stannius). Eighty-one new generic  combinations are established and one new name is proposed for a secondary homonym.  Four genera that were sometimes included in the subfamily are excluded, namely  Colobocerus Parent, Katangaia Parent, Pseudohercostomus Stackelberg and Vetimicrotes  Dyte. A key to the world genera of Dolichopodinae is provided. The Tachytrechus  alatus species group (formerly the genus Syntomoneurum) is revised. This species  group includes five Neotropical species, all of which are redescribed. A key to the  species of the T. alatus species group is provided. The new genus Ethiromyia is also  described, including two Nearctic and one Palaearctic spec</description><creator>Brooks, Scott Edward</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Dolichopodidae -- Classification.</subject><subject>Dolichopodidae -- Phylogeny.</subject><title>Systematics and phylogeny of the Dolichopodinae (Diptera:Dolichopodidae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322d805.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859g13h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vr41s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two-way chaining is a novel hashing scheme that uses two  independent truly uniform hash functions f and g to insert m keys into a hash table  with n chains, where each key x is inserted into the shortest chain among the chains  f(x) and g( x), breaking ties randomly. It is known [13, 18] that the worst-case  search time of two-way chaining is log2 log n + m/n + O(1), asymptotically almost  surely. In this thesis, we study the two-way chaining paradigm under different  assumptions. First, we generalize the result to nonuniform hash functions. We  analyze two-way chaining in the fixed density model where the two independent hash  functions behave according to two densities defined on the unit interval. When m =  O(n), we prove that asymptotically almost surely, the worst-case search time is at  least log2 log n - O(1). If, in addition, the densities are bounded, then it is at  most log2 log n + O( m/n). Secondly, we consider the off-line version of two-way chaining  where all the hashing values available for the m keys are known in advance. For  constant k ~ N , we show that there is a threshold ck such that if m  ≤ ckn, then one can assign the keys to the chains so that the maximum search  time is at most 2k, asymptotically almost surely. We tightly estimate ck, and prove  that it is, in fact, asymptotic to k. Algorithms for finding such assignments are  also given. Thirdly, we utilize the two-way chaining paradigm to design  efficient open addressing hashing schemes. We study two-way linear probing  algorithms. These are algorithms that employ two independent linear probe sequences  to hash the keys. We prove an O(log log n) universal lower bound on the worst-case  search time of any two-way linear probing algorithm, where n is the hash table size.  We show, however, that some simple two-way linear probing algorithms, unexpectedly,  have implausible worst-case performances. Subsequently, we present several efficient  two-way linear probing algorithms whose performance matches the lower bound.  Simulations back up the theoretical results.</description><creator>Malalla, Ebrahim</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Two-way hashing with separate chaining and linear probing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c18c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vr41s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vb81z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following thesis describes two stereoselective carbon-carbon  bond forming processes---the aldol reaction and its one-carbon homologue, the  homoaldol reaction. The first chapter describes our efforts to increase the  stereoselectivity of a catalytic homoaldol reaction. This methodology features a  second generation Binol titanium (IV) fluoride catalyst capable of opening a  silyloxycyclopropane ring to form discrete homoenolates. These homoenolates react  with a variety of aldehydes to form 1,4-hydroxy carbonyl compounds. The catalyst was  prepared by a literature method and has improved the stereoselectivity of this  reaction compared to the first generation Binol titanium (IV) triflate catalyst. A  variety of substituted Binol ligands were studied to determine the effect of steric  and electronic modifications on reaction selectivity. In the second chapter, a general method for the asymmetric  synthesis of alpha,alpha-disubstituted-beta-hydroxy carbonyl compounds is described.  This methodology relies on the stereoselective formation of acyclic  alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates. These enolates were prepared using  methodology developed in the Gleason laboratory. Transmetallation of the initially  formed lithium enolate was necessary to achieve high relative and absolute product  stereocontrol. The E- and Z-enolate isomers were investigated. The Z-enolate reacted  with high stereocontrol, whereas the E-enolate was not able to provide the anti  isomer selectively. An X-ray crystal structure confirmed the absolute configuration  of the product.</description><creator>Burke, Elizabeth Diane</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Stereoselective carbon-carbon bond forming reactions : improving the stereoselectivity of a catalytic homoaldol reaction and the development of a general method to access the [alpha]-quaternary carbon [beta]-hydroxy carbonyl motif</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vt850.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb81z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43300</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>