<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:04Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107321f" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107321f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:00:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mitochondria generate the majority of cellular energy through oxidative phosphorlyation. The machinery of oxidative phosphroylation consists of five enzyme complexes that are located in the inner mitochondrial membrane. A small number of essential subunits in these complexes are encoded by mtDNA and synthesized on a dedicated mitochondrial translation apparatus. Defects in mitochondrial translation system cause many mitochondrial diseases, but the mechanisms that regulate mitochondrial translation remain largely unknown. We have identified an unnamed human protein C7orf30, as a possible mitochondrial translation factor. The orthologue of C7orf30 in maize is thought to be a chloroplast ribosome assembly factor. We identified human C7orf30 to be a mitochondrial protein through bioinformatics analysis and immunocytochemistry. We knocked down the expression of C7orf30 in human fibroblast using shRNA and observed a reduction in cytochrome c oxidase activity. Using a translation assay, we observed a global reduction in the synthesis of mitochondrially encoded proteins when C7orf30 was knocked down, while the transcript levels were not affected. The assembly of Complex I, III, IV and V also demonstrated defects. Sucrose density gradient analysis suggests C7orf30 interacts with 39S subunit of the mitoribosome. The assembly of the mitoribosome and the levels of 12S and 16S MT-rRNA were not affected by C7orf30 knockdown, suggesting C7orf30 is not necessary for mitochondrial ribosome assembly. We hypothesize that C7orf30 interacts with the mitoribosome and is a regulator of mitochondrial translation.</description><description>Les mitochondries génèrent la majorité de l'énergie cellulaire grâce à l'oxydation phosphorylative. La chaîne respiratoire responsable de ce phénomène est composée de cinq complexes enzymatiques localisés dans la membrane interne de la mitochondrie. Certaines des sous-unités essentielles de ces complexes sont codées par l'ADN mitochondrial. Leur synthèse est assurée par la mitochondrie qui possède son propre système de traduction des protéines. Les déficiences de la traduction mitochondriale sont à l'origine de nombreuses maladies et les mécanismes qui régulent le processus de traduction restent à ce jour peu élucidés. Dans cette étude, nous avons identifié chez l'homme, C7orf30, une protéine probablement impliquée dans la régulation de la traduction mitochondriale. Il existe un homologue de cette protéine chez le maïs. Une étude suggère son rôle en tant que facteur d'assemblage des ribosomes des chloroplastes. Des programmes informatiques prédisent la localisation de la protéine C7orf30 humaine dans la mitochondrie ce que nous avons confirmé par des expériences d'immunocytochimie. L'utilisation de shRNA dirigés contre C7orf30 dans des fibroblastes humains révéle d'abord une réduction de l'activité cytochrome c oxydase (complexe IV). Des expériences de traduction ex vivo montrent ensuite une réduction globale de la synthèse des protéines codées par la mitochondrie dans les cellules déficitaires en C7orf30, la transcription étant normale. L'assemblage des complexes I, III, IV et V de la chaîne respiratoire est également affecté. La séparation des protéines par gradient de sucrose suggère que C7orf30 interagit avec la sous unité 39S des ribosomes mitochondriaux. Cependant, l'assemblage et les niveaux d'expression des rRNA 12S et 16S ne sont pas affectés par la diminution de la protéine ce qui suggère qu'elle n'est pas indispensable à l'assemblage des ribosomes mitochondriaux en soit. Dans cette étude, nous émettons l'hypothèse que C7orf30 est un composant du ribosome et agit comme un régulateur de la traduction mitochondriale.</description><creator>Fung, Hiu Leong</creator><contributor>Eric Alan Shoubridge (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Human C7orf30 is a novel mitochondrial translation factor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dr25w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107321f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>