<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:49:37Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12300" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz40w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Maritime Provinces of Canada offer tempting prospects to the petroleum industry, for oil and gas seepages have been reported from widely separated districts since the early settlement of the country. Yet the petroleum production to date has come almost exclusively from the Stony Creek field in New Brunswick, which has yielded only slightly better than one hundred thousand barrels of oil and twelve billion cubic feet of gas. It is the essential purpose of this thesis to investigate further the petroleum possibilities of this area through the medium of paleogeology. Three sources of information have been exploited in the construction of the accompanying paleogeologic map. They are: (l) published maps and descriptions of the stratigraphy and structure, (2) published geophysical information, and (3) the well logs available at the Borings Division of the Geological Survey of Canada in Ottawa. It is necessary at this point to note that the number and quality of the well logs available greatly restrict the accuracy of this study. Thus, this study is of necessity highly speculative in its outlook and only serves to point the way for future work if the various oil companies feel that such work is warranted. The stratigraphic horizon selected for this study is the pre-Pennsylvanian, that is, the surface geology as it appeared at the beginnings of the Pennsylvanian Period. To understand the interpretation of the paleogeologic map it is necessary to know something of the[...]</description><creator>Castle, Robert Oliver.</creator><contributor>Clark, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Paleontology -- Maritime Provinces.</subject><subject>Geology -- Maritime Provinces.</subject><title>Paleogeological studies in the Maritime provinces.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v166b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz40w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w791p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aeromycology has been largely dealt with for agricultural or medical reasons. Rust spores, smut spores and spores of many other plant pathogens have been found to exist in a viable state in all layers of our atmosphere. Many workers have shown how these organisms through their numerous air-borne spores may be borne thousands of miles to cause new local infections. The almost continuous exposure of wheat to infection by wheat rust is due to the transportation of the rust spores hundreds of miles by air. The infection starts as a wave in the far south of of our continent with winter planting and slowly travels north till all areas are infected. Interest of the allergists is in the local incidence and seasonal variation of the fungous spores known to be allergens. Viability is not essential as mere contact with them is sufficient for an allergic reaction to occur. Academic curiosity led to the first researches on air-borne organisms and continues even today. Such interest in the micro-flora of arctic air particularly in the fungi is stimulated by the desire for knowledge on the distance plant pathogens can travel, but it is of interest to know what kinds of fungi are present and in what numbers, as well as temperatures and other conditions they are able to withstand. While many fungi have been isolated from Arctic and sub-Arctic air only four groups will be discussed in detail in this paper. [...]</description><creator>Carter, Sharon Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Kelly, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Bacteriology.</subject><title>The Kinds and Distribution of Fungi in the Air Over Northern Canada Above 3,000 Feet.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj72c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w791p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t962g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The title of this thesis is a broad one and purposely so, for the problem was first conceived in such general terms. But it soon became obvious, that the role of many electrolytes in many different types of heart disease could not possibly be investigated by one person in a short time. Therefore, in approaching such a study, the problem had immediately to be limited. Because potassium is such an important electrolyte in cellular metabolism and because variations in potassium concentrations have such a marked effect upon the functions of the heart, it was decided that this ion should be the principal electrolyte involved in the investigation. Because changes in the potassium concentration frequently involve reciprocal changes in sodium concentration, sodium, to an extent, also enters this study. The term heart disease also needed closer definition. It was planned to include two general types of heart disease in the investigation, acute and chronic heart disease. This acute and chronic myocardial damage would also have to be of a type easily induced by experimental procedures. Such a problem as the roles of these electrolytes in experimentally induced acute and chronic heart disease could be approached in different ways. For instance, the heart disease could be induced and then the level of serum and tissue electrolyte concentrations determined. On the other hand, the effect of variations of serum sodium and potassium concentration[...]</description><creator>Campbell, Charles G.</creator><contributor>Friedman, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Electrolytes in Heart Disease.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mz78k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t962g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p7939</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work begins with an etymological study of the word “ratification”, and a historical outline of the formality. It examines, next, the problem of the necessity of ratification for the validity of international agreements, with a discussion of Grotius’ traditional agency doctrine and Bynkershoek’s doctrine of the tacit ratification clause. The signature of treaties is then dealt with, particularly the question of its juridical nature. There follows a theoretical explanation of the various theories on the relationship between International Law and Municipal Law, as background for an adequate understanding of the next two problems: Ratification as related to Constitutional Law and the entry of treaties into force. Finally, consideration is given to the forms of ratification.</description><creator>Camara, José Sette.</creator><contributor>Cohen, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Treaties -- Ratification.</subject><title>The ratification of international treaties.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v167m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p7939</identifier><degree><name>Master of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225f39d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phenomenon of coagulation of colloidal systems is analogous in many respects to a chemical reaction, proceeding at a definite rate dependent on temperature and concentration, and being markedly sensitive to the presence of foreign substances. It is, however, mainly a diffusion-controlled process. The consequence of this is that no equilibrium state can be set up to describe the reacting system. Hence the problem cannot be treated on the basis of either the collision theory of chemical reactions or the theory of the transition state, since both of these depend on an equilibrium configuration of the reactants, activated intermediates and products in the reaction. In coagulation the rate is governed by the viscosity of the medium, which determines the rate at which the particles diffuse to each other, since the ensuing collision of the particles generally results in coalescence. This process disturbs the equilibrium greatly and it is only when the probability of coalescence of these collisions is reduced that an equilibrium state can be postulated. Therefore an all-inclusive theory of coagulation cannot be deduced by the standard kinetic methods. However, the application of other methods leads to rate equations similar to those used for chemical reactions. In any colloidal system the sum of the free energies of the separate components is less than that of the system which is formed from them [...]</description><creator>Brady, George William.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The kinetics of slow coagulation of GR-S Latex (Pt.I). : The kinetics of the cis-trans isomerization of azobenzene in solution (Pt.II).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988p13w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225f39d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999989n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fodsol soils constitute a large proportion of the soils of Eastern Canada. They are developed under woodland in cool humid conditions where rainfall exceeds evaporation. The profile from the surface downward consists essentially of an organic layer, a leached layer, and a layer of accumulation just above the parent rock. Thus the simplest podso1 profile consists of three horizons, namely: Ao ‘ the raw humus layer; A2, the leached siliceous layer; B, the layer of accumulation of sesquioxides. The Ao horizon of acid peaty organic matter is considered essential to the development of a true podsol. G.W. Robinson makes the following statement: “.... It would appear that an acid reaction is not in itself sufficient to cause podsolization. This may be readily shown in the laboratory by allowing 0.1 N solutions of hydrochloric acid and oxalic acid, respectively, to percolate through ferruginous sand. Alghough the pH of the hydrochloric acid is lower than that of the oxalic acid, the solvent action of the latter acid is considerably greater and quickly leads to a bleaching by removal of ferric oxide.....” R.T. Jones and J.S. Willcox have demonstrated in the laboratory that oxalic and tartaric acids will bring sesquioxides, from the upper part of the profile, into solution and deposit them lower down.[...]</description><creator>Boswall, Graeme Wyatt.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Investigation of the acidity of leachates from decomposing leaves of deciduous trees.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r863c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999989n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nh88d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of measuring impedance is an old one, but its currency is renewed every time there is an advance into the radio-frequency spectrum. The trend in the development of Radio science has been towards higher frequencies, and particularly during the recent war has there been a rapid advance in this direction. The need for, and emphasis on, practical results from wartime development and research has led to the by-passing or at any rate incomplete solution of many problems in the frequency range from 100 to 200 mc. Because of the dearth of information and the lack of practical techniques to deal with measurements at these frequencies, a great part of the practical results were obtained by trial and error, cut and try methods. As a result of some of this work, it is now possible and undoubtedly profitable to review this portion of the spectrum, and to try to evolve, under less urgent conditions, some more practical and efficient methods of measurement. This thesis deals with the problem of developing a device for the measurement of impedance, in the frequency range from 100 to 200 mc. To gain a better understanding of the problem, and to set the stage for what is to come, the first part of the thesis will be devoted to a review of the methods that have been used to measure impedance in the past, and of how these methods have been modified or found unsuitable as the frequency became higher.[...]</description><creator>Boire, Paul Charles.</creator><contributor>Howes, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>The design of a resonant line impedance measuring device for the frequency range from 100 to 200 mega-cycles.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd941.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nh88d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365840z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The social worker has a contribution to make towards the present intensive program on cancer research. To discover the nature of that contribution is the purpose of this study. The terminally ill have become a most serious social problem in recent years. Since medical science has found cures for the death-dealing infectious diseases, more patients have survived to succumb to the chronic illnesses common to older age groups. Illness resulting from a damaged cardio-vascular system such as arteriosclerosis, a deterioration of the muscular-skeletal system. such as rheumatoid arthritis, a diseased respiratory system such as tuberculosis and diseased body cells producing dreaded cancer are considered to be chronic. Of all the chronically ill groups, none creates a more serious problem in relation to care than does the cancer group. The tear associated with cancer, the hopelessness engendered by such a diagnosis, the intensive care needed by this particular group, and the lack of the necessary facilities to give that needed care, all contribute to the seriousness ot the problem. The mortality statistics ot Canada for 1947 list cancer as the second most frequent cause of death;. one out of every eight deaths result from this disease. The medical profession, recognizing the seriousness of the problem, is concentrating on research to discover the causes, and effective cures. [...]</description><creator>Black, Annie G.</creator><date>1949</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>The role of the social worker in the care of the terminally ill.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214s466.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365840z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042x33h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is based on the literature of Dominion and Provincial Surveys of Canada and other pertinent sources. In scope, this investigation does not include the Grenville Sub-province because of its indecisive geological relationship to the remainder of the Shield. Archean rocks are classed as such because; 1. they consist largely of vo1canics and illsorted sediments and when in contact with the less deformed (Algonkian Type) rocks are bound to underlie them unconformably. 2. the sediments approximate lithologically the younger Algonkian group, but are more strongly deformed. The purpose of this research is to render a summary of what is now known about the kinds and relative quantity of sediments comprising this ancient enigmatic rock assemblage. Time did not permit a more exhaustive examination of all reports published on these rocks; however, the writer believes the list of references of Appendix “A” (page 49) to be representative of that literature containing the better type of descriptive information. Thus, they are the basis of this thesis. It is hoped that paths of research as suggested subsequently will be of contributory value to our knowledge of the Archean. Rocks mapped as Archean today are merely the upended remnants of them. Erosion and peneplanation have exposed such deeply buried rocks that they are shown as usually isolated 3 linear belts in a huge composite mass of crystalline granitic rocks.[...]</description><creator>Black, Philip Thomas.</creator><contributor>O'Neill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>A study of Archean sediments of the Canadian Shield.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tj68g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x33h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w302</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main aim of this study was to determine the effects of hydrogen ions, and of bicarbonate and CO2 on the respiration and anaerobic glycolysis of brain tissue in vitro. Such an investigation is of interest since these substances are important components of tissue fluids, and are known to vary in concentration. Observations on the effects of pH and of bicarbonate and CO2 on aspects of in vitro metabolism might, therefore, aid in an understanding of their functions in vivo. Further, it is important to know precisely the effects of these factors in order to judge the validity of experiments in which these factors have varied. For instance, The pH control in many experiments in the literature was poor, and one needs to know how significant results may be. Similarly, it is common practice to compare results obtained in bicarbonate-and phosphate-buffered media, and the validity of these comparisons has been somewhat uncertain. Respiration in the biochemical sense, “tissue respiration”, means the sum of the processes whereby a tissue consumes oxygen in the combustion of various organic compounds. Respiration is the main source of energy for life processes. With brain tissue, glucose may be considered the predominant physiological substrate for respiration (Kety, Lukens, Woodford, Harmel, Freyhan and Schmidt, 1948; for earlier references see Elliott, Scott and Libet, 1942), and it was, therefore, added to all media in this work.[...]</description><creator>Birmingham, Marion K.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Medicine.</subject><title>Effects of pH and of Bicarbonateand CO2 on the Respiration and Anaerobic Glycolysis of Rat Brain Tissue.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh991.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w302</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tc50t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For many years the study of insect pathogens was not regarded as one of the duties of the entomologist. When insects became numerous and caused economic damage, they were combatted either with insecticides or by the introduction of parasitic or predaceous insects. The use of insecticides in the forest is not economical. Forest entomologists therefore resorted largely to the introduction and propagation of parasitic insects. Unfortunately, experience has shown, in many cases, that introduced parasites multiply too slowly to check current insect infestations. Insect pathogens multiply rapidly and at times contribute more to the control of insect pests than all other combined control factors. The control of the European spruce sawfly by disease created new interest in the possible use of insect pathogens in biological control. Relatively few insect diseases have been discovered. Those which are now known are the obvious cases. A study of any insect population probably would reveal one or more pathogens affecting it. This is being demonstrated as the result of the newly created interest and research in insect pathology. The discovery of an organism pathogenic to insects does not necessarily imply that it can be propagated and immediately disseminated in nature and effect control. This has been attempted too often in the past with disappointing results. Any program of artificial dissemination must be based on a thorough knowledge of the nature of the organism [...]</description><creator>Bird, F. T.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>A virus (Polyhedral) disease of the European spruce sawfly, Gilpinia hercyniae (Hartig).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds77m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc50t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290d80j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mechanism of headache has been studied physiologically by the neurosurgeon, whose conclusions have sometimes proved difficult to correlate with known anatomical facts. This is because of the relative paucity of knowledge concerning intracranial sensory nerves and nerve endings so that the interpretation of physiological investigations has depended to some extent on speculation. There are at present two main groups, one which would consider the pain of headache as mediated solely or almost entirely by periarterial nerves and receptors, the other which attributes to nerves within certain special locations of dura the chief role in pain conduction. The present study has approached the problem from two aspects, the first anatomical, special interest being taken in nerve endings in dura, the second clinical, observations on dural sensitivity in man. It has become apparent that both dural vessels and sinuses as well as certain cerebral vessels are pain - sensitive, but in addition that parts of dura itself are sensitive. Furthermore complicated corpuscular nerve endings demonstrated in dura suggest that afferents other than pain fibres leave the dura. These may play a part in reflexes which control vasomotor tone or even play a part in the regulation of intracranial pressure.</description><creator>Bird, Allan.</creator><contributor>Young, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Neurology.</subject><subject>Neurosurgery.</subject><title>Dural Nerve Endings and Dural Sensitivity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666794n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290d80j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67317231</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis does not attempt to trace British policy in Canada in the late eighteenth century, nor to discover the springs of that policy in other parts of the Empire or in Europe. It is only incidentally concerned with many of the statutes and ordinances pertaining directly to Canada, for their import was not always understood by the French-Canadians in the way that they were intended in London or even in Quebec; likewise, the military phases of the dispute between Great Britain and the American colonies, and even the invasion of Canada in 1775-76 have been most summarily treated. The vast volume of secondary material upon the late eighteenth century in Canada deals almost exclusively with these subjects, either justifying British policy, attacking it from the point of view of the modern French-Canadian, or attempting to reconcile these divergent views. Instead, this thesis attempts to disoover the effects of the transfer of authority from French to British hands, in so far as that transfer affected the population of Canada in 1760. It is thus primarily concerned with the reactions of one generation of French-Canadians to the substitution of British for French rule, and to the economic and social changes that they encountered as a result. The fact that these reactions were frequently negative or else rested upon an erroneous conception of the policy of the British government has often led to the conclusion that they were either negligible or non-existent. [...]</description><creator>Arthur, Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Adair, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>French-Canadians -- History.</subject><subject>Canada -- History -- 1763-1791.</subject><subject>Great Britain -- Colonies -- Administration.</subject><title>The French-Canadian under British rule, 1760-1800.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt59h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67317231</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021j29f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The rocks studied in this thesis have been the subject of considerable discussion as to their original nature. J. D. Bateman of the Geological Survey of Canada considers that they are of igneous origin whereas others believe that they are metamorphosed sediments. It was thought that a petrographical study might provide some information that would help to decide the problem and it was with this object in view that this study was undertaken. Cree Lake, in the vicinity of which the rocks occur, is situated 2 miles North of the Sherritt-Gordon Mine, Manitoba, which lies about 20 miles east of the Manitoba-Saskatchewan border and 120 miles northwest of the north end of L. Winnipeg. The Sherritt-Gordon copper-zinc ore deposit is a very remarkable deposit in that it is a tabular body with a total outcrop length of 16,000 feet and an average width of 15 feet, thus being one of the longest exposed ore bodies in the world. The rocks in question outcrop around Found Lake which lies very close to and just to the southeast of Cree Lake (see Map 44-4) and fall into two groups; firstly, thos that outcrop south of Found Lake in an area which was mapped by J. D. Bateman as an oval body of oligoclase granite (Map 44-4, No. 12) about one mile long and 1/4 mile wide and secondly, those that outcrop as three smaller masses north of Found Lake but enclosed by the arms of Cree Lake and mapped as anorthositic gabbro (Map 44-4, No. 11). [...]</description><creator>Antrobus, Edmund Shakerley Alexander.</creator><contributor>Kranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Metamorphic rocks.</subject><subject>Geology -- Manitoba -- Cree Lake.</subject><title>A Study of Lime-rich metamorphic rocks from Cree Lake, Manitoba.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z25n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021j29f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pk452</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The second world war greatly stimulated investigations on the preservation and use of blood. Numerous groups of workers directed their attention to this problem and rapidly improved methods of preservation and methods for following the survival of red blood cells after transfusion. By the end of the war these studies had advanced to a point where it was evident that further progress in the field of blood preservation could be achieved only through detailed studies of the enzymes, expecially of the formed elements, and the chemical changes that take place during preservation of the blood. The research which has continued in the department of Biochemistry at McGill University since January 1940 has been under the direction of Dr. O.F. Denstedt, and has covered numerous physical and chemical aspects of the preservation of the erythrocytes. It has been supported financially by the National Research Council of Canada, the Markle Foundation and the Baxter Company of Canada. The enzyme studies were begun in 1944 by Rocklin, who studied the glycolytic activity of the red cells. The work was continued the following year by Andreae, and later by Kwiecinska and Woodford. The results obtained, especially by the latter two workers, fit in well with the Meyerhof scheme, but there have been some interesting discrepancies with certain individual bloods. It was of interest, therefore, to investogate certain other enzyme systems, particularly the glyoxalase system [...]</description><creator>Alivisatos, Spyridon Gerasimo Anastasio A.</creator><contributor>Denstedt, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>Changes of the Glyoxalase Activity of Human Red Blood Cells During Storage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jh75k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk452</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b195k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il est bien connu que la réduction de l'entrainement de laitier pendant les operations de transfert de métal liquide inherent a la coulée continue d'acier améliore la propreté du métal. Les méthodes disponibles actuellement pour combattre cet entrainement occasionnent des pertes d'acier, a l'état liquide ou coulé. Le vortex est considéré comme une source majeure d'entrainement de laitier. La formation d'entonnoir d'entrainement de laitier en presence ou non de vortex a été etudiée et le role d'une couche supérieure d'huile a aussi été considéré. Les autres parametres indus dans cette étude sont Ie diamètre de la poche et du trou de coulée, le niveau d'eau initial dans la poche, ainsi que la longueur, la géométrie d'entrée, le coefficient de décharge et l'excentricité du trou de coulée.</description><description>The minimization of slag entrainment during the liquid metal transfer•operations inherent to the continuous casting of steel is known to result inenhanced metal cleanness. Measures currently available to combat suchentrainment entail considerable loss of yield of liquid, as well as cast, steel. Slagvortexing is considered a major source of such entrainment. Slag entraining funnelformation, under vortexing as well as non-vortexing conditions, in water ladleswere studied. The role of a supernatant layer of oil was also addressed. Otherparameters in the study included the diameter of the ladle and nozzle, the initialliquid head of water in the ladle, and the length, entrance geometry, dischargecoefficient and eccentricity of the nozzle.[...]</description><creator>Sankaranarayanan, Ramani</creator><contributor>Guthrie, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering.</subject><title>Modeling of Slag Entraining Funnel Formation ('Vortex') during liquid metal transfer operations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q033h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b195k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784p84j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is the most prevalent form of dementia and is a progressive neurodegenerative disease, characterized by extracellular amyloid-beta plaques, intracellular neurofibrillary tangles, and neuronal death. In Alzheimer's disease patients, atrophy occurs in regions of the brain involved in learning and memory, resulting in cognitive impairment. Late-onset AD (LOAD), 90-95% of cases, is a multifactorial disease, as seen by the many morphological changes in the brain. Familial AD is caused by mutations in the APP or presenilin (PSEN1 and PSEN2) genes. However, the cause of LOAD remains unknown. Several susceptibility genes have been identified and amongst these genes is cystatin C (CysC), a cysteine protease inhibitor. Meta-analysis studies have characterized CysC as a potential risk factor for LOAD. An allelic variant, allele B, has an alanine to threonine substitution in the signal peptide, which results in the switch of a nonpolar amino acid to a polar one, which alters the hydrophobicity profile of the signal sequence, causing impaired secretion of CysC. Furthermore, studies have revealed extremely CysC immunoreactive neurons, as well as activated glia in the cerebral cortex of AD patients. Also, in the most susceptible neurons, CysC protein accumulates in intracellular vesicles. In the brains of patients with AD, neuronal concentrations of CysC are elevated and co-localize with Aβ, depositing in extracellular Aβ plaques. CysC has been implicated in many other processes, including apoptosis regulation, cell proliferation, mitogenic activity, and cell survival/prevention of cell death. The identification and characterization of novel disease mechanisms and treatment targets are important in the field of AD in order to better understand disease etiology and aid the development of potential therapeutics. We hypothesize that CysC is involved in AD pathology and plays a key role in the progression of the disease. The objective of this study is to characterize the effect of CysC on the pathological hallmarks of AD. The results demonstrate that cystatin C is upregulated in the neuronal areas most susceptible to AD pathogenesis, the frontal cortex and the hippocampus of the 3xTg-AD mouse model. Furthermore, CysC causes apoptosis and does not attenuate APP toxicity in neuroblastoma cells. Interestingly, CysC results in the hyperphosphorylation of tau at the PHF-1 site in vitro, which is mediated by GSK3β. Additionally, Egr-1 regulates CysC in vivo, in both Egr-1 knockout and Egr-1 transgenic mice models. The results suggest that CysC may contribute to the pathology of AD. Further research into the mechanisms of CysC induction of apoptosis and tau phosphorylation may shed light on a possible therapeutic target through the inhibition of CysC. </description><description>La maladie d'Alzheimer (MA) est la forme la plus répandue de démence. Cette maladie neurodégénérative progressive est caractérisée par des plaques bêta-amyloïdes, des enchevêtrements neurofibrillaires et la mort de cellules. Chez les patients atteints de la maladie d'Alzheimer, l'atrophie se produit dans les régions du cerveau reliées à l'apprentissage et à la mémoire, ce qui entraîne des troubles cognitifs. La forme tardive de la maladie d'Alzheimer, soit 90-95% des cas, est une maladie multifactorielle, démontrée par les nombreux changements morphologiques dans le cerveau. La forme familiale de la maladie est causée par des mutations des gènes APP et preseniline (PSEN1 et PSEN2). Cependant, la cause de la forme sporadique de la maladie d'Alzheimer reste inconnue. Plusieurs gènes de susceptibilité ont été identifiés et parmi ceux-ci, nous retrouvons les gènes de cystatine C (CysC), des inhibiteurs de cystéine protéase. Or, des méta-analyses ont caractérisé CysC comme étant un facteur de risque potentiel pour la forme sporadique. Un variant allélique, l'allèle B, a une substitution de l'alanine à la thréonine dans le signal peptide, qui provient de la transformation d'un acide aminé non polaire à un acide aminé polaire. Ceci modifie le profil d'hydrophobicité de la séquence signal, provoquant l'altération de la sécrétion de CysC. En outre, des études ont révélé des neurones très immunoréactives au CysC et qui activent des cellules gliales dans le cortex cérébral de patients atteint de la maladie d'Alzheimer. De plus, dans les neurones les plus susceptibles, la protéine CysC s'accumule dans des vésicules intracellulaires. Dans le cerveau des patients atteint de la maladie d'Alzheimer, les concentrations de CysC neuronal sont élevées et co-localisées avec le peptide Aβ ainsi que du dépôt en plaques Aβ. CysC a été impliquée dans plusieurs autres procédés, dont : la réglementation de l'apoptose, la prolifération cellulaire, l'activité mitogène, et la survie des cellules/la prévention de la mort cellulaire. L'identification et la caractérisation de nouveaux mécanismes de maladie et les objectifs de traitement sont importantes dans le domaine de la recherche de la maladie d'Alzheimer afin de mieux comprendre l'étiologie de la maladie et faciliter le développement de thérapies potentielles. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que CysC est impliqué dans la pathologie de la maladie d'Alzheimer et joue un rôle important dans la progression de la maladie. L'objectif de cette étude est de d'analyser l'effet de CysC sur les caractéristiques pathologiques de la maladie d'Alzheimer. Les résultats démontrent que la cystatine C est augmentée dans les zones neuronales les plus susceptibles à la pathogenèse de la maladie d'Alzheimer, le cortex frontal et l'hippocampe. En outre, CysC provoque l'apoptose et n'atténue pas la toxicité APP. D'ailleurs, CysC joue un rôle dans l'hyperphosphorylation de la protéine tau dans le site PHF-1, qui est médié par GSK3β. Aussi, Egr-1 régule CysC en vivo. Les résultats suggèrent que CysC est impliqué dans la pathologie de la maladie d'Alzheimer et provoque la neurodégénérescence. De plus amples recherches sur les mécanismes d'induction de l'apoptose et de  la phosphorylation de tau de la CysC pourraient envisager la possibilité d'une cible thérapeutique par l'inhibition de CysC.      </description><creator>Marcellus, Kristen</creator><contributor>Hemant K Paudel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Elucidating the role of Cystatin C in Alzheimer's disease pathology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676z97b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784p84j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sk53g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: Le syndrome métabolique augmente le risque de maladies cardiovasculaires. Ces perturbations ont souvent une morbidité associée aux troubles de l'humeur, comme la dépression (MDD) et le trouble bipolaire (BP). Elles sont associées à un moins bon pronostic psychiatrique et une dépréciation fonctionnelle plus importante. L'hypothèse a été émise que l'adversité durant l'enfance est un facteur de risque commun pour les troubles métaboliques et les troubles de l'humeur. Cependant l'association précise entre l'adversité durant l'enfance, les troubles métaboliques et les troubles de l'humeur est encore inconnue.Objectifs: (1) Pour examiner l'association entre l'adversité durant l'enfance et les troubles métaboliques de l'hypertension artérielle, l'obésité abdominale, taux élevés de triglycérides, la glycémie à jeun élevée et peu de lipoprotéines de haute densité (HDL). (2) Pour tester si des types spécifiques d'adversité durant la petite enfance (abus, négligence, familles/ménages dysfonctionnels) et le type de trouble de l'humeur interagissent pour aggraver les résultats métaboliques.Méthodes: Ce fut une étude transversale de 68 patients ambulatoires adultes d'une clinique universitaire de soins des troubles de l'humeur avec une dépression telle que définie selon les critères du DSM-IV (N = 28) ou de trouble bipolaire de type I ou II (N = 40). Les critères cliniques définissant le syndrome métabolique  du programme national d'éducation du cholestérol (NCEP), Panel de Traitement pour Adultes III, ont été mesurés. L'adversité durant l'enfance a été mesurée à l'aide de l'auto-questionnaire sur l'expérience adverse durant l'enfance qui recueille les catégories d'adversité relatives à l'abus, la négligence et la dysfonction des familles/ménages. Les régressions linéaires et logistiques ajustées pour l'âge, le sexe et le niveau d'éducation ont été effectuées afin d'étudier l'association entre l'adversité durant l'enfance et les résultats métaboliques. Les analyses d'interaction ont été menées afin de tester si le type de trouble de l'humeur (troubles bipolaires versus dépression) a modifié l'effet de l'adversité durant l'enfance sur les résultats métaboliques.Résultats: Près d'un tiers (32,3%) de l'échantillon répondait aux critères pour le syndrome métabolique. En dépit de la majorité de notre échantillon étant en surpoids (IMC = 25-29,9), tous les autres résultats métaboliques étaient se situaient à un niveau normal. L'adversité durant l'enfance était très répandue dans l'échantillon des troubles de l'humeur, avec 80,9 % des participants ayant connu au moins une catégorie de l'adversité durant l'enfance. Les adversités durant l'enfance incluent l'exposition des ménages à la maladie mentale ou au suicide (45,6 %), la négligence affective (33,8 %), l'abus d'alcool et/ou de drogues (29,4 %), la violence psychologique (27,9%), la violence physique (25,0%), les abus sexuels (25,0 %), et la séparation ou le divorce des parents (23,5%). Plusieurs associations entre type d'adversité durant la petite enfance et les résultats métaboliques ont été trouvées. Tout d'abord, le divorce ou la séparation des parents a été associée à un IMC plus élevé (B = 3,3 ; p = 0,047). Cependant,  après ajustement pour l'âge, le sexe et le niveau d'éducation, le divorce ou la séparation des parents, cela n'était plus significatif. Deuxièmement, la négligence émotionnelle a été associée à une baisse de la pression diastolique du sang (B = -7,0 ; p = 0,043).Conclusion: Cette étude fournit des preuves préliminaires reliant le divorce ou la séparation des parents durant l'enfance et de la négligence émotionnelle à des facteurs de risque métaboliques tels l'IMC et la pression artérielle diastolique. L'évaluation systématique des expériences durant l'enfance, un suivi régulier des indices métaboliques et la promotion de saines habitudes de vie doivent être soulignés dans les soins cliniques de routine des personnes souffrant de troubles de l'humeur.</description><description>Background: Metabolic syndrome is a clustering of conditions that increases the risk for cardiovascular disease. These metabolic disturbances are often comorbid with mood disorders, such as depression (MDD) and bipolar disorder (BP), and are associated with poorer psychiatric prognosis and worse functional impairment. Childhood adversity has been hypothesized to be a common risk factor for both metabolic disturbances and mood disorder. However the precise association between childhood adversity, metabolic disturbances, and mood disorders is still unknown. Objectives: (1) To examine the association between childhood adversity and metabolic outcomes. (2) To test whether specific types of childhood adversity (e.g. abuse, neglect, and family/household dysfunction) and type of mood disorder interact to worsen metabolic outcomes.Methods: This was a cross-sectional study of 68 adult outpatients from a university-based, tertiary-care mood disorders clinic with a DSM-IV defined depression (N=28) or bipolar type I or II disorder (N=40). The National Cholesterol Education Program (NCEP) Adult Treatment Panel III clinical criteria for defining metabolic syndrome were measured. Childhood adversity was measured using the Adverse Childhood Experience self-report questionnaire which collects categories of adversity pertaining to abuse, neglect, and family/household dysfunction. Linear and logistic regressions adjusted for age, sex, and education were conducted to examine the association between childhood adversity and metabolic outcomes. Interaction analyses were conducted to test if type of mood disorder modified the effect of childhood adversity on metabolic outcomes.Results: Nearly one-third (32.3%) of the sample met the NCEP criteria for metabolic syndrome. Despite the majority of our sample being overweight (BMI = 25-29.9), all other metabolic outcomes were within a healthy range. Childhood adversity was highly prevalent in this mood sample, with 80.9% of the participants experiencing at least one category of childhood adversity. Childhood adversities included exposure to household mental illness/suicide (45.6%), emotional neglect (33.8%), alcohol/drug abuse (29.4%), emotional abuse (27.9%), physical abuse (25.0%), sexual abuse (25.0%), parental divorce/separation (23.5%), domestic violence towards mother (13.2%), physical neglect (2.9%), and imprisoned household member (1.5%). There were no statistically significant relationships between the total number of childhood adversities and the range of metabolic outcomes. Several associations between type of childhood adversity and metabolic outcomes were found. Firstly, parental divorce/separation was associated with a higher BMI (B = 3.3, p = 0.047), but after controlling for age, sex, and education, parental divorce/separation was no longer significant. Notably in interaction testing, type of mood disorder modified the effect of parental divorce/separation on BMI such that the association between parental divorce/separation and BMI was greater in the presence of BP versus MDD (B = -7.4, p = 0.016). Secondly, emotional neglect was associated with lower diastolic blood pressure (B = -7.0, p = 0.043). Conclusion: This study provides preliminary evidence linking childhood parental divorce/separation and emotional neglect to the specific metabolic risk factors of BMI and diastolic blood pressure. Systematic assessment of childhood experiences, regular monitoring of the metabolic indices, and promotion of healthy lifestyle habits should be emphasized in routine clinical care of individuals with mood disorders.</description><creator>Yung, Emily</creator><contributor>Nancy Low (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</subject><title>Childhood adversity and metabolic outcomes in adults with mood disorders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j216c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sk53g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g531</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In [Buell(1977)] and [Soleng(1994)], Buell and Soleng found explicit homomorphismsbetween the Mordell-Weil group of elliptic curves and the ideals class group of quadraticelds, which turn out to be essentially equivalent. After recalling the basic conceptsin the theories of quadratic forms, quadratic elds and elliptic curves, we prove thatSoleng's homomorphism can be obtained via a height pairing introduced by Mazur andTate [Mazur and Tate(1983)], under certain conditions. Then the technique developed inthe proof of this result is used to nd new homomorphisms. Examples of explicit computationsof the Mazur-Tate pairing are also given.</description><description>Dans les articles [Buell(1977)] et [Soleng(1994)], Buell et Soleng mettent en évidencedes homomorphismes explicites entre le groupe de Mordell-Weil des courbes elliptiques etle groupe des classes d'idéaux des corps quadratiques. Après avoir introduit les théories desformes quadratiques, des corps quadratiques et des courbes elliptiques, il sera démontré quel'homomorphisme de Soleng, qui est essentiellement équivalent à celui de Buell, peut êtreobtenu à l'aide d'un accouplement de hauteur dû à Mazur et Tate [Mazur and Tate(1983)].Par la suite, les idées rencontrées dans la preuve de ce résultat seront utilisées pour découvrirde nouveaux homomorphismes. Des exemples de calculs explicites de l'accouplement deMazur-Tate sont aussi donnés.</description><creator>Simard, Nicolas</creator><contributor>Henri Darmon (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics </subject><title>The Mazur-Tate pairing and explicit homomorphisms between Mordell-Weil groups of elliptic curves and ideal class groups</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j306.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g531</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fg099</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The principle of autonomy allows each person control over his or her body, and, consequently, to decide what medical treatment he or she will accept or refuse. However, where the individual does not have the ability, or capacity, to make such a decision, they may be subjected to medical treatment carried out in what a substitute decision-maker perceives to be their "best interests", which may not conform to their previous wishes that were reached autonomously. In order to preserve autonomy in the anticipation of a lack of capacity, individuals can formalise their health care plans in documents known as advance care directives. In many common law jurisdictions, the use of these types of documents is provided for by legislation. In this thesis I aim to review the legality of these directives where there is no legislation providing for their use, using Ireland as a case study, as the statutory law in Ireland is currently silent on this issue.I propose that the principle of autonomy which is protected under Irish law allows for the use of advance care directives without the need for legislation. I set out the criteria, as I see them, of a lawful advance care directive under Irish legal jurisdiction. I will address this issue by reviewing the Irish law in relation to the right to autonomy, the criteria for assessment of capacity, and health care decision-making, drawing on relevant examples from other common law jurisdictions.</description><description>Le principe d'autonomie permet à chacun de prendre les décisions relatives à son corps, et par conséquent, permet à l'individu de décider quel traitement médical accepter ou refuser. Toutefois, lorsque l'individu n'a pas la capacité de décider, il ou elle peut être soumis à des traitements médicaux qu'un décideur substitut considère être en son « meilleur intérêt ». Cette décision n'est pas nécessairement conforme aux désirs exprimés par la personne traitée alors qu'elle en avait la capacité. Pour préserver leur autonomie alors qu'ils en ont encore la capacité, certains rédigent un document appelé directive préalable de traitement. Dans plusieurs juridictions de « common law », ces directives font l'objet d'un cadre législatif. Cette thèse considère la légalité de telles directives dans les juridictions dépourvues d'un tel cadre législatif et utilise l'Irlande comme étude de cas parce que le droit statutaire irlandais ne se prononce pas sur les directives préalables de traitement.</description><creator>Veale Martin, Orla</creator><contributor>Margaret Somerville (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Advance care directives and medical treatment decision-making: preserving patient autonomy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j425f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fg099</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pr07c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Irrigation practices change the soil moisture in agricultural fields, and in turn influence the emissions of greenhouse gases. A two year field study was conducted to assess the emissions of CO2, CH4 and N2O from surface drip and subsurface drip irrigated tomato fields in Southwestern Ontario, Canada. Gas fluxes were obtained through the static chamber method, taking samples every 15 minutes over a one hour time period. Soil moisture and soil temperature were measured once per chamber per hour and used to help explain the gas emissions. A peak mean N2O flux at 405 µg N2O-N m-2 h-1 was observed from the five chambers in the surface drip irrigation treatment on July 8th, 2013, shortly following a rainfall event. Most N2O fluxes which occurred during the irrigated portion of the growing season were around 50 µg N2O-N m-2 h-1 in both treatments, water added here was less than some of the large rainfall where peaks occurred. Both the lowest CO2 mean treatment fluxes (12 mg CO2-C m-2 h-1) and highest (12 mg CO2-C m-2 h-1) were observed in the surface drip irrigation plots. Seasonal emissions of CO2 were significantly greater in surface drip plots than subsurface drip plots in 2013, but not in 2012, and this is likely attributed to soil temperature differences. Methane ¬fluxes were mainly negative, indicating that the soil is a sink, as opposed to a source for this gas. Generally, there was no significant difference in soil moisture between the types of drip system. Consequently, there were only a few days which showed significant differences between subsurface drip irrigation and surface drip irrigation treatments for the hourly collected gas fluxes throughout the two growing seasons. Overall, the use of subsurface drip irrigation or surface drip irrigation does not affect the emissions of greenhouse gases from the tomato fields in this study.</description><description>Les techniques d'irrigation affectent l'humidité du sol dans les terres agricoles, ce qui affecte les émissions de gaz à effets de serre. Une étude sur le terrain d'une durée de deux ans a été menée dans le sud-ouest de l'Ontario au Canada afin de déterminer les émissions de CO2, CH4 et N2O de champs de tomates irrigués au goutte-à-goutte de surface et au goutte-à-goutte souterrain. Les flux de gaz ont été obtenus en prenant des échantillons à chaque 15 minute pour une durée d'une heure, en utilisant la méthode de chambre statique. L'humidité et la température des sols ont été mesurés et utilisés afin d'expliquer les émissions de gaz. La moyenne de flux de N2O a atteint un sommet de 405µg N2O-N m-2 h-1 dans le cas de l'irrigation au goutte-à-goutte de surface, peu de temps après un épisode de pluie. La majorité des flux de N2O qui se sont produits pendant le moment de la saison utilisant de l'irrigation était d'environ 50 µg N2O-N m-2 h-1 dans les deux traitements. La plus faible (12mg CO2-C m-2 h-1) et la plus haute (123mg CO2-C m-2 h-1) moyenne des flux des traitements ont toutes les deux été observées dans les champs irrigués au  goutte-à-goutte de surface. Les flux de CH4 étaient principalement négatifs ce qui indiquent que les sols sont des puits, plutôt qu'une source de ce gaz. Une différence significative entre les flux des traitements a été démontrée seulement pour un nombre limité de jour parce que l'humidité des sols créée par les deux systèmes d'irrigation de goutte-à-goutte était similaire. Les émissions saisonnières de CO2 étaient significativement plus hautes dans le cas des champs irrigués au  goutte-à-goutte de surface que les champs irrigués au goutte-à-goutte souterrain en 2013, mais pas en 2012, ce qui est probablement dû aux différences dans les températures des sols. Globalement, l'utilisation de l'irrigation au goutte-à-goutte de surface ou de l'irrigation au goutte-à-goutte souterraine n'a pas d'effet majeur  sur les émissions de gaz des sols dans les champs de tomates. </description><creator>Edwards, Kerri</creator><contributor>Chandra A Madramootoo (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Agriculture - Soil Science</subject><title>Greenhouse gas emissions from drip irrigated tomato fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn561.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pr07c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763b14k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mining operations are highly affected by risk, where commodity price and geology can be considered as the most relevant ones, as they will define the pit's design and the operation's ability to meet production plans. Considering these uncertainties at an early stage is key for project success, and doing so by including managerial flexibility to annually re-evaluate the project allows a more realistic approach, and increases the operation's ability to react timely to change.The current study presents a real-option based evaluation approach to assess the effects of commodity price and geological uncertainty over the performance of a mining operation and the potential life of mine and consecutive pit limit modifications that may occur. The case study presented shows the value of flexibility when dealing with stochastic scenarios, in contrast with conventional evaluation methods. It was found that the stochastic method better assesses the project's potential to expand and provide useful information that traditional methods ignore. A Geometric Brownian motion with Poisson jumps model is used to forecast price, and direct block simulation is used to model geological uncertainty. The model was optimized using the commercial software ILOG-Cplex. Results show that including the option to stop mining, or expand increase the operation's value, but only if expensive infrastructure relocations are prevented, which makes it necessary to study these options at an initial stage, as they allow management to prepare for changes and provides a clearer image of the project's real potential.</description><description>Les opérations minières sont hautement affectées par les risques. Le prix des métaux et la géologie sont considérés comme ayant le plus d'impact puisqu'ils définissent le design de la mine et la capacité des opérations à atteindre les plans de production. La planification sous incertitude est utilisée pour créer un projet performant sous ces risques de sorte que les objectifs de production seront encore atteints. À cette fin, considérer de la flexibilité dans les opérations et dans la gestion ajoute un bénéfice important afin de répondre profitablement aux changements.Cette thèse présente une approche basée sur l'analyse par options réelles pour évaluer les effets de l'incertitude des prix des métaux et de la géologie sur les performances des opérations minières, la  durée potentielle de la vie de la mine et les modifications de la taille définitive du site d'excavation. L'étude de cas présentée montre la valeur qu'ajoute la flexibilité lorsque des simulations de géologie sont considérées, par opposition aux méthodes conventionnelles. Il a été constaté que la méthode présentée permet une meilleure évaluation du potentiel d'expansion du projet et fournie des informations importantes que les methodes traditionnelles ignorent. Les résultats montrent qu'inclure l'option d'arrêt ou d'expansion de la mine à chaque année augmente la valeur des opérations, mais seulement si les dépenses de relocalisation d'infrastructures importantes sont prévues. Ceux-ci rendent nécessaire l'étude de ces options dans une étape initiale puisqu'ils permettent aux gestionnaires de se préparer aux changements et produisent une meilleure vue du potentiel du projet.</description><creator>Del Castillo, Maria</creator><contributor>Roussos G Dimitrakopoulos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mining</subject><title>Effects of price and geological uncertainty over the life of mine and iltimate pit limit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zt826.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763b14k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kn877</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les expériences sociales positives autant que négatives peuvent influencer profondément les interactions sociales subséquentes. Les diamants mandarins sont extrêmement grégaires et les mâles et les femelles de cette espèce établissent des couples à long terme. De plus, les diamants mandarins femelles peuvent identifier les différents mâles en se basant uniquement sur leurs chants et, suite à un établissement de couple réussi, démontrent une préférence marquée pour le chant de leur mâle comparé au chant d'un mâle inconnu. Cependant, on ne sait pas si la qualité des interactions entre les individus des paires qui se sont accouplées peut influencer ces préférences de chants. Nous avons employé l'analyse vidéo des paires qui se sont accouplées pour évaluer la nature et la qualité des couples ainsi que les interactions sociales dans les couples établis. Ensuite, nous avons examiné si des différences dans les styles interactifs dans les paires étaient liées aux préférences comportementales et aux activités neuronales en réponse au chant du mâle. Nous avons trouvé que les comportements liés à l'état reproductif d'un couple (p. ex. un couple dans lequel le mâle est en voie de courtiser la femelle contre un couple qui se prépare pour la ponte des oeufs), mais pas les comportements indicatifs de la qualité d'un couple (p. ex. l'agglutination, le becquetage), étaient corrélés significativement avec le degré de préférence qu'une femelle démontre envers le chant du mâle. En outre, ces mêmes mesures d'état reproductif étaient aussi corrélées avec le niveau d'activité neuronale, qui est indiquée par l'expression du gène immédiat précoce EGR1 dans le noyau taenaie (NT) amygdalien et le niveau supérieur de la région auditoire du mésopallium médial caudal (MMC). Plus précisément, les femelles provenant des couples qui passaient plus de temps engagés dans la construction d'un nid et le chant non dirigé démontraient une expression d'EGR1 accrue dans le NT et le MMC contre les femelles provenant des couples où le mâle était plus engagé dans le chant dirigé pour courtiser la femelle. Ces données indiquent que, peut-être à travers les changements dans la physiologie endocrinienne, l'état reproductif pourrait moduler à la fois les préférences de chants et les activités neuronales.</description><description>Social experiences, both positive and negative, can profoundly influence subsequent social interactions. Zebra finches are highly gregarious songbirds and males and females of this species form long-term pair bonds. Moreover, female zebra finches can identify different males based solely on their song and, following successful pair-bonding, show strong preferences for the song of their mate over the song of an unfamiliar male. However, little is known about whether the quality of interactions between individuals in mated pairs can influence these song preferences. Here, we used video analysis of mated pairs to assess the nature and quality of pair bonds and social interactions in established pairs, then investigated whether differences in interactive styles among pairs were related to behavioral preferences and neural activity in response to the mate's song. We found that behaviors related to the reproductive stage of a pair (e.g. pairs engaged in courtship versus pairs preparing for egg laying) but not behaviors indicative of pair quality (e.g. clumping, pecking) were significantly correlated with the degree of female preference for her mate's song.  Furthermore, these same measures of reproductive stage were also correlated with the level of neural activity, as indicated the by expression of the immediate early gene EGR1, in the amygdalar region Nucleus Taenaie (NT) and the higher level auditory area the caudomedial mesopallium (CMM). Specifically, females from pairs that spent more time engaged in nest building and undirected singing showed greater EGR1 expression in the CMM and NT than females from pairs where males displayed more courtship singing. These data indicate that reproductive status, perhaps through changes in endocrine physiology, can modulate both song preferences and neural activity.</description><creator>Schubloom, Hannah</creator><contributor>Sarah Woolley (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Effects of pair bond quality on female physiology and behavior in the zebra finch «Taeniopygia guttata»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vm21k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn877</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h040p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the interest of exploring the hermeneutics of narrative identity in popular song lyrics, that is, the textual process by which a song's narrator imparts their story to the listener, this thesis examines a specific generic and temporal group of 'narrative' song lyrics against the branch of narrative theory relating to unreliable narration. Theories of unreliable narration have been selected as this study's key theoretical framework both because the area is central to contemporary literary studies (Nünning 2005: 2), and because, like song lyrics themselves, theories of unreliable narration problematize the notion of a unidirectional flow of meaning from the speaker/implied author to the reader/listener. Thoughtful, well-researched, highly literate (and often literary) lyrics are a central facet of the "indie music" genre's aesthetic. In this thesis I will therefore primarily focus on two of the indie music scene's most critically lauded lyricists, Colin Meloy of American indie-prog-rock band The Decemberists and John K. Samson of Canadian indie-folk-punk band The Weakerthans. Both Meloy and Samson's lyrics, I suggest, not only withstand such close critical scrutiny, but actually invite it. Demanding (and, arguably, enforcing) a new contract with the listener, Meloy and Samson's lyrics are representative of a larger shift in what an 'ideal' audience looks like in indie music, from casual listeners to an active (Schafer; Nancy), practiced, and critical audience. Engaging with a range of literary theoretical and musicological texts, the broad intentions of this project are to explore the formal complexities of first-person narration in contemporary indie song lyrics and to simultaneously diversify the potential scope for the application of theories of unreliable narration.</description><description>"Measure me in metered lines": Narration non-fiable et les herméneutes d'identité narrative dans les paroles de chansons 'Indie' contemporaines Dans l'intérêt d'explorer les herméneutes d'identité narrative dans les paroles de chansons populaires, c'est-à-dire le procès textuel par lequel le narrateur d'une chanson partage leur histoire avec l'auditeur, cette thèse examine un groupe de paroles narratives d'une convention de genre et de temporalité particulière, à l'encontre de théorie établie concernant la narration non-fiable. Des théories de narration non-fiable ont été sélectionnées en tant que cadre théorique principal, car ce domaine est central aux études de littérature contemporaine (Nünning 2005 :2) et car, comme les paroles elles-mêmes, les théories de narration non-fiable  rendent problématique l'idée de flux unidirectionnel du message transmis par l'orateur/l'auteur impliqué au lecteur/auditeur. Les paroles réfléchies, soutenues par de la recherche et littéraires sont primordiales à l'esthète du genre musical  indie. Donc, cette thèse ce concentre principalement sur deux des auteurs lyriques les plus célébrés de la scène indie : Colin Meloy de The Decemberists, un groupe américain de musique indie-rock-prog et John K. Samson de The Weakerthans, un groupe canadien de musique indie-folk-punk. Je propose que Meloy et Samson font plus qu'endurer l'examen critique minutieux de leur paroles et vont jusqu'à l'inviter. En demandant (et possiblement en l'imposant) un nouveau contrat avec l'auditeur, les paroles de Meloy et Samson sont représentationnelles d'un mouvement par lequel les auditeurs de musique indie « idéaux » se transforment d'écouteurs décontractés en écouteurs actifs (Schafer; Nancy), pratiqués et critiques.  Engageant dans une gamme de théorie littéraire et de textes de musicologie, les vastes intentions de ce projet sont l'exploration des complexités formelles des récits à la première personne dans les paroles de musique indie contemporaine et, également, de diversifier l'application des théories de narration non-fiable.</description><creator>Malloy, Bronwyn</creator><contributor>Erin Jane Hurley (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Literature - Modern</subject><title>"Measure me in metered lines": unreliable narration and the hermeneutics of narrative identity in contemporary 'Indie' song lyrics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc53g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h040p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838377k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:16:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The debate surrounding the legalization of physician-assisted suicide and euthanasia has seen the introduction of a number of new terms in recent years, the most well known among these being "death with dignity."  Proponents of legalization would claim that these terms help to illustrate the difference between the actions of terminally or incurably ill individuals and the actions of individuals who typically commit suicide: the former are acting rationally, while the latter are not, suggesting that "death with dignity" is a case of "rational suicide."Margaret Pabst Battin has suggested that five criteria need to be met in order for a suicide to be considered rational.  If it is indeed the case that individuals with terminal or incurable illness are acting differently than others who seek suicide, then it seems that these criteria ought to be met in cases of illness but not in other situations.  Upon analysis, however, this does not seem to be the case: individuals with terminal or incurable illnesses are not the only ones who can meet the criteria for rational suicide, and this will have consequences for the way that we treat the suicides of non-terminally or incurably ill individuals.  Further, some kind of adjustment period seems to be necessary in order to ensure that the criteria are indeed met before we allow access to "death with dignity."</description><description>Le débat autour de la légalisation de l'euthanasie et du suicide assisté par un médecin a vu l'introduction de plusieurs termes nouveaux au cours des dernières années, la plus connue parmi eux étant «mort avec la dignité.»  Les partisans de la légalisation prétendre que ces termes aident à illustrer la différence entre les actions des personnes qui souffrent des maladies qui sont terminale ou incurable, et les actions des individus qui commettent généralement suicide: l'ancien agissent de manière rationnelle, tandis que les dernières ne font pas the le même, suggérant que «la mort avec la dignité» est un cas de «suicide rationnel.»Margaret Pabst Battin a proposé que cinq critères doivent être remplies pour un suicide à être considéré rationnel.  Si c'est le cas que les personnes qui souffrent des maladies qui sont terminale ou incurable agissent différemment des autres qui cherchent suicide, il semble que ces critères doivent être remplies en cas de maladie, mais pas dans les autres situations.  Sur l'analyse, cependant, cela ne semble pas être le cas: les personnes atteintes de maladies terminales ou incurables ne sont pas les seuls qui peuvent répondre aux critères de suicide rationnel, ce qui aura des conséquences pour la façon dont nous traitons les suicides des autres personnes.  En outre, une sorte de période d'adaptation semble nécessaire afin de s'assurer que les critères sont bien remplis avant d'autoriser l'accès à «la mort avec la dignité.»</description><creator>Lyster, Caroline</creator><contributor>Kristin Voigt (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Philosophy, Religion And Theology - Philosophy</subject><title>Terminal illness and rational suicide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913t08c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838377k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12325</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>