<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:53:09Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):525" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr607</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents an indepth examination of the exegetical treatment of Qur'anic themes and concepts. It explains the process of communication between God and human beings by using communication models. The invisibility of God to human beings, coupled with His difference in nature, make their interaction difficult to conceive but not impossible. This thesis will thus seek to show how that interaction is feasible, making it as comprehensible as possible. Muslim theologians studied exhaustively the subject of God's speech and its nature without actually revealing its process in any detail or in systematic fashion. This thesis concludes that the theological differences have little bearing on God as a communicator. Finally, it demonstrates that the process of God-human interaction is entirely different from that of ordinary interpersonal communication.</description><creator>Ibrahim, Mohammed Zakyi.</creator><contributor>Boullata, Issa J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Communication -- Religious aspects -- Islam.</subject><title>Communication models in the Holy Qurʾān : God-human interaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk11m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr607</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m383b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Postmodernism, with its interrogation of reality and the im/possibility of representation, presented a legitimation crisis for the documentary which would potentially signal the end. Gauging by the renewed interest in the documentary tradition (in theory and practice) it is obvious that postmodernism had the reverse effect on documentary, freeing a filmmaking practice that had become hopelessly trapped within its own representational contradictions. In response to the challenge postmodernism presented, documentary theorists and filmmakers cleared a new space for documentary, and in the process reconsidered the limitations of Western epistemology and the ideal of 'representing reality'. This new space is reflected in the renewed interest in a new and more self-reflexive documentary theory and practice from the early 1980's onward. This essay will examine the transition which the documentary tradition has undergone in light of the shift from modernity to postmodernity: the shift from Grierson's heavily didactic social documentary to cinema verite and direct cinema and, finally, to the self-reflexive postmodern documentary. A textual analysis of Patricia Gruben's Leylines (1993), a recent postmodern documentary, will allow me to demonstrate how the contemporary documentary deals with the postmodern questions of history, representation, authority, knowledge, and subjectivity. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Gisler, Carolyn M.</creator><contributor>Kaite, Berkeley (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Gruben, Patricia -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Documentary films -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Revisioning the documentary tradition from within : Patricia Gruben's Leylines (1993)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v047.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m383b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz8061892</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The situation of the male characters in Anne Hebert's novels evolves, from Les Chambres de bois to L'Enfant charge de songes. The position of the male characters in relation to the female characters changes, as does their position in relation to physical and psychological space. The male characters gradually acquire greater liberty in the course of this evolution. Concretely, this means that the male characters free themselves, step by step, from the conflictual situation that determines their relations to the female characters and that they free themselves, at the same time, from a restrictive physical and psychological space. We will demonstrate that the evolution in the male characters' position in relation to the female characters and to space is realized simultaneously. When a significant change occurs in the male-female relation, it is accompanied by a similar change in the relation of the male characters to physical and psychological space. Starting from a doubly conflictual position (with relation to the female characters and to physical and psychological space), the male characters evolve, on both counts, towards what we call a harmonious state. This evolution is not, of course, linear; the male characters sometimes seem to hesitate. But still, we cannot deny that they progress, from one novel to the other, towards freedom.</description><creator>Gingras, Julie.</creator><contributor>Everett, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Hébert, Anne -- Characters -- Men.</subject><title>Situation du personnage masculin dans les romans d'Anne Hébert</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm89t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8061892</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h6489</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, "participatory development" has gained popularity in development circles. It has been recognized that participatory approaches in development programs and projects can help in meeting the conventional development objectives of economic growth and equity as well as more recent concerns of sustainability, good governance and democratisation. This is a qualitative study examines the theory and practice of people's participation in development programs and projects on a micro level. The objective study is to understand community participation structures in Barangay Lumangan, a village on the University of the Philippines in the Visayas (UPV) campus in Miagao, Province of Iloilo, Philippines. This is accomplished by assessing the depth and scope of peoples participation in the decision making, implementation and benefits acquisition in two development programs/projects: the Barangay Integrated Development Approach for Nutrition (BIDANI) and the Community-Based Health Care program (CBHP). An attempt is also made to assess the performance of an area-based development consortium (composed of a state university, government agencies and nongovernmental organizations) in strengthening local organizations within the context of the two development programs/projects they have setup. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Fernandez, Pepito R.</creator><contributor>Armstrong, Warwick (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Social participation -- Philippines -- Iloilo.</subject><subject>Community development -- Philippines -- Iloilo.</subject><subject>Political participation -- Philippines -- Iloilo.</subject><title>Understanding participatory development in Barangay Lumangan, Miagao, Iloilo, Philippines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw492.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h6489</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft438</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis summarily examines the concepts of moment, momentariness (ksanikavada) and impermanence (anitya) in Indian Buddhism, especially in the influential treatises produced by Vasubandhu (fifth century A.D.) An expose of impermanence and momentariness is at once a fair picture of the religious philosophy that mostly was Indian Buddhism--a religion appropriate on the philosophical level.</description><creator>Ferland, Eric.</creator><contributor>Hayes, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Causation (Buddhism)</subject><subject>Vasubandhu.</subject><subject>Impermanence (Buddhism)</subject><title>Impermanence et moments chez Vasubandhu</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pj32s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft438</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk81g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Outre-amer is a collection of short stories set in a contemporary Quebec society and depicting events in the genealogy of a family doomed with mythological predispositions. Intertextuality is an important aspect of Outre-amer, since the stories are independent from one another, while linked together by various themes, clues and details which carry enigmas beneath the surface of the stories from one end of the collection to the other. Thus, it is suggested to read the stories in a chronological order. Etude du dialogue dans Nouvelles de J. D. Salinger studies the conversational aspect of the prose of the American author J. D. Salinger. It reflects on the importance and the role of dialogues within a short story, as well as their scriptural representation and mimetic function. The article investigates the French translation of two short stories which are part of Nine Stories. It analyzes the particularities of the translated dialogues compared to those of the original version, and questions the critical validity of a text in translation. The study raises and discusses issues related to the process of translation towards French and denounces the French translator's ethnocentrical approach towards the American text: in this case, the French language and culture assimilate Salinger's stories, thus altering the poetics of the text in translation.</description><creator>Dessureault, Jacinthe.</creator><contributor>Chapdelaine, Annick (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Salinger, J. D. (Jerome David), 1919- Nine stories.</subject><title>Outre-amer ; et, Etude du dialogue dans Nouvelles de J.D. Salinger</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v05h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk81g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n0676</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the transformation in the representation of painters during Charles LeBrun's tenure as Life-Chancellor to the Academie Royale de Peinture et de Sculpture, from an initial definition in terms of the monarchy at Versailles to one founded on the practice of the art of painting. To promote the status of painters and painting, Louis XIV was celebrated as the protector of the arts in a royal portrait by Henri Testelin and was depicted as the ideal subject of art in paintings by Nicolas Loir and others. A painter's stature was then derived from the skillful manner in which he painted the history of the King. Engraved portraits accompanied by verse of Charles LeBrun and Adam Frans Van der Meulen identify allegorical painters as more distinguished than those who painted in a natural style. In both cases, Louis XIV is posited as being the source, subject, and eloquence of the art celebrating his achievements. Nicolas de Largillierre's Portrait of Charles Lebrun is modeled on Testelin's royal portrait and offers a portrayal of the artist which advocates service to the monarchy, but it grounds aesthetic activity in the body of the painter. This conception of LeBrun, in turn, serves as a paradigm for Pierre Mignard to create a self-portrait that proclaims his status in relation to the art of painting rather than through service to the King.</description><creator>Dupuis, Matthew.</creator><contributor>Glen, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Painters in art.</subject><subject>Le Brun, Charles, 1619-1690.</subject><title>Charles Lebrun : painting the king and the king of painting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp742.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n0676</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz55b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Uncharted Lands" is a collection of three short stories, each of which could be described as ethnic but should be considered Canadian. The Afterword explains why, examines the process of writing ethnicity through memory, and explores the position of ethnic minority literature in the evolution of Canadian culture.</description><creator>Denesiuk, Tania L.</creator><contributor>Lecker, Robert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Ethnicity in literature.</subject><title>"Uncharted Lands"</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r756r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz55b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fq82n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The remarkable challenges Finnegans Wake offers to its readers and to the very process of reading are the results of an evolution of Nonsense literature. Despite the unduly "serious" framework of criticism which has been built up around it, Joyce's anomalous last work is a radical "hoax" upon interpretation. The regular confluences of linguistic deconstruction (via word association as well as recurring word and phrase matrices) and ontological metaphor, developed from authors such as Rabelais, Sterne, and Lewis Carroll, are offered by the Wake as tests to the reader's (qua reader) sensibilities. As Nonsense, Finnegans Wake departs from typified modernist modus operandi (metonymic allusion) and instead explores the limits of metaphor. The stakes of Joyce's hoax are of vital interest to the contemporary student of literature and culture, since the Wake dares the reader to find new meanings rather than to project old ones; to exult its eccentricities and its difference; and all the while to call into question (as the text itself does), its authenticity and authority.</description><creator>Conley, Tim.</creator><contributor>Cope, Karin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Joyce, James, 1882-1941. Finnegans wake.</subject><title>The hoax that joke bilked : sense, nonsense, and Finnegans wake</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz580.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq82n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c022f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since Homer, exile is closely linked to literature and even seems to be consubstancial to the very act of writing. Indeed, countless writers have created in exsilio; one just has to think, among others, of Marot, Du Bellay, Madame de Stael, Victor Hugo or Soljenitsyne. The unbearable feeling of loss and relinquishment provoked by transhumance added to the inevitable solitude are determining factors leading to the creative process. Neo-Quebecois writers are undoubtedly part of this line of expatriate authors. Often autobiographical in nature, their work generally describe the migratory journey of misfits trying to make Quebec culture their own. However, it is difficult to be a foreigner in a society which is asserting its own identity, in this case quite problematic, and the passage from outsider to insider is even more so. In this thesis, the idea of transculturation conceptualised by Fernando Ortiz as well as the Freudian concept of unheimlich (uncanniness) will be applied to the works of Regine Robin, Emile Ollivier, Ying Chen, Sergio Kokis and Mona Latif-Ghattas. The object of this essay is to demonstrate that writing is in fact the sole means for the protagonists to reach a total introjection of space and to find order in the scattered components of their fragmented identity.</description><creator>Charbonneau, Caroline.</creator><contributor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Canadian literature -- Québec (Province) -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Authors, Exiled -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Québec (Province) -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><title>Exil et écriture migrante : les écrivains néo-québécois</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s439n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c022f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m37x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An examination is made of important influences that shaped both the development of Plato's religious and philosophical teachings/theories of the Soul and Spirit which were based on core Spiritual Laws or Principles, and his scheme of education as outlined in the Republic. Included are Plato's early years and the teachings and influence of Socrates and the Orphic, Pythagorean and Eleusinian Mystery Schools. Plato's system of education is shown to be very much influenced by the Pythagoreans, to involve the 'Principle of Initiation' and to be soul-centered, where all thought is related to 'The One'. The conclusion is that the philosophy and teaching of education today tends to ignore the important integrative principle of unity--the Soul/Spirit connection. A renewed philosophy and scheme of education is introduced incorporating a vision of the whole person.</description><creator>Brooks, Barbara Honey.</creator><contributor>Smith, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Mysteries, Religious.</subject><subject>Plato -- Contributions in education.</subject><subject>Education -- Philosophy.</subject><title>An examination of the influence of Socrates and 3 ancient mystery schools on Plato, his future theories of the soul and spirit, and system of soul-centred education as portrayed in his Republic with educational implications for today /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z292n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m37x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j314q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of the thesis presented herein is to provide an overview of current issues in auditory display design and to suggest how these issues may be applied to the development of applications for the World Wide Web (WWW). The software developed as part of this thesis, the SprocketPlug plug-in for Netscape Navigator, provides a tool for exploring various auditory display techniques at three levels of WWW development: HTML, Javascript, and Java. The strength of SprocketPlug is that it enables WWW developers to incorporate interactive spatialized sound as an integrated component of WWW documents and applications. The implementation of SprocketPlug is based on currently available technology: the Netscape plug-in architecture, Netscape LiveConnect, and the Apple SoundSprocket.</description><creator>Breder, Elijah.</creator><contributor>Pennycook, Bruce (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>World Wide Web.</subject><title>Towards the sonification of the World Wide Web : SprocketPlug</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m6083.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j314q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mr86m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Maupassant's writings suggest that the monde, demi-monde and brothels, usually conceived as entirely different universes, resemble each other. They are imperfect copies, which can be mistaken for one another. The characters moving in these worlds are essentially false, hypocritical and superficial beings, prisoners of a role which forces them to play a comedy in society. Some adopt to perfection the values and conventions attached to their role, to the extent of no longer differentiating the true from the false, and forgetting their identity. As the distinction between appearances and reality disappears, the boundaries between the milieux become unclear. Do they exist? Have the boundaries arbitrarily been drawn to preserve social order? If Maupassant implicitly asks these questions, he does not provide an answer. His attitude towards social comedy is rather ambiguous. Though he makes fun of the latter, emphasizing its absurdity and ridicule, he does not condemn it. Spectator and actor of this vast comedy, Maupassant stays detached: of course life is only a game, but why not play it?</description><creator>Boucher, Marie-Violaine.</creator><contributor>Duquette, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Society in literature.</subject><subject>Prostitution in literature.</subject><subject>Maupassant, Guy de, 1850-1893 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Monde, demi-monde, maisons closes : la comédie sociale chez Maupassant</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn47n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr86m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx15b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Exile is a recurring theme in the writing of Antoine de Saint-Exupery; this master's thesis examines three forms--physical, psychological, symbolic--this leitmotif takes. The first chapter includes a review of Exuperian criticism and a discussion of the concept of exile; it also outlines the three critical approaches which frame our study of exile in the second chapter. Our analysis of "physical" exile borrows from the sociohistorical approach of "exile literature" to examine the portrayal of aviation as a world apart in Terre des hommes and Vol de nuit. We turn to feminist rereadings of Lacanian psychoanalysis to assist us in addressing "psychological" exile, which presents itself in the Lettres a sa mere as a constant conflict between the freedom of childhood and the restraints of adulthood. Finally, we examine "symbolic" exile, which arises from the failed relationships of women and men in Courrier sud, in the light of the Anglo-American concept of "gender".</description><creator>Biela, Stephan.</creator><contributor>Everett, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Saint-Exupéry, Antoine de, 1900-1944 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Exiles in literature.</subject><title>Vers une typologie de l'exil exupérien</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r67d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx15b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v699</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the challenge posed to post-imperial British identity by the rise of Scottish political nationalism and its voice the Scottish National Party (SNP) from the late 1960s to 1980. With the ultimate decline of the British Empire in the decades following the Second World War, Britishness, which had been forged through the imperial experience, was fundamentally challenged by older national identities within the United Kingdom. Scottish nationalism was one of these identities which had been subsumed by an imperial British identity for over two hundred years. A combination of the collapse of the industry of empire in Scotland, relative economic deprivation in the 1960s and 1970s, and other Scottish political grievances prompted increased support for the SNP. Scots, viewing themselves as a nation and as distinct in many ways from the rest of the United Kingdom, reacted to the decline of the British unitary state and encouraged the growth of Scottish political nationalism. The political success of the SNP in the late 1960s and 1970s forced the main Westminster parties to address the issue of Scottish nationalism and Scots' sense of alienation from the centre of power. The Royal Commission on the Constitution and the resulting debate over devolution in the late 1970s, prompted by the growth of nationalism, represented the greatest challenge to the legitimacy of the United Kingdom since the Treaty of Union of 1707.</description><creator>Bennett, Andrew Peter Wallace.</creator><contributor>Lewis, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1945-</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Scotland -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Scottish National Party.</subject><title>20th century Bannockburn : Scottish nationalism and the challenge posed to British identity, 1970-1980</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vm96c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v699</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn48x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Proustian aesthetics, the act of reading constitutes a fundamental activity in the elaboration of Remembrance of Things Past. The representation of each art form which the novel proposes to synthesize (architecture, painting, and literature) is based on intertextual relationships that unite texts from non literary (Ruskin, Male), literary (Sand, Sevigne, Racine) and philosophical (Schopenhauer) sources, that contribute to a general conception of art that reintegrates the problem of the reception of art works in the context of an essentially literary experience. In accordance with Hans-Robert Jauss' theory, the presence of such texts enables the reconstitution of the reader's expectations, and provides the context for the multiple representations of the work of art. Consequently, the implicit and explicit interrelations between the Proustian text and its intertext, perceived as an indication of the readers liberty, introduce different strategies of reading into the novel. Not only does the narrative, through its characters, offers a series of examples that are didactic in nature, but the use of quotations creates dynamics that underscores the specificity of the Proustian act of reading and its interdependence on the act of writing. The reception of the text implied by the Proustian reading of the work of art therefore contributes in making Remembrance of Things Past, not a dogmatic exposition of a theory, but rather a long quest through literary creation for knowledge that transcends Plato's idea of the transmission of meaning through art and of communication through the act of reading.</description><creator>Barr, Philippe.</creator><contributor>Lane-Mercier, Gillian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Art in literature.</subject><subject>Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922.</subject><title>La lecture de l'oeuvre d'art chez Marcel Proust /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br48s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn48x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t763</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Menstruation is all at once a cultural, social, historical, and biological process. Intertwined, these forces create menstrual experiences which are neither fixed nor universal, but rather adaptable and transformable not only between cultures, but from within cultures as well. How these factors interrelate, what menstrual discourse they create, and how that translates into women's everyday lives, becomes the focus of this research. Structured around the relationship between prescription and reality, this study examines the interplay of those who defined the menstrual discourse: doctors, mothers, and the sanitary napkin industry, and those who experienced it. Listening to the lives of twenty-four women, born between 1910 and 1965, a complex and ambiguous tale of the menstrual experience emerges. Through their narratives, we learn the importance of early instruction by mothers; the emphasis placed on hygiene and concealment; the effect menstruation had on women's sexual, feminine, and (re)productive identity. Once women's voices are taken into consideration, it becomes clear that the dynamic between prescription deeming menstruation as unclean or deviant and women's reality is not straightforward. Women reacted to the menstrual discourse, at times they rejected it, other times adhered to it, but for the most part, simply transformed it to meet their daily needs.</description><creator>Armeni, Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Morton, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Advertising -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Menstrual cycle -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Women -- Health and hygiene -- Social aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Menstruation goes public : aspects of womens's menstrual experience in Montreal, 1920-1975</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx845.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t763</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs49t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Atherosclerotic narrowing of the carotid arteries in asymptomatic individuals is associated with an increased risk of cerebrovascular ischemic events. The prevention of stroke in this context requires an understanding of the natural history of cerebrovascular atherosclerosis and the availability of an effective means for the detection and follow-up of carotid stenosis. Methodological standards for the conduct and reporting of natural history studies of asymptomatic carotid disease are proposed and used to carry out a structured methodological appraisal of the literature. The findings suggest that greater attention should be paid to the design and statistical analysis of natural history studies. A secondary analysis of the data from a natural history study of asymptomatic carotid disease is undertaken for the purpose of evaluating the prognostic usefulness of repeated duplex ultrasound examinations. Multivariable Cox proportional hazards models with fixed and time-dependent covariates are used to evaluate the predictive ability of carotid stenosis measurements obtained by duplex ultrasound at enrollment and during follow-up. The results of the analysis do not support the use of routine carotid ultrasound in clinical practice to determine prognosis for unselected patients with asymptomatic carotid disease.</description><creator>Lewis, Rosamund F.</creator><contributor>Abrahamowicz, Michal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>The prognostic utility of ultrasound in asymptomatic carotid disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010s14k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs49t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rn290</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis we examine the possible causes of the model-to-model variability observed in the Comparison of Mesoscale Prediction and Research Experiments (COMPARE). A series of sensitivity experiments is performed involving changes to model initial conditions, physical parameterizations, and numerics. Secondary cyclogenesis is most sensitive to latent heat release and moisture fluxes from the ocean surface. Initial differences are found to decay with time, and more rapidly so, in a 'dry' simulation. Sea-level pressures for the low center are lower in integrations with a longer time step, owing to greater rainrates and low-level diabatic heating at the storm center from 12 to 18 h. Moisture fluxes in the first 12 h are crucial in creating grid-box saturation for initiation of precipitation, and the generation of a low-level potential vorticity maximum, with fluxes during the subsequent 24-h period of rapid deepening not as crucial. A westward storm track bias in COMPARE is related to a more robust low-level potential vorticity maximum along the coast, as compared to the maximum offshore.</description><creator>Carrera, Marco.</creator><contributor>Gyakum, John R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Zhang, Da-Lin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Variability in the simulation of a case of secondary cyclogenesis with a mesoscale model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk91z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn290</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv627</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The relationship between Arctic sea ice concentration anomalies, particularly those associated with the "Great Salinity Anomaly" of 1968-1982, and atmospheric circulation anomalies is investigated. Empirical orthogonal function (EOF) analyses are performed on winter and summer sea ice concentrations, sea-level pressure, 500 hPa heights and 850 hPa temperatures: these data cover the Northern Hemisphere north of 45$ sp circ$N during the post-World War II era. Spatial maps of temporal correlation coefficients between EOF 1 of winter sea ice concentration and the atmospheric anomaly fields are calculated. Significant correlations (at 95 and 99% levels) were found to exist between EOF 1 of winter sea ice and the atmospheric anomaly fields at zero lag, and with ice leading by one and one-and-a-half years, and ice lagging by one year. The main emphasis of the thesis is to identify connections between Arctic sea ice and atmospheric circulation anomalies at interannual timescales.</description><creator>Slonosky, Victoria C.</creator><contributor>Mysak, L. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Derome, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Arctic Sea ice and atmospheric circulation anomalies since 1954</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk13x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv627</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n987d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this thesis are to identify key safety concerns related to the introduction of automated underground mining machines. Second, a synthesis of existing standards, and guidelines is required to identify what existing safety standards or parts of standards could apply to mining machine automation systems. Finally, a framework is required for the development of a safety standard or guideline for automated mining machine systems. Two workshops were organized and facilitated by the author to document as many identified safety concerns as possible from a range of parties with a vested interest. Workshop participants included mine operators, automated mining equipment suppliers, safety professionals, students, and academics. In addition, an analysis of underground mining equipment accidents for the province of Ontario was completed. A review of European, and North American safety standards was performed to identify those safety standards which could be used for mining machine automation systems. A synthesis of applicable safety standards is provided. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Atkinson, Glenn.</creator><contributor>Scoble, Malcolm (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><title>Automated mining machine safety investigation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs90x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n987d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w940b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores five documents written by Tagore between 1906 and 1940. Tagore was writing at a time when India was struggling for independence. Among his numerous concerns, he wanted an India which could be compassionate and humane. He realized that such a lofty goal could only be achieved through an education system which not only encouraged these qualities but allowed students to cultivate them by understanding the world around them. Central to the arguments in this thesis is Tagore's discussion of the tapobon, the Indian meditative forest. The tapobon is seen as metaphorical place for contemplation in deciphering the world and developing an understanding of one's place in it. The documents examined here reflect the breadth and depth of Tagore's thoughts on education though they are only a sampling of the extensive work he did in his lifetime.</description><creator>Dhar, Suranjita Nina.</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Education -- India.</subject><subject>Tagore, Rabindranath, 1861-1941 -- Views on education.</subject><title>Rabindranath Tagore's thoughts on education from a socio-political perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1394012.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w940b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr1720248</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Intercountry adoption (ICA) is growing in controversy as it grows in popularity. While heart-warming stories of families with babies from abroad dominate the media coverage on this subject, this represents only a small segment of the entire situation. Using Korea and China as case examples, this thesis extensively reviews and analyzes policy and the cultural, social, economic and political layers of the ICA mechanism from a political-economy perspective and argues that children are treated as commodities in both supplying and receiving countries. ICA is used by governments to solve internal social problems while promoting international relations. The thesis concludes that only a small number of children and parents actually benefit from ICA and the majority of persons involved--unadopted children in both countries, birth parents and some adoptive applicants--do not gain from ICA and may actually experience suffering as a result of it.</description><creator>Penner, Erica E.</creator><contributor>Baker, Maureen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Intercountry adoption -- Korea (South)</subject><subject>Intercountry adoption -- China.</subject><title>Comparative analysis of international child adoption practices and policies in Korea and China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b38q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1720248</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j0932</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study argues that there is an essential unity to John Donne's poems and sermons. Chapter One is a survey of Donne criticism: Ilona Bell suggests Donne "seeks communion, but is continually prepared to recognize disjunction." It is argued that Bell's notion is validated in both genres where Donne renders concrete a movement of thought or emotion through figurative language. Chapter Two examines how the sermons move between the literal sense of scripture, and its multiform spiritual significance. Chapter Three examines the writerly tradition of the Church Fathers in relation to some of Donne's poetry. Augustine read the bible as a unified entity, The Word, and yet understood it through manifold meanings. Donne writes of the union of lovers' souls, yet weaves in the theme of inconstancy and separation. In sum, this study discusses how Donne's creation of figurative meaning produces both his literary intensity, and some parallels of spiritual discovery in his poems and sermons.</description><creator>Bishop, Scot.</creator><contributor>Conway, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Donne, John, 1572-1631 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Donne, John, 1572-1631 -- Religion.</subject><title>John Donne's poetry and sermons : some parallels in spiritual discovery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032496h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j0932</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g469c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One-atmosphere melting experiments have been performed on two shoshonitic basalts; SO-1 and SO-20; (14 and 9 wt.% MgO, respectively) and an olivine nephelinite HF-13 (11 wt.% MgO), at different oxygen fugacities (NNO+1, NNO, and FMQ), with temperature varying from super-liquidus (1300$ sp circ$C) to near-solidus (1075$ sp circ$C) conditions. The experimental results reveal that iron-oxide crystallization depends strongly on oxygen fugacity, and that their precipitation drives residual liquids towards silica enrichment. Residual liquids obtained from SO-1 and SO-20 reached a maximum of 64 wt.% SiO$ sb2$ for olivine, clinopyroxene, plagioclase and iron-oxide saturated melts at NNO+1, and 59 wt.% SiO$ sb2$ for olivine, clinopyroxene and plagioclase saturated melts at FMQ. The experimental liquids produced from HF-13 reached a maximum of 48 wt.% SiO$ sb2$ at NNO and NNO+1 for iron-oxide, olivine and clinopyroxene saturated melts, however no variation in SiO$ sb2$ concentration was observed for olivine and clinopyroxene-saturated melts at FMQ.</description><creator>Guernina, Souad.</creator><contributor>Baker, Don R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Geology.</subject><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>An experimental study of the effect of Fe-Ti oxide crystallization on basaltic liquids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw456.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g469c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):550</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>