<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:39:34Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39150" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pf75g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the state of Islamic law in the modern context as perceived by the Muslim scholar Abdullahi an-Na`im, assessing its suitability for contemporary society, with particular emphasis upon its relationship to international human rights standards. The first part of this work reviews the impact of the nation-state upon the current international structure and then considers Islamic law as it was classically conceived and developed. The focus of this discussion addresses the importance of clear and definite texts in the Qur'an and the roles of ijtihad and naskh in us&amp;dotbelow;ul al-fiqh, exploring the dimensions of flexibility and change allowed in this system. The second part involves an investigation of the development of international human rights standards and provides an appraisal of their authority and validity by which the Shari'a is today judged. The areas in the Shari'a that are seen to conflict with these modern standards, specifically the status of women and non-Muslims, and criminal punishment, are examined. Finally, the methodology for the reform of Islamic law proposed by an-Na'im is then evaluated, with due consideration given to the importance of hermeneutics and historical context. The value given to the difference between the Meccan and Medinan verses for the construction of a new understanding of the Qur'an within the framework of legal methodology is presented, as are the methodological tools that an-Na'im employs for modern legal reform.</description><creator>Erwin, Courtney Paige.</creator><contributor>Hallaq, Wael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>An-Na'im, Abdullahi.</subject><subject>Human rights -- Religious aspects.</subject><subject>Islamic law.</subject><title>Islamic law and modernity : Abdullahi an-Naim's proposal for reform</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q5968.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pf75g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md654</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The focus of this paper will be revolutions as a Third World phenomena. It will try to analyse what are the conditions and challenges faced by Third World states; and what are the functions that those states perform, or fail to perform. In other words, what are the conditions likely to lead to a revolution within Third World nation-states? Of course, every Third World state possesses its particular circumstances and, therefore, different factors will influence the occurrence of a revolution in each case. It would be presumptuous of me to attempt to address all of these issues which have been raised. My task is indeed more modest. Since it is very unlikely to elaborate a single theory that will fit all cases, this paper will rather consider a theoretical framework and assess its applicability and its explanatory potential of one Third World revolution, the Nicaraguan revolution. What this paper will also do is to examine what happens when a successful revolution has taken place. How is the new regime constructed? How is the power of the revolutionary government employed? Can we assess the relative success of a revolution? The use of a single case study, Nicaragua, can be explained by the richness of this particular example. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Dugal, Zoe.</creator><contributor>Noumoff, Sam J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Revolutions -- Nicaragua.</subject><subject>Nicaragua -- History -- Revolution, 1979.</subject><title>The illegitimacy of the state and the revolution in Nicaragua /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z261.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md654</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602266n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research presents new audio creation and processing tools for the virtual electronic music studio. The Tools were created by the author in the Max/MSP authoring environment. Some Tools model analog production techniques lost when studios moved inside computers, and provide additional functionality only possible in the digital world. Others make use of traditional processing ideas but add a level of control difficult to find in today's audio software plug-ins. The Tools are small, simple, real-time, and user-controllable devices for working with sound.</description><creator>Davies, Robin, 1975-</creator><contributor>Depalle, Philippe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Computer sound processing</subject><title>Toolkit : specialized software tools for electronic music composition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw30b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602266n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3013162</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phenomenon of female teenage violence within the last decade has been receiving rapid social interest and concern. The present study is concerned with exploring causes for teenage girl violence. Specifically, this qualitative study seeks to explore and describe teenage girl violence from the experiences and perspectives of girls aged 16 to 19 years of age whom have been in the past arrested and/or incarcerated for violent crimes. Data was collected using a semi-structured interviewing format. Five teenaged girls having current or past involvement with the Child Welfare system were interviewed. Despite the study's limitations, findings indicated several variations on similar common themes. These themes are discussed using three main categories of findings: (1) entrance into the legal system, (2) social aspects and (3) cultural presence. The need for describing and understanding why teenage girls act out violently in the ways they do was evident from the perspective of the girls themselves.</description><creator>Oliver-McFarlane, Cheryl.</creator><contributor>Wright, Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Female juvenile delinquents -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Teenage girls -- Canada -- Social conditions.</subject><subject>Aggressiveness in adolescence.</subject><subject>Violence in adolescence.</subject><title>What is causing teenage girls to act out violently? : a qualitative perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365704w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3013162</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc957</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study analysed why children under four years old were admitted to care, and whether they suffered harm due to abuse or neglect, based on file documentation regarding all 175 admissions, involving 129 children and 93 mothers, by one Ontario Children's Aid Society between 1992 and 1996. Using the Ontario Child Welfare Eligibility Spectrum to classify reasons for admission, more admissions were due to risks defined under Caregiver Capacity than Harm by Commission or Omission. Mothers' background and lack of resources were common factors. Evidence of harm was often hard to establish but was rated as clear or extreme in 12% of cases. Differences related to fathers' status, number and age of children in the home, and history of agency involvement were found between cases where children suffered severe harm due to abuse or neglect, and cases where they did not, but these differences were not statistically significant.</description><creator>Murphy, Lorenzo.</creator><contributor>Duder, Sydney (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Preschool children -- Ontario -- Risk assessment.</subject><subject>Child welfare -- Ontario -- Risk assessment</subject><subject>Social case work with children -- Ontario.</subject><title>Reasons for the admission to care of preschool children using the Ontario Eligibility Spectrum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq34q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc957</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx29f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ninety-six child protection files were scrutinized according to the Holland Complex Care Case Review Data Collection Instrument in order to verify the applicability of the instrument to determined the variables influencing social workers in the determination of bringing an adolescent in need of protection into care. Results show that school related issues seem to influence workers in determining the need to remove the child from the family. Statistical analyses indicated numerous correlations supporting the link between case complexity and the need to bring an adolescent into care.</description><creator>Tripp, Lisa M.</creator><contributor>John, Lyndsay (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Social case work with teenagers.</subject><subject>Child welfare -- Ontario -- Decision making</subject><title>A study to determine what variables may increase the risk of an adolescent coming into the care of the Children's Aid Society /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d178t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx29f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k45r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite calls for increased attention to religion and spirituality in social work education and practice, the topic remains a neglected area. This small exploratory study seeks to examine barriers that cause religion and spirituality to continue to be on the periphery in social work education. Involved are six faculty members, teaching a range of social work courses. Insights into some of the controversial issues that arise in the classroom when religion and spirituality are discussed are offered. Findings suggest a lack of uniformity in teaching approaches, indicating that educators may be unclear about how to address the topic.</description><creator>Starnino, Vince.</creator><contributor>Wright, Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Social work education.</subject><subject>Social service -- Religious aspects.</subject><title>Religion, spirituality, and social work education : taking the next step</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t92n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k45r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p213k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Should the lack of confidence in the airline industry, led by the September 2001 terrorist attack, stop the liberalization process of the airline ownership and control? Following this dreadful event, even though the rationale of the ownership and control restrictions comes back now to the original concept of national identity, States should pursue the liberalization of cross-border investments, which will undoubtedly contribute to the growth and expansion of the airline industry. Indeed, the principle of airline substantial ownership and effective control is one of the biggest impediments to the air transport industry growth. Legitimately included in the bilateral agreements since 1946 for national security reasons, States have maintained the principle over the years and used it as a protectionist tool, as well as a bargaining chip. Today, considering that liberalization and globalization concepts are already well-established in the biggest industrial sectors, and a large number of cross-border investments occurs in most of the service sectors through mergers and acquisitions, the time is ripe to remove national restrictions on foreign investments from the airline industry. A number of States have already liberalized their ownership system, but the reluctance of the United States to open their airlines' capital to foreign investments, slows down considerably the worldwide liberalization process. After describing the current national policies regarding the ownership and control of airlines and examining their rationale, this thesis will discuss the consequences of the recommended liberal system. Advocating a total liberalization of cross-border investments, this thesis will then consider the steps to be taken towards achieving that goal, as well as the role of the international organizations in this process.</description><creator>Lelieur, Isabelle.</creator><contributor>Milde, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Law and policy of substantial ownership and effective control of airlines : prospects for change</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r7393.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p213k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t79v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multinational enterprises shape global and national politics by their enormous economic power. In the introduction, I briefly discuss the definition of a multinational, as well as the role of labour standards relating to child labour. In Part I, I will focus upon the political and economic relationship between States and MNEs. I will also discuss the tensions this relationship creates. In the second part, I focus on the issue of child labour and different kinds of approaches countries take. Before dealing with international efforts to create a universal code, I examine two internal codes. Part III addresses two main issues. First, the question how human rights and MNEs relate to each other is dealt with. Then the issue of international legal responsibility will be elaborated. Finally, the thesis concludes that public opinion and shame may be the key to successfully address the issue of child labour.</description><creator>Kovacs, Zoltan Balazs.</creator><contributor>Toope, Stephen J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Sociology, Industrial and Labor Relations.</subject><title>International labour standards, codes of conduct and multinational enterprises</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb258.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t79v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j070r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Ottawa Senators' lobby for comprehensive tax relief in favour of Canadian NHL teams towards the end of the 1990's is commendable. The argument that the Ottawa Senators hockey team is unfairly taxed in comparison to other Canadian businesses rejects reliance upon familiar economic impact studies of dubious validity, and is almost undeniably true in respect of property taxes. The argument is also colourable with respect to tax incentives which are given to businesses with links to Canadian culture and heritage, but are denied to professional hockey. Ultimately, however, the absence of any need to encourage Canadian participation in hockey, the obvious capture of any benefits by star players unwilling to participate in the structuring of an assistance programme, and the extraordinary public appetite for the NHL in Canada, distinguish hockey from those comparable businesses.</description><creator>Keon, Ryan.</creator><contributor>Janda, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>The Ottawa senators' lobby for comprehensive tax relief : a somewhat (but only somewhat) principled appeal to the notion of tax fairness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh83j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j070r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z022t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Under the Canadian Copyright Act, a cinematographic work is qualified as a dramatic work. The Act does not say if a motion picture is a work of joint authorship, nor does it say who is, or who are, the authors of the film. The present study is devoted to demonstrate that the author of the musical compositions specifically composed for the motion picture is one of the co-authors of the film, created jointly with other authors. Since the Canadian legal sources alone cannot provide us with a precise answer, we look at other jurisdictions, from civil law countries to common law countries, to demonstrate that the music composer is a co-author of the cinematographic work, in Canada.</description><creator>Larose, François, 1970-</creator><contributor>Gendreau, Ysolde (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Le compositeur de la musique du film : coauteur de l'œuvre cinematographique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z956d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z022t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj17f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The rate of intraspecific nest parasitism was determined for a colony of Red-breasted Mergansers (Mergus serrator) nesting on the Tern Islands in Kouchibouguac National Park, New Brunswick. In order to recognize instances of nest parasitism, field criteria and microsatellite analysis testing for parentage between attending hens and the eggs in their nests were used. Traditionally, molecular analysis has involved collecting blood samples from females and offspring, however, for the purpose of this study, DNA was extracted successfully from feathers, egg membranes, and unhatched embryos which were collected during the summers of 1999 and 2000. A total of 8 primer pairs which amplified microsatellite loci in closely related avian species were tested (Sfimu-2, Sfimu-3, Sfimu-4, Sfimu-5, Sfimu-6, Sfimu-7, Bcamu-6, and Alamu-1). Four of these primers produced product of the expected size (Sfimu-3, Sfimu-4, Sfimu-7, and Bcamu-6). Amplification of these loci, however was inconsistent and subsequent sequence analysis revealed that the amplicons did not contain tandem repeats and therefore were not useful in genotyping. From field criteria we were able to establish rates of parasitism of 46% and 44% for each season. Rates of parasitism tended to be higher at the beginning of the season, compared to nests initiated later. Field criteria bring support to several hypotheses on causes of nest parasitism, indicating that more than one may influence rates of parasitism in a population.</description><creator>Bouchard, M'Liki Jovette.</creator><contributor>Titman, Rodger D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Red-breasted merganser -- New Brunswick -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Brood parasitism -- New Brunswick.</subject><title>Determining rates of intraspecific nest parasitism in a colony of Red-breasted Mergansers (Mergus serrator) using microsatellite analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr814.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj17f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472z28k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We examined the effect of a functional oil (FctO), with potential weight-controlling and blood lipid-lowering attributes, vs beef tallow as control (C), on the cardiovascular risk profile of overweight women. The FctO comprised energy expenditure-enhancing medium chain triacylglycerols, cholesterol-lowering phytosterols and triacylglycerol-suppressing n-3 fatty acids. In a randomized, single-blind, crossover design, inpatient trial, 17 women consumed each oil as part of a controlled, supervised, energy-adjusted diet for 27 days. Body weight decreased similarly during both dietary periods. Plasma total and LDL cholesterol levels decreased by 4.8% and 10.4% following FctO, and were lower by 9.0% and 16.4% respectively, after FctO vs C. HDL cholesterol and circulating triacylglycerol levels were unaffected by treatment, though HDL:LDL and HDL:total cholesterol ratios increased by 19.5% and 9.4% on FctO. Plasma total homocysteine levels were higher on FctO vs C. Plasma glutathione increased with FctO supplementation. We conclude that consumption of FctO improves the overall cardiovascular risk profile of overweight women.</description><creator>Bourque, Christine.</creator><contributor>Jones, Peter J. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Phytosterols.</subject><subject>Functional foods.</subject><subject>Reducing diets.</subject><subject>Omega-3 fatty acids -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Blood lipids.</subject><subject>Sterols -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Overweight women.</subject><title>Evaluation of a functional oil composed of medium chain triacylglycerols, phytosterols and n-3 fatty acids on the cardiovascular risk profile of overweight women</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b0633.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z28k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r49g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various aspects of the airline industry will have to be considered. In determining what the way forward should be, the very essence of airline transport must be laid bare. The industry will have to be classified, does it qualify as a global public good, or is it a mixed public/private commodity? What are the ill effects that this good has yielded as its by products? The aviation industry as a branch of global transportation will be examined in order to classify it. Methods of managing public goods effectively will be briefly considered. Following this will be an analysis of aviation development, the events preceding and following deregulation, the most significant player in the aviation world. Various perspectives and forms of regulation will be considered. References will be made to strict government regulation, deregulation and self regulation. This will lead to a consideration of other matters pertinent to the aviation industry e.g. health, safety, security, environmental aspects and how these should be managed. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Addy, Naa Adoley.</creator><contributor>Milde, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Aviation : the new order (deregulation, the environment, health, safety and security</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g454r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r49g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301317b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A land tenure system is a set of rules which govern social relations between peoples in respect to land. It defines the property rights in land of individuals or groups in a specific locality or society. The property rights, which are in effect bundles of rights, may include the right to use, lease, mortgage, transfer, and so on. The source of these tenurial rules can be either customs or enacted laws. This thesis examines in detail these aspects of land tenure systems in respect to Eritrea, a country situated in the Horn of East Africa. Accordingly, the indigenous systems of land tenure of the country, land reforms introduced by the country's colonizers, and land laws enacted by the country's Government after independence, are discussed and criticized.</description><creator>Abbay, Futsum Tesfatsion.</creator><contributor>Glenn, Jane M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>History, African.</subject><title>The eritrean land tenure system from historical and legal perspectives /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx64f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301317b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676x51h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective. The diagnostic interview for borderline personality disorder (DIB) requires a long duration of administration (45 minutes). This led to the development of a briefer (10 minutes), and therefore more feasible, version of the DIB named the DIB-Ab. It is the aim of this study to test the validity and reliability of the DIB-Ab. Method. Forty-seven previously suicidal adolescents, aged 14--21 years, participated in this study. The DIB-Ab and DIB-R were administered during a battery of tests separated by 130 minutes of unrelated measures. Results. The Pearson correlation coefficient of the DIB-Ab with respect to the DIB-R ranged from .52--.80 with respect to the total scores on three sections (i.e. affect, cognition, and impulse/action). The correlation coefficient of the DIB-Ab ranged from .43--.91 for the total section scores and the same section scores. The standardized alpha for internal consistency of the DIB-Ab ranged from .54--.83 for the total scores and for cognition and impulse/action section scores. Conclusion. The preliminary data analysis revealed that the DIB-Ab is a valid and reliable instrument, and it could replace the parent version in certain research and clinical paradigms.</description><creator>Ahmadi, Shamila.</creator><contributor>Greenfield, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Psychology, Psychometrics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>The validity and reliability of the abbreviated version of the diagnostic interview for borderlines (DIB-Ab) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b517f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x51h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67315743</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Whey media, containing 2% (w/v) whey powder, 1% (w/v) glucose, and 0.5% (w/v) yeast extract, were fermented with nine Lactobacillus strains to produce angiotensin I-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitory peptides. Lb. brevis, Lb. helveticus, and Lb. paracasei were most effective in producing whey hydrolysates that contained potent ACE inhibitors, with the inhibition rate ranging from 93.3 +/- 0.3 to 100%. The hydrolysates of three Lactobacillus strains were partially purified by dialysis (6,000--8,000 Da cut-off) to remove larger molecules, and subsequently subjected to RP-HPLC, equipped with a Delta Pak C18 column. Each chromatogram displayed at least three distinct peaks at the hydrophobic region of the elution profile. Altogether fourteen peaks were purified and assayed for ACE inhibitory activity. All peaks except one exhibited ACE inhibitory activities, with IC50 ranging from 5.3 +/- 0.1 to 2637.8 +/- 366.9mug/ml. Three of these peaks contained pentapeptides, which consisted of mostly hydrophobic or aromatic amino acids at the C-terminal.</description><creator>Ahn, Jae-Eun.</creator><contributor>Lee, Byong H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Angiotensin converting enzyme -- Inhibitors.</subject><subject>Whey.</subject><subject>Lactic acid bacteria.</subject><title>Production and characterization of angiotensin I-convertine enzyme inhibitory peptides from whey fermentation with lactic acid bacteria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z0233.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67315743</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v7336</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is a neurological disorder characterized by plaque deposition and an elevated immune response. Epidemiological studies have shown that use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) by the elderly is associated with a decreased relative risk and a delayed onset of AD. Moreover, the apolipoprotein E (apoE) gene has been proven to be a risk factor for AD with apoE ε4 AD patients having been found to show lower levels of brain apoE. In the present study, treatment of primary rat mixed glial cell cultures with indomethacin, aspirin, and interleukin-1beta resulted in significant increases in extracellular apoE protein. Furthermore, treatment of primary rat astrocyte cell cultures with aspirin, interleukin-6, and a cyclooxygenase-2 selective aspirin derivative was found to result in increased levels of apoE. Consequently, NSAID-induced increases in apoE protein may enhance apoE-mediated immunosuppression and compensatory synaptic plasticity, potentially resulting in decreased risk and delay of disease onset.</description><creator>Aleong, Rosanne.</creator><contributor>Poirier, Judes (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The effect of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs on in vitro glial apolipoprotein E expression - implications for the mechanisms and treatment of Alzheimer's disease /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x69f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7336</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gv433</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of length-bias and left-truncation in survival data have been well studied in the statistical literature. To a lesser extent, the phenomena of length-bias and left-truncation have also been investigated when group comparisons are of interest. This literature examines various biases that may occur under different scenarios, and also, on occasion, proposes procedures for the estimation of covariate effects when using prevalent data. In this thesis, we review the literature concerned with the analysis of length-biased and left-truncated data, paying particular attention to the issue of group comparisons. Some shortcomings of the methods developed in the literature are pointed out. We also assess the effects of failure to recognize the presence of length-bias when performing group comparisons in natural history of disease studies. To our knowledge, this issue has not yet been addressed in the literature.</description><creator>Addona, Vittorio.</creator><contributor>Wolfson, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Group comparisons in the presence of length-biased data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws060.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv433</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th26r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un plan de traitement rapide et précis est essentiel en                radiothérapie et les techniques par Monte-Carlo produisent les résultats les plus                précis pour le calcul de dose. Dans la présente recherche, nous avons développé un                script de Monte-Carlo rapide basé sur des données pré-calculée (PMC, Monte Carlo                pré-calculé) pour des applications en radiothérapie. Le code informatique PMC prend                l'avantage d'une grande quantité de mémoire actuellement installée de nos jours sur                les ordinateurs afin de générer des données pré-calculées. Les traces primaires des                électrons sont générées au centre de matériaux homogènes (eau, air, os, poumons) avec                des énergies entre 0.2 et 18 MeV en utilisant le code EGSnrc. Les électrons                secondaires ne sont pas transportés, mais leurs positions, énergies, charges et                directions sont sauvegardées et utilisées comme particules primaires. D'après le type                de matériel et d'énergie de l'électron, le tracé est sélectionné et utilisé comme                particule primaire. La performance de cette méthode est testée dans plusieurs types                de configurations homogènes et non- homogènes. Les résultats, lorsque comparés à ceux                de EGSnrc, sont à l'intérieur d'une marge de 2% tandis que la rapidité de calcul est                de 40 à 60 fois supérieure. Les codes informatiques pré calculés de Monte-Carlo sont                précis, rapide et indépendant de la physique et par conséquent applicables à                plusieurs type de faisceaux tels que les particules à haute charge. Dans un autre                projet, nous avons étudié la capacité du code Monte-Carlo à utiliser des faisceaux                orthogonaux de bremsstrahlung dans le cadre d'imagerie en radiothérapie. Les                caracté</description><description>A fast and accurate treatment planning system is essential for radiation                therapy and Monte Carlo (MC) techniques produce the most accurate results for dose                calculation in treatment planning. In this work, we developed a fast Monte Carlo code                based on pre-calculated data (PMC, Pre-calculated Monte Carlo) for applications in                radiation therapy treatment planning. The PMC code takes advantage of large available                memory in current computer hardware for extensive generation of pre-calculated data.                Primary tracks of electrons are generated in the middle of homogeneous materials                (water, air, bone, lung) and with energies between 0.2 and 18 MeV using the EGSnrc                code. Secondary electrons are not transported but their position, energy, charge and                direction are saved and used as a primary particle. Based on medium type and incident                electron energy, a track is selected from the pre-calculated set. The performance of                the method is tested in various homogeneous and heterogeneous configurations and the                results were generally within 2% compared to EGSnrc but with a 40-60 times speed                improvement. Pre-calculated Monte Carlo codes are accurate, fast and                physics-independent and therefore applicable to different radiation types including                heavy-charged particles. In another project, we worked on Monte Carlo feasibility                study to use orthogonal bremsstrahlung beams for imaging in radiation therapy. The                basic characteristics of orthogonal bremsstrahlung beams are studied and the                feasibility of improved contrast imaging in linear accelerator with such a beam is                evaluated. In the context of this work orthogonal bremsstrahlung beams represent the                component of the bremsstrahlung distribution perpend</description><creator>Jabbari Najafabadi, Keivan</creator><contributor>Jan Peter Frans Seuntjens (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Radiation</subject><title>Development of a fast Monte Carlo code for dose calculation in a treatment planning and feasibility study of high contrast portal imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf79c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th26r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wf62x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'échec de détonation dans le nitromethane pur dans un                confinement d'aluminium a été étudié dans une géométrie annulaire, où l'explosif                d'essai était placé dans un volume formé entre un cylindre et un tube concentrique.                Cette technique a été motivée par le désir d'avoir une condition limite périodique                dans la direction orthogonale à l'épaisseur annulaire et placé dans le plan frontal                de la détonation. Cette géométrie est avantageuse par rapport aux expériences faites                dans une configuration rectangulaire soumise à l'absence de conditions limites                latérales. Avec un rapport d'aspect essentiellement infini, les phénomènes d'échec de                longue durée pouvaient être isolés des perturbations issues des conditions latérales.                La propagation ou l'échec de la détonation a été déterminé par l'observation de                marques d'échec gravées sur le cylindre en aluminium par la détonation. L'échec de la                détonation de nitromethane dans le confinement en aluminium était qualitativement                différent de celui dans le nitrométhane dilué ou le nitrométhane pur placé dans un                confinement faible. Bien que les études précédentes sur les détonations dans les                confinements failbles aient constaté que la détonation pouvait se propager                indéfiniment malgré la présence de quelques ondes sombres hétérogènes, la détonation                dans l'emprisonnement en aluminium échouait finalement dès que la première marque                d'échec fût observée. Cette étude a identifié que le croissance des marques d'échec                était une fonction de l'épaisseur de l'ouverture annulaire. Un modèle d'ondes                coniques a été proposé pour expliquer les structures d'échec tridimensionnelles.</description><description>The failure of neat nitromethane detonation in aluminum confinement was                studied primarily in an annular geometry, where the test explosive filled the gap                between a concentric rod and tube. This technique was motivated by the desire to have                a periodic boundary condition in the direction orthogonal to the annular gap                thickness in the front plane, as opposed to the weakly confined lateral edges of                typical slab geometry experiments. With an effectively infinite aspect ratio,                long-time failure phenomena could be isolated from lateral boundary perturbations.                Detonation propagation or failure was determined by the observation of failure                markings engraved on the aluminum rod by the passing detonation. Detonation failure                of nitromethane in aluminum confinement was found to be qualitatively different from                failure in dilute explosive or weaker confinement. While previous studies of                detonation in weaker confinement found that detonation could propagate indefinitely                despite the presence of some non-uniform dark waves, detonation in aluminum                confinement would eventually fail once the first failure marking was observed. The                present study identified that the growth rate of failure markings was a function of                annular gap thickness. A conical wave model was proposed to explain the                three-dimensional failure structure.</description><creator>Mack, David Barry</creator><contributor>Andrew J Higgins (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - General</subject><title>Experimental investigation of failure markings associated with nitromethane detonation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf804.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf62x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz38x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De nombreux signaux musicaux d'intérêt historique sont                stockés sur des supports analogues dégradés, tels que les enregistrements                phonographiques. La dégradation est souvent associée à des gênes sonores qui sont                désagréables pour l'auditeur. La restauration audio utilise les technologies de                traitement du signal numérique pour réduire ces artefacts associés aux bruits des                signaux audionumériques. La restauration des clics, en particulier, s'attaque à la                corruption du signal par des bruits impulsifs. Ce projet a permi de développer un                logiciel de restauration de clics, lequel utilise une méthode fondée sur le modèle                auto-régressif bien connu pour détecter et supprimer les clics. Les résultats de la                restauration ont été évalués subjectivement par des auditeurs experts, qui ont                comparé la qualité sonore associée aux enregistrements phonographiques restaurés par                la méthode d'autocorrélation avec celle d'un système matériel de restauration très                respecté et disponible commercialement. Cette thèse revisite les travaux précédents                sur la restauration audio, décrit la conception et la mise en œuvre du logiciel de                restauration, explique la procédure d'évaluation, indique les résultats obtenus,                dresse les conclusions et propose des suggestions de travaux futurs.</description><description>Many audio signals of historical interest are stored on degraded analog                media, such as phonograph records. Degradation is often associated with audible                disturbances that can be annoying for listeners. Audio restoration uses digital                signal processing technology to reduce artifacts associated with noise in audio                signals. Click restoration, in particular, addresses corruption by impulsive noises.                This project developed click restoration software using a well-known autoregressive                model-based method for the detection and suppression of clicks. The restoration                results were subjectively assessed by expert listeners who rated the audio quality                associated with phonograph recordings restored by the autoregressive method and                compared to a commercially available well-respected hardware restoration device. This                thesis document reviews previous work in audio restoration, describes the design and                implementation of the restoration software, explains the evaluation procedure, gives                results, draws conclusions, and provides suggestions for future work.</description><creator>Eustace, Gregory</creator><contributor>Ichiro Fujinaga (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Subjective evaluation of an autoregressive model-based method for the restoration of audio recordings contaminated with impulsive noise</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q598t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz38x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956h73d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is a growing body of evidence that Canadian consumers have                concerns about the impact of agricultural production on the health of the environment                and on society. This study investigates the preferences of rural and urban consumers                in Quebec for food attributes that provide environmental, health, and social                benefits. The choice modeling technique was employed to estimate the implicit prices                of specific food attributes and willingness to pay (WTP) values for alternative food                products. Results suggest that rural consumers place higher value on environmental                benefits and have higher social existence values than urban consumers, while urban                consumers value health benefits to a greater extent than rural consumers. Further,                neither consumer group is dissatisfied with current animal welfare standards used in                hog production. These findings imply that improvements in economic efficiency are                possible if the agriculture sector improves its ability to capture the market for                environmental and health benefits and if agricultural policy works to strengthen                consumer confidence in food labeling and food regulation.</description><description>Une évidence grandissante propose que le consommateur                canadien augmente son intérêt concernant l'impact de la production agricole sur la                santé, l'environnement et la société. Cette étude fait l'investigation des                préférences des consommateurs ruraux et urbains du Québec concernant les                caractéristiques conférant des bénéfices environnementaux, de santé, et sociaux. Le                modèle d'analyse par choix est employé pour estimer les prix implicites de certaines                caractéristiques des aliments et ainsi déterminer la volonté de payer pour des                produits alimentaires alternatifs. Les analyses suggèrent que les consommateurs                ruraux accordent une valeur supérieure aux bénéfices environnementaux et à la                proximité des activités agricoles alors que les consommateurs urbains accordent une                plus grande valeur aux bénéfices liés à la santé. De plus, aucun de ces deux groupes                ne s'est révélé être insatisfait des normes en matière de bien-être animal pour la                production de porc. Ces conclusions démontrent que la société améliorerait sa                situation si le secteur agricole capturait les bénéfices liés à l'environnement et à                la santé et si les politiques agricoles favorisaient la confiance des consommateurs                par l'étiquetage et des réglementations alimentaires appropriées. </description><creator>Yen, Sue May</creator><contributor>Paul Thomassin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Economics - Agricultural</subject><title>Valuing environmental, health and social benefits using choice modeling: a comparison of the implicit prices of food attributes for rural and urban consumers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq51m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h73d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fz518</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The recovery of the Peregrine Falcon (Falco peregrinus) in eastern North                America is a great conservation success, but the largely new urban population that it                has produced has received remarkably little study. Satellite telemetry, detailed                monitoring of active nests, and a review of archived nesting data since the                resumption of breeding in the east were used to characterize aspects of the ecology                of this rebuilding population. The accuracy of small satellite transmitters was                confirmed to be appropriate for tracking long-distance movements, and they were used                to compare the dispersal and migration of 34 Peregrine Falcons. Adults from Alberta                migrated farther than juveniles from eastern North America. Among the juveniles,                those raised at natural nest sites or in rural habitat departed earlier, while males                were much more likely to migrate long distances than females. Siblings varied                considerably in their migratory strategies, and the one juvenile tracked over                multiple years adapted his behaviour annually, suggesting that there are many factors                involved in determining migratory movements in Peregrine Falcons, and that their                relative importance may change with time. In Ontario, the Peregrine Falcon population                has grown to a record size, initially due to an intense captive-breeding and release                effort, and more recently to considerable immigration from adjacent states. This                influx resulted in a substantial dilution of the original F.p. anatum gene pool, in                part because anatum juveniles appear to have been recruited to the breeding                population at a lower rate. The shift was also facilitated by a small number of                immigrant adults producing a disproportionate percentage of the off</description><description>Le rétablissement du Faucon pèlerin (Falco peregrinus)                dans l'est de l'Amérique du Nord est un grand succès de conservation, mais la                nouvelle population n'est pas bien connue. La télémétrie satellite, l'observation                détaillée de nids en Ontario, et une analyse des données concernant les nids depuis                le recommencement de la reproduction dans l'est de l'Amérique du Nord ont été                utilisés pour caractériser des aspects de l'écologie de la population. L'exactitude                des petits émetteurs satellites pour la documentation des grands mouvements a été                vérifiée, et ils ont été utilisés afin de comparer la dispersion et la migration de                34 faucons pèlerins. Des adultes de l'Alberta ont entrepris des migrations plus                longues que des juvéniles de l'est de l'Amérique du Nord. Parmi les juvéniles, ceux                des nids naturels ou des sites ruraux sont partis plus tôt, et les mâles avaient                tendance à se déplacer sur de plus grandes distances. Les frères et sœurs ont                démontré des stratégies plutôt différentes concernant la migration, et le seul                juvénile suivi pendant plusieurs années a changé sa stratégie à chaque fois,                suggérant que plusieurs variables ont de l'influence sur le comportement migratoire                des faucons pèlerins, et que l'importance relative de ces facteurs peut changer                progressivement. En Ontario, la population du faucon pèlerin s'est agrandie à un                niveau record, grâce à un programme vaste d'élevage en captivité, et plus récemment à                l'immigration des individus des états contigus. L'arrivée de plusieurs adultes                américains a causé une dilution de la composition génétique de la population qui                était à l'origine entièrement de la s</description><creator>Gahbauer, Marcel A</creator><contributor>David M Bird (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Zoology</subject><title>Breeding, dispersal and migration of urban Peregrine falcons in eastern North America</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074x06h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz518</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430656s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:55:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse présente une analyse novatrice et exhaustive                de la cosmologie d'Abū Naṣr al-Fārābī (mort 950) en exposant divers concepts issus de                ses ouvrages. Les deux premiers chapitres récapitulent la contribution d'al-Fārābī à                la tradition des commentaires grecs et arabes, évaluent les sources premières, et                examinent la méthode cosmologique du deuxième maître, autant vis-à-vis de la                tradition astronomique ptoléméenne que vis-à-vis du corpus aristotélicien. La place                de l'astronomie, de l'astrologie, de la physique et de la métaphysique dans la                méthode cosmologique, et l'importance de la démonstration et de l'analogie, sont                examinées afin de reconstituer la méthodologie employée par al-Fārābī. La structure                de sa cosmologie, et en particulier la question de l'origine de son modèle énnadique,                ainsi que la relation entre les moteurs immobiles aristotéliciens et les théories                cinétiques ptoléméennes sont soulevées dans le chapitre III. Les chapitres IV, V, et                VI, étudient, quant à eux, la matière céleste, l'intellect, et le mouvement des                astres, tout en délinéant l'influence que les auteurs grecs eurent sur al-Fārābī.                L'analyse montre les liens étroits qui unissent al-Fārābī aux mouvances                péripatéticienne et néoplatonicienne de l'antiquité, et particulièrement à Alexandre                d'Aphrodise, Themistius, et Proclus. Conséquemment, l'auteur critique la thèse                Mahdienne selon laquelle la philosophie d'al-Fārābī serait principalement redevable à                la philosophie politique du moyen-platonisme. L'accent est placé non seulement sur                les correspondances entre le deuxième maître et ses prédécesseurs grecs, mais aussi                sur les$</description><description>This dissertation offers a new and comprehensive analysis of Abū Naṣr                al-Fārābī's (d. 950) cosmology by focusing on various important issues that have been                largely neglected by the modern scholarship. It provides an examination of the                physical, metaphysical, and astronomical aspects of al-Fārābī's cosmology by adopting                a multidisciplinary approach that takes into account the history of philosophy and                the history of astronomy. Accordingly, my dissertation explores how al-Fārābī                attempted to reconcile features of Ptolemaic astronomy with Aristotelian and                Neoplatonic theories, an endeavor which resulted in the formulation of innovative                cosmological ideas. Chapters I and II provide background information on al-Fārābī's                activity as a commentator and his relation to the Greek commentatorial tradition and                assess the relevant primary sources. In addition, they examine al-Fārābī's approach                to cosmology and his scientific method in terms of both the Ptolemaic astronomical                tradition and the Aristotelian corpus. Chapter III addresses problems related to the                structure of al-Fārābī's cosmology, especially the origin of his ennadic cosmological                model and his spherology. Particular attention is devoted to the question of how                Aristotle's unmoved movers and Ptolemy's astronomical theories are reconciled.                Chapters IV, V, and VI analyze the place of celestial matter, intellect, and motion                respectively in al-Fārābī's cosmology and attempt to redefine the second teacher's                relation to the various trends of Greek philosophy. The study stresses al-Fārābī's                connection with the Neoplatonic and Peripatetic currents, particularly with thinkers                such as Alexander of Aphrod</description><creator>Janos, Damien Triffon</creator><contributor>Robert Wisnovsky (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Faiz Ragep (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>Intellect, substance, and motion in al-Farabi's cosmology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns764.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430656s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39175</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>