<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:20:13Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20300" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w29m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bessie Head's fiction reflects the author's consciousness of power as the definitive force in the South African context. By considering Head as a social realist, the thesis relates sociological evidence to authorial interest and demonstrates Head's treatment of the power issue in her three novels, When Rain Clouds Gather, Maru, and A Question of Power. Biographical data, particularly Head's unique, though socially marginal position as a political exile, a Coloured, and a woman are also applied. The thesis covers three areas--politics, race, and gender. The first explores the nature of power in South African politics within the time-frame of the present, past, and future. The second which focuses on the institution of apartheid examines racial relations between the blacks and whites and also among the blacks, with attention given to the dilemma of the Coloured. The third section discusses sexual politics, looking at male-female relationships in both traditional and contemporary societies.</description><creator>Bong-Toh, Mei Choo Aileen</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Head, Bessie, 1937-1986 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Fictions of power : the novels of Bessie Head</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r679v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w29m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dw66v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three experiments used an appetitive Pavlovian conditioning procedure to investigate the ability of the context to generate excitation. Discrete stimuli (CSs) signalling food unconditioned stimuli (USs) were used to decrease contextual conditioning. Detailed observations of the behaviours of rats during and immediately preceding the presentation of CSs, and in an event-free period were analysed. Experiment 1 showed that a discrete visual CS was able to interfere with contextual conditioning because it was a more efficient cue for food than the context. Experiment 2 found that an auditory CS could reduce contextual conditioning in a similar manner but the topography of responding during the event-free period was specific to the modality of the CS. Experiment 3 demonstrated that signal-appropriate responding during the event-free period occurred only if the CS was a signal for reinforcement.</description><creator>Steinwald, Hannah</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Classical conditioning.</subject><title>Effect of signalling a positive reinforcer on contextual conditioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s359x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw66v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b738c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is known that the use of batch experiments for the estimation of kinetic coefficients is a better alternative than continuous flow reactors, in terms of the time needed to perform the experiments. In this study a new methodology to estimate the four Monod-kinetic parameters from batch reactor data set is presented. This method fits biomass and substrate plots simultaneously via nonlinear least-squares analysis. The nonlinear equations are solved via the secant method. The methodology performed satisfactorily with two synthetic data sets. It was also applied to seven batch reactor data sets available in the literature and to ten data sets from batch experiments using wastewater and sludge from the municipality wastewater treatment plant in Granby, Quebec. The constants estimated vary considerable among themselves, and some were not within the range of values commonly found in the literature. The methodology proposed yields parameter estimates which produce the minimum sum of squares residuals. It is believed that further studies are needed if one is to attempt estimating the four Monod-kinetics constants using batch reactors experiments.</description><creator>Villarreal Rodriguez, Marco Antonio</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Assessment of nonlinear least-squares estimation of monod kinetic parameters from batch reactor experiments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bq525.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b738c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zv52d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Within the context of oceanographic research on northern estuaries in James Bay and Hudson Bay, and in relation with hydroelectric developments and their impact on the physical environment, two studies were undertaken. Both concern the importance of bottom topography, tidal motion and fresh water input on the estuarine processes in these areas. The first one, in Rupert Bay (south-eastern corner of James Bay), describes tidal and local wind effects on circulation and mixing patterns for summer conditions. An estimate of terms in the lateral momentum equation shows that the centrifugal acceleration, the Coriolis force and the baroclinic pressure gradient are the most important forces at a mid-bay cross section transect. The second study is concerned with the freshwater plume of Great Whale River (south-eastern Hudson Bay). CTD measurements were used to examine the lift-off point of the plume for under-ice and increasing discharge conditions. Comparison with existing models shows them to be inappropriate for under-ice conditions. Finally, the presence of supercooled water masses in the region of the study is reported.</description><creator>Veilleux, Lorraine</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Physical oceanography of northern estuaries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96021990.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zv52d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289k30j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Poor user interfaces in programming environments detract from environments' power and ineffectively communicate with users. Moreover, specification, development, testing, and modification of these usually large, complex, and handcrafted user interfaces are difficult, error prone, slow, and costly. An alternative is user-interface generation. This thesis deals with two primary issues: xmupe2, a user-friendly user interface for the MUPE-2 programming environment, and user-interface generation. Implemented in Modula-2 and C for the X Window System, xmupe2 shows MUPE-2's character with: windows tailored to program-fragments, textual and graphical representations of fragments' contents, and editing commands fired by context-sensitive mouse-based menus. Secondly, and because of the effort in handcrafting xmupe2, the thesis introduces MUISL, an experimental event-driven user-interface specification language. MUISL defines user-interface objects with inheritable classes, attributes, and actions. Then presented in muigen--a flexible, table-driven, and MUISL-based user-interface generator. Both MUISL and muigen simplify user-interface development, as exemplified in the thesis.</description><creator>Boulos, Sami</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A user interface for a programming environment /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903113z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289k30j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53ww957</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A Decision Support System for the design and planning of soil conservation systems on a watershed scale was conceived and applied to southwestern Quebec. The system integrated Geographical Information System, distributed parameter hydrologic modeling and Expert System technologies. Maps of appropriate soil conservation practices were produced for two small rural basins representative of the study region. The effect of the selected practices on runoff and sediment was assessed using the ANSWERS model. Erosion sites were targeted using a once-in-25 year design storm. It was observed that small portions of the study basins produced large amounts of eroded sediment. The expert system was designed to select appropriate conservation practices for the 1-ha cells which had more than one ton of erosion as a result of the design storm. The results demonstrated that the selected conservation practices would reduce sediment yield and average erosion rates by 50% in each of the study basins.</description><creator>Montas, Hubert J.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Decision support systems.</subject><subject>Soil conservation -- Québec (Province) -- Planning.</subject><title>A decision support system for soil conservation planning /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m529n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53ww957</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1070223</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My thesis centers on a critical analysis of the concept of the "educated person" in Kieran Egan's theory of educational development. Egan presupposes that the erudite human being in western societies is ideally a sophisticated ironic thinker, that is, a person who possesses the fullest range of sense making capacities known to our culture; and furthermore, a person who tactfully and innovatively applies these capacities in everyday life. My thesis attempts a "thick" description of Egan's notion of ironic understanding in light of the writings of Martin Buber on dialogue, Hannah Arendt on human thinking, Hans Georg Gadamer on the serious playfulness of the interpretative act, Richard Rorty on private irony and liberal democracy, and finally, Michael Oakeshott on the educational conversation. It suggests that these theoretical notions of the fully human life may be practically realized in the educated ironist characterized by Egan in his various writings.</description><creator>Hammond, David</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Education -- Social aspects</subject><subject>Egan, Kieran -- Contributions in education</subject><subject>Education -- Philosophy</subject><title>The common play of ironic understanding : a critical study of Kieran Egan's theory of educational development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj87x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1070223</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623d71s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The production of charmonium states J/$ Psi$ and $ Psi sp prime$ was measured at 300 GeV/c with $ pi sp{ pm}$, p, and p beams on a lithium target. The cross sections were determined by analyzing a fraction (10%) of the data recorded by the experiment E705 at Fermilab. The data acquisition took place at the High Intensity Laboratory located on the "Proton West" beam line, and extended over a period of nine month during 1987-1988. The efficiencies for the different detector components of the E705 spectrometer were measured, and the global acceptance was determined. The measured absolute cross sections for J/$ Psi$ and $ Psi sp prime$ are consistent with the measurements obtained in other experiments. The differential cross section for J/$ Psi$ production was measured for the kinematical variables X$ sb{ rm f}$, P$ sb{ rm t}$, and for the J/$ Psi$ decay angles. The distributions obtained are compared with the distributions measured at other energies by previous experiments.</description><creator>Simard, A.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>A measurement of the hadronic production of J/[psi]'s /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz296.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d71s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569559d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The contribution of dissolved organic carbon (DOC) to mineral weathering was investigated under the changing Eh and pH conditions in three subarctic fens, near Schefferville, Quebec. No evidence of increased weathering rates nor different weathering patterns were found in the fen basal sediment despite DOC-rich and low Eh (0 to +200 mV) conditions. Solutions containing 50 mg DOC/L derived from subarctic fen peat, and of 50 and 300 mg DOC/L, derived from deciduous leaf litter were used as weathering agents. Clinochlore, microcline and the Fe-rich basal till from the Schefferville fens were used as weatherable mediums. The DOC rich solutions and controls (made of distilled water buffered to the same initial pH) were used to investigate the relative weathering ability of DOC-rich waters under aerobic and anaerobic conditions. The relative ability was determined by comparing the changing cation concentrations in the solutions.</description><creator>Heyes, Andrew</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Fens -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Chemical weathering</subject><subject>Fens -- Arctic regions</subject><title>Mineral weathering by dissolved organic carbon in subarctic fens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w103n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569559d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:736665662</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study primarily examined the use of second language production as a measure of second language text comprehension in 18 first-year nursing students enrolled in French for Nursing courses (nine low-intermediates, nine high-intermediates). Although few differences were found between the two levels of proficiency with respect to recall and inference, the high-intermediates were more proficient in reading highly variable material and difficult vocabulary in their second language than the low-intermediates as measured by sentence reading times. The within-subjects results indicate a greater amount of propositional recall of the second language text when it was interpreted in the first language than when it was interpreted in the second language.</description><creator>Silva, Maria</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Second language acquisition -- Evaluation</subject><title>Cross-language comprehension of case files by nursing students</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv95g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736665662</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268596z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tucker, Gerald Etienne</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Jamaica -- Civilization</subject><subject>Jamaica -- Social conditions</subject><title>Afro-European political culture and development in Jamaica</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8060594.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268596z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kn94b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Warn, Thomas</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Geophysics -- Fluid models.</subject><subject>Stability</subject><title>On the stability of quasi-geostrophic waves in a rotating annulus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt532.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn94b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hc965</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Vincent, Claude.</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Jahn-Teller effect</subject><subject>Spin-lattice relaxation</subject><title>Spin-lattice relaxation of a 2E Jahn-Teller system.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j183q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hc965</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290b252</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tarasoff, Frederick John.</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Harp seal -- Anatomy.</subject><subject>Otters -- Anatomy.</subject><title>Anatomical observations on the river otter, sea otter and harp seal with reference to those structures that are of known significance in thermal regulation and diving.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d056k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b252</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9030761</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Taylor, Kenneth Robert.</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Titanium</subject><subject>Chelates</subject><subject>Stereochemistry</subject><subject>Organic compounds -- Synthesis.</subject><title>The synthesis, characterization and stereochemical investigation of Ti(chelato) 2X2 compounds.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq587.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9030761</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w66344456</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Walmsley, John L., 1943-</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Boundary layer (Meteorology) -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>A one-dimensional time-dependent air-water boundary layer model.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs47t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66344456</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kh20j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tobe, Stephen S.</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Tsetse-flies</subject><title>Aspects of nutrient transfer during the reproductive cycles of the female of the tsetse fly, Glossina Austeni Newst.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx14q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kh20j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p114n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tattrie, George Arthur</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Edwards, Jonathan, 1703-1758.</subject><title>Jonathan Edwards' understanding of the natural world and man's relationship to it</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806060w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p114n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p115x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Silverman, M. (Marilyn), 1945-</creator><date>1973</date><subject>West Berbice, Guyana -- Politics and government</subject><subject>West Berbice, Guyana -- Economic conditions</subject><title>Resource change and village factionalism in an East Indian community, Guyana</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000080x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p115x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t271j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Sylvestre-Williams, Richard Henry.</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Trafficability</subject><subject>Penetrometer</subject><title>Indentation and trafficability studies on clay.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r176t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t271j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r57s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Spevack, Michael Gerald</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Drug abuse -- Canada.</subject><subject>Youth -- Drug use -- Canada.</subject><title>Drugs and the adolescent high school student: a three year survey study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547s223.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r57s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sk340</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Sutherland, Eileen Ann</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Prediction of scholastic success</subject><title>Teacher expectancy effects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr69g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk340</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m253d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Scanlon, R. Lorcan</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Psychometrics</subject><subject>Psychology -- Methodology</subject><title>The Joint effects of simultaneiously violating the homogeneity of regression and homogeneity of variance assumptions on the F-test in the analysis of covariance - a Monte Carlo simulation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602154n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m253d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687j284</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Sawai, Tsutomu.</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Transition metals.</subject><subject>Sulfur.</subject><title>Physical studies on some sulfur-containing transition metal complexes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634446g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j284</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r582</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:43:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Shaffir, William.</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Hasidism.</subject><subject>Jewish sociology.</subject><title>Life in an urban Chassidic community : insulation and proselytization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xf96s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r582</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20325</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>