<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:59:24Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):14725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042x55j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>White adipose tissue (WAT) dysfunction plays an essential role in the etiology of diseases such as insulin resistance, type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease. It is characterized by its reduced ability to hydrolyze and store triglycerides. Several factors such as adipokines and WAT enzymes are known to affect this process. However, the work of this thesis indicates that apolipoprotein C-I (apoC-I) is a novel player in this process.ApoC-I is an apolipoprotein found on triglyceride rich lipoproteins (TRL) and high-density lipoproteins (HDL). It has several roles in lipid metabolism such as the activation of lecithin-cholesterol acyltransferase, the inhibition of cholesteryl ester transfer protein, lipoprotein lipase and hepatic lipase. Although ubiquitously expressed in several tissues, we were the first to demonstrate its synthesis and secretion from a human adipocyte cell model. The pertinence of apoC-I secretion from human WAT has not been examined, and has been the focus of this PhD thesis. We particularly focused on normolipidemic healthy postmenopausal obese women, thus eliminating the possible confounding effect of chronic disease on the regulation of apoC-I.  Firstly, we demonstrated that total fasting plasma apoC-I concentrations do not correlate with adiposity, lipid parameters, markers of insulin resistance or inflammation in this population. Similarly, loss of fat mass without concomitant changes in plasma lipids did not induce any significant changes in plasma apoC-I. However, we later demonstrated that when plasma lipoproteins were separated by fast-protein liquid chromatography, the non-HDL fraction of total plasma apoC-I, although minor at &lt; 20%, associated positively with fasting pro-atherogenic lipoproteinemia and delayed postprandial TRL and TRL-remnants clearance. Moreover, in contrast to what has been reported in the literature, postprandial increases in TRL apoC-I were not associated with decreases in HDL apoC-I. On the other hand, both fasting and postprandial increases in non–HDL apoC-I were associated with apoC-I secretion from women's WAT, a relation that did not exist for HDL apoC-I. Additionally, WAT apoC-I secretion was associated with delayed postprandial dietary fat clearance. Finally, mature adipocytes isolated from women's WAT secreted apoC-I, indicating that WAT apoC-I secretion in humans was, at least in part, attributed to the adipocyte cell population of this tissue. Incubation of 3T3-L1 adipocytes with synthetic TRL in the presence of exogenous apoC-I induced a time-dependent inhibition of LPL activity in these adipocytes. Therefore, the work presented in this thesis has demonstrated that apoC-I secretion from adipocytes / WAT is an upstream element regulating the function of this tissue. We propose that the pertinence of WAT apoC-I secretion lies in a negative crosstalk between WAT apoC-I secretion and WAT function in the postprandial state. We believe that the transfer of apoC-I from WAT to TRL inhibits WAT LPL activity and delays the clearance of plasma TRL. The accumulation of TG-rich TRL-remnants, leads to increased uptake and production of VLDL by the liver, which further aggravates the postprandial dyslipoproteinemia. Thus, WAT apoC-I may be at the root of WAT dysfunction and its associated dyslipoproteinemia; a phenotype that is closely related to the development of insulin resistance, type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease in humans.</description><description>Le tissu adipeux blanc (WAT) dysfonctionnel joue un rôle essentiel dans l'étiologie des maladies telles que la résistance à l'insuline, le diabète de type 2 et les maladies cardiovasculaires. Il est caractérisé par sa capacité réduite d'hydrolyser et stocker les triglycérides. Plusieurs facteurs connus, tels que les adipokines et les enzymes du tissu adipeux blanc, peuvent affecter ce processus. Cependant, le travail de cette thèse indique que l'apolipoprotéine C-I (apoC-I) est un nouvel acteur dans ce processus.L'apoC-I est une apolipoprotéine trouvée sur les lipoprotéines riches en triglycérides (TRL) et les lipoprotéines de haute densité (HDL). Elle a plusieurs rôles dans le métabolisme des lipides tels que l'activation de la lécithine-cholestérol acyltransférase, l'inhibition de la protéine de transfert des esters de cholestérol, l'inhibition de la lipoprotéine lipase et de la lipase hépatique. Elle est exprimée dans plusieurs tissus et nous avons été les premiers à démontrer sa synthèse et sa sécrétion dans un modèle de d'adipocyte humain. La pertinence de cette la sécrétion n'a jamais été examinée et fait l'objet de cette thèse. Nous avons mis l'accent sur les femmes saines, ménopausées, obèses et normolipidémiques pour éliminer l'effet des maladies chroniques sur l'homéostasie de l'apoC-I.Nous avons montré que la concentration de l'apoC-I total du plasma à jeun ne corrèle pas avec l'adiposité, les paramètres lipidiques, les marqueurs de résistance à l'insuline et l'inflammation dans cette population. De même, la perte de masse grasse sans changements simultanés des lipides plasmatiques n'a pas entraîné de changements significatifs de la concentration de l'apoC-I totale. Cependant, nous avons ensuite démontré que lorsque les lipoprotéines plasmatiques sont séparées par chromatographie liquide rapide des protéines, la fraction non-HDL plasmatique de l'apoC-I totale, bien que mineure (&lt;20%), s'associe positivement avec une lipoprotéinémie pro-athérogène à jeun et une réduction de la clairance des TRL postprandiales et leurs TRL-remnants. De plus, contrairement à ce qui a été rapporté dans la littérature, l'augmentation postprandiale de l'apoC-I des TRL n'est pas associée à une diminution de l'apoC-I des HDL. Aussi, des augmentations à jeun et postprandiale de l'apoC-I non-HDL ont été associées à la sécrétion de l'apoC-I du  WAT chez ces femmes, une relation qui n'existe pas pour l'apoC-I des HDL. Cependant, la sécrétion de l'apoC-I par le WAT a été associée à une réduction de la clairance post-prandiale du gras alimentaires. Enfin, des adipocytes matures isolés du gras de ces femmes obèses sécrètent de l'apoC-I, ce qui indique que l'apoC-I secrétée par le WAT de nos patientes provient, en partie, des adipocytes retrouvés dans ce tissu. De plus, l'incubation d'adipocytes 3T3-L1 avec des TRL synthétiques en présence d'apoC-I exogène induit une inhibition chrono-sensible de l'activité LPL dans ces adipocytes.En conclusion, la sécrétion de l'apoC-I des adipocytes / WAT pourrait être un élément en amont de la régulation de la fonction de ce tissu. Nous proposons que la pertinence de l'apoC-I du WAT soit celle d'une interaction négative entre la sécrétion de l'apoC-I par le WAT et la fonction réduite de l'hydrolyse et la captation de TG par le WAT dans l'état postprandial. Nous suggérons qu'il y a un transfert d'apoC-I à partir du WAT aux TRL, qui cause une réduction de l'activité de la LPL à la surface du WAT. Ceci retarde la clairance des TRL plasmatiques et entraine une accumulation de remnants de TRL riche en triglycérides. Cependant, il y a une absorption accrue de TRL et une surproduction de VLDL par le foie, ce qui aggrave encore plus la dyslipoprotéinémie postprandiale. L'apoC-I du WAT peut être à l'origine de la dysfonction du WAT et de la  dyslipoprotéinémie associée; un phénotype qui est lié au développement de la résistance à l'insuline, du diabète de type 2 et des maladies cardiovasculaires chez l'humain.</description><creator>Wassef, Hanny</creator><contributor>Jean Davignon (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>May Faraj (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Pertinence of apolipoprotein C-I in human adipose tissue</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dk10t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x55j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vf86z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les digues des résidus miniers sont des ouvrages géotechniques conçus pour offrir un stockage adéquat et sécuritaire des résidus et ce pendant et après la fin de la vie de la mine. La conception des digues à  résidus  est actuellement basée sur les méthodes d'équilibre limite (LEM) qui sont utilisés pour calculer les facteurs de sécurité  de la stabilité des pentes sous diverses charges opérationnelles. Le facteur de sécurité minimal obtenu à partir de ces analyses est considéré comme facteur de sécurité de conception. Ils sont présentement utilisés dans la conception géotechnique. Cependant, LEM a des lacunes notamment le manque d'information sur la déformation d'une digue et de l'interaction entre les contraintes effectives et la pression interstitielle. Ainsi, les techniques de modélisation numérique avancées  qui considèrent le couplage hydro-mécanique survenant dans la structure de la digue ont été développées. Ces modèles procurent un aperçu plus précis du comportement géotechnique de la digue à résidus. Cependant, les deux approches LEM et modélisation numérique sont déterministe. Par conséquent, ces approches ne tiennent pas compte de l'incertitude inhérente aux propriétés des matériaux de construction  et ceci est un fait bien connu par l'ingénieur géotechnicien et  pourtant ceci doit être abordé.Dans cette thèse, les approches d'analyse stochastiques tels que le Monte Carlo (MC) sont adoptées pour étudier l'effet de l'incertitude inhérente aux propriétés du matériau sur le coefficient de sécurité. Les deux LEM et les modèles numériques hydro- mécaniques couplés sont d'abord développés et après les résultats des modèles déterministes sont compilés. Ces derniers sont ensuite comparés aux résultats obtenus à partir des analyses stochastiques.Une étude de cas d'une nouvelle conception d'une digue à  rétention d'eau à résidus avec des données géotechniques bien documentées est adoptée dans cette étude. Tout d'abord, l'analyse LEM a été poursuivi et suivi par une analyse de sensibilité pour déterminer les paramètres les plus influents sur le facteur de sécurité de la conception.Ensuite, un model couplé d'hydro-mécanique a été développé avec FLAC2D dans lequel la séquence de construction a été simulée en sept étapes. Le coefficient de sécurité (FOS) a été calculé à la fin de chaque étape en utilisant la technique de réduction de la résistance (SRT). Par la suite, la méthode d'estimation ponctuelle (PEM) a été utilisée pour obtenir la probabilité d'un rendement insatisfaisant en tenant compte de l'angle de base de la digue, de la friction, de la cohésion et de la perméabilité  comme variables stochastiques. Le coefficient de variation des propriétés du matériau a été varié et ses conséquences sur la probabilité ont été enregistrées. Ensuite, la méthode de MC a été adoptée pour calculer la probabilité de rendement insatisfaisant de la digue à résidus ainsi que sa fiabilité. Par ailleurs, l'effet de la modification de la fonction de densité de probabilité (PDF) du paramètre d'entrée stochastique sur la fiabilité de sortie a encore été analysé. En outre, l'effet du hasard au niveau local a été étudiée en utilisant le hasard Monte-Carlo (RMC) et la méthode par rapport à la sortie de la méthode de MC. Enfin, l'effet du coefficient de corrélation entre l'angle de friction du noyau  et la cohésion sur la fiabilité de la digue a été analysé.  Ceci a été suivi d'une analyse stochastique avancé à l'aide de la méthode MC qui comprenait une troisième variable stochastique qui est la perméabilité du noyau. L'incorporation de paramètres à la fois mécaniques et hydrauliques en tant que variables stochastiques  ont réduit la fiabilité de la digue, ainsi, mettant en évidence l'impact  de l'analyse stochastique hydro-mécanique avec l'approche  hybride. Les résultats de toutes les analyses sont présentés dans la thèse suivante ainsi que les  découvertes dans la conclusion.</description><description>Mine tailings dams are geotechnical structures that are designed to provide adequate and safe storage of tailings materials both during and after the end of mine life. The design of tailings dams is currently based on limit equilibrium methods (LEM) which are used to calculate slope stability safety factors under various operational loads. The minimum safety factor obtained from these analyses is retained to be the design safety factor. LEM's however suffer from a number of shortcomings most notably the lack of information on dam deformation and the interaction between effective stress and pore pressure. For this, advanced numerical modeling techniques accounting for the hydro-mechanical coupling occurring in the dam structure have been developed. These models provide much greater insight into the geotechnical behavior of the tailings dam. However, both LEM and numerical modeling approaches are deterministic in nature; thus, they do not take into consideration the inherent uncertainty of the construction material properties – a fact that is well known to the geotechnical engineer, yet, needs to be addressed.In this thesis, stochastic analysis approaches such as the Monte Carlo (MC) method are adopted to investigate the effect of the inherent uncertainty in material properties on the design factor of safety. Both LEM and coupled hydro-mechanical numerical models are first developed and the results for deterministic models are compiled. These are then compared with the result obtained from stochastic analyses. A case study of a new water retention tailings dam project design with well documented geotechnical data is adopted throughout the thesis study. First  the LEM analysis was pursued followed by a sensitivity analysis to determine the most influential parameters on the design safety factor. Next, a fully coupled hydro-mechanical model was developed with FLAC2D in which the construction sequence was simulated in seven stages. The factor of safety (FOS) was calculated at the end of every stage using the Strength Reduction Technique (SRT). Following that, the Point Estimate Method (PEM) was then used to obtain the probability of unsatisfactory performance by considering the dam's core angle of friction, cohesion and permeability as stochastic variables.  The coefficient of variation for the material properties was varied and its consequence on the probability was recorded. Next, the MC method was adopted to calculate the tailings dam's probability of unsatisfactory performance as well as its reliability. The effect of changing the probability density function (PDF) of the stochastic input parameter on the output reliability was further analyzed. Furthermore, the effect of randomness at the local level was studied using the Random Monte-Carlo (RMC) method and compared to the output of the MC method.Finally, the effect of the coefficient of correlation between the dam's core angle of friction and its cohesion on the impoundment's reliability was analyzed. This was followed by an advanced stochastic analysis using the MC method that included a third stochastic variable, the dam's core permeability. The incorporation of both mechanical and hydraulic parameters as stochastic variables lowered the impoundment's reliability; thus, highlighting the power and novelty in the hydro-mechanical stochastic analysis hybrid approach. The results of all analyses are presented in the thesis along with the findings in the conclusion.</description><creator>Hamade, Tarek</creator><contributor>Hani Mitri (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Mining</subject><title>Geotechnical design of tailings dams - a stochastic analysis approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77st51t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf86z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848t97x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background:  T2DM (Type 2 Diabetes) has relatively recently emerged as new epidemic now affecting children.  T2DM also disproportionately affects Canadian First Nations and Inuit.  Physical activity during childhood has been shown to reduce the likelihood of the progression to overweight and obesity in adulthood.  Overweight and obesity are predictors of the onset of T2DM. Objective:  To describe and assess activity levels of schoolchildren in an indigenous elementary school with and without the presence of a playground animator in order to further enhance knowledge and prevent T2DM in this population.  The proportions of students in sedentary, active, and walking (moderate) physical activity levels were described with and without the presence of a playground animator. The relationship of physical activity to contextual variables such as supervision, organization and equipment were also described.  The effect of temperature and time were also observed for their effects on physical activity level.  In order to address other issues affecting healthy lifestyles, we also examined negative behaviours such as bullying or teasing (name calling) and used field notes to provide an ethnographic description of the playground atmosphere. Methods:  A direct observation method entitled SOPLAY was used to assess physical activity and record other contextual variables.  Children in grades 1-6 were observed during three months (September to December 2011) at recess and lunchtime when an intervention in the community offered an animator at the school on alternate days for recess and lunch time. Results:  After 3 months of observations the average number of children per scan observed engaging in sedentary activity was 0.49 ± 1.21, for walking activity 7.22 ± 6.96, and for active 2.94 ± 4.38. A comparison of days with and without the animator showed no differences in activity level overall.  The contextual variables (organisation, equipment provision and supervision) were found to be significantly positively associated with walking and active (MVPA) behaviours (p&lt;0.05) but not with sedentary activity.   Temperature change (-4°C to 25°C) showed significant correlations with activity levels (p&lt;0.05), higher temperatures were found to be positively associated with increases in sedentary and active levels. Poor snack choices and peer teasing and bullying were observed in the school's environment as well. Conclusions: Improving physical activity levels, and healthy lifestyles among children in schools as a group poses special obstacles and numerous resources are needed to effect change.  More research involving the critical examination of the most promising behaviour change techniques with school children is needed. Barriers to successful implementation of school based physical activity and healthy behaviour interventions require in-depth policy guidance.</description><description>Contexte: DT2 (diabète de type 2) a relativement récemment émergé comme une nouvelle épidémie qui affecte  maintenant les enfants. DT2 affecte aussi les Premières nations du Canada et les Inuits de façon disproportionnée. L'activité physique pendant l'enfance a prouvé réduire le risque de la progression de la adiposité et l'obésité à l'âge adulte. L'adiposité et l'obésité sont des facteurs prédictifs de diabète de type 2.  Objectif: décrire les niveaux d'activité des enfants d'école, dans une école élémentaire indigènes, afin d'améliorer les connaissances sur le DT2 et de prévenir le DT2 dans cette population.  Les proportions d'étudiants qui mènent une vie sédentaire, active (intensité modérée à vigoureuse) et les niveaux d'activité physique de marche ont été décrits. La relation entre l'activité physique à des variables contextuelles telles que la supervision, l'organisation et l'équipement qui ont également été décrits.  La température et le temps font effet et ont également été observées pour leurs effets sur le niveau d'activité physique.  Afin de répondre à d'autres questions qui touchent les changements de mode de vie sain, nous avons également examiné les comportements négatifs tels que l'intimidation et les taquineries (insultes) et des notes de terrain utilisé pour fournir une description ethnographique de l'atmosphère des aires de jeux. Méthodes: Une méthode d'observation directe qui se nomme SOPLAY a été utilisée pour évaluer l'activité physique et pour enregistrer d'autres variables contextuelles. Les enfants aux niveaux primaires (1-6) ont été observés pendant trois mois (Septembre à Décembre 2011) à la récréation et pendant l'heure du dîner quand un appui communautaire a offert un animateur à l'école tous les deux jours ou le pendant le temps de la récréation et du dîner.  Résultats: Après 3 mois d'observations, le nombre moyen d'enfants par observation qui participe à une activité sédentaire était de 0,49 + / - 1,21 ; 7,22 + / - 6,96 pour une activité de marche et 2,94 + / - 4,38 pour actif.  Les variables contextuelles (organisation, la fourniture d'équipements et de supervision) se sont avérés significativement et positivement associée à la marche et aux comportements actifs (p0,05), mais pas avec l'activité sédentaire. Changement de température (-4ºC à 25ºC) démontre des corrélations significatives avec les niveaux d'activité (p0,05), la température qui augmente graduellement se révèle être positivement associée à l'augmentation des niveaux sédentaires et actives.  Les niveaux d'activité de marche augmentent avec la température plus fraîche.  L'addition d'un animateur de jeux a démontré une corrélation positive avec la marche qui augmente au fil du temps (r=0,26, p0,0001). Conclusions: Améliorer les niveaux d'activité physique et le mode de vie sain chez les enfants dans les écoles comme un groupe pose des obstacles spéciaux et de nombreuses ressources sont nécessaires pour effectuer un changement.  Il faut davantage de recherches portant sur l'examen critique des techniques de changement comportement plus prometteurs avec les élèves. Obstacles à la mise en œuvre réussie de l'école selon l'activité physique et un comportement sain interventions nécessitent des orientations détaillées.</description><creator>Horne, Sarah</creator><contributor>Katherine Gray-Donald (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>Assessing activeness in response to the addition of a playground animator at an indigneous elementary school with the Kahnawake schools diabetes prevention project</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf338.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t97x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bs86d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le VIH-1 requiert plusieurs protéines cellulaires à chaque étape de son cycle de réplication pour assurer une réplication efficace. Notre travail a mené à l'identification que l'ARN génomique du VIH-1 n'est pas un substrat pour la dégradation des ARNm aberrants (NMD), même si elle a plusieurs cadres de lecture ainsi qu'une longue 3'UTR. Nous avons démontré que UPF1 est impliqué dans la stabilité de l'ARN génomique du VIH-1 car la surexpression de UPF1 a engendré une augmentation des niveaux d'ARN du VIH-1 et de Gag. Par ailleurs, le rôle de UPF1 est distinct de son rôle dans le mécanisme NMD, il est observé dans les compartiments nucléaires et cytoplasmiques et ne nécessite pas sa liaison à UPF2. De plus, la fonction navette de UPF1 est requise pour assurer l'exportation de l'ARN  génomique du VIH-1 car le mutant NES d'UPF1 bloque son export et le mutant NLS n'immunoprécipite pas avec celui-ci. Ce nouveau rôle d'UPF1 est observé dans la présence et l'absence de Rev. De plus, UPF1 se trouve en complexe avec Rev, CRM1, Nup62 et DDX3, les protéines cellulaires déjà caractérisées comme étant impliquées dans l'exportation de l'ARN génomique du VIH-1. Enfin, nous avons également identifié UPF2 comme étant un régulateur négatif, de telle sorte que sa liaison à UPF1 engendre un blocage nucléaire de l'ARN génomique du VIH-1. Nous avons identifié un mécanisme possible démontrant comment le VIH-1 s'évade du mécanisme NMD en cooptant UPF1 pour faciliter l'exportation, la stabilité et la traduction de l'ARN génomique du VIH-1.</description><description>HIV-1 co-opts host cell proteins at every step of its replication cycle to ensure proper replication. Our work identified that the HIV-1 genomic RNA is not a substrate for nonsense-mediated mRNA decay (NMD) even though it has multiple open reading frames as well as a long 3'UTR. We demonstrate that Up-frameshift protein 1 (UPF1) is involved in HIV-1 genomic RNA stability such that overexpression of UPF1 increases HIV-1 genomic RNA levels and Gag translation. Moreover, the role of UPF1 in HIV-1 is NMD-independent, is observed in both nuclear and cytoplasmic compartments and does not require binding to UPF2. Furthermore, the shuttling function of UPF1 is required for HIV-1 genomic RNA export since a UPF1 nuclear export mutant sequesters the genomic RNA in the nucleus and a nuclear localization mutant does not immunoprecipitate with the HIV-1 genomic RNA. UPF1's role in HIV-1 genomic RNA export is observed in both Rev-dependent and -independent conditions. In addition, UPF1 is found in complex with Rev, CRM1, Nup62 and DDX3, cellular proteins with already characterized roles in HIV-1 genomic RNA export. Lastly, we also identified UPF2 as a negative regulator, such that its binding to UPF1 results in the nuclear sequestration of the HIV-1 genomic RNA. We have identified a possible mechanism to explain how HIV-1 escapes the RNA quality control mechanism of NMD by co-opting UPF1 function for efficient HIV-1 genomic RNA export, stability and translation.</description><creator>Ajamian, Lara</creator><contributor>Andrew J Mouland (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Virology</subject><title>Up-frameshift proteins and their distinct roles in HIV-1 RNA metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0326470.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bs86d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289n449</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When an observer views a moving object, the projection of the motion onto the retina is first converted into information about velocity in the primary visual cortex (V1).  These motion signals are then sent to numerous visual cortical structures, known collectively as the extrastriate cortex.  One such area is the middle temporal area (MT), which contains neurons that are highly selective for velocity.  The outputs of MT are then sent to even higher cortical areas that are responsible for generating conscious motion perception.  Many studies have devised sophisticated models to explain the process by which velocity selectivity arises in MT.  In most of these models, complex computations are carried out on the inputs reaching MT from V1, which are typically modeled as linear filters of visual inputs.  The outputs of such MT model are then used to infer perceptual behavior.  While these models are often quite successful in capturing the relationship between MT neuronal responses and visual stimuli, they are often built on abstract mathematical assumptions about V1 processing.  In particular the assumption that V1 neurons have responses that are linearly related to the visual stimulus is contradicted by the demonstration of multiple nonlinearities at this stage.  Similarly, MT outputs presumably go through several nonlinear processing stages before affecting perception.  Thus, in order to facilitate the development of biologically plausible models, it is important to first understand the relevant input nonlinearities.  The present thesis explores this issue by analyzing electrophysiological data collected from awake-behaving macaques and through the development of novel computational models.  In particular, this thesis shows how many of the seemingly complicated functions of MT can be explained largely on the basis of a realistic account of nonlinearities in the V1 inputs.  The thesis also provides a new formulation of the individual contributions of the center and surround of MT neuron receptive fields, in the process revealing important nonlinear inhibitory inputs that had not previously been observed.  Finally, this thesis shows how many of the perceptual phenomena that are thought to depend on center-surround antagonism in MT could actually arise from of the accumulation of nonlinearities along the visual pathway.</description><description>Quand un observateur perçoit un objet en mouvement, la projection du déplacement sur la rétine est d'abord convertie en information sur la vélocité au niveau du cortex visuel primaire (V1).  Ces données sont ensuite distribuées à plusieurs structures visuelles corticales, collectivement connues sous le nom de cortex extrastrié.  Une des ces aires corticales, l'aire temporale moyenne (MT), contient des neurones sélectifs à la vélocité.  Les signaux sortants de MT sont ensuite envoyés aux aires corticales supérieures où une perception consciente du mouvement est intégrée.  Plusieurs études ont construit des modèles mathématiques sophistiqués pour expliquer le procédé par lequel la vélocité est analysée spécifiquement par MT.  Selon la majorité de ces modèles, des computations complexes sont appliquées par MT aux signaux provenant de V1, qui eux sont typiquement des filtres linéaires des stimuli visuels.  Les données construites par MT sont ensuite utilisées pour inférer une perception.  Ces modèles, tout en étant efficaces pour expliquer la relation entre les réponses neuronales de MT et les stimuli visuels, s'appuient sur des assomptions mathématiques des computations de V1.  En particulier, la supposition que les réponses neuronales de V1 aux stimuli visuels sont linéaires est contredite  par la démonstration de multiples non-linéarités à cette étape.  Similairement, les données sortantes de MT passent par plusieurs étapes non-linéaires avant d'influencer la perception.  Donc, pour faciliter le développement de modèles biologiques plausibles, il faut d'abord comprendre la non-linéarité des données entrantes à MT.  La présente thèse explore cette question en analysant des données électro-physiologiques recueillies de trois macaques rhésus conscients et en développant de nouveaux modèles computationnels.  En particulier, cette thèse démontre que plusieurs fonctions de MT qui paraissaient compliquées sont en fait largement expliquées par la non-linéarité des signaux de V1.  De plus, cette thèse apporte une nouvelle formulation des contributions du centre et du pourtour des champs récepteurs visuels, révélant des données entrantes inhibitrices non-linéaires, ce qui n'avait jamais été observé auparavant.  Finalement, cette thèse démontre que plusieurs des phénomènes perceptuels dépendant supposément de l'antagonisme centre/pourtour au niveau de MT pourraient en fait être dus à l'accumulation de non-linéarité dans le système visuel.</description><creator>Tsui, James</creator><contributor>Christopher Pack (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>The role of input nonlinearities in the primate visual system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kp16g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289n449</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445ch69s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Students with learning disabilities (LD) and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) are an emerging clientele in post-secondary institutions, and may have difficulties with various academic skills. The risk and resilience framework can be applied to this population in order to discern what factors contribute to academic successes and difficulties. Stigma theory (Blaine, 2000; Goffman, 1963; Jones et al., 1984; Link &amp; Phelan, 2001) will be used to investigate self-perceptions of stigma as a potential risk factor for university students with LD and ADHD. Proponents of stigma theory hypothesize that self-perceptions of stigma arise from the perceived association between one’s disability and negative stereotypes. Such perceptions are proposed to contribute independently to reduced likelihood to disclose one’s disability, as well as emotional difficulties such as increased depressive symptoms and reduced self-efficacy. In this dissertation, the impact of perceived stigma on variables implicated in risk and resilience (i.e., disclosure, self-efficacy and depressive symptoms) was explored among a sample of university students with a diagnosis of LD and/or ADHD from 22 participating Canadian universities (n = 212; 126 females, 86 males). The objectives were twofold. First, an exploratory analysis examining variables that predict the degree of perceived stigma highlighted three significant predictor variables of gender, reported academic difficulty and reported family support. Specifically, males, individuals who reported high levels of academic difficulty and those who reported low levels of family support were significantly associated with a higher level of perceived stigma. Second, multiple regression analyses were employed to test both the direct effect of stigma on the outcome variables (i.e., depression, self-efficacy) and the mediating effect of disclosure using the path analytic approach. Results showed that perceived stigma had a significant direct effect on self-efficacy, but not depression. Further, mediation analyses indicated that this relationship was partially mediated by disclosure; individuals higher in disclosure ratings were associated with higher self-efficacy ratings, and the overall effect of stigma was reduced when disclosure ratings were accounted for. The findings support the theoretical importance of perceived stigma as an independent risk factor with negative implications for disclosure of one’s disability and self-efficacy, two potential protective factors. Findings were not supported for depression. Implications for stigma theory, school psychologists and service provision are discussed.</description><description>Les élèves ayant des troubles d'apprentissage (TA) et de déficit de l'attention avec hyperactivité (TDAH) sont une clientèle émergente dans les établissements postsecondaires, et peuvent avoir des difficultés avec diverses compétences académiques. Le cadre de recherche visant le risque et la résilience peut être appliqués à cette population de façon à pouvoir discerner les facteurs qui contribuent aux succès académiques ainsi que des difficultés. La théorie de la stigmatisation (Blaine, 2000; Goffman, 1963; Jones et al, 1984;. Link &amp; Phelan, 2001) sera utilisée pour étudier les perceptions de stigmatisation comme étant un facteur de risque potentiel pour les étudiants ayant des TA et de TDAH. Les partisans de la théorie de la stigmatisation émettent l'hypothèse que les perceptions de stigmatisation résultent de la perception associée à son handicap et les stéréotypes négatifs. Ces perceptions sont proposes pour contribuer de façon indépendante à la probabilité réduite de divulguer son handicap, ainsi que des difficultés émotionnelles tells que l'augmentation de symptômes dépressifs et la réduction de l'auto-efficacité. Dans cette thèse, l'impact de la stigmatisation perçue sur les variables impliquées dans le risque et la résilience (c'est à dire, la divulgation, l'auto- efficacité et les symptômes dépressifs) a été exploré auprès d'un échantillon d'étudiants universitaires avec un diagnostic de TA et TDAH ; ces étudiants provenant de 22 universités canadiennes participantes (n = 212; 126 femmes, 86 hommes). Les objectifs étaient de deux ordres. Tout d'abord, une analyse exploratoire examinant les variables qui permettent de prédire le degré de stigmatisation perçu et qui a mis en évidence trois variables signifiantes dont celles du sexe, l'état de la difficulté scolaire et le soutien de la famille. Plus précisément, les hommes, les individus qui ont déclaré des niveaux élevés de difficultés scolaires et ceux qui ont déclaré de faibles niveaux de soutien de la famille étaient significativement associés à un niveau plus élevé de stigmatisation perçue. Deuxièmement, les analyses de régression multiples ont été utilisées pour tester à la fois l'effet direct de la stigmatisation sur les variables de résultat (les symptômes de dépression et l'auto-efficacité) et l'effet médiateur de la divulgation en utilisant la trajectoire d'approche analytique. Les résultats ont montré que la stigmatisation perçue a eu un effet direct significatif sur l'auto-efficacité, mais non pas sur la dépression. De plus, les analyses de médiation ont indiqué que cette relation a été partiellement médiée par la divulgation; un taux plus haut de divulgation été associés à une meilleure auto-efficacité, et l'effet global de la stigmatisation perçue a été réduite lorsque évaluations de divulgation ont été pris en compte. Les résultats confirment l'importance théorique de la stigmatisation perçue comme un facteur de risque indépendant avec des conséquences négatives pour la divulgation de son handicap et de l'auto-efficacité, deux facteurs de protection. Les résultats n'ont pas été concluants pour la dépression. Les implications pour la théorie de la stigmatisation, les psychologies scolaires et les fournisseurs de services seront discutées.</description><creator>Roberts, France Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Nancy Lee Heath (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Education - Psychology </subject><title>Exploring perceived stigma, risk and resilience among university students with learning disabilities and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj39p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445ch69s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kr540</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The original goal was to use a downcomer to create swarms of solvent-coated bubbles  to scale-up the air-assisted solvent extraction (AASX) process. The downcomer provides a close-packed bubble bed considered attractive for solvent coating and fast extraction kinetics. During initial testing, the bubble bed was observed to collapse upon introduction of solvent, evident from decreasing gas holdup, decreasing aspirated air rate, and formation of air slugs. Neither changing solvent introduction technique, solvent composition nor addition of frother or salt alleviated the situation. In many cases collapse was complete (air rate became zero) at less than 900 ppm solvent. Thus, the focus shifted to address this phenomenon. Because conditions in the bubble bed approach those of foam (gas holdup over 45%), the de-foaming action of oil droplets was thought to be responsible, the solvent taking the role of de-foaming agent. The mechanism is related to oil droplets bridging and/or spreading to destabilize the inter-bubble film. Testing two hydrophobic solids, talc and graphite, showed that solids did not collapse the bed suggesting that the solvent's ability to spread gives the de-foaming (bed collapse) effect. A setup was established to view coalescence of two bubbles held in proximity when exposed to circulating dispersions of solvent, solid and solvent/solid. Conditions giving coalescence generally agreed with those yielding bed collapse, including the MIBC/talc system which resisted coalescence and bed collapse on introduction of solvent. Solvent bridging was captured on video although spreading was not observed. In conclusion the downcomer is not suited to AASX. The unit is used in Jameson Cells employed to remove solvent droplets in SX plants. The solvent levels appear to be less than 200 ppm where collapse is only partial and the phenomenon may not be noticed in those applications. </description><description>Le premier objectif de la recherche consistait à faire usage d'une goulotte de façon à créer des bulles enrobées de solvant afin d'augmenter l'échelle de mesure pour l'extraction au solvant par air assisté (AASX). La goulotte assure un contact plus étroit entre la bulle et le solvant et celui est considéré comme avantageux pour l'enrobement des bulles du solvant et pour la cinétique d'extraction rapide. Lors des tests initiaux, l'effondrement du lit formé par les bulles dans la goulotte, était observé à l'introduction du solvant comme le démontre le bas niveau du gaz, la diminution du débit de l'air aspiré, et la formation des grandes bulles d'air. L'on a observé qu'en changeant de technique d'introduction du solvant, la composition du solvant, et en ajoutant du sel et du moussant, le problème restait entier. Puisque les conditions dans le lit des bulles dans la goulotte avoisinent celles de la mousse (niveau de gaz plus que 45%), les propriétés des gouttelettes de solvant étaient tenues pour responsables, les gouttelettes de solvant jouant le rôle d'agent démousseur. Ce faisant, la recherche s'est penchée sur ce phénomène. Le mécanisme est lié à l'action de formation de pont (entre les bulles) et/ou l'enrobement des bulles par des gouttelettes de solvant. Celles-ci déstabilisent le film entre les bulles. Plus d'investigations sur les effets des matériaux hydrophobique sur la stabilité du lit des bulles en comparant le solvant à deux solides hydrophobiques, le talc et le graphite, avaient révélé que les solides n'avaient pas produit l'effondrement, sinon favorisé la stabilité: Ceci suggère l'habileté du solvant à s'étaler, ce qui confère la propriété démoussante (effondrement du lit). En conséquence, un montage avait été fait pour visualiser la coalescence entre deux bulles de plus prés, lorsque celles-ci étaient exposées à la circulation des dispersions de solvant, solide et des mélanges solvant/solides. Les résultats ont montré que les conditions entrainant la coalescence s'accordaient bien avec celles qui engendraient l'effondrement du lit dans la goulotte. Le pont formé entre les bulles et le solvant avait été capté par vidéo alors que l'étalement ne l'était pas. En conclusion, la goulotte n'est pas indiquée pour l'extraction au solvant par air assisté (AASX). L'unité est utilisée dans la cellule de Jameson pour éliminer les gouttelettes de solvant dans les unités d'extraction. Le niveau de solvant est moins de 200 ppm et dans ce cas, l'effondrement est partiel et le phénomène n'est peut-être pas observé dans ces applications.</description><creator>Kuan, Seng How</creator><contributor>James A Finch (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Collapsing bubble bed in a downcomer with the introduction of solvent</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nf577.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kr540</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tj95c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Structural failure due to earthquakes poses a serious threat to the life safety of Canadians.  This threat is greater in existing structures than in new structures due to advancements in the understanding of seismology and structural design that have recently been incorporated into the relevant design codes and standards.  This thesis documents an evaluation of the seismic vulnerabilities of existing single storey concentrically braced frame steel structures.  Focusing on the brace and brace connections, brittle failure of the connection was identified as a key concern.  Use of a structural fuse element to input ductility into the seismic force resisting system and control force levels was proposed as a rehabilitation technique to address the brittle connection failures.  Two ring fuses were designed to provide ductility and force control to the seismic force resisting system.  The line ring fuse, designed to connect to a single brace, and the cross ring fuse, designed to connect to the centre of an X-brace, were evaluated by means of physical testing and numerical modeling to determine their suitability as a retrofit scheme.  The physical testing contained five test sets, including full scale pin connected frame tests using quasi-static cyclic test protocols.  The testing demonstrated that the ring fuses were able to provide increased ductility to a brittle brace system, greatly improving energy dissipation potential, and limiting the force demand on the seismic force resisting system.  The results from testing also provided data for calibration and verification of the structural models. Two structural modeling approaches were used in this research.  Finite element method models were used to model the ring fuse components and the braced bay of a typical structure.  The component finite element models allowed for the investigation of potential ring fuse geometries and the verification of the seismic simulation models.  Seismic simulation models were used to evaluate the structural performance of representative retrofitted and un-retrofitted single storey steel buildings with respect to ground motion excitation.  Through the use of assessment guidelines the performance of the buildings retrofitted with the proposed ring fuses was quantified, including the development of fragility curves and the related probabilities of failure.  The ring fuses provided clear improvements to the seismic performance of the single storey concentrically braced frame structures, demonstrated by the reduced probability of failure.  The ring fuses also provide an affordable solution for the seismic retrofit of existing single storey steel structures.  Guidelines on the assessment of the brace and brace connection, along with design of the fuse and appropriate uses are outlined herein.  </description><description>La défaillance structurelle due aux tremblements de terre constitue une menace grave pour la sécurité de la vie des Canadiens. Cette menace est plus grande dans les structures existantes que dans les nouvelles structures grâce à la plus grande compréhension de la sismologie, de son effet sur la conception des structures et des récents changements intégrés aux codes de conception et normes pertinentes. Cette thèse documente une évaluation des vulnérabilités sismiques de structures en acier d'un étage à contreventement concentrique du châssis. La rupture friable des contreventements et de leurs connexions a été identifiée comme le point faible à améliorer. L'utilisation d'un élément structurelle fusible pour ajouter de la ductilité  et mieux résister aux forces sismiques a été proposée pour remédier aux défaillances de connexions friables.Deux anneaux fusibles ont été conçus pour fournir de la ductilité et gérer les forces agissantes sur la structure. Le fusible anneau-ligne, conçu pour se connecter à un doublé unique, et le fusible anneau-croix, conçu pour se connecter au centre d'un contreventement croisé, ont été évalués au moyen d'essais physiques et de modélisation numérique afin de déterminer leur applicabilité dans la réhabilitation sismique de bâtiments. Le test physique contenait cinq jeux de test, y compris les essais pleine-échelle tige de châssis connectés en utilisant un protocole quasi-statique d'essais cycliques. Les tests ont démontré que les anneaux fusibles étaient en mesure de fournir une ductilité accrue à un système d'armature friable, améliorant considérablement le potentiel de dissipation d'énergie, et de limiter les forces appliquées au système de résistance aux forces sismiques. Les résultats des essais ont aussi fourni des données pour l'étalonnage et la vérification des modèles structurels. Deux approches de modélisation structurelle ont été utilisées dans cette recherche. Un modèle en éléments finis a été utilisé pour les anneaux fusibles et la baie contreventées d'une structure typique. Ces modèles ont permis d'évaluer différentes géométries d'anneau fusibles et la vérification des modèles de simulation sismique. Les modèles de simulation sismique ont été utilisés pour évaluer la performance structurelle des bâtiments en acier à un étage (avant et après réhabilitation sismique) par rapport à l'excitation mouvements du sol. Grâce à l'utilisation de directives pour l'évaluation de la performance des bâtiments rénovés avec les anneaux fusibles proposés a été quantifiée, y compris l'élaboration de courbes de fragilité et les probabilités connexes de l'échec.L'anneau fusible fournit de nettes améliorations de la performance sismique des structures à d'acier d'un étage à contreventement concentrique, tel que démontré par la réduction de la probabilité de défaillance. L'anneau fusible est d'autant plus une solution abordable pour la réhabilitation sismique de ces structures existantes. Des lignes directrices sur l'évaluation des contreventements et le renfort de connexion, ainsi que sur la conception des anneaux fusibles et leurs utilisations sont décrites.</description><creator>Morrison, Thomas</creator><contributor>Colin Andrew Rogers (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Seismic mitigation technique for existing single storey steel CBF structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430805q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tj95c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hw135</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Through the prism of Richard Lachmann's 'elite conflict theory of historical contingency,' this dissertation brings a new perspective and a fresh interpretation to the study of the attitudes of the Ottoman central ulema toward the pre-Tanzimat Westernizing reforms. Contrary to the prevailing view of intra-elite vertical dichotomy conflict as the primary basis for ulema reactions, this research proposes inter-elite horizontal conflict as the root cause for the failure of the reform initiatives. Moreover, this study challenges the commonly-held belief that the goal of centralization of the revenues of religious endowments by the ruling authority was to silence ulema opposition to the Westernizing reforms. Instead, through a detailed examination of the evolution of early European taxation models and fiscal centralization trajectories, this research concludes that the Mahmudian centralization of awqaf should be seen, rather, as an emulation of the wider eco-geographic trend in response to the historical challenges faced by European states and the Ottoman Empire. By problematizing the prevailing nomenclature of Ottoman historiography, this research clarifies the longstanding misconceptions attached to the term 'ulema.' Finally, through a comprehensive survey of waqf-elite relations, this study will advance the understanding of the dynamics of the pre-Tanzimat Ottoman Empire.</description><description>À travers le prisme de la « théorie du conflit entre groupes d'élite et de la contingence historique » élaborée par Richard Lachmann, la présente thèse propose une nouvelle perspective ainsi qu'une nouvelle interprétation de l'étude des attitudes des oulémas ottomans envers les réformes occidentalisantes durant la période précédant l'adoption du Tanzimat. À l'opposé de l'opinion dominante, qui voit dans les échanges entre groupes d'élite un conflit à dichotomie verticale, cette recherche privilégie le principe d'échanges en tant que conflit horizontal, pour expliquer l'échec des initiatives de réforme lors de la période en question.En outre, cette étude remet en question la représentation classique qui attribue à la centralisation par l'autorité de l'État des recettes fiscales provenant des fondations religieuses la raison principale de la suppression de l'opposition aux réformes chez les oulémas. Bien au contraire. Par le biais de l'examen détaillé de l'évolution des premiers modèles de fiscalité européenne et les trajectoires de centralisation budgétaire, la présente étude arrive à la conclusion que la centralisation des awqaf pendant le règne du Sultan Mahmoud II fut plutôt le résultat de l'émulation des tendances économiques et géopolitiques existantes à l'époque en tant que réponse aux défis historiques auxquels se heurtèrent les pays européens tout comme l'Empire ottoman. C'est en interpellant la terminologie utilisée couramment dans l'historiographie ottomane que la présente étude expose les idées infondées associée au libellé « oulémas. » Enfin, grâce à une enquête approfondie sur les rapports entre waqf et groupes d'élite, l'étude fera avancer la compréhension du dynamisme de l'Empire ottoman dans la période qui précède l'adoption du Tanzimat.</description><creator>Argun, Selim</creator><contributor>Abisaab, Malek (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>History - Middle Eastern</subject><title>Elite configurations and clusters of power: the Ulema, Waqf and Ottoman State 1789-1839</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128f51f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw135</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wn833</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude a pour but d'observer les effets de l'apprentissage autodidacte —en anglais «self-regulated learning» (SRL)— sur les capacités de résolution de problème des élèves en mathématiques. Particulièrement, elle s'adresse à la question de si les élevés peuvent profiter de l'utilisation de l'enregistrement vidéo pour réviser leur propres essais à résoudre des problèmes de mathématiques. 40 élèves de huitième année ont initialement participé à cette étude en résolvant un problème sur le rapport et la distance. Par la suite, les 20 élèves qui étaient incapables de résoudre le problème sont invités à une reprise. À leur deuxième essai, 11 élevés étaient en condition vidéo alors que neuf élèves étaient en condition non-vidéo). Le protocole verbal de ces 20 élèves a été transcrit et codé en données. La logique de régression a analysé le processus de résolution de problèmes des élèves utilisé lors de l'Action et suite à celle-ci (objectifs, auto-évaluation, raisonnement et condition). Les résultats ont démontré que l'utilisation de la vidéo augmente l'engagement des élèves (envers tout type d'activité) et leur capacité de réflexion (Méta-Action). Nous décrivons de possibles avenues à la recherche dans le domaine de l'apprentissage à  l'aide de vidéo afin de produire des interventions pédagogiques efficaces.</description><description>This study investigated the dynamics of self-regulated learning (SRL) activity on students' mathematical problem-solving skills. Specifically, it addresses the question of whether students can benefit from the use of video by using it to review their own attempts at trying to solve mathematical problems. 40 grade 8 students initially participated in this study by solving a word problem on ratio and distance. Subsequently 20 students who were unable to solve the problem made a second attempt. In the second attempt, 11 students were in the video condition whereas nine students were in the non-video condition. Verbal protocols of these 20 students as they attempted the problem for a second time were transcribed and coded as data sources. Logistic regression analyzed students' problem solving processes for instances of Action and Meta-Actions (goal, evaluation, belief, and condition). Results showed that the video condition boosted student engagement (all types of activity) and reflection (Meta-Actions). The conclusions describe possible directions for future research that emphasize the value of videos to design effective educational interventions.</description><creator>Tung, I-Pei</creator><contributor>Robert J Bracewell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Education - Psychology </subject><title>Show me how i do it: the effects of viewing one's own performance on student engagement and reflection in mathematical problem solving</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zm17g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wn833</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc05k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le terme «neurosciences cognitives du développement» a émergé au cours de la dernière décennie pour encapsuler une innovation passionnante vers la fusion des disciplines qui étaient auparavant disparates, y compris les sciences cognitives, la neuroimagerie, la neurobiologie, la génétique moléculaire et de la psychologie du développement. L'objectif de ce programme de recherche était d'étudier le développement typique de deux domaines cognitifs connus pour être sélectivement altéré dans un certain nombre de troubles du neuro-développement : l'attention et la perception. L'étude des populations en voie de développement présente certaines difficultés méthodologiques, telles que la pertinence des tâches utilisés pour le selection des âges étudiées, quel que soit le domaine cognitif évalué. Dans le domaine de l'attention, l'article 1 (Les tâches Amsterdam Neuropsychologie: Une enquête de la cohérence et de la validité du test de l'attention) a évalué si les différentes mesures de la performance de chaque tâche reflète un processus unique attentionnel. Les résultats ont démontré que la vitesse et la précision dans les tâches de recherche visuelle et de vigilance sont indépendants. Ces résultats mettent en évidence la contribution des mesures d'évaluation à l'étude de l'attention. De plus, cette batterie a été utilisée pour examiner l'évolution typique de différents sous-composantes de l'attention et d'évaluer les processus de base de chaque tâche (vitesse par rapport à la précision) dans l'article 2 (Plus rapide mais pas mieux: à travers le développement attentionnel avec les tâches Neuropsychologie Amsterdam). Les résultats de cette étude indiquent que des améliorations liées à l'âge étaient présents pour la vitesse de traitement, mais pas pour la précision, alors que des differences liées aux tâches étaient présents pour les deux processus de base (vitesse et précision) avec des conclusions plus solides dans le groupe d'âge scolaire. Les chapitres suivants de ce thèse examinent le développement d'un autre domaine cognitif important de la neuroscience développementale: la perception visuelle. Un avantage d’étudier le développement de la perception visuelle est que les mécanismes qui facilitent divers types de procédés visuels peuvent être opérationnellement définies en termes plus stricts. La perception visuelle peut être évaluée en fonction de l'attribut visuel (la luminance par rapport à la texture; statique ou dynamique) qui sollicite des processus relativement distincts (strié vs extra-strié; dorsal vs ventrale, etc.). L'article 3 (Le développement de la perception des formes définies par la luminance et la texture durant les années d'âge scolaire.) et l'article 4 (Le développement différentiel de la sensibilité au contraste spatial pour des information définies par la luminance et la texture.) de cette thèse portaient sur l'évolution de notre sensibilité pour des informations définies par la luminance ou par la texture à différentes périodes du développement au moyen de deux paradigmes différents, un adapté 'landolt C' et la fonction de la sensibilité au contraste spatiale. La dernière étude méthodologique a exploré une question qui n'est pas vraiment regardé dans le développement visuel - l'utilisation des paradigmes de détection par rapport à l'identification pour obtenir des seuils de perception pendant les années d'âge scolaire. Compte tenu de la différence inhérente du jugement requis pour compléter les tâches de détection et d'identification, on ignore si cette sélection affecte différemment les performances visuelles en fonction du développement. Les résultats ont démontré une tendance relativement stable de la performance de l'âge scolaire à l'adolescence- ce qui suggère que la sensibilité n'a pas été affectée différemment par le choix de paradigme en fonction du développement.</description><description>The term "developmental cognitive neuroscience" emerged during the last decade to encapsulate an exciting innovation towards merging previously disparate disciplines including cognitive science, neuroimaging, neurobiology, molecular genetics and developmental psychology to the study of typical and atypical cognitive development. The aim of this research program was to explore the typical development of two cognitive domains known to be selectively impaired in a number of neurodevelopmental disorders: attention and perception. Studying developing populations presents specific methodological challenges, such as task suitability across the age span being studied, regardless of the cognitive domain assessed. In the attentional domain, Article 1 (The Amsterdam Neuropsychology Tasks: An investigation of the consistency and validity of the test of attention) assessed whether different measures of performance from each task reflect a single attentional process. The results demonstrated that speed and accuracy in visual search and vigilance tasks are independent. These findings highlight the contribution of assessment measures (i.e. measures of speed; measures of accuracy) to the study of attention. Furthermore, this same battery was used to examine the typical development of attentional processing in sub-components of attention (selective attention, sustained attention and control) and to assess the core processes within each task (speed of processing vs. accuracy) in article 2 (Faster but not better: Tracing attentional development with the Amsterdam Neuropsychology Tasks). The results of this study indicated that age-related improvements were present for speed of processing but not for accuracy, whereas task-related differences were present for both core processes (speed of processing and accuracy) with more robust findings in the school-aged group. These findings highlight the importance of examining core processes as well as task demands when assessing sub-component processes across development.The following chapters of this thesis focus on the development of another important cognitive domain integral to developmental neuroscience: visual perception. An advantage to studying the development of visual perception, particularly at its early level, is that mechanisms mediating various types of visual processes can be operationally defined in more stringent terms. Visual perception can be assessed as a function of visual attribute (i.e., luminance vs. texture; static vs. dynamic) which solicit relatively distinct neural processes (striate vs. extra-striate; dorsal vs. ventral, etc.). Perceptual profiles based on such assessments have been used to dissociate between different neurodevelopmental disorders, and forward hypotheses proposing condition-specific neural alterations. Article 3 (The development of luminance- and texture-defined form perception during the school-aged years.) and Article 4 (The differential development of spatial contrast sensitivity for luminance- and texture-defined information.) of this dissertation assessed the development of luminance (simple) or texture (complex) stimuli at different periods of development using two different paradigms; an adapted landolt C and the spatial contrast sensitivity function. The final methodological study explored an issue not really looked at in visual development – the use of detection vs. identification paradigms to obtain perceptual thresholds during the school-aged years. Given the inherent difference in judgement required to complete visual detection and identification tasks, it is unknown whether task selection differentially affects visual performance as a function of development. Results demonstrated a relatively unchanged pattern of performance from the school-ages through adolescence, suggesting that sensitivity was not differentially affected by choice of paradigm as a function of development. </description><creator>Hanck, Julie</creator><contributor>Joseph Rochford (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Kim Cornish (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Examining age related changes in attention and perception in typically developing populations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63t040p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc05k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vf877</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La prédisposition au diabète de type 1 est associé aux variantes génétiques qui modulent le taux d'expression de l'insuline dans le thymus et particulièrement dans les cellules médullaires epithéliales (mTECs). Cette expression de l'insuline ainsi que d'autres auto-antigènes dans les mTECs est essentielle pour maintenir l'auto-tolérance. Bien que le régulateur Aire est reconnu comme le principal contrôleur de l'expression des auto-antigènes il n'existe pas beaucoup plus d'information sur la régulation des auto-antigènes spécifiques et particulièrement sur l'insuline. Ma thèse est centrée sur ces questions.J'ai premièrement obtenu la preuve directe que le taux de glucose, le stimulus principal qui module l'insuline dans le pancréas ne modifie pas les niveaux d'expression de l'insuline dans le thymus, et ceci avec des études in vivo et in vitro. J'ai par après aussi démontré que les cytokines pro-inflammatoires Ifn-γ et Tnf-α ont des effets régulateurs dans le thymus, et l'addition de ces cytokines aux lignées cellulaires mTECs réduit les niveaux de l'insuline. Dans les souris manquant les gènes pour ces cytokines l'expression de l'insuline et d'autres auto-antigènes augmente. En plus, ce mécanisme est indépendant du régulateur Aire et constitue la première observation montrant l'absence de correlation entre l'insuline et Aire. Un autre facteur qui modifie les niveaux de l'insuline est la co-culture des thymocytes avec les mTECs. Le contact direct des deux types de cellules a augmenté l'expression de l'insuline ainsi que l'expression de Aire. De plus, nous avons procédé à l'analyse du profil transcriptionnel d'ARN de deux souches clonales de mTECs, une qui exprime l'insuline et une qui ne l'exprime pas. Ces résultats ont permis une vue d'ensemble des gènes qui sont exprimés par un mTEC individuel, que auparavant était impossible. Un nouveau marqueur de surface a été ainsi identifié, CD34, qui est exprimé à plus haut niveau dans le clone positif pour l'insuline. Les cellules mTECs primaires qui expriment CD34 ont étés séparées et elles expriment un niveau élevé l'insuline et le Aire. Ces résultats ont démontrés des nouveaux mécanismes indépendants de Aire qui contrôlent  l'expression de l'insuline comme auto-antigène dans les mTECs. </description><description>Type 1 diabetes susceptibility is associated with genetic variants that cause a lower level of insulin expression in the thymus, and more specifically in the medullary thymic epithelial cells (mTECs). The expression of insulin as well as other self-antigens in these mTECs has been demonstrated to be an essential component in the maintenance of self-tolerance. Although the Aire regulator is a known modulator of self-antigen expression in mTECs, not much else is known on the regulation of specific self-antigens and particularly of insulin's expression. My thesis project centers on this question.I first generated direct evidence that higher glucose, the main metabolic stimulus regulating insulin secretion in the pancreas, had no effect on the expression of insulin in the thymus with studies both in vivo and in vitro. I then showed that pro-inflammatory cytokines Ifn-γ and Tnf-α have a regulatory effect whereby their addition to cultured mTECs decreased levels of insulin, and mice lacking either of the two cytokines had increased levels of both insulin and other self-antigens. In addition, this mechanism was found to be independent of Aire, the first finding where Aire and insulin expression are discordant. Another factor that modulated the expression of insulin was the co-culturing of thymocytes with mTECs. The direct cell-to-cell contact of the two cell types upregulated insulin expression, as well as the expression of Aire. Furthermore, a microarray analysis generated an expression profile for two individual clones of mTECs, one that expresses insulin and one which does not. This has enabled a comprehensive view of the genes expressed by single mTECs, which had previously been impossible to define. A new surface marker was found to be differentially expressed in the insulin positive clone; CD34. The isolation of CD34+ primary mTECs showed an increased level of insulin expression and Aire expression. These findings have uncovered some of the Aire-independent regulatory mechanisms for insulin expression as a self-antigen in mTECs. </description><creator>Levi, Dina</creator><contributor>Constantin Polychronakos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Characterization of regulators of insulin expression in medullary thymic epithelial cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pv080.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf877</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g3595</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cytomégalovirus humain (HCMV) est un herpèsvirus omniprésent dans la population mondiale, qui provoque des symptômes graves et potentiellement mortels chez les nouveau-nés et les patients immunodéprimés. Les données cliniques et expérimentales indiquent qu'un sous-ensemble de lymphocytes innés, dites tueuses naturelles (NK), joue un rôle crucial dans la résistance à l'infection. Comme l'infection par le CMV murin (MCMV) partage de nombreux aspects physiopathologiques de la maladie humaine, la souris constitue un excellent modèle pour étudier l'infection par le CMV. La susceptibilité au MCMV varie grandement selon les lignées de souris congéniques et ce, en fonction de leur patrimoine génétique. Plus précisément, chaque lignée de souris exprime une variété de récepteurs activateurs ou inhibiteurs spécifiques aux cellules NK, les récepteurs Ly49, parallèlement à des répertoires de CMH de classe I variés, dont certains sont des ligands naturels des récepteurs Ly49. En effet, les cellules NK, grâce à l'expression de ces récepteurs encodés dans la lignée germinale, ont la capacité de reconnaître une infection au CMV, ce qui entraîne leur activation et la destruction des cellules infectées. Néanmoins, le mode exact de reconnaissance des cellules infectées par les cellules NK et l'impact sur l'issue de l'infection sont complexes et encore mal compris. Afin de caractériser les mécanismes moléculaires qui sous-tendent la résistance innée au MCMV, nous avons entrepris une étude systématique des ligands possibles des récepteurs Ly49 et de la nature de leur interaction. Nous avons évalué la capacité de reconnaître l'infection MCMV de différents récepteurs Ly49 activateurs ou inhibiteurs, dans le contexte de divers haplotypes de CMH de classe I in vitro et in vivo. Nous démontrons que l'interaction spécifique entre plusieurs récepteurs Ly49 activateurs et des molécules du CMH de classe I dépend de la présence de gp34/m04, un régulateur viral de la présentation d'antigène. De plus, nous montrons que, comme les récepteurs Ly49 activateurs, les récepteurs Ly49 inhibiteurs peuvent aussi être stimulés par une infection au MCMV. Cette interaction complexe, qui dépend du type de molécules de CMH de classe I, se traduit par des niveaux variable de contrôle de la propagation du MCMV par le système immunitaire. Nos résultats mettent en évidence des mécanismes fondamentaux de la fonction des récepteurs des cellules NK dans la reconnaissance et l'éradication de l'infection virale, et fournissent de nouvelles avenues pour comprendre et manipuler la réponse des cellules NK humaines aux infections virales.</description><description>Human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) is a herpesvirus found commonly in the world population, causing a severe and potentially fatal disease in neonates and immunocompromised patients. Clinical and experimental data indicate that a subset of innate lymphocytes, natural killer (NK) cells, plays a crucial role in resistance to infection. As infection with mouse CMV (MCMV) shares many pathophysiological aspects with the human disease, the mouse represents an excellent model to study CMV infection. The outcome of MCMV infection depends on the host genetic background and thus varies among the multiple inbred mouse strains. Importantly, mouse NK cells, through the expression of germ line encoded receptors, have the ability to recognize CMV infection, resulting in NK cell activation and the destruction of the infected cells. In each strain NK cells express amongst others, different sets of activating and inhibitory Ly49 receptors, in the presence of strain-specific MHC class I molecules, some of which are natural ligands to Ly49 receptors. Nevertheless, the exact mode of NK cell recognition of infected cell and the impact on the outcome of infection are complex and not fully understood. In order to characterize the molecular mechanisms underlying innate resistance to MCMV, we have initiated a systematic study to identify the possible ligands of Ly49 receptors and the nature of their interaction. We assessed the ability of distinct activating and inhibitory Ly49 receptors to recognize MCMV infection, in the context of diverse MHC class I haplotypes in vitro and in vivo. We show that the cognate interaction between several activating Ly49 receptors and MHC class I molecules depends on the presence of the viral regulator of antigen presentation, gp34/m04. Furthermore, we illustrate that, analogous to activating Ly49 receptors, inhibitory Ly49 receptors can be triggered by MCMV infection. This complex interaction, conditional on the type of MHC class I molecules, results in a spectrum of innate immune control of MCMV spread. Altogether, our results identify the fundamental mechanisms of NK cell receptor function in the recognition and eradication of viral infection. These will provide new grounds to understand and manipulate human NK cells in response to viral infections.</description><creator>Pyzik, Michal</creator><contributor>Silvia Vidal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Immunogenetics of infection: MHC class I molecules and NK cell receptors interplay in the recognition of MCMV-infected cell and infection outcome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f9513.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g3595</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150n449</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis is to explore a novel biomimetic control approach for goal-oriented reaching tasks. Specifically, it will demonstrate that a simple spinal-like regulator can exhibit complex behaviours for a variety of movement paradigms. A unique controller is designed based on interpretations of simplified reflex circuits. In addition, special attention is paid to the relationship between the central and spinal motor centers and how they affect the generation of movement commands. It has been observed during visually guided reaching tasks that tectal maps project gain related stimuli to the periphery which may aid in system modulation. By designing the controller to include sensory-integration, it is hypothesized that gain modulation can facilitate unique modes or policies for various reaching tasks. These theories are examined in several essential paradigms that include control of reaching in robots, multi-muscle regulation and coordination in humans or monkeys, as well as kinematic and dynamic variability within each system.The symmetrical reach controller will demonstrate inherent robust behaviours that contrast to earlier theories in biomimetic control, but maintain those that are reminiscent of the biology. Specifically, the research will illustrate an ability to modulate speed, vary accuracy, tune trajectory paths, and even reject external noise, without any need for pre-computations or kinematic planning. Moreover, the system shows adaptive regulation based on sensory dependent stimuli that include internally perceived state estimates, and visually perceived kinematic changes. The thesis will also illustrate how the novel biomimetic controller supports biologically relevant characteristics such as dynamic muscle co-activation and learning as they apply to the underlying system. The theoretical and experimental work presented herein has implications for the development of several rehabilitative devices in biomedical engineering and for improved autonomy in mobile robots.</description><description>Le but de cette thèse est d'explorer une nouvelle approche biomimétique de commande pour des tâches d'orientation du bras vers un but. Spécifiquement, il sera démontré qu'un simple régulateur de type moelle épinière peut présenter des comportements complexes pour une variété de paradigmes de mouvement. Un contrôleur unique est conçu se basant sur une interprétation simplifiée des circuits réflexes. En outre, une attention particulière est prêtée à la relation entre les centres moteurs des systèmes nerveux central et périphérique et comment ils affectent la production des commandes de mouvement. Pendant des tâches d'orientation visuellement guidées, il a été observé que les cartes des Colliculi projetaient des stimuli reliés au gain vers la périphérie, pouvant ainsi faciliter la modulation du système moteur. En concevant le contrôleur afin d'inclure l'intégration sensorielle, on présume que la modulation de gain peut faciliter des modes uniques pour diverses tâches d'atteinte. Ces théories sont examinées selon plusieurs paradigmes essentiels qui incluent la commande de l'atteinte chez les robots, la régulation des systèmes multi-musculaires et la coordination du bras chez l'homme ou le singe, ainsi que la variabilité cinématique et dynamique à l'intérieur de chaque mouvement. Le contrôleur symétrique démontrera que des comportements robustes sont inhérents dans la commande biomimétique, ce qui contraste avec des théories antérieures. Cependant, cette théorie demeure compatible avec les observations en biologie. Spécifiquement, la recherche illustrera la capacité de moduler la vitesse, changer l'exactitude, syntoniser des trajectoires et même rejeter le bruit externe, sans aucun pré-calcul ou planification cinématique. D'ailleurs, le système démontre une régulation adaptative basée sur les stimuli sensoriels qui incluent des estimations d'états internes perçus et des changements cinématiques visuellement perçus. La thèse illustrera également comment le contrôleur biomimétique soutient des caractéristiques biologiquement pertinentes telles que la co-activation dynamique de muscles antagonistes et l'apprentissage. Ce travail théorique et expérimental présenté ci-dessous a des implications pour le développement de plusieurs appareils de réadaptation dans le domaine technologie biomédicale ainsi que pour l'amélioration de l'autonomie chez les robots mobiles.</description><creator>Stefanovic, Filip</creator><contributor>Henrietta L Galiana (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Multi-muscle arm movements without planning: proposing a tunable, scalable and robust biomimetic controller</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p64n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150n449</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p378m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Epidemiological studies, genetic analyses, as well as clinical and experimental data indicate a potential for the innate immune pattern-recognition receptor, the toll-like receptor 4, and its bacterial ligand, lipopolysaccharide, to initiate, exacerbate, or conversely prevent or treat allergic airway disease, depending on conditions and mechanisms that are still being elucidated. Animal studies suggest that many of these pro- or anti-inflammatory events are driven by activation of a signaling pathway downstream of TLR4 which relies upon the intracellular adaptor protein 'myeloid differentiating factor 88' (MyD88), whereas the other major TLR4-activated signaling pathway controlled by the adaptor 'Toll, IL-1 receptor and Resistance protein (TIR) domain-containing adaptor inducing interferon-β' (TRIF), has not been explored in the context of allergic asthma. Here, we investigated the role of TLR4 and TRIF activation in different murine models of experimental allergic asthma. In Chapter 2, we studied its role in the context of exposure via the airways to an extract of a natural aeroallergen, the birch tree pollen, hypothesizing that this pathway might function to prime allergic sensitization and/or to facilitate the amplification of the allergic response. In Chapters 3 and 4, we examined the role of TLR4 and TRIF activation in the context of exposure to a mucosal adjuvant consisting of TLR4 and TLR2 bacterial ligands, intended for potential use in vaccination or allergen-specific immunotherapy, in order to determine whether this pathway was relevant to the inhibition of allergic airway disease development. In this latter context, we also examined cellular mechanisms that may be relevant to the prevention of allergic airway disease, namely the immunomodulatory effect of this adjuvant on the T cell response. We find that in both contexts, the TLR4-TRIF-dependent signaling pathway inhibits aspects of allergic airway disease and thus appears to have protective and potentially immunotherapeutic effects against the development of allergic asthma. We also determined that TLR4 activation and, to a significant degree, TRIF-dependent signaling, can influence the CD4+ T cell response by enhancing the expression of a T cell-expressed co-stimulatory molecule, the inducible co-stimulatory molecule (ICOS), and expanding CD4+ICOS+ cells which may contribute to mediating the TLR4-TRIF-dependent inhibition of allergic airway disease development. Thus, we identify TLR4-TRIF-dependent signaling as a potentially important pathway in allergic asthma and advance current knowledge regarding the adjuvant effect of TLR4 ligands upon T cells.</description><description>Les études épidémiologiques, les analyses génétiques ainsi que les données cliniques et expérimentales indiquent un rôle potentiel pour le récepteur toll-like-4 (TLR4) et son ligand de source bactérienne, le lipopolysaccharide, dans l'initiation, l'exacerbation ou au contraire dans l'inhibition ou le traitement de maladies allergiques respiratoires dépendamment de conditions et de mécanismes qui demeurent encore à être élucidés. Des études réalisées chez l'animal suggèrent que plusieurs de ces événements pro- ou anti-inflammatoires sont induits par l'activation d'une voie de signalisation en aval de TLR4 qui dépend de la protéine adaptatrice 'myeloid differentiating factor 88' (MyD88), alors qu'une autre voie majeure activée par TLR4 et sous le contrôle de l'adaptateur 'Toll, IL-1 receptor and Resistance protein (TIR) domain-containing adaptor inducing interferon-β' (TRIF), n'a pas été encore étudiée dans le contexte de l'asthme. Dans cette étude, nous avons analysé le rôle de l'activation de TLR4 et TRIF dans différents modèles murins d'asthme. Au chapitre 2, nous avons étudié sont rôle suite à une exposition des voies aériennes à un extrait d'un aéroallergène naturel, le pollen de bouleau, dans l'hypothèse que cette voie de signalisation puisse être sollicitée afin d'initier la sensibilisation allergique et/ou faciliter l'amplification de la réponse allergique. Aux chapitres 3 et 4, nous avons examiné le rôle de l'activation de TLR4 et TRIF suite à une exposition à un adjuvant muqueux composé de ligands bactériens de TLR4 et TLR2, potentiellement destinés à un usage en vaccination ou dans le cadre d'une immunothérapie allergène-spécifique, afin de déterminer si cette voie de signalisation était pertinente pour contrer le développement de maladies allergiques respiratoires. Dans ce contexte, nous avons également examiné les mécanismes cellulaires  qui pourraient s'avérer pertinents dans la prévention des maladies respiratoires d'origine allergique, à savoir l'effet immunomodulateur de cet adjuvant sur la réponse des lymphocytes T. Nous avons trouvé que, dans les deux cas, la voie de signalisation TLR4-TRIF bloque plusieurs aspects des maladies respiratoires d'origine allergique et ainsi semble avoir un effet protecteur et potentiellement immunothérapeutique contre le développement de l'asthme. Nous avons également déterminé que l'activation de TLR4 et, dans une large mesure, la voie de signalisation dépendante de TRIF, peut influencer la réponse des cellules T CD4+ en augmentant d'une part l'expression d'une molécule co-stimulatrice exprimée par les cellules T, the inducible co-stimulatory molecule (ICOS), et d'autre part en augmentant la population de cellules CD4+ICOS+ qui contribuent à médier l'inhibition dépendante de TLR4-TRIF sur le développement des maladies allergiques respiratoires. Ainsi, nous avons identifié la voie de signalisation dépendante de TLR4-TRIF comme étant une voie potentiellement importante dans l'asthme et fait avancer les connaissances actuelles concernant l'effet adjuvant des ligands TLR4 sur les cellules T.</description><creator>Shalaby, Karim Hamdy</creator><contributor>James G Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>The role of the TLR4-TRIF axis in allergic airway disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt88z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p378m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712mb33r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The eukaryotic cell cytoskeleton plays many important roles in cells and their coordination is crucial for these important biological processes. Their functions are partially achieved by the actin-microtubule (MT) cross-linking proteins. Growth-arrest-specific (Gas) 2 was originally identified in murine fibroblasts under growth-arrest conditions. Gas2 protein contains putative actin- and MT-binding domains, which makes it a strong candidate to be an actin-MT cross-linking protein. However, the mechanisms of Gas2 cytoskeleton binding and its roles in cell division are still unclear. This thesis is focused on these questions. In Chapter 2, we have determined the Gas2 protein functions in Xenopus laevis embryo cell division and oocyte wound healing process. We have found that the full-length (FL) Gas2 protein and its MT-binding Gas2 domain, but not the actin-binding calponin homology (CH) domain, inhibit cell division and result in multinucleated cells. The observation that Gas2 domain alone can arrest cell division suggests that FL-Gas2 function is mediated by binding MTs. To investigate the mechanism of Gas2-induced cell division arrest, we have used a wound-induced contractile array assay and showed that FL-Gas2 stabilizes MTs. In Chapter 3, we have further investigated the FL-Gas2 protein cytoskeleton binding mechanisms in HeLa cells. The Gas2 domain itself significantly changes MTs morphology into a long loop-like bundled network. The FL-Gas2 facilitates MT polymerization and changes the dynamic behaviors of MTs. There are three protein kinase C (PKC) phosphorylation sites in the FL-Gas2 protein, and phosphomimetic point mutations reveal that all three are involved in the FL-Gas2 protein functional changes. Size-exclusive chromatography finally reveals that the FL-Gas2 protein forms a dynamic complex, which presumably has an important role in its cytoskeleton binding properties. Taken together, our data suggest that the non-phosphorylated FL-Gas2 protein forms a dynamic complex to bundle MTs, but its ability to cross-link F-actin and MTs is achieved by the phosphorylated FL-Gas2 protein. We propose that Gas2 function is mediated by binding and bundling MTs, leading to cell division arrest.</description><description>Le cytosquelette participe à de nombreuses fonctions dans les cellules eucaryotes et sa bonne coordination est essentielle au bon fonctionnement de ces fonctions biologiques. Ces fonctions sont partiellement accomplies grâce aux protéines de liaisons des filaments actine-microtubule (MT). La protéine Gowth-arrest-specific (Gas) 2 a été originellement identifiée dans des fibroblastes murins en arrêt de croissance. Le fait que la protéine Gas2 contienne des domaines putatifs d'intéractions avec actine et les microtubules supporte l'hypothèse qu'elle agit comme protéine de liaison des filaments actine-microtubule. Cependant, les mécanismes que Gas2 utilise pour interagir avec le cytosquelette et participer à la division cellulaire ne sont pas connus. Cette thèse répond à ces questions.Dans le deuxième chapitre, nous avons démontré que la protéine Gas2 participe à la division cellulaire de l'embryon et à la cicatrisation de la plaie de l'ovocyte chez le Xenopus laevis. Nous avons trouvé que la protéine entière (FL) Gas2 et son domaine d'intéraction avec les microtubules, mais pas son domaine d'intéraction avec actine homologue a calponine (CH), inhibent la division cellulaire et résultent en la formation de cellules multinucléées. Nous déduisons du fait que le domaine de Gas2 puisse causer un arrêt de la division cellulaire à lui seul que la protéine entière FL-Gas2  fonctionne grâce à l'intéraction avec les microtubules. Pour étudier comment Gas2 induit l'arrêt de la division cellulaire, nous avons utilisé un essai d'induction de contraction par cicatrisation et démontré que FL-Gas2 stabilise les microtubules. Dans le troisième chapitre, nous avons étudié en détails comment la protéine FL-Gas2 interagit avec le cytosquelette dans les cellules HeLa. Le domaine de Gas2 change dramatiquement la morphologie des microtubules, celles-ci forme un réseau de boucles longues et regroupées. La protéine FL-Gas2 favorise la polymérisation des microtubules et change leur comportement dynamique. Il existe trois sites de phosphorylation par la protéine kinase C (PKC) dans FL-Gas2. Des points de mutations imitant la phosphorylation de ces trois sites ont démontré que les trois sites participent aux changements de fonctionnalité de FL-Gas2. La chromatographie par exclusion de taille a démontré que FL-Gas2 forme un complexe dynamique qui doit jouer un rôle important dans l'intéraction de la protéine avec le cytosquelette.En conclusion, nos résultats suggèrent que la protéine FL-Gas2 non-phosphorylée forme un complexe pour regrouper les microtubules, et qu'elle crée une liaison entre F-actine et les microtubules lorsqu'elle est phosphorylée. Nous formulons hypothèse que Gas2 agit en intéragissant et en regroupant les microtubules ce qui cause un arrêt de la division cellulaire. </description><creator>Zhang, Tong</creator><contributor>Craig A. Mandato (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>The investigation of growth-arrest-specific 2 protein functions in cell division and its cytoskeleton binding mechanisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182p58r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712mb33r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c4105</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is undeniable that climatic changes have affected species distributions and adaptations, and considerable effort has been deployed in the last decades to understand their consequences on genetic variation. However, little is known about how climate changes affect evolution of developmental systems within species. To explore this question, I studied populations of the ant Monomorium emersoni in five Arizona Sky Islands. These populations have experienced a climatic warm-up following the last glaciation, which is predicted to further continue under anthropogenic climate change scenarios. Queens of this species have two morphs, winged and wingless, where they each represent a different life history. First, I determined that the wingless queens phenotype has evolved in parallel on each of the Sky Islands and emerged in response to an inherent developmental propensity in combination with changes in the habitat following the last glaciation. I discovered some variations across populations in the developmental genetic processes that underlie the wingless phenotype, and that these variations reflect a demographic split between populations that occurred in the past. I also found that some other changes are shared among all populations, revealing a deterministic evolution of some part of the wing patterning gene network, independent of population history. Furthermore, I identified in the M. emersoni genome a signature of divergent selection on several outlier loci suggesting that populations are also adapting to temperature gradients within each Sky Island following the climatic warm up. This adaptive genomic divergence appears to con- strain gene flow among populations from divergent thermal environments within the same Sky Island. In general, my results show that environmental change can lead to adaptive divergence modifying population demographic parameters, and that it can also facilitate the evolution of variations in developmental systems that can fuel to further phenotypic diversification. Past climatic changes are therefore generating novelties across levels of biological organization.</description><description>Il est maintenant indéniable que les changements dans le climat ont affecté les distributions d'espèces et leurs adaptations. Un effort considérable a été déployé au cours des dernières décennies pour comprendre leur conséquence sur la variation génétique. Cependant, on connait très peu leurs effets sur l'évolution du développement et des réseaux géniques d'une espèce. Pour explorer cette question, j'ai étudié des populations de la fourmi Monomorium emersoni dans cinq Sky Islands d'Arizona. Ces populations ont subi un réchauffement climatique et des changements drastiques dans leur environnement suite à la dernière glaciation, une tendance qui se poursuivra selon les modèles de réchauffement climatique anthropique. Les reines de cette espèce présentent deux morphes, ailée et aptère, qui représentent deux histoires de vie distinctes. Premièrement, j'ai déterminé que le phénotype de reine aptère a évolué en parallèle sur chaque Sky Island et a émergé en réponse à une prédisposition développementale en combinaison avec les changements dans son habitat à la suite au réchauffement climatique après la dernière glaciation. J'ai découvert que certaines variations entre les populations dans les processus génétiques développementaux propres au phénotype aptère et que ces différences reflètent une division démographique antérieure des populations. J'ai par ailleurs trouvé que certains autres changements sont partagés entre toutes les populations, révélant une évolution déterministe du réseau génique propre au phénotype aptère, indépendante de l'histoire démographique. De plus, j'ai identifié dans le génome de M. emersoni une signature de sélection divergente sur plusieurs loci outliers, suggérant que les populations sont aussi adaptées aux gradients de température sur un Sky Island. Cette divergence adaptative semble restreindre le flux génique entre les populations localisées dans des environnements thermiques différents sur un même Sky Island. En général, mes résultats montrent que les changements environnementaux peuvent mener à une divergence adaptative qui modifie les paramètres démographiques à l'intérieur d'une espèce et qu'ils peuvent également faciliter l'évolution de variations développementales qui peuvent par la suite alimenter la diversification phénotypique. En conséquence, les changements climatiques passés génèrent des nouveautés sur plusieurs niveaux d'organisation biologique.</description><creator>Favé, Marie-Julie</creator><contributor>Ehab Abouheif (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Zoology </subject><title>The role of past climate change in driving novelties in Sky Island ant populations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290f02c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c4105</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cx71x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif de cette thèse est d'étudier les réponses biologiques musculo-squelettiques de l'acide linoléique conjugué (ALC). Méthodologie: Étude 1: Des rats Sprague-Dawley ont été randomisés pour recevoir le régime de contrôle AIN-93 ou le même régime supplémenté avec 0,5% c9, t11 + 0,5% t10, c12 d'ALC en forme d'AGL ou de TG. Les profils d'acides gras du foie ont été évalués pour l'incorporation de l'ALC dans les tissus. Les biomarqueurs osseux ainsi que la densité osseuse et la composition corporelle ont été mesurés après 4, 8, 16 semaines. Étude 2: Des rats Sprague-Dawley ont été randomisés au sevrage pour recevoir le régime de contrôle AIN-93 ou le même régime supplémenté avec 0,5% c9, t11 + 0,5% t10, c12 d'ALC en AGL pendant 16 semaines. Du sang a été recueilli à la fois dans un état nourri et à jeun. La PTH a été évaluée à l'aide de test de la PTH de deuxième et de troisième génération. Étude 3: Des hommes âgés de 19 à 53 ans (n = 31) ont été randomisés en double aveugle, lors d'un essai clinique contrôlé pour recevoir: 1,5 g / j ou 3,0 g / j de c9, t11 (4:1 c9, t11 à t10, c12 rapport d'isoforme) ou un placebo (huile d'olive 3 g / j) pendant 16 semaines. L'absorptiométrie biphotonique à rayons X (DXA) a été réalisée pour évaluer la composition corporelle. Des échantillons de sang ont été obtenus mensuellement pour évaluer les changements dans la concentration de la PTH, la 25-hydroxy-vitamine D (25(OH)D), l'iCa, le phosphate et le profil lipidique. Étude 4: En tant que modèle de vieillissement avancé, des cochons d'inde pigmentés (n = 40) on été randomizés à 70 semaines d'âge à 4 groupes: 1) chirurgie fictive (SHAM) + Régime de contrôle (CTRL), 2) SHAM + régime d'ALC (ALC) (1,0% 4:1 c9, t11 à t10, c12 rapport d'isoforme), 3) orchidectomie (ORX) + CTRL, 4) ORX +ALC. L'analyse de la densité osseuse et la composition corporelle (par DXA) ainsi que des échantillons sanguins recueillis pour mesurer la testostérone, l'estrogène, l'interleukin-6 (IL-6), ont été. À 16 semaines, l'iCa et la 25(OH)D ont été évaluées ainsi que, la microarchitecture osseuse utilisant la microtomodensitométrie, la force des os ainsi que le taux de synthèse protéique fractionnaire dans les muscles squelettiques en utilisant une dose d'inondation de 40% en moles de L-[ring-2H5]-phénylalanine (1,5 mmol / kg ip). Résultats: Étude 1: Il n'existe aucune différence entre les groupes pour les biomarqueurs et la masse osseuse, ni l'équilibre minéral. L'enrichissement du foie en c9, t11 sous forme AGL était plus grand que sous forme de TG et AIN-93. Étude 2. Chez les mâles et les femelles, il n'y avait pas de différence entre les rats nourris et à jeun lorsque la PTH était évaluée en utilisant le test PTH INT. Cependant, chez les femelles seulement, la PTH mesurée à l'aide de la PTH Bioactive, était significativement plus faible dans le groupe nourri par rapport au groupe à jeun. Étude 3: Les hommes avec un statut d'ALC c9, t11 dans les globules rouges au dessus de la médiane avait une densité minérale osseuse (DMO) du corps et un pourcentage de masse maigre du corps plus élevé, alors que l'indice de masse corporelle (IMC) et le pourcentage de masse grasse corporelle étaient plus bas. Dans l'analyse de régression, le statut d'ALC c9, t11 dans les globules rouges représentait une proportion significative (r2 = 0,10) de la variation de la DMO du corps entier (P = 0,03). Il n'y avait pas de différence temporel et de traitement pour n'importe quel autre mesure d'os ou de biomarqueurs du métabolisme osseux, y compris la PTH. Étude 4: L'ALC a empêché la perte de la densité osseuse et du volume osseux métaphysaire ainsi que l'augmentation de la porosité diaphysaires observés après l'orchidectomie. Également, aucunes différences dans les taux de synthèse fractionnaire des protéines myofibrillaires et sarcoplasmiques n'ont été détectées. Signification: Dans l'ensemble, des petits avantages de l'ALC sur la perte d'os et de muscles ont été observés.</description><description>The overall objective of this thesis was to investigate differences between the FFA and TG forms of CLA regarding incorporation in liver and biological musculoskeletal responses; if assessment of PTH is affected by gender, fasting and the type of PTH assay used; if CLA status, as measured by red blood cell CLA content, in men is positively related to body composition and bone mass; if CLA supplementation in healthy men reduces PTH concentration; and if CLA can prevent decreases in bone and muscle mass typically observed in advanced aging. Methods: Study 1: Sprague-Dawley rats were randomized at weaning to receive a control AIN-93 diet or the same diet supplemented with 0.5% c9, t11 CLA + 0.5% t10, c12 CLA in FFA or TG form. Liver fatty acid profiles were assessed using gas chromatography. Biomarkers of bone metabolism were measured along with bone density and body composition using dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) after 4, 8, 16 wk. Study 2: Sprague-Dawley rats were randomized at weaning to receive a control AIN-93 diet or the same diet supplemented with 0.5% c9, t11 CLA + 0.5% t10, c12 CLA in FFA for 16 wk. At wk 16, a blood sample was collected in both a fed state and a non-fed state. PTH was assessed using both a second and third generation PTH assays. Study 3: Healthy men 19-53 y (n=31) were randomized in a double-blind, placebo controlled clinical dose-response trial to receive either: 1.5 g/d or 3.0 g/d of c9, t11 CLA (4:1 c9, t11 to t10, c12 isomer ratio) or placebo (olive oil 3 g/d) for 16 wk. DXA was performed to assess body composition at baseline and end of study and blood samples were obtained monthly to evaluate changes in PTH concentration, 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25(OH)D), iCa, phosphate and lipid profile. Study 4: As an advanced aging model, pigmented guinea pigs (n=40) were block randomized by weight at 70 wk of age to 4 groups: 1) SHAM+Control diet, 2) SHAM+ CLA diet (1.0% 4:1 c9, t11 to t10, c12 isomer ratio), 3) Orchidectomy (ORX)+Control diet, 4) ORX+CLA diet. DXA scans for bone density and body composition in addition to blood samples to measure testosterone, estrogen, interleukin-6 (IL-6), were performed at baseline and wk 16. At 16 wk, iCa and 25(OH)D were assessed as well as, bone microarchitecture using micro computed tomography, bone strength and acute protein fractional synthesis rate in skeletal muscle using a flooding dose of 40 mol% of L-[ring-2H5]-phenylalanine (1.5 mmol/kg ip). Results: Study 1: There were no differences among groups for growth, bone biomarkers or mass nor mineral balance. Liver enrichment of c9, t11 CLA in FFA form was greater than TG form and AIN-93. Study 2: Females had a lower iCa compared to males. In males and females, there was no difference between fed and non-fed groups when PTH was assessed using the INT PTH assay. However, in females only, PTH measured using the BIO PTH was significantly lower in the fed group versus the non-fed. Study 3: Men with red blood cell (RBC) c9, t11 CLA status above the median had higher whole body bone mineral density (BMD) and whole body lean mass % (WBL), whereas body mass index (BMI) and whole body fat mass % (WBF) were lower. In regression analysis, RBC c9, t11 CLA status accounted for a significant proportion (r2=0.10) of the variation in whole body BMD (P=0.03). There were no time or treatment differences among any bone or biomarkers of bone metabolism including PTH. Study 4: CLA prevented an increase in Tb.Sp and a decrease in vBMD in metaphyseal regions of ORX compared to SHAM CTRL. CLA also decreased porosity in ORX compared to SHAM. ORX decreased free testosterone whereas interleukin-6 increased. CLA prevented ORX-induced loss of metaphyseal vBMD and bone volume as well as enhanced diaphyseal porosity. Also, no differences in quadriceps mixed muscle sarcoplasmic and myofibrillar protein fractional synthesis rate were detected. Significance: Overall, small benefits of CLA on the musculoskeletal system were observed.</description><creator>Deguire, Jason Robert</creator><contributor>Hope Weiler (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Dietary supplementation of conjugated linoleic acid: muscoskeletal investigations in men and selected animal models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj29j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx71x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935637g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La psychologie évolutionniste est une perspective théorique de plus en plus consolidée par des études empiriques, mais son application potentielle à la psychologie de la personnalité demeure inassouvie (Buss, 1999). La présente thèse se veut une conciliation de la psychologie évolutionniste et la psychologie de la personnalité. Zuroff et ses collègues (2010) suggèrent qu'une théorie évolutionnaire de la personnalité pourrait permettre l'identification de différences individuelles existant dans les domaines sociaux fondamentaux postulé par la psychologie évolutionniste. Le questionnaire des styles d'échanges sociaux (Social Exchange Styles Questionnaire) fut développé dans le but d'évaluer les différences individuels dans le domaine de la réciprocité (Leybman et al., 2011a). Dans cette thèse, le modèle de style d'échange social fut développé et exploré en plus de détails. L'article 1 a présenté un modèle plus détaillé des styles d'échanges sociaux, ainsi que la version révisée du questionnaire des styles d'échanges sociaux (SESQ-II), lequel évalue les différences individuels selon 5 dimensions: Poursuite, Justice, Individualisme, Recherche de Bénéfices et Surinvestissement. Le SESQ-II a démontré une bonne cohérence interne et validité du construit. Aucune des dimensions n'étaient redondantes avec l'échelle de réciprocité de normes personnelles, ni avec les dimensions de styles d'attaches adultes. De plus, les dimensions avaient de relations prévisibles avec les cinq facteurs de trait, et avec des variables liées aux perceptions de soi et d'autrui. L'Article 1 adresse aussi le lien entre les dimensions et le support sociale reçu et perçue. La Poursuite et le Surinvestissement prédissent de façon négative la perception de support, tandis que la Justice prédit positivement la perception de support. De plus, l'Individualisme prédit négativement la réception de support. Nos dimensions prédissent le support social au-delà des cinq facteurs de trait.L'article 2 tentait d'enrichir le model d'échange social en en étudiant une seule dimension d'échange: la Poursuite. Les antécédents développementaux et conséquences affectives de la Poursuites ont été explorés. La théorie du Marcher Biologique (Noe &amp; Hammerstein, 1994; 1995) a été utilisé pour identifier de potentiels antécédents développementaux de la Poursuite. La Poursuite pouvais être prédite par les mémoires d'instances d'avoir eu moins de ressources que ses pairs, d'avoir eu peu de control de ressources, ainsi que de surprotection parentale. La poursuite a aussi été prédite par une interaction entre peu de chaleur parentale et être gâté. Afin de tester les conséquences affectives de la Poursuite, nous avons examiné la relation entre le niveau de Poursuite des gens et leurs réactions émotionnelles face au support sociale reçu. En utilisant la même sous-population qui a été utilisé ultérieurement durant la deuxième étude de l'Article 1, des analyses a multiniveaux ont démontré que les gens qui avaient de haut niveaux de Poursuite ressenti plus de Jovialité durant les jours durant lesquels ils ont reçu des niveaux de support particulièrement élevés. Ils ont aussi ressenti de hauts niveaux d'Hostilité durant les jours ou ils rapportent d'avoir reçu de plus bas niveaux de support qu'à l'habitude. De résultats similaires n'ont pas été obtenus avec les mesures de Sérénité, de Peur, ou de Culpabilité en tant que variables dépendantes, démontrant ainsi la spécificité des effets à la Jovialité et l'Hostilité. Les résultats sont adressés en termes de contributions théorique qui surviennent de l'intégration de la psychologie évolutionniste et la psychologie de la personnalité. De plus, nous avons identifiés des pistes de recherche pour le futur. Finalement des applications pratiques de styles d'échange social sont discutées en mettant de l'emphase sur les implications pour la conceptualisation et le traitement de troubles mentaux dans le contexte de la psychologie clinique.</description><description>Evolutionary psychology is a theoretical perspective that is increasingly supported by empirical studies, but its potential to be applied to personality psychology remains largely unfulfilled (Buss, 1999). The current dissertation sought to bring the perspective of evolutionary psychology to bear on personality psychology. Zuroff and colleagues (2010) proposed that an evolutionary theory of personality could seek to identify individual differences in the core social domains that are postulated by evolutionary psychologists. Following this line of thinking, the Social Exchange Styles Questionnaire (SESQ) was developed to assess individual differences within the reciprocity domain (Leybman et al., 2011a). For this dissertation, the social exchange style model was further developed and explored. Article 1 presented an expanded social exchange style model, along with the revised Social Exchange Styles Questionnaire (SESQ-II), which assesses individual differences in ways that people approach and maintain exchange relationships in terms of five dimensions: Tracking, Fairness, Individualism, Benefit-Seeking, and Overinvestment. The SESQ-II showed good internal consistency, retest reliability, and construct validity. Regarding construct validity, multiple regressions demonstrated that none of the social exchange style dimensions was redundant with the Personal Norms of Reciprocity Scale (Perugini et al., 2003), nor with dimensions of adult attachment styles. Additionally, multiple regressions demonstrated that the social exchange style dimensions had predictable relationships with the five-factor traits, and with variables related to perceptions of oneself and others. Article 1 also addressed the relationship between social exchange style dimensions and perceived and received social support in a second study that used a daily diary method. Multilevel modeling showed that Tracking and Overinvestment each negatively predicted perceived support, while Fairness positively predicted perceived support. Additionally, Individualism negatively predicted received support. Social exchange style dimensions predicted social support over and above the five-factor traits.Article 2 sought to extend the social exchange style model and did this by focusing on a single social exchange dimension: Tracking. The developmental antecedents and affective consequences of Tracking were explored. Biological market theory (Noë &amp; Hammerstein, 1994; 1995) was used to identify potential developmental antecedents to Tracking. Multiple regression analyses showed that Tracking was predicted by recalled experiences of having less access to resources than one's peers, having low control over resources, and parental overprotectiveness. Tracking was also predicted by an interaction of low parental warmth and being spoiled. To test the affective consequences of Tracking, we examined the relationship between people's Tracking levels and their emotional reactions to received social support. Using the same sample that was used in the second study of Article 1, multilevel analyses showed that people who were high in Tracking experienced more Joviality on days when they experienced particularly high levels of received support, and that they experienced high Hostility on days when they experienced less received support than usual. Similar results were not obtained with Serenity, Fear, or Guilt as the dependent variables, demonstrating the specificity of the effects to Joviality and Hostility.The results of these studies are discussed in terms of theoretical contributions that stem from integrating evolutionary psychology with personality psychology. Additionally, avenues for future research to elaborate both the content and process components of our model of social exchange styles are identified. Finally, practical applications of social exchange styles are discussed with a focus on implications for conceptualization and treatment of disorders within clinical psychology. </description><creator>Leybman, Michelle Judith</creator><contributor>David C Zuroff (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Psychology - Personality</subject><title>Social exchange styles: An evolutionary model of individual differences in exchange relationships</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt359.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935637g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xg338</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Husbands Living with Women on Dialysis: Embracing Their Transformed LifeThe purpose of this qualitative study was to explore the adjustment process of husbands living with women on dialysis. Using Glaser's (1978) grounded theory methodology, data were collected from 18 husbands through semi-structured face-to-face or telephone tape-recorded interviews. In using the constant comparative method of data analysis, the most central issue for these husbands was dealing with multiple changes imposed by the demands and impact of kidney failure and its treatment regimens on various dimensions of their lives. The changes impacted roles and responsibilities at home and work, social and recreational activities, finances, relationships with their spouse and others, home environment, daily routines, and future plans, as well as health and/or sleep patterns. Although the impact of these changes created many hardships for husbands, witnessing their wives' suffering was more distressing. In response, these men involved themselves in supporting their wives and engaging in the basic social process of embracing their transformed life. The four stages of embracing a transformed life are becoming aware,  involving themselves, centering life on their wives, and striving to achieve balance. The marital relationship, the women's health status, as well as the presence of informal support and formal support are conditions which significantly influenced the process.  The theory of embracing a transformed life provides a framework for understanding and explaining the complex interplay of strategies undertaken by these husbands to respond to, adjust to, and integrate changes in their daily and future lives. Moreover, the focus on husbands living with women on dialysis contributes towards closing an existing gap in knowledge and the findings underscore the husbands' abilities to learn and carry out complex roles, responsibilities, and routines that require sophisticated observation, decision making, and technical and problem-solving skills. The discrete stages of the theory guide nurses to better understand the various changes dialysis-caregivers may experience during different phases of the patients' illness trajectory and to implement supportive care to enhance their adjustment and sustain their efforts.Keywords: dialysis, spousal caregiver, dialysis-caregiver, adjustment, change, chronic kidney disease, end-stage renal disease.    </description><description>Les hommes habitant avec une femme dialysée: Accepter la transformation qui s'effectue dans sa vieLe but de cette étude qualitative était d'examiner le processus d'adaptation des hommes habitant avec une femme qui subit des traitements de dialyse. Les données ont été recueillies au cours d'entretiens semi-structurés enregistrés, réalisés en personne ou au téléphone, auprès de 18 hommes mariés, conformément à la méthode de la théorie ancrée décrite par Glaser en 1978. Selon la méthode comparative constante d'analyse de données, il s'est avéré que la préoccupation centrale de ces hommes était de composer avec les multiples changements, aux différents aspects de leur vie, qu'imposaient les demandes et les répercussions de l'insuffisance rénale et du schéma thérapeutique correspondant. Les changements ont en effet une incidence sur divers aspects de leur vie, notamment les rôles et les responsabilités à la maison et au travail, les activités sociales et récréatives, la situation financière, les relations de couple et les relations amicales, l'ambiance à la maison, les activités quotidiennes, les projets futurs, la santé et la structure du sommeil. Bien que ces changements aient occasionné maintes difficultés pour ces hommes, il leur était encore plus difficile de voir leur femme souffrir. Ils se sont donc appliqués à leur apporter du soutien et à entamer le processus social fondamental qui consiste à accepter volontiers la transformation qui s'effectue dans leur vie. Les quatre étapes à suivre pour accepter la transformation d'une vie sont la prise de conscience, la participation, la centralisation de la vie sur la conjointe, et la recherche d'équilibre. La relation de couple, la santé de la femme et la présence d'un soutien formel et informel sont tous des facteurs qui ont une grande incidence sur le processus. La théorie qui consiste à accepter la transformation d'une vie propose un cadre qui permet de comprendre et d'expliquer l'ensemble complexe de stratégies qu'emploient ces hommes pour répondre aux changements, s'y adapter et les intégrer à leurs activités quotidiennes et à leur avenir. En outre, le fait de diriger le regard sur les hommes habitant avec une femme dialysée contribue à combler une lacune existante sur le plan des connaissances, et les constatations soulignent la capacité de ces hommes à apprendre et à mettre en pratique des rôles, des responsabilités et des routines complexes qui demandent des compétences avancées en observation, en prise de décision et en résolution de problème de même que sur le plan technique. Les étapes subtiles de la théorie guident les infirmières vers une meilleure compréhension des différents changements que les fournisseurs de soins de dialyse peuvent observer durant les différentes phases de la maladie de la patiente et leur permettent d'adopter des méthodes de soins de soutien qui facilitent leur adaptation et les poussent à poursuivre leurs efforts.Mots clés: dialyse, époux/épouse aidant, aidant en dialyse, adaptation, changement, insuffisance rénale chronique, maladie rénale terminale.</description><creator>Pelletier-Hibbert, Maryse L</creator><contributor>Margaret A Purden (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Franco Carnevale (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Philosophy, Religion And Theology - Philosophy</subject><title>Husbands living with women on dialysis: embracing their transformed life</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1619677.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xg338</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Ingram School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zr901</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the application of k-space Image Correlation Spec- troscopy (kICS) to the analysis of fluorescence microscopy image time series for the measurement of particle diffusion in heterogeneous membranes, composed of micro- domains. The extension, testing and application of kICS for such measurements is developed both in silico with simulation and with in vivo cellular experiments.Connections between kICS analysis and other existing fluorescent microscopy techniques used in the study of heterogeneous membranes, such as single particle tracking (SPT) and spot vary Fluorescence Correlation Spectroscopy (FCS) are introduced. This is followed by the development of kICS theory of fluorescent particle diffusion within a heterogeneous two dimensional (2D) environment. Two possible membrane heterogeneities, isolated lipid micro-domains and actin proximal meshwork, are considered separately. The emergent models suggest that the kICS correlation function (CF) can be fit by a sum of two Gaussians in the case of particle diffusion in the presence of isolated micro-domains. These two fit components, called 'fast' and 'slow', with the fast associated with the rapid decay of the kICS CF at small spatial frequencies due to particle motion on large spatial scales outside domains while the slow component refers to the confined particle motion on large spatial frequencies or small spatial scales in domains. On the other hand, the meshwork confinement is well fit with a single Gaussian model for the analysis of kICS CF. These models suggest that the exponents and amplitudes of the fits embed the characteristic system parameters such as diffusion coefficients outside and inside domains, the partitioning rates, micro-domains radii and mesh pore size.Furthermore, systematic simulations to study different confinement scenarios were conducted and the calculated kICS correlation functions were fit and the output interpreted for recovery of self system parameters. The characterization of the simulated data suggests that kICS CFs exhibit various confinement dependent features, such as decays due to effective slow and fast dynamics populations and effective domain sizes. The in silico characterization of different confinement scenarios, suggests a connection between the apparent measured confinement properties, and the set system defining parameters. We explore the range and limits where confinement effects can be detected and accurately measured by kICS analysis. Possible systematic errors in the values of the fit extracted parameters due to background noise is discussed with possible alternative solutions.Finally, we apply this extension of kICS to the heterogeneous membrane en- vironment to explore the confinement dynamics of GPI-GFP anchored proteins in the basal plasma membrane of COS-7 cells. We employ a novel labelling approach of GPI-GFP using anti-GFP-Alexa594 and image the protein in COS-7 cell mem- branes with TIRF microscopy. Cells were exposed to enzymatic treatments, using the Cholesterol Oxidase (COase) and Sphingomyelinase (SMase), in order to dis- rupt membrane domains and change GPI-GFP confinement dynamics. We observe that GPI-GFP mobility and the effective domain size measured correlates with the enzymatic exposure time. We attribute it to the conversion of the membrane domain constituents, cholesterol and sphingomyelin, upon the enzymatic reactions, leading to membrane domain that are effectively larger and leakier. Finally, we conclude with possible improvements and future directions.</description><description>La thèse qui suit est a propos de l'adaptation de la technique de la spectroscopie par la corrélation des images dans l'espace de Fourier, appelle kICS. La nouveauté consiste en utilisation de kICS pour analyser les séries temporelles d'images fluorescentes afin de caractériser la diffusion des particules en présence des membranes hétérogénes, composées de micro-domaines.Tout d'abord, une parallèle est exposée entre l'analyse fondée sur kICS pro- posé ci-dessus et d'autres techniques de microscopie à fluorescence existantes et utilisées dans l'étude des membranes hétérogénes. Ensuite, on expose le développement de la théorie de kICS dans les cas de la diffusion des particules fluorescentes dans un espace hétérogène bidimensionnel (2D). Les deux hétérogénéités membranaires possibles, micro-domaines lipidiques isolés et le réseau de l'actine proximale, sont considérés séparément. Les modèles émergents suggèrent que la fonction de corrélation de kICS doit être caractérisé par une somme de deux Gaussiennes dans le cas de la dynamique des particules en présence de micro-domaines isolés. Ces deux éléments, appelés 'rapide' et 'lent', représentent les composantes dynamiques a deux échelles d'espace différentes. La rapide est associé à la décroissance rapide de la fonction de corrélation de kICS à petites fréquences spatiales dues au mouvement des particules sur de grandes échelles spatiales. La composante lente réfère au mouvement des particules confinées à des petites échelles spatiales, observées sur de grandes fréquences spatiales de kICS. D'autre part, la fonction de corrélation de kICS due au confinement par le réseau du cytosquelette peut être caractérise par unique décroissance Gaussienne. Ces modèles suggèrent que les exposants et les amplitudes obtenus par la caractérisation de la fonction kICS dépend des paramètres caractéristiques du système tels que les coefficients de diffusion à l'extérieur et à l'intérieur de domaines, les taux de migration de particules vers intérieur ou extérieur de micro-domaines ou des tailles de porosités du réseaux du cytosquelette.Les études systématiques par les simulations des scénarios différents de confinement et leurs effets sur la fonction de corrélation de kICS ont été explorés. La caractérisation des données simulées suggèrent que les fonctions de corrélation ont des caractéristiques qui dépendent de confinement et les propriétés spécifiques, tels que la dynamique des populations lents et rapides et la tailles effective de micro-domaines. La caractérisation des scénarios de confinement différents, représente les liens entre les propriétés apparentes mesurées de confinement, et un ensemble de paramètres définissant hétérogénéité. Nous explorons les limites pour lesquelles des effets de confinement ne sont pas observées dans la fonction de corrélation kICS. Les éventuelles erreurs systématiques dans les valeurs des paramètres extraits à cause du bruit de fond est discuté avec des possibles solutions. Finalement, nous utilisons l'analyse afin d'explorer la dynamique de confinement de la protéine ancrée à GPI-GFP dans la membrane plasmique basale des cellules COS-7. Nous explorons une approche nouvelle de la conjugaison entre le GPI-GFP et les anti-GFP-Alexa594 et imagé par la microscopie TIRF. Les cellules ont été exposées à des traitements enzymatiques, par Coase et SMase, afin de perturber domaines membranaires et changer la dynamique de confinement de GPI-GFP. Les réactions enzymatiques augmentent la mobilité et la taille effective des domaines de GPI-GFP. Nous attribuons cela à la conversion des constituants des domaines, le cholestérol et la sphingomyéline, par les réactions enzymatiques, ce qui conduit aux plus grandes et moins étanches domaines membranaires.</description><creator>Pandžić, Elvis</creator><contributor>Paul Wiseman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biophysics - General</subject><title>Measurement of protein transport and confinement in heterogeneous membranes by k-space image correlation spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wt953.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zr901</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074z51j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines a novel type of standardization in medicine by investigating the production and regulation of clinical practice guidelines. As an important tool of the Evidence Based Medicine (EBM) movement, guidelines have been at the center of polarized debates in which they are praised for rationalizing medicine and criticized for undermining humanism in health care. Based on document analysis, interviews and (participant) observation, this dissertation examines how 'evidence based' guideline developers respond to such contradictory demands and critiques. In doing so, I present an empirical examination of the way EBM practices construct, avoid or reconcile tensions between supposed binaries such as universal/local, evidence/values, standards/individuality, science/care. After the introduction and a review of the existing literature on the epistemological basis and regulatory impact of EBM guidelines, the findings are presented in two parts. The first part analyzes how formal EBM principles are understood and performed during guideline production, with Chapter three highlighting the diversity of knowledge, procedures and materials required to classify Evidence and formulate the guideline text. Chapter four analyzes how an absence of Evidence is handled and proposes the term 'Evidence Searched Guidelines' to capture the distinctive character of EBM guidelines. The second part focuses on 'guidelines for guidelines' that regulate guideline development. Chapter five presents the Guidelines International Network, which aims for a 'universal' procedure for standard-setting, but objects to the standardization of guidelines. Chapter six presents four models of Patient &amp; Public Involvement that aim to integrate evidence with 'values' and 'context', making guidelines more personalized, democratic, locally relevant and/or objective. In aiming for Gold Standards that avoid standardization, EBM guideline developers challenge the accounts of EBM proponents and critics alike. The contested relation between the standardized (or universal) and the individualized (or local) at the heart of Evidence Based Medicine is managed not by the quantity, quality or universality of evidence, but by standardization of procedures.</description><description>Cette thèse étudie la production et la réglementation des lignes directrices pour la pratique clinique, afin d'examiner un type de standardisation médicale novateur. Servant d'outil important dans le mouvement de la médecine basée sur les données probantes (Evidence Based Medicine ou EBM), les lignes directrices ont été au centre de débats polarisés dans lesquels on fait l'éloge d'elles pour avoir rationalisées la médecine et on les critique d'avoir minées l'humanisme dans les soins de santé. Basée sur l'analyse de documents, des interviews et l'observation (participative), cette thèse examine comment les développeurs des lignes directrices répondent aux telles demandes et critiques contradictoires. Ce faisant, je présente un examen empirique des façons que les pratiques de la EBM construisent, évitent et réconcilient les tensions entre de présumés binaires, tels universel/local, données probantes/valeurs, standards/individualité et sciences/soins. Après l'introduction et l'analyse de la littérature existante sur les bases épistémologiques et l'impact de la réglementation des lignes directrices de la EBM, les résultats sont présentés en deux parties. La première partie analyse la compréhension et la performance des principes formels de la EBM durant la production des lignes directrices, le troisième chapitre mettant l'accent sur la diversité des connaissances, des procédures et des matériels nécessaires pour classifier les données probantes et formuler le texte des lignes directrices. Le quatrième chapitre analyse comment l'absence de données probantes est gérée et propose le terme «Evidence Searched Guidelines» (lignes directrices cherchantes les données probantes) pour saisir le caractère distinctif des lignes directrices de la EBM. La deuxième partie met l'accent sur les «lignes directrices pour les lignes directrices», qui régularisent le développement des lignes directrices. Le cinquième chapitre présente le Guidelines International Network, visant une procédure universelle pour l'établissement des normes, mais s'opposant à la standardisation des lignes directrices. Le sixième chapitre présente quatre modèles d'Implication du Public visant à intégrer les données probantes à des «valeurs» et des «contextes», afin de rendre les lignes directrices plus personnalisées, démocratiques, pertinentes et/ou objectives. Visant des Étalons-or qui évitent la standardisation, les développeurs des lignes directrices de la EBM mettent au défi à la fois les explications des défenseurs de la EBM et celles des détracteurs. Le rapport contesté entre standardisé (ou universel) et personnalisé (ou local) au cœur de la médecine fondée sur les données probantes n'est pas gouverné par la quantité, la qualité ou l'universalité des données probantes, mais par la standardisation des procédures. </description><creator>Knaapen, Anne-Loes</creator><contributor>Alberto Cambrosio (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Sociology - Sociology General</subject><title>In search of standards that avoid standardization: the production and regulation of evidence based guidelines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sx35h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074z51j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj217</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transforming growth factor-beta (TGF-ß) is a multifunctional growth factor involved in a variety of cellular processes including wound healing, extracellular matrix deposition, inflammation, and fibrosis. Excessive TGF-ß signaling during wound healing causes sustained inflammation and elevated expression of extracellular matrix proteins, which have both been associated with fibrosis and scarring. Therefore, inhibition of TGF-ß during wound healing is an attractive target to reduce fibrotic skin disorders.  Our lab is interested in CD109, a 150 kDa GPI-anchored protein which has been shown to bind TGF-ß in its soluble form and to inhibit TGF-ß signaling in keratinocytes and fibroblasts in vitro.  The TGF-ß antagonist properties of CD109 suggest that modulation of its expression in vivo might ameliorate fibrosis and scarring, perhaps via differential activation of keratinocytes and fibroblasts.  To investigate the role of CD109 in the skin, we generated transgenic mice overexpressing CD109 in the epidermis.To explore the role of CD109 during wound healing, I conducted incisional and excisional wound healing studies using CD109 transgenic mice and wild-type littermate controls.  These studies demonstrate improved scarring parameters including reduced myofibroblast differentiation, reduced granulation tissue, and improved extracellular matrix architecture in the CD109 transgenic mice.  Additionally, the data in this thesis show that overexpression of CD109 in the epidermis inhibits immune cell recruitment, and is associated with a reduction in expression of the proinflammatory cytokines IL-1 and MCP-1.  I correlated these data with immunohistochemical analysis of Smad2/3 phosphorylation, and show that CD109 overexpression is associated with a reduction in TGF-ß signaling. Collectively, these data suggest that overexpression of CD109 in the epidermis inhibits fibrosis during wound healing in a TGF-ß dependent manner.To better understand the role of CD109 in fibrosis, I employed a murine bleomycin-induced model of fibrosis, which exhibits similarities to scleroderma, in CD109 transgenic mice and wild-type littermates.   This study shows that CD109 transgenic mice express reduced levels of the extracellular matrix proteins fibronectin and collagen I, as well as Smad2/3 phosphorylation, and also display improved extracellular matrix architecture and reduced dermal thickness.  Collectively, these data suggest that CD109 resists bleomycin-induced fibrosis, and could thus be an attractive target for therapeutic treatment of fibrotic skin disorders.To better understand how CD109 modulates TGF-ß in vivo, I analyzed the TGF-ß signaling molecules in skin, primary keratinocytes, and primary fibroblasts harvested from CD109 transgenic mice and wild-type littermates.  Here, I show that CD109 transgenic mice express less collagen I and fibronectin, and display elevated ALK1 expression and signaling through the Smad1/5/8 pathway while wild-type mice express elevated ALK5 and preferentially signal through the Smad2/3 pathway.  Investigation of cultured keratinocytes showed a similar expression pattern, with the only difference existing in the expression of ALK1 and ALK5 which were both increased in the CD109 transgenic keratinocytes, and fibroblasts from both genotypes showed similar expression patterns.  In both cultured keratinocytes and whole skin extracts, the CD109 transgenic tissue expressed less TGF-ß than their wild-type counterparts.  The differential TGF-ß signaling described here could underscore our previous observations indicating that overexpression of CD109 inhibits scarring and fibrosis in vivo.Collectively, the data presented here demonstrate that CD109 potently alters physiological processes in the skin in vivo.  The capacity for CD109 to reduce scarring, fibrosis, and inflammation in vivo makes it an attractive target for treating fibrotic skin disorders.</description><description>Le facteur de croissance transformant bêta (TGF-ß), est un facteur de croissance multifonctionnel impliqué dans une multitude de processus cellulaires tel que la cicatrisation, la déposition de matrice extracellulaire, l'inflammation et la fibrose.  Ainsi, l'inhibition de TGF-ß semble être une cible de choix pour réduire les désordres fibrotiques de la peau. Notre laboratoire a identifié CD109, une proteine de 180 kDa ancrée à un glycosylphosphatidylinositol agissant comme co-récepteur cellulaire de TGF-ß. Ce nouveau récepteur, auquel TGF- ß s'ancre avec très haute affinité, aurait pour propriété d'inhiber la signalisation intra-cellulaire de TGF-ß. Les propriétés antagonistes de CD109 suggèrent que la modulation de son expression in vivo dans la peau pourrait améliorer la cicatrisation et la fibrose cutanée. Pour investiguer le role de CD109 dans la peau, nous avons généré une souris transgénique en clonant CD109 en aval du promoteur de keratin-14, limitant ainsi la surexpression de CD109 à l'épiderme.Afin d'explorer le rôle de CD109 au sein de la guérison des plaies, nous avons conduit des études de ce processus où nous avons pu observer une amélioration des paramètres de cicatrisation tels que  la réduction de la différentiation des myofibroblastes, la réduction du tissu de granulation et une amélioration de l'architecture de la matrice extracellulaire chez les souris transgénique CD109 comparées au souris de génotype sauvage pour la même portée. De plus, la surexpression de CD109 dans l'épiderme inhibe le recrutement de cellules immunitaires au site de la plaie et est associé avec une réduction de la signalisation de TGF-ß ainsi que l'expression des cytokines pro-inflammatoire IL-1 et MCP-1. Toutes ces données, suggèrent que la surexpression de CD109 dans l'épiderme inhibe la fibrose cutanée lors de la guérison des plaies.Nous avons ensuite examiné le rôle de CD109 lors de la fibrose en utilisant un model de sclérodermie murine induit par bleomycine. La souris transgénique CD109 exprime des niveaux réduits des protéines fibronectine et collagène 1 dans la matrice extracellulaire, ainsi que des niveaux réduits de phosphorylation de Smad2/3. Elle démontre aussi une meilleure architecture de la matrice extracellulaire et une réduction de l'épaisseur de la couche dermique. Toutes ces données suggèrent que CD109 résiste à la fibrose induite par bleomycine. Cela pourrait donc en faire une cible attrayante pour traitement thérapeutique des désordres fibrotiques de la peau.Pour mieux comprendre comment CD109 modifie l'action de TGF-ß in vivo, nous avons analysé les molécules de signalisation de TGF-ß dans la peau, les keratinocytes primaires et les fibroblastes primaires récoltés des souris transgéniques et de leur sœurs de portée du génotype sauvage. Les souris transgéniques CD109 expriment substantiellement moins de collagène I, de fibronectine et démontre une expression élevée de ALK1 et une activation élevée de la voie Smad1/5/8. Les études utilisant des keratinocytes cultivés démontrent une phosphorylation de Smad et une expression des gènes de la matrice extracellulaire similaire; l'expression de ALK1 et ALK5 étant toutefois plus élevée dans les keratinocytes transgéniques CD109 comparé à ceux du génotype sauvage. Les fibroblastes des deux génotypes démontrent des profils d'expression similaires. La signalisation différentielle de TGF-ß pourrait rehausser nos observations précédente et ainsi renforcer l'idée que la surexpression de CD109 inhibe la cicatrisation et la fibrose cutanée in vivo.Ainsi, les données présentée démontrent que CD109 est un puissant altérateur des processus physiologiques de guérison des plaies, cicatrisation, fibrose et inflammation dans la peau in vivo. La capacité pour CD109 de réduire la cicatrisation, la fibrose et l'inflammation dans la peau in vivo en font une cible attrayante pour traiter les désordres fibrotiques de la peau.</description><creator>Vorstenbosch, Joshua</creator><contributor>Anie Philip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Overexpression of CD109 in the epidermis reduces skin fibrosis and inflammation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301490j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj217</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nv316</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les troubles neuropsychiatriques et les comportements suicidaires contribuent de façon importante au taux de mortalité au Canada. Parmi les facteurs associés aux troubles neuropsychiatriques, on retrouve des altérations lipidiques autant périphériques que centrales, ce qui supporte une implication lipidique dans les mécanismes neuropathologiques. Étant donné la complexité des mécanismes régissant le cholestérol, et malgré les études animales qui soutiennent un rôle fonctionnel dans le cerveau, les déterminants biologiques sous-jacents à une telle association chez les humains demeurent incertains. Alors que les mécanismes impliqués dans la régulation du cholestérol ne sont pas entièrement compris, on attribue au cholestérol un rôle important dans la régulation de plusieurs fonctions cérébrales telles que la neurotransmission, les modifications synaptiques, et la neurodégénération avec des contributions uniques aux neurones, astrocytes et oligodendrocytes. Compte tenu de l'étendue de ces mécanismes, de leur relation entre les différents types cellulaires et de leur implication dans les troubles neuropsychiatriques, déterminer une association biologique demeure d'une importance majeure afin de comprendre l'implication du cholestérol dans les troubles psychiatriques. Ce projet de recherche vise à explorer les mécanismes neurobiologiques et génétiques supportant une relation entre le cholestérol et différents phénotypes psychiatriques. Les résultats présentées aux chapitre 3 suggère, tandis que pas de différences distinctes ont été remarqués dans les suicidés, l'expression de plusieurs gènes liés à la CHL associer plus fortement avec les niveaux de CHL dans la substance blanche par rapport à la substance grise, ce qui suggère une contribution potentielle des SORT1 , LPL, et ABCA2, dans la régulation de CHL dans la substance blanche. Les résultats du chapitre 4 indiquent une altération des niveaux de phospholipides et l'expression du gène lipase acide lysosomale A chez le cortex préfrontal des suicides violent, qui aurait des conséquences importantes pour la neurotransmission inhibitrice. Les résultats du chapitre 4 suggèrent une augmentation de 24-hydroxycholestérol dans le cortex préfrontal des suicidés, ce qui pourrait avoir des implications pour l'entretien et la perte des synapses dans la neuropathologie de suicide. En ce qui concerne les niveaux de CHL, cependant, peu de preuves ont été constatées à l'appui des altérations de cholestérol du système nerveux central aux troubles neuropsychiatriques et aux comportements suicidaire.</description><description>Neuropsychiatric disorders and suicidal behaviour represent major contributions to mortality in Canada. Among the many factors associated with psychiatric disorders and suicide, alterations in lipids and cholesterol have been demonstrated both peripherally and centrally, supporting their roles as mediating variables in the underlying neuropathology. Cholesterol (CHL) regulation is a complex and dynamic system, and while animal studies also support a mediating role of CHL on brain function, efforts to determine a biological association in humans have achieved only modest gains. While mechanisms governing cholesterol regulation are not entirely understood, cholesterol is well accepted to have important impacts on a variety of brain functions from neurotransmission to synaptic plasticity and neurodegeneration, with unique contributions from neurons, astrocytes, and oligodendrocytes. Given the extensive regulatory feedback mechanisms and the implications in neurological function, determining a biological basis for the association of cholesterol with neuropsychiatric disorders remains an important area of research. This research aimed to explore the neurobiological mechanism whereby alterations in CHL may relate to neuropsychiatric phenotypes. The results presented in chapter 3 suggest, while no clear differences were found in suicide completers with major depressive disorder, expression of several CHL related genes associate more strongly with white matter CHL levels compared to grey matter, suggesting a potential contribution of SORT1, LPL, and ABCA2, in the regulation of white matter CHL. The results of chapter 4 suggest altered phospholipid levels and expression of lysosomal acid lipase A gene in violent suicides in the prefrontal cortex, which would have important consequences for inhibitory neurotransmission. The results of chapter 4 suggest an increase in 24-hydroxycholesterol in the prefrontal cortex of suicide completers and this could have implications for synapse maintenance and loss in the neuropathology of suicide. In regards to CHL levels, however, little evidence in support of alterations in CNS CHL in neuropsychiatric disorders and suicidal behaviour was noted.</description><creator>Freemantle, Erika</creator><contributor>Naguib Mechawar (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Gustavo Turecki (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Brain lipids and cholesterol in neuropsychiatric disorders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dq64c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nv316</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r454d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:27:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Most people know the ceratopogonid midges as "no-see-ums" and "sandflies" and have encountered them while on a fishing trip or on a holiday to the seaside, countryside or to mountain regions. The annoyance they give from their bites invariably engenders an abrupt fall in morale and produces an instant strong desire to be elsewhere. As Kettle (1962) has put it, "one midge is an entomological curiosity, a thousand ean be hell!" The term "sandfly" is inappropriate for these insects as it leads to a confusion of the group with the true sandfly Phlebotomus (Psyohodidae) and certain blackflies (Simuliidae). [...]</description><creator>Chan, Kai-Lok.</creator><contributor>Leroux, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1965</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><subject>Diptera.</subject><title>Systematics of the Forcipomyiinae (Diptera: Ceratopogonidae) with ecology of certain Quebec forms.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b10p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r454d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):14750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>