<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:27:35Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34600" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr322</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two empirical studies are presented which investigated Sexpert, a rule-based expert system for the treatment of couple sexual dysfunctions. The following hypotheses were evaluated: (1) couples' attitudes towards computerized psychotherapy would improve subsequent to an interaction with Sexpert, (2) couples would find Sexpert more engaging than other sources of information, (3) couples interacting with Sexpert would report learning more about their relationship than those exposed to other sources of information, and (4) Sexpert could influence the sexual behavior of volunteer couples. The research hypotheses were tested in 2 studies (81 &amp; 77 couples respectively) which compared the effects of Sexpert, a sex education book and video, and a therapist, with a no-information control (crossword puzzles). A rigorous statistical analysis of the reliability of couples' self-report of their sexual behavior was made. In study 1, positive attitude shifts towards Sexpert were replicated with semantic differential as well as dissimilarity scales. In study 2, positive attitude shifts were only demonstrated via a ranking methodology. Sexpert was reported to be the most engaging of the experimental manipulations tested in either study. Couples provided with information via Sexpert, video, book, or therapist retrospectively reported significant positive changes in communication, sexuality, feelings, and relationship satisfaction. The highest change ratings were given by participants in the therapist group, followed by the Sexpert, video and book groups. Participants also reported significant learning about many aspects of their relationship and sexuality; however, there were no significant differences between the Sexpert, video, and therapist conditions. The sexual behavior monitoring data did not corroborate retrospectively reported changes in behavior. These inconsistencies in behavioral reporting were attributed to couple reactivity to the monitoring of sexual behavior and to s</description><creator>Ochs, Eric Peter Paul.</creator><contributor>Binik, Irv (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Expert systems (Computer science)</subject><subject>Sex therapy -- Computer programs.</subject><title>A sex-expert computer program in therapeutic dialogue with couples : an investigation of resultant attitudes, learning, and sexual behaviors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c2243.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr322</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v8382232</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA tumor virus oncoproteins have evolved to regulate the p53 tumor suppressor. They must overcome p53-dependent cell cycle arrest and apoptosis, which would interfere with viral replication. Upon cellular stress, signalling to p53 takes the form of a large increase in the stability of the protein, by inhibition of the MDM2 protein which normally targets p53 for rapid degradation. Expression of the adenovirus type 5 early region 1 A (E1A) polypeptides can stimulate a quiescent cell to reenter the cell cycle and induces the accumulation of p53 protein and p53-dependent cell death under certain conditions. We mapped the regions of E1A necessary to induce p53 stabilization. Binding of either the p300 or pRb family of proteins can signal to p53, and these are the same activities required for E1A to push the cell to enter S phase. To replicate, the virus must combat this accumulation of p53, and we discovered that two other early viral proteins, E1B55K and E4orf6, can target p53 for ubiquitin-mediated degradation by the 26S proteasome. We found that when cells are infected with adenovirus, no significant accumulation of p53 occurs, and this is due to a large reduction in the half-life of the protein. E4orf6 and E1B55K each bind p53 and also bind each other, and we generated a series of E4orf6 mutations to study the regions necessary for this interaction. We identified a region at the amino terminus of E4orf6 that is the minimal domain permitting interaction with E1B55K. We also determined that binding E1B55K along with functions requiring most of the E4orf6 carboxy terminus have to be intact for E4orf6 to mediate p53 degradation. We tested the activity of the viral proteins in MDM2-deleted cells, and found that E4orf6/E1B55K don't require MDM2 to induce p53 turnover. A series of cellular proteins that interact with E4orf6 were discovered in our lab, and we identified this complex as Cullin 5, Elongin B, Elongin C, Rbx1, E4orf6 and E1B55K. This complex is very similar</description><creator>Querido, Emmanuelle.</creator><contributor>Branton, Philip E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Regulation of the p53 tumor suppressor by early products of adenovirus serotype 5</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z7037.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8382232</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m347g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the issues of collaboration and competition in the context of oil and gas sector organizations. The convergence of economics and organization science literatures suggests a connection between the prevalence of extraorganizational exchange and the role of technology in driving innovation and growth. Specifically, the role of collaboration as a strategy for increasing the returns to technology and providing competitive advantage is explored in this research. Two questions were advanced to examine the framework. The first investigated the relationships between a set of organizational characteristics and collaborative success; four propositions were developed to test this question. The second issue explored how organizations manage collaborative-competitive tensions in an environment characterized as fiercely competitive and marked by widespread collaborative arrangements. Using a qualitative research methodology, thirty face-to-face interviews were conducted with executives and senior-level managers from twenty-three companies over an eight-month period; a questionnaire was also used to gather the more objective information. The sample included diversified energy, exploration and development, pipeline and oil and gas service companies. The majority of firms were located in the Houston, Texas area. The most important implications of the study pertain to innovation and organizational change issues. Principal findings were that the ability to manage complex and multiple time frames was positively associated with an organization's level of collaborative capability, a construct that measured collaborative experience and expertise; organizational boundaries that are neither completely permeable nor fully defined were consistent with more successful collaborations; and the proposed direct relationship between collaborative capability and competitive advantage was only weakly supported. Further results indicate that three-fourths of the sample did not experience conflict between collaborative and competitive strategies, while those firms that noted tensions were confined to oil and gas service companies; and collaborative arrangements were motivated by three imperatives of capital intensity, competition and dependency, each of which led to distinct organizational outcomes.</description><creator>Haugen, Leslie K.</creator><contributor>Jorgensen, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Gas industry -- Texas -- Houston.</subject><subject>Petroleum industry and trade -- Texas -- Houston.</subject><subject>Strategic alliances (Business)</subject><subject>Competition.</subject><title>Organizational exchange and competitive implications : the meanings and manifestations of partnerships in the oil and gas sector</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c4362.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m347g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698916k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Serving as the extra-thalamic relay from the ascending reticular activating system to the cerebral cortex, basal forebrain neurons and particularly the cholinergic neurons therein, are believed to play an important role in cortical activation that occurs during waking and paradoxical sleep (PS). However, basal forebrain neurons are also thought to be involved in slow wave sleep (SWS), and thus accordingly influence cortical activity in different ways across the sleep-waking cycle. The present research aimed to elucidate the way the basal forebrain modulates cortical activity and sleep-wake states in response to the different neurotransmitters contained in its brainstem afferents. Microinjections of chemicals into the basal forebrain of rats were performed using a remotely controlled apparatus that allowed study of electroencephalographic (EEG) and behavioral changes without disturbing the rat's normal sleep-waking cycle. In a first study using spectral analysis of the EEG, it was established that high frequency gamma (30--60 Hz) activity reflects cortical activation and behavioral arousal during waking and PS and that gamma varies reciprocally with delta (1--4 Hz) and positively with theta (4--8 Hz) across these states. Noradrenaline, which excites cholinergic neurons to discharge in a tonic mode and has differential effects on non-cholinergic neurons, increased gamma and decreased delta EEG activities while eliciting waking. The glutamate agonist, AMPA, produced similar effects, and NMDA, which is known to induce a bursting discharge in cholinergic neurons, additionally increased theta activity in association with an active waking state. Moreover, neurotensin, which acts selectively to excite cholinergic cells to discharge in a bursting mode, evoked gamma and theta while enhancing both waking and PS in the provoked absence of SWS. In contrast, serotonin, which inhibits cholinergic neurons and has minimal effects on non-cholinergic neurons, decreased gamma and th</description><creator>Cape, Edmund G.</creator><contributor>Jones, Barbara (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Role of cholinergic basal forebrain neurons in the modulation of cortical activity across the sleep-waking cycle : a pharmacological study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z44w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698916k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j720f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The power industry is undergoing a revolutionary change due to deregulation and associated restructuring. Deregulation is the legislation that governs open access to the transmission grid by competing producing and consuming entities. In this newly-created market structure, bilateral power transactions are emerging as a major trading mechanism. As such, bilateral contracts have become important decision variables in all aspects of power system operation and planning. Consequently, a critical question is how to evaluate the success of any given transaction, especially in the presence of other random simultaneous trades. A successful transaction is understood to be one under which a power system is secure and the proposed trade will be approved as is. This is a necessary condition for the transaction to be economically viable. The originality of this thesis lies in the integration of random bilateral trading with the physical transmission network. A methodology is developed to estimate the probability of success of any given transaction in the presence of simultaneous random trades with the security requirements of the power system as a given. This measure of success is termed POST (Probability of Secure Transaction). Different forms of POST are defined from the perspectives of the system, the trading partners, or the partners and amount transacted. These and other similar measures form a group of transaction-based security indices. A Monte Carlo simulation approach is developed as a practical means to estimate the transaction-based security indices. Extensive testing and simulations show that this methodology is effective in transaction risk management, and in network adequacy assessment in the context of random trading. Furthermore, the methodology is used to determine the viability of proposed system reinforcements, especially major power system interconnections involving substantial investments in equipment and resources.</description><creator>Cheng, Wing Mao John, 1960-</creator><contributor>Galiana, F. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>McGillis, D. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Random bilateral trading in power systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s645m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j720f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw31w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pre-operative image based image guided neurosurgery (IGNS) systems involve the mapping of intraoperative real world coordinates and trajectories to one or more preoperative image data spaces. This is accomplished using a rigid body transformation from patient to image coordinate systems, which is usually obtained by identifying external landmarks on the patient and on the images, and employing a least squares minimization technique. The validity of the rigid body transformation relies on the assumption that the patient and localizing device form a completely rigid body for the duration of the procedure. It has been observed that the brain tissue moves significantly within the skull, particularly after large open craniotomies, violating this assumption of rigidity. A surgical guidance system has been developed that combines pre-operative image information (e.g. MRI or CT) and intraoperative ultrasound imaging to detect brain tissue deformation during IGNS. The system includes hardware and software to track the ultrasound transducer during image acquisition, and visualization software to view the live ultrasound and co-planar MRI images. The software includes tools to delineate structures in either modality and overlay these images on one another, and warp the preoperative image based on the delineated structures. The thesis includes a discussion of techniques, instruments and results, using a novel calibration tool and a multi-modality deformable phantom. Finally, the clinical experience from the use of this system in the operating room are presented.</description><creator>Comeau, Roch.</creator><contributor>Peters, Terry M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Intraoperative ultrasound imaging for the detection and correction of tissue movement in image-guided neurosurgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v957x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw31w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sb96p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Describing Bernard Lonergan's relation to philosophy of religion is tricky business, with complications arising on different levels. To begin with, he does not use the term as it is usually understood in the field of the same name. Moreover, he addresses the same issues as philosophers of religion, but under the guise of philosophy of God or natural theology. Finally, he understands idiosyncratically the issue of religious experience, which is now a specialized category in philosophy of religion called upon to support formally rational statements for or against theistic belief. This central issue in Lonergan is further complicated by the fact that his idiosyncratic understanding of (religious) experience plays different roles in his thinking about God and religion. In this study I flesh out the dynamics of these various components, their interrelationships, and their function from early to late development. My point of departure is a period in Lonergan's thought where he attributes more to the influence of religious experience in our thinking than at any time prior in his career. In chapter 1 I pursue some reasons that have been given for the tardiness of his response, intimating its nature and what it meant for his controversial "proof" for God's existence. Something of a detour is taken in chapter 2 since discussion of the concept of religious experience in Lonergan must grapple with what he means by experience in general. I decipher three senses to the term integral to his concept of consciousness that I distinguish from a contemporary model, that of David Chalmers. Since Lonergan is emphatic about distinguishing consciousness from its concept I trace this aspect of his philosophical claim against the background of Kant and Hegel, his main dialogue partners on the question. In chapter 3 I return to the specifically religious dimension of the notion of experience in the early Lonergan. Here I track the development of his category of religious experience as it moves from the periphery to the explanatory basis of his thought. In chapter 4 the relevant later literature in Lonergan is examined in which is seen the emergence of what is technically philosophy of religion to him. Among the distinctions I introduce is the difference between his model of religion and what he calls his philosophy of religion. Conceiving it historically, I see the former, his model of religion, as the departure point for what in his philosophy of religion he sets out to accomplish. They are related, of course, but not one and the same thing. To avoid confusion with the field of the same name, I recommend that we refer to his philosophy of religion as it is literally, as a philosophy of religious studies, distinguishing it firstly from his philosophy of God and secondly from his model of religious experience. Besides providing an unprecedented comprehensive understanding of Lonergan's philosophy of religion, outlining the matter this way also aids in identifying precisely what are the points of contact between Lonergan's thoughts on God and religion and the issues presently discussed by philosophers of religion. The conclusion offers an example of this at the level of "philosophy of," the formal component of Lonergan's philosophy of religion in the generic sense in which I understand it. It represents steps toward a larger project, which I adumbrate in the appendix.</description><creator>Kanaris, Jim.</creator><contributor>Boutin, Maurice (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Lonergan, Bernard J. F.</subject><subject>Experience (Religion)</subject><subject>Philosophy and religion.</subject><title>Bernard Lonergan's philosophy of religion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht451.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sb96p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm14q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Most adult human activities reflect a moral position. This thesis aims to show that art, as one form of human endeavour, follows suit. Consequently, art education should reflect this connection. In this thesis I make a philosophical investigation of one possible approach to art education. Furthermore, to be reflective of western society's emphasis on personal autonomy and authenticity, I contend that the only appropriate moral stance in education should be intuitive, non-calculating and non-utilitarian. In order to philosophically illustrate and support my position, I use the aesthetic thoughts of Bergson and Nietzsche and put them in opposition. This is because they exemplify two opposite conceptions of morality that currently permeate society. Bergson's concept of aesthetics depends upon a stance of disinterest. Nietzsche's is utilitarian. The first exemplifies a humanist orientation that supports an altruistic morality and an aesthetics that puts emphasis on perception. This ethical position actually emerges from an active consciousness, a personal mode of being. On the other hand, Nietzsche's stance is a precursor to one strand of postmodern thought that may be described as a pragmatism oriented towards the achievement of power. This attitude excludes any possible form of disinterestedness. Indeed, Nietzscheism espouses a "noble egoism" and an impersonal mode of being that breeds a narcissistic and immature form of artistic creation. This is a creation that becomes a glorification and edification of oneself, albeit an impersonal self. This is a narcissistic attitude that finds an echo in some trends of contemporary art. In regard to contemporary art, I argue that Nietzsche's influence may be seen in a deviant utilitarian morality that results in a scientistic and anti-aesthetic artistic current. This is a nihilistic trend evident in the work of artists such as Marcel Duchamp. As an alternative, I propose a Bergsonian "ethico-aesthetic" conception of art, inspired and encompassed by disinterestedness as a mature pedagogical value. From this perspective, instead of a neutral attitude, we maintain a more empathic position toward life and art. This altruistic morality produces a responsible and sensible art---concerned with the creation of common grounds. This suggests a need for a form of creation that unfolds from what Bergson could term a "mysterious" sentiment of obligation to bear witness to beauty, in all its forms, as a precisely non-utilitarian and disinterested experience of perception.</description><creator>Savoie, Alain.</creator><contributor>White, Boyd (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Bergson, Henri, 1859-1941.</subject><subject>Education -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Art -- Study and teaching -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1844-1900.</subject><title>Le désintéressement comme valeur de base de l'art et de son enseignement : Bergson contre Nietzsche</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wk95g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm14q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sh949</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study was an exploratory investigation of the efficacy and acceptability of a parent-teacher mediated intervention program for young boys demonstrating externalizing behavior problems. A primary purpose of the study was to compare the efficacy of three indirect models of service delivery: a highly individualized behavioral consultation model (BC); group videotape therapy with minimal consultation (GVT); and a self-administered videotape therapy (VT) program. A second purpose was to investigate the acceptability and satisfaction with these programs as evaluated by parents. More specifically, the relationships between treatment acceptability and outcome as well as factors influencing parent treatment acceptability were examined. Thirty preschool and elementary school children, their parents, and teachers were assigned to one of three intervention conditions (BC, VT, and GVT). A total of 37 parents (29 mothers, 7 fathers, 1 grandmother) participated in the delivery of intervention services over an 8 to 10 week period. An A-B research design was used to analyze the effectiveness of consultation. Outcome variables included parent and teacher ratings of social skills and problem behaviors as well as direct observations. Results indicated that children's target behaviors improved from baseline to treatment in all three intervention conditions. Pretest and posttest parent treatment acceptability was assessed via rating scales, and at the end of the program parents also completed a satisfaction questionnaire. During the intervention phase, a brief semi-structured interview was used to assess parental perceptions of acceptability. High acceptability and satisfaction ratings were reported by parents in all three intervention conditions. There was partial support indicating a relationship between treatment effectiveness and acceptability but there was little evidence of an association between parental perceptions of problem-solving skill, parenting competence, an</description><creator>Finn, Cindy A.</creator><contributor>Sladeczek, Ingrid E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Child psychotherapy -- Parent participation.</subject><subject>Behavior disorders in children -- Treatment.</subject><subject>Behavior therapy for children -- Audio-visual aids.</subject><title>Remediating behavior problems of young children : the impact of parent treatment acceptability and the efficacy of conjoint behavioral consultation and videotape therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v7140.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sh949</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z704h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates L2 acquisition of intransitive verb constructions in Japanese and English. Within the Generative framework, the Unaccusative Hypothesis has been proposed, which divides intransitive verbs into two syntactically distinct classes: unergatives and unaccusatives (Burzio 1986). The sole argument of unergative verbs is an Agent generated in subject position, whereas that of unaccusative verbs is a Theme or Patient base-generated in object position. While the unaccusative/unergative distinction at the level of Deep (D)-Structure holds universally, as derived by a universal principle called the Uniformity of Theta Assignment Hypothesis (UTAH, Baker 1988), languages differ as to where the underlying object of unaccusatives may be positioned at the level of Surface (S)-structure. In the case of English, it surfaces in the subject position where it receives Nominative Case. In the case of Japanese, on the other hand, it has been argued that the argument of unaccusative verbs remains in its base-generated object position and that Nominative Case is assigned within the Verb Phrase. Experimental studies are conducted to examine learners' knowledge of unaccusativity at the two levels, i.e. D-Structure and S-Structure. It is hypothesized that learners will show sensitivity to unaccusativity at D-Structure, but that they may not acquire the correct representation of unaccusativity in the L2 at S-Structure, at least in an earlier stage. The first two studies present the L2 acquisition of English by Japanese speakers. The next two studies are concerned with the L2 acquisition of Japanese by English speakers. Overall, results of the four studies confirm the hypotheses, and L2 learners appear to have problems where the L1 manifests a different representation from the L2. Nevertheless, it is observed that L2 learners behavior is not random even when difficulty arises, in that the L2 learners are often consistent with one class of verbs, but not with the other. Thus, it is suggested that the L2 acquisition of intransitive verb constructions is constrained by universal principles, such as the Unaccusative Hypothesis and the UTAH.</description><creator>Hirakawa, Makiko.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>White, Lydia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Japanese language -- Study and teaching -- English speakers.</subject><subject>Japanese language -- Verb.</subject><subject>English language -- Verb.</subject><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Japanese speakers.</subject><title>Unaccusativity in second language Japanese and English</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj04m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z704h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz86k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When do militias---whose power, riches, and legitimacy depend on the continuation of civil wars---accept negotiated settlements? An unexplored and crucial dimension of militia decision-making is the process of militia institutionalization. Militias create institutions to improve their odds of winning the war and project legitimacy internally as well as externally. Militia institutions affect the strategic choice of decision-makers. They create financial and organizational interests that modify the preferences of the militia leadership. The modified preferences increase the win-set of militia leaders at the negotiating table. Militia institutions also change the decision-making context. Institutions unleash three dynamics that decrease a militia's ability to withstand fluctuations in the military balance of forces. Institutions can lead to factionalism, increased visibility (and hence vulnerability to attack), and strains in relations with patrons. Using the logic of two-level games, I argue that leaders evaluate peace settlements with an eye on two boards. Externally, they evaluate their position vis-a-vis other protagonists in the conflict. Internally, leaders are concerned with their positions in power. Institutionalization results in a tension between "raison de la revolution" (ideological motivations) and "raison d'institution" (institutional preservation). Embattled leaders who increasingly find it difficult to withstand changes in the balance of forces find that their institutional interests are better preserved by peace. They agree to compromise on their ideological preferences thus opening a window of opportunity for the attainment of sustainable peace settlements. Employing the comparative case-study method, the dissertation examines the attitudes of the Lebanese Forces and the Bosnian Serbs respectively toward conflict-resolution schemes that sought to bring the Lebanese and Bosnian civil wars to an end. By focusing on leaders' incentives to settle, the research allows us to predict a priori which settlements are more sustainable. Theoretically, it refines the concept of "ripeness" for negotiations by specifying both its intra-communal and its extra-communal dimensions. In terms of practical policy implications, the research argues that militias are prime candidates for the role of spoilers. Thus, it is important not only to understand their incentives to settle but also to craft peace agreements that give even such radical factions a vested interest in peace.</description><creator>Zahar, Marie-Joëlle.</creator><contributor>Brynen, Rex (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Conflict management -- Political aspects.</subject><subject>Militia movements -- Bosnia and Hercegovina.</subject><subject>Militia movements -- Lebanon.</subject><subject>Military policy -- Decision-making.</subject><title>Fanatics, mercenaries, brigands ... and politicians : militia decision-making and civil conflict resolution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h3501.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz86k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f90v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the first part of the thesis, we analyze the expected time complexity of range searching with k-d trees in all dimensions when the data points are uniformly distributed in the unit hypercube. The partial match results of Flajolet and Puech are reproved using elementary probabilistic methods. In addition, we analyze the expected complexity of orthogonal and convex range search, as well as nearest neighbor search. We introduce a new data structure, the squarish k-d tree, in which the longest edge is always cut first. This modification makes the expected time behavior of lower-dimensional partial match queries behave as for perfectly balanced complete k-d trees on n nodes. This is in contrast to a result of Flajolet and Puech, who proved that for (standard) random k-d trees with cuts that rotate among the coordinate axes, the expected time behavior is much worse than for balanced complete k-d trees. We show that the expected complexity for range search and nearest neighbor search for squarish k-d trees is either optimal or near optimal. In the second part, we analyze branch-and-bound search for random b-ary trees. In particular, let Tn be a b-ary tree of height n, that has independent, nonnegative, identically distributed random variables associated with each of its edges. The value of a node is the sum of all the edge values on its path to the root. Consider the problem of finding the minimum leaf value of Tn. Assume that the edge random variable X is nondegenerate, has E {Xtheta} &lt; infinity for some theta &gt; 2, and satisfies bP{ X = c} &lt; 1 where c is the left-most point of the support of X. We analyze the performance of the standard branch-and-bound algorithm for this problem and prove that the number of nodes visited is in probability (beta + o(1)) n, where beta ∈ (1, b) is a constant depending only on the distribution of the edge random variables. Explicit expressions for beta are derived. We also show that any search algorithm must visit (beta + o(1))n nodes with probability tending to one, so branch-and-bound is asymptotically optimal where first-order asymptotics are concerned.</description><creator>Zamora Cura, Carlos Alberto.</creator><contributor>Devroye, Luc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Analysis of random trees</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tn63f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f90v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz859</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Distributed memory parallel architectures support a memory model where some memory accesses are local, and thus inexpensive, while other memory accesses are remote, and potentially quite expensive. In order to achieve efficiency on such architectures, we need to reduce remote accesses. This is particularly challenging for applications that use dynamic data structures. In this thesis, I present two compiler techniques to reduce the overhead of remote memory accesses for dynamic data structure based applications: locality techniques and communication optimizations. Locality techniques include a static locality analysis, which statically estimates when an indirect reference via a pointer can be safely assumed to be a local access, and dynamic locality checks, which consists of runtime tests to identify local accesses. Communication techniques include: (1) code movement to issue remote reads earlier and writes later; (2) code transformations to replace repeated/redundant remote accesses with one access; and (3) transformations to block or pipeline a group of remote requests together. Both locality and communication techniques have been implemented and incorporated into our EARTH-McCAT compiler framework, and a series of experiments have been conducted to evaluate these techniques. The experimental results show that we are able to achieve up to 26% performance improvement with each technique alone, and up to 29% performance improvement when both techniques are applied together.</description><creator>Zhu, Yingchun, 1968-</creator><contributor>Hendren, Laurie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Optimizing parallel programs with dynamic data structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb02s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz859</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j056x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new technique to study the dynamic adsorption of a surfactant on a rising bubble is established, which combines the single bubble velocity profile and numerical solution of the governing equations. Through investigation of the single bubble velocity profiles in water and surfactant solutions, a physical model describing the surface retardation of the bubble and surfactant mass transfer is proposed. A pseudo-steady state approach is employed to solve the mass transfer and fluid flow interactively. Various models are tested against the velocity profile of a 0.8 mm bubble in Triton X-100 solutions as a function of concentration and temperature. The combination of stagnant cap model and boundary layer mass transfer gave good agreement with experiment at 6°C and 25°C. Failure of the model to converge at 45°C is discussed. Terminal velocity in water and surfactant solutions was defined from the profiles and tested against the available models. A new empirical correlation is proposed to estimate terminal velocity in pure water. Surfactant concentration on the bubble surface was estimated from the numerical solution and showed a bubble size and temperature dependence. The application of single bubble velocity profiles to systems of practical interest is considered.</description><creator>Zhang, Yongqin, 1964-</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Single bubble velocity profile : experiments and numerical simulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx46h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j056x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z7062</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The incorporation of divalent metals into calcite grown from low-temperature (~25°C) aqueous solutions is quantified by partition coefficients (DMe). However, DMe values are commonly derived from bulk analyses of calcite seeds, a practice that underestimates the effect of differential incorporation at symmetrically nonequivalent sectors (i.e, sector zoning) and limits the application of DMe in diagenetic and environmental studies. This study sheds some light on the effect of sector zoning on DMe by investigating the growth kinetics and morphology of calcite and the incorporation trends of divalent Cd, Mn and Zn. Despite their similar ionic radii, Mn and Zn were found to exhibit opposite surface site preferences over a large range of chloride concentration. Zn was preferentially incorporated at geometrically less constrained surface sites of (101¯4) faces of calcite when coprecipitated from stepwise diluted solutions. The anomalous incorporation trend of Zn is not due to the prevalence of "large" aqueous complexes (e.g., ZnCln2-n ) but is probably controlled by its electronic configuration. The increase in Cl incorporation into calcite observed in parallel with its stepwise dilution in solution correlates also with an increase in surface roughness, suggesting that the latter is a factor contributing to impurity incorporation during crystal growth. Investigation of the spontaneous nucleation and growth morphology of calcite from aqueous solutions prepared with different (Ca2+):( CO2-3 ) activity ratios and NaCl and NH4Cl concentrations demonstrated the potential role that the amine functional group in organic molecules may play in influencing biomineralisation and the role of the (Ca2+):( CO2-3 ) activity ratio as an abiotic habit modifier. Cd2+, Mn2+ and Zn2+ respectively inhibited the growth of the (101¯0), (011¯2) and (0001) surfaces of calcite and were preferentially incorporated in the stabilized corresponding growth sectors. DMe values unaffected by growth kinetics approach DMe,ideal when calculated from analyses of the stabilized growth sectors and may represent equilibrium values. DCd,eq = 2235 +/- 400 at {101¯0}, DMn,eq = 97 +/- 6 at {011¯2} and DZn,eq = 190 +/- 32 at (0001). While at {101¯4}, D Cd and DMn reached only 500 +/- 120 and 21 +/- 3.4, respectively. These findings demonstrate that equilibrium partitioning is attained only when (1) calcite growth reaches stoichiometric saturation and "morphological equilibrium" with the aqueous solution and (2) if metal incorporation occurs entirely at surface sites offering optimal geometry and coordination for ion incorporation. A conceptual model is proposed to quantify the contribution of sector zoning on DMe values derived from bulk analyses of precipitates.</description><creator>Temmam, Mounir.</creator><contributor>Paquette, Jeanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>A geochemical and mineralogical investigation of calcite growth and its interactions with divalent cadmium, manganese, and zinc /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t18q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z7062</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s646w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The chelating agent ethylene diamine tetraacetic acid (EDTA) is promising. The ligand is more effective in removing the metal contaminants from soils than HCl. In a batch experiment, EDTA released a large portion of metals from soils to soil extracts. A batch method was also developed for recovering the metal contaminants in the resulting EDTA soil-extracts. Using an anion exchange resin (AER) AG 3-x4, up to 99% of the Cd, Cu, Pb, and Zn were removed from the leachates. To increase the efficacy of the extraction method we tested different reagent, amount, and technical application strategies using soil columns. Mixing the reagent with the whole soil column was found to be the most efficient method for the application of the chelating agent for the purpose of metal extraction from soils. It was found that EDTA was superior to citric acid in removing Cd, Cu, Pb, and Zn from the soils investigated. Up to 27% more Cd, 23% more Cu, 42% more Pb, and 21% more Zn were removed by the EDTA and the removal was further increased with the addition of an acid/salt solution (1.0 M HCl and 1.0 M KCl) to the columns. Other promising results are that the AER in columns is an effective method for extracting metals from EDTA soil-extracts with different properties. The resin column method was found to be more efficient than the resin batch procedure. The results of the simulated field experiment confirmed that the remediation of contaminated soils can be achieved using EDTA. The majority of the contaminated soils were decreased to the point that they could be reused for commercial and/or residential use. Computer models can be used to predict the possible metal speciation and interaction with solid surfaces in soils. Using the MINEQL+ program, the models estimated that most of the metal species in the soil extracts (in the presence of EDTA, chloro, hydroxo, and carbonato ligands and humate and hydrous ferric oxide (HFO) solid phases) were present as soluble metal-EDTA complexes. It appears that the metal-EDTA complexes found in the systems are very stable over a wide range of soil pH. Our surface complexation models also indicated that the EDTA is much stronger than the humate and the HFO solid phases in forming complexes with the metals. As a consequence, the adsorption of the Cd, Cu, Pb, and Zn by the solid surfaces was negligible in the presence of EDTA. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Tejowulan, Raden Sri.</creator><contributor>Hendershot, W. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Metals -- Decontamination.</subject><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><title>Remediation of trace metal contaminated soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666624r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s646w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95052191</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although previous research has examined how dependent and self-critical people recall their parents, there has been little investigation of the influence of Dependency and Self-Criticism on parental attitudes and behavior. The present research examined these relationships in mothers of adolescent children. In Studies 1, 2, and 3, mothers completed measures of Dependency and Self-Criticism and of baseline affect, then were given experimentally manipulated feedback about the child's competence and autonomy. Affect was assessed again, and mothers "coached" children on computer problem-solving puzzles. Studies 1 and 2 examined mothers of adolescent girls, and Study 3 examined mothers of adolescent boys. In mothers of adolescent girls, Dependency was associated with punitive and controlling reactions to daughter autonomy. This was also true of mothers of less competent adolescent sons. In mothers of highly competent sons, however, Dependency was associated with punitive and controlling reactions to low autonomy. Dependency was also associated with increases in depressed affect in response to daughter, but not son, autonomy. In mothers of adolescent girls, Self-Criticism was associated with punitive behavior, regardless of the manipulated characteristics of the daughters. This was true even when, in Study 2, the highly competent performance of daughters was made extremely salient. Self-Criticism had no discernible impact on the parental behavior of mothers of adolescent sons. These results were interpreted as indicating that, especially in mothers of adolescent daughters, parents high in Dependency and Self-Criticism interact with their children in ways that are likely to foster the development of Self-criticism and Dependency in their children. Study 4 examined the relationship between parent and child Dependency and Self-Criticism in the combined data collected from the first three studies. Contrary to expectations, there was no relationship between parent and child</description><creator>Thompson, Ralph Richard.</creator><contributor>Zuroff, David C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Autonomy (Psychology)</subject><subject>Dependency (Psychology)</subject><subject>Performance in children.</subject><subject>Mother and child.</subject><title>Dependency, self-criticism, and maternal reactions to adolescent autonomy and competence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x072f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052191</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc53b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Strip casting is a new process, which can produce cast strips with thicknesses of only 2--5mm and eliminate hot rolling. Cold rolled strips produced by strip casting have low mechanical anisotropy, which is related to the texture of the strip; however, this link has not yet been investigated. Texture development from strip casting through to cold rolling and subsequent annealing was therefore studied. Cast strips of two types were produced by solidification into the dual (delta ferrite + gamma austenite) phase and single (delta ferrite) phase domains. The {001}⟨uvw⟩ delta ferrite texture is converted into the {001}⟨uvw⟩ gamma final texture in the first steel, while most of it transforms into the fcc {011}⟨uvw⟩ fiber in the second. The observed variant selection can be explained using the Bain strain model. The cast strips and a hot rolled strip were subsequently cold rolled and annealed. The gamma-to-alpha' deformation-induced transformation took place during cold rolling and low symmetry rolling textures were produced in the (delta ferrite + austenite) steel after 50% reduction by cold rolling. By contrast, the 80% cold rolled textures displayed orthorhombic symmetry. The recrystallization texture components changed from {001}⟨100⟩ and {110}⟨111⟩ to {110}⟨001⟩, {110}⟨112⟩ and {112}⟨111⟩ when the cold reduction was increased. The cast strips displayed weaker recrystallization textures than the conventionally processed material. Moreover, the delta ferrite steel contained stronger {110}ND fiber components than the two-phase material. Texture development in the rolled and annealed products is discussed in terms of the Kurdjumov-Sachs transformation relationship.</description><creator>Teraoka, Shin-ichi, 1962-</creator><contributor>Jonas, J. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Texture development in strip cast type 304 stainless steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks10v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc53b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn186</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA methylation is a vital component of several mammalian genome functions such as X-inactivation, allele and tissue specific gene expression, parental imprinting, and condensation of transcriptionally inactive chromatin. Aberrant post developmental fluctuations in the levels of DNA methylation and patterns of DNA methylation are commonly observed in transformed or cancerous cells. Proper control over the process of DNA methylation appears to be essential for proper cellular function, however the regulation of the expression of DNA MeTase has remained only loosely elucidated and is still debatable. Chapter 1 presents the complete genomic structure of the human dnmt1 gene which provides an essential template to resolve the existing contradictions. Using this structure chapter 2 demonstrates that there are several different transcriptional control elements that influence the production of different dnmt1 transcripts from several different points of initiation. Furthermore it demonstrates that each of the transcriptional control elements can respond individually to oncogenic and tumor suppressor pathways. Proper control over dnmt1 expression in non transformed cells is achieved in a posttranscriptional manner. Chapter 3 of this thesis shows that the mechanism of the posttranscriptional control over dnmt1 expression is mediated by a conserved stretch of sequence contained within the 3' untranslated region of its mRNA. Evidence is presented that a labile protein factor existing in the G0-G1 part of the cell cycle, which is rapidly cleared in S-phase, mediates the degradation of the dnmt1 mRNA. The pharmacological potential of specific inhibition of dnmt1 expression in a whole organism tumor model is evaluated in Chapter 4. Inhibition of dnmt1 expression, by systemic administration of a phosphorothioate modified antisense deoxyoligonucleotide directed against dnmt1 mRNA, inhibits tumorigenesis with no overt toxicity. The energetics of DNA demethylation suggested that it is an improbable event to occur in a cellular context, so alternative activities which repair DNA were rationalized to be the activities responsible for the observed demethylation events. Chapters 5 and 6 of this thesis reveal a true or bona fide DNA demethylase (dMTase) activity which catalyzes the reverse reaction of DNA MeTase. Chapter 5 describes a cDNA which encodes bona fide DNA dMTase activity and chapter 6 purifies a DNA dMTase activity, characterizes the reaction and identifies the products of the reaction as methanol and nonmethylated cytosine. The DNA dMTase cDNA cloned in chapter 5 is shown to be over expressed in cancer cells and that DNA dMTase activity can only be isolated from tumor tissue. Inhibition of DNA dMTase inhibits the tumorigenicity of cells on semi-solid media, indicating that over expression of dMTase is also a critical component of tumorigenesis. Taken together the results presented in this thesis demonstrate that the DNA methylation machinery is a target for the development of anticancer therapeutics. The data presented here provide the rationale that direct inhibition of DNA dMTase or inhibition at molecular points of regulation are targets to be potentially exploited for therapeutic use.</description><creator>Ramchandani, Shyam.</creator><contributor>Szyf, Moshe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Identification of the DNA methylation machinery, its regulation and uses as potential anticancer therapeutics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js87w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn186</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx11g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rates of carbon and peat accumulation were studied in a series of peat landforms within discontinuously frozen peatlands near Fort Simpson, Northwest Territories. An extended distribution of the White River volcanic ash layer was used as a chronostratigraphic horizon to ensure a consistent time span of peat deposition among peat cores and to allow a large core sample size without the expense of radiocarbon dating. Apparent recent carbon accumulation rates measured over the past 1200 years were not significantly different among rich fen, peat plateau, and collapse fen (means 13--14 g C M-2 yr-1). Poor fen and bog mean accumulation rates were 20--22 g C M-2 yr -1 and were not significantly different from each other. Microtopography and water table position appear to be important controls on both carbon and vertical peat accumulation rates. A regional survey incorporating measurements from other parts of the southwestern Northwest Territories and the southeastern Yukon shows rates similar to those near Fort Simpson. The aggradation of permafrost results in 50 and 65% decreases in carbon and vertical peat accumulation rates, respectively. Carbon and peat accumulation continue to decrease significantly with both increasing permafrost maturity and the number of ground fires. The internal degradation of permafrost results in nearly a doubling in carbon accumulation rates, yet permafrost degradation at the margins of a peat plateau results in carbon accumulation rates similar to the peat plateau. Clymo's (1984) carbon accumulation model was applied to cores from each landform in addition to a core spanning the entire developmental history of the peatland. Results indicate that true carbon accumulation and sequestration efficiency rates in ombrotrophic peatlands are lower in the upper Mackenzie Valley than for other boreal regions, primarily owing to high decomposition rates. The cessation of carbon accumulation is being approached. The model also serves to highlight the dangers of using apparent and true carbon accumulation rates interchangably. Apparent and true carbon accumulation rates are significantly lower than published rates from other parts of northern Canada, Finland, and the Former Soviet Union. Low and variable summer precipitation in the region may be a significant factor through increased aerobic decomposition and/or decreased plant production caused by moisture stress.</description><creator>Robinson, Stephen D.</creator><contributor>Moore, Tim R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Peatlands -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Simpson Region.</subject><subject>Carbon sequestration -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Simpson Region.</subject><title>Carbon accumulation in discontinuously frozen peatlands, southwestern Northwest Territories, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw15g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx11g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj03b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a technology driven world, technology acquisition decisions as to when and which new technologies to acquire are becoming increasingly critical for firms to survive and grow. The issue of technology acquisition is addressed with three different focuses in the current dissertation. In the first essay, we extend the results of some existing literature. Existing literature suggests that, in an oligopoly, identical firms acquire the same technology at two different dates under Nash or pre-commitment equilibrium, which assumes infinite information lag between two firms. The set of equilibrium dates turn out to be different under subgame perfect or pre-emption equilibrium that assumes zero information lag. We show that allowance for asymmetry between firms leads to the same equilibrium dates under Nash and subgame perfect equilibrium. In the second essay, a two-period technology game is considered to study the effect of expectations regarding technological progress on a firm's technology adoption decision in a duopoly. It is shown that expectations of better future technology retard adoption of the currently available technology. Uncertain future progress is shown to have either no effect or negative effect on the adoption of the currently available technology when a Nash or open-loop equilibrium holds. However, under subgame perfection, uncertainty may actually encourage adoption of the current technology, contrary to what literature suggests. In the third essay, a stochastic mathematical programming framework is used to build a decision model to solve for technology decisions facing rapid and uncertain technological progress. In our scenario-based approach, we allow uncertainties in both technological developments as well as in output product market demands. Furthermore, the acquisition costs of the technologies are assumed to be concave to reflect economies of scale in acquisition. An efficient procedure to solve the problem is proposed and implemented. Our numerical results show that the expectation of future technologies impacts the acquisition of the current technology in a negative way, and highlights the importance of incorporating expectations in a technology acquisition model.</description><creator>Rahman, Atiqur.</creator><contributor>Loulou, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Automation -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Technological innovations -- Management -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Technological progress and technology acquisition : models with and without rivalry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf68v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj03b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h1204</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Part I we investigate the thermodynamic consistency problem and a closure for the Ornstein-Zernike relation. A thermodynamically consistent closure is deduced from the grand canonical ensemble theory. When applied to a hard sphere fluid, the closure yields analytic expressions for the equation of state and the excess chemical potential, which turn out to be identical with those of the scaled particle theory as well as those calculated via the compressibility route in the Percus-Yevick theory. In Part II we study the bulk viscosity etab of simple liquids and the shear viscosities eta of simple and molecular liquids, respectively. We present an analog of the Stokes-Einstein relation for the bulk viscosity of a simple fluid etab; a relation of etab to the self-diffusion coefficient D. The formula derived for eta of simple fluids explains how the Chapman-Enskog prediction of the eta - D relation crosses over to the Stokes-Einstein relation as the density increases. When computed with the empirical D values, the formula for eta of rigid diatomic liquids yields the shear viscosities of N 2 and CO2 in good agreement with experiments. The present theory for the relation of etab - D (or eta - D) exploits the minute density fluctuations occurring in the compressional (or shearing) processes. The range of density fluctuations is found to be directly related to the size of the molecule in the liquid. In Part III we study the nonequilibrium liquid-vapor interface under a shearing perturbation. The nonequilibrium density profile equation is derived for a shear flow on the basis of the nonequilibrium ensemble theory by Eu and it retains the same form as the equilibrium Born-Green-Yvon equation except for the dynamic pair correlation function g(r 1, r2; t) and the effective intermolecular potential. A perturbation method is presented for the calculation of g(r1, r2; t) involved. The formula derived is tested for the equilibrium interfacial properties, such as surface tension, before the nonequilibrium effects are investigated. Analysis has been made of the nonequilibrium effects as the shear rate changes.</description><creator>Rah, Kyun-Il.</creator><contributor>Eu, Byung Chan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Statistical mechanics and the viscosity of simple and molecular liquids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft04k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h1204</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c9216</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Shallow recirculating flows dominated by bed-friction effect are numerically simulated in this thesis using two-dimensional models. A two-length-scale k-epsilon turbulence model which is based on Reynolds averaged procedure, and a two-dimensional Large Eddy Simulation (2DLES) model based on subgrid stress are employed. The performance of these models is evaluated by comparing the numerical results with the available laboratory experimental data for a range of conditions from deep to shallow water depth. In the two-length-scale k-epsilon model simulations, the small-scale turbulence is treated as a background component locally in equilibrium, while the large-scale turbulence is modeled by a second-order closure model. Two versions of wall-function models, a high-Reynolds number and a low-Reynolds number wall model, are considered in the implementation of the k-epsilon model. The reattachment length, the recirculation flow rate, and the tracer concentration distribution of shallow recirculating flows are correctly predicted by the k-epsilon model for all of the conducted tests. However, the secondary eddy observed in the experiments in the corner of the main recirculating region is reproduced only when the low-Reynolds-number wall model is implemented. The length of the secondary eddy is ≃25% of the length of the recirculating eddy. In the 2DLES model, the Smagorinsky model for the subgrid stress is modified taking into account the bed-friction effect. A series of numerical simulations are conducted to determine the Smagorinsky coefficient, Cs, for shallow recirculating flows. The results show that the value of the Smagorinsky coefficient is not constant but it is related to a dimensionless parameter (the bed-friction number, S) and to the size of the numerical mesh. For a mesh size 180 x 60, the Cs ranges from 0.1 to 0.25 for shallow to deep recirculating flows respectively. This range of Cs becomes 0.13 to 0.30 for a mesh size 360 x 120. The secondary (corner) eddy as well as the mean flow characteristics are predicted by the 2DLES model when fine mesh sizes of 180 x 60 and 360 x 120 are used in the simulations. Using the optimum Cs values, the numerical results obtained for all parameters (such as the mean flow, the Reynolds stresses, the mean tracer concentration, and the tracer concentration fluctuations) are in agreement with the laboratory observations. The Strouhal number for the oscillations of the shallow recirculating flows is also obtained from the 2DLES. Unlike the k-epsilon model which needs a pair of differential equations for k and epsilon, the 2DLES relates stress and strain at the subgrid scale using an algebraic relation. Provided that a correct Cs is selected, the 2DLES model is more stable, easier to implement and hence would be a more suitable simulation scheme for engineering applications.</description><creator>Nassiri, Masoud.</creator><contributor>Chu, V. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Babarutsi, Sofia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Hydrology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Two-dimensional simulation models of shallow recirculating flows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vv91b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c9216</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v303</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Applicability of Monte-Carlo method for the textural and microstructural changes during annealing processes is studied. Models that are developed for explaining annealing processes are incorporated into Monte-Carlo procedures and the textural and microstructural changes are then followed. The simulated results are compared with the experimental observations to validate the proposed models, The three exemplary annealing processes selected for the present work are industrially important and diversified in their annealing characteristics, These are: (I) Cube {100}⟨001⟩ texture development during recrystallization of Al, (II) Abnormal grain growth of Goss {110}⟨001⟩ grains in Fe-Si steels, (III) The competition between (111) and (100)-fiber textures during annealing of nanocrystalline Ni and Ni-Fe alloy electrodeposits. The model for each annealing process is developed by analyzing the relevant metallurgical information obtained from the corresponding metals and alloys prior to annealing, In Application-I, the texture and orientation-dependent stored energy measurements have been made on the cold rolled can-body aluminum alloy and the detailed discussion is presented, These results are analyzed for developing nucleation and growth models that would lead to the final cube texture formation during primary recrystallization of aluminum. The proposed recrystallization model for aluminum predicts the development of cube texture and equiaxed grain structure as observed in experiments. For the abnormal grain growth in Fe-Si steel (Application-II), the role of high energy grain boundaries has been studied in detail using separate computer experiments to understand the importance of fraction of high mobility grain boundaries. From these experiments, it has been proved that the assumption of high mobility to CSL boundaries for the abnormal growth of Goss grains is not valid. Finally, the Monte-Carlo procedure is employed for testing the proposed model for the texture competition between (111) and (100)-fibers in nanocrystalline Ni, Ni-20% Fe and Ni-45% Fe electrodeposits (Application-III). Based on the texture analysis, the proposed model assumes high mobility to the grains boundaries, which are in high non-equilibrium states. The results of the Monte-Carlo simulation using the proposed model are compared with experiments, The simulated results show that (111)-fiber grows faster than (100)-fiber as annealing progresses. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Narayanan, Rajmohan.</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Computer simulation of textural and microstructural changes during annealing processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks114.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v303</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m348r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this study were: (1) to compare lung fibre concentration and dimensions found in two groups of former Quebec chrysotile miners (Asbestos and Thetford-Mines) and, (2) to investigate the relationship between lung-retained mineral fibre concentration and dimension (length, diameter, and aspect ratio) to severity of interstitial lung fibrosis (asbestosis) within these groups. Lung fibre content was determined for 86 former employees of chrysotile mines and mills in two Quebec mining regions: Thetford-Mines and Asbestos (Jeffrey Mine). Six lung samples were selected for each subject from predetermined intrapulmonary sites. In summary, the concentrations of tremolite for short (&lt;5 mum) intermediate-length (5--10 mum) and long (&gt;10mum) fibres were 4, 2, and 2 fold higher respectively among workers of Thetford-Mines than those from Asbestos. These differences were statistically significant between the two groups (p &lt; 0.05 for all tremolite size categories). No consistent and biologically important difference was found among fibre dimensions in any of the size categories (p &gt; 0.1 for all fibre types and size categories). These observations suggested that the much higher exposure in Thetford-Mines to asbestos fibres, tremolite fibres being more apparent, is the most plausible factor which may explain the higher incidence of lung diseases among the former miners and millers of Thetford-Mines. Concentration of short (&lt;5 mum) tremolite fibres was the best predictor of asbestosis severity in both mining groups (r = 0.44, p &lt; 0.01 and r = 0.39 p &lt; 0.01 for Thetford-Mines and Asbestos, respectively). Chrysotile fibre concentration showed a lower correlation with asbestosis severity among subjects from Thetford-Mines (r = 0.28, p &lt; 0.1 and r = 0.39, p &lt; 0.01 and for fibres &lt;5 mum and fibres 5--10 mum respectively). Long (&gt;10 mum) amosite fibre concentrations showed a linear relationship with asbestosis severity in the group of miners and millers from Asbestos (r = 0.5, p &lt; 0.01). Shorter commercial amphibole concentrations did not show this relationship and these fibres were largely absent from the lungs of miners from Thetford-Mines. Concentration of asbestos bodies from lung digests was significantly associated with fibrosis for subjects from Thetford-Mines only (r = 0.3, p = 0.05). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Nayebzadeh, Ataollah.</creator><contributor>Dufresne, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><title>Lung fibre concentration, dimension, and asbestosis severity : relationships among Québec chrysotile miners and millers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs125.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m348r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34625</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>