<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:21:10Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):8050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m684x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le procédé de fabrication sous sac à vide hors-autoclave des matériaux pré-imprégnés offre une alternative durable et rentable comparativement au procédé conventionnel de fabrication par autoclave. Pour des pièces relativement plates fabriquées hors-autoclave, les propriétés mécaniques sont comparables à des pièces fabriquées en autoclave. Cependant, il reste des problèmes pour des pièces complexes, particulièrement avec les changements d'épaisseur dans le rayon des coins. Bien qu'il existe des solutions pour minimiser l'épaississement des coins, il est désirable d'en améliorer le procédé. Cette thèse propose un procédé dans lequel un stratifié est chauffé par lumière infrarouge à intervalles réguliers pendant le compactage sous vide durant le processus d'empilement. Le but d'un compactage chauffé est de minimiser l'épaississant des coins durant l'empilement en encourageant le glissement des plis entre eux, en accélérant la sortie des gaz, et en augmentant le niveau d'imprégnation du pré-imprégné.La première étape de développement d'un procédé est de caractériser les matériaux et de fabriquer des pièces simples pour démontrer la faisabilité. La friction entre des plis a été caractérisée en utilisant un test de traction afin d'évaluer les forces requises pour initier le glissement. Le changement du degré de polymérisation de la résine durant le procédé de consolidation a été évalué en utilisant l'analyse mécanique dynamique (DMA). Une relation entre l'augmentation des températures et des temps de traitement avec le dégrée de réticulation a été établie. L'étude de l'évacuation de l'air entre la surface du moule et un pli de pré-imprégné a démontré que l'évacuation d'air n'était pas affectée par la température du matériau. D'autre part, entre les séquences de compactage, une fois que le sac sous vide était retiré, l'air se retrouvait à nouveau dans le pli lorsque la viscosité de la résine est faible.L'impact d'un compactage sur la qualité des pièces fut d'abord étudié sur des stratifiés plats. Il a été trouvé que la diminution de résistance au cisaillement interlaminaire lorsque la température de compactage des pièces augmentait. Pour des compactages à basse température, le taux de porosité se trouvait aussi augmenté. Ensuite, des raidisseurs  en forme de « L » ont été fabriqués en utilisant un moule concave. Dans ces pièces, le compactage en température permit de réduire l'épaississement du rayon de 25 % en comparaison des pièces compactées à température ambiante, avec seulement un cinquième du taux de porosité.Ayant démontré la faisabilité de réduire l'épaississant des coins en utilisant un compactage en température, un procédé a été mis au point en utilisant une lampe infrarouge pour chauffer les plis, du tissu de drainage de fabrique de fibre de carbone pour faciliter l'absorption de chaleur, et de la glace carbonique pour refroidir le laminé avant de relâcher le sac sous vide.  Ce procédé fut utilisé à différentes températures, durées et fréquences de compactage. Il s'est avéré que plus le compactage à chaud durait longtemps, moins les rayons de coins étaient épais, bien que des améliorations étaient également observées pour des compactages courts à haute température. À haute température, de longs compactages menaient à une augmentation du taux de porosité. Si la fréquence de compactages était réduite, l'épaisseur des coins et la présence de porosité se trouvaient alors augmentées, quelle que soit la température de compactage. Afin d'améliorer notre compréhension de la relation entre la température et la durée de compactage, un modèle existant a été modifié  pour simuler les tendances observées. Avant de raffiner ce modèle, certains défis théoriques et empiriques devront être relevés. La contribution de ce projet est d'être la première littérature publique sur le développement scientifique d'un processus de compactage chaud et de montre que le compactage chaud peut améliorer la qualité des pièces complexe.</description><description>Vacuum Bag Only, Out-of-Autoclave prepreg processing offers a sustainable, cost-efficient alternative to conventional autoclave manufacturing of high strength composite parts. Flat or low curvature parts made with Out-of-Autoclave prepregs have demonstrated comparable mechanical properties to their autoclave counterparts, yet challenges still remain with the fabrication of parts with more complex features. One area of concern is corner thickening in concave corners. Best practices for reducing this defect exist; however, a more robust processing technique is desirable. In this work, a manufacturing process is proposed that involves heating the laminate during the vacuum bag compaction at regular intervals in the layup process. The aim of these heated debulks is to reduce corner thickening early on in the manufacturing process by encouraging inter-ply slipping, precipitating air removal, and increasing the degree of impregnation.Before the process could be designed, its potential was assessed through material characterization and demonstrator studies. Inter-ply friction was characterized for debulked samples using pull-out tests, allowing for a better understanding of the forces required to encourage prepreg slip. Dynamic mechanical analysis was used to assess changes in the degree of cure caused by debulking, and found a slight increase in curing with increased debulk temperature and duration. Investigating the removal of air from a tool-part interface showed no impact of heating on air removal rate. It was observed that air returned to the plies if vacuum was released when the resin viscosity was low.Initial trials were run on flat plates. There was a decrease in short beam shear strength as the debulk dwell temperature increased. Meanwhile, low temperature hot debulks led to an increase in voids. L-brackets were manufactured on a concave tool. The hot debulk led to a 25% reduction in corner thickening and a 80% reduction in void content compared to the part debulked at room temperature. Such improvements in quality motivated the development of a more robust design for a hot debulk process. This procedure consisted of using an infrared lamp to heat the prepreg, dry carbon fibre fabric as breather to absorb the heat while evacuating gases, and a bath of dry ice used to cool the tool before the vacuum bag was vented.Parts were then made using this procedure with different debulk durations, temperatures, and frequencies. Longer hot debulks led to the greatest reduction in corner thickening, although improvements were observed for short, high temperature debulks. Long, high temperature debulks led to an increase in voids. Fewer debulks led to thicker corners and higher void contents, regardless of debulk temperature. Short beam shear strength was not impacted by the debulk procedure.A better understanding of the relationship between debulk time and temperature was necessary so an existing model was modified to simulate the trends observed. There are several barriers, both theoretical and empirical, that need to be overcome before this model can be used for process refinement. The work presented here contributes to the field in being among the first publicly available literature to methodically develop a detailed hot debulk procedure and to establish processing conditions to lead to improvements in part quality.</description><creator>Hughes, Marissa</creator><contributor>Pascal Hubert (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Thermally assisted consolidation of out-of-autoclave prepreg for concave parts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q191.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m684x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w2418</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette recherche entend contribuer à l'étude de l'hindouisme en diaspora. Elle s'appuie sur une documentation historique et un travail de terrain de caractère ethnographique. Elle est centrée sur l'évolution du culte de la divinité Mardévirin/Maduraivīraṉ entre l'Inde du Sud où il prend naissance et l'île Maurice, une des sociétés de plantation du XIXe siècle où l'a amené l'engagisme. Ma recherche m'a conduit à une étude parallèle de l'histoire culturelle des communautés pratiquant le culte de Mardévirin. J'ai d'abord replacé les origines de ce culte dans l'Inde précoloniale afin de pouvoir situer certains thèmes importants, tels que le symbolisme politique, l'ambiguïté morale et l'antinomisme religieux, thèmes reproduits et subvertis à l'île Maurice. Dans un deuxième temps, j'ai exploré le développement et le déclin du culte dans leurs contextes politiques et religieux respectifs. Je soutiens que la période coloniale a été un terrain fertile pour la popularité de Mardévirin, sa légende et son culte faisant écho aux réalités sociales de l'époque. Avec l'influence des nationalismes religieux indiens et l'arrivée de l'indépendance mauricienne, le culte de Mardévirin perd de sa popularité, n'étant plus compatible avec la sensibilité religieuse du nouvel ordre « mondial ». Finalement, principalement à travers un travail de terrain, j'ai enquêté sur ce qui subsiste du culte dans l'île Maurice d'aujourd'hui. J'avance que même s'il n'est plus que marginal et résiduel, la figure de Mardévirin est rappelée comme un symbole d'indentité religieuse subalterne. Globalement, cette recherche insiste, à travers Mardévirin, sur l'importance des divinités gardiennes entre l'Inde de l'engagisme et l'Ile Maurice coloniale. Est aussi mise en avant la transformation radicale de cette économie religieuse par la modernité postcoloniale.</description><description>This research is a contribution to the study of diasporic Hinduism. It draws on historical documentation and ethnographic fieldwork, focusing on the evolution of the cult of deity Mardévirin/Maduraivīraṉ, between South India where it originates and Mauritius Island, one of nineteenth-century plantation societies where it was transplanted following indenture. My research is an attempt to write a cultural history around the cult of Mardévirin. I first locate the latter's origins in precolonial South India, in order to map out important themes - such as political symbolism, moral ambiguity and antinomian religiosity - that are mirrored and subverted on Mauritius Island. In the second part of the thesis, I argue that the colonial period was fertile ground for Mardévirin's growing popularity, as the god's legendary narrative and worship echoed the indentured plantation's world and social reality. Under the influence of Indian religious nationalisms and the arrival of Mauritian independence, Mardévirin worship lost ground, the deity's figure failing to fit in with the religious sensitivities of a new, nascent, "global" order. Finally, mainly through fieldwork, I have inquired about what subsists of Mardévirin in today's Mauritius. I found that although the worship is now marginal and residual, Mardévirin is still remembered as a symbol of subaltern religious identity. Globally, this research insists, through the figure of Mardévirin, on the importance that guardian deity worship played in the liminal religious life that connected South India and colonial Mauritius Island. It also highlights the way the religious economy was radically transformed by postcolonial modernity. </description><creator>Ahnee, Marek</creator><contributor>Davesh Soneji (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Religious Studies</subject><title>Reimagining Mardévirin: the memory of forgotten religion in post-colonial Mauritius</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301411w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w2418</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q693n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La petite corbeille d'Asie Corbicula fluminea est une des espèces dulcicoles les plus envahissantes au monde. On croyait jadis que sa distribution était limitée aux cours d'eau des régions tempérées chaudes mais elle a récemment élargi son aire de répartition en Amérique du Nord vers le nord, dans des régions tempérées froides. À l'aide d'expériences en laboratoire, j'ai démontré que la tolérance à l'hypoxie froide varie entre populations. Ainsi, les évaluations de risques basées sur les données de tolérances environnementales dérivées d'une seule population ne sont pas fiables. En utilisant des techniques de modélisation de la qualité du climat, j'ai identifié des régions d'Amérique du Nord potentiellement à risque de faire face à une invasion de C. fluminea sous les conditions climatiques actuelles et futures. Finalement, j'ai quantifié les taux de dégradation des coquilles de C. fluminea entre différent types d'habitats afin d'évaluer la faisabilité d'utiliser ce trait en tant qu'indicateur de succès d'établissement. Mes résultats soulignent l'importance de considérer la variation phénotypique et la dépendance contextuelle lors de l'identification des écosystèmes à risque d'invasion de petites corbeilles d'Asie. </description><description>The Asian clam Corbicula fluminea – one of the world's most invasive freshwater species – was previously believed to be limited to warm temperate habitats, but has extended its North American range northward into cold temperate waters in recent years. Using lab experiments, I show that C. fluminea tolerance to low oxygen varies across populations; therefore, risk assessments that are based on environmental tolerance data derived from only a single population are unreliable. Using climate suitability modeling techniques, I identify regions in North America at risk of C. fluminea invasion under current and future climate conditions. Finally, I experimentally quantify variation in shell degradation rates across different habitat conditions, to evaluate the feasibility of using spent shells as an indicator of establishment success. These results highlight the importance of accounting for phenotypic variation and context dependence when identifying ecosystems at risk of invasion.   </description><creator>Morden, Andrea</creator><contributor>Anthony Ricciardi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>The northern range extension of the invasive bivalve «Corbicula fluminea»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042w674.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q693n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nb66v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les Objectifs: Les trois études de ma thèse de doctorat sont motivées par l'ensemble des objectifs de la SFLT et par les inégalités socio-économiques en matière du tabagisme. La première étude a évalué l'efficacité des taxes sur les cigarettes comme  outil pour la prévention du tabagisme, ainsi que  comme outil pour la prévention du développement d'habitudes tabagiques chez les jeunes. La deuxième étude a évalué l'efficacité des taxes sur les cigarettes pour faciliter le sevrage tabagique et réduire la fréquence du tabagisme chez les adultes. La troisième étude a évalué l'effet protecteur de la législation antitabac sur la prévalence du tabagisme et la fréquence de la consommation du tabac sur la population adulte canadienne. Les deuxième et troisième études comprenaient également une évaluation de l'impact potentiel sur les écarts du tabagisme par niveau d'éducation Résultats: Pour nos analyses nous avons utilisé la base de donnes de L'Enquête de surveillance de l'usage du tabac au Canada (ESUTC), pour les années 2002 à 2012. Nous avons aussi exploité la variation des niveaux de la taxe d'accise sur les cigarettes pendant cette période et la mise en œuvre de la législation antitabac par les provinces. Nous avons utilisé des modèles de régression avec des effets fixes pour chaque province, des variables de niveau individuel et des variables de niveau provincial.Pour la recherche de l'objectif de la première étude, les changements dans les taxes d'accise sur les cigarettes ont donné des contributions négligeables à la réduction de l'usage du tabac chez les jeunes. Avec une augmentation de 1,00 $ en taxes d'accise sur un paquet de 20 cigarettes, l'effet marginal était de 0,2 (IC 95%: -1,8, 2,2) points de pourcentage pour la prévalence du tabagisme, et de 0,3 (IC 95%: -1,2, 1,8) cigarettes fumées dans la dernière semaine. Nous avons obtenu des résultats similaires pour l'effet moyen des impôts sur le tabagisme chez les adultes pour l'objectif de la deuxième étude. Avec une augmentation de 1,00 $ en taxes d'accise sur un paquet de 20 cigarettes, l'effet marginal était de -0,1 (IC 95%: -1,7 1,5) points de pourcentage pour la prévalence du tabagisme, et  de -0,1 (IC à 95%: -1.9, 1.7) cigarettes fumées, pour la fréquence de consommation. Nous avons aussi tiré des résultats nuls lors de l'évaluation de l'impact des taxes d'accise sur les cigarettes en rapport avec chaque niveau d'éducation, et ce pour l'effet sur la prévalence du tabagisme et la fréquence de consommation du tabac. De même pour l'objectif de la troisième étude, la législation antitabac provinciale a eu peu d'impact sur le tabagisme chez les adultes. L'estimation de l'effet moyen marginal de la prévalence du tabagisme était de 0,1 (IC 95% : -1.3, 1,4) points de pourcentage. L'effet moyen marginal pour la consommation du tabac était de -0,6 (IC 95%: -2,2, 1,0) cigarettes. Encore une fois, nous avons tiré des résultats nuls lors de l'évaluation de l'impact de la législation antitabac provinciale en rapport avec chaque niveau d'éducation, et ce pour l'effet sur la prévalence du tabagisme et la fréquence de consommation du tabac.  Conclusions: De 2002 à 2012, la prévalence du tabagisme et la moyenne de la fréquence de la consumation du tabac ont été en baisse constante au Canada. Ces baisses, cependant, sont présents même dans les provinces où les niveaux d'imposition des cigarettes sont stable ou en baisse, ainsi que pour les provinces qui ont mise en place de la législation antitabac plus tard que d'autres. Cela suggéré que d'autres facteurs communs dans toutes les provinces, telle que un sentiment anti-tabac florissant, ont eu une plus grande influence sur la consommation du tabac.</description><description>Background: Various tobacco control laws and strategies have been implemented in Canada since the 1980s. Excise tobacco taxes are a common form of tobacco control, and tax levels in Canada have been gradually increasing since the 1980s. More recently, the Federal Tobacco Control Strategy (FTCS) was launched in 2001 as a planned 10-year initiative by Health Canada (HC), in partnership with Public Health Agency of Canada (PHAC) and other agencies. We can summarize the FTCS goals as the following: (i) prevention of smoking among youths, (ii) cessation and reduction of consumption among smokers, and (iii) protection of non-smokers from environmental tobacco smoke. Although both smoking prevalence and smoking frequency have declined during the time of the FTCS, the contributions of the various tobacco control strategies in effect in achieving FTCS goals are unclear. Moreover, there exists a socioeconomic gap in smoking among the adult population, and it is also unclear what impact tobacco control strategies operating during the time of the FTCS have had on this gap. Objectives: The three studies of my PhD dissertation are motivated by the set of  Federal Tobacco Control Strategy (FTCS) goals and the socioeconomic inequality in smoking. The first one evaluated the effectiveness of cigarette taxes as a tool for the prevention of smoking and the development of a habit among youths. The second study assessed the effectiveness of cigarette taxes in facilitating smoking cessation, and reducing smoking frequency among adults. The third study evaluated the protective effect of smoke-free legislation, but assessed smoking prevalence and frequency on the adult Canadian population. The second and third studies also included an evaluation of the potential differential effects by education. Results: For our analyses, we used the Canadian Tobacco Usage Monitoring Survey 2002-2012 database and exploited the variation in excise cigarette tax levels and implementation of smoke-free legislation among the provinces. We used regression models with province and year fixed effects, individual-level covariates, and provincial-level covariates. For Research Objective 1, changes in excise cigarette taxes yielded negligible contributions to the reduction in smoking behaviour among youths. For an increase of $1.00 in excise cigarette taxes per package of 20, the marginal effect was 0.2 (95% CI: -1.8, 2.2) percentage points for smoking prevalence, and 0.3 (95% CI: -1.2, 1.8) cigarettes for smoking frequency (past-week). We obtained similar results for the average effect of taxes on smoking behaviour among adults for Research Objective 2. For an increase of $1.00 in excise cigarette taxes per package of 20, the marginal effect was -0.1 (95% CI: -1.7, 1.5) percentage points for smoking prevalence, and -0.1 (95% CI: -1.9, 1.7) cigarettes (per week) for smoking frequency. We continued to derive null results when assessing the impact of excise cigarette taxes by education for both smoking outcomes.Likewise, for Research Objective 3, provincial smoke-free legislation (PSFL) had little impact on smoking behaviour among adults. The marginal average effect for smoking prevalence was 0.1 (95% CI: -1.3, 1.4) percentage points. The marginal average effect for smoking frequency was -0.6 (95% CI: -2.2, 1.0) cigarettes. Again, we derived null results when assessing the impact of PSFL by education for both smoking outcomes. Conclusions: From 2002-2012, both smoking prevalence and mean smoking frequency have been in steady decline in Canada. These declines, however, are present even in provinces with stable or decreasing cigarette tax levels and for provinces which implement smoke-free legislation at a later time, suggesting that other factors common to all provinces such as growing anti-smoking sentiment have had a greater influence over tobacco use.</description><creator>Manivong, Phongsack</creator><contributor>Erin Strumpf (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Samuel Harper (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</subject><title>An evaluation of tobacco control strategies on smoking-related outcomes in Canada during the time of the federal tobacco control strategy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547v196.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nb66v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bp35k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Observational studies have long reported an association between decreased vitamin D and increased risk of multiple sclerosis (MS). However since it is difficult to fully protect these approaches from confounding and reverse causation, it remains unclear whether vitamin D is a causal risk factor in MS etiology. Objectives: To review the current literature of the association between vitamin D and MS and discuss the limitations of these previous approaches. Next, to introduce Mendelian randomization (MR) and apply its principles to investigate whether the genetic determinants of vitamin D are associated with MS susceptibility. Methods: PubMed was used to search for relevant ecological, observational and randomized controlled trials. For our MR analysis, we first selected single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) that achieved genome-wide significant (p-value &lt; 5 x10-8) for 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD), the clinical determinant of vitamin D status, in the SUNLIGHT consortium (N= 33,996). We then obtained effect sizes for these SNPs upon MS in the International Multiple Sclerosis Genetics Consortium (IMSGC), the largest genome-wide association study for MS (including up to 14,498 cases and 24,091 controls). MR estimates were obtained by weighting each SNP's effect on MS by its effect on 25OHD, with estimates pooled to provide a summary measure of the effect of genetically lowered vitamin D upon risk of MS.Results: Results of our MR analysis using four vitamin D associated SNPs, demonstrated that a 1 standard deviation decrease in natural log 25OHD increased odds of MS by 2 fold (OR=2.02, 95% CI: 1.7–2.5; p = 7.7 × 10−12; I2 = 63%, 95% CI: 0%–88%). Conclusions: Using MR, our findings support vitamin D as a causal risk factor for MS, substantiating conclusions first suggested by observational analyses. This provides rationale to promote vitamin D awareness among individual at risk for MS. Whether vitamin D supplementation can prevent MS warrants further investigation by long-term clinical trials. </description><description>Contexte: Des études observationelles rapportent depuis longtemps une association entre la baisse du niveau de vitamine D et l'augmentation du risque de sclérose en plaques (SP). Or, puisqu'il est difficile de complètement protéger ces approches de l'effet des facteurs de confusion et de la rétrocausalité, il reste toujours à déterminer si le niveau de vitamine D est réellement un facteur de risque causal dans l'étiologie de la SP.Objectifs: Passer en revue les publications portant sur l'association entre la vitamine D et la SP et discuter des limites des approches précédentes. Ensuite, introduire la randomisation mendélienne (RM) et appliquer ses principes pour évaluer si les déterminants génétiques de la vitamine D sont associés à la prédisposition à la SP. Méthodes: PubMed a été utilisé pour identifier les études randomisées, observationelles et écologiques pertinentes. Pour notre analyse de RM, nous avons d'abord sélectionné les polymorphismes nucléotidiques (SNP, single-nucleotide polymorphism) qui étaient significatifs au niveau du génome (valeur-p &lt; 5 x10-8) pour la 25-hydroxyvitamine D (25OHD), le déterminant clinique du niveau de vitamine D, dans l'étude du consortium SUNLIGHT (N = 33,996). Nous avons ensuite obtenu les tailles d'effet des SNPs sur la SP pour l'étude du International Multiple Sclerosis Genetics Consortium (IMSGC), la plus importante étude d'association pangénomique portant sur la SP (incluant 14,498 cas et 24,091 témoins). Les estimés de l'étude de RM ont ensuite été obtenus en pondérant l'effet de chaque SNP sur la SP par son effet sur la 25OHD, les estimés étant finalement groupés afin d'obtenir une mesure conjointe de l'effet sur le risque de SP d'un niveau génétiquement bas de vitamine D.Résultats: Les résultats de notre analyse de RM utilisant quatre SNPs associés à la vitamine D démontrent qu'une baisse du niveau de 25OHD équivalant à une erreur type (sur l'échelle logarithmique) double la cote de la SP (OR=2.02, 95% CI: 1.7–2.5; p = 7.7 ×10−12; I2 = 63%, 95% CI: 0%–88%). Conclusions: En utilisant la RM, nos conclusions supportent l'hypothèse de la vitamine D comme facteur de risque causal pour la SP, appuyant les conclusions d'abord suggérées par les études observationelles. Elles supportent aussi la promotion de la vitamine D chez les individus à risque de SP. Toutefois, des études randomisées de longue haleine sont nécessaires pour déterminer si les suppléments de vitamine D peuvent prévenir la SP.</description><creator>Mokry, Lauren</creator><contributor>John Brent Richards (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</subject><title>Using Mendelian randomization to elucidate the role of vitamin D in multiple sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333510q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bp35k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb396</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This PhD thesis pertains to the subject of small field dosimetry. Small photon fields, generally referring to fields smaller than 2 × 2 cm2, are routinely used in the clinic during modern radiotherapy treatment deliveries. However, several investigators have raised questions regarding the accuracy of the dosimetry in such conditions. An important issue involves the significant perturbations that are caused by most detectors in small field conditions. These perturbations will result in erroneous dose calculations during treatment planning and affect the treatment outcome. Currently it is still not clear which detector system should be preferred in small fields. In this work, the response of modern dosimeters is investigated via Monte Carlo simulations and experiments. Detector-specific correction and perturbation factors are reported for modern detector systems and their accuracy is evaluated experimentally. The need for off-axis corrections is also investigated, a less explored area in previous research. The calibration process, essential for some detector systems, is carefully examined and recommendations are provided. Another unexplored area that directly affects the dosimetry in small fields is the accurate knowledge of the X-ray source distribution. As the field size is reduced and becomes comparable to the X-ray source size, significant accelerator output variations are observed. In principle these variations can be predicted if direct source reconstruction methods are developed. Current source reconstruction methods require special equipment, not easily accessible in every clinic. In this work we suggest a novel approach for the source reconstruction problem, which requires no prior knowledge of the source's functional form nor any specialized equipment. The method is based on a maximum-likelihood expectation-maximization algorithm and utilizes small field photon fluence profiles. The method is evaluated and benchmarked against simulations and experiments and significant sources of uncertainties are identified.</description><description>Cette thèse de doctorat porte sur le sujet de la dosimétrie en petits champs. Les sources de photons dits en "petits champs " font généralement référence à des champs plus petits que 2 × 2 cm2 et sont couramment utilisés en clinique durant les traitement de radiothérapie modernes. Cependant, plusieurs chercheurs ont soulevé des questions quant à l'exactitude de la dosimétrie dans de telles conditions. Une question importante concerne les perturbations considérables causées par la plupart des détecteurs dans des conditions utilisant des petits champs. Ces perturbations vont entraîner des calculs de doses erronés lors de la planification du traitement et ainsi affecter leur résultat. Actuellement, le système de détecteur à privilégier dans des conditions de petits champs n'a pas encore été déterminé. Dans ce travail, la réponse des dosimètres modernes est étudiée via des simulations Monte-Carlo, ainsi que dans des conditions expérimentales. Les facteurs de corrections et de perturbations spécifiques aux différents détecteurs modernes sont présentés dans cette étude, et leur exactitude est évaluée expérimentalement. La nécessité des corrections hors-axe est également étudiée, une zone moins explorée dans les précédents travaux de recherches. Le processus d'étalonnage, essentiel pour certains systèmes de détection, est méticuleusement examinée et des recommandations sont établies. Un autre domaine inexploré qui affecte directement la dosimétrie en petits champs est la connaissance précise dela distribution spatiale de la source de rayons X. Lorsque la taille du champ est considérablement réduite et devient comparable à la taille de la source, d'importantes variations en sortie de l'accélérateur linéaire sont observées. En principe, ces variations peuvent être prédites si des méthodes de reconstruction directe de la source à rayons X sont développés. Les méthodes de reconstruction de la source actuellement utilisées nécessitent des équipements spéciaux qui sont difficilement accessibles dans chaque clinique de radiothérapie. Dans cette étude, nous proposons une nouvelle approche pour résoudre le problème de la reconstruction de la source à rayons X qui ne nécessite aucune connaissance préalable de la forme fonctionnelle de la source, ni aucun équipement spécialisé. La méthode est basée sur un algorithme dénommé "maximum-likelihood expectation-maximization" et utilise des profils de fluence de photons en petits champs. La méthode est évaluée et comparée à des simulations et expériences de références, et d'importantes sources d'incertitudes sont identifiées.</description><creator>Papaconstadopoulos, Paul</creator><contributor>Jan Peter Frans Seuntjens (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>On the detector response and the reconstruction of the source intensity distribution in small photon fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r126x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb396</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3014125</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A growing body of research suggests that the perception and production of complex auditory signals such as music and speech is fundamentally anticipatory: Listeners generate future-oriented expectations for upcoming sounds during perception, and producers generate future-oriented plans for upcoming movements during production. The role of interactions between auditory and motor systems in anticipatory processing during perception and production, and the neural indices of these influences, are unknown. This thesis hypothesizes that, when a sensorimotor stimulus has been learned by production, the motor system generates plans for upcoming events during subsequent perception, and the auditory system generates expectations for upcoming events during subsequent production. This hypothesis is investigated using electroencephalography methods in the context of music perception and production, which are common anticipatory behaviors. Roles of auditory-motor integration in anticipatory processing are investigated in three empirical studies. The first study investigated whether performing music can enhance memory and expectations during subsequent listening to that music. This study revealed that motor networks contribute to enhanced recognition of expectancy violations in music that has been learned by performance. The second study investigated whether performing music can alter sensory and cognitive expectations for musical pitch during subsequent listening. This study revealed that production learning diminishes the extent to which listeners generate sensory and cognitive expectations during subsequent listening. The third study investigated whether planning during music performance can influence the perception of concurrent pitch feedback. This study revealed that disruptive effects of altered auditory feedback on performance are linked to future-oriented planning processes. Together, these studies support the hypothesis that motor plans and auditory expectations work in association to anticipate upcoming events during music perception and production. Effects of auditory-motor integration on anticipatory processing can take place rapidly (within 200 ms) following acoustic onsets, and anticipatory processes during perception and production take into account previously learned auditory-motor associations.</description><description>Un nombre croissant de recherches suggère que la perception et la production de signaux auditifs complexes tels que la musique et la parole sont fondamentalement anticipatoire: Les auditeurs génèrent des attentes orientées vers l'avenir pour les sons à venir lors de la perception, et les producteurs génèrent des plans orientés vers l'avenir pour les mouvements à venir lors de la production. Le rôle des interactions entre les systèmes auditifs et moteurs dans le traitement anticipatoire pendant la perception et la production, et les indices neuraux de ces influences, sont inconnus. Cette thèse hypothèse que, quand un stimulus sensori-moteur a été appris par la production, le système moteur génère des plans pour les événements à venir au cours de la perception subséquente, et le système auditif génère des attentes pour les événements à venir au cours de la production subséquente. Cette hypothèse est étudiée en utilisant  des méthodes de l'électroencéphalographie dans le cadre de la perception et de la production de la musique, qui sont des comportements d'anticipation communs. Les rôles de l'intégration audito-motrice dans le traitement anticipatoire sont étudiés dans trois études empiriques. La première étude a examiné si l'exécution de la musique peut améliorer la mémoire et les attentes lors d'une écoute subséquente de cette musique. Cette étude a révélé que les réseaux moteurs contribuent à une meilleure reconnaissance des violations des attentes dans la musique qui a été appris par la performance. La deuxième étude a examiné si l'exécution de la musique peut modifier les attentes sensorielles et cognitives pour la hauteur musicale lors d'une écoute subséquente. Cette étude a révélé que l'apprentissage par la production diminue la mesure dans laquelle les auditeurs génèrent des attentes sensorielles et cognitives pendant l'écoute subséquente. La troisième étude a examiné si la planification pendant l'exécution de la musique peut influencer la perception de la rétroaction de la hauteur musicale concurrente. Cette étude a révélé que les effets perturbateurs du retour auditif modifié sur la performance sont liés aux processus de planification orientés vers l'avenir. Ensemble, ces études soutiennent l'hypothèse que les plans moteurs oeuvrent en association avec les attentes auditives pour anticiper les événements à venir au cours de la perception et de la production de la musique. Les effets de l'intégration audito-motrice sur le traitement anticipatoire peuvent avoir lieu rapidement (moins de 200 ms) après le débout acoustique, et les processus anticipatifs pendant la perception et la production tiennent compte des associations audito-motrices apprises préalablement.</description><creator>Mathias, Brian</creator><contributor>Caroline Palmer (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Neural and behavioral indices of auditory-motor integration during music perception and production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf65b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3014125</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676z55t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study a class of symmetric space orbital integrals important for relating distinction of automorphic representations on unitary groups to distinction on general linear groups. In the first part, we verify a fundamental lemma for U(2)xU(2)-&gt;U(4) via an explicit calculation, showing strong evidence that there is a general theory of endoscopy lurking here. In the second part, we determine a formula for the dimension of a family of affine Springer fibers associated to a symmetric space arising from the block diagonal embedding GL(n)xGL(n)-&gt;GL(2n). These dimensions ought to be related to the transfer factors in a conjectural fundamental lemma. </description><description>Nous étudions une classe d'intégrales orbitales pour les espaces symétriques qui sont utilisées pour relier a distinction de représentations automorphiques sur les groupes unitaires à distinction sur GL(n). Dans la première partie, nous vérifions un lemme fondamental pour U(2)xU(2)-&gt;U(4) par un calcul explicite, montrant évidence qu'il cettes une théorie générale de l'endoscopie qui se cache ici. Dans la deuxième partie, nous déterminons une formule pour la dimension de fibres de Springer affines qui sont associées à un espace symétrique découlant du plongement diagonale par blocs GL(n)xGL(n)-&gt;GL(2n). Ces dimensions doivent être liées à des facteurs de transfert d'un lemme fondamental conjecturale.</description><creator>Polak, Jason</creator><contributor>Jayce Getz (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Henri Darmon (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Relative endoscopy for unitary symmetric spaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh50k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676z55t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445ch07s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the past years, much of bilingualism research has demonstrated that regardless of the intention to use only one language, both languages known to the bilingual are simultaneously activated. The current dissertation is designed to answer one of the most persistent questions in the study of bilingual language production: given the parallel activation of both languages, how does the bilingual brain distinguish and select words from the language in use? According to one view, the process of lexical selection restricts competition to nodes from the target language alone. In contrast, the second view assumes that lexical selection entails cross-language competition. More recently, a third reconciliatory view has emerged, suggesting that the language selection mechanism is dynamic and may or may not entail cross-language competition depending on a host of factors. The studies in the present dissertation were motivated by this debate and specifically examined whether factors such as word status and individual differences in domain-general inhibitory control modulated the mechanism of lexical selection for production. The first study investigated whether the process of lexical selection varied as a function of the ability to recruit inhibitory control and as a function of cognate status of a word in a group of French-English bilingual younger adults through a picture-word interference task and the Simon task. The second study investigated whether older adults demonstrate different patterns of within- and cross-language activity during lexical selection from younger adults, given age-related declines in executive functions. Taken together, findings from studies 1 and 2 suggest that lexical alternatives from the non-target language are co-activated and compete for selection. Overall, younger and older bilinguals demonstrated similar patterns of within- and cross-language distractor effects. However, older adults showed larger magnitude distractor effects and had greater difficulty in resolving competition to achieve successful word production. Of note for the role of individual differences in inhibitory control in lexical selection, increased inhibition of lexical competition was significantly predicted by enhanced inhibitory control across both age groups. Finally, cognate status of a word marginally influenced lexical access for speech production.In sum, the data presented in the current dissertation fit within the framework of those models that prescribe a central role for inhibitory control during lexical access. Keywords: bilingual lexical selection, cross-language competition, cognitive aging, individual differences in inhibitory control, picture-word interference.</description><description>Au cours des dernières années, une grande partie de la recherche en bilinguisme a démontré que les deux langues connues par le locuteur sont co-activées durant la production de la parole, peu importe la langue cible à produire. Le but de la présente thèse est de répondre à une des questions fondamentales du domaine : comment le cerveau bilingue arrive-t-il à distinguer et sélectionner les mots de la langue cible malgré la co-activation des deux langues ? D'un côté, certains auteurs proposent que les processus de sélection lexicale impliquent une compétition seulement entre les lexèmes de la langue cible. À l'opposé, d'autres auteurs tiennent pour acquis que la sélection lexicale implique une compétition interlinguistique, due à la co-activation des deux langues. Plus récemment, un troisième angle de recherche s'est développé. Ce dernier suggère que les mécanismes de sélection lexicale sont en fait dynamiques et qu'un grand nombre de facteurs peut favoriser ou limiter la compétition interlinguistique.Les deux études présentées ici ont été motivées par ce débat et visent à observer si les mécanismes de sélection lexicale peuvent être influencés par des facteurs tels que le statut lexical et les différences individuelles affectant le contrôle inhibiteur. La première étude vise à déterminer si les processus de sélection lexicale varient en fonction de la capacité de mobiliser le contrôle inhibiteur et en fonction du statut lexicale du mot (mot apparenté ou non apparenté ; ang. : « cognate »). Pour ce faire, on a recours à un groupe de jeunes adultes bilingues (français – anglais) qui participent à une tâche de dénomination d'images et une tâche de type Simon (ang. : « Simon task »). La deuxième étude vise à déterminer si les personnes plus âgées présentent des patrons d'activation ou de co-activation linguistique différents de ceux des jeunes adultes lors de tâches de sélection lexicale, ce qui pourrait être expliqué par le déclin cognitif normal affectant cette population.Pris dans leur ensemble, les résultats de ces deux études démontrent qu'il y a co-activation des deux langues et donc compétition interlinguistique lors de la sélection des lexèmes à produire. Ainsi, les deux groupes de participants (jeunes adultes et personnes plus âgées) présentent des patrons d'activation et de co-activation linguistique similaires. Toutefois, les personnes plus âgées ont eu plus de difficulté à sélectionner le lexème adéquat lorsqu'en présence d'un distracteur (peu importe la langue). Il est aussi intéressant de noter que l'efficacité de la sélection lexicale en présence de distracteur (nécessaire pour l'inhibition des compétiteurs) varie en fonction de l'efficacité du contrôle inhibiteur dans les deux groupes d'âge ; meilleur est le contrôle inhibiteur, meilleur est la sélection lexicale malgré le distracteur. Finalement, le statut de mot apparenté (« cognate ») ou pas n'a eu qu'un impact marginal sur la sélection lexicale pour la production de la parole.En somme, les données présentées dans la présente thèse concordent avec le cadre théorique des modèles qui assignent un rôle central au contrôle inhibiteur dans l'accès lexical. Mots-clés: Sélection lexicale bilingue, compétition interlinguistique, déclin cognitif, différences individuelles dans le contrôle inhibiteur, interférence image-mot.</description><creator>Sudarshan, Aruna</creator><contributor>Baum, Shari (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015-12</date><subject>Communications Sciences &amp; Disorders</subject><title>Bilingual language control: Effects of cognitive aging, word status and individual differences in executive functions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb024.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445ch07s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128d79x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse se compose de trois essais sur l'implication de trading multi-marchés sur la liquidité et les spreads de CDS. Le premier essai d'évaluer les avantages de la diversification potentiels de la détention d'actions transversales inscrites dans une perspective du risque de liquidité. En examinant la structure de dépendance entre le portefeuille du marché des États-Unis et de cotations croisées 1950-2012, je trouve que la corrélation linéaire moyenne, corrélation de rang, et la queue dépendance des innovations de liquidité sont notamment inférieurs à ceux des rendements du portefeuille. La solution du problème d'optimisation de portefeuille dans le cadre Mean-Variance-liquidité montre que la tenue d'inscriptions étrangères dans le États-Unis peut réduire le risque de liquidité de près de 40 pour cent pour les investisseurs nationaux U.S. Mes résultats suggèrent les avantages de la diversification internationale sont particulièrement profonde dans la dimension du risque de liquidité. Dans le second essai, j'examiner le rôle des marchés internationaux pour la fourniture de liquidité et le partage des risques en utilisant un échantillon complet des entreprises américaines négociés sur 20 bourses étrangères depuis 1901 avec les données disponibles de retour et de liquidité de 1950. Les tests montrent que le marché de ralentissement de la liquidité des entreprises intercotées est significativement supérieur à celle des entreprises qui sont inscrites seulement au niveau national. Ce résultat est d'autant plus forte lorsque les entreprises sont contre-cotée sur plusieurs bourses, ainsi que dans les marchés liquides plus grands et plus. L'estimation ultérieure révèle que le commerce étranger en actions fermes conduire à une réduction significative de deux bêtas de liquidité, qui sont basées sur la sensibilité de la liquidité ferme à sa liquidité du marché intérieur et son retour sur le marché intérieur. Nos résultats soulignent donc l'importance des marchés financiers mondiaux pour fournir la liquidité et de réduire le risque de liquidité. La troisième étude de dissertation comment les échanges dans plusieurs marchés affecte l'intégration de la structure du capital d'une entreprise. En utilisant des données quotidiennes sur les titres de la Croix-cotées et les swaps de défaut de crédit (CDS) échangés à travers le monde, nous constatons que l'inscription étrangère améliore la synchronisation entre les fermes d'actions et CDS rendements. Les tests d'intégration révèlent que, après la cotation étrangère, le risque de crédit propre à l'entreprise devient plus exposés à la fois mondiale et les risques du marché des actions locales, avec un plus grand changement dans la version bêta du marché mondial. Nos résultats suggèrent que les cotations croisées ont un impact important sur la dette et marché des actions d'intégration, et que cette intégration est plus facilement atteinte des titres d'entreprises plus visibles.</description><description>This thesis consists of three essays about the implication of multi-market trading on liquidity and CDS spreads. The first essay evaluates the potential diversification benefits of holding cross-listed stocks from a liquidity risk perspective. By examining the dependence structure between the U.S. market portfolio and cross-listings from 1950 to 2012, I find that the average linear correlation, rank correlation, and tail dependence of liquidity innovations are notably lower than those of portfolio returns. The solution of the portfolio optimization problem under the Mean-Variance-Liquidity framework shows that holding foreign listings in the U.S. can reduce the liquidity risk by up to 40 percent for U.S domestic investors. My findings suggest the benefits of international diversification are especially profound in the dimension of liquidity risk. In the second essay, I examine the role of international markets for liquidity provision and risk sharing using a full sample of U.S. firms traded on 20 foreign exchanges since 1901 with stock return and liquidity data from 1950. The tests show that in market downturns the liquidity of cross-listed firms is significantly higher than that of companies that are listed only domestically. This result is especially strong when firms are cross-listed on multiple exchanges, as well as in larger and more liquid markets. The subsequent estimation reveals that foreign trading in firm shares lead to significant reduction in two liquidity betas, which are based on the sensitivity of firm liquidity to its domestic market liquidity and its domestic market return. Our findings therefore highlight the importance of global financial markets for supplying liquidity and reducing liquidity risk. The third essay studies how trading in multiple markets affects the integration of a firm's capital structure. Using daily data on cross-listed securities and credit default swaps (CDS) traded around the world, we find that foreign listing improves the synchronicity between firm stock and CDS returns. Integration tests reveal that, after foreign listing, firm-specific credit risk becomes more exposed to both world and local equity market risks, with a larger change in the world market beta. Our results suggest that cross-listings have an important impact on debt and equity market integration, and that this integration is more easily attained for securities of more visible firms.</description><creator>Jiao, Feng</creator><contributor>Sergei Sarkissian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Management</subject><title>Multi-market trading and its implication on liquidity and CDS spreads</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jb574.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d79x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257h66m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Associations are a very common concept in software modelling, in particular when using class diagrams for expressing domain models or structural design models. Concern-Oriented Reuse (CORE) proposes a new way of structuring model-driven software development where models of the system are modularized by domains of abstraction within units of reuse called concerns. This thesis illustrates how many of the variations of associations and association implementations have been captured within a concern called Association, together with behavioural models that ensure uniqueness, minimum/maximum size constraints and referential integrity. Furthermore, the provided Association concern documents the impact of using a specific association variation on high-level system qualities. Finally, the thesis describes how the TouchCORE tool was streamlined to support concern-oriented, agile, UML-conformant modelling with associations and rapid selection of association variants according to desired high-level system qualities.</description><description>Les associations sont un concept très commun en modélisation de logiciel, particulièrement en utilisant des diagrammes de classe pour représenter des modèles de domaine ou des modèles de conception. La réutilisation orientée préoccupation (CORE) propose une nouvelle manière de structurer le développement de logiciel dirigé par des modèles où les modèles du système sont modulables à l'intérieur d'une unité réutilisable appelée une préoccupation. Cette thèse illustre les variations des associations et la mise en œuvre des associations capturées dans une préoccupation appelée Association, ainsi que les modèles de comportement qui garantissent l'unicité, les contraintes de taille minimum ou maximum d'une collection et de l'intégrité référentielle. De plus, la préoccupation Association documente les impacts sur les qualités du système lors de l'utilisation d'une certaine variation. Enfin, cette thèse décrit comment l'outil TouchCORE a été modifié pour faciliter la réutilisation de cette préoccupation de manière agile et adaptée aux normes UML. Ses modifications permettent une sélection rapide d'une variation de l'association selon les qualités du système choisies.</description><creator>Bensoussan, Céline</creator><contributor>Jorg Andreas Kienzle (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Associations in MDE: a concern-oriented, reusable solution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc01q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257h66m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c110v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les fragments de code (petite portion réutilisable de code source) sont d'importantes ressources aﬁn de comprendre les interfaces de programmation (API) de bibliothèques logicielles. Dans plusieurs scénarios d'utilisation de fragments de code, ils doivent être réduient à l'essentiel. Par exemple, lorsqu'il servent d'indices pour de plus longs programmes, aﬁn de rappeler aux développeurs des idiomes qu'ils connaissent déjà ou encore pour afficher des résultats de recherche. Cette dissertation fait un compte-rendu de la recherche sur la réduction, ou la synthèse, des fragments de code, et apporte trois principales contributions : L'étude de cas sur la génération de résumé de fragments de codes est basée sur une approche d'apprentissage automatique supervisée qui détermine si chaque ligne dans un fragment de code devrait faire parti de la résumé. Nous présentons les leçons que nous avons apprises et qui sont essentielles à la réussite des deux étapes suivantes de la recherche : la collection de caractéristiques la plus performante, qui est une combinaison de caractéristiques syntactiques et particulières à des requêtes, et trois restrictions de la méthode d'apprentissage automatique supervisée et de la formulation du problème par chaque ligne. Ces restrictions provenaient de l'emploi de lignes comme le niveaux de granularité, des problèmes pour l'obtenir des données de bonne qualité and des problèmes de travailler seulement sûr une ligne sans considérer les dépendances entre différentes parties du code. Motivés par les limites de la résumé par ligne, nous avons étudié comment les humains réduisent des fragments de codes aﬁn de comprendre la nature du résultat du procédé de résumé. D'après 156 résumés faites à la main par 16 participants, nous avons analyzé les décisions de sélection et de présentation du contenu de la résumé. Nous avons obtenu un catalogue des pratiques de résumé communes pour ces décisions parmi ces résumés, ainsi qu'une explication de ces pratiques, en employant des méthodes qualitatives et quantitatives. Nous avons découvert qu'aucun des participants a construit une résumé en utilisant textuellement des fragments de code en façon exclusif. Les participants ont utilisé diverses techniques aﬁn de modiﬁer le contenu, raccourcir une ligne, tronquer le code, amasser de vaste quantités de code et réingénierie logicielle. Les participants n'étaient seulement occupés par l'objectif principal de réductionde code, mais voulaient également obtenir un code lisible, compréhensible et pouvant être compilé. Finalement, nous avons conçu une technique pour créer des résumés restreintes par leur hauteur et leur largeur : à partir d'un fragment de code et d'une requête (un ensemble de mots clés), notre technique produit une version du fragment plus courte qui occupe un espace bidimensional de L lignes par W colonnes et qui capture autant d'éléments du code original que possible, relatifs à la requête, tout endemeurant lisible. Aﬁn de générer ces résumés, nous avons développé un outil de résumé de code : Konaila. Konaila utilise un algorithme d'optimisation qui maximise la valeur du contenu sélectionné et le restreint à l'espace bidimensionalen L par W. Dans une évaluation avec des juges humaines sur les résumés créées à partir de fragments de code sur "Stack Overﬂow", un site internet populaire oú les utilisateurs répondent à des questions, nous avons découvert des indications démontrant que les résumés de Konaila sont efficaces : il fut jugé que la majorité des résumés de Konaila capture autant d'éléments originaux du code relativement aux questions de "Stack Overﬂow" que l'espace le permet, tout en demeurant lisibles. Un important resultat pour les prochaines technologies de résumé serait que l'optimisation est une étape essentielle à la creation de résumés efficaces.</description><description>Code fragments are an important resource for understanding the Application Programming Interface (API) of software libraries. Many usage scenarios for code fragments require them to be distilled to their essence: for example, when serving as cues to longer documents, for reminding developers of a previously known idiom, or for displaying search results. This dissertation reports on research on shortening, or summarizing, code fragments and makes three main contributions: a set of lessons learned from a case study on a supervised machine learning approach to the generation of code fragment summaries; an empirically grounded catalog of source code summarization practices; and the design, implementation and evaluation of a novel optimization-based summarization technique for code fragments. The case study on the generation of code fragment summaries was based on a supervised machine learning approach that classifies whether a line in a code fragment should be in a summary. We present the lessons learned that were key to the two subsequent parts of the research: the best performing feature set being a combination of syntactic and query-related features, and three limitations on our supervised machine learning approach and the line-based problem formulation. The limitations were in using line as the granularity, obtaining training data with high quality, and using only features that are local to a line without considering dependencies among different parts of the code. Motivated by the limitations of line-based summaries, we studied how humans shorten code fragments to understand the nature of the output of the summarization process. Based on 156 hand-generated summaries obtained from 16 participants, we analyzed decisions on which content to select and how to present this content in a summary. We elicited a catalog of common summarization practices behind these decisions across the summaries, as well as the rationale behind the practices, using a mix of qualitative and quantitative methods. We found that none of the participants exclusively extracted code verbatim for the summaries. Participants employed many practices to modify the content, by trimming a line, truncating code, aggregating a large amount of code, and refactoring code. Not only were the participants concerned with the main goal of the task to shorten code, but also with whether the summary looked compilable, readable and understandable. With the insights from the machine learning case study and the catalog of summarization practices, we devised a technique to generate summaries constrained in both height and width: given as input a code fragment and a query (a set of keywords), our technique produces a shorter version of the fragment that fits in a two-dimensional space (L lines by W columns) and that captures as much as possible of the essential elements of the original code related to the query, while remaining readable. To generate these summaries, we developed a code summarization tool called Konaila. Konaila maximizes the value of the content selected and constrains the chosen content to be formatted within the L by W space. In a human evaluation on summaries generated from code fragments on Stack Overflow, a popular question answering forum, we found evidence that Konaila's summaries are effective: the majority of Konaila's summaries were judged to capture as much as possible the original elements of the code related to the Stack Overflow question while remaining readable. One important insight for future summarization technology is that optimization is an essential step in the generation of effective summaries. The three contributions of this dissertation are a step towards generating effective code fragment summaries that can benefit usage scenarios involving the vast amount of publicly available code on the web.</description><creator>Ying, Annie</creator><contributor>Martin Robillard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Code fragment summarization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655k29q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c110v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m78x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Infants recovering from surgery and anesthesia are at risk of life-threatening Postoperative Apnea (POA). There is no way to predict which infants will experience POA, and therefore all infants with postmenstrual age (PMA) ≤ 60 weeks need to be monitored in hospital for at least 12 h postoperatively. Evidence shows a link between abnormal postoperative respiratory patterns and the occurrence of POA. Thus, study of these patterns might be useful to predict an infant's risk of POA, as well as the time when such risk abates.Comprehensive study of the postoperative respiratory patterns has been limited by two main factors. First, no representative set of respiratory data from infants at risk of POA is publicly available to investigators, and so any POA study involves a data acquisition phase that requires planning, approval, and execution. All these activities consume extensive resources and so the number of infants that can be enrolled is limited by the available budget. Second, there are no appropriate tools for the comprehensive analysis of the respiratory patterns. The most accepted method is conventional manual scoring (CMS), performed by expert scorers following guidelines from the American Academy of Sleep Medicine (AASM). CMS has several limitations: it has low intra- and inter-scorer repeatability, is labor intensive, time-consuming, and expensive. Moreover, CMS does not produce a comprehensive analysis of the respiratory patterns, but rather a list of "clinically relevant" events and the time of their occurrence. Thus, any pattern not considered "clinically relevant" by the AASM guidelines is not scored and cannot be analyzed.This thesis addresses these limitations by creating a library of infant data and developing several tools for the comprehensive analysis of infant respiratory patterns. We accomplished this in 5 stages. First, we acquired a representative dataset comprising cardiorespiratory signals from infants at risk of POA, and made these data available to the public. Second, we developed a set of tools for the efficient, repeatable, and reliable manual scoring of infant respiratory patterns. We demonstrated that use of these tools produced an analysis with high accuracy and consistency, and improved intra- and inter-scorer repeatability. Third, we developed a method based on Expectation-Maximization (EM) to combine analyses from multiple manual scorers to minimize the effects of intra- and inter-scorer variability and yield "gold standard" results with very high accuracy and consistency. These two developments improved the accuracy and repeatability of manual analysis but did not address its labor intensive, time-consuming and expensive nature. The fourth stage of this thesis addressed these limitations by automating the analysis. To do this, we developed an Automated Off-line Respiratory Event Detector (AORED) that analyses respiratory patterns by comparing metrics of respiratory behavior to thresholds to determine the presence of patterns. Optimal threshold values were selected using Receiver Operating Characteristics (ROC) analysis using manual analysis results as reference. AORED analysis agreed well with the "gold standard" manual analysis. However, its thresholds were based on the results of manual analysis so its performance will be influenced by the limitations of manual scoring. The fifth stage of the work addressed this through the development of AUREA, an Automated Unsupervised Respiratory Event Analysis system that applies unsupervised, K-means clustering to the metrics of respiratory behavior to classify the respiratory patterns. K-means requires no human intervention to work, so AUREA is completely automated and is not affected by the limitations of manual scoring. The validation results showed that AUREA had substantial accuracy (significantly higher than AORED), and almost perfect consistency.The contributions from this work will impact the study of respiratory patterns and POA in 7 ways: ...</description><description>La récupération post-chirurgicale et anesthésique des nourrissons présente un risque d'Apnée Postopératoire (APO) qui est potentiellement mortelle. La prédiction d'une APO est impossible, par conséquence tous les nourrissons d'âge post-menstruel (APM) ≤ 60 semaines doivent être surveillés à hôpital, pendant au moins 12 heures après la fin de l'opération. Des données ont montré un lien entre des schémas respiratoires postopératoires anormaux et l'occurrence d'une APO. L'étude de ces schémas pourrait ainsi se révéler utile quant à la prédiction d'un risque d'APO chez le nourrisson, mais également à la prédiction du temps nécessaire pour que ce risque disparaisse.L'étude complète des schémas respiratoires postopératoires a été limitée par deux facteurs principaux. Tout d'abord, aucun échantillon de données représentatives provenant de nourrissons à haut risque d'APO n'est disponible publiquement pour les chercheurs, et donc toute étude sur l'APO doit impérativement comporter une phase d'acquisition de données. Ceci implique planification, approbation et exécution, et ces tâches nécessitent de vastes ressources. Par conséquence, le nombre d'enfants participant à l'étude est limité par le budget disponible. Deuxièmement, aucun outil dédié à l'analyse complète des schémas respiratoires n'est actuellement disponible. La méthode généralement acceptée, le Score Manuel Conventionnel (SMC), est effectuée par des opérateurs experts qui suivent les directives de l'Académie Américaine de la Médecine du Sommeil (AAMS). Le SMC a plusieurs limitations: une faible reproductibilité intra- et inter-opérateur, ainsi que beaucoup d'efforts, de temps et d'argent. De plus, le SMC ne produit pas une analyse complète des schémas respiratoires, mais plutôt une liste d'événements "cliniquement pertinents", accompagnés du moment de leur occurrence. Ainsi, un schéma considéré comme n'étant pas "cliniquement pertinent" d'après les directives de l'AAMS n'est pas évalué et ne peut être analysé.Cette thèse se penche sur ces limitations en créant une banque de données et en développant des outils pour l'analyse complète de schémas respiratoires chez le nourrisson. Ce travail se découpe en 5 phases. En premier lieu, nous avons acquis une banque de données représentatives comprenant des signaux cardio-respiratoires de nourrissons à risque d'APO, et avons rendu ces données disponibles au public. Deuxièmement, nous avons développé une série d'outils permettant d'évaluer manuellement les schémas respiratoires des nourrissons de façon efficace, reproductible et fiable. Nous avons démontré que l'utilisation de ces outils produisait une analyse précise et robuste, et améliorait la reproductibilité intra- et inter-opérateur. Troisièmement, nous avons développé une méthode basée sur l'algorithme Espérance-Maximisation (EM) pour combiner les analyses de plusieurs marqueurs manuels afin de minimiser les effets de la variabilité intra- et inter-opérateur, et produire des résultats "gold standard" plus exactes et robustes. Ces deux développements ont amélioré la précision et la reproductibilité de l'analyse manuelle, mais n'ont pas résolu le problème du temps, du coût et des efforts nécessaires. La quatrième étape de cette thèse s'est plus particulièrement penchée sur ces limitations en automatisant l'analyse. Pour cela, nous avons développé un Détecteur d'Évènements Respiratoires Automatisé Hors-ligne (AORED en anglais) qui analyse les schémas respiratoires en comparant des métriques du comportement respiratoire à des seuils afin de déterminer la présence ou non de schémas. Les valeurs optimales des seuils ont été sélectionnées avec l'aide de l'analyse ROC (de l'anglais Receiver Operating Characteristics), en utilisant l'analyse manuelle comme référence. L'analyse AORED a montré une très bonne corrélation avec l'analyse manuelle "gold standard". Cependant, les seuils étaient basés sur les résultats de l'analyse manuelle, donc ...</description><creator>Robles Rubio, Carlos</creator><contributor>Karen Brown (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Robert E Kearney (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biomedical Engineering</subject><title>Computer-aided analysis of infant respiratory patterns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g2831.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m78x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m2203</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La contamination des eaux souterraines par les bactéries présente un grand danger pour nos approvisionnements en eau potable. Dans les régions froides, les micro-organismes dans les couches supérieures du sol sont soumis à de basses températures et de multiples cycles de gel et de dégel au début de l'hiver, ainsi qu'au printemps lors de la fonte des neiges. L'influence des variations de température autour du point de congélation, connus sous le nom de gel-dégel (GD), sur les taux d'inactivation, la croissance et la formation de biofilm de Salmonelle typhimurium est étudié. Les effets de GD sur les caractéristiques de transport de S. typhimurium dans le sable de quartz ont été suivis dans des solutions d'eau de trois forces ioniques différentes modèles de l'eau interstitielle (IS; 1, 10, 100 mM de KCl) et deux concentrations d'acides humiques (HA) différentes (1 et 5 mg / L HA). Les forces de liaison relatives entre la surface des bactéries et du sable ont été caractérisées par l'étude du détachement bactérien suite à l'injection d'une solution à faible force ionique (1 mM KCl). Après avoir été exposé au GD, S. typhimurium a présenté moins d'attachement au sable de quartz et une diminution de la force de liaison. L'absence de nutriments aurait pu affecter les tendances d'attachements bactériens observés et d'autres expériences sont nécessaires. Singulièrement, une augmentation du nombre de cycles GD n'a montré aucun effet sur la survie de S. typhimurium dans les solutions modèle de l'eau interstitielle. Bien que les traitements GD n'aient pas affecté leur viabilité, la plupart des cellules deviennent viables mais non cultivables (VBNC) et la capacité des cellules à former des biofilms a diminué. Pour chaque condition expérimentale, les distances de recule entre l'emplacement de puits d'eau potable et les activités d'épandage de fumier ont été déterminées à partir des calculs d'efficacité d'attachement entre les cellules et surfaces de silica. Une comparaison entre les distances de recule calculée et la distance de recule établi par la réglementation québécoise révèle qu'il existe un risque de contamination des milieux d'eaux souterraines après 10 cycles GD, surtout dans les sols à faible teneur en matières organiques. Cette étude démontre les effets des variations de température typique des Printemps canadiens sur les propriétés de S. typhimurium présent dans les couches supérieures du sol et le risque accru de contamination bactérienne des eaux souterraines et en surfaces dans les régions froides. Elle donne des informations importantes qui aideront à définir des distances de recule appropriées pour les puits d'alimentation en eau dans les zones climatiques soumises aux cycles GD.</description><description>Groundwater contamination by bacteria is a great hazard to our drinking water supplies. In cold climate regions, microorganisms in the upper soil layers are subject to low temperatures and multiple cycles of freezing and thawing at the beginning of winter as well as at the beginning of spring during spring melt. The influence of temperature fluctuations around the freezing point, known as freeze-thaw (FT), on the inactivation rates, growth, and biofilm formation of Salmonella typhimurium were studied. FT effects on the transport characteristics of S. typhimurium in quartz sand were monitored in artificial porewater solutions of three different ionic strengths (IS; 1, 10, 100 mM KCl) and two different humic acid (HA) concentrations (1 and 5 mg/L HA). The relative bond strengths between the bacteria and sand surface were characterized by monitoring bacterial detachment following injection of a low IS solution (1 mM KCl). After exposure to FT, S. typhimurium exhibited less attachment to the quartz sand and a decrease in bond strength. Starvation may have affected the bacterial transport patterns observed and further experiments are required. Surprisingly, a higher number of FT cycles showed no significant effect on the survival of S. typhimurium in model porewater solutions. While FT treatments did not significantly affect viability, most cells became viable but non-culturable (VBNC) and the cells' ability to form biofilm decreased. For each experimental condition, the minimum setback distances between the location of drinking water wells and manure spreading activities were determined from the measured bacterial cell-silica attachment efficiency. A comparison between the calculated setback distances and the minimum setback distance set by Québec regulations reveal that there is a risk of contamination of groundwater environments after 10 FT cycles, especially at low organic matter contents. This investigation demonstrates the effects of spring temperature variation in upper soil layers on S. typhimurium properties and the increased risk of bacterial contamination in surface and groundwater environments for colder regions. It further provides important information that will help ensure proper setback distances for water-supply wells in areas subject to FT cycles.</description><creator>Rocard, Jennifer</creator><contributor>Subhasis Ghoshal (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Nathalie Tufenkji (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Natural freeze-thaw cycles may increase the risk associated with «salmonella» contamination in surface and groundwater environments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg32g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m2203</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107179f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurons of the brain communicate at specialized cellular junctions termed synapses, where release of neurotransmitter pre-synaptically and binding to neurotransmitter receptors post-synaptically is a highly regulated, yet plastic process.  Among the best studied forms of synaptic plasticity are Hebbian plasticity mechanisms which are induced by (de-)correlations in neuronal activity, and whose induction and expression is relatively rapid (seconds to minutes).  Other than Hebbian mechanisms, various other synaptic plasticity phenomena have been demonstrated, among which is homeostatic synaptic plasticity (HSP) which is thought to regulate synaptic strength by negative feedback (in opposite sign to Hebbian plasticity), and is expressed on a slower time-scale (hours).  Tumor Necrosis Factor alpha (TNF) was found to regulate trafficking of neurotransmitter receptors, principal among them is the GluA1 subunit of AMPAR; by regulating AMPAR trafficking, TNF has been shown critical for the expression of HSP, yet is dispensable for Hebbian plasticity.  In this thesis, the mechanism of AMPAR trafficking in HSP was examined by addressing the question of whether AMPAR trafficking is subunit-dependent.  To this end, neuronal cultures derived from mice deficient in GluA1, or GluA2, the two principal subunits of AMPAR, were exposed to tetrodotoxin for 2 days to silence neuronal activity and induce HSP, specifically "scaling up" of synaptic strength.  Surprisingly, in all conditions tested, neurons displayed scaling up of synaptic strength, which is counter to the prevailing model of AMPAR trafficking where the subunit composition of the AMPAR governs its synaptic trafficking in Hebbian, as well as non-Hebbian models of synaptic plasticity.  Additionally, this thesis explored an in vivo function for TNF in regulating synaptic transmission in response to acute stress, which previously has been shown to potentiate glutamatergic transmission in forebrain synapses.  Schaffer collateral glutamatergic transmission onto CA1 pyramidal cells of ventral hippocampus was potentiated by acute exposure to stress, developing on a time-scale of hours to reach significance by 24 hours.  Stress-induced potentiation was critically dependent on TNF; mice constitutively lacking TNF were deficient in this response, and injection of XPro1595 - an antagonist of TNF signalling - to wild-type animals also blocked the stress-induced potentiation.  Importantly, previous studies have suggested that acute stress-induced potentiation of glutamatergic transmission, governed by the stress hormone corticosterone, shares features of Hebbian plasticity expression mechanisms.  However, TNF-deficient mice were found to have a normal stress-induced release of circulating corticosterone, and furthermore, glutamatergic transmission in TNF-deficient brain slices was potentiated by direct application of corticosterone, demonstrating that the absence of the in vivo stress response in glutamatergic synapses of TNF-deficient animals was not due to a general loss of synaptic plasticity mechanisms.  The conclusions from these studies is that corticosterone alone does not fully explain the in vivo stress response, and that the response to acute stress of forebrain glutamatergic synapses requires TNF signalling.  The studies presented in this thesis challenge the prevailing model of AMPAR trafficking in the context of synaptic plasticity, and expand the physiological roles played by TNF, and by extension non-Hebbian plasticity mechanisms, in the brain.</description><description>Les neurones du cerveau communiquent aux jonctions appelées synapses, où la libération du neurotransmetteur présynaptique et la liaison aux récepteurs des neurotransmetteurs post-synaptique sont très réglementés, mais sont néanmoins des mécanismes plastiques.  Parmi les formes les mieux étudiées de la plasticité synaptique sont des mécanismes de plasticité Hebbienne qui est induite par l'activité neuronale corrélée, et dont l'induction et l'expression est relativement rapide (secondes à quelques minutes).  Autres que les mécanismes de Hebb, divers phénomènes de plasticité synaptique ont été démontrés, parmi lesquels la plasticité synaptique homéostatique qui est cru de réguler la force synaptique en signe opposé à la plasticité Hebienne, et est exprimée sur une échelle de temps plus lente (heures).  Tumor Necrosis Factor alpha (TNF) régule le trafic des récepteurs de neurotransmetteurs, le principal d'entre eux étant la sous-unité de GluA1 AMPAR; par le contrôle de trafic AMPAR, le TNF a été démontré comme étant critique pour l'expression de la plasticité synaptique homéostatique, mais le TNF est dispensable pour la plasticité Hebienne.  Cette thèse a examiné le mécanisme de régulation des AMPAR, en abordant la question de savoir si le trafic de AMPAR est dépend des sous-unités.  Des cultures neuronales dérivées de souris déficientes en GluA1 ou GluA2 ont été exposées à la tétrodotoxine pendant 2 jours pour faire taire l'activité neuronale et induire la plasticité synaptique homéostatique.  Dans toutes les conditions testées, les neurones ont exprimé la plasticité synaptique homéostatique, qui est contraire au modèle dominant de la traite AMPAR où la composition de sous-unités de la AMPAR régit son trafic synaptique dans la plasticité Hebienne, ainsi que des modèles non-Hebiennes de plasticité synaptique.  En outre, cette thèse a exploré une fonction in vivo pour le TNF dans la régulation de la transmission synaptique en réponse à un stresse aigu, qui a été montré précédemment de potentialiser la transmission glutamatergique dans les synapses du cerveau antérieur.  La potentialisation de la transmission glutamatergique de Schaffer sur les cellules pyramidales CA1 de l'hippocampe ventral développé sur une échelle de temps d'heures suivantes une exposition aiguë au stresse, atteignant la signification statistique par 24 heures.  La potentialisation induite par le stresss dépend essentiellement de TNF; les souris dépourvues de TNF sont déficientes dans cette réponse, et l'injection de XPro1595 - un antagoniste de la signalisation du TNF - au animaux sauvages aussi bloque la potentialisation induite par le stresse.  Surtout, des études antérieures ont suggéré que la potentialisation de la transmission glutamatergique induite par le stresse aϊgue est le résultat d'un mécanisme Hebbien, qui est régi par la corticostérone l'hormone du stresse.  Cependant, les souris dépourvues de TNF ont une libération normale induite par le stresse de la corticostérone en circulation,  et la transmission glutamatergique dans des tranches de cerveau TNF-déficient est potentialisée par l'application directe de la corticostérone, ce qui démontre que l'absence de la réponse au stresse in vivo des synapses glutamatergiques d'animaux déficients en TNF n'est pas due à une perte générale de mécanismes de plasticité synaptique.  Les conclusions de ces études sont que la corticostérone seule n'explique pas entièrement la réponse in vivo du stresse, comme ceci ce est largement répandue; en outre, la réponse au stresse aigu des synapses glutamatergiques du cerveau antérieur nécessite la signalisation du TNF.  Les études présentées dans cette thèse contestent le modèle dominant du trafic de AMPAR dans le contexte de la plasticité synaptique, et élargissent les rôles physiologiques joué par le TNF, et par des mécanismes de plasticité non-Hebbien, dans le cerveau.</description><creator>Altimimi, Haider</creator><contributor>David Stellwagen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Mechanisms and in vivo functions for Tumor Necrosis Factor alpha-dependent non-Hebbian synaptic plasticity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v123j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107179f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sg32n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La bilharziose ou schistosomiase, infection parasitique, demeure l'une des plus importantes maladies tropicales qui sont toujours négligées. Ces maladies débilitantes et chroniques ont des conséquences sérieuses pour le développement socio-économique des pays tropicaux.  Elles sont endémiques dans plus de 70 pays, mais il est toujours nécessaire de trouver de nouveaux instruments d'intervention pour réaliser un diagnostic précis des cas d'infection afin d'empêcher la morbidité et la mortalité.  Il est peut-être possible de réaliser de nouveaux tests diagnostiques en identifiant des biomarqueurs spécifiques qui deviennent positifs au début de l'infection. L'identification de protéines associées aux différentes maladies pourrait indiquer de nouvelles formes de diagnostiques, qui peuvent être utilisées pour le diagnostic des phases aiguës et chroniques de l'infection et pour la validation du traitement. Cette étude a deux objectifs: (a) identifier des modèles protéomiques dans les sérums pour les différentes phases de l'infection, en commençant par la phase préliminaire (3 semaines), puis en étudiant la phase aiguë (6 semaines) et ensuite la phase chronique (12 semaines) des infections à Schistosoma mansoni dans un modèle de souris; (b) établir le profil des sérums d'humains infectés par S.mansoni et S. haematobium et le comparer avec un profil de sérums sains.  En vue de cela, des analyses protéomiques ont été effectuées sur les sérums d'humains et de souris en utilisant de puissantes méthodes à haut débit. Ces recherches ont non seulement identifié des protéines de l'hôte/des quantités maximums de protéines qui sont régulés en hausse et en baisse dans les sérums infectés (d'humains et de souris), mais ont aussi caractérisé les protéines de schistosome dans les sérums de souris infectées.  La présence de protéines de l'hôte, telles que la transferrine et l'alpha 1-antitrypsine, ainsi qu'une des protéines de schistosome, la glutathion S-transférase (GST), a été confirmé par le Western Blot. Les résultats ont montré que les profils de protéines sont liés aux différentes maladies et aux phases de l'infection. Ils ont aussi identifié certains protéines de l'hôte qui peuvent servir individuellement comme de nouveaux tests diagnostiques pour la schistosomiase, comme l'apolipoproteine A-I (Apo A-1 : régulée en hausse auprès des patients chroniques qui sont infectés par S. haematobium) et l'anhydrase carbonique 1 (CA1 : régulée en baisse auprès des patients chroniques qui sont infectés par S. mansoni). Si des études plus vastes confirment ces résultats, ces nouveaux biomarqueurs, et aussi d'autre biomarqueurs qui n'ont pas encore été identifiés à partir de nos grandes banques de données MS, pourraient contribuer de manière importante à l'éradication de la schistosomiase. </description><description>Schistosome infections, caused by a family of helminth parasites, are major neglected tropical diseases (NTDs) that have serious implications for socio-economic development in many tropical countries. These debilitating and chronic diseases are endemic in more than 70 countries but diagnostic tools are limited and new tests are necessary to limit morbidity and mortality. The development of such tests may be facilitated by the identification of disease-specific biomarkers that are positive early in infection, that can distinguish between acute and chronic infection and that can serve as validation of cure. This thesis work has two major goals: (a) to identify stage-specific proteomic patterns during early (3 week), acute (6 week) and chronic (12 week) Schistosoma mansoni infection in a mouse model; (b) to profile the sera of humans infected by S. mansoni, or S. haematobium and compare these patterns with the protein profile of healthy human serum. To achieve these goals, proteomic analyses were performed on mouse and human sera using several different mass spectrometry (MS) methodologies. These investigations not only identified large numbers of host proteins/protein peaks that are up- or down-regulated in infected sera (mouse and human) but also found large numbers of schistosome-origin proteins in the serum of infected mice. The presence of host proteins, such as transferrin and alpha 1- antitrypsin, as well as one of the schistosome proteins, glutathione S-transferase (GST), were confirmed by Western blot. In addition to these disease- and stage-specific protein profiles, we also identified a number of host proteins that may individually have potential as novel diagnostic tests for schistosome infections in humans, including apolipoprotein A-I (Apo A-I: up-regulated in chronic S. haematobium infected patients) and carbonic anhydrase 1 (CA1: down-regulated in chronic S. mansoni infected patients). If confirmed in larger field studies, these novel biomarkers, and others yet to be identified from our large MS databases, have the potential to contribute significantly to schistosomiasis detection and subsequent eradication efforts.   </description><creator>Kardoush, Manal</creator><contributor>Momar Ndao (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Brian Ward (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Parasitology</subject><title>Identification of candidate serum biomarkers for schistosomiasis infection using mass spectrometric approaches</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk95d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sg32n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870z80n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'artériosclérose est une maladie inflammatoire responsable de la majorité des décès liés aux maladies cardiovasculaires. L'adhésion leucocytaire à la surface d'un endothélium enflammé est connue pour être une étape importante dans la phase initiale de la maladie. Cependant, bien que de nombreuses molécules et transductions de signal aient été identifiées dans la cascade de l'adhésion leucocytaire, le mécanisme moléculaire reste incompris. Le glycocalyx est une couche riche en hydrate de carbone recouvrant la surface luminale des cellules endothéliales. Il a pour capacité de contrôler la perméabilité des cellules, leur alignement, leur migration et la mécanotransduction. De par sa structure singulière et son emplacement, le glycocalyx pourrait jouer un rôle dans le mécanisme d'adhésion leucocytaire, cependant peu de recherches ont jusqu'alors étudié ce phénomène. De surcroit, ces études ne prennent pas en compte le lien entre le mécanisme moléculaire et le phénomène d'adhésion. Par conséquent, dans le cadre de nos recherches, nous avons analysé le rôle du glycocalyx dans l'adhésion leucocytaire des cellules endothéliales de l'aorte abdominale humaine. Les recherches ont été réalisées avec des modèles en 3-D de culture cellulaire dans lesquelles des cellules endothéliales ont été soumises à une contrainte de cisaillement laminaire constante  (10 dynes/cm2). Les résultats démontrent qu'une dégradation enzymatique du glycocalyx résulte en un phénotype pro-inflammatoire des cellules endothéliales. En effet, soumises à des conditions hémodynamiques, l'expression de la protéine ICAM-1 augmente, celle de eNOS disparaît, l'activité de NF-κB est perturbée et l'adhésion des leucocytes se voit augmenter. Nous avons alors cherché à étudier la façon dont la structure du glycocalyx pourrait être endommagée en considérant des éléments relatifs à la genèse et à l'évolution de l'artériosclérose, notamment la stimulation des cytokines et  la perturbation des conditions hémodynamiques. Il a été constaté que, dans un modèle courbe idéalisé, l'expression du glycocalyx (sulfate d'héparane et Syndecan-1) diminue lors de stimulations provoquées par TNF-α et dans les régions soumises à des conditions hémodynamiques anormales. Les métalloprotéases matricielles ont également montré qu'elles jouaient un rôle dans la perturbation du glycocalyx à travers les augmentations de l'expression et de l'activité de la protéine MMP-2 dans des conditions similaires. De plus, nos résultats prouvent que la dégradation du glycocalyx peut influencer, à lui seul, l'activité du MMP-2. Ainsi, à travers ces analyses, nous avons démontré que le glycocalyx est un élément important dans l'homéostasie des cellules endothéliales et que sa perturbation provoquée par différents stimuli pathologiques pourrait perturber le fonctionnement des cellules endothéliales et donc l'adhésion leucocytaire. </description><description>Atherosclerosis is an inflammatory disease underlying the majority of cardiovascular related deaths. Leukocyte adhesion to the surface of an inflamed endothelium is well documented as an important early event in disease initiation. While many different molecules and signalling pathways have been identified in the adhesion cascade, the precise molecular mechanisms remain poorly understood. The glycocalyx is a carbohydrate-rich layer covering the luminal surface of endothelial cells. It has proposed roles in several endothelial cell functions such as permeability, cell alignment and migration and mechanotransduction. Due to its unique structure and location, it has also been suggested to play a role in leukocyte adhesion and the inflammatory response associated with atherosclerosis. Existing studies have failed to elucidate the molecular mechanisms underlying a role for the glycocalyx in adhesion or its integrity with inflammation. Therefore, the work presented in the current dissertation examines the role of the glycocalyx in leukocyte adhesion, its role as a mechanotransducer and adaptation to inflammation on cultured human abdominal aortic endothelial cells. Studies were performed using three dimensional cell culture models in which endothelial cells were exposed to fluid shear stress. Our results show that enzymatic degradation of the glycocalyx results in a pro-inflammatory endothelial cell phenotype under flow conditions marked by an increase in ICAM-1 protein expression, impaired NF-κB activity, suppressed eNOS expression and an increase in leukocyte adhesion. We then sought to determine how the structure of the glycocalyx might be damaged in response to inflammatory cytokine stimulation and disturbed flow, two underlying factors in the initiation and progression of atherosclerosis. We found a reduction in the expression of the glycocalyx (i.e. heparan sulphate and Syndecan-1) upon exposure to TNF-α stimulation. We identified a role for matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) in the disruption of the glycocalyx by showing there is a concomitant increase in MMP-2 protein expression and activity under similar conditions. Moreover, our results show that glycocalyx degradation alone can mediate MMP-2 activity. Finally we present preliminary results on the changes in the glycocalyx in response to disturbed flow in a 180° bend. We show that the expression of heparan sulfate and Syndecan-1  respond to wall shear stress gradients and this may occur through increased MMP activity. Taken together, the findings presented in this thesis provide evidence that the glycocalyx plays a large role in mediating endothelial cell phenotype and that disruption of the glycocalyx in response to different pathologically relevant factors may be an up-stream event in endothelial cell dysfunction and consequential leukocyte adhesion.</description><creator>McDonald, Karli</creator><contributor>Richard L Leask (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biomedical Engineering</subject><title>The role of the endothelial glycocalyx in leukocyte adhesion and its disruption under pathologically relevant conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j384d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870z80n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xc24z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les mitochondries ont de nombreuses fonctions cellulaires importantes, dont l'une est la production d'ATP. Au cours de ce processus, les électrons sont transmis à l'accepteur d'électrons terminal, l'oxygène moléculaire. De temps en temps, un électron réagit avec l'oxygène prématurément, générant des dérivés réactifs de l'oxygène (DRO). Les DRO sont très réactifs et ont le potentiel d'endommager les macromolécules biologiques. Cependant, les DRO ont également d'importantes propriétés de signalisation, y compris des rôles dans la réponse au stress, le vieillissement, la tumorigenèse, la progression cancéreuse, la mort cellulaire programmée, et d'autres. Dans cette thèse, j'étudie sur le rôle des DRO dans deux domaines: la régulation d'un rythme physiologique, et la spécification du destin cellulaire lors d'un événement du développement.Les altérations du métabolisme des DRO ainsi qu'un phénotype pléiotropique sont des caractéristiques communes des mutants mitochondriaux longéviques. Dans le chapitre 2, je cherche à établir dans quelle mesure les DRO sont responsable de plusieurs des phénotypes associés à la longue durée de vie des mutants clk-1. Chez ces mutants, mes recherches se concentrent sur la détermination de la façon dont le rythme de la défécation est dérégulé. Je démontre que ce phénotype est étroitement lié à la synthèse de molécules acides biliaires et de lipoprotéines, et que les altérations du métabolisme des DRO affectent la synthèse des acides biliaires. J'étudie aussi de nouveaux suppresseurs génétiques de la défécation lente des mutants clk-1. Certain de ces suppresseurs sont impliqués dans le métabolisme des DRO et peuvent supprimer d'autres phénotypes des mutants clk-1, y compris l'insensibilité à la température, la sensibilité altérée par rapport au cholestérol, le faible taux de reproduction, la lenteur de mouvements de nage,  et la longue durée de vie. L'élévation du niveau des DRO est souvent associée à des états pathologiques, y compris le cancer, le diabète, l'inflammation, et d'autres; Toutefois, leurs mécanismes d'action restent souvent peu caractérisés. Comprendre précisément comment les DRO affectent les voies de signalisation serait bénéfique dans de nombreux domaines d'importance clinique. Dans le chapitre 3, nous utilisons le développement de la vulve chez C. elegans comme un système model pour étudier comment les changements dans le métabolisme des DRO affectent la signalisation par la voie canonique de signalisation RTK-Ras-MAPK. Nous développons un modèle d'interactions qui indique que les DRO ont des effets sur le développement de la vulve qui sont différents selon le type cellulaire et le compartiment cellulaire.  Nous constatons également que plusieurs gènes qui sont impliqués dans le développement des cancers humains sont aussi modulés par les DRO. Dans l'ensemble, mes résultats montrent que l'étude du développement de la vulve de C. elegans peut servir de système model pour l'analyse de la signalisation par les DRO in vivo, avec des applications dans la biologie du cancer.</description><description>Mitochondria have many important cellular functions, one of which being the generation of ATP. During this process, electrons are passed to the terminal electron acceptor, molecular oxygen. Occasionally, an electron reacts with oxygen prematurely to generate reactive oxygen species (ROS). ROS are highly reactive and have the potential to damage all biological macromolecules; however, they also have important signaling properties and are involved in stress responses, aging, tumorigenesis and cancer progression, programmed cell death, and other processes. In this thesis, I investigate the role of ROS in setting the rate of a physiological rhythm, and in affecting cell fate specification during a developmental event. Altered ROS metabolism and a pleiotropic phenotype are common features of long-lived mitochondrial mutants in Caenorhabditis elegans. In Chapter 2, I investigate the extent to which ROS are responsible for inducing several of the phenotypes exhibited by the long-lived clk-1 mutant. Most of the chapter focuses on elucidating how the slow defecation phenotype of clk-1 is regulated. I demonstrate that this phenotype is closely tied to the synthesis of bile acid-like and lipoprotein-like molecules, and that alterations to ROS metabolism affect bile acid synthesis. I also investigate whether novel suppressors of the slow clk-1 defecation rate, including those involved in ROS metabolism, can suppress other clk-1 phenotypes, including temperature insensitivity, cholesterol sensitivity, low brood size, slow thrashing rate, and long lifespan. An elevated ROS level is commonly associated with disease states, including cancer and diabetes; however, their mechanisms of action often remain uncharacterized. Understanding precisely how ROS function to affect signaling pathways would therefore be beneficial in many areas of clinical importance. In Chapter 3, I use vulval development in C. elegans as a model system to investigate how changes in ROS metabolism affect signaling through the canonical RTK-Ras-MAPK signaling pathway. I develop a model of interactions that indicates that ROS have cell type- and cellular compartment-specific effects on vulval development. I also find that several alterations to ROS metabolism that exacerbate human cancers involving activated Kras have conserved effects on vulval development in worms. Overall, my results support using C. elegans vulval development as a model system for dissecting in vivo ROS signaling.</description><creator>Desjardins, David</creator><contributor>Siegfried Hekimi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>Reactive oxygen species as regulators of physiology and development in the nematode «Caenorhabditis elegans»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z709050d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xc24z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289m70q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse explore l'état de la démocratie environnementale au Québec et en Colombie- Britannique en analysant la façon dont s'articulent les droits procéduraux environnementaux dans les deux provinces. Ces droits, qui ont été structurés en trois piliers par le principe 10 de la Déclaration de Rio, sont reconnus comme étant l'accès à l'information environnementale, la participation du public au processus décisionnel et l'accès à la justice environnementale. La procédure d'évaluation environnementale est un des cadres où ils s'exercent tout particulièrement. Afin de mettre en lumière la force de la démocratie environnementale dans les deux juridictions provinciales, un examen de leur procédure d'évaluation environnementale respective sera effectué suivi d'une analyse comparative pour chacun des piliers. Ce faisant, cette thèse tirera pour chacun des droits analysés des conclusions et proposera différentes solutions afin de renforcer l'exercice des droits procéduraux environnementaux comme la constitutionnalisation du droit à l'information environnementale dans certains contextes, l'identification de certains problèmes de légitimité des institutions effectuant l'évaluation environnementale ainsi que la création de cours de justice spécialisées en environnement. </description><description>This thesis explores the state of environmental democracy in Quebec and British Columbia by analyzing the articulation of the environmental procedural rights in the two provinces. Those rights, which were constituted in three pillars in principle 10 of the Rio Declaration, are known as the right to environmental information, the right to public participation in decision making and the right to environmental justice. They are often used in the context of an environmental assessment. In order to shed light on the state of environmental democracy in the two provinces, an examination of the structure of their respective environmental assessment process will be done followed by a comparative analysis for each of the pillars. In doing so, this thesis will draw conclusions regarding each right and will propose different solutions to reinforce environmental democracy, including constitutionalizing the right to environmental information in some circumstances, identifying some legitimacy issues with the institutions carrying the environmental assessment, and creating specialized environmental courts. </description><creator>Bertrand-Le Borgne, Frédérique</creator><contributor>Sébastien Jodoin Pilon (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Notre mot à dire: état des lieux sur la démocratie environnementale au Québec et en Colombie-Britannique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848t26z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m70q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b623s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As a result of expanding use, nanomaterials such as nanosilver (AgNP), are being continuously released into the environment through production, usage, and disposal. Research is needed to develop cost‐effective and sensitive methods to quantify AgNP in various environmental compartments in order to fully evaluate the exposure and risks associated with the presence of these nanomaterials in the environment. This work is hampered by the lack of sensitive methods to detect AgNPs and other nanomaterials in environmental matrices. The present study focused on the development, calibration and application of a passive sampling technique for detecting AgNP and estimating low concentrations of these nanomaterials in aquatic matrices. This thesis work included the design, calibration and application of the designed sampler to the detection of silver in nano-form in surface waters and wastewater. The Carbon Nanotube Integrative Sampler (CNIS) developed in this study was deployed in an experimental lake dosed with AgNP in order to demonstrate the applicability of these samplers for monitoring in natural surface waters. The time weighted average (TWA) concentrations of "CNIS-labile" Ag estimated from deployments of the sampler in the dosed lake varied between 1-10 ppb, which were similar to the concentrations of total Ag determined from grab samples collected in the lake.  The samplers were then applied to monitoring AgNP in a wastewater treatment plant (WWTP), as well as the quantification of AgNPs in surface waters. Results of monitoring in the WWTP for the city of Peterborough, ON showed an estimated TWA concentration of CNIS-labile Ag of 0.2 ppb in the treated effluent, but there was no evidence of an increase in CNIS-labile Ag in receiving waters of the Otonabee River, ON, downstream of the wastewater discharge. Deployments of CNIS in two nearshore areas of Lake Ontario situated near discharges of municipal wastewater also showed estimated TWA concentrations of CNIS-labile Ag that were lower than 1 ppb. These monitoring results are consistent with recent literature showing that much of the Ag in municipal wastewater will settle out of the suspension as Ag2S before final discharge into receiving waters. This thesis provided an assessment of the presence of AgNP in environmental waters and demonstrated the potential of the CNIS samplers as a tool to monitor concentrations of nanomaterials in surface waters and wastewater.</description><description>En raison de leur utilisation croissante, les nanomatériaux tels que les nanoparticules d'argent (AgNP), sont relâchées en continu dans l'environnement suite à la production, l'utilisation et la disposition de divers produits. Des recherches sont donc nécessaires pour le développement de méthodes économiques et suffisamment sensible pour la quantification de AgNP dans diverses matrices environnementales et ce, afin d'évaluer l'exposition réelle et les risques associés avec la présence de AgNP sur l'environnement et la santé publique. La présente étude a porté sur le développement, l'étalonnage et l'application d'un échantillonneur passif à la détection de AgNP et la mesure de faibles concentrations dans des matrices complexes. Les travaux de la présente thèse ont permis de concevoir un échantillonneur passif basé sur les nanotubes de carbon (nommé ici CNIS) et de l'étalonner pour le suivi de l'argent sous forme de nanoparticules. Le CNIS a ensuite été appliqué à la détection de AgNP dans les eaux de surface et les eaux usées. L'échantillonneur développé dans cette étude a été déployé dans un lac expérimental dosé avec des AgNP afin de démontrer l'applicabilité du CNIS pour la suivi d'eau de surface. Les concentrations moyennes pondérées d'argent déterminées à partir des déploiements de CNIS dans le lac dosé variaient entre 1-10 ppb, des valeurs comparables aux concentrations d'argent total déterminées à partir d'échantillons ponctuels. Les échantillonneurs ont ensuite été appliqué à la quantification de AgNP dans une usine de traitement des eaux usées (STEP), ainsi que la quantification de AgNP dans les eaux de surface naturelles. Les résultats de suivi à la station d'épuration de la ville de Peterborough, ON ont démontré une concentration estimée d'argent de 0.2 ppb dans l'effluent traité, mais n'indiquaient aucune augmentation dans les eaux réceptrices de la Otonabee River, ON, en aval de la décharge des eaux usées. Les déploiements de CNIS dans deux zones littorales du lac Ontario situées à proximité rejets d'eaux usées municipales a également montré des concentrations estimées d'argent inférieures à 1 ppb. Ces résultats de suivi sont conformes à la littérature récente qui montre que la majeure partie de l'argent contenue dans les eaux usées municipales est précipitée sous forme de Ag2S avant décharge dans les eaux réceptrices. Cette thèse a fourni une évaluation de la présence de AgNP dans les eaux environnementales et démontré le potentiel des échantillonneurs CNIS comme un outil de suivi des concentrations de nanomatériaux dans les eaux de surface et eaux usées.</description><creator>Shen, Li</creator><contributor>Viviane Yargeau (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Chris Metcalfe (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>A novel passive sampler for monitoring nanosilver in aquatic matrices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386n242.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b623s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nk85d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La formation et l'accumulation de glace sur des surfaces extérieures créent des conditions dangereuses propices à la défaillance des systèmes et infrastructures, en plus de potentiellement causer des blessures, voire la mort. Une façon de mitiger ce problème de givrage est de fabriquer des matériaux réduisant la force d'adhésion de la glace sur leur surface. Dans cette thèse, la viabilité de la texturation de surface par laser femtoseconde (fs) comme une technique de modification de surface pour créer des surfaces glaciophobes est examinée. Puisque la texturation de surface par laser-fs est une technique relativement récente, aucun moyen systématique de caractériser les topographies hiérarchique de surface conférées par l'irradiation laser-fs n'existe dans la littérature. De plus, les mécanismes de formation des topographies créées par des lasers est encore mal comprise. La première partie de cette thèse répond à ces manques dans la littérature en i) introduisant l'analyse de lacunarité pour caractériser quantitativement les structures hiérarchique de surface, et ii) fournissant un aperçu des mécanismes de formation des structures induites par laser au moyen d'analyses détaillées au niveau chimique, cristallographique et topographique. Avec les connaissances acquises à partir de la première partie de la thèse, la deuxième partie de la thèse aborde le problème de l'adhésion de glace grâce à l'utilisation de piliers carrés superhydrophobes texturé par laser-fs, ainsi que deux autres matériaux : un maillage en acier inoxydable 316 et un maillage recouvert de nanotubes de carbone multi-parois (MWCNT). Les résultats indiquent que le mouillage de surface est un mauvais indicateur de l'adhérence de la glace. Au lieu de cela, la topographie de surface du substrat détermine la force d'adhérence de la glace par un équilibre entre deux facteurs concurrents : le verrouillage mécanique et la formation de concentrations de contraintes à l'interface glace-substrat. Cette étude souligne l'importance de considérer la mécanique de la rupture interfaciale dans la détermination de la force d'adhérence de la glace et promeut de nouvelles stratégies pour la conception de matériaux délestant la glace en utilisant leur topographie de surface.</description><description>Ice formation and accumulation on external surfaces create dangerous conditions conducive for the failure of systems and infrastructure, as well as the potential for causing bodily harm, and in severe cases, death. One approach towards mitigating the icing problem is to fabricate ice-releasing materials that reduce the adhesion strength of ice to their surface. In this thesis, the viability of femtosecond (fs) laser surface texturing as a surface modification technique for creating ice-phobic surfaces is examined. Since fs-laser surface patterning is a relatively new technique, a systematic means of characterizing the hierarchical surface topographies imparted by fs-laser irradiation is lacking in literature. In addition, the formation processes of laser-induced topographies are still poorly understood. The first part of this thesis responds to these gaps in literature by i) introducing lacunarity analysis to quantitatively characterize hierarchical surface structures, and ii) providing insight into the formation mechanisms of laser-induced structures through detailed chemical, crystallographic, and topographical analyses. With the knowledge gained from the first part of the thesis, the second part of the thesis tackles the ice adhesion problem through the use of superhydrophobic laser-inscribed square pillars, as well as two other materials: stainless steel 316 meshes and multi-walled carbon nanotube (MWCNT)-covered meshes. The findings indicate that surface wettability is a poor predictor of ice adhesion. Instead, the surface topography of the substrate determines the ice adhesion strength by balancing two competing factors: mechanical interlocking and the formation of stress concentrations at the ice-substrate interface. This study highlights the importance of considering interfacial fracture mechanics in determining ice adhesion strength and promotes new strategies towards designing ice- shedding materials by utilizing their surface topography.</description><creator>Ling, Edwin Jee Yang</creator><contributor>Anne-Marie Kietzig (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Phillip Servio (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Ice adhesion on femtosecond laser textured surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wq57m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk85d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838338w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans le monde industrialisé, les accouchements prématurés représentent la première cause de mortalité infantile. Bien que plusieurs tocolitiques (ex. les médicaments qui bloquent les contractions) aient été développés au cours des dernières années, leur efficacité est limitée et leur toxicité souvent non-négligeable, expliquant le besoin de développer de nouveaux médicaments, moins dangereux et plus efficaces. De manière à pouvoir développer ce type de médicaments, une connaissance plus approfondie des mécanismes de signalisation responsable du déclenchement des contractions utérines est nécessaire. Le récepteur à prostaglandine F2α (PGF2α) ou FP  joue un rôle clé en tant que médiateur de la contraction cellulaire menant à la parturition. Nous avons démontré que la contraction des cellules myométriales pouvait être inhibée chez les souris et chez les moutons par le composé peptido-mimétique, PDC113.824, dont la structure est dérivée de la partie N-terminale de la seconde boucle extracellulaire du récepteur FP. Singulièrement, ce composé semble agir en inhibant les voies de signalisation via Gα12/13 médiées par PGF2α, en affectant la cascade Rho/ROCK, tout en potentiant les voies de signalisation Gαq, en augmentant le niveau d'activation des protéines PKC et ERK1/2, démontrant par le fait même, la capacité de PDC de biaiser de manière allostérique les voies de signalisations de FP.Dans le présent ouvrage, j'ai pour but de tester de nouvelles molécules dérivées de PDC, de manière à mieux pouvoir comprendre comment ce composé module les réponses de FP dans les cellules du myomètre humain.  Basé sur la structure moléculaire de PDC, plusieurs pharmacophores ont été synthétisés de manière à pouvoir performer une étude de relation structure-fonction. Cela m'a permis de mieux exploiter les groupements chimiques importants pour produire les effets désirés de PDC. Dans la série de composés CAR, le groupement indolizidinone de PDC, que nous supposons être la partie active de la molécule, a été remplacé par différents groupes de tailles et de de longueurs variables. Dans la série MER, la géométrie du composé est étudiée. Nous émettons comme hypothèse que ces différentes modifications vont mener à des modes de régulation des voies de signalisation via FP de manière différentes de PDC. Des techniques tels que l'immunobuvardade de type western, l'énergie de résonnance par transfert de luminescence ou bioluminescence ont été employées de manière à répondre à cette question. Nous proposons aussi d'utiliser des mutants de la seconde boucle extracellulaire du récepteur FP dans le but d'étudier le mécanisme d'action des modulateurs. De plus, plusieurs de ces dérivatifs ont été créés de manière à être utilisés pour démontrer la spécificité de PDC à FP ; ces composés nous permettront de performer des études de marquage et de liaison. Dans cet ouvrage, je montre qu'en présence des différents composés, FP active les voies de signalisation des protéines ERK1/2 différemment, démontrant l'importance du groupe indolizidinone ainsi que de la géométrie de la structure pour la conservation des effets modulatoires de PDC sur le couplage de FP a Gαq. Ultimement, cette étude permettra non seulement de mieux comprendre les mécanismes cellulaires impliqués dans l'initiation de la parturition, mais aussi de permettre le développement de nouveaux et meilleurs composés thérapeutiques qui pourront être utilisés pour traiter les femmes sur le point d'accoucher prématurément, et cela sans causer autant d'effets secondaires que les médicaments actuellement disponibles.</description><description>In the industrial world, preterm labor is the main cause of infant mortality. While many tocolytics have been developed and used over the years, the need of better, more potent drugs, which would induce less side-effects, is needed. In order to identify those, a clearer understanding of how uterine cells signal to induce contraction is also required. The prostaglandin F2α (PGF2α) receptor (FP receptor) is known to be implicated in parturition, as it is an important component of cell contraction. Previous studies have shown that myometrial cell contractions could be stopped in mice and sheep by using a peptidomimetic compound, PDC113.824, whose structure is derived from the NH2-terminal part of the second extracellular loop of the FP receptor. Interestingly, this compound is shown to inhibit the PGF2α-mediated Rho/Rock signaling cascade downstream of Gα12, while enhancing ERK1/2 and PKC signaling cascades via Gαq, thus demonstrating its propensity to bias FP receptor response in an allosteric fashion. In the present work, I aimed at studying new molecules derived from PDC113.824 to understand how this compound modulates FP responses in the myometrial cells. Pharmacophores based on PDC113.824 structure were generated in order to perform a structure-function study, therefore allowing us to exploit the part(s) of the molecule responsible for cell contraction inhibition mediated by FP. In the CAR series, the indolizidinone group of PDC was replaced by various chains of different length and bulkiness, in order to test the importance of this particular region on the compound's action. In the MER series the structure of the β-turn in PDC was analyzed. We hypothesized that different modifications in PDC structure will lead to differential effects on FP-mediated signaling and we used different cell approaches (e.g. western blotting, luminescence and bioluminescence- resonance energy transfer (BRET)) to verify our hypothesis in HEK293 and myometrial cell lines. We also ought to utilize ECL2 mutants of the FP receptor to better understand the mechanism of action of these modulators. Moreover, I want to demonstrate the specificity of the binding of PDC113.824 to the FP receptor, by designing derivatives which can be used for binding studies or that can be used for direct mapping analysis of the binding site. Here, I show that these pharmacophores activate differentially FP-mediated ERK1/2 phosphorylation levels and that both the indolizidinone group and β-turn geometry are important for modulation of receptor-dependent signaling via Gαq. I also demonstrate the challenge of developing binding tools and propose a new innovative technique to map PDC binding site(s).Ultimately, my study aims to better understand the cell mechanisms involved in parturition as well as to develop new, better therapeutics that could be used to treat women undergoing preterm labor, without inducing as many side effects as the current medications on the market. </description><creator>Nikolajev, Ljiljana</creator><contributor>Stephane Laporte (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</subject><title>Characterization of new allosteric modulators of the PGF2a (FP) receptor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb40z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838338w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848t277</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chronic pain is a complex and multifaceted disorder associated with considerable disabilities, burden to patients, their families, the health care system and society. Current treatment options are few and inadequate for complete relief. Emerging evidence suggests that the interaction between the immune system and the nervous system plays critical roles in the development and maintenance of pathological pain. Macrophages in peripheral nerves and in the central nervous system also termed as microglia are the key players in the neuroimmune crosstalk. In this thesis, we aim to characterize functional phenotype of macrophages in the nerves and microglia in the brain/spinal cords of rodents associated with different chronic pain conditions. We demonstrated that in aged mice where pain sensation was altered, their spinal microglia were activated by displaying a pro-inflammatory phenotype. Such phenotype was further exacerbated with obesity, where a concomitant enhanced mechanical hyposensitivity and thermal hypersensitivity were observed. While trigeminal nerve injury triggered long lasting neuropathic oro-facial pain, microglia in the brainstem where injured nerve fibers terminate became highly activated, with increased cell density, expression of inflammatory mediators, and morphological alterations. Local LPS induced infection and CFA induced inflammation were also associated with hypersensitivity; however, microglia response was moderate which was not restricted to neuronal pathway, instead mainly in the circumventicular organs where blood brain barrier were absent. We further revealed heterogenous characteristics of macrophages in injured nerves and their potential contribution to neuropathic pain. We found that cytokine-expressing small and round-shaped macrophages were usually distributed close to the injury sites, whereas phagocytic macrophages were spread widely along damaged nerve fibers. CD86+, M1-like macrophages were predominant over CD206+, M2-like macrophages at either acute or chronic phase of neuropathic pain following nerve injury. The majority of these CD86+ macrophages were derived from blood circulation. We also showed that blocking CSF1R signaling can reduce the number of macrophages, mainly CD86+ cells, in injured nerves, with the decreased levels of local inflammatory cytokines. As consequences, CSF1R inhibitor was able to alleviate neuropathic pain in both prevention and reversal paradigms. To conclude, detailed analysis of macrophage/microglia phenotype in association with various abnormal pain conditions provides a novel perspective in understanding potential contribution of macrophages/microglia in the establishment and maintenance of chronic pain. </description><description>La douleur chronique est une maladie complexe et multidimensionnelle, associée à des handicaps considérables autant pour les patients que pour leurs familles, pour le système de santé et pour la société en général. Les traitements actuels sont peu diversifiés et ne garantissent pas un soulagement total. De nouveaux résultats démontrent que l'interaction entre le système immunitaire et le système nerveux pourrait jouer un rôle essentiel dans le développement et le maintien de la douleur pathologique. D'ailleurs, les macrophages dans les nerfs périphériques et dans le système nerveux central, aussi appelée microglie, sont des joueurs clés dans la diaphonie neuro-immunitaire. Le but de notre recherche est de déterminer les phénotypes fonctionnels des macrophages dans les nerfs, ainsi que les microglies dans le cerveau/moelle épinière chez les rongeurs associés avec différentes conditions de douleur chronique. Nos travaux démontrent que les microglies s'activent en exprimant un phénotype pro-inflammatoire, chez les souris vieillissantes ayant une sensation de douleur anormale. L'obésité a aggravé ce phénotype. En meme temps,  ces souris âgés et obese souffrent une hypo-sensibilité mécanique et une hypersensibilité thermale accrue. Une blessure au nerf trijumeau a provoqué de la douleur neuropathique oro-faciale de longue durée, tandis qu'aux terminaisons des nerfs blessés dans le tronc cérébral, les microglies sont devenues fortement activées, exhibant des médiateurs inflammatoires, des altérations morphologiques et une densité cellulaire augmentée. L'infection locale incitée par des LPS et l'inflammation amenée par CFA ont aussi été observées en relation avec l'hypersensibilité. Par contre, la réaction des microglies a été modérée et ne s'est pas limitée à la voie neuronale, diffusant plutôt dans les organes circumventriculaires où la barrière hémato-encéphalique est absente. Nous avons également révélé différentes caractéristiques des macrophages dans les nerfs blessés, ainsi que leur contribution potentielle à la douleur neuropathique. Selon nos résultats, les petits macrophages ronds produisant des cytokines sont distribués près des sites de lésion, alors que les macrophages phagocytiques se répandent tout au long des nerfs endommagés. La majorité des macrophages CD86+ étaient dérivés du système circulatoire. Nous avons aussi démontré que l'inhibition des CSF1R peut réduire le nombre de macrophages, surtout les cellules CD86+, dans les nerfs blessés, diminuant ainsi le niveau de cytokines inflammatoires locaux. Bref, l'inhibiteur du CSF1R est capable d'alléger la douleur neuropathique dans les modèles préventifs et les modèles de traitement. Pour conclure, une analyse approfondie du phénotype des microglies/macrophages dans différentes conditions de douleur anormale offre une nouvelle perspective dans la façon de comprendre le rôle potentiel des macrophages/microglies dans le développement et le maintien de la douleur chronique. </description><creator>Lee, SeungHwan</creator><contributor>Ji Zhang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Dentistry</subject><title>Microglia and macrophages in different types of chronic pain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m863.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t277</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh51v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Patient specific surgical simulators can be effective training tools in cardiac surgery. There is currently no patient specific aortic training models that can fully capture the mechanical and tactile properties of the human aorta. Most current training models are cadavers or animal models. Cadavers and animal organs are expensive, only available in limited supply, and lack patient specific pathologies. Current synthetic models are tubular, idealized geometries and are made of unrealistic materials. To develop new surgical training models, CT datasets from five patients were acquired under informed consent. Section of the aorta from the aortic root to the descending aorta, including the three major branches, were segmented. The generated aortic models were used to create five 3D printed models using a rigid material in order to determine the accuracy and reproducibility of the printout. The 3D printed models were determined to be highly accurate and represent faithfully the patient specific geometry. There is currently no 3D printing material that matches the mechanical properties of the human aorta. By taking advantage of the multi-material capability of the Object1 Connex500 3D printer, we were able to create a 3D printable multi-material composite with variable mechanical properties that mimics the properties of the human aorta. Tensile tests were performed on the printed composite samples and showed that the composites were representative of the mechanical properties of the human aortic tissue. This work provides the method and materials needed to create realistic 3D printed patient specific model for surgical training.</description><description>Le simulateur chirurgical spécifique au patient peut être un outil d'entraînement efficace en chirurgie cardiaque. Il n'existe actuellement aucun modèle aortique d'entrainement spécifique au patient capable de reproduire entièrement les propriétés mécaniques et tactiles de l'aorte humaine. La plupart des modèles d'entrainement actuels sont faits soit à partir de cadavres, soit à partir d'animaux. Ces deux options sont coûteuses, disponibles en quantité limitée et ne reflètent pas les pathologies spécifiques au patient. Les modèles synthétiques actuels sont de géométries idéalisées et tubulaires et faits de matériaux irréalistes. Pour développer de nouveaux modèles d'entrainement en chirurgie, des donnés TDM provenant de cinq patients ont été acquises avec leur consentement éclairé. La section d'aorte comprenant la racine aortique jusqu'à l'aorte descendante, incluant les trois branches majeures, a été segmentée. Les modèles aortiques générés ont été utilisés afin de créer cinq modèles imprimés en 3D à l'aide d'un matériau rigide afin de déterminer l'exactitude ainsi que la reproductibilité de l'impression. Les modèles  imprimés en 3D ont étaient jugés très précise et représentatifs de la géométrie chez le patient.Il n'existe couramment aucun matériau d'impression 3D possédant les  propriétés mécaniques de l'aorte humaine. Les capacités multi-matériaux de l'imprimante 3D Object1 Connex500 nous permettent toutefois de créer un composite multi-matériau imprimable en 3D aux propriétés mécaniques variables capables d'imiter  les propriétés de l'aorte humaine. Les tests de traction effectués sur les échantillons de composite imprimé ont montré que ces derniers reflétaient bien les propriétés mécaniques du tissu aortique humain. Ce document présente la méthode ainsi que les matériaux nécessaires pour créer des modèles réaliste imprimés en 3D spécifique au patient pour formations chirurgicale.</description><creator>Yang, ZhiLin</creator><contributor>Kevin J Lachapelle (Internal/Cosupervisor3)</contributor><contributor>Rosaire Mongrain (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Richard L Leask (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Development of 3D printed patient specific ascending aortic training models for cardiac surgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c1114.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh51v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz8062766</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:56:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The efficiency of electric powertrains is of great importance for the electrification of transport. Different powertrain topologies have various advantages and disadvantages. In this thesis, the efficiencies of two different powertrains are compared. Both designs use a 2 level inverter and a surface mounted Permanent Magnet Synchronous Motor (PMSM). In the first design, the inverter is directly powered by a high voltage battery and is operated using traditional Pulse-Width Modulation (PWM). In the second design, a bidirectional DC-DC converter is used to connect a lower voltage battery to the inverter and is operated using a variable DC link voltage strategy at different Modulation Indices (MI) and battery voltages. Both powertrains are designed to operate a class 4 delivery truck, which uses two separate motors to power the rear wheels independently through two single-speed gearboxes. The efficiency maps of both systems are examined in the context of different drive cycles for a delivery truck. Furthermore, standard and experimentally captured drive cycles are compared and the results demonstrate the conditions under which the new system is most effective.</description><description>L'efficacité des systèmes de propulsion électrique est d'une importance primordiale pour électrifier le réseau des transports. Chaque topologie différente a ses avantages et ses désavantages. Cette thèse a pour but de comparer l'efficacité de deux de ces systèmes. Les deux utilisent un moteur synchrone à aimant permanent. Le premier est contrôlé par un système de modulation de largeur d'impulsion (MLI) qui est connecté directement à la batterie. Le deuxième est contrôlé aussi par un système de modulation de largeur d'impulsion mais est connecté à un lien-DC variable qui opère à différents indices de modulation et voltages de batterie. Ces systèmes sont conçus pour être utilisés dans des camions de livraison qui sont propulsés par deux moteurs liés aux roues arrières. Chacune des roues arrières est contrôlée indépendamment par un moteur et une boîte de transmission à une vitesse. L'efficacité des deux systèmes a été déterminée en utilisant des cycles de conduite identiques à ceux d'un camion de livraison. De plus, des modèles de cycle standardisés et expérimentaux ont été comparés et les résultats démontrent les conditions sous lesquelles le deuxième système est efficace.</description><creator>Najmabadi, Ali</creator><contributor>Benoit Boulet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Application of a bidirectional DC-DC in an electric powertrain for medium duty delivery trucks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128d80p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8062766</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):8075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>